SUB CREATED BY SALILA
Here began the last
bloody march toward Appomattox,
where General Grant met General
Lee for the first time.
And brave men bled,
set the course of history.
I'm so honored to be here,
celebrating the 150th anniversary
of the Overland Campaign.
Thank you to County
Administrator Roberts,
to all the dedicated
re-enactors,
and, of course,
to Governor O'Keefe,
for organizing such a
wonderful three-day event
That's all, sir? That's it.
Short and sweet.
Or at least it's short.
In Gaffney, people called it the
War of Northern Aggression.
I personally take no pride
in the Confederacy.
Avoid wars you can't win,
and never raise your flag for
an asinine cause like slavery.
He's on his way.
Fine.
People will move on.
They won't.
The less you say,
the more they'll dig.
Let them.
Willa, could you
give us two seconds?
I'll be right outside.
McGinnis happened
in college.
The abortion happened
five years later.
There aren't any
medical records.
None at all?
We specifically
made sure.
A nurse? Somebody
in the waiting room?
The doctor was the only one there.
Then where is he now?
It's a long time ago, Connor.
He passed away.
And if I'm not worried,
you shouldn't be.
Even still, sexual assault is
part of the conversation now.
Every article and column
mentions you.
If we offer nothing,
we can't shape your image.
I made it very clear
I don't want exposure.
When we have something new
to say, we'll say it.
Willa, any luck
with the Joint Chiefs?
The Chairman's office
still says he's unavailable.
But they did offer to send the
Director of the Joint Staff.
11:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Confirm it.
We'll meet in Francis' office at
the West Wing. Anything else?
No. I should get going,
hit the road.
Thank you, Connor.
Get Congresswoman Brooks
on the phone.
And see if the First Lady will
be available this afternoon.
You want a brief on everyone
on the Chinese side of the Summit?
No. What Durant's doing
in Washington is just the facade.
This is the real negotiation.
Give me what
you have on Feng.
Xander Feng. Deep family
connections to the Party.
Grandfather fought
side-by-side with Mao.
Big in the
telecom industry.
Estimated net worth
is over $50 billion.
More than Raymond's.
By a few billion.
But who's counting?
Do they have any other
business partnerships
other than the Rare Earth Refinery?
Not that I could find.
All right. Get a progress
update from Durant.
Tell her I'll be in touch as
soon as we know what Feng wants.
When a man like Raymond Tusk gets
involved in state diplomacy,
you can be sure he's not
after the Nobel Peace Prize.
He's an opportunist.
But so am I.
Maybe this is my opportunity to
loosen his grip on the President.
Mr. Vice President,
when are you
returning to Washington?
Mr. Vice
President, are you...
Mr. Vice President,
do you have any idea
how long you'll
be in Spotsylvania?
Any comments on the talks
with the Chinese?
Can we get a comment on
the upcoming summit talks?
Vice President will be
working from his room
for the remainder
of the day. Go away.
Sir, when are you returning
to Washington?
Mr. Feng. It's a pleasure.
Likewise,
Mr. Vice President.
Coffee? Tea?
I've already been offered,
but thank you.
Thank you, Meechum.
Ifs a long flight from Beijing.
You must be exhausted.
I keep Western hours.
My midnight is your midnight.
So, have you had a chance
to look over the proposal?
I have.
Shall we?
Page four.
The refinery.
With Mr. Tusk.
With the highest bidder.
We're prepared to offer
Clayton West a 40-year lease
on the Mei Mei Rare Earth
Elements Refinery.
To which I will
lend my name.
I understand that you and Raymond
are business associates,
but you're gonna have to
open it up to bidding.
Mr. Tusk will outbid
any competitors.
Well, even so,
for appearances.
Yes. Appearances.
If you must.
So, there are no
issues here, then?
We may proceed.
Page six.
The bridge.
The Committee on
Foreign Investment
will approve a pilot
infrastructure project
to build a bridge over
the Long Island Sound,
from Port Jefferson
to Milford,
in exchange for a 25-year
toll-taking contract.
Before we consider
the bridge,
there's one more item
I'd like to discuss.
"Consider"? I thought the
bridge was definite.
Nothing is definite.
This bridge is
a priority-one item.
It's very important to your President.
I understand.
What would you
like to discuss?
The currency
manipulation suit
which you have
filed against us
in the World Trade
Organization.
Which we are prepared to drop if
all other conditions are met.
The point of this meeting
is to allow us to say things
that cannot be said
in formal settings, yes?
Yes. Of course.
We don't want you
to drop the lawsuit.
Forgive me. I...
I don't understand.
Do not back off
in the WTO.
But you've been fighting us on
currency manipulation for years.
A free-floating currency
is inevitable.
Now I have something
I can work with.
Why the sudden
change of heart?
Not sudden,
it has taken those of us who
are more forward-thinking
many years to convince
our counterparts.
But China could
just do it.
I mean, you know as well as I,
you don't require a WTO ruling.
Appearances, as you say.
It's important that it looks
like America forced us out,
not that we gave in.
Well, I'll need
a little more time,
so that I can brief
the President.
I'm here for as
long as necessary.
However you would like to
communicate, I leave that to you.
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
Thank you, Mr. Feng.
In Gaffney, we had our
own brand of diplomacy.
Shake with your right hand,
but hold a rock in your left.
Look who got stuck
with the pool.
We volunteered because
we hate ourselves.
Ali's well on
the Southern front?
No news is no news.
Come on. I hear there's
muskets out there.
When you giving us
something real?
We're here in beautiful
Spotsylvania, aren't we?
This is dress-up for
grown men with toy guns.
Sounds like
500 words to me.
Tell Durant that China
won't discuss the bridge
unless we drop
the WTO suit.
I thought you said
they want to keep it.
Feng does,
which means Tusk does.
But we don't know
if Beijing does.
You think Feng's lying?
An open currency could
free up interest rates,
reduce inﬂation in China.
They'd both profit.
If they're forcing
Beijing's hand, or we are,
that could throw
the summit into chaos.
Exactly. Look,
Feng may well have support,
but my guess is that the
Standing Committee's divided.
Either way, we'll throw
'em off balance.
Let's leak we're dropping the suit
as soon as Cathy presents it.
Just the lawsuit?
Nothing else in the leak?
A hint of Feng,
but no names.
Let's let this
grow on its own.
How was that?
GAVIN: Much better.
I feel good.
What do you think?
I think you're ready.
How long on the code?
Just a couple of
bugs to workout.
I told them tomorrow or Wednesday.
Work's not done.
If I postpone again, don't you
think it'll draw attention?
It'll be done
when it's done.
I'll email you when
the bugs are fixed.
Somewhere public,
a place and time.
Hey, are you sure
you wanna do this?
I understand the risks.
Well, you think you do.
This isn't the first time
I've been in danger.
Yeah? Paper cuts
at The Herald?
Death threats.
When I exposed
a drug ring in D.C.
You know, I read the articles.
That's small time.
I almost had to go
into protection.
This is the FBI.
It's not a few street cops.
You think you're badass
because you're on some
vigilante anarchy kick?
At least I have the balls to
put my name on the work I do.
You've never faced 100 years in
prison, you self-righteous prick.
Most of my friends are
locked up and rotting away
'cause they poked the bear
one too many times.
Why? They wanted to expose
government surveillance,
the PRISM program, embezzlement,
abuse, fucking torture, lies.
You're a journalist.
Who gives a shit?
We're fucking soldiers.
It's personal for me now.
I don't have a choice,
but you still do.
I don't have a choice.
Where did
you get this?
You could say a source close
to the Chinese delegation.
Give me a name. All I know is
that it's a Chinese businessman
with ties to the Standing Committee
back-channeling the summit.
In Washington?
I don't know.
With who?
I don't know that either.
If I call the USGR's
office, they'll confirm?
I'm telling you
as much as I know.
Why are you telling
me this at all?
They're going public
with it tomorrow anyway.
You might as well
get the scoop.
Why me, specifically?
You deserve better than a Civil
War reenactment.
Please don't pretend you've
suddenly become Santa Claus.
I give you something now,
maybe you remember.
It's an investment
in the future.
I'm not big on favors.
I said, "Maybe."
Connect me to the USGR's office.
Skip the Press Secretary.
Tell them I want to talk
about the WTO suit.
Who did
you speak to?
Connor. He's
talking to Ayla Sayyad.
How much did
you fill him in?
The bare minimum.
I'd be
a lot more comfortable
if it was you going
directly, as we discussed.
This puts distance on me,
which puts distance on you.
I want you to meet with Feng tonight.
No proxies.
Understood.
Now where are we
with Mr. Goodwin?
Any day now.
Thirty-five to life.
Cyber terrorism.
Penalties are stiff.
This needs to be clean, Doug.
It will be.
One fall of the ax.
Keep me informed.
Yes, sir.
Well, I just think what you
did took so much bravery.
To go on air like that,
in front of the whole country,
and say what you did?
That means a lotto me.
And I admire
what you both have
been doing to
advocate for the...
Well, for the victims.
Well, women, like you and me.
Not victims.
Men, too.
It's not gender-specific.
Well, yes.
Would you consider
pitching in?
How?
It would send
a strong message
if we had the First Lady
in our corner.
If you think I could help.
If the head of
the Women's Caucus,
both wives from
the White House...
That's a meeting they
couldn't sweep under the rug.
And the fact that the Chairman
sent anyone is promising,
but we need to make sure our
message gets back to him.
I just... I haven't been through
the same sort of experience.
Well, why should
that prevent you?
I don't know if I have a
right to speak about it.
You're the First Lady.
You have the right to speak
about anything you want.
Mr. White?
Mrs. Marbury.
I'm Susan. Well, it's a
pleasure to meet you.
I know I'm a little
off the beaten path.
Did you have any
trouble finding me?
No. The directions
were great. Easy as pie.
Well, good. Come in.
I have to admit I've been looking
forward to this all day.
I didn't realize you
were announcing so soon.
We've had some great luck
with the endowment.
Well, my husband didn't get much
recognition while he was alive.
I was so thrilled
when Planned Parenthood asked
to name a fund after him.
Well, we're thrilled
that you're open to it.
When you called, you said
you had some questions?
They're delicate. That's
why I wanted to come in person.
Delicate, how?
There are a lot of
people who will protest
this sort of financial
assistance to minors.
And we want to make sure they
have no cause to smear us.
People tried to smear my
husband his entire career.
He never let it affect
the work he was doing.
Did your husband ever perform
any illegal abortions?
I need you to answer me,
Mrs. Marbury.
Did your husband perform
any illegal abortions?
I won't discuss that.
Nothing unreported?
Young man, you're not
old enough to remember.
But there was a time
when everybody...
What about any
prominent figures
who the Anti-Choice
crowd could vilify?
No.
Did Dr. Marbury perform an
abortion for Claire Underwood?
No, he did not.
I know for a fact
that he did.
That is not true.
And I would like you
to leave now.
Forgive me, Mrs. Marbury.
I haven't been entirely
honest with you.
My name's Seth Grayson. I don't
work for Planned Parenthood.
No. Let him come to me.
Get Mr. Tusk on the phone.
You should be
ashamed of yourself.
I'm doing this for your
own good, Mrs. Marbury.
Imagine the media frenzy. Your
husband's legacy, destroyed.
The press hounding you,
day and night.
And Planned
Parenthood Fund, gone.
How do I know
you work for her?
That you're not just some
right-wing fanatic
who wants to destroy...
Because I wouldn't have done you
the courtesy of paying a visit.
There would've been
an army of satellite trucks
at your door instead of me.
Well, I won't tell anyone, if
that's what you're worried about.
I believe you.
Did your husband keep records
of any kind of who he assisted?
Anything at all? Notes?
Unofficial records?
He kept a journal.
Do you still have it?
May I?
Go ahead.
Oh.
I need to take
this with me.
Can't you just take out that page?
Someone finds this with pages
missing, that could raise eyebrows.
There's 60 years
of his life in there.
From when we met
until he died.
And do you want
six decades
reduced to one night
in August 25 years ago?
Now just imagine what it
looked like back then.
The edge of the ridge
was a dense thicket,
which allowed
the Northern troops
to come in and form
on the Mule Shoe.
Now, the Southern regiments
were entrenched
in this area at
the apex of the line.
As you can see,
the topography
really forced the two sides
down towards each other.
This is the Bloody Angle.
That's right.
I was reading
about it last night.
Close quarters,
hand-to-hand combat.
All told, about 15,000
Union-Confederate soldiers
lost their lives here
at the Bloody Angle,
on a battlefield that's only
about half a mile wide.
Now, Mr. Vice President, we
have a surprise for you today.
I'd like to introduce you to
Corporal Augustus Elijah Underwood
of the 12th Regiment
of McGowan Brigade,
your great-great-
great-grandfather.
I died here in this battle.
I think there's
been a mistake.
My grandfather never mentioned
any Underwoods in the war.
We did our research. He
definitely fought and died here.
I was 24.
My son, your
great-great-grandfather
was two years old.
I never met him.
It happened here,
at the Bloody Angle?
At the
edge of those woods.
My skull was bashed
in with a rock.
Leon, thank you.
Now, over here
we've got something
that's very
interesting as well.
Just a moment.
Tell me more.
It was the middle
of the night.
And we were out of musket
balls, just bayonets.
Only half of us
had those.
I had nothing.
Just these hands.
So dark,
couldn't see nothing.
But you could hear 'em,
the Yanks, running toward us.
And then you
could smell 'em.
First Yank that
brushed up against me,
I grab him by the throat,
fall down on the ground.
I bit him so hard,
I could taste the bone.
Then he grabs a rock and
brings it down right here.
And that was that.
I was buried in a mass
grave, no headstone.
Could we get a picture
with you and Augustus?
Yes.
Thank you.
He takes it
rather seriously.
Oh, yeah.
They all do.
Now, up ahead,
we have examples
of Confederate ramparts
that we've reconstructed.
And you can see how they cut the
timber and made the trenches.
Now these trenches traded hands many
times over the course of the battle.
You have keys.
We own you.
Yes, we have keys.
I'm gonna put some clothes on.
Forget your clothes.
And I quote, "You sure
you wanna do this?"
And I quote, "I don't have
a choice, but you do."
What the fuck do you
think you're doing?
He should know
what he's getting into.
Are those silk pajamas?
Looks even
fancier in person.
Cashew.
No. Don't touch her.
Hey there, little guy.
I've seen you before
on camera, hmm?
Please put her down.
Don't take the chance.
I bought these shoes at J.C.
Penney, $72 with tax.
Rubber soles. You can clean
'em off with a hose.
Please, you're
hurting her.
I have a pet, too. His
name is Gavin Orsay. Sit.
I said, "Sit."
Look what a good
boy you are, Gavin.
Is that what you
need me to do?
Quiet. When I say
"Fetch," you fetch.
And now we are going to fetch
Lucas, just like we discussed.
If you try to bite my hand,
I will put you to sleep.
Mind if I take a couple?
Doug Stamper, I'm the Vice
President's Chief of Staff.
I know. Sit down.
My grandfather fought
in the Revolution.
China was poor then.
Sugar was hard
to come by.
Now, sugar's
everywhere in China.
Do you like
Old Fashioneds?
No, thanks.
I've seen the news.
Your government was enthusiastic
about us dropping the suit.
They've touted it
as a victory back home.
It is a victory, but not
the victory we wanted.
We're finding that
difficult to believe.
By "we," you mean
the Vice President.
I mean the American
government.
Which he proclaims
to represent.
He does.
And I'm representing him.
Don't inflate your
status, Mr. Stamper.
You're nothing
but an errand boy.
Do you have a message
for the Vice President?
If he represents
the American government,
then why did he fail to
communicate my request?
We question your
legitimacy, Mr. Feng.
Nothing your delegation
has done or said
has in any way
supported your requests.
Mmm.
Smell that.
I use Macallan rare and fine, 1926.
$40,000 a bottle.
You used to be an
alcoholic, correct?
Not "used to be."
Still am. A sober one.
Do you miss it?
$5,000 you just spilled.
I'll send you a check.
I like you, Mr. Stamper, even
if you're just an errand boy.
I'll ask you again.
What is your message
for the Vice President?
There will be no
Port Jefferson Bridge
unless the lawsuit
is reintroduced.
When you do,
there will be those on the
Standing Committee who protest,
but I'll manage them.
The majority want reform.
I'll tell the
Vice President.
Mr. Stamper,
one more message.
Please remind the Vice President
that we are both here
at the behest of our
mutual friend, Mr. Tusk.
If the Vice President fails to
cooperate, I will simply bypass him.
Yes?
It's Doug.
Fine.
Spoke with Feng.
Here's your onion rings.
Did you know that General Longstreet
was shot here accidentally,
by his own men
in the dark?
No, I didn't.
All right. Bring me up to date.
Where are we with Feng?
He wants us to
resume the lawsuit.
So, he's sticking
to his guns.
If we don't reintroduce it,
there's no bridge project.
Well, that would greatly
upset the President.
Do you want me to
deliver Feng's message?
Absolutely not.
We want the
President angry.
The tricky part is making sure
he doesn't direct it toward me.
So what do you
want me to do?
Get a hold of
Cathy's people.
Do not mention
the lawsuit at all.
Have them bring up
the bridge instead.
Let's see if
Feng is bluffing.
Yes, sir.
We must learn
from Longstreet.
He rode too high
in the saddle.
If a bullet comes my way tomorrow,
it will not be an accident,
and I must be
quick to duck.
Gentlemen,
thank you for coming.
Is the Vice President
attending?
No, he's not.
He's out of town.
I just decided
to use his office
because it's a bit bigger than mine.
Please, sit.
I know this isn't
the first conversation
you've had about
sexual assault.
We've had a very
open dialog
with the Congresswoman
for quite some time.
Open is
one way to put it.
I think the Joint Chiefs have
tolerated my concerns, but...
To be fair,
we've been quite responsive.
Over the past
two years alone...
The Congresswoman has
expressed her frustration to me
that there's still
room for improvement
Mrs. Underwood,
if I may.
Please.
This is an issue
we've grappled with seriously.
Increased education
and prevention measures,
restructuring
the reporting process,
insulating courts martial
from abuse of power.
It's still not enough.
Civilian jurisdiction
is not gonna happen.
We're all aware that's what the
Congresswoman would prefer,
but we won't allow our...
Am I late?
It's my fault. The
meeting got pushed up.
I meant to e-mail you.
I'm very sorry.
That's fine.
Please, sit.
We didn't know you'd be
attending, Mrs. Walker.
I'm sorry for interrupting.
Continue.
As I was saying,
putting sexual
assault cases
entirely in the hands
of civilian courts
fundamentally erodes the military's
ability to self-discipline.
What about civilian oversight
instead of civilian courts?
That's
a slippery slope.
There were those who said
the same of racial integration.
Integration didn't change the
core operational nature of the...
But it did prove that the
military could shape its own evolution.
Absolutely. But in this case,
civilian oversight is not the answer.
My husband is a civilian
who oversees the military.
Are you suggesting
that civilians can offer
no guidance
in matters like this?
Forgive me, Mrs. Walker. I didn't
mean to suggest that at all.
Then maybe you
should listen
to the civilian
sitting across from you.
Yes, ma'am.
This is from your own sexual
assault prevention literature.
And in it, it says
in some cases,
it may be advisable
to submit than to resist.
I think it's quite clear that
there's still room for improvement.
Did you know about Xander Feng?
Not until I saw
his name on the wire.
He's been charged
with corruption twice.
Both times the charges
were dropped.
Do you know what happens in
China if you're convicted?
I'm guessing
it's not good.
You die.
There you go.
We're talking about a man
who's only one kangaroo court
away from lethal injection,
who's filthy rich
and clearly corrupt
And this is who
the Chinese send?
You're asking
the wrong guy.
Stop dodging-
I passed a note in class.
That's all.
We placed our
faith in you, Frank.
We still have
the rest of today
and all of tomorrow,
Mr. President.
I need this bridge.
Otherwise, we have to stall
my infrastructure program.
No foreign investment,
no deficit reduction.
And the Chinese know this.
They're using it for leverage.
Yeah, but for what?
Well, that
I'm not sure of.
Then why did we send you
to Spotsylvania, Frank?
You're supposed to have
answers to these questions.
Mr. President, I spoke
to Mr. Feng an hour ago.
What's' he say?
Here comes the bullet.
He claims
that Frank hasn't been
delivering his
messages properly.
I have conveyed his
requests word for word.
He says you've
been doing the opposite.
Whose responsible for the
back-channeling here, me or Raymond?
You are, Frank. I'm simply here
to facilitate, not negotiate.
And yet, you continue
to have private conversations
with Beijing's
supposed emissary.
Listen, Frank...
Are you prepared to trust Mr. Penny's
word over mine, Raymond?
No one is doubting
your word, Frank.
Well, if Feng is truly representing
his government's interest,
then why is he telling Raymond one
thing and telling me another?
How do you explain
the bridge falling through?
Well, he personally profits
from a free-floating currency,
just as anyone would
who's in business with him,
such as yourself, Raymond.
The refinery and the bridge are
two completely different issues.
Let's keep our focus here.
I want the bridge back on the
table, end of story. Catherine?
It'll be the first
item I bring up in the morning.
Frank, stay put for now.
But don't contact Feng.
And that goes for
you too, Raymond.
I don't want any more back-channeling
until the bridge is revived.
And, Catherine, you
communicate directly with me.
Yes, sir.
We're done here.
The first drops of
blood have been spilt.
Bullet grazed my cheek,
but I haven't fallen.
Doug, find me a way
to meet Feng.
We need to discuss something first.
What's wrong?
I just got off the phone with
a guy named Seth Grayson.
I've spoken
with my husband.
GRAYSON: Doug told me.
Thank you for
fitting me in today.
Is that it?
August '86.
And why should
we trust you?
There was evidence that
Connor didn't make disappear.
I could've taken this to Us
Weekly and bought a new house.
Instead,
I brought it to you.
And why didn't you apply when I
was interviewing candidates?
There's no point.
Willa doesn't like me.
I intimidate her.
That journal is my
version of a resume.
Or extortion.
I'm not extorting you,
Mrs. Underwood.
I'm just highlighting
the difference
between a good choice
and the right choice.
And tell me, how would we
handle the repercussions
of firing our comm director three
months after we hire him'?
You don't fire him.
You tell him that you're bringing me
on board to help with the workload.
He stays on with you.
I cover your husband.
Connor will hate
working with me.
I'll arrange a job offer
elsewhere in a few months.
By the time it comes in,
he'll want to move on.
Connor knows.
What's to prevent him
from going public?
I can handle
Connor Ellis.
You just have to take me
on my word on that. I...
Here's what I know.
It is far easier for
you to destroy me
than the other
way around.
I have to speak
to my husband.
Of course.
I didn't make any copies.
You have the only one.
Uh, Johnnie Walker
Black, neat.
Where is it?
It's in my pocket.
Come on.
Something up'?
No. We're good to go.
You seem nervous.
Just because I've been
breaking the law for 20 years
doesn't mean I don't
still get nervous.
Gavin.
Do not say my name.
Look at me.
It's gonna be fine. We practiced.
I'm confident.
This is gonna work.
I got your drink.
He's more
than qualified.
What do your
instincts tell you?
That I just don't wanna
end up more exposed.
Well, Grayson
already knows,
and if we don't exhibit
some degree of...
Have Doug look into him. Let's
see if there's some leverage.
Yeah, but we don't know
what he'll find or when,
or what he'll do
in the meantime.
And that puts us into
unchartered territory.
Well, Connor will expose
us too, if we let him go.
Not if it goes smoothly.
If we tum away Grayson now,
we can't predict anything.
And look, he has a lot
less to lose than we do.
Okay. I just...
I don't think we can
trust him, Francis.
We wouldn't be having
this conversation
if Connor had done his job.
I'd rather manage someone I don't
trust than someone who is reckless.
Fine. What's the next step?
I'd like to talk to
Grayson myself first,
and then I'll have
Doug talk to Connor.
How are you doing'?
You been following
the news?
Is it bad for us?
Or good?
Could go either way.
Fm here if you need me.
I'm back tomorrow.
I love you.
Love you too.
We all set'?
All set, sir.
Let's go.
Oh, no, no. Turn those off.
Turn those off.
Where is he?
Right this way, sir.
Did Augustus play?
I like to think I did.
What's your name?
When I'm here,
I'm Augustus Underwood.
What's your real name? Doesn't
this feel real to you?
Will you show me where he died?
The exact spot.
I will, sir.
I'm gonna pay respects
to my ancestor.
I would appreciate
a little privacy.
We'll wait here.
John on the move.
Just beyond those trees.
Thank you.
I'll be good from here.
We're fine.
I hope you haven't
waited long.
It's peaceful here.
I didn't mind.
Peaceful now.
Fifteen thousand men
died in these woods.
My grandfather's grandfather
died where we're standing.
My grandfather was killed
in the Revolution.
So I've heard.
Do you fear death,
Mr. Vice President?
No more or less
than any man.
It motivates me.
To experience everything,
accomplish all I can
before it all vanishes.
I think you and I are
similar in that regard.
Then why are we working
at cross purposes?
Now what you mean is,
"Why am I not submitting
to you and Mr. Tusk?"
You're sabotaging
the negotiations.
And you're using them
for your own personal ends.
Wrong.
It's taken me seven years to
convince the Standing Committee
that this was the right
course of action.
A course of action that will
earn you and Tusk billions.
Why did you want this meeting?
Just to attack me?
To send a message
to Raymond.
The President of the United
States and I are not his puppets.
Now you tell him that. Fine.
The bridge deal is dead.
There will be
no saving it.
Stick a knife through its heart
and put an apple in its mouth.
I won't shed a tear.
Your President will ascribe
the failure to you.
I'll take the risk.
Think strategically,
Mr. Vice President.
You're setting us on
a very dangerous course.
Do you know how
Grant defeated Lee?
He had more men.
That's all.
And he was willing
lo let them die.
It was butchery, not
strategy, which won the war.
Mr. Tusk and I have great
resources at our disposal.
Add up all your
billions together,
and you get the GDP
of Slovakia.
I have the federal government of
the United States of America.
Your money doesn't
intimidate me.
The most that you
can buy is influence.
But I wield
constitutional authority.
The strongest army
doesn't always win.
Mao started out with
only a few thousand men.
They took over
half a continent.
Mao is dead.
And so is his China.
But I'm not.
Not yet.
Don't forget. Your ancestor
fought for the losing side.
There is no sacred ground
for the conquered.
We have over
9,000 sewers here,
utilized by several
hundred clients.
Everything from small businesses
to major corporations.
What are some of
the largest clients?
The largest here is AT&T.
Their servers occupy more
than half of the floor space.
And can you show me?
I am.
Right this way.
Did you or did you not
meet with Feng last night?
Where is this
coming from, Raymond?
Answer the question, Frank.
I have not contacted him since
you and I spoke, Mr. President.
Just as you
instructed me to do.
Not according to Feng.
I believe you were also instructed
to avoid him too, Raymond.
He reached outta me.
I just answered the call.
We had clear,
prearranged terms, Frank.
Months of back-channeling.
I am on the front
lines, Mr. President.
And I can tell you firsthand
that we are dealing with a regime
that is not being forthright
and will seize upon the
faintest whiff of trepidation.
This is a test to see how far
they can push us before we break.
Do not play their game.
End the talks.
We can't
overreact here.
Well, they walked away
from the Joint Commission.
We can walk away
from the summit,.
The economic fallout would be catastrophic.
The market would...
Or we can just
kowtow and submit to
the new reigning superpower.
Don't be
hyperbolic, Frank.
Well, we are dealing with one
quarter of the world's population.
Mr. President, you would be
making a disastrous mistake.
Where are your
allegiances, Raymond?
With Xander Feng
or to the United...
Don't you dare
question me about...
All right. Silence.
There were two mistakes.
Both of them mine.
The first was
allowing you, Raymond,
to enlist one of your business
partners for these talks.
I was simply trying to...
And the second
was enlisting you, Frank.
Instead of clarity,
we got miscommunication.
That's poor diplomacy.
Mr. President, listen...
I've listened to both of you and
all I've heard is accusations.
Now, if neither one of you will
take responsibility, I will.
We're pulling out.
That's not because you
suggested it, Frank.
It's because you've made such
a mess of these negotiations
that I have no other choice
than a show of strength.
You've both disappointed
me greatly.
Mr, President?
The President
has left the call.
Raymond,
are you still there?
That's the first time he's ever
hung up on me in 20 years.
I feel for you.
Goodbye, Frank.
And the butchery begins.
It's all the way down this row
and the next seven rows over.
Now you wanted to see
inside one, right?
Yeah, that would
be great.
Go ahead.
There's not much
to it, actually.
Just a lot of hard
drives and wires.
So in terms of backup,
if the power goes down,
some natural disaster hits,
like a storm, or an
earthquake, what exactly...
On the ground. Freeze!
No, no, I...  Right now.
On the ground!
On the ground now!
Why don't you ride
back to D.C. with me?
We need to discuss something.
What's up?
Talk about it
in the car.
Today, we break earth on the
Overland Campaign Visitors Center.
So that generations to come
will fully absorb the importance
of this hallowed ground,
the wilderness where
the campaign commenced.
Augustus.
Would you clothe honor?
And now, a moment of silence
and prayer for the dead.
Thank you.
And God bless the United
States of America.
I just heard.
We got Lucas Goodwin.