Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed when
the fire nation attacked
Only the avatar mastered all
four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother and
I discovered the new avatar
an airbender named Aang
And although his airbending
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
...Aang can save the world
You and Sokka have to go
with Aang somewhere safe
it's the only way to keep hope alive.
I'm going to join the Avatar,
and I'm going to help him defeat you.
Since you're a full blown traitor now
and you want me gone, why wait?
Because I know my own destiny.
Taking you down is the Avatar's destiny.
I know just the place for us to go
where we'll be safe for a while.
The Western Air Temple.
Book Three: Fire
Chapter Twelve: The Western Air Temple
This is humiliating.
Do you mean getting thoroughly
spanked by the Fire Nation,
or having to walk all the way
to the Western Air Temple?
Both.
Sorry guys, but Appa gets tired
carrying all these people.
I wonder how the rest of the troops are.
They're probably on their way to a prisson.
Seems like my dad just got out,
now he's going back in.
I miss Pipsqueak.
I miss not having blisters on my feet.
Hey! We're here! I can feel it.
Uhh... I think your feet
need their eyes checked...
No, she's right. We're here.
Wow! It's amazing!
What a stunning view!
The only view I'm interested in seeing
is the Avatar in chains.
You know the Avatar hasn't been seen
for a hundred years.
The chances of finding
him here are very slim.
First we'll check each of the Air Temples.
Then we'll scour the world,
searching even the most remote
locations until we find him.
Prince Zuko,
it's only been a week
since your banishment.
You should take some time to heal and rest.
What else would I expect to hear from
the laziest man in the Fire Nation.
The only way to regain my honor is
to find the Avatar...
so I will.
It's so different from
the Nothern Air Temple.
I wonder if there are any secret rooms.
Let's go check it out.
You guys go. I think we need to talk
about some things.
I'll race you Duke.
I told you, is The Duke!
Why can't I go?
We need to decide what we're gunna do now,
and since you're the Avatar
maybe you should be a part of this.
Fair enough.
So, what's the new plan?
Well, if you ask me,
the new plan... is the old plan.
You just need to master all four elements and
confront the Fire Lord before the commet comes.
Oh, yeah. That's great.
No problem. I'll just do that.
Aang, no one said it's gunna be easy.
Well, it's not even going to be possible.
Where am I supposed to get
a firebending teacher?
We could look for Jeong Jeong.
Yeah, right. Like we'll ever
run into Jeong Jeong again.
Who's...
Oh... never mind.
If it's important I'll find out.
Oh well, guess we can't
come up with anybody.
Why don't we just take a nice tour
around the temple?
What's up with him?
There's got to be someone who
can teach him firebending.
Hello,
Zuko here.
But I guess you probably already know me,
sort of... uh.
So, the thing is, I have a lot of
fire-bending experience
and I'm considered to be pretty good at it.
Well you've seem me...
you know, when I was attacking you...
Uh, yeah, I guess I should
apologize for that.
B...but anyway... I'm good now.
I mean I thought I was good before
but now I realize I was bad...
But anyway... I think it's time I joined your
group and taught the Avatar firebending.
Well, what's your answer!
Yeah, that's what I'd say too.
How am I supposed to convince
these people I'm on their side!?
What would uncle do?
Zuko, you have to look within yourself
to save yourself from your other self.
Only then will your true
self reveal itself.
Even when I'm talking for him I
can't figure out what he means.
What would Azula do?
Listen Avatar, I can join your group or I can do
something unspeakably horrible to you and your friends.
Your choice.
I guess I'm not that
good at impersonations.
Aang, can we talk about you
learning firebending now?
What? The wind is too loud in my ears.
Check out this loop.
Aang, I think we should be making
some plans about our future.
Okay. We can do that while I show you
the giant Pai Sho table.
Oh, your gunna love the
all-day echo chamber.
I think that'll have to wait.
Hello, Zuko here.
Hey, I heard you guys flying around down there so...
I just thought I'd wait for you here.
I know you must be
surprised to see me here.
Not really, since you followed
us all over the world.
Right... Well, uh, anyway...
What I wanted to tell you...
about is that I've changed.
And I, uh, I'm good now.
And, well I think I should join your group.
Oh, and I can teach firebending, to you.
See, I, uh...
You wanna what now?
You can't possibly think that any
of us would trust you, can you!?
I mean how stupid do you think we are?
Yeah, all you've ever done is try to hunt
us down and capture Aang.
I've done some good things.
I mean, I could have stolen your bison
in Ba Sing Se, but I set him free.
That's something.
Appa does seem to like him.
He probably just covered himself in honey or something
so that Appa would lick him. I'm not buying it.
I could understand why you wouldn't trust me, and
I know I've made some mistakes in the past...
Like when you attacked our village.
Or when you stole my mother's necklace and
used it to track us down and capture us.
Look, I admit I've done some awful things.
I was wrong to try to capture you, and
I'm sorry that I attacked the Water Tribe.
And I never should have sent that
Fire Nation assassin after you.
I'm gunna try to stop...
Wait! You sent Combustion Man after us!
Well, that's not his name, but...
Oh, sorry.
I didn't mean to insult your friend.
He's not my friend.
That guy locked me and Katara in
jail and tried to blow us all up!
Why aren't you saying anything?
You once said you thought
we could be friends.
You know I have good in me.
There's no way we can trust you
after everything you've done.
We'll never let you join us.
You need to get out of here, now!
I'm trying to explain that
I'm not that person anymore.
Either you leave, or we attack.
If you won't accept me as a friend, then
maybe you'll take me as a prisoner.
No, we won't!
Get out of here and don't come back.
And if we ever see you again...
well, we'd better not see you again.
Ugh. I can't believe how stupid I am.
I mean, what was I thinking, telling them
I sent an assassin after them.
Why didn't I just say Azula did that?
They would have believed that. Stupid.
Why would he try to fool us like that?
Obviously he wants to lead
us into some kind of trap.
This is just like when we were in
prison together in Ba Sing Se.
He starts talking about his mother and making it
seem like he's an actual human being with feelings.
He wants you to trust him and feel sorry for him
so you let your guard down. Then he strikes.
The thing is, it worked.
I did feel sorry for him.
I felt like he was really
confused and hurt.
But, obviously when the time came he
made his choice, and we paid the price.
We can't trust him.
I kind of have a confession to make.
Remember when you two were sick and I got captured by Zhao?
And you made us suck on frozen frogs.
How could I forget?
I had a wart on the flap that hangs down
from the back of my throat for a month.
Sokka, I looked at it and told
you there was nothing there.
I could feel it. It's my throat-hole flap.
Anyway, when Zhao had me chained up it
was Zuko who came in and got me out.
He risked his life to save me.
No way. I'm sure he only did it so he
could capture you himself.
Yeah, face it Aang.
You're nothing but a big prize to him.
You're probably right.
And what was all that crazy stuff
about setting Appa free? What a liar.
Actually, he wasn't lying.
Oh, hurray. In a lifetime of evil at least
he didn't add animal cruelty to the list.
I'm just saying... that considering his messed up family and
how he was raised, he could have turned out a lot worse.
You're right Toph.
Let's go find him and give him a medal.
The not as much of a jerk as
you could have been award.
All I know is that while he was
talking to us he was sincere.
Maybe you're all just letting your hurt
feelings keep you from thinking clearly.
Easy for you to say! You weren't there
when he had us attacked by pirates...
Or when he burned down Kyoshi Island...
Or when he tried to capture me
at the fire temple.
Why would you even try to defend him!?
Because, Katara, you're all
ignoring one crucial fact.
Aang needs a firebending teacher.
We can't think of a single person
in the world to do the job,
now one shows up on a silver platter
and you won't even think about it!
I'm not having Zuko as my teacher.
You're darn right you're not buddy.
Well, I guess that's settled.
Urrg! I'm beginning to wonder who's
really the blind one around here.
Who's there? Stay back!
It's me.
You burned my feet!
I'm sorry! It was a mistake!
Get away from me!
Let me help you. I'm sorry.
Get off me! Get off me!
I didn't know it was you. Come back!
Gaww! Why am I so bad at being good!?
Has anyone seen Toph?
I haven't seen her since
she stormed off yesterday.
Maybe she's just exploring the air temple.
There are some pretty fun spots
to practice earthbending.
I think we should go look for her.
Aah, let her have fun with her rocks.
I'm in no rush to have
her yelling at us again.
We can go check for her.
Yeah, I want to ride that tunnel
down at the hall of statues again.
It'll work a lot better now
that I fixed my breaks.
Toph, what happened?
My feet got burned.
Oh, no! What happened?
I just told you, my feet got burned.
I meant how.
Well, I kind of went to
see Zuko last night.
You what!
Zuko!
Aah!
I just thought he could
be helpful to us, and,
if I talked to him maybe we
could work something out.
So he attacked you.
Well, he did and he didn't.
It was sort of an accident.
But he did firebend at you.
Yes.
See, you trusted Zuko and you got burned.
Literally.
It's gunna take a while for your feet to get better.
I wish I could've worked on them sooner.
Yeah, me too.
Zuko's clearly too dangerous to be left alone.
We're gunna have to go after him.
I hate to go looking for a
fight, but you're right.
After what he did to Toph, I don't think
we have a choice.
He's crafty but we'll find
a way to capture him.
Maybe just invite him back here.
He's already offered himself
up as a prisoner once.
Yeah... Get him to come back,
and say he'll be our prisoner,
then we'll jump him and really make him our prisoner.
He'll never suspect it.
You are a master of surprise Sokka.
Aah, that's the stuff.
Now I know how the rest of you guys feel.
Not being able to see
with your feet stinks.
Stop! I don't want you
hunting the Avatar anymore.
The mission is off.
I'm ordering you to stop.
If you keep attacking, I won't pay you.
Aah. Alright, I'll pay you double to stop.
He's going to blast this whole
place right off the cliff side.
I can't step out to waterbend at
him without getting blown up.
And I can't get a good enough angle on
him from down here.
I know how to get an angle on him.
Alright buddy, don't fail me now.
Yeah, boomerang!
Aww, boomerang.
I can't believe I'm saying this, but...
thanks Zuko.
Hey, what about me?
I did the boomerang thing.
Listen. I know I didn't explain
myself very well yesterday.
I've been through a lot in the past
few years, and it's been hard.
But I'm realizing that I had to go through
all those things to learn the truth.
I thought I had lost my honor, and that
somehow my father could return it to me.
But I know now that no one
can give you your honor.
It's something you earn for yourself
by choosing to do what's right.
All I want now is to play my part in
ending this war.
And I know my destiny is to help
you restore balance to the world.
I'm sorry for what I did to you.
It was an accident.
Fire can be dangerous and wild.
So as a firebender, I need to be
more careful and control my bending,
so I don't hurt people unintentionally.
I think you are supposed to
be my firebending teacher.
When I first tried to learn firebending, I burned Katara,
and after that I never wanted to firebend again.
But now I know you understand how easy
it is to hurt the people you love.
I'd like you to teach me.
Thank you. I'm so happy you've
accepted me into your group.
Not so fast. I still have to ask my friends
if it's okay with them.
Toph, you're the one that Zuko burned.
What do you think?
Go ahead and let him join. It'll give me plenty
of time to get back at him for burning my feet.
Sokka?
Hey, all I want is to defeat the Fire Lord.
If you think this is the way
to do it, then I'm all for it.
Katara?
I'll go along with whatever
you think is right.
I won't let you down, I promise.
So, here you go. Home sweet home.
I guess, you know, for now.
Unpack. Lunch, soon.
Uhh. Welcome aboard.
Yeah.
Okay. This is really, really weird.
If I have to, I will spend every day of
the rest of my life hunting the Avatar.
I know it's my destiny to capture him.
You know, prince Zuko,
destiny is a funny thing.
You never know how things
are going to work out.
But if you keep an open
mind and an open heart
I promise you will find
your own destiny someday.
You might have everyone else here
buying your "transformation",
but you and I both know you've struggled
with doing the right thing in the past.
So let me tell you something right now.
You make one step backward, one slip up,
give me one reason to think
you might hurt Aang...
and you won't have to worry
about your destiny anymore.
Because I will make sure your destiny
ends, right then and there. Permanently.
Fixed by LEO33
Subtitle by Osimon [at gmail dot com]