Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air.
Long ago...
The four nations lived
together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the fire nation attacked.
Only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most
he vanished.
100 years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
an airbender named aang.
And although his airbending
skills were great
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe aang
can save the world.
I am proud of you, prince zuko.
You slayed the avatar.
You're so beautiful
when you hate the world.
I don't hate you.
I don't hate you, too.
I have everything
I always wanted.
But it's not at all
how I thought it would be.
The avatar is alive.
I want you to find him...
And end him.
I'm so excited to spend
the weekend on ember island.
It's gonna be great to hang out
on the beach and do nothing.
Doing nothing
is a waste of time.
We're being sent away
on a forced vacation.
I feel like a child.
Lighten up.
So dad wants to meet
with his advisors alone
without anyone else around.
Don't take it personally.
Doesn't your family have
a house on ember island?
We used to come every
summer when we were kids.
That must've been fun.
That was a long time ago.
Welcome to ember island, kids.
It smells like
old lady in here.
Gee, I wonder why.
Who are these
two beautiful women?
Can't you tell?
It's li
and me. S lo and me.
Ooh, I love
this seashell bedspread.
Are you serious?
It looks like the beach
threw up all over it.
We know you're upset
that you were forced
to come here this weekend.
But ember island
is a magical place
keep an open mind.
Give it a chance.
And it can help you understand
yourselves and each other.
The beach has a special way
of smoothing even
the most ragged edges.
Time to hit the beach.
Aang, I know
swimming is fun and all
but do you really think you should
be exposing yourself like that?
Cover up.
What?
I'm wearing trunks.
I know, it's youtattoos
I'm worried about.
What if someone sees you?
There are walls all around us.
It's completely safe.
Whoo, hey!
This has got to be the most
boring job in the fire nation.
Nothing ever happens.
Whoa!
Let's go again.
The avatar's alive.
We better send a messenger
hawk to the fire lord.
A black ribbon message.
This is so exciting.
Ahh!
Hey, you need
some help unpacking?
Sure, thanks.
Could you scooch just
a little bit more to the...
Perfect.
Here...
This is for you.
Why would I want that?
I saw it and I thought
it was pretty.
Don't girls like
stuff like this?
Maybe stupid girls.
Forget it!
Wow, thanks.
This is so pretty.
Not as pretty as you are.
That shell's not so great.
Ahem, shade... shade.
I thought since
it's so hot... here.
Thks.
This is really refreshing.
Hey, beach bums,
we're playing next.
Ty Lee, get over here now.
See that girl with
the silly pigtails?
When she runs
towards the ball...
There's just the slightest
hesitation of her left foot.
I'm willing to bet a childhood
injury has weakened her.
Keep serving the ball to her
left and we'll destroy her
and the rest of her team.
Dismissed.
Yes, we defeated you
for all time.
You will never rise from the ashes
of your shame and humiliation.
Well, that was fun.
I'm having a party tonight.
You should come by.
Sure...
I love parties.
Your friend can come, too.
Uh, what about
me and my brother?
Aren't you going to invite us?
You don't know
who we are, do you?
Don't you know who we are?
We're chan and ruon-jian.
Yeah.
But fine, you're invited.
Just so you know, though
some of the most important
teenagers in the fire nation
are gonna be at this party so...
Try and act normal.
We'll do our best.
Why didn't you tell
those guys who were were?
I guess I was intrigued.
I'm so used to
people worshipping us.
They should.
Yes, I know, and I love it.
But for once,
I just wanted to see
how people would treat us if
they didn't know who we were.
Like waves washing away
the footprints othe sand
ember island gives
everyone a clean slate.
Ember island
reveals the true you.
To the party.
Um... you're a little early.
No one's here yet.
I heard you telling someone
you'd be partying
from dusk till dawn.
It's dusk so we're here.
But that's just an expression.
We are the perfect party guests.
We arrive right on time
because we are very punctual.
All right, listen,
my dad's an admiral.
He has no idea
I'm having this party
so don't mess anything up.
That's a sharp
outfit, chan... careful.
You could puncture the hull
of an empire-class fire nation battleship
leaving thousands
to drown at sea...
Because it so sharp.
Um... thanks.
Hey, first ones here, huh?
He thinks he's so great.
Well, what do you think of him?
I don't have any
opinion about him.
I hardly know him.
You like him, don't you?
So how do you know ty Lee?
I met her at the beach today.
She was pretty impressed
by a sand pagoda that I made for her.
Well, I met her first.
Look, it doesn't matter
who I met first 'cause I like you all.
But which one of us
do you like?
Yeah.
Tell us.
I don't know, I don't know.
Ooh.
Ahh...
Oh, I'm glad you're here.
Those boys won't
leave me alone.
I guess they all
just like me too much.
Come on, ty Lee,
you can't be this ignorant.
What are you talking about?
Those boys only like you because
you make it so easy for them.
You're not a challenge-
you're a tease.
It's not like they
actually care who you are.
Ok, ok, calm down.
I didn't mean what I said.
Look, maybe I just said it
because I was a little...
Jealous.
What?
You were jealous of me?
Um, but, you're the most beautiful,
smartest, perfect girl in the world.
Well, you're right
about all those things.
But for some reason
when I meet boys
they act as if I'm going to do
something horrible to them.
But you probably
would do something horrible to them.
I'm sure they're
just intimidated by you.
Ok, look, if you want
a boy to like you
just look at him and smile a lot
and laugh at everything he says
even if it's not funny.
Well, that sounds
really shallow and stupid.
Let's try it.
Ok.
"Hey, there, sweet sugar cakes.
How ya likin' this party?"
- I'm bored.
- I know.
I'm hungry.
So what?
So find me some food.
Sure.
Chan, I'm ready for
a tour of the house.
Is this your first time
on ember island?
No, I used to
come here years ago.
It's a great place
if you like sand.
Yeah, it's like,
"welcome to Sandy land."
Your arms look so strong.
Yeah, I know.
You're pretty.
Together, you and I will be...
The strongest couple
in the entire world.
We will dominate the earth!
Uh... I gotta go.
Hey, watch it.
That food was for
my cranky girlfriend.
Whoa...
What are you doing?
Stop talking to my girlfriend.
Relax, it's just a party.
Uh!
Zuko, what is wrong with you?
What's wrong with me?
Your temper's out of control.
You blow up over
every little thing.
You're so impatient and
hot-headed and angry.
Well, at least
I feel something... as opposed to you.
You have no passion
for anything.
You're just a big blah.
It's over, zuko.
We're done.
Who broke my Nana's vase?
That's it, you're out of here.
I was just leaving.
Have fun by yourself,
loser boy.
Nice.
Guys, you're all gonna
think I'm crazy
but it feels like
a metal man is coming.
I thought I'd find you here.
Those summers we spent
here seem so long ago.
So much has changed.
Come down to the beach with me.
Come on,
this place is depressing.
Hey...
Where's your new boyfriend?
Are you cold?
I'm freezing.
I'll make a fire.
There's plenty of
stuff to burn in there.
This is crazy.
How can we beat a guy who blows
things up with his mind?
We can.
Jump on appa.
I'll try to distract him.
I'm ok.
Well, that was random.
I don't think so.
I get the feeling
he knows who we are.
What are you doing?
What does it look
like I'm doing.
But it's a painting
of your family.
You think I care?
I think you do.
You don't know me, so why don't
you just mind your own business?
Ah, I know you.
No, you don't.
You're stuck in your
little ty Lee world
where everything's
great all the time.
Zuko, leave her alone.
I'm so pretty, look at me.
I can walk on my hands, whoo!
Circus freak.
Yes, I'm a circus freak.
Go ahead and laugh
all you want.
You wanna know why
I joined the circus?
Here we go.
Do you have any idea
what my home life was like
growing up with six sisters
who look exactly like me?
It was like,
I didn't even have my own name.
I joined the circus because
I was scared of spending
the rest of my life
as part of a matched set.
At least, I'm different now.
Circus freak is a compliment.
Guess that explains why you
need 10 boyfriends, too.
I'm sorry, what?
Attention issues?
You couldn't get enough
attention when you were a kid
so you're trying
to make up for it now.
Well, what's your excuse, mai?
You were an only child
for 15 years.
But even with all that attention
your aura is this
dingy, pasty, gray...
I don't believe in auras.
Yeah, you don't
believe in anything.
Oh, well, I'm sorry I can't be as
high-strung and crazy as the rest of you.
I'm sorry, too.
I wish you would be
high-strung and crazy for once
instead of keeping all your
feelings bottled up inside.
She just called your aura dingy.
Are you gonna take that?
What do you want from me?
You want a teary confession
about how hard my childhood was?
Well, it wasn't.
I was a rich only child
who got anything I wanted
as long as I behaved...
And sat still
and didn't speak
unless spoken to.
My mother said I had
to keep out of trouble.
We had my dad's political
career to think about.
Well, that's it, then.
You had a controlling mother
who had certain expectations
and if you strayed from them
you were shut down.
That's why you're afraid
to care about anything
and why you can't
express yourself.
You want me to express myself?
Leave me alone!
I like it when you
express yourself.
Don't touch me.
I'm still mad at you.
My life hasn't been
that easy, either, mai.
Whatever- that doesn't excuse
the way you've been acting.
Calm down, you guys.
This much negative energy
is bad for your skin.
You'll totally break out.
Bad skin?
Normal teenagers worry
about bad skin.
I don't have that luxury.
My father decided to teach me
a permanent lesson on my face.
Sorry, zuko, I...
For so long, I thought
that if my dad accepted me, I'd be happy.
I'm back home, now.
My dad talks to me.
Huh, he even thinks I'm a hero.
Everything should
be perfect, right?
I should be happy now,
but I'm not.
I'm angrier than ever
and I don't know why.
There's a simple question
you need to answer then.
Who are you angry at?
No one, I'm just angry.
Yeah, who are you
angry at, zuko?
Everyone... I don't know.
Is it dad?
No, no.
Your uncle?
Me?
No, no... no, no.
Then who?
Who are you angry at?
Answer the question, zuko.
Talk to us.
Come on, answer the question.
Come on, answer it.
I'm angry at myself.
Why?
Because I'm confused.
Because I'm not sure
I know the difference
between right
and wrong anymore.
You're pathetic.
I know one thing
I care about...
I care about you.
Well, those were wonderful
performances, everyone.
I guess you wouldn't
understand, would you, azula
because you're just so perfect.
Well, yes, I guess you're right.
I don't have sob stories
like all of you.
I could sit here and complain how
our mom liked zuko more than me
but I don't really care.
My own mother...
Thought I was a monster.
She was right, of course,
but it still hurt.
What lo and li said came true.
The beach did help us
learn about ourselves.
I feel all smoothed.
I'll always remember this.
You know what would make
this trip really memorable?
We've got some bad news, chan.
Party's over.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk