05 Firefly Our Mrs Reynolds - Episode 05 2002 English
Pardon me for intruding, but I believe
y'all are carrying something of mine.
Ain't yours.
You think we wouldn't find out
you changed your route?
You gonna give us what due us
and every damn thing else on that boat.
I think you gonna give me a little
one-on-one time with the missus.
Oh, I think you might want
to reconsider that last part.
See, I married me
a powerful ugly creature.
How can you say that? How can you
shame me in front of new people?
If I could make you prettier, I would.
You are not the man I met a year ago.
Now, think real hard.
You been bird-dogging this township
a while now.
They wouldn't mind a corpse of you.
Now, you can luxuriate
in a nice jail cell...
but if your hand touches metal...
I swear by my pretty floral bonnet,
I will end you.
Take them!
In the morning,
we'll head for Beaumond.
Give you a chance to find work.
I appreciate it.
This place is lovely, but...
Not your clientele.
I understand.
- You gotta play at being a lady.
- Well, yes.
So explain to me again
why Zoe wasn't in the dress.
Tactics, woman.
Needed her in the back.
Besides, those soft, cotton dresses
feel nice. There's a whole airflow.
And you'd know that because...?
You can't open the book of my life
in the middle.
Like women, I'm a mystery.
Best keep it that way.
I withdraw the question.
It makes the rain come
when you turn it.
The rain's very scarce.
It comes only when needed most.
And such it is with men like you.
This is the most...
You, friend.
You're the guy.
I'll treasure this.
Elder Gommen,
thank you for the hospitality.
We owe you a great debt.
I'm sorry we have so little
to pay it with.
Though I hope our gifts
will show our regard.
Well, I don't think Jayne's
ever letting go of that stick.
Alliance patrol boat
heading into atmo.
Well, we gotta fly.
We'll pray for a safe voyage.
And hope to lay eyes on you again
ere too long, my friend.
- Count on it. Bye, now.
- Bless you.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye, now.
Who the hell are you?
- What do you mean?
- I was pretty clear.
What are you doing on my boat?
But you know
I'm to cleave to you.
To wha...? By who?
Did Elder Gommen not tell you?
Tell me what? Who are you?
Mr. Reynolds, sir...
I'm your wife.
- Could you repeat that, please?
- I am your wife.
That was your agreement
with Elder Gommen...
since he hadn't cash or livestock...
I'm... I'm sorry.
Go back to the part
where you're my wife.
- I don't please you?
- You never met me.
- Zoe, why do I have a wife?
- You got a wife?
All I got is that stick
sounds like it's raining.
- How come you got a wife?
- I didn't.
- We're not married.
- I'm sorry that I shame you.
You don't shame me.
Zoe, would you get Wash?
This is Zoe. We need all personnel
in the cargo bay.
All? I said Wash.
Everyone should have a chance
to congratulate you on your day of bliss.
There's no bliss.
I don't know this girl.
- Then can I know her?
- Jayne.
Don't sully this.
You'll clean latrines with your face,
you don't cut that out.
Who's the new recruit?
Everybody,
I want you all to meet...
Mrs. Reynolds.
You got married?
Wow, that's... Congratulations.
We'd always hoped you two kids
would get together.
- Who is she?
- She's no one.
- Captain!
- Would you stop that?
- I'm sorry.
- You brute.
Oh, sweetie, don't feel bad.
He makes everybody cry.
He's like a monster.
I'm not a monster.
Wash, turn the ship around.
- Can't.
- It's an order.
- We can't.
- What is wrong with you?
Have you got an encyclopedia?
There's already a bulletin on the cortex
as to the murder of a prefect's nephew.
One of our bandits has family ties.
Unless you feel like
walking into a gallows...
I suggest we continue to Beaumond,
and you, enjoy your honeymoon.
This isn't happening.
Would you stop crying?
For God's sake, could you be
a human being for 30 seconds?
- As one married man to another...
- I'm not married!
I'm sorry.
You have very nice qualities,
but I didn't ever marry you.
I believe you did.
Last night.
- How drunk was I last night?
- I don't know. I passed out.
It says here, The woman lays
the wreath upon her intended.
Which I do recall.
Which represents his sovereignty.
That was you?
And he drinks of her wine.
And then there's a dance
with a joining of hands.
The marriage ceremony
of the Triumph settlers.
You, sir, are a newly-wed.
What does it say in there
about divorce?
Really think you're the one
to talk to her?
The way I see it, me and her
got one thing in common.
We're the only ones
don't think this is funny.
Hello?
Woman person.
You all right?
I thought last night during the ceremony
that you were pleased.
Well, yeah, last night I was.
Had some mulled wine, a pretty girl
gave me a hat made out of a tree.
Nobody said I was signing up
to have and to hold.
- Are you gonna kill me?
- What?
What kind of crappy planet
is that? Kill you.
I heard talk of men who weren't
pleased with their...
Well, I ain't them.
Don't stand for that.
If someone tries to kill you...
you try to kill them right back.
Look, wife or no, you are no one's
property to be tossed aside.
You got the right, same as anyone,
to live and try to kill people.
I mean, you know, people that are...
That's a dumb planet.
What will you do with me?
Not rightly sure.
We're bound for Beaumond.
Decent kind of planet.
Might be able to set you up
with some work there.
- I'll not be anyone's doxy.
- Not whoring. They got factories.
Some ranches,
if you're more for the outdoors.
Near a week before we get there.
We'll figure something.
I'd be a good wife.
Yeah, well, I'd be a terrible husband.
You have five whole days
to figure that out.
For five days, we'll be together?
We'll be together on the ship,
but not...
That'll be fine.
I'll do for you or not, as you choose.
Well, shiny.
Hungry? Kitchen's just through there.
I'll cook you something.
- No, I meant for you.
- I'm a fine cook. Everyone says.
That's... It's great.
Look... Hold it. Hold.
- I ain't never even...
- My name is Saffron.
Divorce is very rare. It requires
dispensation from her pastor.
I can send him a wave,
see what I can do.
I appreciate that.
She's a nice girl.
- Seems very anxious to please you.
- It's their way, I guess.
I suppose so.
If you take sexual advantage of her...
you're going to burn
in a very special level of hell.
A level they reserve
for child molesters...
and people who talk at the theatre.
What...?
I am not...
- Preacher, you got a smutty mind.
- Perhaps I spoke out of turn.
- Per-maybe-haps, I'm thinking.
- I apologise.
I'll make her up a room
in the passenger dorm.
The special hell.
Thank you.
Something smells good.
Having yourself a little supper, captain?
Saffron insisted on it.
I didn't want to make her feel...
- This is damn tasty.
- Ls there more where that came from?
I didn't think to make enough
for your friends.
But every-thing's laid out if you'd like
to cook for your husband.
Yeah.
Isn't she quaint?
I'm just not hungry.
So are you enjoying your
own nubile, little slave girl?
She wanted to make me dinner.
At least she's not crying.
I might.
Did she really make fresh bau?
Quaint.
Remember that sex
we were planning to have?
You're all making a big deal.
I would appreciate it if one person
on this boat would not assume...
that I'm an evil lecherous hump.
Nobody's saying that, sir.
We're pretty much just giving each other
significant glances, laughing incessantly.
- Is that cider?
- By the stove.
Yum. I'll get you a refill. Hon?
That's for me to do.
You know...
you weren't lying about your cooking.
If I hadn't already eaten...
- You don't want to finish?
- No, I just, um...
I have captainy things to do,
but truthfully, that's a fine meal.
- Do you need anything else?
- No. No.
You just have something to eat
yourself, and I'm gonna go...
captain.
If you're done with supper...
would you like me
to wash your feet?
Beaumond.
City of New Dunsmuir.
Arrival, October 24.
- Departure...
- Can I come in?
- No.
- See, that's why I usually don't ask.
- What do you want?
- Oh, I just needed to...
hide.
So I take it the honeymoon is over?
Oh, she's a fine girl.
Don't misread. Hell of a cook too.
I'm sure she has many exciting talents.
Do you ever...
wash your clients' feet?
It's my speciality.
We'll be at Beaumond
at least two weeks, right?
- Can't exactly be sure.
- I need you to be sure.
I can't make commitments
and then not keep them.
That's your speciality.
Are you touchy because I got a bride
or because I don't plan to keep her?
I find the whole thing degrading.
That's just what Saffron said
about your line of work.
You should think twice
about letting go of Saffron.
- You two sound like quite a match.
- Maybe you're right.
- Maybe we're soul mates.
- Yes.
Great. I wish you hundreds
of fat children.
Could you imagine that? Me with
a whole passel of critters underfoot.
- Hell, 10 years' time I could...
- Can you leave me alone, please?
I wasn't looking for a fight.
Always do seem to find one, though.
Do I have your attention?
Kind of going to extremes here,
ain't we?
There's times I think
you don't take me seriously.
I think that ought to change.
Do you think it's likely to?
- You got something you don't deserve.
- And it's brought me a galaxy of fun.
Six men came to kill me one time.
The best of them carried this.
It's a Callahan full-bore auto lock.
Customised trigger, double cartridge
thorough-gauge.
It is my very favourite gun.
- You offering me a trade?
- A trade?
It's theft. This is the best gun
made by man.
It has extreme sentimental value.
It's miles more worthy
than what you got.
- What I got? She has a name.
- So does this.
I call it Vera.
My days of not taking you seriously
are certainly coming to a middle.
I'd treat her okay.
She's not to be bought.
Nor bartered or borrowed or lent.
She doesn't know a damn thing about
the world and needs our protection.
- Well, I'll protect her.
- Jayne.
Go play with your rain stick.
God!
You do sneak about, don't you?
You're a good man.
You clearly haven't been talking
to anyone else on this boat.
I don't wish to be wed
to the large one. I'd rather...
If I'm not to be yours, I'd rather
have the work you spoke of.
I could be useful on a ranch.
It's good work.
My mama had a ranch.
Back on Shadow, where I'm from.
Ran cattle mostly.
Wasn't nobody ran them
harder or smarter.
She used to tell me:
Don't brand the cattle. Brand the buyer.
He's the one likely to stray.
- She raised you herself?
- Her and about 40 hands.
I had more family for a kid...
- That is odd.
- What?
I just don't...
I'm not one who talks about
what's past, and here you got me...
Does your crew never show interest
in your life?
No, they...
are...
They just know me well enough to...
Well, what about you?
What's your history?
Not much to say.
Life like yours, I fear
you'd find mine terrible dull.
Oh, I long for a little dullness.
Truth to say, this whole trip's getting
to be just a little too interesting.
It's a wreck.
- No, this is good.
- It's parts.
A lot of cheap parts we'll never unload.
This is why you'll never be
in charge, Bree.
You don't see the whole.
- The parts are crap...
- I said that.
But you put it together,
you got a Firefly.
Thing will run forever, they got
a mechanic even half-awake.
It's got no flash.
Some people ain't looking for flash.
She's a good catch.
She comes our way,
you prep the nets.
Clearly, she's out of her mind.
Well, she's led a sheltered life.
Did you see the way she grabbed
that glass from him?
Every planet has its own
weird customs.
A year before we met,
I spent six weeks on a moon...
where the principal form
of recreation was juggling geese.
My hand to God. Baby geese.
Goslings. They were juggled.
Of course.
A man rushes in to defend her.
I'm talking about geese.
Captain shouldn't babysit
a groupie, and he knows it.
Okay, when did this become not funny?
When you didn't put her ass back down
on Triumph where it belongs.
Hey! Now it's even my fault? Anything
else on your mind I should know about?
There's all sorts of twists
and cul de sacs.
- She's trouble.
- I'm getting that.
I'm going to bed.
Hey!
You're, uh... Uh...
- Well, there you are.
- I've made the bed warm for you.
Yeah, it looks warm.
And I've made myself ready for you.
Let's ride right past the part where
you explain exactly what that means.
Didn't you see you got
a room of your own?
- And I'm to sleep there?
- That's the notion.
Assuming you're sleepy.
But we've been wed.
Aren't we to become one flesh?
Well, no. We're still two fleshes here...
and I think that your flesh
ought to sleep somewhere else.
I'm sorry. When we talked, I'd hoped...
I don't please you.
Hey, flesh.
Saffron, it ain't a question
of you pleasing me.
It's more a question of what's...
Um...
Of what's morally right.
I do know my Bible, sir.
On the night of their betrothal,
the wife shall open to the man...
as the furrow to the plough...
and he shall work in her
in and again...
till she bring him to his fall...
and rest him then
upon the sweat of her breast.
Oh.
Good Bible.
I'm not skilled, sir,
nor a pleasure to look upon...
Saffron...
you're pleasing. You're...
Hell, you're all kinds of pleasing,
and it's been a while...
a long damn while since anybody
but me took a hold of my plough...
so don't think for a second
that I ain't interested.
But you and me,
we ain't married.
Because you got handed to me by
some hu-dong couldn't pay his debts...
don't make you beholden to me.
- I keep trying to explain...
- Let me explain.
I lived my life in the maiden house,
waiting to be married off for trade.
I seen my sister paired off with
ugly men, vicious or blubberous.
Men with appetites
too unseemly to speak on.
And I've cried for those girls.
But not half so hard as I cried
the night they gave me to you.
Why?
Is there blubber?
I cried for I'd not dreamed
to have a man so sweet...
so kind and beautiful.
Had I the dare to choose,
I'd choose you...
from all the men on all the planets
the night sky could show me.
If I'm wed, I am a woman...
and I'll take your leave
to be bold.
I want this.
I swell to think of you in me.
And I see that you do too.
Oh, that's just...
Leave me at the nearest port,
never look upon me again.
I'll make my way with the strength
that you taught me.
Only let me have my wedding night.
Oh, I'm gonna go to the special hell.
I...
I really wish it was that simple, girl,
but I don't...
Ooh.
Son of a...
Night, sweetie.
Well, if it isn't the master chef.
Not sleepy?
Am I allowed to be up here?
Well, sure. Why not?
It's not like anyone else
is taking up space.
I've never been off world before.
- It's beautiful, isn't it?
- It's like a dream.
The planet I'm from, couldn't see
a one of them, pollution's so thick.
Sometimes I think I entered
flight school...
just to see what the hell
everyone was talking about.
What are you doing?
Now we're alone.
Just us and the stars.
No ship, no bellowing engines,
no crew to bicker at each other. Look.
Do you know the myth
of Earth that was?
Not so much.
That when she was born,
she had no sky...
and was open, inviting...
and the stars would rush into her...
through the skin of her...
making the oceans boil
with sensation.
And when she could endure
no more ecstasy...
she puffed up her cheeks
and blew out the sky.
Oh.
Good myth.
My whole life, I saw nothing but roofs
and steeples and the cellar door.
In a few days, I'll be back to that life
and gone from yours.
Make this night what it should be.
Please...
show me the stars.
Do I wish I was somebody else
right now.
Somebody not married...
not madly in love with a beautiful
woman who can kill me with her pinky.
- I've been too forward.
- No.
Well, yes, but I actually like that
in a woman.
That's part of why Zoe and I are,
as previously mentioned, married.
I thought...
She didn't seem to respect you.
Not everybody gets me and Zoe
at first glance.
Did it get very hot in here?
I need airflow.
You love her very much.
Yeah.
I never did meet anyone
quite like Zoe.
The first time we met,
she actually threw...
Are you lost?
I'm sorry, I thought the other shuttle
was yours.
It is. I was on the cortex and my
screen shorted. This one's out too.
- Looking for customers?
- What were you looking for?
I don't mean to be rude. A companion's
life is so glamorous and strange.
I wish I had the skill for such a trade.
You'd like to please your new husband?
Oh, he'll have none of me.
For true, I'm somewhat relieved.
If I'm to learn of love...
I'd like it to be at the hands
of someone gentle.
Someone who could...
feel what I feel.
But Mal said you don't approve
of my work.
Sure, and he said that
to keep you from me.
I was too curious about you.
Ever since I saw you.
Come to my shuttle.
You would...?
You would lie with me?
- I guess we've lied enough.
- You're good.
You're amazing. Who are you?
Malcolm Reynolds' widow.
Baby. Wake up.
- He's bleeding.
- There's no one in there.
What's going on?
Mal! Mal, Mal, Mal, Mal, Mal!
Get the doctor. Mal's hurt.
You stupid son of a...
ls it Christmas?
- Well, he's back.
- What happened about me?
Your blushing bride was a plant.
She took both of you out.
How did...?
Narcotic compound, probably
spread over a seal on her lips.
- You get it on yours, and pow.
- Lips, huh?
Well...
We used to get a lot of guys
brought in on the night shift at the ER...
usually robbed, very groggy.
They called it the good night kiss.
- So you two were kissing.
- Well, isn't that special?
- Wash, how did...?
- I just got kicked in the head.
- My man would never fall for that.
- Most of my head wishes I had.
- You guys don't understand.
- Seems pretty simple.
- You were taking advantage...
- I was the one being taken advantage of.
My apologies.
You were victimised, Wash was beaten,
and Inara found you here.
Then I fell.
My head got hurt like Wash.
- I don't get any of this.
- I only fell, is all.
- What the hell's our status?
- We're shut down...
trying to get on the bridge.
All we know is, we're headed
somewhere, and it ain't Beaumond.
Oh, I'm fine.
I don't need to be examined.
I'm comfy.
She didn't just lock it. She fused
both entrances to something.
But why the big act?
What was she after?
Besides molesting captains.
You wanna stow it, preacher?
We're in some peril here.
If she can fly this,
why take the shuttle?
Maybe she likes shuttles?
Some people juggle geese.
- She's a pro.
- This is a masterful job of muck-up.
See how she crossed the dry feeds?
So we even try to re-route,
it'll lock down.
- She went straight for the thermal cap.
- Yeah, yeah.
We are so hung.
I'm glad you're having a good time.
Can we make it right?
That's not gonna happen
for a while.
Well, we don't have a good long while.
We could be headed straight into
a solid moon for all we know...
so how's about we get to work?
Hey, it was your big make-out session
that got us into this, sir.
- I was poisoned.
- You were drugged.
That's why I never kiss them
on the mouth.
What can you do?
We can get the cortex and navcom back
online, at least see where we're headed.
- What about steering?
- What about stopping?
She humped us hard.
We're gonna have to do a lot...
Well, do it! Doesn't help me to see
where I'm going if I can't change course.
- This girl really knows her ships.
- That's not all she knows.
She's well-schooled.
What do you mean, the sedative?
The good night kiss?
I only hit my head,
but Mal went through that.
But, no, I mean, seduction,
body language, signals.
She's had training.
As in companion.
As in academy.
Our little Saffron's quite a wonder.
I'm beginning to think
she married beneath herself.
How do you know? About the training?
She tried to seduce me too.
Really?
Did she...?
Uh, did you...?
You don't play a player.
It was sloppy of her to try it,
but she was in a rush.
But she had professional...
So in my case,
I mean, it was really...
You would've kissed her too.
- Wash didn't.
- But she was naked.
And all articulate.
Okay! Everybody not talking about sex,
in here. Everybody else, elsewhere.
They're coming.
- How far out?
- Ten minutes or so, right on target.
Speed, A-1.
- That girl's a wonder.
- She gets it done.
Tell the boys.
Yes!
Got it?
We got life, we got screens.
It's a qualified yes, a partial.
- What about nav control?
- No.
- Where we headed?
- Coordinates she entered.
We're headed for something
not too far.
Did she signal anybody?
She did. Same coordinates, no ID.
Who's out there?
Let me see if her signal wave can
translate to a visual. There might be...
Yeah. Electromagnetic interference.
It's bouncing the signal
all over the place. Look at it.
It's like a circle.
It's a net.
I don't get it.
Where are we headed?
The end of the line.
It's a carrion house.
Scrap shop.
Takes ships and pulls them apart,
or fixes them up.
- Doesn't sound that scary.
- That pattern you're looking at is a net.
We fall into that, we're helpless.
It'll turn this ship into an electrical
conduit and burn us from the inside out.
Some of the new ones
will just hold you.
And then the scrappers will override the
air locks, pull the O2 or just gas you.
They're not looking
to deal with survivors.
One day, you're gonna tell us how
a preacher knows so much about crime.
Kaylee.
- I'm trying, sir.
- Keep on it. We can't fall into that net.
We're gonna need a plan B.
Zoe, get our suits prepped now.
I figure we got one shot at this.
- Give me a visual, soon as we're close.
- Won't be long.
What do I do?
You go get Vera.
She needs oxygen around to fire,
and we don't have a case.
Gonna use a suit.
Here, we got it.
- What am I aiming for, the window?
- That won't disrupt the net.
See these six brightest points?
Those are the breakers.
Hit one, should short it out.
What do you mean, should?
- You see it?
- Clear as day.
You see, Vera? Dress yourself up,
you get taken out somewhere fun.
We got it.
It's not pretty, but we can steer enough
to turn the hell around.
Nice work.
Weren't soon enough to help.
It's easier to pull things apart
than put them right.
Still the best mechanic floating.
Don't you know kissing girls
makes you sleepy?
Sometimes I just can't help myself.
Now, let's go visiting.
Honey, I'm home.
Looks like you get that wedding night
after all.
It's the first time, darling.
I think you should be gentle with me.
You gonna kill me?
Can you conjure up a compelling
reason for me not to?
I didn't kill you.
You handed me and my crew over
to those that would kill us.
I made you dinner.
Why the act?
The seduction games, the dancing about.
There has to be an easier way to steal.
You're assuming
the pay-off is the point.
I'm not assuming anything
at this juncture.
How did you find me?
Only a few places that shuttle would
make it to from where you left.
Happy to find it intact.
You're quite a man, Malcolm Reynolds.
I've been waiting a long time for
someone good enough to take me down.
Saffron...
you even think about playing me again,
I will riddle you with holes.
Everybody plays each other.
That's all anybody ever does.
- We play parts.
- You got all kinds of learning.
You made me look the fool without
trying, yet I have a gun to your head.
That's because I got people with me.
People who trust each other and ain't
always looking for the advantage.
Promise me you're gonna kill me soon.
You already know I ain't gonna.
You did pretty well.
Most men, they're on me
inside of 10 minutes.
Not trying to teach me
to be strong and the like.
I got one question for you.
Just one thing I'd like to know,
straight up.
Ask me.
What's your real name?
You'd only have lied anyhow.
Come in.
Back on course.
Be on Beaumond a day or two late.
Hope it's all right.
Should be fine, thank you.
- And does the vixen live?
- Yeah, if you can call it that.
- All's well, I suppose.
- Yes.
You're a very graceful woman, Inara.
I...
Thank you.
So here's where I'm fuzzy.
You got by that girl,
came and found me...
and somehow you happen
to just trip and fall.
- What do you mean?
- Come on, Inara.
How's about we don't play?
You didn't just trip, did you?
No.
Well, isn't that something.
I knew you let her kiss you.