07 Firefly Out Of Gas - Episode 07 2002 English
- A real beauty, ain't she?
- Yes, sir.
Tell you what. You buy this ship,
treat her proper...
she'll be with you for the rest
of your life.
Well?
You paid money for this, sir?
On purpose?
What? Come on, seriously, Zoe,
what do you think?
Honestly, sir, I think you got robbed.
Robbed? What do you mean?
It's a piece of fei-oo.
Fei-oo?
Okay, she won't be winning any beauty
contests anytime soon, but she is solid.
A ship like this, be with you
till the day you die.
- Because it's a death trap.
- That's not...
You are very much lacking
in imagination.
I imagine that's so, sir.
You haven't seen most of it.
Let me show you the rest.
And try to see past what she is
and on to what she can be.
- What's that, sir?
- Freedom, is what.
I meant what's that?
Step around that.
Something was living in here.
I tell you, we get a mechanic,
get her up and running again...
hire a good pilot, maybe a cook,
live like real people.
A small crew. They must feel the need
to be free. Take jobs as they come.
They never have to be under the heel
of nobody ever again.
No matter how long the arm
of The Alliance might get...
we'll just get ourselves
a little further.
- Get her running again?
- Yeah.
- So not running now?
- Not so much. But she will.
I already know what I'm gonna call her.
Got a name all picked out.
No. That is not true.
- No.
- I swear it is.
Surely one of you must've told him.
No. Not one of the brethren
had the heart to say anything.
He was so proud.
What? What was he proud of?
Who he?
Looked rather natty,
truth be told, you know?
What was natty? I wanna hear
about the natty thing.
Shepherd Book was just telling us funny
stories about his life at the monastery.
Monastic humour. I miss out
on all the fun.
And all the food too, apparently.
Just who do you think
you're married to?
- Voilà.
- I love my wife.
- So we got a course set?
- We do.
Took creative navigating,
but we should make it to Greenleaf...
without running afoul
of Alliance patrols.
- Or a living soul, for that matter.
- The way it should be.
Of course, what should be
an 18-hour trip...
will take us the better part
of a week by this route.
We're in no rush.
I like an easy, languorous journey.
Gee, I wonder what that would be like.
Let me help you with that.
It's your turn.
My turn?
Shepherd told us a funny story
about being a preacher.
Now you tell us a funny story
about being a doctor.
A funny story.
Yeah, because sick people
are hilarious.
Well, they... They can be. Uh...
Well, in fact, I remember this time
I was working the ER...
and this... This, uh... This fellow, this,
uh, you know, upright sort of citizen...
he comes in, and he's, you know,
complaining...
Inara, she's gotta have some funny
whoring stories, I'd wager.
Oh, do I ever. Funny and sexy.
You have no idea.
And you never will.
I don't discuss my clients.
Aw, come on, Inara. Who'd know?
You. A companion
doesn't kiss and tell.
So there is kissing?
Hey, doc, I think Kaylee may
need your help after all.
Care to make the first incision,
Dr. Tam?
- Happy birthday, Simon.
- Happy birthday!
This is, uh...
How did... How did you know?
River, did you...?
"Day" is a vestigial mode of time
measurement based on solar cycles.
It's not applicable.
I didn't get you anything.
Seems a fresh warrant for your arrest
came up over the cortex.
Had your birthday attached right to it.
Really?
I hope you like it. Couldn't get a hold
of no flour, so it's mostly protein.
In fact, it's pretty much
what we just had for dinner.
But I tried to get the frosting as
chocolaty-tasting as possible, so...
Thank you.
I'm really... I'm very, very
deeply moved. Thank you.
Well, deeply move yourself to blow out
them candles, so we can try a slice.
Come on, doc. Give a good blow.
What the hell was that?
Maybe just a hiccup.
I'll go check it out.
- I'll take a look at the helm.
- Fire.
Okay, right.
- Zoe!
- Fire!
Fire!
Baby. You've gotta talk to me.
Seal off everything
that leads below decks!
Do it now!
- Is she gonna be okay?
- I need my med kit.
Not this way. We've got fire.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Zoe's been badly hurt.
- I need my medical supplies.
- Sorry, nobody leaves.
- Every thing's sealed tight.
- If you don't let me go, she could die.
I let you through, we all die.
It's okay.
She's in shock. I need to bring
her vitals back up.
- How bad is it?
- There's no sign of burning.
- It must be internal. I'll do a scan.
- Baby? Zoe, can you hear me?
Zoe? Come on, sweetheart.
Zoe? Come on, talk, baby.
- Look at me, sweetheart.
- Kaylee.
Kaylee, look at me.
I need you up in the engine room
figuring out what caused this.
She ain't moving.
Serenity's not moving.
I know it.
Which is why we need to suss out what
happened so we can get her going again.
- Think you can do that?
- Yes, captain.
That's a good girl.
Come on, baby. You're strong,
the strongest person I ever met.
- You can do this.
- Ls she gonna make it?
- Please, I need to work.
- Wash.
- I need you on the bridge.
- Zoe's hurt.
And the doctor's gonna do
everything he can.
Meantime, I gotta have you on the
bridge. We need to know how bad it is.
How bad? It's bad, okay, sir?
My wife may be dying here,
so my feeling is it's pretty bad.
- Wash...
- I'm not leaving her side, Mal!
Don't ask me again.
I wasn't asking. I was telling.
You're gonna get to that bridge, and
you're gonna get us back on our feet.
Yeah. This is all very doable.
Shouldn't be a problem at all.
A few modifications.
Get some real manoeuvrability
out of this boat.
You'd be surprised.
So you'll take the job then?
Might do, might do.
- Think I'm starting to get a feel here.
- Good.
Well, take your time.
Make yourself to home.
Just fiddle around with the dials there.
We'll be nearby.
- Great, ain't he?
- I don't like him.
- What?
- Just something about him bothers me.
- What? What about him bothers you?
- I'm not sure. It's something.
Your something comes up against a list
of recommendations as long as my leg.
Tanaka raves about this guy.
Renshaw's been trying to get him
for a month.
- And we need us a pilot.
- I understand, sir. He bothers me.
We finally got ourselves
a genius mechanic.
It's time we hired someone
to fly this.
Genius? No one's ever called me
that before. Shiny.
He just bothers me.
Her heart stopped.
Someone should get
her husband down here.
- No. What do you need, doc?
- That drawer, right there.
- That's the one.
- What is it?
Pure adrenaline.
Cap?
Zoe gonna be okay?
You let the doctor worry about Zoe.
Come on.
Tell me what you know.
Catalyser on the port
compression coil blew.
- It's where the trouble started.
- I need that in captain dummy-talk.
- We're dead in the water.
- Can you fix it?
- I can try.
- Just get us to limping. That's all I need.
What? What is it?
- It's worse than just the coil.
- How can it be worse?
Main life-supports down
since the engine's dead.
- But we've got auxiliary life-support.
- No, we don't. Ain't even on.
Explosion must've knocked it out.
So, what are we breathing?
Whatever got pumped into the atmo
before the explosion shut it all down.
Most of that oxygen got ate up
by the fire on its way out the door.
Well, whatever left is what we got.
How long?
Couple of hours, maybe.
We'll start to feel it, and then
we won't feel nothing at all.
How is she?
She's still unconscious,
but her vitals are strong.
She won't know it, but as long as
her condition remains like this...
she'll outlive us all.
She's using less oxygen.
I always thought the name Serenity...
had a vaguely funereal sound to it.
I love this ship.
I have from the first moment I saw it.
I just don't want to die on it.
I don't want to die at all.
Suffocations not exactly
the most dignified way to go.
The human body will...
Please, I don't really require
a clinical description right now.
I'm sorry.
I just...
It was my birthday.
Don't be afraid.
That's what it says.
"Don't be afraid."
Yes.
But you are afraid.
You're afraid we're going
to run out of air...
that we'll die gasping.
But we won't.
That's not going to happen.
We'll freeze to death first.
You get that beacon sent?
- Yeah, it's sent.
- Good.
Pointless.
- What?
- Nothing, sir. It's a brilliant plan.
I'm sure we'll all be saved.
I'm getting a little weary
of this attitude.
Are you? Well, I'm so very sorry, sir.
I guess the news that we'll be purple,
bloated and fetal in a few hours...
has made me a little snippy.
It's possible someone might pick up
that signal.
No, Mal, it's not possible. No one's
gonna pick up the damn signal.
You wanted us under the radar.
That's where we are.
- Out of range of anyone.
- Then make it go further.
- I... What?
- Make the signal go further.
I can't make it go further.
Not if you're gonna sit around
and whinge.
- What do you expect me to do, Mal?
- Whatever you have to.
If you can't do it here, get a suit on
and go outside the boat...
And what? Wave my arms around?
Wave your arms around.
Jump up and down.
Divert the nav sats to the transmitter.
Divert the... Right!
Teenage pranks are fun
when you're about to die.
- Give the beacon a boost, wouldn't it?
- Yes, Mal, it would boost the signal.
But even if a passer by did receive,
it would muck up their navigation.
- Could be that's true.
- Damn right!
They'd be forced to stop and dig out
our signal before they could go any place.
Maybe I should do that then.
- Maybe you should.
- Okay.
- Good!
- Fine!
What do you two think you're doing,
fighting at a time like this?
You're gonna use up all the air.
Life-support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
Bester?
What's this I hear about
yet another delay?
Supposed to have this engine fixed
and us up and...
What in the name of...?
Bester?
Bester!
What?
You do realise we've been parked on this
rock a week longer than we planned?
Yeah, but there's... There's stuff to do.
As, for example, that job we've
got waiting for us on Pacquin.
When we landed, you said you needed
a few days to get us space-worthy...
and is there something wrong
with your bunk?
What?
Oh, no, captain. She likes engines.
They make her hot.
Bester, get your prairie harpy
off my boat and put us back in the air.
Okay, but can't.
- What do you mean, "can't"?
- No can do, cap.
- Secondary grav boot's shot.
- No, it ain't.
Ain't nothing wrong with your grav boot.
Grav boot's just fine.
Hello.
She doesn't... That's not what it...
No, it ain't.
Sure it is. Grav boot
ain't your trouble.
I seen the trouble plain as day when I
was down there on my back before.
Your reg couple's bad.
The reg... The what?
The reg couple.
Right here.
See?
- No.
- This.
I'm pointing right at it.
Hey.
Here. Hand me that, will you?
Don't serve much
of a purpose anyway.
Just tends to gum up the works
when it gets tacked.
So I figure why even have one?
Better to just take your G-line, plug it
straight into the port pin-lock...
and that should...
There!
- What'd you do?
- She fixed it.
Well, it wasn't really broke.
Where'd you learn to do that, miss?
Just do it, that's all.
- Daddy says I got natural talent.
- I'll say you do.
- Don't we need this?
- You work for your daddy, do you?
When he got work,
which ain't too often lately.
You got experience with a vessel
like this?
I never even been up in one before.
Wanna?
- You mean...?
- Sure.
- For how long?
- Long as you like.
- Long as you can keep her in the sky.
- You offering me a job?
- What?
- Believe I just did.
I just gotta ask my folks.
Don't leave without me.
Mal, what do you need
two mechanics for?
I really don't.
Kaylee?
Kaylee, what are you doing?
I'm sorry, captain. I'm real sorry.
I should have kept better care of her.
Usually she lets me know
when somethings wrong.
Maybe she did, I just wasn't
paying attention, or...
Kaylee, I cannot be having this from you
right now. We got work to do.
Catalser's broke.
Gonna need a new one.
There is no new one.
You gotta make do with what you got.
- It's broke.
- Come on.
This the part? It don't hardly seem
like nothing.
All right. Where does it go?
Here.
But it don't fit no more.
Well, you gotta figure a way
to make it fit.
Sometimes a thing gets broke
can't be fixed.
Without this, the engine don't turn?
Engine don't turn, life-support
won't function. We don't breathe.
You wanna keep breathing, don't you?
So do I.
Life-support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
Well, as you're all keenly aware,
we've run into a bit of a situation.
Engine's down, life-supports
on the Fritz...
and I got nine people here
all wanting to breathe.
Truth is, don't got a whole lot
of options at this juncture.
So instead of focusing on what we don't
got, time to talk about what it is we do.
And what we got are two shuttles.
Short-range, won't get far.
But each got heat,
and they each got air.
Last longer than what's left on Serenity.
- Long enough to reach some place?
- No.
So where will we go then?
Far as you can get.
We send both shuttles
in opposite directions...
betters the chances of someone
getting picked up.
Shepherd Book, Kaylee, Jayne
will ride with Inara in her shuttle.
Doc, you and your sis will ride
with Wash and Zoe...
seeing as how Zoe still needs
some doctoring.
What about you?
Four people per shuttle. That's
the arrangement. Evens the odds.
I'm staying with Serenity.
- Captain...
- We sent out a beacon.
Even managed to boost it a little.
If by some chance we get a response...
someone's gonna have
to be here to answer.
Let's get those shuttles prepped.
Wash, shuttles are that way.
I know. But like you said, someone
might answer the beacon.
And when they do, I wanna make sure
that you can call everyone back.
Won't take but a minute.
Jayne, get shuttle number two ready.
I'll see to Inara's.
Let's get moving.
Take only what you need.
- Mal...
- If you fly smart, don't push too hard...
- shuttle life-support will last.
- This isn't the ancient sea.
Don't go down with your ship.
She ain't going down.
She ain't going anywhere.
Jayne'll be valuable if you're in trouble.
Don't trust him. Don't let him take over.
You're paid for the month.
It's your ship.
Mal.
As far as your security deposit goes,
that I might have to owe you.
Well, here she is.
Nice, ain't she?
- Smallish.
- Well, not overly.
How much room do you really need
for what you do anyway?
I got a surveyor and his wife
interested in renting it.
They're just waiting to hear back.
- What's her range?
- Standard short.
She'll break atmo from a wide orbit...
get you where you need to go,
bring you back home again.
She's space-worthy, just like
the rest of Serenity is.
No need to sound so defencive, captain.
I prefer something
with a few miles on it.
Were we to enter into
this arrangement, captain...
there are a few things
I would require from you...
the foremost
being complete autonomy.
This shuttle would be my home.
No crew member would be allowed
entrance without my invitation.
You'd get your privacy.
And just so we're clear...
under no circumstances will I service
you or anyone who is under your employ.
I'll post a sign.
That won't be necessary.
The other thing I insist upon
is some measure of assurance...
that when I make an appointment,
I'm in position...
to keep that appointment,
so far as such assurances are possible...
on a vessel of this type.
That's an awful lot of caveats
and addendum's there.
As I stated, I just want to be clear.
I'll take that into consideration
while I review the applications.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're gonna rent this shuttle to me.
- Am I?
- Yes.
And for one-quarter less
than your asking price.
- That a fact?
- It is.
And you figure you'll be getting
this discount why, exactly?
You want me.
You want me on your ship.
- Do I?
- Yes.
Because I can bring something
your surveyor...
or any of the other fish
you might have on line can't:
- A certain respectability.
- Respecta...
And based on what little I've seen
of your operation...
I suspect that's something
you could use.
Fine.
Let me ask you this.
If you're so respectable,
why are you even here?
I mean, I've heard tell of fancy
ladies such as yourself...
shipping out with big luxury liners
and the like...
but a registered companion
on a boat like this?
- What are you running from?
- I'm not running from anything.
If it's Alliance trouble, you might
want to consider another ship.
Some here fought for the Independents.
The Alliance has no quarrel with me.
I supported Unification.
Did you?
Well, I don't suppose you're
the only whore that did.
Oh, one further addendum.
That's the last time you get
to call me whore.
Absolutely.
Never again.
Keep everything set as low as possible.
Don't waste what you got.
Let me do that. You never
could operate this thing.
And try not to talk.
Talking uses up air.
Ain't no need for it.
Mal, come with us.
Can't. Four to a shuttle, Inara. Four.
One more. It can't make
a difference, not now.
I'm not leaving Serenity.
Mal, you don't have to die alone.
Everybody dies alone.
- Every thing's set and ready.
- Good.
I linked the nav systems of both
shuttles into the helm here.
When your miracle gets here, pound this
button once. It'll call back both shuttles.
Go see to your wife.
I went ahead and closed off
all below-deck vents...
diverted what's left to the bridge.
Ain't much.
My advice is seal off everything
behind you on your way back up.
Might buy you some time.
And I prepped a suit for you.
It's hanging in the fore deck.
- So when the time comes...
- I won't be needing it, but thanks.
Okay.
Well.
Firefly...
Your distress...
Firefly Serenity...
I'm sorry for your troubles, captain.
They sound many.
But you do understand, I can't
invite you aboard my vessel.
- I don't know you.
- I ain't asking for a ride, just a push.
Right. Your mechanical trouble.
Your compression coil, you say?
- It was the catalyser.
- Not even the coil.
- Catalyser's a nothing part, captain.
- It's nothing till you don't got one.
Then it appears to be everything.
Well, it is possible we might
have something that could do you.
We just come from a big
salvage mission off Ita Moon.
- I'd appreciate it.
- Trouble is...
how can I know for certain
your story's true?
Ambush could be waiting for me
and my people on the other side.
You can plainly see my shuttles
have been launched, just like I said.
And by now you've scanned me.
You know I got no life-support.
I don't expect to see any weapons
when we board.
And I do expect to see that engine part
before I open the door.
I feel like maybe we can do business.
Check him.
Search the ship. Start with the cockpit
and work your way down.
- Is this what you meant by ambush?
- I'm just verifying your story.
If you find anybody on board not
supposed to be, you shoot them.
I thought we were gonna be
reasonable about this.
Reason. He's gonna talk to us
about reason now.
Yeah, that's a joke.
- Which one you figure tracked us?
- The ugly one, sir.
- Could you be more specific?
- Do we look reasonable to you?
Well, looks can be deceiving.
Not as deceiving
as a low-down, dirty deceiver.
Well said.
Wasn't that well said, Zoe?
Had a kind of poetry to it, sir.
You want I should shoot
them now, Marco?
Wait till they tell us
where they put the stuff.
That's a good idea.
Good idea.
Tell us where the stuffs at,
so I can shoot you.
Point of interest.
Offering to shoot us might not work
so well...
as an incentive as you might imagine.
Anyway, we've hidden it.
So you kill us, you'll never find it.
Found you easy enough.
Yeah, you did, didn't you?
How much they paying you?
Huh?
I mean, let's say you did kill us
or didn't.
There could be torture, whatever.
But somehow, you found the goods.
- What would your cut be?
- Seven percent, straight off the top.
Seven? Huh.
- What?
- Hm?
Nothing. Not a thing. No, I just...
- Does that seem low to you?
- It does.
- That ain't low.
- Stop it.
- Seven percent's standard.
- Okay. Zoe, I'm paying you too much.
- What does she get?
- Knock it off!
Forget I said anything.
I'm sure you're treated well.
You get the perks, got your own room.
No?
You share a bunk?
With that one.
- Really?
- Jayne, this ain't funny.
- Yeah, I ain't laughing.
- You move on over to this side...
we'll not only show you
where the stuffs at...
we'll see to it you get
your fair share.
Not no sad seven.
- Private room?
- Jayne!
Your own room, full run
of the kitchen.
Jayne, I ain't asking...
Shut up.
How big a room?
Ship's clear, captain.
You check the engine room?
Just like he said,
the catalyser's blown.
That's all he needs.
Anything that's worth anything
is right here in this cargo bay.
So you take a look around,
decide what you think is fair.
Already decided.
We're taking your ship.
Billy, get this plugged in.
Jesse, call Stern over here. You're
gonna pilot this pile of gosa out of here.
We'll get it as far as...
Jesse, don't call Stern.
Billy, leave the catalyser.
Do as he says.
Take your people and go.
You would've done the same.
We can already see I haven't.
Now get the hell off my ship.
Life-support failure.
Check oxygen levels at once.
- Real beauty.
- Serenity's not moving.
- When your miracle gets here...
- Come with us.
Everybody dies alone.
I'll run up and scrape off a piece.
- You'd do that for me?
- I'd do anything for you.
I don't think it's something
he should see when he wakes up.
Welcome back, sir.
- I go some place?
- Very nearly.
We thought we'd lost you.
I've been right here.
- Wash, you okay?
- Yeah, Mal, I'm fine.
- You got a thing in your arm.
- Yeah.
Try not to speak.
You're heavily medicated...
and you've lost a lot of blood.
I thought I ordered you all
off the ship.
- I call you back?
- No, Mal, you didn't.
I take full responsibility, captain.
The decision saved your life.
Won't happen again, sir.
Good.
And thanks. I'm grateful.
It was my pleasure, sir.
Hey, we'd have been back first...
except there's something wrong
with Inara's shuttle.
She done something to it.
Smells funny.
- I told you, that's incense.
- So you say.
- Hey, captain.
- Hey.
You fixed the ship. Good work.
- Thanks.
- All right.
I have to insist, the captain
needs to rest.
Yeah. I think the doc might not
be wrong about that one.
Just gonna need a few...
You all gonna be here when I wake up?
We'll be here.
Good.
That's good.
Yep. Real beauty, ain't she?
Yes, sir, a right smart purchase,
this vessel.
I'll tell you what, you buy this ship,
treat her proper...
she'll be with you for the rest
of your life.
Son?
Hey, son?
You hear a word I've been saying?