It's...
Monty python's flying circus.
senores, senoras y senoritas,
buenas noches.
esta noche presentamos
con mucho gusto
informacion interesante
acerca de la llama.
la llama!
Ay-ya!
amazonas!
Pa-pa-pa!
ole!
cuidado, llamas!
cuidado, cuidado, cuidado,
cuidado las llamas.
ole!
Fine.
Okay.
And now for something
completely different:
A man with a tape recorder
up his nose.
And now for something
completely different:
The office
of sir george head, o.b.e.
Next, please.
Ah, one at a time, please.
There is only me, sir.
So there is.
Ah, take a, um...
Seat?
Seat, seat--
take a seat.
So, you want to join
My mountaineering
expedition, do you?
Me, sir?
Yes.
Yes, I'd very much
like to, sir.
Jolly good,
jolly good.
And how about you?
There is only me, sir.
Well, bang goes
his application then.
Now, let me
fill you in.
I'm leading
this expedition
And we're
going to climb
Both peaks of
mount kiliman jaro.
I thought there was
only one peak, sir.
Well, that'll
save a bit of time.
Well, then.
Now, the object of
this expedition is
To see if we can find
Any traces of last
year's expedition.
Last year's expedition?
Yes, my brother
was leading that.
They were
going to build
A bridge between
the two peaks.
My idea,
I'm afraid.
Now, I ought
to tell you
That I have practically
everyone
That I need for
this expedition.
So what special qualifications
do you have?
Well, sir...
Yes, you first.
There is
only me, sir.
I wasn't
talking to you.
Carry on.
Well, I'm a fully
qualified mountaineer.
Mountaineer?
Mound... mountain...
A mountaineer:
Two men skilled in
climbing mountains.
Jolly good,
well, you're in.
Congratulations.
Both of you.
Now, what are
your names?
Arthur wilson.
Arthur wilson, right.
Well, look, I'll call
you arthur wilson one
And you
arthur wilson two
Just to avoid
confusion.
Are you actually leading this
expedition, sir?
Yes, we are leading
This expedition
to africa.
And what routes will
you both be taking?
Good questions.
Shall i?
Fine.
Well, we'll be
leaving on january 22
And taking the
following routes:
The a23s through purleys
Down onto the main roads
near purbrights--
Avoiding leatherheads--
and then taking the a231s
Entering rottingdeans
from the north.
From rottingdeans, we go
through africa to nairobis.
We take the south road
out of nairobis
For about 12 miles and then ask.
Does anyone speak
swahili, sir?
Oh, yes, I think most
of them do down there.
Does anyone in our party
speak swahili, sir?
Well, matron's got a smattering.
Apart from the two matrons...
Good god, i
forgot about her.
Apart from them,
who else is coming
On the expedition, sir?
Well, we've got
the arthur brown twins
Two botanists
called machin
The william
johnston brothers...
Two of them.
No, four of them--
Pair of
identical twins.
And a couple of the
ken spinoza quads.
The other two
pulled out.
And, of course,
you two.
And none of these
are mountaineers?
Well, you two are.
And we've got
a brace of guides
Called jimmy blenkinsop
Because kiliman jaro's a pretty
tricky climb, you know.
Most of it's up
Till you reach
the very, very top
And then it tends to slope
away rather sharply.
But jimmy's put
his heads together
And worked out
a way up-- jimmy?
I don't believe
you've met.
Jimmy blenkinsop,
arthur wilson.
Arthur wilson,
jimmy blenkinsop.
Arthur wilson two,
jimmy blenkinsop one.
Jimmy blenkinsop one,
arthur wilson two.
Carry on, jimmys.
Don't worry
about the, uh...
We'll get him
up somehow.
Now, the approach
to kiliman jaro
Is, quite simply,
over the foothills.
And then we go
on after that
Up to set a base camp
Somewhere in the region
of the bottom of the glacier
When after the
glacier we'll find...
And of course, we have this
rather difficult climb...
You'll be leading
the first assault.
Well, I'm afraid
I shan't be coming
On your expedition, sir
As I've absolutely no confidence
in anyone involved in it.
Oh dear.
Well, how about you?
Well, I'm game, sir.
So are we.
And now for something
completely different:
A man with a tape recorder
up his brother's nose.
Thank you, thank you.
Have you ever considered
the advantages
Of owning a really fine
set of encyclopedias?
For only ten shillings.
George...
Louise, I told you never
to call me at the office.
Congratulations, sir.
You've just one
this lovely cupie doll.
Get off!
And get a haircut, you pansy!
Morning.
Ah, morning sir,
morning, morning.
I'll b-b-be with
you in a minute.
Oh, fine, fine.
Um, how... how do
you like it, sir?
Just short back
and sides, please.
How do you do that?
Just ordinary short
back and sides.
It's not a,
um, a razor cut...
Razor razor razor razor cut!
Blood spurt artery murder!
Oh, thank god,
thank god.
It's just,
uh... scissors.
Yes, yes.
You wouldn't rather have it
just combed, would you, sir?
I beg your
pardon?
You wouldn't rather
forget all about it?
No, no, no,
I want it cut.
Cut cut cut cut cut cut!
Blood spurt artery murder!
Hitchcock psycho blood damn it!
Right, so I'll get
e-e-everything ready.
In the meantime
Perhaps you'd fill
in one of these.
All right,
fine, yes.
Excuse me.
What?
Where it says
"next of kin"
Should i
put "mother"?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
There we are.
Thank you.
Right.
Ha ha.
There. finished.
I finished
cutting cutting
Cutting cutting cutting
cutting cutting your hair.
It's all done.
You haven't
started cutting it.
I have.
I did it very quickly,
your honor...
Sir... sir, sir, sir.
Look here,
old fellow.
I know when a chap's
cut my hair
And when he hasn't
So will you please
stop fooling around
And get on with it?
Yes... yes,
I will, sir.
I'm going to cut
your hair, sir.
I'm going to start
cutting your hair, sir.
Start cutting-- now.
Nice day, sir.
Yes, flowers could do
with a drop of rain there.
You see the match
last night, sir?
Yeah, good game,
I thought.
I thought hurst played
well, sir.
Beg your pardon?
I thought hurst played well.
Oh, yes, only one
who did, though.
Can you put your head
down a little, sir?
Oh, sorry.
I prefer to watch
palace nowadays.
Oh, sorry, was that your ear?
No, no, didn't
feel a thing.
Hey! what's
going on?
Yes, it is a nice
sport, isn't it?
It looks very
nice, sir.
It's exactly the same
as when I first came in.
All right!
All right,
I confess
I haven't cut
your hair.
I hate cutting hair.
I have this terrible
un-un-un-uncontrollable fear
Whenever I see hair.
When I was a kid
I used to hate the sight
of hair being cut.
My mother said
I was a fool.
She said the only
way to cure it
Was become a barber.
So I spent five
ghastly years
In the hairdresser's
training center at totnes.
Can you imagine
what it's like--
Cutting the same
head for five years!?
I didn't want to
be a barber anyway.
I wanted to be a lumberjack.
Leaping from tree to tree
As they float down the mighty
rivers of british columbia.
The giant redwood, the larch,
the fir, the mighty scots pine.
The smell of fresh-cut timber!
The crash of mighty trees!
With my best girlie by my side.
We'd sing... sing... sing!
I'm a lumberjack
and I'm okay
I sleep all night,
I work all day
he's a lumberjack
and he's oka y
he sleeps all night
and he works all da y.
I cut down trees,
I eat my lunch
I go to the lavatory
On wednesdays I go shopping
And have buttered scones
for tea.
he cuts down trees,
he eats his lunch
he goes to the la vatory
on wednesda ys
he goes shopping
and has buttered scones
for tea.
he's a lumberjack
and he's oka y
he sleeps all night
and he works all da y.
I cut down trees,
I skip and jump
I like to press wild flowers
I put on women's clothing
And hang around in bars.
he cuts down trees,
he skips and jumps
he likes
to press wild flowers
he puts on women's clothing
and hangs around in bars?
he's a lumberjack
and he's oka y
he sleeps
all night
and he works
all da y.
I cut down trees,
I wear high heels
Suspenders and a bra
I wish I'd been a girlie,
just like my dear mama.
He cuts down trees,
he wears high heels...
Suspenders
and a bra
A bra!
I wish I'd
been a girlie
Just like my dear mama.
Oh, bevis!
And I thought
you were so rugged.
"dear sir, I wish to complain
in the strongest possible terms
"about the song which
you have just broadcast
"about the lumberjack
who wears women's clothes.
"many of my best friends
are lumberjacks
And only a few of them
are transvestites."
"yours faithfully
Brigadier sir charles
arthur strong (mrs.)."
P.s. I have never kissed
the editor of the radio times.
Well, I object to all
this sex on the television.
I mean, I keep falling off.
Well, I think television's
killed real entertainment.
In the old days,
we used to make our own fun.
At christmas parties
I used to strike myself
on the head repeatedly
With blunt instruments,
while crooning.
Only make-believe
I love you.
That you love me.
Oh! ow!
Others find peace of mind...
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen
And welcome to the refreshment
room here at bletchley.
My name is kenny lust and
I'm your compere for tonight.
You know, once in a while, it
is my pleasure and my privilege
To welcome here
at the refreshment room
Some of the truly great
international artists
Of our time.
And tonight we have
one such artist.
Ladies and gentlemen
Someone whom I've always
personally admired
Perhaps more deeply,
more strongly
More abjectly
than any other performer...
A man... well,
more than a man, a god...
A great god whose personality is
so totally and utterly wonderful
That my feeble words
of welcome sound
Wretchedly and
pathetically inadequate.
Someone whose boots
I would gladly lick clean
Until holes wore
through my tongue.
A man who is so totally
and utterly wonderful
That I would rather be sealed
in a pit of my own filth
Than dare tread
on the same stage with him.
Ladies and gentlemen
The incomparably superior
human being, harry fink.
He can't come.
Never mind.
He's not all
he's cracked up to be.
Ladies and gentlemen
We give you ken buddha
and his inflatable knees.
Ken buddha, a smile,
two bangs and a religion.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
for your further entertainment
Brian islam and brucie.
So, anyway,
I became a barber.
Oh, poor chap.
Yes, pity, really.
I always preferred
the outdoor life--
Hunting, shooting,
fishing
Getting out there
with a gun
Slaughtering a few
of god's creatures.
That was the life.
Charging about
the moorland
Blasting
their heads off.
I'm sorry, we don't
need you this week.
And now for something
completely different.
Would you... would
you mind terribly
If... if I held
your hand?
Oh! oh, no,
not at all.
Oh, iris, you're
so very beautiful.
Oh! oh, do you really mean that?
I do, I do, I do.
I think I'm beginning
to fall in love with you.
Oh, victor!
Huh! silly, isn't it?
No! no, not at all
Dear, sweet victor.
No, I didn't
mean that.
Only just us being
so close together
For so many months in
the soft-toy department
And yet
never daring to...
Oh! oh, victor!
Oh, iris!
Who can that be?
Oh, well, you try
and get rid of them.
Yes, I will,
I will, yes.
Won't be a moment.
I'll get rid of them.
Hello!
Hello?
Remember me?
Oh, no, I'm...
In the pub--
the tall, thin one
With the mustache,
remember?
No, I'm afraid...
About three years ago.
No, I don't,
I'm afraid.
Oh, blimey,
it's dark in here.
That's better.
Only you said we must have
a drink together sometime
So I thought I'd
take you up on it
As the film society meeting
was canceled this evening.
Yes, but, look,
to be frank
It is a little awkward
this evening.
Hello, I'm arthur,
arthur name.
Name by name
but not by nature.
I always say that,
don't i, vicky boy?
Really?
Is that your wife?
Uh, no, actually, but...
Oh, I get the picture.
Eh? well, don't worry
about me, vicky boy.
I know all about
one-night stands.
I beg your pardon!
Mind if I change
the record?
No, look, look,
we put that on.
Oh, here's a good one.
I heard it in a pub.
What's brown...
What's brown and
sounds like a bell?
I beg your pardon?
What's brown and
sounds like a bell?
Dung!
That's a good one,
that one.
I like that one.
There, I won't
keep you long.
Oh, that's better.
Now, don't worry
about me.
I'll wait here till
you've finished.
Who the hell is that?
Oh, I'll get it.
It'll be friends of mine.
I took the liberty
of inviting them along.
Look, we were
hoping to have
A quiet evening
on our own.
Oh, they won't mind.
They're very broad-minded.
Hello!
Good evening.
Oh, good evening.
My name is equator,
brian equator.
Like round the
middle of the earth
Only with an "l."
This is my wife, audrey.
She smells a bit, but
she has a heart of gold.
Well, there must have been
some kind of misunderstanding
Because this is not the...
Oh, who's that then?
What?
Who's the bird?
Well, I mean...
You got a nice pair
there, haven't you, love?
Come on, give us
a kiss.
Shut up, you silly bitch,
it was only a bit of fun.
Now, look here.
Big gin, please.
I'll get it!
Look, leave
those drinks alone.
And three tins of beans
for me, please.
I told you to lay off
the beans, you whore!
I only want three cans!
Button your lip, you rat-bag!
It was rather witty, wasn't it?
Where's my gin?
Who the hell's that?
Oh, why, uh, I took the liberty
of inviting an old friend along
As his wife has just passed away
and he's somewhat distraught
Poor chap.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, my god, what
a simply ghastly place!
It's not too good, is it?
A pint of creme de menthe
for my friend.
Well, how are you,
you great poof?
Bit lumpy.
Ah, no wonder,
I was sitting on the cat.
I brought along this
simply gorgeous little man
I picked up at the odeon.
Is he sexy, then?
I had to bring the goat
and he's not well.
I only hope he don't
go on the carpet.
Come on, then, love,
drop them.
Blimey, she don't
go much, do she?
Oh! I wet them.
The goat's...
goat's done a bundle.
Nice to see you.
Look, get out, all of you.
Go on, get out!
get out! get out!
I beg your pardon?
I'm turning you all out.
I'm not having my house
filled with filthy perverts.
Now, look, I'm giving
just half a minute.
Then I'm going to call
the police, so get out.
I don't much like
the tone of your voice.
Right, let's have
a ding dong.
Ding dong! merrily on high
In heav'n the bells
are ringing...
Ding dong! verily the sky
Is riv'n
with angels singing
Glor-or-or-ia
Hosanna in excelsis.
cuida...
cuidado llamas!