- What's today?
- It's Thursday.
Really?
It feels like Tuesday.
Tuesday has no feel.
Monday has a feel.
Friday has a feel.
Sunday has a feel.
- I feel Tuesday and Wednesday.
- Shut up, the both of you.
You double dipped the chip.
Double dipped?
What are you talking about?
You dipped the chip.
You took a bite...
...and you dipped again.
- So?
- It's like putting your whole mouth...
...right in the dip.
From now on, when you take a chip
just take one dip and end it.
Could I offer you
something to drink?
Okay, yeah. I'll have a...
Do you have a decaf cappuccino?
I don't think we have that.
Well, that's a little strange.
- Why does that surprise you?
- Well, it's a very popular drink.
- This is an office.
- That's true.
Magellan? You like Magellan?
Oh, yeah. My favorite explorer.
Around the world. Come on.
- Who do you like?
- I like de Soto.
- De Soto? What did he do?
- Discovered the Mississippi.
Oh, like they wouldn't have found
that anyway.
I was talking to this guy,
and I just happened to throw...
...my purse on the sofa.
And my diaphragm goes flying out.
So I just froze, you know:
Staring at my diaphragm, you know?
It's just lying there.
So this woman who sold me
this hair thing...
...she grabbed it before
the guy noticed, so, I mean...
...big deal, right?
So I carry around my diaphragm.
Who doesn't?
I mean, like, it's a big, big secret...
...that women carry around
their diaphragms.
You never know when
you're gonna need it.
I hate Keith Hernandez.
- Hate him!
- I despise him.
- Why?
- Why? I'll tell you why.
- Let me tell her.
- You can't -
- You always tell it.
- All right, tell it.
- You just tell it.
- All right.
June 14th, 1987, Mets-Phillies.
We're enjoying a beautiful afternoon
in the right-field stands...
...when a crucial Hernandez error
opens the door...
...to a five-run Phillies ninth.
Cost the Mets the game!
Our day was ruined.
There was a lot of people waiting
by the players' parking lot.
Now we're coming down the ramp.
Newman was in front of me.
Hernandez was coming toward us.
As he passes us, Newman turns
and says, "Nice game, pretty boy."
Hernandez continued past us
up the ramp.
Then, a second later,
something happened...
...that changed us in a very deep
and profound way...
...from that day forward.
- What was it?
- He spit on us!
And I screamed out, "I'm hit!"
Then I turned, and the spit ricocheted
off him, and it hit me.
What a story.
Unfortunately, the immutable laws
of physics contradict...
...the whole premise of your account.
Allow me to reconstruct this,
if I may, for Ms. Benes...
...as I've heard this story
a number of times.
Newman, Kramer,
if you'll indulge me.
According to your story...
...Hernandez passes you
and starts walking up the ramp.
Then you say you were struck...
...on the right temple.
The spit then proceeds to ricochet...
...off the temple, striking Newman
between the third and the forth rib.
The spit then came off the rib...
...made a right turn,
hitting Newman in the right wrist...
...causing him to drop
his baseball cap.
The spit then splashed off the wrist,
pauses...
...in midair, mind you...
...makes a left turn and lands
on Newman's left thigh.
That is one magic loogie.
Story is the foundation
of all entertainment.
And people really have
to care about the characters.
Care? Forget about care. Love.
They have to love them.
Now, get the hell out of my house.
Quiet! You shut up!
At this moment, you're banned
from the store. Banned!
It's a pizza the moment
you put your fists in the dough.
I have a hair on my tongue.
Can't get it off.
You know how much I hate that?
Soup's not a meal.
You're supposed to buy me a meal.
Yeah. Just keep out
of my business, you big ape.
Who you calling "big ape"?
I'm calling you an ape.
All right, break it up.
Come on, you two.
Just cut it out now.
But you put on a pair of shoes
in the New York Public Library, fella.
We had a funny guy with us in Korea.
A tail gunner.
They blew his brains out
all over the Pacific.
There's nothing funny about that.
We will annex Poland by the spring
at any cost!
And our stock will rise high.
You think you're an idiot,
but with all due respect...
...I'm a much bigger idiot
than you are.
Don't insult me, my friend.
Remember who you're talking to.
No one's a bigger idiot than me.
Am I a hipster doofus?
- No.
Said I'm not good-looking enough.
Not good-looking.
Jerry, look at me. Look at my face.
Am I beautiful?
George, am I beautiful?
- You're very attractive.
- Yeah.
Is it possible I'm not as attractive
as I think I am?
We're not gay.
Not that there's
anything wrong with that.
- No, of course not.
- It's fine, if that's who you are.
- Absolutely.
- I mean, I have many gay friends.
- My father's gay.
- Look...
...I know what I heard.
- Heard. It was a joke.
- Look, you wanna have sex right now?
Do you wanna have sex
with me right now? Let's go.
Come on! Let's go, baby! Come on!
Hey, come on. Let's go.
I thought we were gonna take a steam.
- No, I don't want any steam.
- No. No steam.
Well, I don't wanna
sit there naked all by myself.
- You've faked?
- On occasion.
- And the guy never knows?
- No.
How can he not know that?
Because I was good.
I guess after that many beers,
he's probably a little groggy anyway.
Well, you didn't know.
What's that?
You didn't know.
- Are you saying-?
- I think I'll have a piece of cake.
- With me?
- Well...
- You faked with me?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- No. You faked it?
- Yes. I faked it.
That whole thing, the whole
production, it was all an act?
Not bad, huh?
What about the breathing, the panting,
the moaning, the screaming?
Fake, fake, fake, fake.
I'm disturbed. I'm depressed.
I'm inadequate. I got it all!
Can't you see what's happened?
I've become George.
Don't say that.
It's true. I'm George.
I'm George.
Tuna on toast, coleslaw...
- ...cup of coffee.
- Yeah.
No, no, wait a minute.
I always have tuna on toast.
Nothing's every worked out for me
with tuna on toast.
I want the complete opposite
of tuna on toast.
Chicken salad on rye...
...untoasted, with a side
of potato salad...
...and a cup of tea.
Well, there's no telling
what can happen from this.
Chicken salad's
not the opposite of tuna.
Salmon's the opposite of tuna
because salmon swim...
...against the current,
and the tuna swim with it.
Good for the tuna.
George, you know that woman
just looked at you.
So what?
What am I supposed to do?
Go talk to her.
Elaine, bald men with no jobs
and no money...
...who live with their parents...
...don't approach strange women.
Try the opposite.
Instead of tuna salad...
...and being intimidated by women,
chicken salad...
- ...and going right up to them.
- Yeah, I should do the opposite.
If every instinct you have is wrong...
...then the opposite
would have to be right.
Yes.
I will do the opposite.
I used to sit here and do nothing
and regret it for the rest of the day.
So now I will do the opposite,
and I will do something.
Excuse me.
I couldn't help but notice that...
- ...you were looking in my direction.
- Oh, yes, I was.
You just ordered
the same exact lunch as me.
My name is George.
I'm unemployed,
and I live with my parents.
I'm Victoria. Hi.
Catch phrases
Boy, these pretzels
are making me thirsty.
These pretzels are making me thirsty.
These pretzels...
...are making me thirsty!
Boy, I'm really starting to
dislike the Drake.
Hate the Drake!
You are so good-looking.
You can't believe her.
She's one of these low-talkers.
Because he's a high talker.
He's nice. Bit of a close talker.
How about you, Jerry?
I'm swamped.
You sure? You can examine
the artwork up close.
I don't have a square to spare.
I can't spare a square.
I need hand! I have no hand!
- Newman.
- Hello, Newman.
So you're still master
of your domain.
Yes. Master of my domain.
I am king of the county.
Lord of the manor.
I'm queen of the castle.
- You mean shrinkage.
- Yes.
Significant shrinkage.
So you feel you were shortchanged?
Yes.
If she thinks that's me, she's under
a complete misapprehension.
Well, so, what's the difference?
- What if she discusses it with Jane?
- Oh, she's not gonna tell Jane.
Could you tell her about
the shrinkage factor?
I'm not gonna tell her
about your shrinkage.
Besides, I think women know
about shrinkage.
How do women know
about shrinkage?
Isn't it common knowledge?
- Elaine.
Elaine!
- What?
- Do women know about shrinkage?
What do you mean, like laundry?
No.
Like when a man goes swimming,
afterwards...
It shrinks?
Like a frightened turtle.
- Why does it shrink?
- It just does.
I don't know how you guys
walk around with those things.
- About the script.
The script. Now, I've read
this thing three times.
Yeah.
And every time I read it...
What?
- Excuse me for a second.
- What?
Would you like a Pepto-Bismol?
I keep them in my wallet.
You think he liked it?
I'm not sure.
The air conditioner!
My mother caught me.
Caught you? Doing what?
You know.
I was alone...
You mean-?
- She caught you?
- Where?
I stopped by the house
to drop the car off...
...and I went inside
for a few minutes.
Nobody was there.
They're supposed to be working.
My mother had a Glamour magazine.
I started leafing through it.
Glamour?
- So one thing led to another.
- What did she do?
First she screams, "George,
what are you doing? My God!"
Looked like she was gonna faint.
She started clutching the wall,
trying to hang onto it.
I didn't know whether to keep her
from falling or zip up.
- What did you do?
- I zipped up.
- So she fell?
- Yeah.
Well, I couldn't run over there
the way I was.
- No, I guess you couldn't.
- I wouldn't think so.
So she fell, and then she starts
screaming, "My back, my back!"
I picked her up.
I took her to the hospital.
- How is she?
- She's in traction.
- I'm sorry.
- It's not funny, Elaine.
I know. I'm sorry. It's serious.
Her back went out. She's gotta
be there for a couple days.
Glamour?
I'll tell you this, though:
I am never doing...
...that again.
What? You mean in your mother's
house or altogether?
- Altogether.
- Give me a break.
Yeah, right.
- You don't think I can?
- No chance.
- You think you could?
- I could hold out longer than you.
Care to make it interesting?
Sure. How much?
Hundred dollars?
You're on.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
Count me in on this.
You? You'll be out before we
get the check.
I want in on this.
- No, no.
- It's apples and oranges.
- It's different.
- Why? Why?
- Because you're a woman.
- So what?
It's easier for a woman not to do it
than a man. We have to do it.
It's part of our lifestyle.
It's like shaving.
That is such baloney.
I shave my legs.
Not every day.
- You wanna be in?
- Yeah.
You gotta give us odds.
At least 2-1. You gotta put up $200.
No. A thousand.
No. I'll put up 150.
- All right. You're in for 150.
- Okay, 150.
How we gonna monitor this?
Obviously, we all know each
other very well.
I'm sure we'll all feel comfortable within
the confines of the honor system.
All right. Come on.
Fire!
We have sacrificed everything,
all for the sake of our little...
...bubble boy.
- Excuse me.
- Oh, here.
Amazing how many
beautiful women live in New York.
You're as pretty as any of them.
Just need a nose job.
Yankee bean. Yankee bean.
I like my Yankee bean.
In fact, I hate anyone that ever had
a pony when they were growing up.
I had a pony.
Well, I didn't...
When I was a little girl in Poland...
...we all had ponies.
My sister had pony.
My cousin had pony.
- So, what's wrong with that?
- Nothing, nothing at all.
He was a beautiful pony,
and I loved him.
Well, I'm sure you did.
Who wouldn't love a pony?
Who wouldn't love a person
that had a pony?
You. You said so.
It's my father's cabin!
I just realized, you never gave
me back the change from the tolls.
So you heard that
I was in a car accident...
...and then decided to stop off
for some Jujyfruit?
Well...
...the counter was right there.
I didn't know she had a pony.
Who figures an immigrant
is gonna have a pony?
I mean, in all the pictures I saw
of immigrants on boats...
...coming into New York Harbor...
...I never saw one of them
sitting on a pony.
But why would anyone come here
if they had a pony?
Who leaves a country packed with
ponies to go to a non-pony country?
It doesn't make sense.
Now we'll open
the peritoneal cavity...
...exposing the body's
internal organs.
- What are you eating?
- Junior Mints.
- You want one?
- No.
Now, I can't see.
Could you get-?
Where'd you get those?
- The machine. You want one?
- No.
- Here. Take one.
- I don't want one.
- They're good.
- I don't want any.
- Just take one.
- No. Stop- Kramer, stop it.
It's a Junior Mint.
Drake's Coffee Cake?
- Snapple?
- No, thanks.
- PEZ?
- No.
A box of Jujyfruits?
- Clark Bar.
- I love Yoo-hoo.
- Oh, Chunkys.
- Chocolate babka.
It's Gore-Tex.
- Cashmere?
- No, Gore-Tex.
Who's gonna turn down
a Junior Mint?
It's chocolate, it's peppermint.
It's delicious.
- That's true.
- It's very refreshing.
What's going on over here?
There's a beached whale.
She's dying.
Is anyone here a marine biologist?
The sea was angry that day,
my friends.
Like an old man trying
to send back soup in a deli.
I got about 50 feet out,
when suddenly...
...the great beast
appeared before me.
I tell you, he was 10 stories high
if he was a foot.
As if sensing my presence,
he let out a great bellow.
I said, "Easy, big fella."
And then, as I watched
him struggling, I realized...
...that something was obstructing
its breathing.
From where I was standing, I could
see into the eye of the great fish.
- Mammal.
- Whatever.
- What did you do next?
- Well, then...
...from out of nowhere,
a huge tidal wave lifted me...
...tossed me like a cork,
and I found myself on top of him...
...face to face with the blowhole.
I could barely see from the waves
crashing down upon me...
...but I knew something was there.
So I reached my hand in...
...felt around, and pulled out
the obstruction.
What is that, a Titleist?
A hole in one, huh?
We go into NBC, tell them we got
an idea for a show about nothing.
- Exactly.
- "What's your show about?"
- I say, "Nothing."
- There you go.
I think you may have something here.
Why don't you two go to the movies
by yourselves. I'm not in the mood.
Well, me either.
I'm going to Sky Burger.
- So you're not going?
- You don't need us.
Well, I can't go to a bad movie
by myself.
What, am I gonna make
sarcastic remarks to strangers?
I guess I'll just go to my uncle's.
- Should we tell him we're leaving?
- What for? Let's just get out of here.
Seinfeld, four!