Oh, hi.
A hundred episodes.
That's a lot. During the course of
which George, Elaine, Kramer and I...
...have had many experiences,
both positive and negative.
Well, mostly negative.
There've been some relationships
that haven't worked out...
...ambitions that were unfulfilled...
...hopes dashed...
...some property damage,
hurt feelings...
I know one guy got deported.
Physical injury and...
All right, maybe even
a death or two.
But we've persevered.
Because we're people.
Real TV people.
And for 30 minutes a week...
...that's pretty important to us.
So if you're joining us late...
...here's some highlights
from what's happened so far.
Why don't they have salsa
on the table?
What do you need salsa for?
Salsa is now the number-one
condiment in America.
Do you know why?
Because people like to say " salsa."
Do you have any salsa?
We need more salsa.
Where is the salsa? No salsa?
You know, it must be impossible
for a Spanish person...
...to order seltzer and not get salsa.
I wanted seltzer, not salsa.
Don't you know the difference
between them?
You have the seltzer after the salsa.
This should be the show.
This is the show.
- What?
- This.
Just talking.
Yeah. Right.
No, I'm really serious.
I think that's a good idea.
Just talking?
Well, what's the show about?
It's about nothing.
What's that red dot
on your sweater?
Hey, didn't we come in over there?
I thought we came in over there.
I'm out.
- What?
- Yeah, I'm out.
I'm out of the contest.
- No story?
- No, forget the story.
- You gotta have a story.
- Who says you gotta have a story?
Four. Seinfeld.
Four.
That'll be five, 10 minutes.
What, do you smell something?
Do I smell something?
What am I, hard of smelling?
What is it?
I think its BO.
And who's on the show?
Who are the characters?
I could be a character.
- You?
- Yeah. You base a character on me.
It's come to my attention
that you and the cleaning woman...
...have engaged in sexual intercourse
on the desk in your office.
- Who said that?
- She did.
Was that wrong?
Should I not have done that?
I got to plead ignorance
on this thing...
...because if anyone
had said anything to me...
...when I first started here that that
sort of thing was frowned upon...
And who else is on the show?
Elaine could be a character.
I wonder what happened
to my fiancé.
I know he's here somewhere.
I have lost my fiancé,
the poor baby.
Maybe the dingo ate your baby.
What?
The dingo ate your baby.
- Kramer.
- Now, he's a character.
The bus is out of control.
So I grab him by the collar,
take him out of the seat...
...get behind the wheel.
Now I'm driving the bus.
- You're Batman.
- Yeah. I am Batman.
Then the mugger, he comes to,
and he starts choking me.
So I'm fighting him off
with one hand...
...and I kept driving the bus
with the other, you know?
Then I managed to open the door
and kicked him out the door...
...with my foot, you know,
at the next stop.
You kept making all the stops?
Well, people kept ringing the bell!
So everybody I know...
- ...is a character on the show.
- Right.
My wallet's gone! My wallet's gone!
- Jerry.
- Uncle Leo.
Hello.
How could you?
- How could I what?
- You were making out...
...during Schindler's List?
How long does it take to find a bra?
What's going on in there?
You ask me to get a pair of
underwear, I'm back in two seconds.
You know about the cup sizes
and all?
- They have different cups.
- Yeah, I know about the cups.
You got the A...
...the B...
...the C...
...the D. That's the biggest.
I go out for a quart of milk.
I come home and find
my son treating his body...
...like it was an amusement park.
I'm a United States postal worker.
Aren't those the guys
that always go crazy...
...and come back with a gun
and shoot everybody?
Sometimes.
- Why is that?
- Because the mail never stops.
Every day it piles up more and more
and you gotta get it out...
...but more keeps coming in!
Then the bar code reader breaks,
and it's Publishers Clearing House day!
All right, all right, all right.
So you're saying I go into NBC
and tell them...
...I got this idea
for a show about nothing.
We go into NBC.
We? Since when are you a writer?
What writer?
We're talking about a sitcom.
You wanna go with me to NBC?
Yeah, we really got something here.
- What do we got?
- An idea.
- What idea?
- An idea for the show.
- I still don't know what the idea is.
- It's about nothing.
- Right.
- Everybody's doing something.
We'll do nothing.
Come on. Let's go do something.
I don't want to just sit around here.
- Wanna get something to eat?
- Where?
I don't care. I'm not hungry.
We could go to one of those
cappuccino places.
They let you just sit there.
What are we gonna do there, talk?
We can talk.
I'll go if I don't have to talk.
Then we'll just sit there.
Oh, that's the astronaut pen. I heard
about that. Where did you get it?
- It was a gift.
- Because a lot of times I write in bed...
...and I have to turn and lean on
my elbow to make the pen work.
- Take the pen.
- Oh, no.
- Go ahead.
- I couldn't.
- Take it.
- I can't take it.
- Do me a personal favor.
- I'm not comfortable.
- I cannot take it.
- Take the pen.
- Are you sure?
- I'm positive. Take the pen.
Okay, thank you very much.
Thank you. Gee, boy.
- Jack, what are you doing?
- Stop it.
Jack, we should go.
It was nice meeting you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Thanks again.
Come on!
- This?
- Yeah.
- I agreed to wear this?
- Yeah, yeah.
Well, when did I do that?
When we went to dinner
the other night.
What, are you crazy?
What were you talking about
when I went to the bathroom?
I don't know.
I couldn't understand a word she said.
- I was just nodding.
- There you go.
Where I go?
You mean she was asking me
to wear this ridiculous shirt...
- ...on national TV, and I said yes?
- Yes, yes. You said it.
I didn't know what she was
talking about. I couldn't hear her.
- Well, she asked you.
- I can't wear this puffy shirt on TV.
I mean, look at it. It looks ridiculous.
Well, you gotta wear it now.
This pirate trend
she's come up with, Jerry...
This is gonna be
the new look for the '90s.
You're gonna be the first pirate.
But I don't wanna be a pirate.
I made a reservation.
Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do.
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
But the reservation
keeps the car here.
That's why you have
the reservation.
- I know why we have reservations.
- I don't think you do.
If you did, I'd have a car.
See, you know how to take
the reservation.
You just don't know how to hold
And that's really the most important
part of the reservation, the holding.
Anybody can just take them.
I think I can sum up the show
for you with one word:
Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
What does that mean?
What did you do today?
- I got up and came to work.
- There's a show. That's a show.
How is that a show?
Well, maybe something happens
to you on the way to work.
No. No! No! Nothing happens!
Well, something happens.
- Well, why am I watching it?
- Because it's on TV.
Not yet.
I'm telling you, she's good-looking.
- What about the body?
- Good body. Nice body.
- How nice?
- Nice. Pretty nice.
- Really good?
- Really, very nice and good.
- What about personality?
- Good personality.
Funny. Bright.
I don't want anyone
smarter than me.
How could she
be smarter than you?
He's a really, really funny guy.
What does he look like?
- Pardon?
- What does he look like?
Well, he's got a lot of character
in his face.
He's short. He's stocky.
He's fat.
Is that what you're saying,
that he's fat?
Powerful.
He is so powerful. He can lift
100 pounds right up over his head.
And, what else? What else?
Oh, right, well...
He's, he's kind of-
Just kind of- Losing his hair.
- He's bald?
- No.
No, no, no. He's not bald.
He's balding.
- So he will be bald?
- Yeah.
Thick, lustrous hair
is important to me.
"Thick, lustrous hair
is important to me."
- Is that what you said?
- Right.
Just clarifying.
Let me ask you this.
Do you want to get it out?
Or do you want to not be able
to get it out?
- I'd like to be able to get it out.
- I think you'll get it out.
What about the skin?
I need a good cheek.
I like a good cheek.
She's got a fine cheek.
Is there a pinkish hue?
- A pinkish hue?
- Yes, a rosy glow.
There's a hue.
She's got great eyebrows.
Women kill to have her eyebrows.
Who cares about eyebrows?
Look at you.
Why don't you do something
with your life?
You sit around here all day.
You contribute nothing to society!
The alarm didn't go off.
You're gonna miss the plane, it's 9:15.
- 9:15?
- Yeah. It's 9:15!
We'll never make it.
I'll leave tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Are you crazy?
No. Now, now, let's go.
Let's go. You get dressed,
you get dressed.
I mean, how can I be
with someone like you?
Wouldn't respect myself.
Put your pants on.
- I'll go tomorrow or the next day.
- You have your ticket.
- You have to go now.
- We'll never make it.
- Don't say that.
- Well, it takes 45 minutes to get-
It takes 45 minutes to get there.
That only leaves me five minutes...
- ...to get to the plane.
- Shut up and pack!
I take it all back!
Every word!
I love you!
It's not you. It's me.
You're giving me
the "it's not you, it's me" routine?
I invented "it's not you, it's me."
Nobody tells me it's them, not me.
- If it's anybody, it's me.
- All right.
- George, it's you.
- You are damn right it's me.
Elaine, you don't know the first thing
about first base.
Well, I know something
about getting to first base...
...and I know you'll never be there.
The way I figure it,
I've already been there.
And I plan on rounding second
tonight at around 11:00.
Well, I'd watch the third-base coach
if I were you...
...because I don't think
he's waving you in.
I guess things changed for me
on Tuesday night.
Tuesday night?
What happened Tuesday night?
I saw your act.
My act? What does that
have to do with anything?
Well, to be honest...
...it just didn't make it for me.
It's just so much fluff.
What are you saying?
You didn't like my act?
So that's it?
I can't be with someone
if I don't respect what they do.
You're a cashier.
You don't know my name, do you?
- Yes, I do.
- What is it?
It rhymes with a female body part.
What is it?
Mulva?
- I think you're really sick.
- I'm not sick.
You said much sicker things
than me.
I'm leaving.
So where were we?
- I was just leaving.
- Right. You were leaving.
I can't believe you sent a woman
into the sauna to do that?
That was an accident.
I think you're both mentally ill.
And by the way, they're real
and they're spectacular.
Why shouldn't we
be able to do that...
- ...once in a while if we want to?
- I know.
I mean, really, what is the big deal?
We go in there...
...we're in there for a while,
then we come back out here.
That's not complicated.
It's almost stupid if we didn't.
- It's moronic.
- Absurd.
Course...
...I guess maybe some little
problems could arise.
There are always a few.
I mean, if anything happened...
...and we couldn't be friends the way
we are now, that would really be bad.
- Devastating.
- Because this is very good.
And that would be good.
That would be good too.
The idea is to combine the this...
...and the that.
But this cannot be disturbed.
Yeah, we just want to take this...
...and add that.
But of course, we'd have
to figure out a way...
...to avoid the things that
cause the little problems.
Maybe some rules or something.
For example:
Now I call you whenever
I'm inclined, and vice versa.
But if we did that, we might feel...
...a certain obligation to call.
Well, why should that be?
I have an idea.
No calls the day after that.
Beautiful.
Let's make it a rule.
All right, sir.
- Now, here's another little rule.
- Yeah.
When we see each other now...
...we retire to our separate quarters.
But sometimes when people
get involved with that...
...they feel pressure...
...to sleep over.
When that...
...is not really sleep.
Sleep is separate from that,
and I don't see...
...why sleep got all tied up
and connected...
...with that.
Okay, okay, rule number two:
Spending the night is optional.
Well, now we're getting somewhere.
I slept with Elaine last night.
- Oxygen. I need some oxygen.
- I thought you'd like that.
Oh, this is huge!
- I know.
- All right, okay. Let's go. Details.
- No, I can't give details.
- No details?
I'm not in the mood.
You ask me here to have lunch...
...tell me you slept with Elaine...
...and then say you're not
in the mood for details.
Now, you listen to me.
I want details,
and I want them right now.
I don't have a job,
I have no place to go.
You're not in the mood?
Well, you get in the mood!
I was at the unemployment office.
I told them I was very close to getting
a job with Vandelay Industries...
...and I gave them your phone number.
So when the phone rings...
...you have to answer,
"Vandelay Industries."
- I'm Vandelay Industries?
- Right.
- What is that?
- You're in latex.
- Latex.
- Right.
- What do I do with latex?
- I don't know! You manufacture it!
- Right here in this little apartment?
- And what do I say about you?
You're considering hiring me
for your latex salesman.
- I'll hire you as my latex salesman?
- Right.
I don't think so.
Man, I'm telling you this pizza idea
is really gonna happen.
This is the thing where you go and
you have to make your own pizza?
We give you the dough.
You smash it. You pound it.
You fling it up in the air.
And then you get to put your sauce
and sprinkle your cheese.
And then,
you slide it into the oven.
You have to know how to do that.
You can't have people shoving
their arms into a 600-degree oven!
- It's all supervised.
- Oh, well...
Tolstoy used to write
in the village square.
The faces inspired him.
Although, one wonders
if War and Peace would have been...
...as highly acclaimed, had it been
published under it's original title...
...War-What Is It Good For?
- What?
- Yeah.
Mr. Lippman, it was his mistress
who insisted...
- ... that he call it War and Peace.
- Elaine, Elaine.
War-What Is It Good For?
Absolutely nothing
If I see her, what do I say
I'm doing here?
To see me. I work in the building.
What do you do?
I'm an architect.
You're an architect?
I'm not?
I don't see architecture
coming from you.
We'll make our choice in a few days
and we'll let you know.
- I have no chance, do I?
- No.
You know I always wanted
to pretend I was an architect.
- What do you do?
- I'm an architect.
Have you designed
any buildings in New York?
Have you seen the new addition
to the Guggenheim?
- You did that?
- Yep, yep.
Really didn't take very long either.
The beauty of my book is,
if you don't have a coffee table...
...it turns into a coffee table.
- Is that fabulous?
- Look at this.
What-delay Industries?
- No.
- Vandelay!
Say Vandelay!
No, you're way, way, way off!
- No, say-
- Vandelay! Say-
Vandelay Industries!
No problem, no problem.
And you want to be
my latex salesman.
I think Superman probably has
a very good sense of humor.
I never heard him say anything funny.
He's got super strength, super speed.
I'm sure he's got super humor.
Either you're born with humor,
or you're not. It's not gonna change.
Even if you go
from the red sun of Krypton...
...all the way to the yellow sun
of the Earth.
Why? Why would that one area
of his mind...
...not be affected
by the yellow sun of the Earth?
I don't know. But he ain't funny.