New York's classic rock
q104.3.
Good morning.
I'm Jim Kerr.
Coming up a little bit later
on the "q"...
Half an hour,
he says.
It's a fucking hour
and a half already.
He's busy.
Enjoy the music.
I thought
you weren't coming.
You don't wanna know.
Actually, I do.
We had intel
A salafist cell
was at Newark airport
Boarding somebody
onto a 767 to London.
You're right.
I don't wanna know.
We get this all the time.
Our source was either wrong
Or it was done
to study our response.
Happens all the time?
What's up, my?
You know, my kid is
obsessed with this shit.
But we tell him he's making
a molehill out of it.
Is he right?
Hey.
Probably another hour.
Just leave it out,
All right?
I'll heat it up.
Well, then don't
leave it out.
What do you want me to say?
You got a rough enough job
with this terrorism shit.
I'll let you get home. The
reason I called is those two arabs
I turned you on to
- well, I happened to remember
My nephew
mentioned a bank
Where they had an account-
A branch...
The mintner first
merchants bank.
- you just remembered that?
- yeah.
Thanks.
Oh, whoa-
listen,
I know you got that friend
in the Brooklyn office.
Is it possible he knows
where Phil leotardo is?
I want to try to avoid any
more of my guys getting hurt.
I'm just saying,
If you heard anything
from your pal-
Är du försiktig?
- Det här oroar mig.
- Ring när du kommer hem.
You're overreaching.
Okay.
- See you Thursday.
- Bye.
Where are you going?
I just got here.
I'm really late meeting
patrick in the city. Bye.
Bye-bye.
How are you doing?
She smelled
that odor too.
Your remodel
will fix all that.
Maybe it's toxic. Maybe we
shouldn't be breathing it.
It's not toxic.
The owners were, what,
90 years old?
It's piss.
I got to get home.
I'm working on it.
I went to see Sil...
And Gab.
Oh my god, Tony.
Yeah.
Are you being careful?
This kind of
bothers me.
Call me when you
get home, okay?
Okay.
Thanks.
Who is she
gonna tell?
But you should used
the back door.
I wouldn't kick her out
of bed for purging cookies.
Real funny.
We're just friends.
I know.
Nice work.
- She's a model.
- She's doing some modeling.
All right? She's a
junior in high school.
What?
She's quitting modeling
anyway.
She's tired of being exploited.
Did you help your mother
take the carpets outside,
- put 'em in the sun?
- he did.
Uncle Bobby's funeral
is finally set
For Thursday.
And you're gonna be there.
How's that
supposed to work?
We're all on def-con 4,
living in separate houses
And we're gonna stand out in the open
at the cemetery?
There is always
a large FBI presence.
Unbelievable.
He was different, you know?
We forget.
When he was
with blanca.
We commend to almighty god
our brother robert
And we commit his body
to its resting place...
The ceremony
just ended.
...The lord
bless him and keep him.
The lord make his face
shine upon him...
Every one of these things
is lemon chicken or fish.
- look at that.
- can I have some sauce?
- I heard cauliflower's $3.99 a pound.
- I'm not gonna have this.
Can you believe that?
Oh, pop, they got
roast pork.
Give me one.
Thanks.
- She had won "American idol. "
- No.
Jennifer Hudson? Absolutely.
Jason G. Was the winner
of italian "American idol. "
He could say "fuck"
more times in a sentence
Than any other contestant.
Uncle Paulie,
come sit down.
Yeah, I'll sit with you.
I'm young at heart, right?
Who are you, dear?
Tara Zincone.
Bobby's niece.
My condolences.
Oh...
- did I eat.
- it was good.
In the midst of death,
we are in life.
Or is it the other way around?
I think it's
the other way around.
Either version, you're
halfway up the ass.
Pardon my french,
sweetheart.
- I've lost two dear friends.
- Sil's hanging on.
I lost ma
last month.
You can take 2007 and give
it back to the indians.
- I'm sorry.
- what are you gonna do?
Life goes on.
We were discussing
"dreamgirls. " did you see it?
You people are fucked.
You're living in a dream.
You still sit here talking
about the fucking Oscars?
"what rough beast slouches
toward bethlehem to be born?"
- huh?
- "yeets. "
- A.J.
- yeats?
The world-
don't you see it?
Bush let
Al Qaeda escape...
- ho!
- ... In the mountains.
Then he has us invade
some other country.
Let's join up, go kill
some fucking terrorists.
It's more noble than watching
these jack-off fantasies on tv
Of how we're
kicking their ass.
It's like, America-
- What about it?
- This is still where people come
To make it.
It's a beautiful idea.
And then what
do they get? Bling?
And come-ons for shit they
don't need and can't afford?
You're all over the place. I don't
know what you're trying to say.
He's saying the framus
intersects with ramistan
Approximately
at the paternoster.
Julius, what do I
have to do?
What do I have to say
to get you out of here?
Give me a chance.
Give me first dibs at this-
This television series
thing, or whatever it is.
Let me do the
pilot, please.
Julius, my boy,
sit down.
Julius, I'm not a hard man.
I'm not a mean man...
Tell you right now,
it's light.
...But the television industry
today is looking for talent.
They're looking
for quality.
They're preoccupied
with talent and quality,
And a writer is
a major commodity.
You know, this situation
ain't all bad.
I haven't had a green
vegetable in over a week.
We can't even go down
to the pork store?
- we gotta hang around here all day doing nothing.
- baciagalup.
- Who does he belong to?
- He just showed up during the big storm.
Already caught a mouse
down the cellar.
A lot of my customers giving
their action to New York.
Power vacuum,
they're taking advantage.
Oh.
- the fuck you come in that way for?
- sorry.
We're gonna meet Paulie
down at the hospital,
Visit Sil.
You wanna come?
Nah, I got...
Shit I gotta do.
My daughter...
...Scratching plaintively on a closed door.
Mr. Julius moomer,
a would-be writer...
Yesterday it was
his gout.
This is New York's famous little Italy.
It once covered over
40 square blocks
But has now been reduced to
one row of shops and cafes.
Hello.
It's me.
Where are you?
Are you close?
Let's do it over the phone.
No word yet.
No one knows
where our friend is.
It's not that there's no word,
it's that there's no progress.
Nobody's taking
this lightly, Phil.
He should have been
done first.
They thought they'd find
them both at the strip joint.
I've heard this
already.
I know you're
disappointed, Phil.
I can hear it
in everything you say.
Fuckin'- a
I'm disappointed.
I'm thinking.
- Come on in, check it out.
- I don't know.
- maybe...
- what?
Are you talking
about reaching out?
We can't go back. Are you
out of your fucking mi?
- no, I know.
- then what did you say it for?
I didn't, Phil.
You did.
Listen, kid,
When this is over
we're gonna sit down,
- me and you.
- I hope so.
I can't hear you.
You're breaking up.
I said I hope-
"ferrara's. "
- want a pastry?
- I need to watch my weight.
I need to snag
another husband.
You're the only one
who realized that's a joke.
You had to grow up
in our family.
That dig you made about me giving
guys head under the boardwalk?
He took it so seriously,
Bobby.
Anyway,
Thank you
for being here.
So what happens now?
Well, robert's already said he
wants to go live with his aunt.
- what about sophia?
- nica is my daughter.
She's very much
into her older sister.
Sophia's out of her mind if she
thinks she's getting out of this house.
Is that a joke? 'cause
that one even got by me.
You know,
five, six years ago
When johnny sack bought this house,
This was all
cornfields here.
I'd like to give it
a shot with Bobby's kids.
Bobby would want it.
I put in a lot of effort
with sophia-
Baking together... I think
we actually have a bond.
I've had therapy.
I'm a good mother.
I put ma and all her
warped shit behind me.
Good.
Not that I get
any thanks for it.
You know you could form
a new nuclear family.
You bring
harpo down here...
It's a big place.
Harpo changed
his name.
He's hal now.
Janice...
Well, you need anything,
you know I'm minutes away.
- Yeah.
- Multiple calls
Traced back to a payphone
in oyster bay, long island.
What?
Oh. Oh, uh...
- where's the phone at exactly?
- gas station, most likely.
- gas station?
- he's lammed out.
He may not be able to put his
hands on a clean cell phone.
All right, listen, thanks. Really-
All right.
You kept telling me
this guy is good.
It's amazing it was written so long ago.
It's, like,
about right now.
This could be
a mistake.
I know.
We're good friends.
Yeah.
Oh, wait.
Holy shit.
Oh my god.
Go!
Oh, christ.
I parked in leaves!
Wow.
At least my gas tank
was practically empty.
How many fucking times
have I told you:
It's an S.U.V., watch
where you park off-road?
The catalytic converter
and the dry vegetation!
I didn't see
the leaves.
You can grill fucking
steaks on that converter!
I told you!
If there was children
playing in those leaves,
- you'd have run them over?
- I guess.
Oh, you're gonna
get cute now?
- I was just answering her question.
- dad, he wasn't being funny.
You mind your own goddamn business
unless you want some of this too.
- Mr. Fat mouth.
- What did you say?
What was going through your mind?
What do you want from me?
I am depressed.
I'm supposed to go around
looking for piles of leaves?
Wanna hear depressed?
$30,000 for that car.
Isn't that what
you have insurance for?
Excuse me? You're not
getting another one.
Actually, that's good.
It'll force me
to take the bus.
What?
We have to break our
dependence on foreign oil.
- Cafe Napoli.
- George, it's Anthony.
Your fucking ears must be ringing.
I just left your friend,
the son, crying the blues
Over the situation between
you and that outfit over there.
That's why I'm calling.
I need you to reach out
to the little guy.
He's not happy with Phil neither.
I know.
You're not part
of that family.
You're basically retired.
Everybody trusts you.
What I'm thinking, you'd supply
a neutral location,
Guarantee
everybody's safety.
I could do that.
- Hi, George.
- Hey.
They're here.
They've been patted down too.
Anybody want a water?
- no.
We started it?
We got a dead goomar
In queens and her
old ukrainian father.
And I'm not even
gonna blame Phil.
John sacramoni,
my friend,
I'm sorry to say,
was an insecure guy.
He created
a constant tension
Within his own family
which spilled over.
Go ahead, Carmine.
George was good enough
To broker this meeting for us.
You're just gonna sit there?
It didn't have
to be this way.
We agree.
It's gone too far.
Phil, I don't know-
he's changed.
You got my word:
we'll back off.
My price is you help us
get a location on Phil.
Uh, I can't go there.
But you do
what you gotta do.
One more thing:
you hit my brother-in-law.
- so?
- this is my sister
We're talking about.
She's gotta see
something out of this.
We'll come up
with a number.
Look at all this mail.
Anybody need
some barber's scissors?
- ton'?
- put some next to my coat.
He was at the safe house.
We brought him over.
Get him the fuck out.
These are snakes
with fur.
The old italians
will tell you-
You can't even
put them around a baby.
They suck the breath
right out.
Well, you're the only baby
here, so we're ahead of the game.
You wanna be wearing his
fucking pelt on your head?
- I said get rid of him.
- Leave him.
He's a good guy.
No payphone.
...Daughter gloria on the tv series...
Look, there's
a double-breasted robin.
It doesn't cost anything to be polite.
That goes two ways, ma'am.
...Series "maude"?
- Arthur?
- Yes, Bea Arthur.
Beatrice Arthur.
Put an x in the center
box. $300 to the pot.
And we shuffle the
categories around again.
Pat, how are you?
- hi.
- livia.
I'm Janice,
her daughter.
What did he say?
I can't-
Uncle jun',
I wanna show you
something.
Bobby and my baby.
- Janice.
- no, I'm Janice.
That's my little girl.
Her name is domenica.
Sweet as she looks, she
left my stove on on purpose,
Put the flame out
with a wet dishrag.
I caught her.
Uncle jun',
I'm afraid
I have bad news.
Bobby's dead.
The ambassador hotel.
Your Bobby,
Bobby baccalieri.
I'm a widow now.
She was inveigling him.
She's after his money.
You're not even
curious about him?
He can fucking rot.
When you were
an inpatient,
You said you might try
and get a job.
I can't now
because of the car.
I need to get
a bus schedule.
The thing is,
Ever since it blew up
I feel, like...
Cleansed or something.
Because...
It was a polluter?
No.
I mean,
just watching it go,
That huge fireball-
You have no idea.
The heat-
My seat melted.
I had been in it
just a few seconds before.
Carlo.
Yeah.
T, I had a meeting down
here with Carlo this morning.
We were supposed to go see butch
and them on a couple of items.
Carlo didn't show.
And he don't answer
his phones neither.
I'll call you back
on the prepay.
Yeah.
- what are you thinking?
- that maybe we were had.
That this fucking butch has
taken out another ranking guy.
T?
What if he flipped?
- who? Carlo?
- well?
- you there?
- his kid, the imbecile-
- Jason?
- he got picked up yesterday,
Patsy told me,
for selling ecstasy.
Mead', they're gonna
be here in-
Miss Hunter!
Long time no see.
How are you,
mrs. Soprano?
Oh my god,
when was it?
It was right around
when you quit college.
You're being kind. I was kicked
out for partying and drunk driving.
Well, I didn't want
to say, but...
Well, that was
always you.
So what are you
up to now?
I'm in my second year
of med school.
- oh.
- yeah.
I completed undergrad
at purchase,
Got my act together.
Yes. They're gonna
be here, Meadow.
A man took his horse
to a vet
And the vet says to him,
"why do you have a long face?"
"a horse goes. "
there's no man.
Right right.
A horse goes to a vet.
And the vet looks at his
face and he says to him,
- "my friend-" - a
horse goes to the doctor.
The doctor says,
"why the long face?"
Can't tell jokes.
- more pinot grig', Patrick?
- no, thanks.
Speaking of jokers, where's
that other son of yours today?
I didn't think
he was invited.
I just thought with all the
wedding talk, you know...
No no, really, that pal
of his, the other Jason-
I heard he ran
into some trouble,
- Carlo's Jason.
- he's a mess.
All right.
Well, he's got
no shortage of lawyers here.
Ton', patsy needs
a refill.
- no, ton', I'll-
- sit down.
Of course, this one here would
only take the case for free.
That's why we want her over
at Grubman, Grubman & Curcio.
Actually, Mead' and I
have had some conversations
And we may still snag her
over at the firm
- when she's done with law school.
- no kidding?
We went out to dinner with steven
grubman and the subject came up.
Steven was very impressed with
her work at the poverty law center.
He even got into starting
salaries. He was talking $170.
Jesus. Sweetheart,
that's fantastic, huh?
He had had
too much gevrey.
Don't devalue yourself.
We've got a really
interesting case right now.
We're defending
James Trefoglio,
The county commissioner,
on those corruption charges.
Is that your case,
honey?
Bid rigging.
It's got bagmen, whores.
It's fascinating.
Yeah, he does that,
Sometimes most of the day
- just stares at chrissy's picture.
The fuck?
You know,
they're funny that way.
I had an aunt,
her cat would only sit
At the exact corners of
the table, staring at her,
Or at the intersection
of two walls, staring in.
This fucking animal
is history, today!
- pick him up.
- you pick him up.
T, you see
this shit?
Does it all the time,
he says.
- oh yeah?
- look at him staring at that dead kid.
Gives me
the fucking creeps.
Walden, give us
some privacy.
Yeah.
Walden
- the fuck kind of name is that for an italian?
I was named
after mr. Bobby Darin-
Walden Robert Cassotto.
Heh.
The Cifaretto crew
- it's a fucking chinese fire drill over there,
Especially now that
Carlo is absent.
I know.
I want you
to skipper that thing.
- really?
- fucking thing is one big ATM machine.
All our construction with New
York folds right into your kick.
Yeah.
Jesus christ,
I thought you'd be pleased.
I didn't hand you
the diagnosis of the clap.
With due respect, I'd like
to just mull it a little.
I'm no spring chicken
no more.
I don't want to have me dying on you,
leaving you worse off than before.
Oh, you with
the dead thing.
You got the arms and upper
body of a 20-year-old.
I gotta work at that.
And I had the prostate.
All right, sure.
Go ahead.
I'm a little miffled,
but yeah, sit with it.
Thanks, T.
This means everything,
Your faith in me.
In the line of duty.
But we're short-handed.
Anyway, mid-60s,
Probably used
the payphones.
We don't have payphones. Just a
couple of stations have them anymore.
Get in.
Activity-
that's good.
I can already
see a difference.
Yeah.
Gonna get
back at it myself.
Listen...
I'm gonna join the army.
What?
Did you sign any shit?
No, but this week
I will.
I gotta deal
with rhiannon first.
Rhiannon?
What about your mother?
- her too.
- are you nuts?
You wanna get sent
to Iraq?
Afghanistan.
The army's probably
good for my career.
You don't have
a career.
Right.
My ultimate goal is
to qualify for
helicopter pilot training,
Afterwards go to work
for trump or somebody,
Be their personal pilot.
I'm not even gonna tell
your mother about this.
And don't you
do nothing
Until we've had
another chance to talk.
- you hear me?
- yes.
He's gonna join
the fucking army.
I gotta be frank,
You people got him out
of his room- great-
So he can be
cannon fodder?
I wasn't aware
of this latest plan.
Sorry.
I should have gone
before we left the house.
Still on the army thing.
On the other hand, I'm
thinking maybe he could benefit
From the training,
the discipline.
Maybe the army'd be
great for him
If there wasn't
a war going on.
Oh, I didn't tell you,
he spent $200
On a set of cds
that teach arabic.
Jesus Christ, come on. "shish kebab"
- what else do you need to know?
He used to just veg
in front of that tv.
He says he wants
to get past the hate,
Focus it only
on the terrorists.
I really can't
reveal much more.
Right.
Even though we're paying.
This whole therapy thing,
I gotta tell you-
What?
My mother was
a borderline personality.
So what?
- I don't know if you knew that.
- no.
Well, I did not have
a very happy childhood.
No?
There was little love
in the house.
He's mentioned your mother
very briefly.
A very difficult woman,
Undermining.
I tried to place her
in a retirement community
For her own good-
She turned on me
completely.
You see, I never could
please my ther.
To what do I owe this
chance to go sake bombing?
We used to have dinner
all the time.
You're gonna get married and
my chances are flying by me.
- yeah.
- so, your brother,
Our little soldier boy-
What do you think is wrong
with that googootz?
The world is
a sad, fucked-up place.
If there's so much
suffering in the world,
- why did you go off the pediatrician bit?
- we talked about that.
You said you wanted to be
a lawyer for black people.
Oh, that's all I said?
Really?
What I said was: the state
can crush the individual.
- New Jersey?
- the government.
Specifically,
the federal government.
And what about
little babies
In the face
of meningitis?
You know what really
turned me?
Seeing the way
italians are treated.
It's like mom says. And if we can
have our rights trampled like that,
Imagine what it's like
for recent arrivals.
- well...
- if I hadn't seen you
Dragged away all those times by the fbi
Then I'd probably be
a boring suburban doctor.
Bye-bye.
Wave "bye-bye, grandpa. "
- bye-bye, pop-pop.
- say "bye-bye. "
- bye-bye.
I gotta make
a phone call.
I'll meet you
at the drugstore.
Tell the goddamn pharmacist
to call dr. laconis.
I should get a 60-day
supply of the plavix.
Phil! Phil!
Oh my god!
Phil!
Help!
Help me!
Oh my god!
My babies!
Somebody help!
Help me!
The babies!
- somebody help me!
- okay, okay.
Help me, please!
Oh, god, they're
locked in there!
- oh!
- oh shit!
- seen metro news?
- no.
Your old beat.
Phil Leotardo got popped.
Damn. We're gonna win this thing.
Okay...
As your parents
we don't feel
Joining the army
is in your best interest.
This country is
in a crisis.
How can one soldier
stop it?
When my enlistment's up,
I could join
the CIA or something.
And with a military
background I'll have a leg up.
And as an arabic speaker,
I'll be really useful.
I don't understand.
You're gonna ask the donald
For some time off from your
pilot job to go on CIA missions?
- everything's a joke to you.
- I'm not having a good time.
Did you or did you not want
me to go to military school?
But I started to cry.
At least you'd have
come out an officer.
Even then
I was opposed to it.
I hate this idea.
I'm applying for
officer's candidate school.
I want to be
a liaison officer
With the local
population anyway.
Officer's candidate school?
You have terrible grades.
You flunked out of college.
Here we go. That's all
this is about, right?
No, Anthony, that's not
what this is all about.
You don't want to go to college
- don't go to college,
- but don't get your legs blown off.
- always with the drama.
So what does your girlfriend
say, the fashion model?
She doesn't think
I should go either.
Well?
Not that long ago you
talked about owning a club.
Right. You had a problem with that too.
A lot of your friends are
in film school, you say,
Especially the ones you
used to go to the clubs with.
Uh...
So I got this screenplay
from danny baldwin.
We met at your
cousin's movie.
Danny hoped I'd set him
up with some financing,
- but I never read it.
- well, you did now.
Yeah, I did now and...
Well, long story short, it's
about a private detective
That gets sucked into the internet
through his, uh, data port.
And he's gotta solve
Some murders and some
virtual prostitutes.
I read it.
It's scary.
Point is, I talked
to little Carmine
And he's interested in
developing it through his company.
He does porn.
He did "cleaver. "
he's branching out.
You would work for his producer, Inge.
You would be-
what is the word-
Development executive
on this project.
Really?
What's this gotta do
with clubs?
Hollywood and gossip
columns, the nightspots...
And you get some real-world
experience under your belt,
You come see me
and we will talk
About me investing
in a club.
Run that past rahoony,
see what she says.
Somebody's giving grand
jury testimony on something.
- so Carlo has flipped.
- we don't know.
And subpoenas are flying.
My hunch-
80 to 90% chance
you'll be indicted.
That fucking
gun charge-
I get sick
when I think of it-
Plus interstate fraud and if
Carlo starts talking, homicide-
Give me
the fucking thing.
Not like we haven't
envisioned this day.
No no, it's not.
Look, trials are there
to be won.
...Easiest omelet ever.
In 10 seconds you can
open a can of instant soup
Or you can make homemade
soup from scratch,
Ready to eat
and serve!
In 10 seconds
you can begin
Grating cheese
for a snack
Or you can grate cheese,
shred chicken,
Chop onions and peppers
to make a zesty filling
That you can
heat and serve
For hot delicious quesadillas
the whole family will love-
All three
ready to heat and serve...
- oh.
- ... All in 10 seconds or less
With the original
magic bullet-
The versatile personal
countertop magician
That does any job
in 10 seconds or less.
Now you can do
small everyday jobs
Like chopping
garlic or onions
Without the sticky, smelly
mess in just three seconds.
Grate cheese
in just four seconds.
Then screw on
the handy shaker top
And sprinkle
onto pasta or pizza.
Or turn ice, coffee,
milk and chocolate syrup
Into a fancy frozen
coffee drink in just se-
Oh my gosh,
I won, I won, I won, I won!
So?
With all due respect, and I mean
that from the bottom of my heart,
- I'm gonna pass.
- I don't fucking believe this.
- why?
- every guy who ran that crew died prematurely.
- aw, come on.
- I beat cancer once.
You've got no idea
what that does to you.
Yeah, I know,
but jesus-
Richie aprile, ralphie m. I.A.; Vito,
And who knows what the
fuck with Carlo, gigi-
Gigi died
taking a shit.
Doesn't mean it's not
part of an overall pattern.
Paulie, are you gonna deny
yourself life-changing money,
A package to leave your
niece who has m. S.?
It's like your bullshit
with the cat.
The fucking animal
catches mice for us,
- but you'd drown it.
- I would.
He's not looking
at christopher.
A rat died in the wall
back there or some shit.
I moved the picture.
The fucking thing
Came to the new spot
and stared!
It's the abstract shapes
or something.
Tell you this:
Since he's dead,
My gambling luck's
done a 180.
Oh, okay.
It's fine for you
to believe that shit,
But I can't
worry about a jinx?
Ton', I never told this to
another living soul, but...
Yeah?
One time at the bing,
I was alone to meet
eddy lind-
I saw the virgin mary.
Why didn't you
say something?
Fuck strippers,
we coulda had a shrine,
Sold holy water
in gallon jugs.
Coulda made billions.
I tell you something deep in
my heart and you laugh it off?
I'm not saying there's
nothing out there, Paulie,
But to not live your life?
What the fuck are you gonna do?
You don't want the job-
you don't want the job.
I can put patsy in there.
He's gonna be
part of my family now.
It'd be good.
Prick.
You always know what
to say to me, don't you?
No, I'm serious.
I live but to serve you,
my liege.
Well, they had to
get it for me.
There's no real
public transport out here.
But I said no more suv.
Well, that's
the cool part-
23 highway.
It's not so bad.
Hey.
Oh, listen, we're not
eating at home tonight.
I thought we'd go
to holsten's.
You said we have
manigott'.
I got meetings
with carpenters.
Holsten's is
the consensus.
I gotta see some people.
I'll meet you there.
- Carter?
- That's correct.
And you win $400.
Your spin, marcia.
- joker, africa and quotations.
- sir.
I'll take quotations for 100, please.
Sir, sir,
excuse me.
...Explained his humor this way:
"all I know is just
what I read-" where?
"in the papers. "
That's right. You have $200.
- your spin, ron.
- okay, thank you, jack.
Law enforcement,
quotations and a joker.
Let's take quotations for 100, Jack.
The correct answer will bring you $500...
- hello.
- what, you don't recognize me?
We used to play catch.
You don't remember
that you shot me?
Enough with
the fucking birds.
I'm Anthony,
johnny's son.
Fuck you want,
a boutonniere?
All right, listen to me.
Uncle pat came to see me
About Janice,
about your money.
People keep asking me.
I don't know.
There's a man from another
galaxy that came here.
That's your accountant.
I'm confused!
Any money should go
to Bobby bacala's kids.
Now Janice may not do that,
but Bobby was with us.
He's a made guy.
Wouldn't be right.
Me, I never had kids.
You remember where your stash
is, you let uncle pat know.
Me as the head
of the family,
I'll hold on to it as a
guardian, for Bobby's kids.
- you remember Bobby?
- sure.
You don't know
who I am, do you?
Remember johnny-
johnny boy,
Your kid brother?
"this thing of ours. "
I was involved with that?
You and my dad.
You two ran north Jersey.
- we did?
- yeah.
Hmm.
Well, that's nice.
- hey.
- what looks good tonight?
- eh, I don't know.
Where's googootz?
He just called.
He's on his way.
Mead's coming separately.
She had to go to the doctor,
Switch birth control.
Did you talk
to mink again?
It's Carlo.
He's gonna testify.
Mmm, onion rings.
Best in the state
as far as I'm concerned.
Shit.
How was work today?
All I'm doing is getting coffee
and placing endless phone calls.
You may not realize it
but you are making contacts.
It's an entry-level job.
So buck up.
Right, focus
on the good times.
Don't be sarcastic.
Isn't that what
you said one time-
"try to remember the times
that were good"?
- I did?
- yeah.
Well, it's true,
I guess.
I went ahead and ordered
some for the table.