Frankie, where are you?
Welcome to the chop shop,
Cugine.
You can't kill
me twice, Sally boy.
I'm already fucking
dead, remember?
I'm the boss, Michael.
What you had belongs to me.
Even the girl I loved?
What's mine is mine.
What's yours is mine.
Well...
This is mine too, Sally.
Now you can have it.
Vaffancul'.
Fuck Ben Kingsley.
Danny Baldwin took him
to fucking acting school.
Very well directed, Morgan.
I Think there's potentially more money
in this than in the porn we've done.
So what do we think?
We need the extra scene or not?
I like it the way it is.
I don't know, Rissy,
these audiences today love blood.
I tend to agree with Carlo.
I'm thinking
one more sexy kill.
When Michael follows
Centrella to the strip club,
What if he chops up one
of the women?
Who as fate would have it,
Was at one time
Sally boy's mistress.
Two extra shoot days,
at a minimum.
- Kid, if it buys us a bullshit
theatrical release-
I'm gonna have to get
more money from Tony.
I want this fucking thing
out there.
Yeah, T, what's up?
You talked to the guy
with the air mattresses?
I'm in editing. We just
saw the cut of "cleaver. "
- And?
- Awesome as is.
The lawyer called, though. We
might have to change the title.
The Eldridge Cleaver estate,
they with an injunction.
Listen, if you wanna see some of it,
we're finishing the ADR after lunch.
- What's that again?
- Sound dubbing.
Just call this dispatcher.
It's a holiday weekend.
Thousands of people will
be out at the beach.
I'm on it.
- He coming down?
- Please.
He don't give two shits
about production.
Mr. Sacrimoni,
how are you today?
Isn't that for you
to tell me?
I wish I had
better news.
Based on the latest pictures,
The cancer has continued to
metastasize from the lungs.
We now show masses in the
mediastinal lymph nodes,
Both kidneys
and the brain.
The headaches.
So the...
Lobectomy, radiation,
The goddamn chemo,
What was all that?
for kicks?
Those were our options
at the time.
And now what are
our options?
Limited to the extent that
I wouldn't recommend any.
At this point, we're looking at stage
four small cell carcinoma of the lungs.
- And there's no stage five.
- That's correct.
How long?
Difficult to say.
- I have seen miracles over the years.
- Forget the miracles.
Three months.
Give or take.
Thank you
for your candor.
We have a plane
back to Springfield.
How you doing, John?
It's funny-
ironic- whichever.
I got here.
I quit smoking
after 38 years,
Exercised, ate right.
And for what?
Even still,
It was the right move.
Oh, there she is, my girl.
How are you, sweetie?
- Hey, dad.
- Hi.
What did Rosen say?
- How's the hotel? You all settled in?
- It's fine.
- How are you, angel? You look beautiful.
- I'm good.
- Eric sends his love.
- That's nice.
John, what about Rosen?
I don't know. I...
I don't know, sweetie.
- I'm very very sick.
- Oh my god.
All right, don't cry.
Don't cry. You don't have to make
it any harder than it is, all right?
No physical contact,
please.
- I Love you, John.
- I Love you, too.
- Daddy.
- I Know. I Know.
Ladies, no contact.
All right.
You come back,
you see me again tomorrow.
We have more time, huh?
Could I bum one of those?
It's casual, though, right?
It's your cousin's movie premiere.
We should dress accordingly.
It's what they call
a cast-and-crew screening.
It's in the city, Tony,
With an after-party
at some rooftop bar
In the meat-packing district.
That place is very chic now.
Meat packers?
I'm a happily married man.
I'm telling you it's not dress up.
Speaking of dress up, Christopher told me
Kelli is having her wedding
dress made into an outfit
- For the baby to be christened in.
- Oh, sweet.
You all right?
Are you taking a date
to the screening?
If I can meet
a normal guy, maybe.
I heard that
What, Finn wasn't normal?
I don't intend
to discuss Finn.
What about that guy
in your mcat review?
Please, he's completely
fixated his O-Chem final.
He wants to be a doctor.
Tell him it's educational.
There's body parts
all over this movie.
Hey, screw the movie. I
Just wanna hang with celebs.
Why, you think you're gonna
get to sleep with Paris Hilton?
What? No.
Stop fidgeting
and eat your noodles.
- I don't want them.
- Where are you going?
The bathroom.
Jesus.
- Meow.
- You two have a fight?
I don't know.
Keep an eye on his temp, and we'll
finish out the week on the ceftin.
You rest now. I'll
see you in the morning.
- He should be on heparin.
- Excuse me.
Listen to him.
Check his ABG.
I'm gonna have to ask you
again to not interfere, Warren.
I'm gonna change your sheets.
So what are you,
The world's smartest orderly?
These days I am.
22 years a
practicing oncologist,
Specializing
in cancers of the liver.
Roll to your right,
please.
Let me spare us
the awkwardness.
I killed my wife.
Not that it's
any justification,
I had reason to suspect
She was cheating on me
with her chiropractor.
- Jesus.
- Granted, I was abusing cocaine at the time,
And alcohol.
But I came home one day
Shot her four times-
twice in the head.
I killed her aunt, too.
I didn't know she was there.
Roll over, please.
And the mailman.
At that point,
I had to fully commit.
Why are you here exactly?
I'Ve been accused
of being part
Of a certain
italian-american subculture.
hey, I know who you are.
I meant,
what's wrong with you?
Oh.
- Lungs.
- I'Ve been wanting to meet you, actually.
I saw you on Bill Curtis.
- Warren Feldman.
- John sacrimoni.
Good to know you.
- I take it you done chemo, huh?
- Twice.
Mind if I take a look
at your chart?
What about Gunga Din?
Gupte? Fuck him.
Oh, you're seeing Rosen.
They let me fly
to cleveland, my expense.
- You know him?
- I saw him speak once
At an ASCO conference
in Georgia.
- Good man.
- But...
Actually, very few
people know this,
But he really can't walk
on water.
What was his prognosis?
Three months.
- With the treatment you've had?
- What do you mean?
You got a window
of one to three years.
What about the metastases?
Two rounds of paraplatin,
Docetaxel and platinol
Concurrent with radiation?
Come on, any cancer inside
you has slowed to a crawl.
Why is he so
fucking negative?
We tell the patient three months. He
lives a year. Who looks like a hero?
I'll see you around, John. You
take it easy. Hang in there.
Fuck me.
Tony, morning.
You got a sec?
As I told you,
my partner and I are
With the joint terror
task force now.
You're around Port Newark
often enough.
We're concerned about what might come
through there from the middle east.
Yeah, and...
Let's talk terror funding.
Most of it comes about
through illegal enterprise.
Our pitch is this, and it's the
same we gave Christopher Moltisanti-
If he never
mentioned it:
If you or any of your people
ever heard of anything going down,
Middle easterners,
pakistanis,
You'd be helping us a lot
if you let us know.
I Think there's
a word for that.
Your daughter takes
pre-med classes in New York.
She use the tunnels?
Just something
to keep in mind.
That's the last time I'm
going down for the paper.
You tell that fucking
polack to get here earlier
And bring up the paper with her
Or she can go clean somebody
else's fucking toilets.
What happened?
It's too dangerous.
Has been for years.
May I have your
attention, please?
Welcome to the premiere
of "cleaver,"
The story of a young man
who goes to pieces
Then manages
to find himself again.
In all seriousness, however,
I'd like to say a few words.
Much like a child,
a film has many parents,
That is to say
many individuals
Who act like parents,
Or that by aversion,
The film is their baby.
I, as an executive producer,
Am one of those individuals.
Two more examples
are here with me tonight.
Ladies and gentlemen, my
Co-E.P. Christopher Moltisanti
And our director
Morgan Yam.
Yeah, hey!
I Know you're all psyched
to see the movie,
So I'm not gonna give
a big speech here.
I Just wanna give a shout out
To the man who without him
This whole thing would be
impossible. Where is he?
Anthony Soprano, everybody.
- Hey!
- All right, Ton'!
Once he came on board,
the whole thing fell together.
And all the other
investors, too.
Plus my wife Kelli and our
new baby. I Love you guys.
Okay, then. Cell phones off
And hope you
like the movie.
You don't know what?
He's a fucking rat!
- But we can't really prove it.
- You're gonna argue with me?
No, it's just, I mean,
he's practically like your own son.
I'm sorry, Sally. I think
we oughta give him a pass.
I didn't ask you
what you fucking think.
Motherfucking
son of a...
- That's you.
- No.
- It is.
- You find where this pezzonovante is
And you bring him
to the butcher shop.
They're gonna find pieces of this
kid all over fucking canarsie.
- Yeah.
- I'm sure he's fine, sweetie. You gotta relax.
But for Michael not to have called
and the wedding's in two days.
Who, the guatemalan?
What time is he gonna be there?
I hate to say this, but the truth
is he ain't good enough for you.
I mean, he's a good kid.
What you need is a man.
Tell him to put it in the trunk
Shh!
You know how long I've
been waiting to do that?
Dad, that was neat at the end, the
creepy figurine and the crucifix.
I'm glad you caught that,
Alexandra. Very observant.
The sacred and the propane.
There's a ton of people wearing
t- shirts here. I told you.
Is it so horrible
you look nice?
I'm starving. I need to
eat something already.
I asked if you wanted popcorn.
- You want me to make you a plate?
- Yeah.
- What?
- What? I'll give you what.
Come here. The fucking
boss down in the cellar,
White bathrobe-
where'd you get that?
I don't know.
Artistic choice.
Seriously though,
I'm very proud.
Whatever else happens,
you made a movie, Christopher.
Nobody could
take that away.
A hundred years from now,
we're dead and gone,
People will be watching
this fucking thing.
You know how much Imperia
vodka I scored just
From this
party alone?
I had a couple of cases
put down in your car, too.
Look at this-
the family of early man.
Great, thank you.
Hey, Danny, come here.
Take a picture
with us. Phil Leotardo.
Larry and I hung out at the set.
I don't know if you know this,
But the actors, they don't
make up what they say.
- It's true. Even De Niro, the girl told me.
- The script girl.
- Lorenzo Barese.
- Hey, how you doing, my friend?
You getting enough to eat?
Bryan Rawley,
u. s. Marshal's service.
Terms of your bail confine
you to your home, sir.
- Say hello to Danny?
- Yeah.
- Larry!
- Call the fucking lawyer!
- Excuse us, excuse us.
- Leave him alone, you bastard!
Jesus Christ.
There's Danny's manager.
I Better go talk to him.
There he is.
So how was Florida?
Hot and sticky,
like my balls.
I spoke to Ginny.
She's a wreck.
John's in the cancer ward.
She's down the road
in some fucking motel.
Poor prick.
Prison's not bad enough,
fucking lung cancer to boot.
Tell me about it-
quintuple bypass,
Then the infection,
Seven months
of physical thery.
I'm just now starting
to get back to myself again.
Sausage, cioppino,
anything spicy
Put me back in the emergency
room, I'm not careful.
All in all,
we're lucky fucks.
I tell myself that
every day.
So now you're back. How about
you straighten that family out?
Not for me, Anthony.
Obviously, healthwise, being
a boss is a young man's game.
Between the joint fitters
and the carpenters,
Those envelopes are light
er 10% each week.
I feel it, too.
Well, word on the street is
Gerry's the favorite to take over.
He's my protege.
I don't stand in his way.
There's a ringing endorsement.
- Hey, Tony.
- Doc, Doc.
- You know Danny, huh?
- How you doing, Mr. Soprano?
Got a ticket on the Jersey turnpike.
Broken windshield wiper.
I said he should talk to you.
- I'll take care of it.
- That's not necessary.
- Let's take a picture here.
- All right, chill out, Doc.
If you're Phil Leotardo you cannot be happy
With the state of affairs,
despite appearances.
We're joined now via satellite
from Bainbridge Island, Washington,
By Jerry's fellow
mob expert Manny Safier,
The author of the new book
"The Wise Guide to Wiseguys. "
Manny, welcome to the program.
How goes the book tour?
Thank you, Geraldo.
Excellent.
- Jerry, how are you?
- Manny.
So we're discussing the apparent mob
power vacuum here in New York city.
Are you shocked that there's still
no successor to John Sacrimoni?
Not really.
I Mean, the last 10, 12 years,
That's been
a dysfunctional family.
And as Jerry said earlier, there
are several viable candidates.
Well, viable,
I don't know.
You had Phil Leotardo
as the logical successor.
You also have
Gerardo "Gerry" Torciano,
Also Faustino "Doc" Santoro,
who I believe is the frontrunner.
I'm surprised you haven't
mentioned Carmine Lupertazzi, jr.
I Was about to, Manny,
before you interrupted.
In fact, if you take a
look at my book in chapter 14...
This Santoro thing,
I called it a year ago.
Hey.
Thank you for coming, Anthony.
I Know it's a long trip.
What, and miss a chance
to see Missouri?
So how's Jenny today?
She went with Allegra to buy
some stuff for the kitchenette.
Oh, good,
clear her mind.
Reason I asked
you here today,
She's a bright kid,
your sister.
But business...
My life insurance,
I Want to put her
on a monthly stipend.
Probably a good idea.
Not all the doctors agree,
But if I do only
have a few months,
I Wanna take care
of all this now.
Wait a second.
Which doctor doesn't agree?
Feldman, the guy
I told you about.
- The wife murderer?
- He's still a doctor, Anthony.
He was a highly-respected
oncologist.
I Know, but, John-
He reviewed my case.
He says I could
hang on for years.
You're right. He still
has the knowledge.
I mean, O.J. is no less
of a running back, right?
Let me ask you
something, Anthony:
How will I be remembered?
A wonderful husband.
A loving father.
On the street,
though, I mean.
From what I know,
you were well-liked, John.
Respected across the board,
despite the allocution even.
God knows, guys have
actually named names
For a hell of a lot less than
what you were looking at.
The only nega-
What?
When Carmine died
and you took over,
People felt you changed,
Became a little
trigger-happy, maybe-
A hothead.
God forbid
Any of them
would find themselves
In that position.
It's a thankless job.
- What are you, hungover?
- What? I had two glasses of wine.
Why are you so pissy?
- The portrayal of that guy in the movie.
- What guy?
- The boss, Tony.
- What about him?
It was based on you.
Yeah, I know,
you said the yelling.
It wasn't just the yelling.
Imitation's a form of flattery.
- You think that was flattering?
- It was okay.
He's a tough prick, that Baldwin.
What about the girlfriend?
- What girlfriend?
- The cleaver guy.
The lead character.
His entire motive for revenge.
I don't know.
You lost me, Carm.
Sally boy, the boss,
he fucked the guy's fiancee.
The thing with Adriana?
I told you it never
fucking happened.
Well, apparently,
your nephew feels otherwise.
Ro pointed it out to me, but if she
saw it, that means other people did.
It's a movie.
It's fictional.
It's a revenge fantasy, Tony,
Which ends with the boss's head
split open by a meat cleaver.
Oh, there he is.
Good time last night?
Yeah, it was all right.
How about you?
Gab had fucking nightmares.
- Club soda, hon.
- Sure.
So what did you think
of the movie?
Chrissy's the last person I
would have confused with Marty,
But I gotta say,
it wasn't bad.
- Is he around?
- Chrissy? Nah.
He don't come around here
no more, you know that.
That Baldwin was
pretty good, huh?
He was a mean fuck.
I'll give him that.
And that girl that played
the fiancee, she was hot,
The one he was fucking.
It's weird how it works,
the creative process.
I'm watching that movie
"Edward Scissorhands,"
When boom, all of a sudden,
it hits me.
What if instead of a pair of
scissors, it's a meat cleaver instead?
A couple years later,
you got a movie.
Originally, I thought a ball-peen
hammer, but a cleaver's better.
I tell ya, man, it's like
I'm living somebody else's life.
You're just not comfortable
with success yet.
I Know. It's scary.
Feel the fear and do it anyway.
Without chemicals, either.
So Kelli, the baby.
Good, fucking great.
She's a doll.
She cries a lot, though.
The baby, not Kelli.
I Hope you're taking the time
To reflect on all this.
Savor the good stuff.
Yeah- no, I am.
There's my other sober buddy.
- Is that an FBI guy?
- Your tax dollars at work.
Does he follow you
around all the time?
They drop in and out.
It's fun.
Look, seriously, think where
you were just three months ago.
You came into that meeting. yo were
so fucked up you could barely talk.
And that woman friend
was even worse.
I'Ve been trying
to do what you said-
Hold back a little, steer clear
of old habits, same people.
Must be hard, though,
given your lifestyle.
They already misinterpret, I
don't wanna hang around so much.
Fucking Paulie especially
Have you explained how hard
it is to be around alcohol?
- How familiar surroundings set it off?
- They don't give a fuck.
"But he's fucking my wife,
Carmine. I want him dead,"
Jimmy says.
"He will be," he said,
"but not just right now.
He earns too much. "
Eight years later,
Jimmy gets a call one day.
"Remember that guy who
we were talking about
Who's fucking your wife?
He can go. "
The guy wasn't making
him money no more.
And that was
Carmine Lupertazzi.
- Holy fucking shit.
- Yeah.
There you are.
We went-
John, what the hell
are you doing?
- What?
- You're smoking.
- So?
- Daddy, you're on oxygen.
Warren, pardon me, I'm sorry.
Just calm down, all right?
Calm down?
I don't fucking believe you.
what do I got to lose, Gin?
What's the difference?
You told me dr. Feldman
doesn't agree with the others.
- Yeah, well.
- Miracles do happen, John.
Not to this family
they don't.
It's that kind of attitude that probably
brought this on in the first place.
You're gonna start
with that again?
What about all these
six-year-olds with leukemia?
What's that from,
all their negative thinking?
All due respect,
he's a great guy, Doc,
But boss material?
Important thing's
we all work together,
Whoever winds up
in the driver's seat.
Phil, though,
I'll never get it.
The man was my mentor. It was
right there for the taking.
His heart, Gerry.
What was he gonna do?
That's my point, though,
what you just said.
Johnny goes away. It's Phil's
turn in the driver's seat,
And his heart gives out.
- Right.
- his heart.
I Know, what?
It's a metaphor. He lost
his balls is what I'm saying.
Just say it then.
Walt fucking Whitman over here.
- Ladies.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Should we get some more wine?
This fucking waiter,
on sabbatical?
What's the name of that
sangiovese we had at Quattro Gatti?
The night your-
Come on!
Let's go.
Yeah, give me
five dimes a piece
On st. Louis,
Minnesota and Baltimore.
I Would have invited you to play,
but we already had our fourth.
You're not happy.
Let's order.
- What can I get you?
- Seared ahi, mixed greens
And an iced tea,
please.
Philly cheesesteak.
You know what? Give me an Arnold
Palmer instead of the iced tea.
- Okay.
- I Always enjoy those,
- But it never occurs to me to order one.
- What the fuck, Carmine?
This family of yours.
Fucking senile Doc Santoro uses
one of my guys as a diversion?
Sil could have got hurt.
Doc showed a lack of respect.
This fucking leadership, boy.
Step up, Carmine.
Get your hands around this thing.
You know you got the support.
You never thought you'd
mutter those words, did you?
What do you want me to say?
I hear you, Tony,
and I'm flattered.
But boss-
I don't think so,
Especially now that Doc
has cemented his position.
Phil was bad enough
in the top spot,
But him I could
have lived with.
Here you go.
There was a time I was
obsessed with being in charge.
- You remember?
- So do it.
One night around then
I had this dream.
It's my pop's 100th birthday, even
though he'd been dead for years.
The whole family's there-
grandkids, everybody.
He's wearing one of these
gold paper crowns,
Like at Burger King.
Anyway, I give him his present
This mellifluous box-
ribbons,
He opens it up
then looks at me.
This gaze of absolute
disappointment.
There's nothing in the box.
So he hands it back to me.
"Go fill it up," he says.
"Come back when I'm 200."
So go for it, Carmine.
Fulfill that part of yourself.
We have this ritual
at my house for years.
Our kids are
in boarding school.
Every night I come home from work,
I strip down, jump naked in the pool.
Nicole brings me
a scotch and water.
We sit,
relax a little talk.
I go up to bed,
the air conditioning.
She brings me a light
dinner on a tray.
One night during
all that fighting with John,
I Come home,
I'm exhausted.
So tired, so tense,
I skip the pool.
I go right upstairs,
flop on the bed.
Nicole comes up with a drink.
She says, "darling,
I think it's time
you took a rest. "
I say, "I'm gonna.
We're gonna take a vacation. "
She says,
"that's not what I meant.
I don't wanna be the
wealthiest widow on Long Island.
I Want you to quit now. "
I'm not ashamed to say
that she made me cry.
That wonderful loving woman.
That dream with my father,
the empty box-
It wasn't about being boss.
It was about being happy.
Warren, hi.
Hi, hon.
How's he doing?
Listen, I've been meaning to
talk to you about the smoking.
John shared with me
how upset you were.
Psychologically, when a
person's told they're dying,
It's the ultimate
loss of control.
To hear him wheeze
like that...
I Know.
It doesn't make any sense.
I do know he's a leader.
I suspect his smoking
on some level
Is an attempt
to die as he lived-
In total control.
Years ago, I asked him
to stop for me and the kids.
I lost 27 Ibs.
He couldn't quit smoking?
I gotta go.
Goodbye, Caitlin.
I'll see you soon, muffin.
Oh my god.
I love these little hands.
Thanks so much
for watching her.
You'd think we're planning a
coronation instead of a christening.
- We all set?
- You know what? I'd better pee.
Goody, I get
to keep holding you.
So how you doing? Tony said you
got an offer on the house you built.
Two, actually, yes.
Ivana Trump.
I gotta be honest. I am very
disappointed at what you did.
- What are you talking about?
- Your movie.
The boss sleeping with the
other guy's fiancee?
- What?
- Please, like that wasn't based on Tony and Ade.
What? No.
Carmela, I didn't
even write it.
Story by
Christopher Moltisanti.
Isn't that what it said
up there on the screen?
Yeah, but that's just for the
Writers Guild health insurance.
- Oh, really?
- Come on, you can't be serious.
She's an oriental,
for Christ sake.
Have you heard
from Ade lately?
No, why would I hear from her?
Would it be so surprising?
She left me for some other guy.
Is it any wonder?
Her poor mother is so upset,
she's practically delusional.
She's convinced herself
that Ade is dead.
Her mother's an alky.
You know that.
Regardless, Christopher.
You're my cousin,
and I love you, Carmela,
But I don't like what
you're inferring here,
Either with the movie
or how I treated Adriana.
Kelli comes out,
tell her I went to smoke.
There's my pal.
How you doing?
"Billy Bathgate. "
they had it in the library.
I thought of you.
I don't know if you heard,
but Gerry Torciano,
He was hit last week
in Brooklyn.
- Who?
- Gerry Torciano.
It was all over the news.
They whacked him
in some restaurant.
Did you know him?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Good guy.
It's hard to breathe.
I'll talk to Gupte,
See if I can get him
to up the beclovent.
I'm dying, aren't I?
It's not good.
I Won't lie to you.
The aggressiveness
surprises me.
I gotta concur with Rosen.
I Appreciate everything
you've done, Warren.
- Who is it?
- You don't answer your phone?
I shut the ringer.
It's the middle of the night.
Honey, what's wrong?
Nothing, sweetie, it's
fine. Go back to sleep.
It ain't fine.
We got a problem.
That whole sequence with
Sally boy banging the fiancee,
You gotta tell Tony
that was your idea.
It wasn't my idea.
What, are you fucking stupid he probably
thinks I put it in there to embarrass him.
- Why did you put it in there?
- It was an idea.
I don't know. Who knows
where they fucking come from?
Isaac Newton invented gravity 'cause
some asshole hit him with an apple.
It's bad enough that I don't
get credit for my own ideas.
Now I'm supposed to take responsibility for
some shit that's gonna get me in trouble?
Fuck that, man.
Humanitas Award.
What's that?
Humanitas.
From the Paulist Brothers,
For writing themes
of socially redeeming-
Ow!
Look out the window. You see a
fucking Hollywood sign out there?
Maybe you talk
to your agent like that,
But don't ever get fucking
snippy on me again.
The fucking scary thing was
I didn't know what happened
Till after the shot was fired.
Fucking weird.
- Tony, hey. Gentlemen.
- Hey, how are you?
T.J. Hooker.
J.T., actually, but uhm
I'm looking for Chris.
I'm supposed to meet him.
What, here?
The thing is
he left me a message,
But this fucking verizon-
- Mind if I wait?
- Yeah, sit down.
- Diet coke, please.
- You got it.
So what did you think
of "cleaver"?
It's good, you know.
Congratulations.
I hope we're gonna see
some money soon.
Yeah.
As a writer, you can
never tell, you know?
You come up with an idea. You don't
know how the audience is gonna respond.
I mean, just 'cause I like
something, I think of
Doesn't mean
anyone else will.
That's the challenge.
It is challenging sometimes,
Inventing characters,
how they interact.
The boss Sally boy
for example,
His whole persona-
I stole that from Broderick
Crawford in "Born Yesterday. "
What's that?
Garson Kanin, 1950.
It's terrific.
William Holden falls in love with
Crawford's girlfiend, played by Judy Holiday
The black girl,
the singer.
No, that's Billie Holiday.
Although Judy's character
in the movie
Is named Billie too, so I
can see why you're confused.
I've never seen it.
Why would I be confused?
Anyway, the Sally boy character
Is based on Crawford-
sort of a big, burly guy.
The love triangle, the cuckolding of
Michael, sleeping with the fiancee,
Very similar to
the Holden-Holliday dynamic.
- So the whole thing was your idea.
- Apologies to Garcon Kanin.
- What happened to your head?
- What?
Oh. Cabinet.
Duh.
If I see Chrissy, I'll tell
him you were looking for him.
Now listen to me, you two heels.
I mean business.
I got too much at stake down here.
You got somthing that belongs to me.
If you wanna get out of here alive,
you better give it back.
Now I'm no blowhard.
Tell him.
He's no blowhard.
He's had people killed before.
- About six years ago, there
was this guy- - shut up!
You ain't gonna be telling
nobody nothing pretty soon.
This is the image of me
he leaves to the world.
I remember when he was born,
I would hold him in my arms.
He was an adorable kid, too.
Big eyes.
You always talk about him
More like a son.
In some ways he was,
Especially after his dad died.
When he was little,
I used to give him rides.
I'd put him in the basket
of the butcher bike,
Pedal him around,
Back when Satriale's
made deliveries.
I reminded him
of that recently.
- He didn't remember.
- But you do.
We had fun.
All those memories,
and for what?
All I am to him
is some asshole bully.
You're hurt.
His dad Dickie was
Like my me to him.
A mentor.
Yeah, but more than that,
A friend,
A fucking guy
you could look up to.
And the hope is that
you pass that shit down,
The respect and the love.
And all I did
for this fucking kid
And he fucking hates me
so much.
I'm sure on some level
he loves you, too.
Yeah?
Take that home.
Judge for yourself.
Last five minutes should
answer that question.
I'm not going to do that.
- Not a horror fan?
- It's what you think that matters.
I think he fucking despises me.
It's pretty obvious.
Wants to see me dead.
Without invalidating
your feelings,
Is it possible that
on some level
You're reading into all this?
I'Ve been coming here for years.
I know too much about
the subconscious now.
Look, sweetie,
They're nice and clean
like you like them.
Mommy, he can't really hear you.
They're right here by the bed.
- My...
- What, baby, your what?
Want more morphine, daddy?
Mo- mother.
Grandma? What, daddy?
Is he hallucinating?
I don't know. He could be.
Sometimes they see
people who've passed.
John, look at me, baby.
You want a cigarette, baby?
John?
You can't do that when
you're on my fucking team?
Hey, Ton',
Anthony Infante to see you
Send him in.
There he is.
X- ray specs.
- How's John?
- That's why I'm here, Tony.
John passed away
late this morning.
Oh, fuck,
you're kidding me.
I only wish.
He was a great guy, John.
Sorry for your loss.
Thanks. Honestly, though,
it was for the best.
What are you gonna do?
"I beat cancer,
but it took him out. "
"Ride the painted pony.
Let the spinning wheel fly. "
Huh?
John Sacrimoni,
a buon' anima.
A buon' anima.
We're here to celebrate
what would have been my brother's-
Your uncle's-
47th birthday.
Blow it out for him.
Right here at this bar,
this seat
Was uncle Billy's favorite
place in the whole world.
More than Shea stadium?
More than Shea stadium.
He'd sit with his friends and
tell stories about his family,
Who he loved more than anything
and was so very proud of.
From now on, his ashes
will be right here
So when his friends come
to visit, he can see them.
- Can he see us now?
- Yeah.
- Who knows who is Leonardo Da Vinci?
- I do.
- Matty.
- Yeah, he wrote "The Da Vinci Code. "
Another man wrote that, but
it's a hideous sacrilegious book.
- Annabella.
- He was a painter,
Of the "Mona Lisa. "
Very good. He was not only a
painter, he did medical drawings,
- And he designed a tank for the army.
- Wow.
Leonardo was a great italian,
And that was our name
originally, Leonardo.
But many years ago, when my
grandpa came over from Sicily,
They changed it at
Ellis Island to Leotardo.
What did they do that for?
Because they're stupid,
that's why, and jealous.
They disrespected
a proud italian heritage
And named us
after a ballet costume.
- Marissa.
- That's for modern. In ballet, you wear tutus.
It doesn't make a difference.
- That's right, it doesn't.
- Can we have cake now?
How you doing, Phil?
You okay?
47-
He was a fucking kid.
Me, I'm an old man.
I'd like to do it over, boy.
Let me tell you.
I fucking compromised
everything.
Nah, what are you
talking about?
20 years inside,
Not a fucking peep.
For what?
To protect the likes
Of Rusty fucking Millio,
Doc Santoro?
You were a man, Phil.
That's saying a lot nowadays.
That cocksucking piece of shit
Tony Soprano's cousin-
I can't even
say his name-
Murdered Billie.
And what did I do about it?
My weakness.
Sometimes I think
it's in my DNA.
My family took shit
from the Medigans
The minute we got
off the boat.
Come on, what the fuck
you talking about?
Leotardo.
That's my fucking legacy.
No more, Butchie.
No more of this.