50 years have passed.
But I do not age.
Time has lost its effect on me.
Yet the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Got to get back ...
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
5x03 - XCIV
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
They're coming!
Huh?
Look at you.
You've survived worse.
This isn't about
your pathetic little cut.
It's about that girl you killed.
We've never killed a human
before, have we?
Sure, mountains of robot corpses.
But this?
This was the first human being.
Real flesh and blood.
What happens
when the others find you?
You'll have to kill them, too.
Can you?
Will you be able to
when the time comes?
Maybe they will kill you.
Or is that what you want?
No.
Emperor!
Your guards are dead,
and you are next!
Your choices have
clearly led you here, as have mine.
I will give you a new choice.
Leave now and live
or stay and face your destiny.
Ha! Your Bushido nonsense
means nothing to us.
Your destiny is death!
Huh?
The decisions you make
and the actions that follow
are a reflection of who you are.
You cannot hide from yourself.
Death is failure.
Follow the river.
I'll take watch.
Samurai blood.
The river guides our way.
- What... is that?
- Quiet!
Mother told us there
would be other creatures.
Wait.
Something else approaches.
Is it with the Samurai?
Should we kill it?
Aku.
It is surely one of his minions.
It will devour the weaker one.
- What madness is this?
- What are they doing?
- I... don't know.
- Well, I don't like it.
Look.
You have chosen this path.
Life works in strange ways.
Your choices have clearly
led you here, as have mine.
I will give you a new choice.
Leave here now and live
or stay and face your destiny.
Our destiny is your death!
So... I guess you're staying.
Perhaps I was unclear.
Enough words! Show yourself,
Samurai, so you can die!
Very well.
The decisions you make
and the actions that follow
- are a reflection of ...
- Shut up!
...of who you really are.
You worthless scum!
I will kill you!
You can never escape from Aku!
You will die!
You will die a horrible death,
and then Aku will sing,
for he is free
from the parasite that you are!
Die, Samurai!
Die, die, you scum!
Die! Die!
Die, Samurai!
You will... diiiiiie!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Got to get back ♪
♪ Back to the past, Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~