50 years have passed,
but I do not age.
Time has lost it's effect on me.
Yet, the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Got to get back,
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
5x05 - "XCVI"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Ha-ha!
We found him!
- We're ready, dad!
- Wha?!
Flora! What in Bonnie
blazes are ya' wearing?!
I take you out
for a day of battle,
and ye dress like
you're going dancing!
Cover yourself!
- You'll catch your death of cold!
- Dad!
That goes for all of you!
Dad!
Now we....
charge!
Can somebody please
stop all that noise!
I'm sorry, master, but it
seems we are under attack.
Under attack?
Hmm, perhaps
annihilating this scum
will break me out of my
melaise.
Wha?!
You know what?
This was a bad idea!
- Time to go, girls!
- But, dad...
No arguing!
Go!
I'll stall him while you escape.
Meh.
Oh!
Eh, better to make it
a complete annihilation.
Hold it!
You're not going anywhere,
ya' big buffoon!
I'm sorry, old man.
I think you're lost.
I ain't lost, ya tree ogre.
I might be old,
but I've lived long enough
to see the world rise
against your tyranny!
Admit it, ya big oaf!
You're scared.
The samurai is still out there
inspiring people by the thousands.
After all these years,
you're powerless against him.
You've been shivering like
a wee baby, hiding in your crib,
afraid to show yourself
'cause ya know he's out there,
and you can't do anything about it!
You're just a big baby!
Why don't you go cry to your mama?
No.
Dad.
Ah, why did he
bring up the samurai?
We will avenge you, father.
And we will never forget you.
I be back,
and in me prime no less!
Dad?
Oh, you live!
Ha! Eh, kind of...
But, how?
Oh, my darling Heather
blossoms ... Celtic magic.
What's next, father?
We regroup and plan
to fight another day.
We'll amass a bigger army.
We'll find Jack, and finally
defeat that big baby!
Aku is the creator
of this world and everything in it.
Aku is the one
that has ravaged this world.
The samurai is
the poison killing the land.
If you let go of your hate,
you will see the truth.
Ashi, what are you doing?
The samurai sleeps.
Kill him in his slumber
before he wakes.
No.
I have questions, mother.
The samurai ... he saved my life.
- He ...
- How dare you?
You know he is deceitful.
He will do everything in
his power to defy the master!
You were always the weak one
... distracted, unfocused.
May Aku punish you for your sins!
I just want the truth.
You have failed us.
Get on.
Hold on.
Thank you, friend.
I shall not forget your kindness.
Goodbye.
Please, no more, please.
- What do you want?
- The truth.
- I have already told you the truth.
- Show me.
- No.
- No?! What do you mean, no?!
You tell me that everything
that I know is wrong,
but refuse to prove any of it.
You're afraid ... afraid
that I will see you're a liar!
You are too blinded by Aku's hate.
You won't change.
What do you know of me,
everything I have endured
up until this moment?!
You know nothing, samurai.
- You are just a lowly, soulless pig.
- Very well.
I will show you.
Please sit.
- Well, when do we start?
- In the morning. Have patience.
Samurai, the stars.
They are Aku's creation, yes?
- You th... no!
- Then who?
When I was very young,
my mother told me a story
of when all the earth
was covered in darkness.
But a little magical boy named "Sun"
and his little sister named "Moon"
rode a Phoenix up into the darkness.
They shot enchanted arrows
that exploded and filled the dark sky
with an infinity of stars.
- That tree...
- One of many.
The trees stretched as
far as the eye can see.
It was a testament to nature's wonder
until Aku destroyed everything.
He left but one ... a reminder
of his power and oppression.
- Why?
- Aku is evil personified ...
the darkest soul from the pit of hate.
To him, all that is good and
innocent must be decimated.
That is his will, his desire.
Here is your truth.
A city of Aku ... a gateway to evil.
Come quickly!
My friend, trust me.
It is a thing of beauty on you.
Fresh shoes, freshly made every day.
Vintage, period coats ...
16th, 17th, 18th centuries.
There.
We are criminal banished from our world.
We hear that Aku welcomes
those that are like us.
Most enthusiastically.
Your new home will be
coordinates 6-12-71.
- It is occupied.
- Is that a problem for you?
No. No problem.
The innocent and weak
always preyed upon.
Catastrophe.
Devastation.
Carnage.
Enough.
I've seen enough.
Do you believe now?
Yes. What can we do?
- Nothing.
- What?!
What do you mean, nothing?
We have to do something!
I've fought Aku for ages.
I've seen countless innocents die.
I've lived this nightmare for
what seems like an eternity.
There is no way to defeat him.
There is no hope.
No way out.
Help.
You've come back at last, Samurai Jack.
- You've come.
- What happened?
They ... they took all the children.
- Where?
- The factory.
- Do you hear that?
- No. Run.
What?
Run!
Something has to be
controlling them ... that sound!
Destroy the source!
Wha...?
Well, what do we have here?
A little samurai sympathizer.
And quite the pretty one.
Sorry, Princess.
Ran out of juice.
No worries, though.
A quick re-charge and
then back to the fun.
Would you look at that.
Righteous fool.
After everything, he still
can't hurt an innocent.
Turning those little
brats into weapons ...
pretty ingenious, right?
Children are foolish
little things, easily manipulated.
Surgically implant a chip in their neck,
and the right audio
frequency does the rest.
Well, back to the fun.
What the...?
Oh, no, you don't!
Ah! Ooh!
Oof!
No!
N-o-o-o-o-o!
It is time.
Yes.
Samurai! Samurai?!
We did it.
Samurai!
Samurai?
Samurai Jack!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Got to get back ♪
♪ Back to the past ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Watch out ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~