Edited at https://subtitletools.com
Remember...
I just turned 65.
I made a wish on my birthday.
Just like a child would...
Another impossible wish, of course.
You know what I wished for?
To be a good man.
You know me.
I do.
You're a good man.
KILL
Nesrin, pulling a gun is so different
than to pulling the trigger.
You couldn't find any of this footage
on the internet or on TV.
Welcome to the fan club
of the first real Turkish serial killer.
Do whatever it takes, but stop them.
Tufan Elibol, whom
the killer used to throw us off his track
will be instrumental in catching him.
The killer will be a victim
to his own game.
Go on, get out.
Clouds foaming overhead.
The sea within, the sea without.
I'm a walnut tree in Gülhane Park.
Neither you realize this...
Nor the police.
I MET A GIRL TODAY
HER NAME IS NEVRA ELMAS
I TRUST ONLY HER
BECAUSE NEVRA GETS ME
IT IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY TODAY
I GOT HER A PRESENT
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
I TOLD NEVRA EVERYTHING
BUT SHE WON'T BELIEVE ME
TONIGHT, A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
I MADE A WISH
I WISHED THAT THEY ALL DIE
-They're all dead.
-All?
Ufuk had two brothers.
One of them was shot at his workplace.
The other one in the forest.
Our guy?
-Messages on both their foreheads.
-Their father's outside.
Came to pick them up,
waiting on paperwork.
He can't. We need to do an autopsy.
I couldn't tell him.
I could never tell him.
Come on! Come on!
I'll tell him.
Son!
You killed them!
-You killed my children!
-Salih...
-Salih, please don't.
-You killed my babies!
You ended them! You ended my babies.
Are you happy now?
Are you happy now, Nevra?
-Did you get what you wanted?
-Shut up!
If you had been looking for the killer
instead of going after Ufuk.
-They both would be alive now.
-Shut up!
Tell me I'm lying!
Damn!
I want to die!
What happened to me?
We had to pump your stomach, Zuhal.
Why?
What happened?
You had alcohol poisoning
when you arrived.
Nevra?
Nevra, what are you doing?
It's fine. I had a nosebleed.
I got blood on my sleeve.
-Are you alright, daughter?
-I'm not.
I'm not alright at all.
You are sad about Ufuk, right? Poor boy.
I'm powerless.
People are dying around me,
and I'm powerless!
It's driving me mad!
I try to control myself.
I tense every muscle in my body
just so nobody suspects anything.
Suspect what?
That I'm afraid.
That I'm afraid. I'm so afraid.
I'm afraid that I'm never
going to catch the killer!
I'm so afraid!
I'm so afraid...
Nevra, my darling...
It was so hard,
not crying in front of the crowd.
I ran and I ran, and here I am.
My darling...
Just like when you were a child.
You'd run home, about to piss your pants.
You'd barely make it.
Are you feeling better?
Yes. I think.
-Don't be afraid, Nevra.
-Mom...
Hush.
Don't be afraid.
Don't be afraid to be afraid.
Plus... So what?
I'm afraid, as well.
You're never afraid.
That was then.
I'm so scared that
something will to happen to you.
Come on, I'll wash it.
And...
They can't even get a bloodstain out...
Yet they go become cops.
Some cop you are.
-Someone sent you flowers, Zuhal.
-Who?
-Me.
-You can leave when you're feeling better.
-You didn't go?
-No.
You were here through the night?
Hello?
Yes, I'm here.
I have the file.
Where are you?
Hello?
Hello? You're breaking up. Hello?
Cemil, I'm so sorry.
I'm so embarrassed.
I don't know what to say.
I can't even imagine the spot
I put you in.
I should quit the job.
What am I to do, Cemil?
WATER IT TWICE A WEEK
Water it twice a week...
And come with me. Let's go.
-What will you do now?
-Get back to Istanbul.
I need to ask you something.
Why did you lie, Selim and you?
About how the house burned down.
Why would I lie?
I already told you.
Selim forgets to take his pills
and hallucinates.
-That's all.
-Fine. If you say so.
Why wouldn't I tell you
if I knew something?
There's something that scares you.
I'd forgotten about it.
What's that?
You're scared of being left alone.
You always were.
What would you do
if something were to happen to Selim?
If you knew that
I was scared of being left alone,
why did you up and leave?
You didn't take me to Istanbul.
You were being scared of loneliness,
and I was scared of you.
Fine! Then don't come here
with tears in your eyes ever again.
Why shouldn't I? Didn't you tell me
not to be afraid of being afraid?
Take care.
Hello?
You're breaking up. I can't hear you.
The door is opening.
Stop! Stop!
Call the police! Call the police, Galip!
-Are you alright?
-Take your gun.
Are you alright?
-What happened? Did they find him?
-I just got word.
He's trapped
in a shopping centre's garage.
Yes. We have all the exits blocked.
This is the only exit.
He's definitely in here.
Let's go!
I found his costume.
He's going up to the roof!
To be honest...
I don't even like
the taste of alcohol, Cemil.
But after I have that first glass...
Something happens...
I can't stop myself.
All I want to do is drink.
No matter what.
Come what may.
"All I need right now is a drink.
Just let me have one more drink."
I can't stop myself.
There this writer called Bukowski,
you might've heard of him.
You know what he said?
He said drinking is a form of suicide.
He said drinking yourself unconscious
is attempted suicide.
-I don't want to die, Cemil.
-Are you sure?
Of course I am.
I don't even want to talk about this.
Talking about this with you
is such an embarrassment for me.
Hurting someone else
is embarrassing, Zuhal.
There's nothing embarrassing
about having hurt yourself.
You have enough problems as it is.
-Would you like to leave?
-No.
-We should stay.
-Alright.
I should tell you why we're here, then.
There was this elder in Kambura. Turan.
He took me aside one day
and told me I wasn't the first.
I asked him what he meant.
"You're not the first boy whose education
the Kamburan people paid for.
They paid for three more children
before you." he said.
I was surprised.
I asked him where they were,
what they did now.
They paid for the first one's education.
He said he was a good student.
Finished college. Started a business.
Made a lot of money.
But he forgot about Kambura.
He never went back to Kambura.
He said they sometimes saw him on TV,
but changed the channel immediately.
There was a second boy.
They paid for his education, as well.
"He finished college,
and we sent him to London
for a graduate degree."
But he became a gambler.
All that money that
the Kamburans scraped together...
He lost it all on roulette.
Apparently, he was jailed at some point.
After that, no one saw him
or heard of him ever again.
Their one last hope...
They paid for one last boy's education.
He got into medical school.
But he started drinking.
I met him, actually.
Rahim was his name.
Five-six years older than I was.
I went up to him...
"Rahim,
a whole village depends on you."
"You'll become a doctor
and cure the people who raised you."
You know what he said to me?
He told me they never asked him
if he wanted an education.
Told me they should educate themselves.
It was right here
that I had that conversation
with Rahim, Zuhal.
He was an intern at this hospital.
He came down here to drink in secret.
Now...
I'll tell you why we're here.
You're going to make a decision.
I never saw Rahim's face again.
Will I get to see yours?
My father never asked me, either, Cemil.
He never asked me anything.
Never asked me
if I wanted to go to boarding school.
If I wanted to go to college...
He was always so distant.
I told him I was moving to Australia.
"Farewell," he said.
I was so lonely.
I sometimes look at my photos
from those days.
I'm always by myself.
In the photos,
there are beautiful landscapes.
Beautiful bridges...
Statues...
And me...
Just me...
You know what I'd actually like?
I want the photos...
I want the photos to have my mom in them.
I want my mom, my dad and I together.
I want nothing else in the photos.
I want nothing else.
Even if we're in front of the best view,
in the most beautiful place in the world,
I want all of it gone.
I want us and only us to remain.
Because...
We'd be enough for each other.
But it didn't turn out that way.
I'd remember.
Even if
there were nothing else in the photos,
I'd look at my mom and dad's faces,
and I'd know that
we were standing
in front of a huge waterfall.
I know it's not in the photo,
but we're
standing by a huge sycamore tree.
That would be enough for me. But...
But it was never like that. Never.
The photos have only me in them.
And the setting sun.
The setting sun.
The sun.
There it is, always.
But it's setting.
I...
I've never been able to forgive
my father, Cemil.
-He must've had a reason.
-I wish he'd shared it with me.
-Let's go, Cemil. Let's get out of here?
-Sure. Let's go. However...
I need you to make me a promise.
-I promise never to drink again.
-No. It's not that.
It's something else.
Promise me you'll never forget
this place. And this smell.
I do. I promise. I'll never forget it.
Your father looked after me.
It's my turn to look after you now.
That's nonsense.
My job is to look after you.
-That's nonsense.
-No.
That's different.
Answer me this one question.
Is there room for me in that photo?
Cemil?
We're done here.
-Are you alright? Are you cold?
-I'm fine. A bit cold, maybe.
-Don't worry. You'll get over it.
-Thank you so much.
There's this writer.
Named Coubert...
He said that...
Love is the only adventure left
on this earth.
That's what he says.
I see.
MORGUE
This is a joke, right?
There's only one entrance
and one exit to the garage.
But there's no one inside...
With your permission,
I'd like to take this
to the lab for DNA analysis.
Sure, take it.
Is Nevra around?
Yeah. She's here.
I want to ask you something.
Do you know what's the most
dangerous thing for a murder specialist?
Obsession.
You get an idea.
Then you start believing it.
It takes hold in your mind.
Then it turns into an obsession.
It blinds you.
You can always have theories, of course.
But do you know the difference
between a theory and a conspiracy?
I'll tell you that, as well.
Theories are smart.
Conspiracy theories are sicknesses.
Because the evidence
for a theory is rooted in truth.
But the evidence for a conspiracy
is another conspiracy theory.
Itself, in other words.
It's right even when it's wrong.
A conspiracy theory is never wrong.
You know who else is never wrong?
Dumb people.
Don't get me wrong. I'm not only talking
about you, talking about myself, as well.
That's why we're going to build
a perimeter of logic together.
We'll keep running into each other.
Until we find the truth.
We will consider every single possibility.
Even the possibility that none of this
has anything to do with Kambura.
-Who is it?
-He didn't have an ID on him.
I didn't talk to him.
I waited for you to arrive, Cemil.
Good. Let's find out
what's his problem with Kambura.
By the way...
You should be glad
that Ufuk handled himself.
Yes, Cemil. We couldn't stop him, sadly.
You made up for it, though.
-Sir, his connection to the victim...
-Nevra...
-Are you talking about the house?
-Yes.
Nevra, we went there. You read the report.
Nobody burned it.
I don't believe that report.
-Is that so?
-Yes.
On what grounds? Your mom's husband?
What was his name?
Selim.
What about what Ufuk told us?
His brothers were killed.
You went there to interrogate Ufuk
and utter chaos took over.
I got calls from the ministry
asking what's going on in Kambura.
I swear I don't know anything
about Kambura.
I don't even know where it is!
I swear I'm not him!
Please don't!
Speak! Why did you kill
all those people? Speak!
But sir, we also know
that the deceased Naz Çörtük
is also connected to Kambura.
-She worked in the municipality office.
-Sure, but when?
Twenty years ago? Forty years ago? When?
-Please don't! Please don't!
-Tell me who you are.
What did you want from those people?
Why did you shoot that women? Why?
They'll kill me!
They'll put me in the ground!
I'm the one who'll put you in the ground!
I'll bury you so deep
that no one will see you ever again.
Alright! How about this?
I got a call from narcotics today.
The woman who was killed in
the parking garage, you know who she is?
I know that she worked at
a logistics firm as an accountant.
Not even close.
There's no such logistics firm.
It's a front.
They were running drugs, Nevra.
Narcotics has been after them
for six months.
They convince the woman
to turn state's evidence.
They were supposed to meet today.
She went to the office to gather evidence.
But she's gone. So is the evidence.
Now. Do you still think...
That the murders are connected to Kambura?
I saw it in the papers.
A guy in a cat costume
was killing people after people!
The people I told you about
gave me the hit on the accountant woman.
I just got out of prison.
I couldn't go back in.
But I needed the money!
So I donned the cat costume.
I thought it would be a good idea.
He's killed four, five, so many people!
I thought I could pin it on him.
I thought it would be forgotten.
What will you do to me?
Please!
Why aren't you saying anything? Please!
Tell me how much you were paid,
you bastard. Tell me!
If all that isn't convincing enough,
here's the file on that Terazi guy.
Read his file.
What does it say?
Go ahead. Read it out loud.
-Post-traumatic stress disorder.
-That's right!
He was sick!
But what did I do?
I asked myself, "What if Nevra's right?"
What if they burned that house down?
What if that report was fake?
Then what happened today?
We found out that the woman who was killed
had nothing to do with Kambura.
What did I do? I accepted that.
Now, Nevra, I'm begging you...
It's your turn to accept it.
If you want to look for connections
between the victims, look elsewhere!
Forget about that burnt down house!
Listen, Nevra.
Sometimes things don't turn out
the way we expect them to.
We want them to be another way.
We imagine them to be. But they're not.
They're nothing but illusions.
Get out.
Then we get a phone call, and wake up.
Sir? Can I have that file?
I wasted my breath, didn't I?
You'll do what you want anyway.
Sure. Take it.
Do what you want.
I'm so glad we finally got to meet.
I've been telling him.
If you hadn't come to me,
I'd have come to you.
I was almost about to, in fact.
I even have your address!
As you might guess,
communication with patients'
families is a must for us.
Especially when it comes to
patients like your father.
It's very important
that the people close to them
get together to support them.
-Again, welcome, Zuhal.
-Thank you.
I have some questions prepared.
Let's move to the table
and I can begin asking them.
I hope you've been doing your homework.
Agah, I don't know why I said yes to this!
This is madness!
I have to tell your doctor the truth.
What will you tell him? Don't be silly.
-I can tell him it was all a joke.
-You can't do that. It's too late.
I'll tell him the truth, then.
I'll tell him Agah's daughter
is undergoing cancer treatment.
He thinks telling her will upset her.
He was worried that you might want to
visit his home, so we came up with this.
Gonca, my girl, please!
If you won't do it for me,
do it for Münir.
You've been his veterinarian for years.
You practically raised Münir!
Let's forget about that, even.
Zuhal is what's important here!
What would Zuhal do in her state
if she found out her father's sick?
You're a doctor of many years.
Could you take such a responsibility?
Don't you know how important optimism is
when it comes to cancer treatment?
But what next, Agah?
How long can we keep it up?
It's already done.
There's nothing to keep up.
He has your number.
He might call you once, if that.
You'll just nod your head
and be done with it.
It was so embarrassing,
having to lie. I'm terrible at it.
-Do you think he could tell?
-Of course not!
You were such a great actor!
I'm sure he'd never even suspect you.
I'll do whatever you want from me now.
I don't want to go through this again.
And I hope Zuhal gets her health back.
Amen. Thank you.
-I could give you a ride.
-It's fine, really.
Alright. Alright, then. Thank you so much.
You were great in there.
You deserved an Oscar, I'm telling you.
Ali, I need a phone number.
Used to work at Kambura Hospital.
It's been ten years.
Psychiatrist Nedim Doğru.
Of course.
Nevra...
The stupid cat costume worked.
They found some DNA on it.
They're trying to find a match for it.
If they get a match, this is over.
I need to oversee
the autopsy of the triplets.
You can follow up on the DNA. Good luck.
To you, as well.
Thanks.
Here we are...
We're immortalizing this historic moment.
What are you doing?
-Writing my memoir.
-Sure you are.
What happens in your memoir?
Do you die at the end?
Medically, no. But my career? Yes.
-Why?
-What do you mean, why?
Do you know how many corpses
come in here every day?
Should we call the police or something?
I work so much I've forgotten
what my place looks like.
I'm listening, Timur.
Born on the same day,
died on the same day.
Proper triplets.
That's some investigating!
Yes, Nevra?
Really? I'll be right there.
-Did they find him?
-How did you know?
That's how it always is in this place.
Whenever I start to speak...
Go on.
You might really have him this time.
Timur, do you have diarrhea
of the mouth or something?
-Welcome, Nükhet.
-Thank you.
This is for you.
-Don't mention it.
-You're so classy.
-Not at all.
I hope I haven't
kept you waiting for too long.
I've been waiting for ten years.
I live here.
-We're going out for dinner, right?
-Yes.
We're already there. This is it.
-This is it?
-Yes. After you.
What a beautiful building.
It's a bit rough around the edges,
but it's still magnificent.
Abdulhamid the Second built it.
He had an Italian architect design it
for use by Italian opera singers.
Actually, fun fact.
This is the first building
with an elevator in Istanbul.
That's why it keeps breaking.
Truly wonderful.
Are all the tenants bars like this one?
No. There's just this one,
and a folk bar upstairs.
And a trattoria with divine mezzes.
That's where we're going.
I live here, of course. But that's it.
Doesn't it get loud at night?
It used to.
They used to play the drums
at the folk bar. Made quite a ruckus.
So I went and had a word with them.
We came to terms.
They're much quieter now.
You get used to it after a while.
They all close after 2 AM.
Only ones left are me and the kids.
There's no one else in the building.
Truly wonderful.
Must be so much fun. So full of life.
Agah...
How about we go in there for a start?
The music's so loud.
We won't even hear each other.
They're playing rock 'n roll!
It's been such a long time
since I've had some beer in Beyoğlu.
Let's start there.
We can go upstairs later.
Sure. Alright. After you.
They've found whose the DNA from
the cat costume belongs to.
-Is the SWAT team on the way?
-Yes.
To you.
-To you.
Life's a beautiful thing, isn't it?
It is.
-We're almost there.
-Tell them to hold until we're there.
Tell the SWAT team not to go in
until we're on the scene.
I have a question.
How did you come up with the idea
to write a book named "Life is Traffic"?
-How do you think?
-I wouldn't know.
I was in a traffic accident.
I lost my husband in that accident.
I was in the hospital for 11 months.
The doctors told me I'd never walk again.
But I met you while doing the tango.
Indeed...
Everything fell into place
after that accident.
I realized how simple life is.
As simple as a traffic accident.
As simple as traffic.
I love the image of...
The image of road signs.
"Stay out." "No u-turns."
Stuff like that.
We carry those road signs around with us.
Stop. Go. You can park here.
You can't park here.
The rules for traffic, Agah,
turn out to be the rules for life.
Open up! Police!
How did the accident happen?
-My husband broke a rule.
-Which one?
Fuck!
Sefa, it's me, Firuz!
Tell the team to pull back.
I'm opening the door.
Firuz...
If you want to commit suicide together,
the first rule is
you should ask the other person
whether they want to die, as well.
Firuz, are you alright?
Did he do it on purpose?
The worst part is, I knew what he was
when I got married to him.
I thought I could heal him. But...
-Whom can you truly heal, right?
-Right...
Firuz...
Sefa...
I have a gun pointed at me.
Tell the team to pull back.
Alright.
Lower your weapons.
-What does he want?
-I don't know. I'm about to find out.
I'm closing then door now. Alright?
Hold on, Sefa!
Pull back. Pull back.
Back!
But I have no doubt
that people have been healed
after reading your book.
Perhaps...
But I didn't write the book for them.
I wrote the book to heal myself.
If they want to heal themselves,
they need to write books of their own.
Speak! Where the fuck
did you hide the money? Speak!
Speak or you get one in the head! Speak!
Did you write any other books?
No...
I'm still in the investigation part.
-What is it about?
-Agah Beyoğlu.
What do you mean? Why?
Because something tells me...
That nothing is as it seems.
Yes, chief. Alright.
Alright, chief. We're waiting outside.
Alright, chief. Of course.
It's Firuz! Don't shoot, I'm coming out!
Excuse me. There was a small problem.
I had two bullets jammed in my gun.
-Lower your fucking weapons.
-I'm glad.
I heard you on the radio
and came straight over. He fell on me.
But I have bad news.
He isn't the guy you're looking for.
What do you mean?
He was a hired gun.
He knew there was a serial killer
running around in a cat costume.
He decided to become a cat
and catch himself a mouse.
-I'm leaving, then.
-Where to?
-I'll tell you afterwards.
-Alright.
-You scared us.
-Why would you be scared?
The devil looks after his own.
I'm here to see Dr. Nedim Doğru.
Do you have an appointment?
A moment please.
So he hung himself.
I knew that's how it would end.
-Where have you been?
-Excuse me?
I've been waiting for you for ten years.
What do you mean?
I've been waiting for a cop
to come asking about Ufuk Terazi.
Then...
Why didn't you go to the police?
You wouldn't be asking me that
if you knew how this report was made.
I had just been assigned to Kambura.
To the state hospital there.
Something horrible had happened.
It was before my time.
A fire. A house had burned down.
The family inside had perished.
They brought Ufuk to me. His father did.
Ufuk didn't want to talk at first.
But when he realized
I wasn't a Kamburan, he opened up.
He told the same story
over and over again.
I burned the house down, he said.
I didn't believe him at first.
I thought the trauma
had altered his perception of reality.
But how detailed it all
was told me he wasn't hallucinating.
He wasn't lying, either.
So I called the police.
I told them what happened,
just as I'm telling you now.
I told them Ufuk confessed.
One day, when I was on night shift,
a man came to see me.
I remember every word he said to me.
"You will forget all about this."
"Or you disappear," he said.
"What do you mean, disappear?" I asked.
"You'll disappear the same way
people all around this country do."
I got what he meant then.
He told me I was to write a report.
So I did.
Who was he?
I don't know.
You never asked who he was? What he did?
Look, Nevra.
I'll explain it to you this way...
Conmen prey on hope.
A conman comes to you:
"Give me a dollar
and I'll give you ten back."
And if you're greedy by nature,
you get hopeful and give him the dollar.
But the conmen of this country
stopped selling hope.
There's an easier way.
People are so afraid of you...
Tell someone you're a cop on the phone,
and they'll give you every dime.
If the conmen of a country
con you through not hope but fear,
you never ask them who they are
or what they do for a living.
Then...
Could you identify him if you saw him?
Actually...
I was really scared that night.
I couldn't even look him in the eye.
But you can never tell.
You can never tell what someone
might suddenly remember.
-Not even I can.
-Give me a second.
-I don't have to be afraid anymore?
-You don't.
-What did he do?
-He was a judge.
Heavy penal court.
After all these years...
That's such a load off my back.
Forgetting feels good sometimes.
But other times, so does remembering.
I'll never forget it.
Where did he come from?
Where did he go?
-Where did that cop come from?
-A cop? What cop?
The one who took my statement.
He spoke to me the next morning.
Where did he come from?
-The cop?
-The cop.
Probably from Istanbul.
I didn't get his name.
He was young. He was a young man.
I might be able to identify him
if I saw a photo.
What is it?
What's that?
It's what I owe you.
It's over. We're even.
I'm done doing your dirty work.
Is that so?
Tell me it's done.
Tell me you're letting me go.
Suppose I let you go.
Will what you've done stop haunting you?
I killed someone over that money!
Oh, Firuz...
You think you can pay me back in money?
It's a debt in blood.
How's your son doing, by the way?
In good health, I hope...
The foundation
sees to his every need, right?
Let me know if you need anything.
It's a hard condition.
Not only hard...
Also expensive.
Don't beat yourself up.
You're not a bad person.
You're just doing my bidding.
Tell your conscience that
the blame's all mine.
It'll feel better.
In the meantime, put these in your pocket.
You obviously deserved them.
Shall we go upstairs?
Aren't you getting hungry?
No. This is beautiful.
Turn the music off. Turn it off!
-Get out of my way!
-What's going on?
-What?
-Get out!
Get out! Get out!
-Go! Go! We're closing up! Go on!
-What are you doing?
Go on, uncle! Out!
-Nükhet!
-Go on!
-Go on, uncle! Go on!
-What do you think you're doing!
-Get back, bitch!
-Throw them out! Throw them out!
Go on, what are you looking at?
Get the fuck out of here!
-They didn't pay their tax this month!
-Fuck you!
Do you have a death wish or something?
That's exactly what I have.
What will you do about it?
-Somebody help him!
-Shut him up!
Nükhet, I'm so sorry. I really am.
This kind of thing
never happens around here.
Don't worry about it. It's not your fault.
It can't be helped.
Besides, I had so much fun.
I'm mad that I didn't say anything
to those two-bit crooks.
Don't be silly. What if they have guns?
How do we know they don't?
Isn't it that way in traffic also?
You should never pick a fight.
You don't know who anyone might be.
What if they have a gun in their car?
What we did was right,
not getting involved in their affairs.
Thank you so much for everything.
Good night.
Good night...
-Some outfit. What's this now?
-He looks ridiculous.
Are you from the mafia?
Hush. It's saying something.
-What?
-I asked you if you're from the mafia.
-He's a loon.
-Are you drunk or something?
Are you looking for trouble?
Hold on. Show me your face. Show it!
Come on, we have another stop
to make at Sıtkı's.
Fucking clown.
I asked you
if you're from the mafia, my boy.
Yes. That's exactly what we are. So what?
Here's the mafia for you.
Just a bunch of wannabes.
PERSONAL