It's been five days since I debuted
as a professional hero.
There haven't been
any serious incidents so far.
However, for some reason Genos
is staying at my house.
What are you writing over there?
I'm recording the details of
your lessons and training regimen.
Crap. He's raising the bar again...
I can't think of a single thing
I can teach the guy.
I feel bad, like I'm scamming him
or something.
Come on, think. Or just make up
some techniques or a spiritual theory.
Bah, strength training is all I've got!
I know Genos won't be satisfied
with that, plus the dude's a cyborg!
By the way.
At the seminar
they said if you're a Class C hero
at the seminar
and you have no hero activity
for a week,
your name will be removed
from the Hero Registry.
Your name will be removed
Will you be all right, Master?
They said that?!
Yes.
But I was Watching TV and
there wasn't anything going on.
The news only reports
major incidents,
like natural disasters, terrorism
and dangerous monsters.
Like natural disasters, terrorism
You always fight
the most powerful enemies,
so you probably do not know it,
but Class C heroes primarily
take care of purse snatchers,
robberies and random attacks.
Robberies and random attacks.
With Class C so full of heroes,
to survive they must actively
look for cases to resolve.
To survive they must actively
I hear many of them get discouraged
and change careers.
Like a salesman doing cold calls,
nothing will come your way
without legwork.
Nothing will come your way
This is no time to be reading mange!
So we're going?
You stay here!
If I'm with a Class S hero,
a Class C like me
won't get any credit!
A Class C like me
But as your disciple...
Genos, from the beginning
my intense desire to be a hero.
my intense desire to be a hero
was what drove me
to strength training.
Was what drove me
That's how I made it this far.
For you, perhaps things will change
if you aim higher as a hero.
Frankly speaking, you're a cyborg,
so training your body won't do.
Instead, a change in mindset
may lead you to greater strength.
Damn, I'm just making
all this crap up...
So... in other words,
"How I Developed Indomitable Will
By S Class Hero King"
"l-low I Developed Indomitable Will By S Class Hero
King" it's not about having raw power or technique;
"L-low I Developed Indomitable Will By S Class Hero
"L-low I Developed Indomitable Will By S Class
Hero King" it's about training your mind.
You must first fight your way through
the professional hero industry.
Aim to break into the top ten
of the Class S heroes.
That will be your goal for now.
I understand. I will try!
He bought it... Sweet.
After that, I sped around town.
While frantically looking
for bad guys...
I ran.
And ran.
But!
The city was quiet!
I give up...
Just one more day left.
Guess I'll head home.
I'll leave tomorrow's problems
to tomorrow's me.
"The Following Day."
It's quiet today too!
There's nothing to do!
I'm gonna lose my registration!
Hey! You're that guy...
What was it?
"Seed-on-the-Ground... "?
No wait, "Lost-and-found..."?
Jack-d-lantern Panic!
It's Speed-d-Sound Sonic.
I've finally found you, Saitama.
Today is the day we-
Hey sorry, I'm busy. See you 'round...
Huh?
You think...
you can run from me'?!
You can run from me'?!
What the-?
I didn't see what happened.
His face should have been
sliced open, but the blade...
I told you... I'm busy.
Plus I'm pissed,
so anyone in my way...
gets punched.
That's him!
He's very, very dangerous.
Please stop him.
So you're the offender, eh?!
Well, the hero Tank-Top Tiger
is here now!
Hero?
Sonic, they think you're
some sort of criminal.
Maybe getting tossed in a cell
will cool off your hot-
She means you, cue ball.
Huh?
He's been running around town
with this scary look on his face
since yesterday!
With this scary look on his face
But I'm a hero too!
I've never heard of a hero like you.
So what? I just started!
In any case, you're causing
problems for everyone.
If you're really a hero, then don't
go around frightening people.
You're hurting
all the other heroes' reputation.
Hey isn't that Tank-Top Tiger?
Oh yeah, it is Tank-Top Tiger.
No way!
Awesome, he's the real deal!
Even Class C heroes get recognized
if they're in the top 10.
So how 'bout it, new guy?
Wanna go a little wild here
and make me look good?
Exploding Shuriken.
"Exploding Shuriken."
Tank-Top Tiger?!
Is this really happening?
What are you doing, Sonic?
He was interfering,
so I put him to sleep.
Hey, call a hero!
A hero!
Run!
Saitama...
So you too have become one of
these worthless "heroes"?
Then all I have to do
is create a situation.
is create a situation
where you have no choice
but to fight me, Saitama the Hero!
Where you have no choice
Hail of Carnage!
Huh?
Hey! Cut it out!
Saitama, come stop me!
You're a hero!
I'll kill them all!
Damn it.
Can't everyone
just let me do my job?
I don't have time for this!
I gotta find a bad guy to take down.
A bad guy?
If you're not coming, I'll go to you!
I'm right here.
I wonder if this will count as work?
The man apprehended in City Z
by the Class C hero.
by the Class C hero
is suspected of being involved in
several heinous crimes,
including assassination.
City Z...
What's the status of
the investigation I requested?
The one for the ghost town?
Yes.
Let's see...
We've submitted an official request.
Well now,
doesn't that sound interesting.
Want me to go?
Tornado?
Where'd you come from?
Why? Aren't I allowed in here?
Of course.
But for City Z,
the investigation is just a formality.
What?
You think I'm not good enough?
Not at all.
The Association decided that
this was not a Class S matter.
Yes, exactly right.
You'd better tell me if you find
anything that looks like it can fight.
It'd be so much faster
if I just went myself.
You're such an idiot.
"City A - Hero Association HQ."
"City A - Hero Association HQ"
Reports have come in from.
Reports have come in from
each location being investigated.
First is Watchdog Man,
Class S hero, investigating City Q.
"Nothing unusual."
Nothing unusual?
- That's right.
- That's hard to believe.
We all know City Q is a hot zone.
We all know City Q is a hot zone
with more casualties and monsters
than any other area.
With more casualties and monsters
Knowing him,
I'm sure he's implying that,
"Whatever occurs,
I'll be able to take care of it."
Though he has focused
his efforts on City Q,
his track record at
monster elimination is top-notch.
His track record at
Class S heroes don't
pay much attention to details.
They're not cut out
for writing reports.
Next, City W.
Class A hero Heavy Kong reports :
"Nothing unusual."
For City H, reports from Mushroom,
Class B, and Horsebone, Class C!
"Nothing unusual."
For City D, Lightning Genji,
Class AI.
"Slow restoration after
the devastation caused by."
the devastation caused by"
"the gigantic creature aside,
nothing unusual."
Cities B and D
both sustained extensive damage.
The Association took
a lot of heat for that.
In order to prevent
more such disasters,
we must detect any covert activity
that could threaten the community.
We must detect any covert activity
Well, this investigation was
requested for that express purpose.
But early detection of monsters
is proving difficult.
City F, Class A hero,
"Snakebite" Snek.
"Hammerhead, former leader
of the Paradiser terrorist group,."
of the Paradiser terrorist group,"
"has been spotted
in a suit and tie."
"Further investigation
is being conducted."
No other reports.
What of City Z?
I hear rumblings of
a potential disaster brewing
in the abandoned area there.
In the abandoned area there.
No reports available.
However, two highly capable
Class A heroes.
Class A heroes
have been sent to the area
to investigate.
Have been sent to the area
Here we are in City Z.
"Class A, Rank 33
Spring Mustachio."
"Class A, Rank 33 Spring Mustachio"
Shall we begin our little inquiry?
"Class A, Rank 29 Golden Ball."
"Class A, Rank 29 Golden Ball"
Yeah, let's get on with it.
City Z is quite expansive,
but further ahead lies.
but further ahead lies
the uninhabited area
we were told about.
The uninhabited area
Compared with other areas,
"Beware Of Monsters!!"
"Beware Of Monsters!!" City Z has an abnormally
high rate of monster-related incidents.
The frequency has been gradually
increasing over the past 1O years,
while the last few have seen
more and more
highly advanced monsters appearing.
Highly advanced monsters appearing.
The residents have entirely fled
for the city center.
I know all that.
The place is a real ghost town,
just with the water and electricity
still intact, yeah?
Just with the water and electricity
On the lookout for a cheap house?
Come off it.
People say something
real nasty's living 'round here.
Even you must've heard.
But of course.
I assume that's why We have been
assigned this investigation.
Once we hit the abandoned area,
we better be ready to fight.
Indeed,
we mustn't let our guard down.
But, Why here?
Why the increase in monsters here?
That's the mystery.
Many theories have been advanced,
but my own is this :.
A colony of monsters here is
naturally producing more of them.
Or perhaps a queen exists,
birthing more of her kind.
Of course I have no proof yet,
but there is something
to this ghost town...
Or rather, something in it.
Of that you can be sure.
The proximity alarm?
If we can hunt down
this mysterious being,
we'll go straight to
the top of the rankings.
We'll go straight to
That's true.
We can't let Mr. Amai Mask
remain first for...
- Somethings there?!
Was that a monster?
No way to be sure...
But it's hard to imagine a human
still living in these conditions.
Let's pursue it!
Seems they are not after us.
Can this be the place
I heard about?
Sure don't seem like it...
Aw man, I came all this way.
Isn't anyone around?
A monster.
It popped up out of nowhere.
Golden Ball, are you ready?
Hell yes.
Victory to the swift!
Hey, people!
I can blast through
a 20mm steel plate
with one of my shape-memory
golden bullets!
With one of my shape-memory
Eat this!
He flicked it away like nothing.
Golden Ball!
Wow!
Tomboy...
thrust!
It slipped past my Tomboy?
Not bad.
Those tentacles...
From the way they react,
they're tough as steel.
A monster that can use
its infinite number of tentacles.
its infinite number of tentacles
like steel whips...
Such power!
I must call in reinforcements
from the Association.
May I ask if you were born
in this neighborhood?
Nah, I'm from out of town.
I heard a bunch of crazy strong monsters
were all getting together here.
Looks like it was
just a rumor though.
But now,
I feel like it'd be kinda fun to
stick around and make the rumor true.
"The Ghost Town Monster..."
It's got a nice ring to it!
We have a backup request from
the heroes dispatched to City Z.
Class A rank 29, Golden Ball,
has been knocked out.
Class A rank 33,
Spring Mustachio, is in trouble.
They're in the abandoned city.
Call in all nearby heroes
for immediate assistance!
Class A and above!
See the monster alert for City Z?
The threat level seems to be
Tiger or higher.
Is it the ghost town monster?
They're not sure yet.
I'll go...
I want to catch the tiger
by its tail.
Now I see...
If it means running into monsters
like this all the time.
like this all the time
I wouldn't want to
live here either.
Man, boring. This is boring me!
I finally kick a hero's butt
and I don't get even a single scream.
Now that I think about it,
even if I start living here,
I'll never be famous
if there's no people.
Guess I'll keep going.
Gotta find Where they live.
There's somebody.
Another hero?
Or a regular guy?
I thought all the humans
cleared out.
If all those monsters
were really around,
there's no way he could live here...
I guess that means
it was just a rumor.
Shoot...
I forgot to buy konbu soup stock.
Master, I saw a lot of konbu
right outside the door.
Oh yeah, I just...
just happened...
to get it for cheap.
Just happened...
Yes, people say that konbu
is good for hair growth,
but since there is
no real scientific proof,
its real effects
are yet to be confirmed.
Its real effects
I did some research,
so I am sure, Master.
For example,
according to this site-
No one said anything about hair!
City Z Investigative Report.
"Nothing noteworthy about
the downtown or residential areas."
"“During our investigation,"
"we encountered a ferocious monster
in the abandoned area,"
"but were unable to
exterminate it."
"We escaped death,."
"We escaped death,"
"but the monster
we encountered disappeared"
"and it is possible that
it still roams the area."
"Also, according to this monster,
there's a rumor that..."
"'... powerful monsters
already exist in this area."
Sounds like it was pretty brutal.
A monster?
Yes.
I think I'll pass this time.
See? I told you I should have gone!
But...
faced with this,
I'm sure even you would
have had a tough time.
I would have been fine, idiot!
The rumor has not been confirmed,
but the reinforcements saw signs.
but the reinforcements saw signs
that point to the existence
of some horrible monstrosity.
That point to the existence
Holy crap, what is this?
What kind of monster could
cause such violence?
I'd hate to face off
against this thing.
Hey, what's this?
Is it a part of the monster
Spring Mustachio fought?
There may have been
a territorial dispute.
a territorial dispute
between the monsters...
Seems like there's definitely
"something" here.
We must continue our investigation
and maintain vigilance over City Z.
Hey, did you hear?
There are monsters living
in the City Z ghost town.
Yeah, rumor has it the toughest ones
are secretly plotting something.
No, no. Not that rumor.
It's about a more dangerous monster.
What's that?
You didn't hear?
I hear the place
has now become terrifying
for both humans and monsters.
For both humans and monsters.
"The Terrifying City."
Master, I filled in the holes
in front of the house.
Oh, thanks!
Also,
"Mystery Monster Defeats Class A Heroes" your rank
has gone up from last place, 388th, to 342nd.
Oh? Because of that Panic guy?
He boosted my ranking.
So it's been a week now.
Have you done anything?
No, not yet.
I guess it's only been a week.
I'm still ranked last in Class S
for ability... in 17th place.
Sounds like you've still got
a lot of training to do, Genos.
But in the public polls,
for popularity I rank number six.
Why?!
"A genius who, at the tender age
of 19, made his debut in Class S."
"He'll do great."
"He's so handsome."
"Love how he refuses to do
media interviews. Very cool."
Those kinds of comments.
You're not embarrassed
to read those out loud?
These comments are based on
impressions from my photo,
not evaluations of me.
Not evaluations of me.
I think nothing of them.
Oh yeah?
They continue.
"The Cyborg Prince."
"Behind the steely exterior,
I feel his fragile self."
"Among the top five
handsomest heroes."
Enough already!
"Next Episode :
The Ultimate Disciple."
"Next Episode : The Ultimate
Disciple" This is Blizzard.
"Next Episode : The Ultimate Disciple" Perhaps
you know me better as "Blizzard from Hell"?
Well, I only had a bit part
this episode.
Next on One-Punch Man
is episode 7,
"The Ultimate Disciple".
The Blizzard Bunch will
finally make its appearance.
Miss Blizzard, we're not scheduled
to go on next week!
That can't be right!