- Well, this is it.
- This is what?
This is what I bought this
morning.
- What?
- This.
The land?
No you plonker. This pile of bricks, only cost me 100
nicker, nice one, eh?
Oh shrewd move Del, yeah, I mean people
are panic-buying bricks nowadays ain't they...
Who the hell's gonna buy a
pile of old bricks off us?
Well, butcher or chemist. Who d'you think's going
to buy the bricks, builders ain't they.
Over 200 per cent profit here and all in the readies.
Come here...They've just demolished a factory here that
used to make prefabricated structures, right.
Chalets, bungalows, greenhouses, you know,
garden sheds, that sort of thing.
So I thought - using my noddle - that we'd make
enough out of the bricks alone,
but you never know what's underneath do you, eh?
Decent lengths of timber, bits of metal, you know,
few gross of them roofing tiles.
Come and see what I found.
Get yer feelers on that.
Here, that's lead Del, that's
pure lead.
There's about another 30 boxes
underneath. I estimate three ton altogether.
Three ton? What's that at
today's prices? That's that's about 1000 pounds innit?
Am I brilliant or am I brilliant? Let's get some of
it in the van, we can do it in three shifts, come on.
- Is it ours Del?
- Of course it's ours.
- Legally Del?
- Don't split hairs with me Rodney. Come on.
Oh that's the lot Del Boy.
No, no, no, no, Grandad not there.
No, no, we've got three tons of it here.
You see you've got to spread it out over a wide area,
otherwise we'll be having tea with Mrs Obooko downstairs!
Right, I hope this humping and sweating
is not disturbing you Royal Highness!
No, no, don't you mind me,
carry on.
Oh thanks a...Here, look at this Grandad, you've been
carrying this one upside down, this is the way.
You are a lazy little bark.
And what's that you're reading, eh?
It's another dirty book I suppose, is it?
Honestly you've got a mind like a brown paper envelope.
I'll have a look at that when you're finished.
It's some paperwork I found in one of them boxes...
D'you know what we've got here?
Yeah, I know what we’ve got here. We've got three ton of
lovely lead, that's what we've got here.
No, no, it's more than that... That factory was producing
prefabricated structures right?
Bungalows, garden sheds, that sort of stuff. Well, this
is one of their experimental lines -
it's a do-it-yourself
nuclear fall-out shelter!
Nuclear fall-out shelter, you
are a wally.
No, it is. Honest. Look, here's the brochure. Here's the plans
shows you how to build it.
He's right an' all. This is a nuclear fall-out shelter. This
is probably worth more than we thought.
You can't sell it.
You don't want to put money on it do you?
What do you suggest we do with it? Build it?
- Yeah!
- Leave it out Rodney!
Do you realise how close we came to World War Three over
Cuba, Vietnam, Afghanistan and Poland?
I mean, it only takes one little rumble in the middle
East then missiles are gonna start flying!
And what have we got, eh, in this country to
combat the might of the Soviet Union?
Three jump-jets and a
strongly worded letter to the Russian Ambassador!
No, no, no, you don't know what we've got
up our sleeves, us Brits Rodney.
Do you know Rodney that we've got a device
that can track the movements of any Russian nuclear submarine?
They can't keep track on ours.
- We've only got one.
- Have we?
Yeah I think so.
Well anyway, they don't know where it is...
I sometimes wonder whether we do!
I bet your life we don't. You see this country is just not
prepared for war,
I mean, nobody knows what we're
supposed to do in the event.
Yes, of course we do.
Alright then, what would you
do if you heard the four minute warning?
Well, what's it sound like the
first?
Well, that's it, no one knows.
Maybe they're gonna ring church bells,
or bang tom-toms or send every ice-cream van
out in the country to play its jingle.
Your guess is as good as mine innit? Do you realise
the great powers have got underground salvos
primed with enough nuclear weapons to destroy this planet
30 times over. I'm talking about neutron bombs, Del,
multi-warheads - chemicals that  attack your central nervous
system, and leave you writhing in agony like a worm in bleach.
Bit like after a curry you mean? No, no, it's alright
Rodney, don't worry, forget about it.
Look we've got 1000 pounds here. Just think what we
could o with 1000 pounds. Eat, drink and be merry...
For tomorrow we die!! Oh come on Del, this is a Godsend.
Look if we build this thing we're gonna be safe, ain't we.
Everything's here, the inner walls, the outer walls,
the air tube, the filter system, everything!!
Oh come on Del. Oh sorry.
Alright soppy, just suppose,
just suppose, that we do build this thing, right.
Where we gonna
put it?
Well, you always fancied a little weekend place. Why don't
we find a spot in the New Forest?
And how are we gonna get from Peckham to the New Forest
in four minutes, you old div?
Grandad's allotment? That's only a couple of miles up the
road, we could do that in four minutes.
Yeah, on a Sunday, with a
following wind, maybe.
Well let's give it a go, eh? We'll have a dummy run and time
ourselves. I'll get the stopwatch.
What - what you, look, I mean, what's the point eh?
Alright, so say you can do it in four minutes,
what is it going to prove. Knowing them Russian rats
they'll probably declare war in the middle of the rush hour.
- Where's grandad?
- I don't know.
Grandad, come on, hurry up you
stupid old git.
Never mind your fag, get in.
Three minutes and counting.
Yes, alright Rodney.
The missiles are just going
over Sweden!
They're bloody fast aren't they, they only left Siberia
20 seconds ago.
Two minutes 15 seconds and counting Del. The missiles are
over the sea and approaching Middlesbrough.
Yes, yes, alright Rodney.
Put yer foot down Del Boy!
I can't Grandad.
Look, I'm going to the main road, ain't I?
What's it like your side
Rodney?
Alright after this red one.
No!!
- Bloody hell...
- I meant that red one!
You tit Rodney.
- Come on Del, they're just going over Luton.
- Sod Luton.
One minute 35 and counting.
Oh Gordon Bennett.
Switch the...Wayne...the siren ...switch it off!
He's young, enthusiastic...
Well, how are you then Del Boy?
- Not too bad Eric. How's yourself?
- Can't complain...How are you then Grandad?
Alright Eric boy.
Now what's all that about? 60 miles an hour in a built-up
area. You just herd the four- minute warning or something...
Well as it happens, Eric...
- Where's yer tax disc? Fell off did it?
- In the post.
Well, why haven't you got a little sign on your windscreen
saying 'Tax in Post'?
We did have - it fell off.
- You been at those funny fags again, Rodney?
- No I haven't.
Good, 'cos Wayne here's looking for his first nick...
Talking of that Del Boy, you might be able to help me.
I'm on the look-out for some stolen summer-wear,
short- sleeved shirts and blouses,
men's and women's slacks,
swimming trunks, bikinis.
You after promotion Eric?
No, me and me wife are off to Corfu next month,
gotta look the part ain't yer?
Well if I hear of anything
I'll let you know.
Good luck. I'll see you around.
And oi, take it easy will you...
.
Stop playing with that siren
will you Wayne, you'll end up breaking it!
- Here, how are we doing for time?
- We died 45 seconds ago.
Terrific. We're never gonna do
this run in four minutes.
Oh, it don't matter, it's not
the end of the world is it.
I thought that's exactly what
it was.
All we got to think about is a
place closer to home.
I've been thinking.
Oh my God, you haven't got an
aspirin you can give him have you Rodney?
No listen. I may have found us
just the spot.
Is that door shut tight Del?
Yes, don't worry Rodney, no radiation can get in here!
Here, what's this pipe!
Oi, don't do that Del, it's fragile. Del, Del, don't do it.
Del, this is our air-filter, our life line,
our umbilical cord and one thing you must never
do with an umbilical cord is bash it about with a hammer!
I see, so this is our only source of oxygen is it, eh?
What happens if a pigeon decides to nest
in the other end, we're all dead I suppose,
are we?
Statistics prove that pigeons
rarely nest in the middle of nuclear wars!
- We're not in the middle of a nuclear war.
- We're practicing for one!
Yeah, well, do the bloody
pigeons know that?
Look, a pigeon will not nest
in our air tube...Have faith in me please.
How can you have faith in him, eh, Del Boy?
I brings me telly in here then he finds out the signals
can't get through the lead!
I've said I'm sorry ain't I Grandad. There's some pages
missing out of this brochure,
and you can't expect me to know everything can yer?
Anyway, that's why we're having this weekend's practice
so we can iron out
all the little wrinkles.
Yeah, well I'll tell you one thing
we've got to iron out.
And that is this has got to be back on that building site
first thing Monday morning otherwise them Paddies'll go mad.
You, you are a wally, you
really are!
You don't have to stay here Del!
I do have to stay and I'll tell you why I have to stay here.
I've got a grand's worth of lead tied up in this shelter
and I'm not gonna leave it in your hands.
Knowing you two, you'd probably lose it!
Just think what I could do with a grand, eh?
Fly to America on Concorde.
I could buy myself one of them flash Rolex watches.
Have me adenoids taken out privately.
Yeah, but how many people can boast they have their own
private nuclear fall-out shelter?
Yes, that's true, knowing your bloody luck there won't even
be a bloody war...Here that's what we ought to do you know,
we ought to drop a bomb on all them Russian cities,
you see and declare war on them.
And what we say is that the declaration
for war got held up in the post
due to a communist-inspired strike at
a sorting office.
Yeah, that's typical of a
ruthless little mercenary like you innit?
What d'you mean ruthless mercenary? I'm not a ruthless
mercenary. Who is it goes round at every Christmas
making sure all the old people
have got enough to eat and drink?
Yeah, and who is it, during the Brixton riots, drove down in
the van selling paving stones to the rioters?
I mean, what did you think they were going to do with them?
All run off home and start building patios.
Mine is not to reason why,
mine is but to sell and buy! No, anyway.
Anyway I know a lot of them youngsters down in
Brixton and their trouble and frustration.
Yes, you see, modern society has denied them
their birthright of a war!
Oh I don't believe you! You
saying war's our birthright?
Oh yes, yes it is. For century after century you see every
generation of British youth has been guaranteed a decent war!
Well that's sort of, you know, raw, 'Over the top chaps, you
know, try that one on for size Fritz'
I mean that sort of courage is obsolete. Because the next war's
gonna be fought by computer programmers...
See, that's what's frustrating the modern youth! You can see them
any day down the amusement arcade, you know,
they're doing their national service on the space invaders.
Yeah but that sort of, of real war that I'm talking about,
you know Errol Flynn leading the gallant 600 into the
Valley of Death. John Mills marooned in a dinghy,
it's Kenneth More refusing to let a little thing
like no legs get him down. It's a glorious war that!
- Don't talk like a berk Del!
- Do what?
What do you know about it anyway? The only war you've ever
fought is the inch war!
Ah no, I've seen all the films
ain't I.
Ah tomato sauce and stuntmen... I'm talking about the real
thing. I remember when I was a little nipper
and I saw the soldiers marching off to
battle. Oh yes, it was a glorious sight alright!
Yeah I bet all them spears and
chariots must have stirred the blood mustn't they?
- Just hear him out will you!
- Alright, alright.
My brother George was at Passchendale. Nigh on half a
million Allied troops died there,
all for five miles of mud! I was at King's Cross station
when his regiment came home after the armistice.
Most of them was carried off the train. I saw men with limbs
missing, blind men - men who couldn't breathe properly
'cos their lungs had been shot to bits by mustard gas!
While the nation celebrated
they was hidden away in big grey buildings,
far from the public gaze.
I mean, courage  like that could put you right off
your victory dinner couldn't it?
They promised us homes fit for
heroes, they give us heroes fit for homes!
I'd never wear a British
uniform - on principle!
What principle?
Well on the principle that the
Russians might shoot at it!
The politicians, and the military men used to
con you see. They had little lads, youngsters believing
that their country really did need them! D'you know,
they used to have little lads of 14
pretending they was 18 just so
they could fight for their king and country!
What, and they accepted the
little sprogs?
More often than not...My brother
George lied about his age!
Pretended he was 18?
No, he was 18, he pretended he was 14,
they saw through it though.
I think it was the moustache.
- Oh yeah 'cos 14-year-olds they don't...
- Bloody hell...
Oi, oi, what are you doing?
I think there's a pigeon trying to nest in our air tube.
Think I've frightened it away, now don't worry!
The battery's
getting a bit low an' all.
Here, these batteries you've
got here. How long do they last?
About 12 hours each!
12 hours? Cor, we been 'ere 12 hours, only another 36 to go.
Don't time fly when you're having fun...
Here, here Oppenheimer, listen if the bomb was to drop round
here, how long would we have to stay inside this thing here?
Well, it depends upon the degree of the contamination in
the air outside. 'Cos we're very vulnerable position here
being close to the dock. But I would say roughly - give or
take a week or two - about... two years!
- Two years?
- Yeah, give or take a week or two!
If you think I'm staying in a lead-lined nissan hut with you
and Grandad and a chemical khazi you've got another think coming.
Yeah, but if we leave the shelter within two years we'd
die of radiation poisoning!
And if we stay inside the shelter for two years we'll
die of bloody lead poisoning.
He's right Rodney. The rescue team will whip us straight
round the nearest scrap metal yard!
Yeah, that's another point, that's a point. Listen, oi!
These batteries are supposed to purify the air right,
they last 12 hours, right?
Okay how many of them are we gonna need?
Come on Einstein, you're the one with the GCE in Maths!
Well, it's two a day, seven
days a week two sevens are 14.
See that Grandad - two sevens
are 14. Just like that, no hesitation.
Shut up will yer! So that's 14
times 52...
- Twice!
- I know! So that works out at about 1450-odd.
Well, that's not too bad, I thought we were gonna need a
lot! What we're gonna need is 1450-odd heavy duty batteries,
about five ton of canned food,
30,000 gallons of fresh drinking water,
and a three and 'arf acre warehouse
to store it all in!
Well I did say we'd have to
iron out a few little wrinkles, didn't I?
Few little wrinkles? A few little wrinkles? We've got
more wrinkles than a elephant's got in his bleedin' trunk!
All in all, and taking every thing in consideration Rodney,
I think I would rather be outside and go instantly with the bomb!
Instantly eh? And what makes you so sure it'd ne instant eh Del?
Them bombs contain Strontium 90 not Nescafe!
You see the bomb explodes bout a mile above the city right,
causing a radioactive rain to fall.
Now this radiation then penetrates the pores of the
skin causing violent sores and diseases.
Um, best not to wear anything
decent then eh?
Will you be serious for one minute. Look, it's here once
the radiation is in the blood stream
it begins to attack your metabolism. You'll become subject
to drastic biological changes, that's metamorphosis!
Yeah anyway, your shape and form will alter radically as
the mutation takes effect!
Don't sound too promising do it Del Boy, I mean you have a
job to get a suit off the peg now don't yer!
Alright, alright, you can laugh, but I'm telling you,
this city would be inhabited by roaming mobs of mutants!
Vacant eyed sub-humans dragging their knuckles through the
litter and debris that was once civilization.
Sounds a bit like Stamford Bridge after a bad result...
Look if this is true Rodney
what the hell are we doing
trying to survive?
Well, it's our duty ain't it, I mean when we step out of here
we're gonna be intact, perfect.
Yeah, well I mean you know, the human race will be
looking to people like us to replenish the species,
we'll be like two new Adams going
forth to multiply.
Yeah! And you, you dirty little ram, will be out there
multiplying quicker than a pocket calculator!
I see it all now, he's practically praying
for the end of civilization just so he can get out there
and put it about a bit! What time do you
make it Rodney?
Ten past 12.
Oh yeah, I make it that too. C'mon then Grandad it's
bedtime, come on.
Well, as the saying goes, if my species needs me I will not
be found wanting.
Yeah, anyway that's one thing
to look forward to innit Grandad, eh?
You know, come the end of the war me and Rodney
are gonna make a foursome with a couple of mutants!
I'll have one with three lug 'oles and the eye
underneath her arm, 'cos I don't fancy yours much!
It won't be like that!!!
You bet your sweet bippy it won't! It won't make any
difference to you anyway,
you go out with mutants in peacetime! I mean look at
that thing you took out on Thursday!
Cor, stroll on, I was so embarrassed I had to
tell my mates you were taking it to market!
I did try and warn you it was
a bit ragged!
Bit ragged! You liar! You said
to me it looked like the one out of Abba!
Yes, I meant the one with the beard, anyway we won't be the
only ones to survive the holocaust intact, will we?
I mean I'm thinking of the various institutions -
public schools, that sort of thing.
I mean you bet your life
Rodney’s got a shelter.
Eh Del? A thousand nubile girls - in a shelter...in
school uniform!
You sicko!
No, no, don't misunderstand me. I mean the school uniforms
are of no importance whatsoever.
I don't know why I mentioned
them.
No, no, it's probably because you're a twisted perverted
corrupted, warped little pervo!
Well, yeah, that might have something to do with it!
It's in the line of duty Del!
They're perfect specimens.
They're intelligent.
Course they're intelligent,
they're still at bloody school ain't they?
They're fit - all that hockey!
You might fancy the headmistress!
Oh thank you very much.
Well, I think it's definitely
worth bearing in mind. In an emergency.
- Yeah alright, well, goodnight Rodney.
- Goodnight Del.
- Night Grandad.
- Goodnight Rodney.
- Night John Boy.
- Shut up.
- War is hell!!
- What?
- War is hell! Alan Ladd said that.
- Did he really? Go to sleep.
- Or was it Audie Murphy?
- I dunno, I'm tired.
It must have been one of 'em!
Well perhaps they both bloody
said it! Now go to sleep will you.
No, that was Rock Hudson!
For crying out loud, will you two go to sleep.
Rodney...Here Rodney
don't keep yer eyes closed - I'm talking to you!
What?
I've just been thinking. Might not be a bad idea to survive
the next war after all!
Why? You got something up yer
sleeve Del?
No, no, just a little idea that's been running round in
me old brain box, that's all.
What's the point? All the animals will be dead. Won't be
able to grow nothing 'cos all the earth'll be contaminated!
Where we gonna get something
to eat?
Bound to be  little Paki shop open somewhere! But we won't
be the only ones to survive will we?
I was just thinking
about all them girls down at that Roedean School.
No, no, no, no, nothing like that, nothing like that. I was
just thinking you see, most of those girls down there,
they are daughters of the noblesses!
The what Del?
The noblesse, the noblesses.
It's French for nobility ain't it eh?
Oh sorry - I was miles off.
Well you see, down there you don't know who's who, do you?
I mean you could meet a scruffy 17-year-old
in a sweaty hockey shirt and muddy plimsoles,
and you could be talking to the 459th in line
for the throne! But after the old Russians have dropped 20
thousand nuclear bombs on us that scruffy 17-year-old
could turn out to be the first in line for the throne.
So, you see, if I got on my bike,
nip down there a bit sharpish like, did me Adams act -
splash of Brut, you know, took her out for a steak meal -
loads of charm - I could end up being the King!
On the other hand a bit of mutation,
a touch of Strontium 90, I could end up being the
Queen. But either way, either way,
see it wouldn't matter because the taxman wouldn't be
able to get at me, would he, eh?
Because I would be the head of State. And what with
you out there multiplying all over the place,
I shouldn't be short of a few subjects,
should I, eh?
We, we could go for our
holidays in Mustique.
- What? What?
- Grandad could be the Queen Mother!
Yeah, we'll dye his hat pink... yeah, yeah. No even if that
didn't happen and I can't honestly see how I could fail.
You see if the entire civilization was wiped out
we'd all be equal wouldn't we,
'cos none of us would have
nothing, right.
- Right!
- Except us Rodney!
Well what would we have Del?
A grands worth of lead eh...
pretty shrewd, eh Rodney?
Yeah, that's a real mindbender
Del, that!
No, no, we'll be alright. We'll survive Rodney,
d'you know why? Because we're survivors that's why.
When did the alarm bells start ringing and the missiles start
firing, and all the people are rushing about
like mad mice trying to find somewhere to hide,
we'll be tucked up in our own little nuclear shelter.
The end of the world could be just the break we're
looking for! Oh we're pretty shrewd Rodney.
If they started dropping the bomb on us right now
we'd be as safe as houses brother, safe as houses!
Subtitles by NVL