What do you know.
Christmas in La Rochelle.
- Real girls in our Christmas stockings.
- The sweet telephone operators.
- The sexy newsgirls.
- We'll fuck our brains out.
A nice, slow, afternoon fuck.
- Now hear this.
- The master's voice.
La Rochelle's out.
We've got a new port of destination.
La Spezia.
That's in the Mediterranean,
as you know.
First, we'll pick up fuel and supplies
at Vigo.
That's in Spain. Over.
Shit.
They must be crazy.
- What a dirty, rotten trick.
- There goes our Christmas stocking.
No sexy little newsgirls. No whores.
I'd like to kill those morons!
Christmas in macaroni land,
I've wished for that.
We've got to get there first,
to get to them!
- Why?
- Why? Gibraltar!
You can figure out what that means!
That's as narrow as a virgin.
If you want to get through that, we need
to cover our boat with Vaseline.
Securing Rommel's supply routes,
that's our official job.
They're losing Africa.
We're called to the rescue.
It's insane.
We haven't enough U-boats
in the Atlantic as it is.
Mediterranean.
It's madness.
It's swarming
with English combat ships.
Werner, stand by.
Zero...
...25 degrees, 43.3 minutes.
Gibraltar.
It's the best chance
to get ourselves killed.
When we reach Vigo, you go ashore,
Lieutenant Werner. You and the chief.
But, sir...
I've already made the decision.
I've got to find me a replacement
for the chief.
Our agents will smuggle you out
of Spain somehow.
Dressed up as Gypsies, for instance.
- But, captain, I thought I'd be going...
- No heroism.
It's all been settled.
It's easier to get two of you out.
Our agents will smuggle you
out of Spain somehow.
The chief needs a break.
He must get home.
I understand, sir
The silence onboard is oppressive.
Each man isolated by an inner struggle
to overcome his disappointment.
But most of all, his fear.
Supplies in Vigo?
But that's not possible.
It's not up to you to worry about it.
But Spain is neutral.
You're pretty smart.
They should have asked you first.
Tough break.
When we reach Vigo, it's goodbye.
Together with the chief.
The captain's ordered it.
So...
...I could deliver your mail for you.
Yeah.
There's quite a bunch of them here.
Well, it's quite a romance, isn't it?
Vigo, Spain.
Peacetime city...
...in a neutral country.
They won't be too happy
about our presence.
Tuesday, 64th day
My longing for the sight of dry land
is so overwhelming...
...sometimes I think I can actually
smell it. Only 24 hours to go.
Equalize.
Guess how long
I've been wearing this shirt.
- Since we sailed.
- No, three weeks before that.
Pipe down.
- Switch to white light.
- Hurry up with that gear.
Quiet, man!
All ahead one-third.
Left 10 degrees, rudder.
Can you see the klieg lights?
On the port bow,
double and triple flashes, wide.
There, navigation lights...
- ...a fishing boat.
- She won't spot us.
Traffic's pretty heavy around here.
We'd better make sure
we don't run anyone down.
Right, Kriechbaum?
That's a new one.
Right.
Keep a check on water depth.
Twenty-six metres.
- Lieutenant.
- 26.5 metres.
- Thank you.
- Twenty-six metres. Constant.
Now we just have to find
this little barge.
SS Weser.
German merchant ship.
She's got herself interned here.
With a bellyful of torpedoes,
fuel and supplies.
- And that's all for us, Kriechbaum.
- Yeah, first-class service.
Starboard beam,
is it a customs launch?
No, fishing trawler.
- There.
- Where?
Over there, sir.
Signaling an A,
a code for us to approach.
Both engines ahead two-thirds.
Left 5 degrees, rudder.
We arrived.
Port engine stop.
Officers to bridge.
Gentlemen.
Three cheers for our brave U-boat men.
- Sieg...
- Heil.
- Heil!
- Sieg...
Welcome, captain lieutenant.
No, no. Please.
This is...
- This is our commander.
- My apologies, sir. I...
A pleasure to have you aboard
the Weser, captain lieutenant.
A hero.
I'm delighted to be so honoured.
Gentlemen, here they stand...
our heroes of the deep.
The Grey Wolves.
Our humble ship is honoured...
...by the momentous occasion
such as this is.
Captain, lead the way.
- Welcome aboard.
- Nice tugboat you got here.
Looking forward to meeting you.
So here we are, captain.
...we've done what we can in our
modest way. I hope it's to your taste.
Quite a table. Just like home.
Fresh bread,
cakes from the ship's bakery...
...belly of pork, fresh sausage,
slaughtered today, of course.
Well, we're waiting to hear your news.
Can't imagine what it means to us.
It isn't easy here. Despite what
people say, it's very frustrating.
Sure, there's plenty to eat.
Fuel supply's no problem.
Torpedoes are tricky, though.
Very tricky. Never mind.
You're all set up.
The Spaniards tolerate us,
but you couldn't call them enthusiastic.
Christmas cake.
Now, tell us...
...how many ships have you sunk?
Now, let's see. I guess about...
Oh, champagne. How forgetful of me.
Take a glass.
Gentlemen, raise your glasses.
Drink to our heroes.
We're proud of you.
To the German U-boats service
and to our beloved... -
Oh, yes. We're not exactly at home,
if you understand what I mean.
Toast. All the best.
Cheers.
And now, plenty for everyone.
Come on.
- Okay. Let's get down to business.
- Yes, come along.
Yes, now, tell us all about it, captain.
Continue.
I'm bursting with curiosity.
Those are fresh figs.
Fresh figs.
Never had one.
Keep quiet.
This time, we very nearly had it.
Phenomenal.
See, gentlemen,
that's the stuff heroes are made of.
There's no other word for it
except "phenomenal."
Come on, captain, I want to hear more.
Here, give me your plate.
Herring salad,
another specialty of our chef.
You have to try it.
His mother's recipe.
Yes, and so...
...what's it like to be underwater?
To be submerged...
...while overhead,
the enemy lies in wait.
It's dark.
- Dark?
- Yes, and very quiet.
Just as long as no one farts.
- Why is that?
- Well, as long as no one...
I can explain.
Our Number Two means...
...at silent speed, the men must always
exercise discipline.
And that's why
you're forbidden to fart, yes?
Captain?
Herr Seewald,
we've been expecting you.
Captain, over here.
Heil, Hitler.
Representative of our
naval attaché here.
Heil, Hitler, captain.
I brought some communications
from Berlin.
First, the documents
for the breakthrough.
And then...
...this cable came.
Chief. Lieutenant Werner.
We are going for a little fresh air.
- Well, Seewald, what's happening?
- Bad news.
Headquarters say no.
Our request has been denied, chief.
There's no replacement.
You stay too, Werner.
I'm sorry.
I guess it's just as well.
Who knows what kind of idiot
they'd have sent you.
One of those newfound warriors
who's all wind and smoke.
Could be right.
I've never been to the Mediterranean.
They say the climate is supposed to be...
No heroic pretence, Mr. Werner.
You don't know what that means.
I don't know.
Something doesn't feel right.
Three boats refurbished here recently.
Two of them sank
as soon as they moved out of the sea.
Remarkable, huh?
Are you still interested to hear about
depth-charge attacks?
Hey, steward, bring a punch bowl here.
- One glass, sir?
- No, not a glass, just the bowl.
Come on, gentleman,
if you don't mind, stand over here.
And you too, my friend. Here comes
a spectacular phenomenon.
- This is the Atlantic, I presume.
- Atlantic, sea, what you will.
Or the channel, by the looks of it.
Pretty narrow crossing.
So now, then. Here, we're down here.
That little lemon pit there.
And hang in there tight.
- Oh, yeah?
- You got it, pal, because...
...the British ships are cruising
here above us.
The British know very well
we're down there.
Though they still don't know
where exactly.
There are two possibilities.
- To wait, hoping you'll surface.
- That's one.
- Or drop their depth charge.
- Where he assumes us to be.
There we are waiting.
Now, will he drop them or not?
Well, I do believe they missed us again.
Those cardboard soldiers.
Those strange guys
from the naval attach?
I feel they can't be trusted,
could talk too easily.
We'll push off from this place
as quickly as we can.
Forget our schedule.
This is not my kind of place.
They should have stocked the sub
with a few horny little senoritas.
Lucky they didn't, lover-boy.
Spanish crabs, that's all we'd need.
Yesterday he was a virgin.
Now he can't live without it.
Hurry up and get this mess out of here.
Get that chart table cleared.
I can't navigate on bananas.
What are you doing?
Get that fruit out of here. Move!
I want those depth controls
completely free.
- Where should we put them?
- Is that a Christmas tree?
What do you think it is,
camouflage for the bridge?
We're staying onboard.
They won't replace us.
I'm sorry, Ullmann.
Our 68th day at sea.
We are nearing Gibraltar.
One question dominates our thoughts
to the exclusion of all others:
Will we get through?
Seven miles from coast-to-coast.
Bit narrow, huh?
Here, the British dockyards.
The only ones the British have
in the Western Mediterranean.
So they are very heavily defended.
The place will be crawling
with patrol boats.
Anything that floats
will be on the water.
And this is where we have to go.
That's the situation.
Gibraltar, where the mildness and
beauty of the Mediterranean world...
...meet the force and expansion
of the Atlantic realm.
So says the sea handbook.
We'll move in under darkness.
The surface.
We'll see if we can slip through
their cordon.
As near to Gibraltar as we can get.
Then dive down...
...and let ourselves drift through.
In the Strait of Gibraltar,
there are two different currents.
One flows on the surface from
the Atlantic into the Mediterranean...
...and a deeper current,
from the Mediterranean out.
That's a lot of pressure.
And so...
...dive...
...and allow the surface current
to pull us through the strait.
Nice and quiet.
And we'll save fuel.
Well, Kriechbaum?
Clever trick, captain.
Arabian week.
Must be our southerly course.
They're hoping to drink
some courage.
- Time check, please.
- 9:39, sir.
We're getting close now.
Be accurate.
Keep checking the water control.
Don't worry, chief.
We've got enough air here.
Double-check the high valves.
I'll check them, sir.
Stupid bananas.
Goddamn it!
Be careful, you idiot!
Both engines stop.
Let's get going.
Both engines half-speed.
The navigator and I stay up here.
Now clear the bridge.
I'm right. 0-7-9.
Then, course 0-7-9, sir.
That's half the British fleet out there.
Come left 20 degrees
and change to main motors.
Steering 0-5-9, sir.
Very kind of the enemy
to show their navigation lights.
- Steer 0-5-0.
- Course 0-5-0.
Destroyer on port bow.
Range about 800.
Going which way?
Is she closing?
No, she's heading away.
That's good.
Breakthrough. Astern of her.
Left full rudder.
- All full ahead.
- Rudder is left full.
Both engines ahead.
Come right.
All full ahead, maximum power.
Right full.
Come on. Quick.
Make it quick.
Both engines indicate maximum rpm.
1-0-0, still turning right.
Now he's in his element.
Course 0-7-9.
All ahead half power.
Right full rudder!
All full ahead! Be quick!
- Right full rudder. All full ahead.
- Damn! Damn!
Kriechbaum.
Gibraltar.
We'll dive in 10 minutes.
Alarm!
Go.
The captain is still up. Don't dive.
Alarm!
Stand by, escape gear!
Ready to abandon ship!
The medic! Right away!
- Where is the medic?
- Medic!
Engines, maximum power!
Hard, starboard!
All hands on escape gear!
Hold on. Hold on to this!
Faster! Faster!
Compress this! Compress this!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Out of the way! Silence onboard!
Chief to captain, we have to stop
port engine! Foundation is loose!
Maintain full power!
All the power you've got!
What's his plan?
Due south. Heading directly
for the African coastline.
Damn it! Damn it!
- Alarm!
- Ready to dive!
All hands forward!
Move, move, move!
Ninety metres!
Close exhausts.
- Bow planes are in action!
- Switch to manual!
The bow plane is jammed!
It's on a dive!
Shit!
All engines stop!
- All men go aft!
- All hands aft! All hands aft!
- What is going on?
- Quiet.
Move! Move! All hands aft!
- Auxiliary pump, out of action!
- With air.
- Tank's blowing.
- We're still going down.
- We've got to shed some weight!
- Pump out 1000 litres!
Damn it, shut him up!
Main ballast pump, out of action!
Permission to blow?
- Both engines hard to stern full!
- Hard to stern full.
- No effect.
- Blow.
- Blow!
- Blow fore ballast.
Stay put. Now.
Now. Stay put now!
All that you've got! All you've got!
All that we've got!
Come on!
Oh, God!
We can't hold the boat.
200.
210.
220 metres.
230.
240 metres.
250 metres.
My God.
Oh, Lord, turn not away from me.
Dear Lord, take away all our sins.
A shovelful of sand.
The merciful God's left a shovelful
of sand to keep us up.
280 metres.
And she's still in one piece.
Water. Goddamn it.
Torpedo hatch taking water!
The torpedo hatch taking water!
Motor room's taking water now,
right behind starboard.
Tank two taking water.
Get around.
- Tank two taking water!
- What do you need?
- Some timber for sawing.
It's in the bow compartment.
Exhaust valve okay?
I need some flooring, quick.
Shit.
Pass it to me.
Give me that flashlight!
- I need a wrench, damn it!
- Give me damage report.
Water coming in
around the after rail.
- Where are the tools?!
- Quick, quick, quick.
The tools!
- Where is it?
- Look.
Main motor switchboard's
out of action.
- Engine room's completely wrecked.
- I want some proper damage reports!
What's going on down there?
We can't stop the flooding!
If saltwater gets in the bearings,
we've had it.
Together.
Where's the most damage?
The shaft's stuffing boxes,
below the decoy.
Check damage to number two battery.
Quickly!
Assess damage!
Tighten carefully.
- I can't see!
- Push! Hard as you can!
I can't.
It's stuck tight!
I can't wedge it.
Here, give me the hammer!
Need a little more men
in aft torpedo room?
I'll ask the lieutenant.
This damn thing! Here, hold my light!
Father, forgive my sins.
Stupid son of a pig!
Idiot.
Toolbox from the engine room!
Hurry up!
Where is that damn wrench?
Bring another wrench!
Tighten those seals!
Don't shear the bolts!
A leak in the cooling system!
Tighten those intake seals!
Hurry up!
Someone give me that shoring.
- Here!
- Good.
Here, take it quickly!
Plugs down here! Quick!
Hurry up! Get me the biggest one!
Higher! Still higher!
Higher!
Careful.
Captain.
Hurry! Hurry! Get on with it.
We're taking water very fast.
The two hull valves burst.
Cooling water system blocked.
And on top of that,
compressors are dislodged.
Shaft stuffing boxes
began to leak, sir.
Damn it.
What about fuel leaks?
Any tank's been punctured?
- Can't tell as yet.
- What else, chief?
Lots of battery cells are cracked,
can't take this kind of hit.
Look out for chlorine gas, men.
Get the bilge water.
Use the litmus paper.
Over there with
the sounding block.
We need each cell.
Look, it's red.
Acid in the bilge.
Piece of line, quickly.
See how many cells are cracked.
Battery straps over here.
Move it, you.
Battery straps.
Easy, Kriechbaum. Quiet. Quiet.
Quiet.
Lieutenant.
Have we a chance?