Both planes steady at zero.
Level at 60 metres.
Is it getting louder?
Seems constant. Ahead of us.
2-8-0.
Two hundred and eighty...
Thirty-five...
Drawing further ahead, 2-9-5.
- Left full rudder.
Rudder is left full, sir.
Steer due north.
- Deeper, chief.
- Bow planes down 15. Stern up 10.
Pump 200 litres forward.
All ahead one-third.
200 metres forward, chief.
Both main motors indicate
ahead one-third.
Now it gets psychological, friends.
Check torpedo tubes!
For God's sake!
Easy. Easy, guys.
This is nothing.
Kill unnecessary lights.
- Kill lights.
Silent speed.
Both main engines at 50 rpm.
Both engines indicate 50 rpm.
Contact coming closer,
0-5-2 degrees, starboard bow, closing.
Closing fast.
Midships.
Both main engines full ahead.
Right full rudder.
Both main engines indicate full ahead.
Coming straight for us, sir.
He knows what he's doing. Deeper.
Bow down 20. Stern up 5.
Destroyer coming nearer.
Almost above us now.
- Deeper, chief, quick.
- Stern up 10.
Don't be afraid.
It's only the pressure.
Deeper.
Stern up 15.
Pump out 250 litres.
Come on, hurry!
Tighten this flange!
Hurry up!
Bring her up 150 metres, chief!
Forward 20! Stern down 10!
Come on, Frenssen, quickly!
Come on, tighter, Frenssen! Hurry!
Get the damn thing tightened!
Depth-gauge hull valves secured.
Both planes are eased to zero.
Level at 150 metres.
Becoming louder.
She's turned around, 0-5-5.
Go on, get it over.
Contact closing fast.
They're above us.
Just above us.
Contact fading to starboard.
Twenty-two.
Twenty-three.
They are far away.
Contact receding aft.
Can barely hear it.
Now?
It has passed us by.
I think that will be all this time.
Silent speed.
Both main engines silent speed,
50 rpm.
Both main engines indicate 50 rpm.
- All compartments report damage.
All compartments report damage.
From my private collection.
- How does it look in the engine room?
- It's smashed up quite badly.
- Be able to patch her up at sea?
- Already started.
Be sure and make it good, chief.
I've got a feeling we're
going to see some action.
Nothing?
Waited over an hour now.
- I guess we've frightened them off, sir.
- Don't be so sure.
He could have stopped
and is still there waiting...
...to surprise us
when we try to surface.
Not dumb, the British.
Stay on silent speed.
When it's dark, we'll surface.
- Aye, aye, captain.
- I guess we'll see.
Captain.
Thanks.
- What's the light like up top?
- It's dark. Sun set two hours ago.
Prepare to surface, 30 metres.
- Thirty metres.
- Bow planes up 15, stern planes up 5.
Ninety.
Eighty metres.
Seventy.
Sixty metres.
Fifty.
Coming up fast.
- Sound check at 30.
- Planes at zero. Stern down 3.
Level at 30 metres.
Well?
- Come to periscope depth.
Bow up 3.
- Surface.
- Bow set to blow.
We made it.
We have returned from hell.
If only your mother could see you now!
- What's he doing here?
- I don't know.
It's the cylinder head gasket.
Probably just a loose bolt.
Can you tighten it?
We got a call from U-48.
- We'll talk about it.
- Yes. I'll be there right away.
- Do we have to turn in off?
- Yes, lieutenant.
Cut it out! All this damn noise!
I got bad news, guys.
What's up now?
Our soccer team is losing.
Five to zero.
Not a chance of making the finals now.
It can't be! I just don't believe it!
Weather forecast,
very low pressure.
Wind speeds up to 150 to 200
kilometres per hour.
Heavy disturbance,
resulting from interaction between...
...subtropical and polar air currents.
This means a storm.
Drop them.
You dirty little boy. Crabs.
A whole army of them.
A winkie like yours,
they'll eat it down to the bone.
Give them a blowout
with the gunpowder!
Excuse me, lieutenant.
Needs a shave, this meat does.
What are those things crawling about
on your eyebrows?
Pardon?
A case for the medic, I'd say.
Crabs, by the look of them.
- What's wrong?
- Are you joking?
When the creatures begin to surface,
it's the fifth stage.
You know, I'm certain
we'll meet a British convoy.
Too bad.
Berthold stopped communications.
Headquarters are waiting as well.
They want him to report his location.
Now this.
North Atlantic interferences.
Couldn't be worse.
Well...
At least
we're showing you a good time.
Okay, guys, get that stuff
into the torpedo room.
Hey, you two, give me a hand.
Move it. Don't fall asleep.
- Boatswain.
- Yes, lieutenant?
- Do you know where the medic is?
- In the bow compartment, lieutenant.
- Come on in. The more the merrier.
- The crabs got you too!
Hey, lieutenant,
got your swimsuit on?
Oh, darling, that's divine.
Are you looking for your camera,
lieutenant?
Hoist the sails,
the wind is blowing.
At least we don't have to deal
with airplanes in this shitty weather.
It's a hard life at sea, huh?
Not if you took it lying down.
What's the matter, lieutenant,
still can't find your camera?
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant, watch yourself, sir.
- What?
- Take it easy! Calm down!
Have you gone crazy or something?
Guess what.
Have you heard the latest?
Our Dufte is tying the knot.
- Lord help the stupid pig!
- You're such a mean bastard!
I thought he only jerks off!
They should stick you in a zoo
and mate you with a chimpanzee.
Here are pictures of
the beautiful Fräulein!
- Let me see.
- Where did you find them, asshole?
Asshole!
Are you really fucking this broad?
- I've got a great idea.
- What?
How'd you like to take
a swim in this weather?
Can you swim at all?
These boats are built to take it.
A real storm on a sailing ship.
You should try that sometime.
You hardly feel a thing down here.
- Captain?
- Compass.
The boat's heaving starboard.
I can't keep her on course.
No cause for concern.
But it is pointless, sir.
We're burning up fuel for nothing.
Prepare to dive.
- Diving stations!
- Diving stations.
Stand by, all main vents.
What a blessing. How merciful.
What a bliss.
The captain is taking
us down for an hour.
One hour...
...of peace and quiet.
Not the greatest success, is it?
Position reports, very faint.
SOS calls from enemy freighters.
Well, well...
When the rudder breaks
on one of those old tenders...
...there's nothing to do but pray.
The sea can't sink us, Hinrich.
No ship's as safe as our U-boats.
Hinrich.
Put the record on again.
You know the one.
Our 40th day at sea.
The storm has been raging now
for one whole week.
Watch out! Heads down!
Look out!
Man overboard!
Pilgrim!
Watch out! Watch out!
Watch out!
Hold on! Hold on!
I got him! Make way!
Hold on!
The first-aid kit.
Bring the first-aid kit!
Damn it!
Bring the first-aid kit! Damn it!
- Prepare to dive.
- The first-aid kit!
"Self-discipline is the only road
to military leadership.
No form of training is possible
without his example."
Three ribs cracked
and a gash on the head.
He was lucky.
What a rotten month.
Absolutely rotten.
Mildew is good for you.
A royal organism...
...just like hyacinths.
Anything that grows on this boat
we've got to be grateful for.
Must be snowing already back home.
"If you wish to learn the art of
leadership...
...become a whole person."
Strange.
It's been years since I've seen snow.
- Can I have a look?
- Sure.
Your wife?
The 15th day of the storm.
Look! There, in front! There!
Bridge to captain, U-boat at port bow!
A German boat! A German U-boat!
Heading 3-5-0.
Over there.
Almost straight ahead!
You're right!
- Both engines stop. Bring up the light.
- Both engines stop! Bring up the light!
Look, it's Thomsen! Thomsen!
Both engines stop. Bring up the lights.
It's Thomsen!
Good hunting, you old rascal!
My God, Phillip.
So they've pushed you
out to sea again.
Goddamn it!
A dozen boats we've got in the Atlantic!
From Greenland to the Azores,
a mere dozen!
But still we almost collide
with one of our own!
Sixty metres. Boat is trimmed, sir.
Something's wrong here.
Have you checked on our position?
- More or less, captain.
- More or less? That's not good enough!
We haven't had a sun shot in 14 days.
And we've been drifting in this storm.
Hard to compute.
I understand.
We make a few errors in our own
position, the others do the same...
...and we end up playing collision
games, leaving the route wide open.
And so we allow the British
to shove the whole armada through.
Yeah, yeah.
It's another story when you're
in the middle of the ocean, lieutenant.
I hope you're making notes of all this.
Maybe Headquarters will listen to you.
You've more influence than I have, sir.
So you believe that?
Come up 100 metres aft.
Stern planes up 10.
Hey, man, ram it with a cork,
will you? Dirty pig.
It's gas, you know.
These Brussels sprouts.
Horst!
Spirits are abysmally low.
This ordeal is putting
human endurance to the test.
It's an experiment to sound out
the limits of our ability to suffer.
It's happened at last.
After three weeks and two days...
...the storm has subsided.
From now on, the intensity and extent
of military operations in the East...
... will be governed by the onset of
the Russian winter. Despite attacks...
A signal, captain.
... German and Italian troops have had
local successes. Enemy forces met...
... with heavy losses. While bombarding
strategic targets in Leningrad...
...our artillery hit an ammunition dump,
causing severe explosions and fires.
Nothing from Thomsen?
I've been trying to make contact
with him for days.
He should have reported in by now.
You will soon be announcing
another submarine missing.
Last night, the enemy penetrated
German airspace at several points.
Nine British bombers were shot down.
Waves of enemy aircraft dropped...
...fire and high- explosive bombs...
...mainly on non military targets
in northwestern and western Germany.
A large number of civilians
in Hamburg and Cologne...
... were injured or killed.
That concludes today's broadcast...
...from the Armed Forces
High Command.
His wife lives in Cologne.
I know.
Didn't you say you had relatives
living in Cologne, Number One?
Lost my fiancée two months back
in an air raid on Cologne.
I'm sorry.
Our lack of success
is depressing the captain.
He seems to feel that the failures...
...of the entire submarine unit
are his personal responsibility.
Cut your flashlight, already.
Ready? Emergency lighting only.
It's bound to be a false alarm.
What's up?
A convoy.
- Permission to come up?
- Affirmative.
Outward-bound convoy, five columns.
Very juicy.
Any escorts in sight?
- Destroyers?
- No, no screen.
They have no protection. Nothing.
That's funny.
They could be off chasing one of ours.
Yeah.
That damn moon.
- How many of our boats are in contact?
- Five.
Do we risk it?
It's worth a try, captain.
Come left to 1-8-0.
Left 5 degrees, rudder.
New course, 1-8-0.
Steady on course 1-8-0, sir.
Kriechbaum, what's your feeling?
It will work, captain. We've got them.
- Prepare tubes 1 through 4 for firing.
- Flood tubes one through four.
I'm going in. Master sight to Bridge.
Master sight to Bridge.
Tubes one through four flooded.
All full ahead, left full rudder.
Come to 1-0-7.
Stand by to attack.
Watch the pressure
of the lubricating oil!
Bow angle bearing 0-5-0.
Locked on.
- Range, 2200 metres.
- Check.
Those two that are overlapping...
...double shot on the big one.
The other two, a single each.
- Targets identified.
- Right standard rudder.
All ahead one-third. Open bow caps.
Lock on tubes one and two.
New bow angle 0-6-3.
- Check, locked on!
- Hold on for bearing.
- All set!
- Tubes one and two, fire when matched.
- Tubes one and two ready!
- Tube one, fire!
- Tube two, fire!
- Tube three, fire when matched.
- Tube three ready!
- Tube three, fire!
Tube three fired!
- Tube four ready.
- Tube four ready!
- Tube four, fire!
Destroyer ahead!
Alarm!
All hands forward!
Forward diving position!
- Quick, quick, quick!
- Keep it moving!
- Clear the way!
- Move, move, move! Keep it moving!
Watch out!
Hurry! Hurry, hurry!