Careful.
Captain.
Hurry! Hurry! Get on with it.
We're taking water very fast.
The two hull valves burst.
Cooling water system blocked.
And on top of that,
compressors are dislodged.
Shaft stuffing boxes
began to leak, sir.
Damn it.
What about fuel leaks?
Any tank's been punctured?
- Can't tell as yet.
- What else, chief?
Lots of battery cells are cracked,
can't take this kind of hit.
Look out for chlorine gas, men.
Get the bilge water.
Use the litmus paper.
Over there with
the sounding block.
We need each cell.
Look, it's red.
Acid in the bilge.
Piece of line, quickly.
See how many cells are cracked.
Battery straps over here.
Move it, you.
Battery straps.
Lieutenant.
Have we a chance?
We'll never do it by hand.
Takes block and tackling.
The chief needs battery straps.
Make it quick.
Find some battery straps, damn it.
They still need it.
Logs and a hammer.
Here. Here.
Thanks, lieutenant.
Got it.
Get me more light here.
We're winning, sir.
And again, turn it.
Shit.
Pull it round.
The other side,
or it will tear the gasket.
Check the valves.
They came straight at us.
It's quite incredible in that light.
They say that the British
are using a new detection system...
...high frequency.
Could be true what they say.
They tried it out on us.
If they can find us in the dark...
...we can only pray.
Another bilge pipe
in the water cooling system.
- Bilge pipe in the water cooling system.
Tell the chief water is out of the bilge
in the torpedo hatch...
...rising faster.
I can't see.
Lieutenant, hold the light.
We've got to close the leaks,
or it's all over for us.
To the right. More to the right. Down.
Careful.
Twenty-four battery cells cracked.
God almighty, what a hell of a mess.
Let's hope these are enough.
He's got to bridge the live cells.
It's our only chance.
Without batteries, we've had it.
Starboard...
Down, lieutenant.
We're drowning.
Wire. Get me wire to bridge them.
Wire! Come on, hurry up!
Wire! The chief needs wire.
Get moving! Look for wires!
Did you hear me?
- Wire.
- What kind of wire?
Any kind of thick wire, man.
There's got to be some wire around.
In the bilge, under the torpedo tubes.
We have got plenty
of fancy torpedoes, right?
Each one is 25,000 marks.
But no damn wire.
All they forgot is 50 pennies' worth
of old wire.
Now what?
Captain, the draining pump's jammed.
- It won't even extend manually.
- That's great.
Captain!
- Here.
- He's got some wire!
- Terrific. Better than nothing.
- Pliers!
- Here.
- Captain?
All the leaks have been stopped, sir.
Good, Johann.
That's good.
Now change your wet things, man.
We must get rid of the water.
The water has to go out.
Into the control-room bilge...
...and then outside.
All right, give it to me!
Come on. Move it.
- Careful, you jerk!
- Hoist the bucket.
Get a move on, boys!
Keep coming and going!
Come on, put your backs into it!
Keep those buckets moving.
Step on it, Dufte, Hermann.
Don't fall asleep. Keep going!
Hurry up!
Faster, goddamn it!
Come on. Don't slow down.
Pull. Pull.
Almost finished. Three cells to go, sir.
How is it going?
Almost ready.
Three more cells.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
See, it works.
That's good.
It's all good.
Mum. Mum.
Stop, boy. Take a rest.
Fucking shit.
Make some room down there.
Chief's coming through.
- Are you guys okay?
- Yes.
Keep going. Keep going.
- Motor didn't get wet, did it, Johann?
- It looks like it, lieutenant.
Here, pass your empty buckets.
Hey, guys, switch.
Captain?
All of our compasses are out of action.
We may have lost
speed indicator and sonar too.
And radio contact seems dead.
Pretty bad damage.
Can we get up again?
Do you think we have a chance, sir?
Good question.
Bit of air must still be
in the ballast tanks...
...from the blowing.
It should help us.
If we use every ounce of
high-pressure air that's left.
Maybe.
We have to reduce our weight.
We've got to get the water out.
We must.
Eliminate and scoop.
Commander, engine-room bilge
now almost clear of water.
It could work. It could work.
It could just work.
By hand, into the trimming tanks.
Then with ballast pump
and high-pressure air...
...we could force the water out.
The ballast pump?
We can do it.
We have to risk it.
Blow.
We can only try once.
When?
When all repairs are completed.
In about six to eight hours.
- CO2 content?
- 1.8 per cent.
Do we have enough oxygen?
No.
Emergency cartridges. For all guys
who are not working.
The others go to the bunks.
Aye, aye, captain.
Emergency cartridges.
Guys not working, go to bunks.
- How is he doing?
- Difficult to say just yet, sir.
Doesn't look too good.
Well, Pilgrim...
- ...everything okay?
- Yes, captain.
Everything's okay.
What about aft?
It's getting better, sir.
I guess I'll go over there.
You should be careful.
- Can you make it?
- We'll make it, captain.
- How's it going?
- All right. It's okay.
How does it look?
Don't worry, captain,
we'll make it.
How's it going?
Two bearings which have
to be changed and fixed.
Then it should run smoothly.
Well, Benjamin, is everything okay?
Yes, captain.
What a mess.
Going well.
It's working out fine.
Yes, captain, we'll make it.
Laps of honour.
They're doing laps of honour.
Believe they made it.
They think we drowned.
Not yet.
I still have some glucose.
They were crazy...
...ordering us through the strait.
It was bound to go wrong.
He knew it.
The bastard, he knew it.
From the moment that radio signal
had come through...
...the captain knew it.
That's the reason
he ordered us ashore at Vigo.
He knew there was very little hope.
He tried to fool us.
"Quite simple," he said.
"An easy trick."
"Dive and drift with the current, and..."
Quite a clever trick.
But it has to work.
Will we ever get up?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
You think it's hopeless now?
It's been 15 hours.
He's not going to make it.
I'm sorry.
I wanted this to happen.
To face the relentless truth.
Where no one's mother
looks around at night.
No woman crossing our way.
Where only reality reigns,
ferocious and great.
I was intoxicated by it.
That is reality now.
Situation report, sir.
Motors in order.
The ballast pump is clear.
Accumulated water can now
be pumped into trimming tanks.
Then blown outboard
with high-pressure air.
Compass is in order.
Sonar clear.
Good.
Good, good.
Go and take a break.
We still have a few little problems.
All you need is a good crew.
A good crew.
And what about above?
Dusk was two hours ago.
We'll surface in 20 minutes.
Wake up. Come on, wake up.
Wake up!
- What's the matter?
- We'll surface in 20 minutes.
We're going to surface.
Wake the crew.
All hands prepare to surface.
We're coming up!
Everybody listen up.
We're going to blow...
...and see if we can get our rear up.
If so...
...it could get ugly again.
Traffic is heavy up there.
There's only one thing we can do:
Pray that the engines will start...
...so we can get out of this mess.
And let's go home.
If it works...
...everybody gets half a bottle of beer.
There's one thing on our side.
They won't be expecting us.
So, guys...
...everything okay?
Aye, aye, captain.
Surface contacts?
Nothing near.
Get ready to surface.
Stand by, escape gear.
Switch to red light.
Let her blow.
- She's rising.
- Yeah!
- Easy, guys.
- Starboard planes down 15.
270 metres!
First watch, stand by.
260 metres.
250 metres.
240 metres.
230 metres.
220.
The air lock's open.
Start up engines?
Both main engines.
Well, let's see.
So?
I think they're running.
I never heard such sweet music
in all my life.
- They're running.
Yes, they're running.
They won't catch us this time.
Not this time.
Just you keep on going, damn it.
Just you keep on going!
Right full rudder.
Come to 3-2-0.
This goddamn bastard!
They haven't spotted us.
They are snoring in their bunks.
You know what?
They are drinking in the bar,
celebrating our sinking.
Not yet, my friends!
Not yet!
Tuesday, December 23, 194 1.
Course: La Rochelle.
Drink up, boys!
- Here's to home!
Just imagine those sexy nurses.
The newspaper girls.
And Dufte and his broad
can get screwed.
How about you, Brückenwilli?
A nice, slow...
...afternoon fuck.
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve, Hinrich.
Easy to forget.
The holiday of love.
Christmas on a bombed-out hulk.
Something different.
Any bright ideas, Henri,
for the celebration?
Have our own celebration?
Sing a few carols...
...read from the Bible.
I guess we're not in the right mood.
Just postpone it, I'd say.
It'll be Christmas for us
when we're back on land.
Good idea.
Postpone.
That's good.
That's really good.
Let's pray the engines hold out.
With a bit of luck, Hinrich...
...we'll make it back home.
The 3rd Submarine Flotilla welcomes
its comrades with three cheers!
Both engines stop.
- Stern line out!
- Stern line out! Watch those cables!
Roll that tighter!
We Build for Victory!
- Thank you, Hinrich.
- It's okay.
The sun is shining out there.
Up with him!
All right. We got you.
Gunboat number three,
guard your position.
guard your position at once.
Hurry up.
Bring a medic.
Over here.