La Rochelle, autumn 1941.
The "Battle of the Atlantic"
grows stronger.
Germany's U-Boats fleet,
with which Hitler...
...hoped to starve Britain,
is beginning to suffer major setbacks.
The British escort freighters with
destroyers, with increasing success.
Nevertheless,
more U-boats are ordered...
...into battle
from their French Atlantic ports.
Of the 40,000 German U-boat sailors
serving in World War II...
...30,000 never returned.
The final night onshore.
We sail at 7 tomorrow morning.
My first assignment on a U-boat...
... with no idea where
they are sending us.
The central Atlantic, probably.
Only a few boats out there.
They reinforced their protection,
it's a bad month.
The tommies learned their lesson.
The aces, there are not many left.
Prien, Schepke, Kretschmer,
all lost during attacks.
They all drowned,
except for Kretschmer.
Kelsch sank off of Gibraltar.
Endrass, with a nervous breakdown.
Our boatswain's mate.
He's on quite a bender.
The street is closed.
Who are those pigs?
The street's free.
Water on!
They call that "fireboat drill."
They're all guys from our boat.
Captain.
Merkel's crew.
They ship out tomorrow as well.
Come on, comrades,
let's explode the whorehouse.
Just don't miss!
- Stick some greetings in with it!
- See you soon, comrades.
They're chickenshit.
They need that like the grave warriors
the schnapps.
What's going on here?
Okay, ready, fire!
Captain!
My second officer.
This is Lieutenant Werner,
navy war correspondent.
He'll ship out with us.
He'll report on everything
that catches his eye.
Welcome aboard, lieutenant.
Good evening.
Lieutenant, come along
and have a drink with us.
- Good evening.
- Good evening. Two beers, please.
Of course, captain. Right away.
Those are some meatballs.
It's nice here, isn't it?
Come with me.
Where's Thomsen?
I thought he wanted to celebrate
his Knight's Cross.
Any news from your wife?
They only connect private calls
after 10:00.
Two beers.
It can't get worse than this.
Captain.
I'm reporting back from U-96.
Oil provisions on board and fully armed.
The boat is clear for sea.
- Thank you, lieutenant.
- One more thing, captain.
On the drive here,
I was molested by some of the crew.
They...
An outrageous event.
Say it already, they peed on you.
- Exactly, captain.
- Me too.
Come, sweetheart. Let the boy live,
the Führer still needs him.
Prosit, lieutenant.
To the Freichor Tönitz.
- First time on a U-boat?
- Yeah.
First time. It's gonna be exciting.
Do you have a will?
Excuse me?
Thirteen boats down last month.
Sank with men and mice.
Exciting, huh?
One moment, please.
I'm asking for your attention.
To the newly appointed
Knight's Cross carrier...
...Captain Lieutenant Thomsen!
Three big cheers!
There is Thomsen from the old gang.
Always drunk now.
Quiet in this whorehouse! Quiet!
To our wonderful...
...abstaining...
...and womanless Führer...
...whose career rose gloriously...
...from apprentice painter...
...to the greatest battle strategist
of all times.
- He better watch his mouth.
- Why? Isn't it true?
He's a great naval expert...
...who took it upon himself...
...in his immeasurable wisdom...
How do I go on?
Who showed
that English bed wetter...
...that cigar-chomping asshole
of Churchill...
...where exactly to go
and stick his stinking cigars!
Don't cry, Françoise, don't cry.
I want to have it.
You know the Resistance.
They make short work of collaborators.
I want to have it.
If you should not come back...
I'll come back.
I promise.
Oh, excuse me.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I have to make a call.
Phillip, this isn't the old gang.
Now it's their turn.
All wet guys.
Bigmouths.
Ass cheeks together,
squeeze the balls...
...and the belief in the Führer
in their eyes.
They, too, will quiet down.
Alarm!
Hello?
Shit.
Lousy eels.
Torpedo failures?
Many.
Sabotage, you can count on that.
Did you hear about Kelsch?
Went down off of Gibraltar.
It was reported.
Not a good year for the old gang.
The tide is turning.
When are you going out?
Tomorrow morning.
Come on, boy.
Show the tommies.
I'll go pee and leave, then.
I still have plans.
Hey! You old pig, you!
Combat! Conquer or die!
Come on. Come on, Phillip, get up!
Come, give me a hand!
I wanted to really...
...screw my brains out...
...but I am not in the condition to fuck.
- That'll do.
- Sieg Heil!
The Thomsen boat.
Is there a special report
while still in dock?
- Starboard propeller blade was bent.
- I see.
That explains that whining noise
at low rpm.
New propeller. We've got
a brand-new propeller, captain.
Chief engineer
to the optical workshop.
Call from Germany.
Our boat.
Crew, stand by for inspection!
Attention!
Eyes, left.
Crew is present
and accounted for, captain.
Lower and upper decks clear for sea.
Thank you, Number One.
At ease.
Well, men...
- All set?
- All set, captain!
We have a guest on board.
Lieutenant Werner.
Navy war correspondent.
He's going to have a look around.
He wants to see good German heroes.
- So act appropriately.
- Yes, captain!
To manoeuvre stations.
Bockstiegel, pull in the rope.
Don't let them overpower you!
All the best! Good luck!
- Do you have a sense for romance?
- Excuse me?
There, the empty house
next to the warehouse.
Is that for you?
Not that I would know.
Isn't that area out of bounds?
Oh, yes.
Françoise.
Goodbye!
Victory! And good hunting!
The escorts left us at noon.
The dark plume of smoke
from the pathmaker disappeared.
The patrol boat is gone as well.
The quartermaster's taken
his final land measurement.
The lookouts feel the salty tang
of the Atlantic on their lips.
The boat is alone now, on course.
Move those crates of lettuce back there!
This isn't a vegetable garden!
Battle station, where we maintain
and stow the torpedoes.
Heads up, boys!
You're gonna be in the paper!
- Thank you, men.
- Come along, follow me.
Here we have the can.
One toilet for 50 men.
The other's full of provisions.
More space for eating, less to shit.
That's some kind of logic, huh?
The chief petty officer's quarters.
My home, if you will.
Here's the war room.
When I see you store your stuff,
I could puke. That's way too much!
It's nice here, very cosy.
- Where are you, lieutenant?
- Coming. Excuse me, please.
Careful!
This radio shack here.
- Here's the control room.
- Could've lived without him.
So this is the control room.
- The boat's command post.
- Thanks.
So this goes on to the U Room.
Let's move this out of the way.
- Morning, lieutenant.
This is where the petty officers bunk.
Sleeps 12 men.
Most bunks are shared by two guys.
One sleeps while the other's on duty.
That means when one man
comes off watch...
...he climbs into the other man's stink.
Right?
This bunk's for you.
Got one to yourself since
you're a guest on board.
Here, lieutenant, that's for you too.
And here's your escape gear.
Very important.
It's only for show.
More for use in the Baltic Sea.
But it's useful when the diesel stinks.
Or when Frenssen farts.
Come with me.
Let us pass.
- This is our galley.
- Ah.
- And here's Johann, the ghost.
- Who?
Well, Johann, everything lubed?
Take pictures of returning crews,
not of departing crews.
Why is that?
Because they mean something then.
The tommies should feel ashamed...
...if they see in the paper
who gives them hell.
Baby-faced kids.
Babies that belong
on the mother's breast.
To be among them
makes you feel ancient.
It's like a children's crusade.
- Permission to pass?
- Yeah.
- Bon appétit.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- From Mexico, aren't you?
- Yes, south of Mexico City.
- Nice there?
- Yes, captain.
Good climate
because of the high altitude.
Quite a way.
It was my duty as a German to come.
What did you do there?
I worked on a plantation.
It belongs to my stepparents.
- So you are the boss' son?
- You could say so.
Stand by, first watch
and starboard watch.
Excuse me.
Can I get by?
Permission to go on watch, captain?
A new breed, our Mexican recruit.
Young marcher.
Worldly, evolved.
He's so uptight, he could crack nuts
with his butt cheeks.
Captain, wind northwest, circling right.
Good visibility.
Barometer, 1003 millibar.
No special incidents.
Thanks, navigator.
After all the problems
and worries onshore...
...our first day at sea seems like
a pleasure cruise in the middle of war.
Our general course is 317 degrees.
Only the captain knows
our final destination.
It was about time to ship out.
Attention!
Zero!
- Thirty-six degrees, 20.5 minutes.
- Good.
Stay alert.
This area isn't safe.
The tommies know exactly
when we ship out.
There are enough informers.
Dock workers, cleaning ladies,
prostitutes.
Damn beasts.
Excuse me, captain.
If you can't handle it, don't do it.
Were you part of it?
Fireboat drill?
Yes, captain.
At least you can aim.
Twenty minutes...
Screws, eggs.
- Permission to come up?
- Yes.
Alarm!
- Stand by, main vents!
- Stand by, main vents.
Starboard exhaust valve!
All men forward!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, come on, move it!
Come on, move it! Up! Up! Up!
Come on, move!
Faster, faster! Keep going! Keep going!
I wanna see steam
coming out of your ass!
In case you didn't know, it's an alarm!
You're not on a pleasure cruise!
Get into diving positions!
Lower negative tank.
Attention. Stern up 10.
April fools.
Practice makes perfect.
Don't get rusty.
A practice drill.
Level off, chief.
Bow up 15. Stern up 10.
Planes at zero.
- Levelled off, sir.
- Shut all main vents.
All main vents shut.
Take her down. Let's see
how the valves and seals hold up.
Bow planes down 15, stern up 10.
The shipyard warranty
extends to 90 metres.
But of course, we could go deeper.
There's a limit somewhere.
We can only take so much
pressure before the boat...
...will be...
...crushed.
Check hull valves.
- The water pressure.
- Yeah, sure.
Deeper.
140 metres.
- She must take this depth.
- 150.
160 metres.
That'll do for now. Surface.
- Surface.
- Bow up 10. Stern up 5.
Well?
Thank you.
We're not an ordinary ship.
Very interesting.
Incoming, bearing 3-2-0 and closing.
Get on.
Both planes down, full.
Wait, my friends.
You only get one more chance.
That was it.
Shut all main vents.
Check hull valves.
The show is over.
Once a whore pissed on my back.
That felt so good.
You're a pervert.
I can tell you some really sexy tricks.
For an example, you take a cork...
...with a nail stuck in it and a
violin string attached on the side of it...
...stick it in the asshole...
...and then sideways jack off.
Could it be any more complicated?
Listen, it's supposed
to buzz real good in there.
Our first night on board.
It's hard to switch off and relax.
The heat of the compartment...
...the stench of oil...
...the engine-room watchers
coming and going.
There is so much to get used to.
As for the officers I bunk with...
...they don't let my presence
cramp their style.
The way they keep harping
on subject number one...
...I'll be lucky to get any sleep.
Is that her?
The girl from the window
of the ruin?
French girl?
You know the shop that sells flowers
beside Cafe A L'ami Pierrot?
- Beside where?
- A L'ami Pierrot.
Sure, I know it.
The two pretty salesgirls,
Jeannette and the other one's called...
Françoise.
We're engaged.
Secretly, of course.
Can I see?
Very pretty. Really.
What's wrong?
She's pregnant.
But, Ullmann...
...don't you know what that means?
If the Resistance ever
finds out that she...
...has a German baby...
What can I do?
She wants to have it.
You've got problems, Ullmann.
Fifth day at sea.
No convoy.
No ship.
Nothing.
What's today's calendar quotation?
"One can only be one's best
when it seems unnaturally hard."
Cicero.
Excuse me?
"One can only be one's best
when it seems unnaturally hard."
Give it to me.
It's always best when it's hard.
Special announcement
from Führer's headquarters...
... October 23, 1941.
The Armed Forces High Command
has issued the following announcement:
Last night,
the Navy and the Luftwaffe...
...lightened their stranglehold
on the British Isles.
Our U-boats in the Atlantic sank
11 merchant ships and one destroyer.
Wiping out 53,000 gross registered
tons of enemy shipping in one blow.
Waste of shipping space.
Three ships and one tanker
were severely damaged.
All they talk is tonnage,
these morons.
All good, seaworthy ships.
We've become nothing but agents
now for their vicious propaganda.
Just scrap merchants.
Butchers of the sea.
Our masters in Berlin
spend all their time...
...finding Churchill
clever new nicknames.
What's their latest creation?
Drunken pig.
Fat bore.
Paralytic.
I must say, for a drunken paralytic,
he's putting up a damn good fight.
You'll see.
We'll force him to his knees.
That is my firm belief.
Listen to me, smart guy.
He is a long way
from being down on his knees.
I'd like to know how many of his ships
are getting through us right now...
...while we sit on our behinds
waiting for orders.
Where are our planes and ships,
Herr Goering?
The British have plenty of them.
Talking big is all he's good for,
that fat slob.
Big heroes. Nothing but hot air.
All of them.
Go on...
...put that one down.
It'll make exciting reading
in your epic.
The Propaganda Ministry will love it.
I didn't know you were interested, sir.
You were mistaken, then.
Music, we need.
Think our Hitler youth leader
might put a record on for us?
The "Tipperary" song
if you have no objections!
Hey, now we're in the Royal Navy.
A simple record won't make you
into the King of England, Number One.
Shut the door...
...you lazy pig!
Stupid jerk.
They should use him as a doorstep.
His rear end's big enough. One of
these days, he'll stick it in the can...
...and he won't be able
to pull it out again.
- Morning.
- Lieutenant.
- Morning, lieutenant.
- It stinks in here.
- Sweaty feet and hair grease.
Pilgrim's specialty.
Tastes just like old shit...
...these rotten eggs.
Like baby poop.
Maybe he wants to hatch chickens
in the control room.
That's right, ducks in a bilge.
Why not? Sweet little ducklings.
We could feed them green snot.
- You dirty pig-
- Why? What's wrong?
That would make them happy.
Every morning...
...they'd feed on those
delicious things.
- Permission to come up.
- Yes.
Morning.
Aircraft closing, 1-7-0.
Alarm!
Move it, gangway.
Stay down. Move it.
Out of the way.
Slow down.
Watch out.
Watch it.
- Upper deck secured.
Flood buoyancy tanks.
Take her down, 60 metres.