All full ahead, left full rudder.
Come to 1-0-7.
Stand by to attack.
Watch the pressure
of the lubricating oil!
Bow angle bearing 0-5-0.
Locked on.
- Range, 2200 metres.
- Check.
Those two that are overlapping...
...double shot on the big one.
The other two, a single each.
- Targets identified.
- Right standard rudder.
All ahead one-third. Open bow caps.
Lock on tubes one and two.
New bow angle 0-6-3.
- Check, locked on!
- Hold on for bearing.
- All set!
- Tubes one and two, fire when matched.
- Tubes one and two ready!
- Tube one, fire!
- Tube two, fire!
- Tube three, fire when matched.
- Tube three ready!
- Tube three, fire!
Tube three fired!
- Tube four ready.
- Tube four ready!
- Tube four, fire!
Destroyer ahead!
Alarm!
All hands forward!
Forward diving position!
- Quick, quick, quick!
- Keep it moving!
- Clear the way!
- Move, move, move! Keep it moving!
Watch out!
Hurry! Hurry, hurry!
Battle stations!
Bow planes up 10, stern up 5.
Clear the way!
Sit down!
Keep quiet, you men.
- Down 80 metres.
Easy.
Bow down 15, stern up 10.
What about the torpedoes?
Any minute now.
Not long to go now.
110.
120.
Those lousy torpedoes.
They don't run true.
What a crazy thing to do.
Charging in like that.
That destroyer won't let us
off the hook.
They'll try and hunt us down,
you'll see.
We hit the first.
Out of the way!
We hit her! We hit her!
Quiet!
Time's up for the third torpedo.
Number three.
Now they are going to the bottom.
It's the bulkheads. They've collapsed.
This is it.
Now it's payback time.
- Well?
- Destroyer bearing 0-4-4.
- In our direction?
- Moving left.
Fading, sir.
Right full rudder.
Both engines ahead two-thirds.
Rudder is right full. Both engines
indicate ahead two-thirds.
Astern of us.
Way astern of us.
They're spitting in the wrong direction.
We haven't thrown them off yet.
I reckon they won't be too happy.
- Propeller noises.
Contact bearing 2-7-0, closing.
- Both engines ahead one-third.
Both main engines indicate
ahead one-third.
Now you'll see.
All full ahead!
- Pump out 150 litres!
- Main engines indicate full head!
Asdic.
Detector system. Ultrasonic.
The swine.
The filthy, rotten swine.
- What's the damage?
- Air shaft fractured.
Quiet, boys.
Keep it quiet.
Nice and quiet, now.
- Whole dead slow.
- Fifty rpm. Kill the fans.
- Left 15 degrees.
Stern left 15, sir.
- Shit!
- All full ahead!
Let's get the hell out of here!
- Both ballasts and gate were fractured.
- Isolate it. Isolate it!
Shut it down!
My God! We're on fire!
Motor room caught fire.
Cut to number two auxiliary!
Calm down! Calm down, for God's sake!
Chief, emergency ventilation.
Switch on fans,
connect emergency cartridges.
Boy, oh, boy.
She doesn't want to let go of us.
What's going on?
Running away?
We have really smashed them.
My God, those bulkheads.
What's her bearing?
0-6-5, sir. Bearing constant.
Deeper, chief. Silent speed.
- Bearing?
- 0-5-0.
Growing louder.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Deeper still. Right 30 degrees.
We'll try doubling back.
Keep them guessing.
Bow planes steady. Stern up 10.
Contact bearing 2-7-0.
It's fading.
- Right full rudder.
Rudder is right full, sir.
Steer 0-9-0.
Shit!
Second contact closing fast,
bearing 0-7-6!
Backup.
Those bastards.
Deeper.
But, sir...
Yes, deeper.
Bow planes down 10.
Stern planes up 7.
190 metres.
200 metres.
210 metres.
220 metres.
230 metres.
The bolts! They're bursting!
That's deep enough, chief.
Ten metres rise!
All ahead starboard.
Look out!
Quiet, men, quiet.
Quiet.
Bring her up to 150 metres!
Both full ahead!
Both full ahead, sir!
Left 20 degrees! Steer 0-5-0!
Steering on course 0-5-0, sir!
He is near his mark.
Not bad.
The foundation bolts are loose!
Quiet, damn you!
Reports! I want actual damage reports!
Leaking badly.
We are leaking badly.
Engine room taking water!
Captain, permission to inspect
engine room.
- Number One, take over!
- Aye, aye, captain.
- The exhaust flap.
- What's the trouble?
- Shit!
- The flange bolts are sheared.
I need gaskets! Fast!
Where are you? Where are the gaskets!
Torpedo hatch taking water!
- Get a crowbar!
They'll soon be out of fireworks.
Exhaust flap secured.
150 metres, all full ahead.
Torpedo-hatch spindle secured.
What's wrong, Johann?
Get back to your battle station.
Right now.
Damn it, don't go crazy!
Back!
Back, Johann.
Back, Johann!
Bring him to the back. Hurry.
He's under control.
Who would have thought it of Johann?
Degrading.
Shameless.
Let it be, Hinrich, we can hear it.
Well, then, come on.
- Water in the machine!
- All full ahead! Maximum power!
Both engines!
Blow!
180 metres!
190 metres!
200 metres!
210 metres!
220 metres!
We're sinking!
Kriechbaum, make a note
for the war diary.
Captain.
After six hours at silent speed...
...it appears that the destroyers
have lost us.
Observing intense fire glow
at 210 degrees.
Probably flames from the tanker we hit.
It's noted, captain.
We'll surface in 10 minutes.
Notify chief engineer.
Switch to red light.
First watch, stand by for duty.
You see, lieutenant?
They didn't kill us.
What a wizard, the chief engineer.
He worked in the machine room
like a crazy man.
Repaired everything
with what was on hand.
Who knows how he does it.
Forward hatch secured again.
Torpedoes are reloaded.
Good, Lumprecht.
These boys.
These great boys.
Her back's already broken.
She's a tough one. She won't go down.
- Let's finish her off, Number One.
- Master sight to Bridge.
- Final shot. Flood number one tube.
- Flood number one tube.
Number one tube is being flooded.
Number one ready for surface firing.
- Target speed, zero.
- Check.
- Range, 650 metres.
Depth, four. Torpedo speed, 30.
Aiming point?
Forward of aft mast.
- Tube one ready.
- Tube one is ready.
- Tube one.
- Fire.
- Fire!
Torpedo running!
- There's still men onboard!
- There!
Why weren't they rescued off the ship?
Damn it! So many hours!
Help me! Help me!
They're swimming towards us, captain.
Help me!
- Both engines back one-half.
Help, save us!
May I clear the table?
It had to be like that.
Not nice, things like that.
But it had to be like that.
Why?
- Excuse me?
- Why did it have to be like that?
Because our boat is barely enough
for the 50 men we need here.
How many men would
you have taken in?
One? Ten?
One hundred?
We are ordered to sink ships
where we find them.
You can ask the men who started
this war about the rest.
More signals, captain.
Read.
"Three freighters sunk. Convoy
dispersed into groups and stragglers.
Contact broken.
Cruising course, 30 degrees." U-112.
Wenzel. Not bad.
Kupsch's in contact
with the same convoy.
Stackmann hit a 6000-tonner.
They're having a field day.
Any hope of joining them?
Difficult. Minimum five hours away
at full speed. The fuel...
- We can't make...
- Yes, yes! It's good!
When do we turn around, captain?
When I order for us to go back.
Navigator.
Fired from tube one at 950 metres.
Hit aft mast with explosion.
Crew, assumed rescued,
still onboard.
Survivors jump off the fast-sinking
wreck, swim toward U-96.
Captain?
I wish to apologize.
This is nothing you can apologize for.
You deserted your post
at a critical moment.
You also disobeyed my order.
Am I going to be court-martialed,
captain?
How many patrols have you done?
Nine.
Why you, Johann?
This has never happened to me before,
captain.
I was...
I blew a fuse somehow...
The nerves.
It won't ever happen again, captain.
You can depend on me.
I swear.
All right, Johann.
No court-martial, sir?
Get some sleep.
Sunk at 192 degrees.
Decision: Return 0700.
What a relief.
After 56 days at sea...
... we are headed home.
Cipher officer.
We'll fix it.
- It's the bulkhead conduit.
- It'll work.
- Morning.
- Morning, captain.
Get moving.
There's a signal to be decoded.
Something top-secret.
Another special engagement.
But not with us.
Our boat is ready for the wharf.
Not to mention the fuel shortage.
It won't last to La Rochelle.
- The last 100 miles...
- We'll sail.
Don't worry, chief.
Decoded it yet?
Well, what is it?
For the captain only.
Very strange. Triple-enciphered.
Number One.
- Number One!
- Captain?
Come here.
- Take a look at this on the map.
- Yes, captain.
Interesting.
We've got a new destination port.
Really?
La Spezia.
- Excuse me?
- La Spezia.
Do you suffer from deafness
all of a sudden?
- That's in...
- Italy, yeah.
Mediterranean.
- The fuel...
- Supplied in Vigo.
Spain.
We're getting fuel, torpedoes,
provisions, everything.
Heart, what else could you want?
Vigo is 200 miles closer.
We can do that without sails.
How nice of the bosses.
They think of everything.
Starboard 15, go to 130 degrees.
Gibraltar.
What do you know.
Christmas in La Rochelle.
- Real girls in our Christmas stockings.
- The sweet telephone operators.
- The sexy newsgirls.
- We'll fuck our brains out.
A nice, slow, afternoon fuck.
- Now hear this.
- The master's voice.
La Rochelle's out.
We've got a new port of destination.
La Spezia.
That's in the Mediterranean,
as you know.
First, we'll pick up fuel and supplies
at Vigo.
That's in Spain. Over.
Shit.
They must be crazy.
- What a dirty, rotten trick.
- There goes our Christmas stocking.
No sexy little newsgirls. No whores.
I'd like to kill those morons!
Christmas in macaroni land,
I've wished for that.
We've got to get there first,
to get to them!
- Why?
- Why? Gibraltar!
You can figure out what that means!
That's as narrow as a virgin.
If you want to get through that, we need
to cover our boat with Vaseline.