The very centre of Africa.
And the centre of two million square
miles of dense tropical rain forest.
At first glance it seems
deserted and eerily still,
not an easy place to live.
But, in fact, there is a greater
concentration of animals here,
than anywhere else in Africa.
And in this world they must
grab every opportunity.
Competition is intense and unrelenting.
Even the forest itself fights its corner
with spines and poisonous sap.
Here, every living thing
must fight for its space.
Such beauty.
But the flower is self-serving, enticing
animals into an unwitting alliance.
Stingless bees.
They have to work hard.
The forest flowers make them do so
by rationing their nectar, forcing
each bee to visit, and so pollinate,
at least a thousand blooms each day.
For the bees, it's worth the effort.
They need the nectar to make honey
which they store in pots.
It's so precious, they keep it hidden
beneath the bark of a tree.
But their secret is out.
Nothing is safe in this forest.
Chimpanzees love honey.
She seems oblivious to danger.
A fall from up here could be fatal.
But she does need a bigger stick.
Only a chimp has the ability to
break into a stingless bees' nest,
as well hidden as this.
Chimps are extremely intelligent,
but none is born with
the skill to use a tool.
Youngsters, like this one,
must learn by watching.
She uses special tools,
one after another,
to get all the honey she can,
and in a few minutes she destroys
what took the bees years to build.
In the rain forest, nothing is safe.
Here in the Congo, there can be
as many as 500 trees
crammed into every acre.
In the battle for space, some will
rise to over 60 metres high,
in just a few decades.
In a valley like this,
there could be close
on 1,000 different species of tree.
Up here, the crowns barely touch.
Each tree seems to respect
its neighbour's space.
When they germinate
down on the forest floor,
young trees and plants
are less restrained.
But every new generation fights it out,
in battles we can see
by accelerating time.
They must get light
if they are to survive,
and they squeeze, crush and even slash
one another in order to reach it.
Despite the thick canopy above,
some sunlight does filter through,
and allows a few low-light specialists
to bloom near the forest floor.
Down here there are animals too
that seek out the sunlight.
The forest's largest predator.
A female rock python.
Her body is five metres long,
weighs 100 kilos,
and has 4,000 muscles
that she uses to crush the
life out of her victims.
But right now, her need
is not for food.
It's for warmth.
She finds a rare patch where a
shaft of sunlight strikes the ground,
and she begins to bask.
She's cold-blooded.
So this is the only way she can raise
the temperature of her body.
But now she's becoming very warm indeed,
more than 10 degrees hotter than usual.
At 40 degrees centigrade
she's in danger of killing herself.
Just in time, she moves off.
She disappears below ground.
This is her nest,
and it's full of giant eggs.
It's critical for the eggs' development
that they stay above 30 degrees.
Here in this special filming burrow,
she gently wraps her super-heated
body around the eggs,
passing on to them
the warmth of the sun.
She has done this every day
for three months.
The repeated heat stress on her body
is so great it could be lethal.
And at the very least,
it will take three years for her
to recover from incubating
this one clutch of eggs.
Her parchment-shelled eggs carry
the pressed imprint of her scales.
An indication of the strength
of her embrace.
At last, her efforts are rewarded.
But the babies can't stay here.
They must leave their sanctuary
and find food
in the tangled world above.
They're over 60 centimetres long,
already big enough to be a threat
to the smaller inhabitants
of the forest.
But they are themselves vulnerable.
Particularly to other snakes.
But this one is their mother.
Unusually for snakes,
her maternal instincts continue
for days after her eggs hatch.
Even so, the forest
is such a dangerous place,
that only one in a hundred
of her youngsters
is likely to reach adulthood.
Just occasionally,
the competition eases.
A tree suddenly produces fruit.
It's a magnet for
the creatures of the canopy,
and they, in turn, as they feed,
create a bonanza for those
on the ground below.
A mob of red river hogs.
They have travelled over two miles
through the thick undergrowth,
to get to this fall of fruit.
But in the African forest,
little comes for free.
This feast is a bribe.
The hogs will carry the seeds
in their stomachs
and deposit them far from
the parent tree.
Night falls.
But one living community,
which is neither animal nor plant,
continues its never-ending
work in the darkness.
This ground is alive with fungi,
that digest all the litter
discarded by the forest.
Some rare fungi do so with enzymes
that are luminous.
The local people call them
"Chimpanzee fire".
Without the fungi, the dead vegetation
would pile so high
the living trees would be submerged.
Dawn.
And a new day reveals
just how much control
the jungle has over its own environment.
The forests of the Congo
are the lungs of Africa.
As they use the sunlight
to build their tissues,
so they release oxygen
and water vapour into the air.
Each hectare of forest produces
as vapour almost 190,000
litres of water a year.
So much that it creates
its own weather.
Clouds blanket the forest,
driving up the humidity
and temperature.
A storm is brewing.
The Congo might be
the richest part of Africa,
but it's also the most violent.
Each year, as many as a hundred million
lightning bolts strike the forest.
That's more than anywhere
else in the world.
And with the lightning comes the rain.
Up to 95% of the rain that falls here
is generated by the forest itself.
With the deluge will come change
to the animals and to the forest.
It's certainly perfect
weather for frogs.
The big storm is the cue for the most
important climb of this frog's life.
It's a male in search of a mate.
But if he is to find one,
he has to get to the top.
He needs to keep his wits about him,
for the rain also brings out hunters.
Easy does it.
The top at last,
but he's late to the party.
The higher a male sits,
the further his voice will carry.
So the top slots are worth fighting for.
And he's won.
He has the top place.
So now it's time to sing.
And a white-bellied female responds.
They join together to mate.
The loser will have to wait for
the next storm, before he sings again.
She lays her eggs
on a blade of a long leaf.
And he, using his back legs,
folds it over,
and glues its two edges together,
shutting the eggs inside.
This sealed nest is the safest place
these leaf-folding frogs can find
to protect their precious brood.
Within days, the eggs are developing.
The timing is perfect.
The rain washes away the glue and
the tadpoles slip out of the leaves
into the growing puddles below.
The rainy season reaches its peak
and the ground has been transformed.
The forest is flooded.
It's a new world.
Fish swim in from the swollen streams,
exploiting this newly-created space,
snapping up the drowning insects.
This is a butterflyfish.
A Congo bichir.
The hunter becomes the hunted.
The butterflyfish is too quick
and leaps out of danger.
The floods gradually drain back
into the established waterways
that run through the forest
like blood vessels.
These is so much water
flowing through the forest
that even little rivulets can carve out
the soil around an ancient boulder.
This is the home of one
forest creature,
that has lived here in the Congo
for 44 million years.
Picathartes.
These birds mate for life,
and the male reaffirms the bond
by displaying to the female.
They're building a mud nest on the
underside of the boulder's overhang,
where it'll be protected from the rain.
The female takes the lead.
The male doesn't seem quite so skilful.
Oh dear.
Luckily she can put things right.
Now she's collecting
the soft furnishings.
He's brought some too,
but he still can't get it right.
In the end, the female seems satisfied
with the finish and just in time.
It might look as if he has
been banished into the rain,
but in fact they're a great team.
They share the incubation.
Twelve hours on, twelve hours off,
for the next three weeks.
In due course, there are mouths to feed,
and now the male must prove his worth.
Worms are a good start
and he's doing well.
But the chicks are insatiable.
Fortunately, other things
are on the menu.
He might be a poor nest builder,
but he is redeeming himself now.
Domestic bliss!
Rocky overhangs are the only place
where picathartes will build their nest.
So they owe their home to the stream,
that revealed the flank
of the giant boulder.
This stream
and countless others like it
merge to form the great rivers
of Central Africa.
More than 450 billion litres
of rainwater,
travelling down thousands of rivers,
are heading west.
The waters pick up speed
as the rivers spill over the edge
of the central plateau
and create giant cascades
of white water.
The Kongou forces its way
through the wildest,
most untouched forest
in the whole of Africa.
The Congo River system
drains an area the size of India,
carrying the waters westwards
towards the Atlantic.
But before it reaches the coast,
the rivers broaden,
forcing back the forest.
And here, for the first time,
there is space.
Wide, flat and safe.
These stretches of sand
attract visitors from the coast.
Skimmers, searching
for somewhere safe to settle.
The lower mandible of their beaks
is greatly elongated.
They slice it through the surface
of the water at 10 metres a second.
If and when it hits a tiny fish,
it'll snap shut.
But why come up river
to these open sand flats?
This is the answer.
But this nursery
will not exist for long.
Four weeks from now
it'll be under 10 metres of water.
If by then these chicks can't fly,
they will drown.
The problem for young skimmers
is that when they hatch
the lower part of their
beaks is the same size as the upper.
While they wait for it to grow,
they do their best
to learn the skimming technique.
Open spaces may be safe,
but they give no protection
against the driving rain.
These storms are a warning
that the skimmers must soon leave.
The river is already rising.
This year, the chicks get away in time.
It's not just water that has the power
to clear a way through the forest.
There are animals
that could do that too.
They have created a network of pathways
that criss-cross the lowland forest
and run for thousands of miles
in all directions.
These path-makers
are surprisingly stealthy.
But as night falls, there's a chance
of catching a glimpse of them.
Forest elephants
are very social creatures,
but in dense jungle it's hard for them
to find one another.
These elephants are lucky.
Here in the Congo,
there is one special place
where they can meet and mingle.
A place that the elephants
have created for themselves.
And this is it.
Dzanga Bai,
the legendary "village of elephants".
As well as being a place
where they can enjoy
one another's company,
this great clearing
satisfies another craving.
For salts.
The salts lie deep under the mud.
So the elephants
have got to mine for them,
which they do with high pressure
water jets from their trunks.
The precious salts
and the chance to socialise
bring in elephants from far and wide.
If an elephant is in the mood to mate,
this is the place to be.
This young bull is in a state of musth,
a kind of sexual fury.
He is so pumped up by hormones
and the excitements of the crowd
that he seems to have
taken leave of his senses.
But will throwing his weight about
impress the females?
The cows only become fertile
once every two years.
So opportunities to encounter one
at the right time are not common.
This could well be the first chance
this young male has had.
He's lucky.
And there are no older bulls around
to put him in his place.
Just for a moment,
he is king of the Bai.
But his rule doesn't last for long.
Enter another lusty bull.
And a much bigger one.
But the young bull
is still charged up with testosterone.
Bold or foolish, he's going into battle.
He never really had a chance.
Dzanga Bai is a huge clearing,
but it's still just a speck
in this vast expanse of green.
Elephants might fell trees
and carve pathways,
but nothing natural
can hold back this forest forever.
Nothing but the Atlantic Ocean.
Loango beach, on Africa's west coast,
one of the last truly wild places
where the Congo jungle meets the sea.
Here the forest gives way
to sand, surf,
and fresh sea air.
The cool breezes and warm sunlight
entice creatures out of the dark forest.
Forest buffalo appear first.
And here in the surf, there are hippos.
Spray blows in from the sea,
making the grass salty.
So, here elephants can get
their tasty salt
without having to dig for it.
This mother with her tiny baby
can feel the sun on her back.
Here it's safe for her little one.
They are free to eat in peace.
The bulls have all the room they need,
so there is less risk of a fight.
Everyone, from gorillas to forest hogs,
ventures out to relax on the beach.
But the forest creatures
can't stay out here forever.
Despite everything,
the intense competition,
the threats, the darkness,
they need their forest,
just as their forest needs them.
The Congo rainforest,
a four-day journey
to the heart of Africa.
Once the plane leaves,
you're on your own.
This expedition planned to film
two of the Congo's best-kept secrets.
But to even find them
the crew would have to work
very hard indeed.
You might as well be
on a different planet
coming to a place like this.
Planet Congo.
Mysterious.
Difficult.
Complex.
Challenging.
You know, everything's
trying to bite you.
Suck your blood.
It's like being tickled by a million
feathers at the same time.
The insects might be torture,
but that's the least of their worries.
The only way to get
deep into the jungle
is to follow these trails.
Trails made by dangerous
forest elephants.
Well, the first thing you need
to know about the forest elephants
is you don't want to meet one.
'Cause running away can elicit a charge
and it could be exactly
the wrong thing to do.
Our team are completely dependent
on their B'aka guides for safety.
It's moved off now.
It's gone? Yes
But it's these same forest elephants
that James has come to film
and just to make the challenge harder
he's here to film them in the dark.
Nobody knows exactly what
they get up to at night.
They haven't been filmed
like this before.
I couldn't rig this place
if the B'aka weren't here.
Watching my back, really.
James needs to operate
the remote cameras
from somewhere
out of the elephants' reach.
A tree platform
seems like the best option.
It's not high enough.
Uh huh.
Apparently, they have
very big elephants round here.
They want us to put it a bit higher,
so I think I'll do what they say.
But no one wants to stay out at night
and help James with the filming.
Usually B'aka stay up in the
trees only if they are very lost.
Very dangerous!
So James will be alone until morning.
If anything goes wrong,
he's on his own.
If they really wanted to,
they could push these trees over.
I can't imagine
that's going to be an issue.
As James settled down for the night,
he's got no idea of the trouble
that's coming his way.
What's going on?
Twenty miles away Mark MacEwan
is also up in the middle of the night.
The animal he's after
is proving impossible to find.
Oh!
So, we get up in the darkness
and we walk through the jungle at night,
hoping to hear the sound
of cracking branches
or leaves moving up in the trees.
That means chimpanzees
are stirring in the treetops
and Mark is here to
film chimps hunting for honey.
There's one chimp in particular
he needs to find,
a teenager with a very sweet tooth,
known to go further in the pursuit
of the bees' nest than any other.
I've spent six days
walking probably the equivalent
of a half marathon every day
in 100 percent humidity
and about 95 degrees in the shade.
And we just can't find our chimpanzee.
Time is ticking away
and Mark is running out of filming days.
At the moment I just need some good luck.
We've come an awfully long way
to get this sequence.
We've got probably 10 to 12 days left.
But it's hard work
at the moment.
All Mark can do is persevere
and hope for a break.
But not all the forest creatures
are so shy.
Perched high in his tree,
James Aldred is waiting patiently
for the elephants to come in.
At last the elephants are here.
But they're behaving strangely.
He knows something's not quite right.
The elephants seem agitated.
They just want to get rid of you.
One begins to thump the tree with its head.
James has no option
but to weather the attack.
Let's lean forward
and keep head-butting,
keep head-butting, keep head-butting.
Suddenly the cameras cut out.
And James is left in complete darkness.
After three weeks searching,
Mark has lost
nearly two stone in weight
but he hasn't given up.
He can't afford to put down
his camera for a second.
Suddenly, the guide
spots the honey hunter.
This is it.
- Where is she?
- She's inside the tree.
Just for some honey,
she's risking her life. It's amazing.
Well, I think,
I just couldn't stop smiling
for several days after filming that.
The relief was just unbelievable.
Back at the camera platform,
James has had a long night.
For over four hours
the elephant tried to shake him
out of the tree.
Got down this morning
when the B'aka came to collect me.
Went to look at the camera
and he'd pulled it out of the tree
and he'd chewed
through the power cable.
He must have gotten a bit of a shock.
I mean only 12 volts.
But serves him right, quite honestly.
But at least we got a shot of him
before he trashed the camera.
Silver lining.
Despite this bumpy start,
the elephants soon got used to James
and James got used to the elephants.
Filming here
was never going to be easy.
But we were soon able to reveal
the night life of forest elephants
like never before.