Africa.
The world's greatest wilderness.
The only place on Earth
to see the full majesty of nature.
There's so much more here
than we ever imagined.
I'm standing where the equator
cuts right across
the middle of the continent.
To the north of me,
there's an immense desert
the size of
the United States of America.
To the west, a vast rainforest,
the size of India.
And behind me, for thousands of miles,
the most fertile savannahs
in the world.
From the roof of Africa
to the deepest jungle,
rarely seen places
and untold stories.
There's nowhere in the world
where wildlife puts on a greater show.
This is the last place on Earth
where you can come eye to eye
with the greatest animals
that walk our planet.
This is Africa.
Our journey starts in the far southwest
in the oldest and strangest
corner of the continent.
Here, the thirsty land is covered
with thousands upon thousands
of circles.
We still don't know their origins.
Poisonous plants, foraging insects
and even magnetism
have all been suggested.
But each ruled out.
The circles don't move
and their shape never varies.
They're unchanging,
much like this part of Africa itself.
Ancient and arid, it almost never rains
on this land.
Yet there is water here, hidden away.
To survive here,
life must use every trick in the book.
Winter.
Dawn temperatures can fall
well below freezing.
And that's a problem for this drongo.
It's too cold for his normal prey,
flying insects.
But he has a plan.
The drongo is
the Kalahari's greatest trickster.
And these are his victims.
A family of meerkats,
desert specialists.
After warming up in the morning sun,
the meerkats begin their search
for breakfast.
The drongo can now begin his tricks.
But he must first win the confidence
of his victims.
He spots an eagle on the hunt
and sounds a warning.
One that sends the meerkats
gratefully scurrying to safety.
Danger over.
And now, he has their trust.
He sounds another warning.
But this time, it's a false alarm.
Thank you very much.
The meerkats fell for it.
This all seems too easy.
He tries the same trick again.
But the meerkats aren't stupid.
They'll only fall for it once.
The juicy scorpion won't be for him.
Then suddenly,
the sound of a sentry's warning.
No meerkat can ignore that.
Sentries never lie.
But the sentry sees no danger.
Guess who?
Of course, it's the drongo.
He's learned to mimic
the meerkats' own warning call.
And now he can enjoy his prize.
A gang of meerkats, outsmarted...
..by a bird.
The drongo is only deceitful
in the hardest winter months.
For the rest of the year,
he provides honest protection.
So, in the long run,
the meerkat family profit
as well as the drongo.
It's a much harder life
if you haven't yet learned
the tricks of your trade.
This young leopard is just a year old
and at a critical point in his life.
His mother has battled
to raise her two cubs,
but finding enough food for them
is now beyond her.
From today,
he'll have to fend for himself.
Kalahari means "land of great thirst".
Prey is scarce.
Of all the leopards in Africa,
these have to be the most resourceful.
A big warthog,
potential prey
but armed and dangerous.
His mother tried to tackle one
but it nearly killed her.
He spots something more promising.
A steenbok.
That's more like it.
He won't strike unless he can get
to within just four metres,
and without making the slightest sound.
A jackal barks an alarm.
But the steenbok still has no idea
it's being stalked.
The nearer he gets,
the quieter he must be.
He's blown it.
A good opportunity like that
won't come around very often.
Hungry and thirsty, he heads back home,
and spots a kill stashed in a tree,
almost certainly by his own mother.
And like any teenager,
he thinks nothing of raiding her larder.
Booby-trapped.
It's not really his day, is it?
Some young leopards grow up
to be brilliant opportunists.
But even they find life hard
here in the Kalahari.
These bizarre little birds
are baby ostriches.
They're just a few days old.
In time,
they'll become superb desert survivors.
But in the Kalahari,
these early days are perilous.
Like leopards and meerkats,
adult ostriches can extract all the
moisture they require from their food.
Their chicks, however, won't survive
much more than another day without water.
But there's none in sight.
How can their parents
conjure up water out here?
The youngsters follow their parents
as they head out onto
a featureless wasteland.
It seems like a suicidal journey.
The Etosha Salt Pan.
Here, water is more often
a mirage than reality.
It's now well over
40 degrees centigrade.
Their father shades his chicks
from the midday sun.
Another mirage?
No.
The ostrich family
is not alone out here.
Surrounded by miles of sun-baked mud,
sweet fresh water wells up
from deep below ground
like a miracle.
Although the ostrich parents
have guided their chicks to water,
there's still a problem.
Traffic.
Heavy traffic.
These tiny, fragile birds
could easily be trampled underfoot.
The water is tantalisingly close.
Where prey gathers,
predators are never far behind.
The brawling lions have unwittingly done
the young ostriches a favour.
The water hole is now clear.
Sometimes, you need
a bit of luck in life.
Their first-ever drink.
And just in time.
Their father's done his job.
A black rhinoceros,
the Kalahari's most
cantankerous resident.
They don't like company.
And they certainly don't like
sharing a water hole with lions.
Fortunately, for everyone else, that is,
they only visit twice a week.
The Kalahari is the black rhino's
last stronghold.
And here, under the cover of darkness,
at one secret and very
special waterhole,
rhino abandon their normally
solitary life,
and come from miles around
to meet under the stars.
Using the latest starlight camera,
we can reveal for the first time
the rhino's true character.
This young female seems nervous.
She senses other rhinos close by.
A mother appears from the shadows
with her calf.
Tentatively, they greet one another.
They may be ill-tempered by day,
but now they become gentle
and affectionate.
More and more arrive.
We had no idea that rhinos
met to socialise
and build friendships like this.
The young female has an admirer.
But she doesn't seem keen on him.
She's excited about something,
or someone.
Here comes a really big male.
This time she's much more welcoming.
Who would have thought
that rhino could be so flirtatious?
The first male tries
to come between them.
Somehow or other, he's got a pair of
antelope horns stuck on his nose.
It looks as if she's been won over
by his eccentric style.
He leads her off, away from the party.
He may have style,
but he's turning out to be
something of a disappointment.
A girl can only put up with so much.
The only way she can get rid of him
is to pretend she's asleep.
To see so many rhino in one place
is a revelation.
And that's the power water has here,
the power to bring together the greatest
gathering of rhinos anywhere on Earth.
Spitzkoppe,
an ancient volcano that towers above a
plateau that is two billion years old.
This land has remained unchanged for
longer than any other part of Africa.
Animals here have had a long time
to find inventive solutions
to the challenge of finding water.
Out on the open plains, life must await
the chance arrival of rain.
When it does fall, it has
an extraordinary effect.
Each sporadic downpour may only
last minutes,
but it can bring life.
And in spectacular numbers.
Red-billed quelea.
They're the most numerous
bird in the world.
In all, more than a billion
live here in the Kalahari.
No one knows quite how,
but they seem to have an extraordinary
ability to locate the fall of rain
and then instantly exploit
the bonanza that follows.
These nomads now have just five weeks
to find food, build a nest,
and raise a brood.
But they're not alone.
The rains have also created a plague.
These are armoured ground crickets,
giant insects with voracious
appetites for meat.
With the quelea parents away feeding,
their chicks are defenceless.
The adults return.
But the cricket fights back,
squirting its own foul-tasting
blood into their eyes.
The cricket is still alive,
but the stench of its blood attracts
the attention of others.
Now it is the target.
These crickets become cannibals.
All too soon,
the bonanza brought by the rain is over.
And the quelea head off
in search of the next rare downpour.
The Kalahari is scarred by rivers
that have long since run dry.
The water claimed by the thirsty land.
But it's not gone far.
Deep below lies a secret,
one that was discovered
only 25 years ago.
Humid air rushing to the surface,
gives this place its name.
Dragon's Breath Cave.
The shaft descends for
60 metres until it meets
water.
Here there is a massive chamber,
big enough to swallow three jumbo jets
nose to tail,
filled with cool, fresh water.
The world's largest underground lake.
This is fossil water.
It's been trapped here undisturbed
for thousands, if not millions of years.
We have no idea how deep the lake is.
Divers have been down to 100 metres
and still there's no sign of the bottom.
Remarkably, Dragon's Breath is part
of a vast cave system
that extends beneath the Kalahari
for thousands of miles.
Even here in this lonely
cave, there is life.
Golden catfish, only found
in this one cave.
They're the rarest and most
isolated fish in the world.
Life down here is as challenging
as it is in the desert above.
There's no food, except the debris that
occasionally falls onto the surface.
And these catfish are totally blind.
The only world they know is
the one that they sense through touch.
A blind fish living in
perpetual darkness
deep beneath one of the
most arid regions of Africa.
Such cruel irony,
so much water hidden away out of reach.
Along the western edge of the Kalahari,
the land becomes so dry,
it seems impossible
that any life could survive here.
The Namib.
A million square miles of sand,
exquisitely sculpted by the wind.
This is the oldest desert in the world.
Respite comes from fog
rolling in from the Atlantic Ocean.
It condenses into a few precious drops.
Just enough to sustain life.
A pompilid wasp is searching the dunes.
She's not looking for a drink,
but for somewhere moist to lay her egg.
How will she pull off a trick like that?
The entrance to a burrow.
That's worth investigating.
She may be tiny, but once
she decides to dig,
she can shift extraordinary
quantities of sand.
She's unearthed this spider
for a grisly purpose.
It's so dry, the only place with enough
moisture for her egg
is within the body of another
living thing.
First, she must paralyse her victim.
But then, the spider plays
its trump card.
The aptly named golden wheel spider
can cartwheel fast enough
to escape its gruesome fate.
For the wasp, her near-impossible
search goes on.
If it's hard enough for a tiny wasp
to survive here in the Namib,
how is it possible for a giant?
A desert giraffe.
It's difficult to imagine how
such a huge animal
can live in a place
with so little water.
This old male is at the
very limit of his endurance.
The land may be bone dry,
but there are signs that
water once flowed here.
The Hoanib,
one of Namibia's rivers.
A river of sand.
The trees that line these sand rivers,
send roots down over 30 metres
to tap water that lies deep
beneath the river bed.
These trees are the giraffe's salvation.
Even if he has to stretch to his very
tallest to get a mouthful.
Even on tiptoe, he still needs
a half-metre-long tongue
to reach the leaves he so badly needs.
He's ruled this stretch of the
Hoanib for over a decade.
And this prime territory
is attracting females.
He waits confidently for her.
But they've got company,
a young male.
The old bull won't tolerate a rival.
Pushing and shoving,
they size each other up.
The young rival seems to think
he has a chance
and attacks.
The first few blows usually
settle things in such battles,
but here the stakes are high.
To lose means exile in the desert.
Neither will back down.
As the fight intensifies,
they change tactics.
The young male aims for the rump.
The old bull targets his rival's legs.
The old bull is down.
Is this the end of his reign?
He knows a knockout blow is coming.
But the old bull ducks,
and strikes a blow
to his rival's underbelly.
Out for the count.
The old bull is victorious,
but only just.
The sand river remains his to rule.
It's a river that is
about to be transformed.
Under clear blue skies,
water floods down the Hoanib.
The welcome consequence of rain
that fell hundreds of miles away.
The water may only flow
for a matter of hours,
but this miraculous flood
is enough to provide
a lifeline for the trees,
and the giraffes of the Hoanib river.
It's what makes this place
worth fighting for.
Here, fossil lakes, secret water holes,
desert fog, and ephemeral
rivers like this
provide just enough water
for life to get by,
no matter how tough it gets.
It's hard to find more inventive
solutions to staying alive
than in this, the most
ancient corner of Africa.
For four years, the Africa team
searched the continent
for new and surprising stories.
Not only of strange
and unfamiliar creatures,
but also of some we think we know.
Veteran wildlife cameraman
Martyn Colbeck
took on the challenge
of shedding new light
on the life of Namibia's desert giraffe.
I jumped at the opportunity
of working with an animal
that I hadn't really
spent much time with.
Straight away, they proved to be
quite an eye-opener.
They're very bizarre-looking animals.
We just kept looking at them
from different angles.
And they looked even weirder.
The combination of the sort of weird close-ups,
the beautiful landscape that they're in...
They're amusing.
I got really attached
to them, actually.
Overlying all this, we were
always waiting for a fight.
But to see a full-blooded fight
is very rare.
So, the only way that we were
going to see it
is if we stuck at it
day after day, every day, for 30 days.
We were lucky enough that
we found a male guarding a female.
And, out of nowhere, this male
came round the corner.
And almost immediately
faced up to our male.
Absolutely no warning that
this was going to happen,
so it was complete
pandemonium in the car.
But luckily, I got the camera
up and running in time
to actually capture this fight.
And it all came down
to one minute in real time.
When I filmed it, you don't
see it in slow-motion.
And you just have to go with the flow.
You're not experiencing the fight.
You're just basically framing it and capturing it.
So it was only afterwards,
when we looked at it in slow-motion
that you could really understand
how ferocious it was.
You can see the impact on the skin.
You see the ripples going through the flesh.
But it was the final blows
that delivered the real surprise.
It was like one of those
chimneys falling down.
At the last moment,
the head just went clunk.
And we thought it was dead.
We thought this thing was dead.
And it lay there for,
it must have been three minutes.
Eventually, this thing suddenly got up.
The one that was lying down.
And the two of them were then standing.
And the one that had been
knocked over completely
then just said, "I've had enough.
"Okay. Okay, you won. And I'm off."
I think it's very unlikely I'm going
to see anything like that again.
I think that's a once-in-a-lifetimer,
I really do.
It won't be easy
to look at giraffes
in the same way again.
On the other side of the desert,
another of Africa's great animal icons
was attracting the attention of the team
as they staked out a secret water hole.
They hoped to reveal
a very different side
to the personality
of the black rhinoceros.
The team have heard that at night
rhinos behave a little strangely.
A specially-built starlight camera would
allow the team to pierce the darkness.
It's amazing. That's filming
something we can't even see.
Yeah, if you look out there now...
Yeah, it's just black, isn't it?
But through this,
it looks as sharp as day.
Rhinos are notoriously antisocial.
Yet here they come to revel
in each other's company.
This is amazing.
This is such intimate behaviour, which
you could only see filming
them at night like this.
It's incredible.
But it wasn't just cameras
that would show a new side to rhinos.
By concealing tiny radio microphones
around the water hole,
the crew hoped to eavesdrop
on the night's activity.
And what they heard was astonishing.
They're really talkative.
They really are having a good chat.
These guys are far more communicative
than elephants even.
It's just going on and on.
Chatting or whatever.
It's a beautiful, crystal clear night.
So you've got beautiful, starry shots,
loads of amazing noise.
They're all puffing and huffing.
So it's... it's about 2:00 in the morning.
We've one rhino left out there.
The rest have gone to bed, but he's
decided to lie down right on top of the radio mic.
The crew prepared for one more
night at the water hole
under the full moon.
It seems that they're
not really here for the water.
But more to socialise.
A bit like going out for the evening.
He's got some kudu horns on his face,
draped over his nose.
It's on camera, too.
These images have a particular poignancy
in a world where rhino horn is worth
more than its weight in gold.
Poaching is going through
a really bad time right now
in Southern Africa.
If you average it out, a rhino
has been killed every day
for the last year.
That's really serious poaching.
It's a huge concern
that what we saw and filmed
just won't happen again, ever.
It's only now that
technology has revealed a new side
to the rhino's personality.
The black rhinoceros
is a symbol of the African bush.
But it seems that this creature
has been long misunderstood.
For the Africa team, revealing
giraffes and rhinos in this new light
was just the beginning.
Africa may be a continent
we think we know,
but it's still full of surprises.