Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow
was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
- Samurai Jack
- Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Watch--watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!
No, man.
That's some magic type junk.
You need to check out
in the swamp.
Time travel, eh?
The hermit of Boga Swamp...
knows many a mystic secret.
Boga Swamp lies exactly
2.7 kilometers due south...
of your current position.
Please take
your complimentary map...
of the complete
forty-hectare region.
For a holographic,
topographical projection...
press Enter when ready.
They say a twisted horn
marks his doorstep.
The hermit knows.
Check the swamps, yo!
Press Enter when ready.
Who dares to blow my door horn?
l am called Jack.
l am a traveler.
Hmm. Never heard of you.
l'm a hermit, after all...
and l have little time
for vagrants!
What is your business here?
l seek to travel back in time...
and l am told you may know
of such things.
Time travel, hmm?
Come with me.
Thank you for your audience.
- l had hoped--
- Quiet!
lt occurs to me that we may be
of some help to each other...
for l study the lore
of ancient days...
and it is here
that l have collected...
artifacts and lost treasures...
with links to mystic forces.
There is legend
of powerful items...
that may serve us both.
Have you ever heard
of the Titans?
Yes--the cosmic beings
that sired the gods of Olympus.
Quiet!
Before the birth of Aku...
before the ancient gods...
it was the Titans
that ruled all things...
and Cronus was their king.
He understood the secrets
of time and space...
and fashioned
for himself three gems:
The Eye of Cronus--
to focus his vision
of the universal time.
Fists of Might and Ability...
to grasp onto
the cosmic essence.
With these, he alone held the power
to command all eternity.
But as Cronus' power grew...
so, too, did his arrogance
and paranoia.
His appetites
drove him to madness!
Until his own son Zeus
rose to challenge him.
Cronus was dethroned
and imprisoned...
in the cold depths of space.
He was stripped
of his mighty gems...
which Zeus cast earthward...
in hopes that
they would be lost...
forever.
But alas, with years of study...
it is l who has
discovered the tombs...
of these powerful relics.
And with the help
of one such as you...
we can unearth these treasures.
And with the magic
of the gems...
we can tear a hole
in the fabric of time...
and mold a tunnel back
to whenever you came from.
Come, then.
Let us claim what you seek...
unless, of course,
you are a coward.
You are a fool.
You're taking forever!
We'll never get anywhere
at this rate.
Vamonos, muchacho!
You are our new ride.
Now, then, l'll worry about
travel arrangements.
You just take care
of the heavy lifting.
Oh, no, young warrior.
l can only guide you
to the challenge.
You must enter it alone.
What are you waiting for?!
Go and get it!
Come on, already!
You better hurry up.
This doesn't look good.
You better get a move on!
l'll meet you out front!
Quit horsing around
and climb up here.
We've still got
a lot of work to do.
l think l can see
our next treasure from here.
Nah, the updrafts are too strong.
Guess we'll have
to use the front door.
l'll stay here
and watch the beast...
while you fetch the treasure.
And be quick about it! Grr!
This thing gets cranky.
Whew!
Nice going, Jackie lad!
Now throw me the fist!
Come on, then!
Two down and one to go!
Ah, here's the porthole.
The clock is timed to open
at the crack of dawn.
The morn is nearly upon us.
The Fist of Might.
Our final treasure lies deep within.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Do it!
That's right, sunshine!
lt's a door!
l'd start using it if l were you...
seeing how you managed
to lose my rope.
May l be of any assistance?
You can stay out of the way
and keep your mouth shut!
Now get him!
Behind you!
He's right behind you!
Fool!
You were so blinded by
your little quest for time travel...
that you couldn't see the truth...
right in front of your face!
Huh?
What's the matter?
Missing something...
Aku?
The Eye of Cronus.
No!
You have deceived me
many times, Aku...
but you have become careless.
Your lust to destroy me
left you the blinded one...
and now my trap is sprung!
Bah!
lnsolent wretch.
Even without deception...
without mystic weapons...
you will fall against
the powers of Aku.
Bah, l say!
Bah!
What?
Now let us test
your enchanted steel...
against the power of the Titans!
Bah!
Run, you cowardly shadow...
for you know
your destruction is at hand.
lt is just a matter of time.
Watch out!
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
- Samurai Jack
- Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out