Long ago in a distant land, l, Aku...
the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Watch--watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack
Yeah, and so l was saying--
Whoa! Look out, man.
How much did you say this was?
lt's free!
Looks like there's a storm brewing.
lndeed.
How much for the soup?
- Was it the fish?
- No. Chicken.
Thank you.
Oh, excuse me.
l did not see you there.
That's it!
People...
always bumping into me.
Always!
Oh, great.
Just what l wanted to do today--
go get another manicure.
Hey, you dirty chicken!
Look what you did
to my pant leg!
l'll show you.
Please, l wish you no harm.
This is the silliest chicken
l've ever seen in my life!
Could it be?
No.
That sound.
You! You in the robe!
l demand that you cease
your walking this instant!
You look like a good chicken...
and l know a good chicken
when l see one.
lt's time, chicken.
All right, you swines.
The chicken pays 2 to 1.
Place your bets.
You going nowhere, chicken.
You'll fight till you win...
or you die!
Chicken! Chicken! Chicken!
He's OK. He's OK.
Get up! Get up! Get up!
He's injured.
Bring out the finisher.
But--but that's
two opponents at once.
That's--that's cheating.
Do it!
lt's always me.
l always have to get the finisher.
Every time. ''Do this. Do that.
Go get the finisher.''
l always have to!
Chicken! Chicken! Chicken!
Of course.
How thoughtless of me.
l almost forgot about the lasagna.
Silly me.
Huh?
What's a matter?
Can't you read?
May l come in?
Uh, why, yes. Yes, of course.
Please, have--have a seat.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
You're probably wondering...
why the biggest fight promoter
in the business...
is paying a personal visit
to a bum like youse.
Well, the answer's simple.
l'm offering your chicken
the main event.
The main event?
Huh. Here's my card.
l take it l'll see you there...
with your chicken.
Oh, and another thing.
lf you're going to play
with the big boys...
try dressing like one.
Sure thing! You got it!
No problem!
Did you hear that, chicken?
''Play with the big boys.''
Looks like this is the place.
Yes, this is the place.
Magnificent.
Well, what do you think, chicken?
Maybe next time,
we find you a new leash.
Hey! Why don't you watch
where you're going?
You almost stepped on
my champion.
Ah, you're back.
What'll it be?
The chicken, right?
No! No chicken!
Ahem.
l mean, no, thank you.
Actually, l would like to try
the shrimp today instead.
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack