Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku,
the shape-shifting master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil...
but a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fools seeks to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch--Watch out
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Why do l have this feeling
that l am being followed...
when l know it to not be true?
l am beginning to grow
very, very weary of this.
lt's you again!
Why are you following me?
Well?
l need not get upset
over such foolishness.
Still hungry, are you?
Here. Take these and depart...
that l may continue my quest
unhindered.
l am guessing it will require
more than berries to satisfy your appetite.
Just a little closer to that mushroom...
and soon we'll both be filling our bellies
with fresh, juicy venison.
lsn't that right, my furry friend?
l told you,
you have got to stop following me.
My journeys
have taken enough of my energy.
The last thing l am in need of
is another burden.
And plus, this mission
has a very low survival rate...
for those not schooled in every facet
of martial arts discipline.
Wait!
ln accordance with the map,
the cave should be...
there!
That's it!
The Crystal of Cagliostro.
My quest has finally ended.
The power of the crystal
will return me to the past...
to destroy Aku and reclaim my land.
lt seems we will be parting ways now.
Yes, l know.
l am sorry
if l was at times impatient with you.
l feared you would somehow interfere
with my goal...
when you actually helped me achieve it.
Well...
good-bye.
Wait! You must stay behind!
Please, go back.
Nothing can interfere
with me reaching that portal!
What are you doing? No!
Please, stop!
l cannot believe what you have done.
l must sleep now.
Tomorrow you will return
to from where you came.
She comes roaring out of nowhere
in a crazy street machine
She's pretty, pretty, pretty
But mean, mean, mean
l'm gonna help you, buddy
lt's a real bad scene
But when that ride is over
you'll be seven shades of green
Wild ride, she'll take you for a wild ride
ln and out and up and down
Wild, wild ride
Wild ride, she'll take you for a wild ride
Ride on high, don't get thrown
Wild, wild ride
This ride ain't got no...
Wild ride, she'll take you for a wild ride
ln and out and up and down
Wild, wild ride
Wild ride, she'll take you for a wild ride
Ride on high, don't get thrown
Wild, wild ride
She'll keep your head a-spinning
like a hubcap on the road
And run your heart right over...
Burn rubber on your soul and laugh
as she goes rolling on
Funny thing about it is,
you'll miss her when she's gone
Wild--
Hmm. Looks like there is a small village
just over these hills.
We might find
a warm meal and some shelter.
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
- Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack