Long ago
in a distant land, l, Aku...
the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Watch--watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Thank you, Jack.
Thank you for helping us.
Now let us help you.
Travel north to the city of Kojima.
There you will find Goseki.
He will guide you through the city
to the foothills of Kazuo.
There you must climb the mountain
to the Bridge of Ogami.
Once you have crossed the bridge...
you have entered
the mystical land of Moon.
There you will come upon a lake...
a lake of great power.
Your journey will start there.
No! Wait!
Stop!
To keep from drowning...
your feet must touch the ground.
Clever how you people use
this beast for travel.
We do not use him.
lt is his generosity
that allows us to cross this lake.
Only he can cross it.
l meant no disrespect.
He has forever lived in this lake.
Seen many things.
All-knowing and very wise.
Great creature of the lake...
l am in search of a passage...
a passage in time.
Please, can you help me?
Come with me.
What?
You seek a passage in time.
Yes.
Come.
He seeks a passage in time.
ls he the one?
Perhaps.
He wields the sword.
l will find out.
You will continue...
with him.
He will take me
to the time passage?
Yes.
Huh?
Have l passed your test?
Yes.
They call me Jack.
The creatures of this mystical land
have guided me here.
ls this the passage through time
that l have quested for?
Yup.
l humbly request your permission
to use this great power.
No.
Guardian, by what right
do you deny me?
For countless eons, l have guarded
this magical power of time travel.
All have been denied...
from the mightiest of giants
to the tiniest of warriors.
You see, samurai...
only one man has been
prophesied to defeat me...
and that man is the only man
who can use this time passage.
And you, my man, ain't that man.
l have hoped that just once
l would not have to battle for my goal...
because it is noble and just.
But l see that this is impossible.
l must use the power
of this time passage.
And so, l will defeat you.
Ain't gonna happen.
We shall see.
Aw, you going
all old school on me, huh?
Well, l got me one of those.
l told you, man.
You ain't the one.
All right, brother, let's see what
you can do with that against...
...this.
Pretty good, but not good enough.
All right, dodge this!
That was my favorite suit
you just ruined.
l have never faced a foe
with such strength and skill.
l told you, man.
lt ain't gonna happen.
Now, why don't you leave
before you really get hurt.
Never!
l must return to the past!
Fool! You will never gain
entrance into--
Huh?
Oh. All right. l understand.
You can't use it yet, Samurai Jack.
Not yet.
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack