Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku,
the shape-shifting master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil...
but a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fools seeks to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch--Watch out
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
That strike you used was a Sun Fist!
And you used an Ox Fist and Tiger Claw.
And l'll use others.
Monkey Steals the Peach!
Countered by...
Dragon Sweeps His Tail.
The Shadowless Kick.
Countered by Horse Drinking Water?
How do you know these techniques?
l am Shaolin, like you.
How can that be?
We have been secret for centuries.
lf you are truly Shaolin,
you must know...
Mantis!
l know it as well as...
Southern Fist.
How about Eagle Claw?
Yes! And Water Beetle.
lf you know all of this...
then you know
the sign of our secret brotherhood.
- Brother.
The Grandmaster must see you.
lt is amazing that you have kept
the temple alive for so long.
lt is refreshing to see.
Yes. And because of the wisdom
and guidance of our Grandmaster...
we are attaining higher levels.
l see.
Step forward.
Speak, my son.
Grandmaster...
l am the pupil of Master Chu.
l am Tan Zang.
l was also a pupil of Master Chu...
with you at the temple.
How can this be?
l remember the day you arrived
at our temple.
l was but a boy then.
An emperor's son
had come to learn our ways.
You were training for your eventual battle
with the ultimate evil.
Eventually, Aku came for us...
and the temple was destroyed.
But the survivors and l
rebuilt the temple in secret.
Over time, l became the Grandmaster.
The years passed...
and my chi grew more powerful.
l became one with nature...
and received energy and nourishment...
from the earth itself.
l have attained the highest levels...
of awareness and wisdom.
But look at you--
you have lived as long as l...
and you are the same
as when l last saw you--
your youth maintained...
your chi and the power within you
must be the--the highest of all.
You have surpassed me.
Uh, no, Grandmaster,
it is not as it appears.
Aku tricked me
and sent me into the future.
l quest to return to the past
and undo the evil that he has done.
Aku! His eyes are always watching!
l must leave.
l have betrayed your secret.
l have revealed you to him.
l should not be here. l must leave!
Do not concern yourself...
for we are safe.
Aku cannot see you here...
for l shield this location from his vision.
You are safer here
than any other place on earth.
l must return to my own time.
Yes. To the north,
you will find a mystic temple...
guarded by a powerful magic.
Atop this structure, a gateway exists--
a gateway that only functions
for a few moments...
when the sun is at its zenith.
We know the way.
And we will help you fight.
l am thankful, my brothers.
Thank you for your help, Grandmaster.
lt was good to see you.
Farewell, young samurai.
That is our goal.
We must reach the top before noon.
Then let us waste no time.
lt was nothing.
Keep moving!
A gateway that only functions...
when the sun is at its zenith.
Time is short!
- You must go.
l cannot leave you two like this.
There's no time.
We'll hold them off.
You must go now.
He is free. We have done it.
We will not escape this...
but we will die with honor.
Head for the cave!
Get behind the statue.
Thank you, brother, for saving us,
but why didn't you enter the time portal?
You were prepared to sacrifice.
l was not.
But with the portal destroyed,
you will have to find another way home.
l am getting used to that.
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
- Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack