Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
♪ the war was lost ♪
♪ the treaty signed ♪
♪ I was not caught ♪
♪ I crossed the line ♪
♪ though many tried ♪
♪ I live among you ♪
♪ well disguised ♪
♪ I had to leave ♪
♪ my life behind ♪
♪ I dug some graves ♪
♪ you'll never find ♪
♪ the story's told ♪
♪ with facts and lies ♪
♪ I have a name ♪
♪ but never mind ♪
♪ never mind ♪
♪ the war was lost,
the treaty signed ♪
♪ there's truth that lives
and truth that dies ♪
♪ I don't know which,
so never mind ♪
♪ my woman's here ♪
♪ my children, too ♪
♪ their graves are safe
from ghosts like you ♪
♪ in places deep
with roots entwined ♪
♪ I live the life
I left behind ♪
♪ the war was lost ♪
♪ the treaty signed ♪
♪ I was not caught ♪
♪ I crossed the line ♪
♪ though many tried ♪
♪ I live among you ♪
♪ well disguised ♪
Trees.
That little place
in the rock
in the trees.
A cave
is how I remember it.
It's like a fairy tale.
Four days?
No, maybe he gave me
something.
Maybe I blocked it out.
It's a black hole.
This empty space,
those four days.
And what I remember
when I got...
I got in the car.
He didn't force me.
He didn't even get
near me.
He called me pretty.
I remember.
I remember
it made me feel...
I liked...
I got in the van
with a stranger.
Every time I remember
that feeling,
like pride,
I get sick to my stomach.
I could lie to myself,
but I felt proud.
I was proud
that he thought
I was pretty.
Makes me sick.
None of that
was your fault.
I walk up behind him.
It's him.
It's the guy.
I've been thinking
about him.
I've been picturing him
for months.
I'm not sleeping.
Passing strangers
who was wondering.
He turned his head
right as I was
up on him.
I planned to say it...
but I didn't say anything.
I got sick,
and to keep from being sick,
I raised up...
right when
he was turning.
And I...
It didn't make
anything better.
It made it worse.
And I know now,
you know, the act,
it described
a trajectory.
People...
whole cultures
wouldn't blame you.
I don't.
It wasn't him.
They got the real guy.
Something in Venice,
you know?
Weeks ago.
Who was he?
I don't even know
if it matters.
So I haven't been
like this in a long time.
Years.
I could tell.
Why?
You seemed like
you were making up
for lost time.
I'd do anything
for 10 more years.
We should have met
when we were young.
We said we wouldn't
regret the past.
Anyway, who said we don't
have 10 more years?
There's 100,000 there.
You're gonna go
with Nails.
I'll meet you
in two weeks or less.
Like hell.
I'm not leaving you.
I know about the clubs.
I saw Blake.
- I'm not--
- You don't have a choice.
I always have a choice.
And I'm not
going anywhere.
It's not gonna work,
the you and me thing.
The way I see it is you
weren't up front with me.
If you can't have a kid, then
what good is the design, see?
You had me on
the fairy tale for a while,
and it was good,
but now it's time to go.
You can't act for shit.
Take it from me.
Where one goes, the other goes.
That's what we said.
That's not acting. Now take your
payout and get the fuck on.
Your ring?
What is that?
You think that I--
here.
You think I give
a fuck about rings?
- That was a big diamond.
- Fuck you.
I am not leaving you. I know
what you're doing, Frank.
Stop reading into things.
Listen to what I'm saying.
I am listening
and you're not convincing.
So you listen to me.
Whatever they do to you,
they do to me.
Do you understand?
There's us.
There's us, and everything
else is in the gray.
So fuck your martyrdom.
I came in this with my
eyes open, same as you.
You have to go.
I got us new cars. Nails is
gonna watch out for you.
No.
You come with me.
100,000 is more
than enough.
- To start over?
- To hold on to what's ours.
I can't run.
They'll come for me
and they'll keep coming.
I need to finish this.
You can't finish this.
They made sure of that before
they threw the first punch.
I have a play.
One thing they don't know.
It's not worth it.
I cannot run.
It'll never stop.
If I do that
and I come home
and I find you, no.
No.
I'm not--
I'm not leaving you.
Baby, you made it all
mean something.
Everything before we met.
If they came to me
through you,
if they hurt you,
I couldn't,
I wouldn't
deserve to live.
If you love me,
I cannot do the things
I have to do
unless I know
you're safe.
If I don't think
you're safe,
I'm lost.
They got me.
Nails has two tickets.
Venezuela
out of Oregon.
Not unless you're with me.
Otherwise the last
six years are nothing.
No, they weren't.
Never nothing.
I know.
I know. That was
never our story.
I got my ticket out.
I'll meet you inside of
two weeks, I promise.
Two weeks.
Or less.
Barquisimeto.
You'll meet me
in two weeks
or less.
El Obelisco.
There's a park there.
Wear a white dress.
You wear a white suit with
a red rose in your jacket.
I'll wear a red rose
in my jacket.
I'll see you coming
out of the crowd,
a head higher
than everybody else.
At first I'm worried.
I can't see you.
But then you do.
I see the white dress.
You don't have
to do that, Frank.
I mean the money.
Couldn't see.
Blood in my eyes.
Nail in my fucking head.
I heard him saying
leave me.
Fucking teamster.
A nail gun.
Slung me over your shoulder.
I don't forget that.
I know you don't.
Nobody's gonna
get near her.
I promise.
We'll see you
in two weeks.
Or less.
_
The security camera
right down the street.
Yeah, he, uh--
he worked under the prosecutor
for the AG that got murdered.
Excuse me.
- Yeah?
- Woodrugh?
He's no longer with us,
I'm afraid.
Hello, Ray.
- What happened?
- Why don't you tell me, Ray?
Hmm?
Davis, Woodrugh.
It's all you, right?
You know I know, right?
The robbery in '92.
Caspere kept
some diamonds.
He was holding them
over you, yeah?
We should meet.
Let's talk this over.
You could come out
of this good, Ray.
I can make it go away.
Put you right.
Get you paid.
Sure.
Yeah, I'll drop by
PD later today.
Where are you?
Come on, Ray.
You're one of us.
Why Woodrugh?
There was no reason.
Why do you care? You know
the guy was a fag, right?
Come on,
you're a player, Ray.
Let's talk.
We can work this out.
Yeah, sure thing,
Lieutenant.
What was that?
Woodrugh.
He's dead.
Who?
Why? What--
Jesus Christ. He was gonna
have a fucking kid.
It was Burris.
They're putting it
on me.
First Davis, now--
fuck!
I can't-- I can't--
Jesus, he was--
after everything else.
Fuck.
He was better than us.
He saved our asses.
Twice.
Three times.
Now.
He deserved better.
Who do we have now?
The girl Erica,
she's in the wind.
There was two of them.
- The kids-- boy, girl.
- What?
Field interviews,
that movie set.
We had a crew list. There was a guy there.
Set photographer.
She talked to him.
The ages are right.
Fuck, they even
kind of looked alike.
Set photographer.
Lenny Tyler.
That's the brother.
Laura and Leonard.
They might have
the hard drive.
Caspere's hidden camera.
Caspere's murder,
if it was them,
it just opened up
all this other stuff.
We were always set up.
So was Frank.
Your gangster buddy.
Yeah, he's actually
not a bad guy,
but, yeah,
Caspere was playing him.
So we find Osterman.
Tyler.
Says here Lenny's
with the union.
They'd have
some kind of address.
Unless you just want
to take off.
I'm pretty sure
I can get us
out of the country.
If there's a chance to get
them, I want to take it.
I was never big
on running myself.
Woodrugh wasn't.
Hello.
Austin?
Tony?
Where is he?
Tony.
I don't know.
What-- what day is it?
- There was yelling.
- Yelling about what?
A Russian man.
Tony's parties.
His new business
or something.
Hard to remember.
How did you meet
Austin the mayor?
Tony introduced us.
He say his father lonely
since mother got sick.
But you were
Tony's friend first?
Shh, shh.
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
How did this--
I-- I don't--
he kill himself?
Where's the daughter Betty?
Betty?
She was there, I think.
With the yelling.
They talk about me.
I hear them.
She's sick
like her mother.
I can't believe
Austin would do this.
Are you fucking dense?
This is your boy Tony.
Made it look like
some half-ass suicide.
And my guess is you'll
be taking the fall.
Where's Tony now?
Think.
Where would he be?
I-- I don't know.
He's cold to me now.
Is there a safe
in the house?
Do you have access
to bank accounts?
Austin handles
those things.
I have allowance.
Then I hope you saved some
of that Miss Ukraine money.
Len?
You?
They split us up after.
I had a foster family,
but Len went
into a group home.
I ran away at 16.
Started working
the streets.
How did you meet
Caspere?
Through Tascha.
She introduced
me to Tony.
Brought me
into the parties.
Then she told me
about his diamonds.
Then I met him...
and I knew.
He used to visit
my mother.
I remembered him.
And you got him
to hire you?
I changed my name.
Dyed my hair red.
He didn't recognize me
from the parties.
I started digging
into all of his stuff.
And Len,
your brother?
We found each other
years back.
He'd been through a lot.
The places he grew up.
I got him a job
on the movie set.
And what happened
with Caspere exactly?
I went to his place.
His other place. I left
the door unlocked.
Put a pill in his drink.
Len came in. He saw
inside the house.
He knew what
I'd been doing.
He went bad.
He was gonna use the
acid to get Ben to talk,
to tell us who else
had robbed us,
who had killed our parents,
but he got carried away.
He was too angry.
He put him
out there on the road.
- Why?
- I don't know.
I think...
he thought it was funny.
Caspere was confessing
everything.
Begging.
He told him about
the rail corridor.
He drove around with Ben's
body through all those places.
Why'd he leave you
like this?
Because I was trying
to stop them.
From what?
He's gonna meet up with
that chief, Holloway.
He's gonna trade him
the hard drive
from Ben's place
for the diamonds.
What's on the hard drive?
Would have been footage
of important men.
- You said would have.
- We didn't have the password.
And the hard drive
erased itself.
Some kind of
security feature.
- It's blank.
- He's going there to kill Holloway.
Where's he meeting
Holloway?
How long ago
did he leave?
A couple of hours. He
wanted to get there early.
- Where?
- The train station here.
The big new one.
He wanted a public place.
We got her testimony. You stay with her
until we can walk her into a precinct.
Ray. Ray, wait.
Saw the mayor went for a swim.
Thought I should say good-bye.
What are you doing, Frank?
This was very unlike you.
Lashing out, childish.
Now I have to answer.
Like I had to answer this,
you patronizing old fuck?
Are you still
in LA, Frank?
Oh, I'm long gone,
cue ball.
But we'll settle up later.
We certainly will.
Good luck with that,
you KGB kike motherfucker.
I'll only need
the one bullet.
Maybe not today
and maybe not tomorrow,
but, Osip,
when the lights go out,
that's me.
Who is this?
-  Velcoro.
- Ray.
I was just
thinking about you.
Where are you
taking me?
Me? Nowhere.
This bus goes
to Seattle.
Hits a couple stops
in between.
You get out of here.
Forget this.
Maybe it can
blow over for you.
This is never
gonna blow over.
My life ended that day.
Except it didn't.
You can lay it down.
I'm giving you that.
Why?
Because...
whatever debt there was,
you're not the person who
needs to be punished now.
What about Len?
Lay him to rest.
Sounds like you
lost him years ago.
What am I supposed to do?
I don't know.
Nobody is here right now.
I just move
a group through.
Anybody come around
asking about me?
No.
What are you doing, Frank?
Taking off soon.
And I'm signing
the place over to you.
All the way.
It's yours.
Thank you.
I was always grateful
for your help.
You heard about Ray?
It's a frame-up.
He'll be back here,
everything goes all right.
They're gonna need
transport to Mexico.
They?
Him and a woman.
What is going on? I heard
about the poker room.
Everything's ending.
Time to wake up.
♪ lately I'm not feeling
like myself ♪
♪ when I look
into the glass ♪
♪ I see someone else ♪
♪ I hardly recognize
this face I wear ♪
♪ when I stare into her eyes,
I see no one there ♪
♪ lately I'm not feeling
like myself ♪
♪ lately I've been
losing all my time ♪
♪ all that mattered
to me ♪
♪ slips my mind ♪
♪ every time I hit
another town ♪
♪ strangers appear
to lock me down ♪
♪ and lately I've been
losing all my time ♪
Don't turn around or I'll cut you in
half before the show even starts.
Just listen closely.
You're fucking
this up, kid.
Who are you?
The guy you blasted
with a fucking shotgun
in your little bird mask.
That was Caspere's.
Sick fuck.
Could have killed you.
Well, you don't need to
worry about that right now.
I know what they did.
- Why you're here.
- You know what they did?
To my father?
To me and my sister?
Executed.
Turned my sister
into a whore.
I know everything.
I want them, too.
But suicide ain't
gonna get that.
You want revenge?
Drag their shit out
into the light.
They won't get punished.
I am the blade
and the bullet.
Then listen
carefully to me.
The hard drive
is in this bag.
Lot of interesting
things on there.
A man with this, buy
himself a lot of juice.
What?
What, a wire?
See, I don't need
a wire, Chief.
I got plenty
of insurance.
What I need
is a payout.
The land documents.
They're in the bag, too.
The man who wanted to
meet, he killed Caspere?
Correct.
One of the Osterman kids.
All grown up.
Where is he now?
In a Vinci landfill.
I got copies
of everything.
Something happens
to me on the way out,
that shit hits the cloud.
News agencies.
What do you want?
Any chance
you brought the stones?
Plastic. Had I known
you were coming,
we could have made
different arrangements.
I want out from under.
I want my name cleared.
For the hard drive
and land documents?
Mm-hmm.
And Bezzerides?
Where is she?
Fuck should I know?
She and that Woodrugh guy
both thought I did Davis.
Think I've been working
for you the whole time.
Too bad you weren't.
Honestly, Ray, nobody had an
idea you were this competent.
You all bought your way
into Vinci with the stones.
Caspere made a deal
with Chessani.
Ben had a talent
for dissembling.
And Dixon?
He wasted his part
of the take, yeah?
He was looking to, what, blackmail
you guys for a new piece?
Where is this going, Ray?
Amarilla.
The shoot-out.
How did that happen?
He may have gotten
a tip about the raid.
Closed everything out,
didn't it?
Now you got a piece
of that central corridor.
You know
Chessani's dead, right?
Not the Chessani
I work for.
Cut the shit, Ray.
Whatever happened in '92
isn't the issue.
You want clear,
we put this on Bezzerides.
Geldof is already
on board.
No sudden movements, son.
You're public enemy
number one.
Don't even need a reason
to vaporize you.
Couldn't you have
just taken the stones?
Way back?
Did you have to kill
those people?
The Osterman woman had
been seeing Ben for years.
She was pregnant
and she knew things.
When he tried to break it
off, she threatened him.
Ben didn't even want the first
kid, much less another one.
The first one?
The girl.
The little one.
That was Ben's
illegitimate daughter.
- Downstairs!
- Oh, my God! Go!
- No!
- Move, move!
Out of the way!
♪ the mystery ♪
♪ that no one knows ♪
♪ where does love go ♪
♪ when it goes? ♪
♪ lately words
are missing ♪
♪ from now on ♪
♪ vanished in the haze ♪
♪ of love gone wrong ♪
♪ there's no future ♪
♪ there's no past ♪
♪ in the present,
nothing lasts ♪
♪ lately someone's missing
from now on... ♪
We met?
You're a cop, right?
Lady cop.
What gave me away?
The tits?
I meant you're a lady.
You have dignity.
You like Ray?
I like Ray.
Sure that means
a lot to him.
Relationships
are important.
Maybe you disagree.
You take this Venezuela
deal we're talking,
you make it
to Barquisimeto,
there'll be this
lady there in two weeks
at this park.
El Obelisco.
Her name is Jordan.
If she's there
and I'm not,
maybe you can give
her a message.
What's that?
Tell her I wanted
to be there.
And that story we told,
it's still true.
Talk to you a minute?
Venezuela works.
Shit extradition.
We could have good lives.
Well, I don't have
much choice at this point.
Anaheim went to shit.
Yeah, but a heist?
You got money to run?
Can't even access a bank.
No credit cards.
Even if retreat
was my inclination,
which it fucking is not,
you want to stay alive,
you and yours,
you need money.
You promised me
the guy who set me up.
It was Blake.
The guy you clipped was some
shit stain had it in for him.
Blake's gone.
He did not go nicely.
Maybe I spared
you that one.
These fucks will never
see it coming, man.
Place is so far
up the mountain,
it'll be a day before anybody
realizes what happened.
This is just
information, right?
Shit in the air.
That guy they're saying
you killed,
he was your buddy, right?
Actually,
I don't think
I knew him that well.
But...
yeah, yeah,
he was my friend.
Maybe that means
something.
Call it what you want--
revenge, justice,
a retirement package.
Men like this...
they always skate.
Not with me they don't.
I did not live my life
to go out like this.
You?
We use a short cruise,
tourists to Ensenada.
From there, we go south
to San Miguel.
My people are there.
We find someone.
We get you all
to Venezuela.
You've done this a lot?
Much easier to bring
people in than out.
I've been trying to get
Ray to see San Miguel.
How do you know them?
The man that hurt me
years ago,
Ray took care of him.
Put him in prison,
I mean.
Disabled wing.
Frank gave me the money
to buy this place.
Never asked
for it back.
How do you know Ray?
Well, I guess we saved
each other's lives.
Tony and Betty. Pitlor, I
want him on the record.
His files. We can
get confessions.
I've heard enough
confessions today.
Venezuela?
We got nothing
to run on.
And I owe these filth.
I owe Woodrugh.
Would you run?
Now?
If I asked,
would you?
I might.
I just might.
_
...a very strong foundation
on which to build a future.
There's a point
to the waltzing in.
I do not like beginning
something unfinished.
Mr. Agronov, have you
ever heard of moderation?
Guess I was wrong.
It was today.
Old times, Frank.
I saved you.
You're like my son.
- Stay down south.
- Yeah.
You're going, right?
We got to get out.
Yeah, that's the plan.
Thinking about
your boy?
Now you can
send him to Yale.
Sure.
You taking the boat?
I made other arrangements.
- But I'll be there.
- All right.
They suicided Pitlor.
Loose ends.
No sign of Betty
or Tony anywhere.
Fuck it.
Later for them.
Maybe one day
we get it to the press.
Maybe that "Times" guy
who wrote about Vinci.
We got a hell
of a retirement bonus.
I'm on my way now.
You understand?
Yeah.
I understand.
All right. You packed?
Yeah, I'm all set.
Boat leaves at 3:00.
All right. I'm 40 miles out.
Plenty of time.
Well, hurry anyway.
All right.
I, uh...
I'll see you
in a bit.
Yeah.
He's okay.
He's on his way.
Thanks.
They have a total valuation
of $3.5 million.
I will stand by their grading
anywhere in the world.
Meets your bio data.
You're even a premium club
member in United and American.
That's your two
plus five.
Frank, you're full
of surprises.
The Russians?
I wonder when we will hear
about what you've done.
Another 500 when
I'm where I need to be.
Safe travels.
So Chad crossed the
bridge and lost Calvin's farm.
Under five, you're
supposed to use the names.
17, that's within your
maximum power threshold.
Under five, you need
18 or higher to use...
Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
Why?
Hey, cutting it
a little close.
I, uh--
I'm gonna be late.
The fuck are
you talking about?
Get on that boat.
Wh-- what?
You hear me?
You get on that boat.
I'll catch up.
Wait. What--
what is--
No, just get here.
I just wanted--
I thought we had time.
What?
I just wanted to see
my boy again.
What?
There's a transponder
on my car.
Maybe they were watching
from school.
I don't know.
Dump it.
Come on,
get rid of it.
Put it on a truck headed north.
Come on-- shit, Ray.
I can't.
They could have already
been watching, see?
And if they got
eyes on me,
it won't matter what I do
with the tracker.
I'd just lead
them to you.
You understand?
- So what-- what are--
- You just get on the boat.
Just take the files, take the
recordings and get on that boat.
Look, I'll ditch the car
in a parking garage.
I'll jack another one.
I'll be
right on your heels.
Then I'll wait.
You stick to the plan.
Please.
Please get
onto the boat.
Trust me.
I can lose these assholes
with a tricycle.
Okay.
Yeah.
Listen, let me talk
to Felicia.
Please. All right?
Just for a second.
I'm gonna talk
to you again, right?
We're gonna see
each other again?
Are you kidding?
You're gonna need
a restraining order.
No. No, I won't.
Okay.
- Hello.
- I'm not gonna make it.
Don't ask,
just listen to me.
You owe me, right?
You owe me.
I don't care if you
have to tie her up,
you make sure
she gets out.
You get her out.
Okay.
I promise.
What did he say?
To make sure
you get on that boat.
You? What the fuck is this?
A turn here, a turn there,
and it goes on for years.
Becomes something else.
I'm sorry,
you know,
for the man I became...
the father I was.
I hope you got the strength
to learn from that.
And I hope you got no doubts
how much I loved you, son.
And you're better
than me.
If I had been stronger...
I would have been
more like you.
Hell, son...
if everyone was stronger,
they'd be more like you.
You taking me out?
I was already gone.
What the fuck
did you come out to say?
You made a deal.
No clubs,
no locations for us.
The clubs burned down.
What was I supposed to do?
Armenians, Russians,
this is their thing.
Where do the Armenians
get their supply,
what they gave to you?
You want to get square?
There's a flat million
in the suitcase.
That's my trade.
God damn it.
We're square, then,
our business?
That'll buy you something.
A million dollars doesn't
buy me a ride back to town?
Take his suit.
He wants your suit.
Give it to him.
You want my suit?
Hurry. Come on.
All right.
I didn't even wear a suit
till I was 38.
Stop, stop, stop!
- We kill him?
- What for?
Fuck!
We made a nice bed
for you.
Lie down, Frank.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
It's okay.
I don't know, boy.
I don't think
them other kids like you.
anybody does.
Who the fuck wants
some lanky loudmouth
pissing in
their ear, huh?
Your mother sure didn't.
It's what made her sick.
Your fucking whining,
that's why she's gone.
Shut up.
Shut the fuck up.
Faggot.
Scared of the dark.
Yeah, I never loved you.
I never asked you to.
Shut up.
Shut the fuck up.
Still got time, Ray.
Where's the papers?
Where's the woman?
Yes, yes, gawky
motherfucker.
I told you not
to come around here.
You fucking retarded
or something?
Told you what
would happen to you.
Fuck your shit up,
Larry Bird.
Stop and lie down,
you dumb motherfucker.
Fuck you.
Never lie down.
Last time, Ray.
Let me help you.
Bezzerides.
Where is she?
In a better place.
_
Please, Frank. They
don't have to do this.
Tell them. Tell them
I'll make it up.
I got stupid.
Please.
Frank, you could
let me go.
They'll never know.
It's not me.
I didn't put you here.
But you could
get me out.
Please, Frank.
I got a family.
It isn't me.
Hi there, handsome.
You made it.
You okay?
I did.
I'm fine.
I'm safe.
I'm coming.
Hold on.
What's a guy like you
doing in a place like this?
Just making my way, baby.
I told you
I'd make it.
You did.
You made it.
You can rest now.
No rest.
Never stop moving.
Babe...
Oh, babe.
You stopped moving
way back there.
The former sheriff's
deputy and City of Vinci detective
was the chief suspect
in the murder
of a state attorney and a
state police investigator.
He was employed
as a security consultant
at a Vinci casino,
which recently burned down.
After a lengthy pursuit,
the fugitive engaged
a tactical squad
of state and city police
in a firefight
which resulted in his death.
_
A lot of the rest was in the
papers over the next year...
if you know where to look.
_
These facts were
paid for in blood...
so honor that.
_
I don't know if it'll
make any difference,
but it should
because we deserve
a better world.
And I owe him that.
I owe his sons that.
Anyways...
this is evidence.
Most of it's here,
some of it's not.
The truth...
is naked larceny,
open murder,
and cascading betrayals.
Come with me.
Testify.
I can bring this
to the "Times."
It's your story now.
I told it.
- But wait, there's--
- Stay here.
Don't leave this room until
I've been gone for an hour.
Understand?
Oh!
Yeah.
Oh.
I know.
It's okay.
Hi.
He's restless.
Long trip ahead.
Ready? Okay.
Mm-hmm,
here we go.
You okay?
♪ lately words are missing
from now on ♪
♪ vanished in the haze
of love gone wrong ♪
♪ there's no future,
there's no past ♪
♪ in the present
nothing lasts ♪
♪ lately someone's missing
from now on ♪
♪ lately I'm not feeling
like myself ♪
♪ when I look
into the glass ♪
♪ I see someone else ♪
♪ I hardly recognize
this face I wear ♪
♪ when I stare into her eyes,
I see no one there ♪
♪ lately I'm not feeling
like myself ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
♪ the mystery
that no one knows ♪
♪ where does love go
when it goes? ♪
♪ the mystery
that no one knows ♪
♪ where does love go
when it goes? ♪