Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
♪ the war was lost ♪
♪ the treaty signed ♪
♪ I was not caught ♪
♪ I crossed the line ♪
♪ though many tried ♪
♪ I live among you ♪
♪ well disguised ♪
♪ I had to leave ♪
♪ my life behind ♪
♪ I dug some graves ♪
♪ you'll never find ♪
♪ the story's told ♪
♪ with facts and lies ♪
♪ I have a name ♪
♪ but never mind ♪
♪ never mind ♪
♪ the war was lost,
the treaty signed ♪
♪ there's truth that lives
and truth that dies ♪
♪ I don't know which,
so never mind ♪
♪ I could not kill
the way you kill ♪
♪ I could not hate ♪
♪ I tried, I failed ♪
♪ you turned me in ♪
♪ at least you tried ♪
♪ you side with them
whom you despise ♪
♪ this was your heart,
this swarm of flies ♪
♪ this was once your mouth,
this bowl of lies ♪
♪ you served them well,
I'm not surprised ♪
♪ you're of their kin ♪
♪ you're of their kind ♪
_
I feel so fucked up.
My head's so fucked up.
You want me to roll a joint?
Oh, those fucking fucks.
Holloway was there.
Fucking Geldof.
The fucking AG was shaking
hands with the...
That piece of shit
tried to choke me out.
He put his hands
on the wrong...
I've been waiting
my whole life for that.
I think I even...
went looking.
That's my whole life.
And when I ran out of the
woods and they found me...
The woods?
What?
You said...
Oh, God.
Hey, look, I don't think...
This wouldn't help you.
It might.
It usually does.
All right.
Oh, it's the drugs.
It's the drugs.
I'm fucked up.
Mmm.
You're too far out
of my league anyway.
I'm gonna check out
the other two.
You and the girl, you should
stay here through tomorrow.
You know, we can see
what the damage is
and report all this to Davis.
Yeah.
You can call your sister.
Addenda to corporate charters
for holding companies,
shares dispersed to new owners--
Eagle Iron LLC.
President Osip Agranov.
Electralux Entertainment.
President Anthony Chessani.
It shows the holding
company's assets.
These are all land parcels
in that corridor.
Valley poisoned by mine runoff.
There was some kind of
buy/sell deal upon death.
I mean, they just repurchased
Caspere's shares for pennies
and redistributed them.
Motive.
Well, it's something.
_
Everything all right?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's just my fiancée.
Okay, what's next?
I got to, uh--
I got to check in at home.
We should drop this on Davis.
You want to hold the fort?
Question her when she comes up.
Yeah.
You think they could make me
for that security guard?
Would they?
I don't know.
I hoped you'd make it home.
But I guess here
is good enough.
Took a couple kicks last night.
Can you talk about it?
There'll be some new people
operating at the clubs
for a while, a few days a week.
What people?
Mexicans.
Something else to solve.
In the midst of being
gangbanged by forces unseen,
I figure I'd drill
a new orifice,
go on and fuck myself
for a change.
Frank, what can you
pull together?
Liquid right now?
Maybe 200K.
Three tops.
We could just walk away
from the table.
That's 45 years of my life.
You see me managing
an Applebee's?
I worked at one once.
They give you a shift meal.
I'll handle
the deliveries at Lux.
Mrs. Semyon.
You look lovely this morning.
Ray, dashing as ever.
Keep it holstered.
Aw. A little bit of
a strange night.
You should just tell
me what's going on, Paul.
The men on the phone scared me.
He said, "Ask Paul
about the pictures."
That's all he said.
He hung up.
What is this about?
Tell me or I'm not going.
It was that case.
I was undercover.
I just want you to be safe
for a couple days.
We are having a baby.
This will all
be cleared up by then.
Why did you get with me, Paul?
Why did you even ask me out?
I'm just trying
to be a good man.
Well, you don't try right.
What happened?
It was bad in there.
If they think I was you,
you need to disappear
for a little while.
What?
How am I supposed to disappear?
I'll give you some money.
Go up north.
Oregon, maybe.
Dad knows some people.
He should go,
too, just--
just to be safe.
For how long?
I-- I'm seeing someone
and I'm starting
school in the fall.
We just need
to put this case down.
And then you're okay.
But you gotta go.
Both of you.
Now, like today.
You get somebody to put some of
your things together for you.
You don't go back home.
What did you do?
I saved a girl.
She's in the next room
coming off of whatever
they had her on.
Did they give you something?
Did you go all the way in?
Inside the party?
Yeah.
Did you?
I don't see how you can
expect us to stay here.
Paul, if something
this wrong is going on,
maybe you should go
to your bosses.
Tell them you need out.
It's more complicated
than that.
The less you know, the better.
I can't go to the bosses,
not yet.
This op I did,
it might be nothing.
But I just want
you both to be safe
if my cover was blown,
that's it.
Two, three nights tops.
And what are we supposed to do?
Room service.
Don't answer the door
or the phone if it isn't me.
And, you know, just relax.
Okay.
You bring someone up,
invest time and emotion,
personal attachment,
and hope for what?
Parity.
Well, this is
way bigger than Blake.
You got probable
future governor
and current Attorney
General Geldof there.
And that guy from Catalast,
McCandless,
- he closed the deal.
- What deal?
We got these documents from one
of Catalast's holding companies,
transferred ownership of assets,
land in that rail corridor.
Now, they sold Caspere's shares
in two other companies.
One of them's owned by the mayor's kid,
Tony Chessani.
Him?
Kid's a twist.
I fixed a hit and run
for him once-- motherfucker.
Well, the other company's
owned by this older cat.
He was at the party.
I saw him at the warehouse
where they dropped the girls last week.
Looked European.
Papers said his name was...
Osip Agranov.
He's Russian Israeli.
Blake was listed
as the holding company's treasurer.
So to me, it looked like
your man helped Tony
and this other guy
fuck you out of Caspere's shares.
It could be they killed
Caspere for them.
My old chief Holloway,
he was there, too.
The girl, Irina Rulfo,
she's had a cop gave her
Caspere's stash.
Paid her to pawn it.
She said he was white.
You found Irina?
Sort of.
She's gone.
You got a name for me?
The man who put you on
my wife's attacker?
I'll have it for you
by the end of the day.
Word of honor.
I guess I'll continue
with the belief it wasn't you.
Uh-huh.
Ray...
go ahead and show
yourself out just now.
I need a few minutes alone,
process the ins
and outs of all this.
Sure.
I gotta go anyways.
Woodrugh, Velcoro.
The Rulfo girl said a policeman paid her
to pawn Caspere's stuff.
Look in LAPD service records,
all right.
Find out where
Holloway was in '92
and who else was in his squad.
Davis is meeting me
this afternoon.
I want her to see
those signatures in person.
Your sister put me onto you.
Said you were missing.
And then this
was delivered to her.
Contents of a mailbox you kept.
I need you to look
at this stuff.
These pictures.
Oh, shit, man.
Forgot I kept that box.
Right.
Yeah, Tascha
must have sent these.
Tascha?
You know Ben Caspere?
He had a girl
he introduced as Tascha.
Yeah.
I met Ben at
the Panticapaem Institute
when I was a maid.
He was the one.
He hooked me up on the circuit.
Tascha-- God--
was his, like, favorite.
She's Hungarian.
But she had these plans.
Photos of these parties.
I warned her.
Fuck, maybe she sent
these as backup.
Bitch tried to involve me in that shit.
She tried to blackmail them.
I warned her.
Dudes like this don't play.
All right, what about
these diamonds?
They mean anything to you?
Those must be--
Yeah, she had said once
that Caspere had shown her these diamonds.
Said they were special like.
What happened to Tascha?
Wherever we were,
it was someplace up north.
They found a camera.
So I think there was a cabin
out back.
It was Tony C and their guys.
They took her into the woods.
- Will you testify?
- Fuck, no.
I was hammered anyway.
You know what? Thinking about it,
I don't know what I've seen.
Is that when you
tried to get out?
I never tried to get out.
Girl fucked up.
All you gotta do
is follow the rules.
I didn't want to get out.
You feel me?
I was never missing.
You didn't look
like you wanted to be
where you were
when I found you.
I took too much Molly
on top of champagne.
So what?
It happens.
All right, so...
who's the other girl?
Her name is Laura, maybe.
I ain't seen her
in like five, six months.
Maybe they took her
out to the cabin?
No, she wasn't dumb
like Tascha.
Look, can I just get a ride?
Or call somebody?
Your sister's on her way.
What the fuck?
You don't think
my sister's fucked up?
The way she waits hand and foot on that
panty-sniffing motherfucker?
Better than being strung out.
Yo, I have a place.
I got nice things.
I had a good thing
with Tony and his people.
Maybe-- and this
is just a thought,
maybe you were put on Earth
for more than fucking.
Everything is fucking.
Oh, thank God.
No, stop.
I am not going with you.
Fuck your pervertido husband.
- He's different now.
- You need to lay low, Vera.
Stay with your sister.
I'll let you know when it's safe.
Till then, you're in danger.
You fucking putas.
You put me in danger.
And I'm the only one
who can get you out.
You reach out to those men,
I'll let them know you talked to a cop
and they'll paint
a cabin with you.
_
You motherfuckers.
Holy fuck.
_
Shit.
Late today.
Had to get Ivar
covering the pit.
Sorry, boss.
I was taking care of some stuff.
The girls had a
little private thing last night.
15 Gs.
- Yours.
- Holy cow.
You must be what they call
a natural-born pimp.
Me, I always saw a difference between
a whore and a pimp.
A whore can still
have integrity.
You want to move me up,
let me know.
That's the thing, right?
There's nothing
to move you up to.
Is there?
I mean, all my shit's been
taken down to the street.
You'll get it back, boss.
Everybody knows you will.
Stan was following you.
And he wasn't
the subtlest guy in the world,
so I'm guessing that
you spotted the tail.
Hey, look, boss,
I don't know--
What did he see you doing
caused you to punch
his ticket like that?
You took his eyes.
Why?
To make it look
connected to Caspere?
Truth is your only
play right now,
because you fucked up
letting yourself be alone
in this room with me.
Look, Frank, there's been
a mistake somewhere.
You're arrogant.
Or else you never would
have walked in here.
Have I got a fucking
story for you.
Hell.
Please-- ah!
Please.
Frank, please.
- I can--
- You can what?
Talk? Osip?
His crew?
Caspere? Stan?
Osip's people,
they've been running Eastern Bloc girls
through Southern California
for over a year, Frank.
Osip's been moving
to take your spot
ever since
your meeting in Paris.
With your help, huh?
They reached out.
All these moves you were making,
you'd have done the same.
You think they give a shit
about handshakes?
You never should have
brought this to Osip.
Fuck.
You kill Caspere?
Or did Osip?
No, no. Nobody knows
who that was, man. Nobody.
So where's the money
I gave him?
Caspere was always
gonna fuck you, Frank.
Osip was backing the play.
Osip and Tony Chessani,
they're absorbing
Caspere's action?
- Why'd you kill Stan?
- He saw me meeting Osip and his guy.
He wanted a payoff, Frank.
He tried blackmailing me.
- Bullshit.
- What the fuck? It's bullshit.
You got all these
big plans, land deals.
Where was that supposed
to leave us?
You taught me, "Make
your own opportunities."
That guy way back,
Velcoro's wife,
who was that guy you gave up?
What? Velcoro?
Frank, what--
He didn't hurt Ray's wife.
Who was he?
This fucking meth head.
He said I ripped him off.
He was gonna come after me.
I heard about
this deputy's wife.
I saw a chance
to step up for you,
get noticed.
Look me in the eyes.
I want to watch
your lights go out.
I can get money back.
I know where there's money.
Osip and Catalast,
there's a big cash exchange
tomorrow night up in Ojai.
McCandless's place.
Crystal Ranch.
Osip's turning over 12 million
for Caspere's shares.
12 million, Frank.
Who's gonna be there?
I don't know for sure.
It's a handoff.
Security.
Osip, he'll be there.
All right.
Get yourself together.
Anything else you can tell me?
Anything?
Might help.
They're taking it all, Frank.
Osip's people bought
the liens on the clubs.
My people won't
go along with that.
You don't have any people, Frank,
that's what I'm saying.
Nails, they never
approached him.
But anybody else,
they already bought.
Ivar.
Anything else?
Look,
they don't know you got me now.
I can work on the inside
for you, man.
Triple-cross.
Do this for me instead.
I can--
Remember where I found you?
Pushing Baby Aspirin
to club kids.
Johnny Mank wanted
to cap you in the alley.
I said, "Nah,
there's potential here."
Now you just shit my carpet.
Can't remember anything?
Something I can use?
Well, I grouped them
as hedonists.
And they seemed very close
in a secretive way.
And they did not stay long.
We had no real relationship.
You seem pretty friendly here.
Well, at the time
everyone was a pilgrim.
You understand? Everyone was passing
in their separate journeys.
And not all looking
for the same thing.
Some exploit openness
and freedom.
It was a shadow
of our best intentions.
But people came and went,
faces lost.
I regret so much of that time.
I remembered his face finally.
The man who took me away.
You always said
you couldn't remember anything.
People came and went.
But there was a man...
and I remember his face.
And I think I always
remembered it.
We couldn't sleep.
I wandered the forest
for four days.
Can't see it, those four days,
but I remembered his face.
I wish I could--
if I could just give you back--
my father-- you see,
my father, he was--
He was a harsh man.
He was strict.
I wasn't going to be like him.
Oh, God.
God damn everything.
That's what I say.
Are you gonna turn yourself in?
No.
I can't.
But I can fix it.
I wish your life
had been easier.
You didn't ask me if I did it.
It doesn't matter.
You're the most innocent
person I've ever known.
Thank you.
I won't forget this.
The APB on you,
they're watching your house.
I should have trusted you
with more of this.
I think with that harassment,
I could have stepped up more.
- Helped you out.
- It's all right.
I was jealous.
I'll say it.
I should have stopped
thinking of you that way
or switched partners.
No, I fucked up there.
You didn't.
I think I--
I think I might be unfair
to people sometimes.
Stay safe.
And stay alive.
Please be careful.
Please get out of this.
I will.
Follow them to Eugene.
They're gonna exit.
Better if you don't know where.
- And watch for tails more than anything.
- Copy that.
Had to toss my phone,
so I'll call you on a burner, check in.
Thank you for this.
Again.
Fuck you, Bezzerides.
Got three in one day.
Bet that's a record.
Delegate nothing.
It's worse than we thought.
We've been in a secret war here
the last six months or so.
Everybody's bought.
Ivar?
Don't tip, either.
Better they think
we're in the dark.
Jordan just walked in.
I'll catch her.
No.
Bring her inside.
Here we are.
Under the bright lights.
They're taking everything,
even what we got left.
They'll come for me.
What can I do?
Pack a bag.
Neils is going with you.
You can't stay at home any more.
All right.
I'll meet you tomorrow.
I love you.
This is GIA graded
with a dossier.
It tests excellent in optical
and symmetry analysis.
Five carats, $700,000.
It'll be between
five and six million.
I'd rather split the total
among more stones.
They don't all need
to be that high-end.
But I'll need the exchange
to happen fast.
Then it is not
about the stones.
It is about the money
behind the stones.
You are changing money you
are not supposed to have.
We do not engage
in such practices.
The money will be
untraceable in itself.
Abner Ehrman told me
I could work with you.
Please, articulate
the percentage
you'd require in order
to transact with me.
40%.
And all exchanges happen here.
As we have not done business,
like today, you will come alone.
It includes
my guarantee of quality
and a secure exchange.
Have your friends
ever been to Venezuela?
No, they've talked about going.
I wanted to treat them.
Engagement present.
Barquisimeto is beautiful.
I've got them both booked out
of Portland in five days.
And the tickets are alterable?
We can change them up if we need to?
Yes, sir. For that price, they
let you do what you want.
Ours are the best.
Digital everything,
including the chip.
But you still owe us
for the consignment, Frank.
300.
Which I'll pay
the day after tomorrow.
- With an extra five on top.
- With what?
You know about the Russians?
They're dropping roots--
women, drugs.
Taking a chunk of development
along the rail corridor.
You'll be taken over
inside a year.
Give me what I need,
I'll help them choke
on their piece of pie.
That's 100 now,
seven, day after tomorrow.
And this buys what?
I need two clean cars
that are fast
and some firepower.
Why trust we'd ever
see you again?
Because I need
that clean passport.
Then I'm moving on.
I get where I'm going,
I got another half mil for you.
What are you planning, Frank?
You might say
my ship's come in.
And who sails this ship?
You got an APB
on Davis's murder?
Davis was supposed to meet
me and get the whole story.
Found her there dead.
They probably did it with one
of the pieces I keep at home.
I switched license plates
at a fucking mall.
That's it, then.
She was our only authority.
You and her are fugitives.
Well, it doesn't make sense.
It was cops.
Back in the '92 robbery,
Burris and Dixon were serving
under Holloway.
Caspere worked
at the same station.
Jewelry store
was their district.
Caspere probably
helped them move the stones.
They were all working together.
Orphaned two kids.
Leonard and Laura.
So that's how they bought in.
The diamonds
and whatever they got for them
went to Chessani.
Next couple of years,
they migrate
into six-figure
salaries in Vinci.
Their own private fiefdom.
Except Dixon.
He was just a regular dick.
Dixon was checking in on those
diamonds before we ever found them.
Maybe he knew Caspere
held onto them.
Maybe it meant
leverage for him.
But Dixon taking that headshot,
I checked every arrest record.
Burris busted
Ledo Amarilla in '06.
Released after interrogation,
no notes kept.
That whole day was a setup.
Amarilla, too.
He thought it was gonna go
a different way, I think.
That's what Caspere's
place was tossed for.
Burris, Holloway,
Dixon, whoever,
they were looking
for those diamonds.
The last piece of evidence
for a 23-year-old double murder.
Tascha was gonna
blackmail Caspere.
So Holloway, Burris,
they killed Caspere.
That doesn't make sense.
Him dying bought them all exposure,
kicked this whole thing off.
And if they had Caspere, why wouldn't they
torture him for the fucking diamonds?
I mean, it's--
_
I gotta head home soon.
All right.
Could you take this to State?
State?
Davis is dead.
Geldof was at the party.
How about Ventura Sheriff's?
Oh.
They're looking to do me.
And what have we got?
Some documents for a holding company?
A theory on some
rogue cops from '92?
-  Feds?
- Not without more.
Unless one of you guys
got a friend there,
I don't see protection.
That ain't a fucking mayor.
That's a homunculus
state corporations slid into office.
Who the fuck
even is Los Angeles?
Nobody can say.
See? Nobody knows.
Nobody expects shit
to actually work.
Me, my family, we are Vinci.
We're a goddamn
political dynasty.
Like the Kennedys.
Do me a favor,
hum my balls a little, huh?
Maybe later.
Frank.
Another gin.
Time to hit the road, Austin.
You don't tell me
what time it is.
I'm just thinking you might want to
get home and take care of business.
What the fuck's that mean?
Your boy Prince Tony has been greasing
the skids to slide into your chair.
Buying the attorney general
with his hookers.
Working with a Russian
named Osip Agranov,
Jacob McCandless from Catalast.
All this in your house
behind your back.
Sober up.
You might realize you're getting fucked.
Now get out of here.
Closing time all around.
I'd have known,
I'd have gotten the red carpet out.
Let me make you a drink.
Our company bought
the lien here, Frank.
Same thing at the Lux.
The clubs are ours.
The clubs?
Shit, man, I'm working
just to stay in the black, here.
We think we can do better.
Bringing in our own girls,
move our own products,
wash our own money.
We're going to be doing a lot
of business in California now.
Good for you.
I tell you, hindsight,
I was out of my element
with that land stuff.
Stick to what you know, right?
I must say, you're taking this
better than expected.
Is Mr. Churchman around?
Blake?
Shit, no. Guy's been around
less the last three months
than my wife's period.
You know, Frank, my board,
they thought we should
take you out.
I said, "Frank Semyon
understands business.
He'll adjust."
So what are my prospects?
Straight up.
You can manage the day-to-day of
the casino and the club.
We put you on salary.
I said,
"Frank knows clubs."
I had ideas of getting
out of this, you know.
There's no such thing
for you, Frank.
That world isn't yours.
You manage clubs.
In time, we find
something new to build on.
Well, what can I say to that?
After all, no fighting
what you can't change.
Look, I ain't lasted this
long without some knowledge
of my own limitations.
And it is my hope
that we can fucking build on this.
Going into the future.
- Velcoro.
-  What's up, man?
I wanted to call.
I think--
I ain't told anybody
about this other...
thing.
But somebody sent me
these pictures.
Pictures of me.
What, of our thing?
No, it's something else.
This is mine.
I think I might be walking
into something.
Then don't.
- I'll call you back.
-  Listen, hold on. Wait...
What the fuck is this?
Orders.
I gotta take your gun.
Don't make a thing of it.
You've got eyes all over you.
Come on,
I can get you through this.
Black Mountain?
Not anymore.
Ares Security.
We rebranded.
We just service one client now--
Catalast Group.
When you got in touch,
what was that?
I had orders to check on you.
After all that press stuff,
make sure you kept
confidentiality.
This is your situation.
I didn't make it.
Let's go.
They just want to talk.
That was Woodrugh.
Something's up with him.
- What?
- I don't know.
He said he'd call me back.
We need an exit strategy.
Get out of the country.
There's no way
they'll let us go to trial.
You hear me?
Vera said this girl's
name was Laura.
Does she look--
she look familiar?
I swear,
there's something--
No.
Her name is Erica.
From the city manager's office.
She was Caspere's secretary.
- You met her on the movie set.
- Yeah.
Woodrugh said
one of the orphans in that robbery,
- her name was Laura.
- Laura.
- Ooh.
- You got it?
Yeah, it's here.
Let me see.
I don't know.
What do you think?
You've been looking
for information about me, son.
Well, here's
your chance to ask.
All right, Mr. Patterson.
Thank you.
No, this was very helpful.
Moved out of her apartment
six weeks ago.
Quit the city manager's
office around that time.
Woodrugh could do a trace on her.
Credit cards, whatever.
Figure out where she went.
Let's try him again.
Voicemail.
What now?
Ride it out till morning.
Guess we'll wait for Woodrugh.
We got a gas leak
spilling into the AC.
Need to clear the place
for three hours or so.
- Are you serious?
- Just fucking do it.
Everybody out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to a sudden safety issue,
we need to request that
you cash out your chips
and vacate the premises.
These tunnels exist
under the entire city.
Most people don't know that.
The pictures of you two
were a happy coincidence
we came across when clearing
Detective Dixon's apartment.
Apparently he was
keeping an eye on you.
Teague always had
a nose for secrets.
If you had just been honest
about who you are,
nobody'd be able to run you.
- You know that, right?
- And this is what?
Some documents were stolen
from a private gathering
of citizens in Monterey.
I believe you have
these documents.
Do not bother lying.
Not on me.
Mm-mm.
Velcoro?
Bezzerides?
Where are they?
- I don't know.
- Oh.
Velcoro has the papers.
He's turning them into the feds.
But I can call him.
We set up a meeting.
But I skate.
And I get every fucking
copy of those pictures.
That's accommodating.
Maybe too much.
Velcoro don't mean shit to me.
This fuck-up
dragging down.
He had me look you up.
Davis used all of us
and she's fucking dead.
The other, this Ventura dyke,
she's been on my ass
from the jump.
I could give a shit
about either of them.
Call Ray.
Set a meeting.
Osip wants to know
where is gas leak.
It's...
I'm just tired.
There.
I want to go to bed now.
That's "Splendor
in the Grass."
I love that one.
You tell Bud Stamper
to bring you home earlier.
Looks old.
It is.
Sad.
Good night, sleep tight,
don't let the bed bugs bite.
Good night.
I don't get
any service down here.
- Let me see. Ah!
- Hey, hey!
Oh, boy, you fucking up.
Cut the shit, son.
Shut up.
Toss all the guns.
Kill the fucking lights.
- Now!
- Do it.
Now...
Kick 'em forward.
Move.
This is gonna be
hard on my son.
The things he'll hear about me.
We can get out of this.
We get that girl's story,
walk her into the feds.
Fucking CNN.
I'm sorry.
I brought you back in this.
No, I made a choice.
A long time ago.
I, uh...
I thought everything
came from something else.
But it came from there.
You had something
like that, too, once, right?
It's not something
I talk about.
Well...
It's one of the things
I admire about you.
You're not a bad man.
Yes...
I am.
Do you miss it?
What?
Anything?
Fuck you.
No, no.
No. Fuck you.
Oh, what a fine boy you are.
So now we're
expecting another child.
I hope it's a girl this time.
You're a fine boy.
Well, I have to go now.
Oh. You'll come
back again sometime?
Will you come back for dinner?
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com