[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS,
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[coin clinks]
[someone dials
a phone]
[sighs]
[busy signal]
TELEPHON E--YOU
HAVE A TELEPHON E?
THANK YOU.
[dialing again]
[busy signal]
OH, THIS
IS MADN ESS.
IT'S IMPOSS I BLE
TO MAKE A CALL
IN NEW YORK.
YOU CAN SAY
THAT AGAIN.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS
AN OUTRAG E!
HE'S MAKING
ANOTHER CALL!
IT'S ONLY
HIS F I FTH.
HE DOESN'T
EVEN TALK.
HE JUST DIALS.
MAYBE HE'S GOT
A DIALECT, HUH?
(male narrator)
MR. ROGER SHACKLEFORTH--
AGE, YOUTHFUL TWENTIES.
OCCUPATION, BEING IN LOVE.
NOT JUST IN LOVE,
BUT MADLY, PASSIONATELY
ILLOGICALLY, M ISERABLY,
ALL-CONSUM INGLY IN LOVE
WITH A YOUNG WOMAN
NAMED LEILA
WHO HAS A VAGUE
RECOLLECTION OF HIS FACE
AND EVEN LESS
THAN A PASSING INTEREST.
IN A MOMENT YOU'LL
SEE A SWITCH,
BECAUSE MR. ROGER SHACKLEFORTH
THE YOUNG GENTLEMAN
SO MUCH IN LOVE
WILL TAKE A SHORT,
BUT VERY MEANINGFUL JOURNEY
INTO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[busy signaI]
OH, I S IMPLY
CAN'T STAND THIS!
I MUST GET
IN THERE NEXT.
I WILL BUY YOUR PLACE.
A DOLLAR.
OH! SOLD.
THANK YOU.
S I R. A DOLLAR
FOR YOUR PLACE.
THANK YOU.
MADAM E. A
DOLLAR FOR
YOUR PLACE.
WHY SHOU LD FIRST
PLACE BE THE SAM E
AS THE THIRD?
TWO DOLLARS.
TWO DOLLARS?
VERY GOOD.
THERE YOU ARE.
THANK YOU.
[phone rings]
HELLO.
HELLO, LE I LA DARLING,
IT'S ROG ER.
OH.
HELLO, ROG ER.
[sigh]
WHAT IS IT?
MAY I COME TO SEE YOU?
U H, NO, NO, I CAN'T.
I COULDN'T BEAR
TO SEE ANYBODY.
I'M A MESS.
OH, YOU COULD
N EVER BE A MESS.
LISTEN, DARLING,
I HAVE TO SEE YOU.
ROG ER, IT'S IMPOSS I BLE.
I MUST SEE YOU,
DARLING, M UST!
FU RIOUSLY, F I ERCELY M UST!
[whispers]
I LOVE YOU.
ROG ER, YOU'VE GOT
TO STOP THIS.
YOU'RE ACTING
LIKE A BABY.
I CAN'T SEE YOU NOW,
AND THAT'S THAT.
WELL, THEN, TALK TO ME.
SAY SOMETHING, SAY ANYTHING!
SAY SOMETHING?
ALL RIGHT, ROG ER,
I'LL SAY SOMETHING.
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
A FLYING J U M P AT
THE MOON?
THERE NOW, YOU'VE
F IN ISH ED, HAVEN'T YOU?
NO, SHE H U NG
U P ON ME.
I'VE GOT
TO CALL HER BACK.
NO, I HAVE
AN EM ERG ENCY.
WELL, SO HAVE I.
IT WON'T DO
ANY GOOD TO CALL.
I U N DERSTAND
YOUR PROBLEM.
I HEARD IT
TH ROUG H THE DOOR.
HERE'S THE
WAY TO SOLVE
YOUR PROBLEM.
LOOK, GO AND SEE
THIS MAN RIGHT NOW.
BELIEVE ME, THERE
IS NO OTHER WAY.
THAT MAN WILL H ELP YOU.
NO--
NO, EXCUSE ME.
GO AND SEE HIM NOW
AND YOUR PROBLEMS
WILL BE SOLVED.
THANK YOU,
THANK YOU.
IT'S AN EM ERG ENCY!
[slams door]
[loud bell rings]
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
STOP SKU LKING AROUND!
I--I WASN'T SKU LKING.
I JUST DIDN'T
KNOW I F, UH--
COM MON ENOUGH DISEASE,
NOT KNOWING I F.
S IT DOWN ON THAT
P I LE OF BOOKS THERE.
DO I KNOW YOU?
NO, S I R.
AS A MATTER OF FACT--
THEN YOU HAVEN'T
COME FOR A BOTTLE
OF THE GLOVE CLEAN ER?
G LOVE CLEAN ER?
NO.
AS A MATTER
OF FACT--
WELL, PERHAPS
ANOTHER TIME.
AS A MATTER
OF FACT...
YOU KEEP SAYING THAT!
COME TO THE PO I NT!
I DON'T KNOW
WHY I CAME AT ALL.
YOU SEE, A MAN GAVE
ME YOUR CARD,
A STRANGER.
OH, YES, SATISF I ED FORM ER
CUSTOM ER, MOST LIKELY.
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHY I CAM E.
I WAS S ITTING THERE--
OF COURSE YOU KNOW
WHY YOU CAME!
YOU WANT
WHAT I'VE GOT!
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'VE GOT.
O I NTM ENTS, SALVES,
POWDERS, SOVERE IG N REM EDI ES,
N ECTARS, LOTUS BLOSSOMS,
TOXI NS, TON ICS,
ANTI-TOXI NS, DECOCTIONS,
CONCOCTIONS AND POTIONS--
ALL GUARANTEED.
OH.
I DON'T NEED
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
WELL, YOU M UST,
YOU'RE HERE.
YES, BUT I DON'T
NEED ANY MEDICIN E.
YOU CERTAIN LY
NEED SOMETHING.
YOU LOOK FEVERISH.
OH, WELL, IT'S SORT
OF... YOU KNOW...
NOTHING.
"NOTHING" I
DON'T SU PPLY.
"SOMETHING" IS
MY SPECIALTY.
"ANYTHING" IS WHAT
YOU CAN GET HERE.
YOU'RE AM B ITIOUS,
IS THAT IT?
YOU WANT SUCCESS,
MONEY, ADM I RERS,
THE WORLD AT YOUR FEET.
NO, THAT'S
NOT IT AT ALL.
POWER! YOU WANT POWER.
NO, YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ALL I WANT IS LE I LA.
LE I LA?
YES, IF I HAVE LE I LA
I CAN DO ALL
THE REST MYSELF.
LE I LA.
I MIGHT HAVE KNOWN.
ALL HE WANTS
IS LE I LA.
I OFFER HIM
PRACTICALLY ANYTHING
AND ALL HE WANTS
IS LE I LA.
AND I GU ESS
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO
ABOUT THAT!
THAT'S THE S IMPLEST OF ALL--
THE ELEM ENTARY
PARLOR TRICK
OF MY SCI ENCE.
YOU DISAPPO I NT ME.
NO, YOU
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU SEE,
I'M IN LOVE
WITH SOMEBODY
NAM ED LE I LA
BUT SHE'S NOT IN
LOVE WITH ME, AND...
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M TELLING YOU THIS.
I DO.
I CAN ARRANG E IT
SO SHE'LL LOVE YOU.
HOW?
I PROMISE YOU
SHE'LL NEVER LEAVE
YOUR SIDE.
WHEN SHE ISN'T TELLING
YOU SHE LOVES YOU,
SHE'LL BE GAZING
AT YOU LOVING LY.
SHE WON'T EVEN EAT
BEFORE YOU DO
AND NOTHING
WILL BE TOO MUCH
FOR YOU
TO ASK OF H ER.
SHE'LL WORSH I P YOU,
SHE'LL BEG FOR KISSES
AND WEEP FOR JOY
AT YOUR TOUCH.
AND IF IN PASSING TIME
YOU SHOU LD PERHAPS
LOOK AT ANOTHER GIRL
OR EVEN DO A LITTLE
MORE THAN LOOK
SHE'LL FEEL H U RT,
BUT SHE'LL FORGIVE YOU
AND LOVE YOU
JUST THE SAM E.
FRANKLY, YOU'D
GET THE SAME SHAKE
FROM A COCKER SPAN I EL.
BUT THAT'S WON DERFU L!
THAT'S ALL IN
THE WORLD I WANT--
MY LE I LA'S LOVE.
HIS LE I LA'S LOVE.
IF IT ISN'T
HIS LE I LA'S LOVE
IT'S HIS DOROTHY'S LOVE,
HIS RH EA'S LOVE,
OR HIS GWEN'S LOVE.
TELL ME, ARE YOU SURE
YOU WOULDN'T BE INTERESTED
IN THE GLOVE CLEAN ER,
AS I CALL IT?
THERE ARE
MANY NAMES FOR IT
I NCLU DING "THE ERADICATOR."
BUT "G LOVE CLEAN ER"
IS A N ICE,
NON DESCRI PTIVE TITLE.
CLEAN, COLORLESS, TASTELESS
U N I DENTIF IABLE AND SURE.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN GLOVE CLEAN ERS.
WHY NOT?
IT'S SURE, IT'S SWI FT,
LEAVES NO TRACES.
IT'S PERFECT
FOR ITS PU RPOSE.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE
MAKING ANY SENSE.
MY BOY,
THAT'S ALL I MAKE.
WHICHIS WHY I'M
SUCH A LON ELY MAN.
YOU'RE SURE YOU
DON'T WANT TO TRY
THE GLOVE CLEAN ER?
IT'S VERY EXPENS IVE.
PERHAPS YOU
CAN'T AFFORD IT.
FOR I NSTANCE THIS
LITTLE BOTTLE
COSTS $1,000.
$1,000? ARE ALL YOUR
PRICES LIKE THAT?
SOME ARE,
SOME AREN'T.
YEAH, BUT
THAT THING
THAT'S GON NA
MAKE LE I LA LOVE ME.
OH, THAT.
THAT'S ONLY
A DOLLAR.
A DOLLAR?
LOVE POTIONS ARE
MY CH EAPEST ITEM.
AND THEY'RE
OVERPRICED AT THAT.
A DOLLAR FOR
MY LE I LA'S LOVE?
IT WON'T H U RT H ER?
IF ANYBODY GETS H U RT,
IT'LL BE YOU.
BUT I DON'T EXPECT
YOU TO BELIEVE ME.
PUT IT IN ANYTHING--
HER DRINK, J U ICE, SOU P,
COFFEE, WATER, ANYTHING.
YOU'LL GET EXACTLY
WHAT YOU SAY YOU WANT.
WELL, I DON'T
REALLY BELIEVE THIS
BUT I'LL TRY IT.
WHY, I'LL TRY ANYTHING.
THANKS, PROFESSOR.
YOU KNOW, IF THIS
WORKS, I'LL BE--
(both)
THE HAPP I EST MAN
IN THE WORLD.
[doorbell buzzes]
HELLO, LE I LA.
ROG ER, I TOLD YOU
I WAS BUSY TONIGHT.
WELL, JUST A MINUTE,
JUST A LITTLE MINUTE.
FLOWERS, SEE?
THAT'S VERY N ICE,
ROG ER, THANK YOU.
NOW IF YOU'LL
JUST RU N ALONG.
I COULDN'T HAVE
LASTED THE EVENING
WITHOUT SEEING
YOU, LE I LA.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S
LIKE TO LOVE SOMEBODY
TO LOVE ANYBODY SO MUCH
AND SO DESPERATELY.
LOOK, CHAM PAG N E--
JUST ENOUGH
FOR TWO GLASSES.
THAT'S NOT
ASKING MUCH.
JUST SPARE ME
FIVE MINUTES
AND HAVE ONE
DRINK WITH ME.
ROG ER, YOU ARE
ACTING LIKE A CLOD--
A SILLY, STU P I D,
SOPHOMORIC CLOD.
I LOVE YOU.
STOP SAYING THAT. I--
ALL RIGHT.
ONE DRINK.
FIVE MINUTES,
AND THEN YOU GO.
I'VE GOT TO PUT
ON MY DRESS.
IT'S LIKE...
IT'S LIKE M I LLEN N I U M.
WELL, LET'S GET
THIS OVER WITH.
WELL, YOUR TIME'S UP.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR THE FLOWERS
AND THE CHAM PAG N E.
NOW, GOODBYE, ROG ER.
EXCELLENT CHAM PAG N E,
WASN'T IT?
IT'LL PASS.
WHAT ARE YOU
LOOKING AT ME
LIKE THAT FOR?
WELL, PERHAPS
IT'S MY LAST LOOK.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU'VE HAD IT.
ONE LAST
LITTLE KISS?
ROG ER, PLEASE,
LET'S NOT PROLONG
THIS ANY LONG ER.
I HAVEN'T THE TIME.
NOW PLEASE GO.
NOW!
I DON'T LOVE YOU.
I DON'T WANT YOU HERE.
I DON'T EVEN LIKE
YOU AT THE MOM ENT.
NOW PLEASE GO!
OH!
HERE.
THAT'S THE BEST
I CAN DO.
AND THAT TOOK
ALL MY STRENGTH.
ROG ER...
WAIT A MINUTE.
PERHAPS I AM
BEING CRU EL.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE.
I KNOW.
ROG ER!
LET ME--MAKE IT
A LITTLE N ICER.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT DIFFERENCE?
COME HERE, BABY.
[shrieks]
LE I LA, COULDN'T
YOU PLEASE S IT
IN A CHAIR?
OH, YES, MY
DARLING H USBAN D.
OH, I'M SORRY
IF IT BOTH ERS YOU,
IT'S JUST THAT
I LOVE TO KN EEL
AT YOUR FEET.
WELL, KN EEL
IN A CHAIR.
OKAY.
WHICH CHAIR, DARLING?
U H, ANY CHAIR,
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
DARLING, DO YOU WANT
YOUR SLI PPERS NOW?
NO, THEY MAKE
MY FEET HOT.
OH, WELL, IF YOUR
FEET ARE HOT NOW
I COULD SOAK MY
HAN DS INICE WATER
AND THEN CARESS THEM.
NO, NO, MY FEET
ARE F IN E.
ALL RIGHT.
DARLING, DON'T YOU WANT
TO SMOKE YOUR P I PE?
NO, IT B ITES
MY TONG U E.
IT'S NOT BROKEN
IN VERY WELL.
OH, WELL,
I'D BE HAPPY
TO BREAK
IT IN FOR YOU.
I COULD SMOKE
IT ALL DAY WHILE
YOU'RE AT THE OFF ICE
AND THEN WH EN
YOU CAME HOM E--
THANKS, LE I LA,
BUT NO THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOM E.
OH, DARLING--
OH, DARLING,
I'M SORRY.
I'LL GET A CIGARETTE
FOR YOU
IN JUST A MINUTE.
JUST ONE MINUTE.
THERE.
I SHOU LD HAVE
PUT CIGARETTES
IN THAT BOX
BY YOUR CHAIR.
HERE.
THERE WE GO.
THANK YOU.
WOULD YOU LIKE
ME TO RU B YOUR
BACK, DARLING?
YOU JUST F IN ISH ED
RU BBING MY BACK.
I KNOW,
BUT I ADORE
TOUCHING YOU
AND I'D BE GLAD
TO RU BIT AGAIN.
NO, THANKS, LE I LA.
AM I DISTU RBING
YOUR READING?
NO, NO.
DID I DISTU RB YOU
BY ASKING YOU
IF I WAS
DISTU RBING YOU?
[impatientIy]
NO.
NO, NO, DEAREST,
NOT AT ALL.
OH, ROG ER.
I LOVE YOU, ROG ER.
I'M SO HAPPY
YOU'RE YOU.
YOU'RE JUST PERFECT.
I LOVE TO SAY
"I LOVE YOU."
I LOVE TO LOVE YOU.
LE I LA, I'VE GOT
TO GO OUT.
OUT. I'VE GOT
AN APPO I NTM ENT.
I ALMOST FORGOT.
DARLING... WILL YOU BE LONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
I MAY BE LATE.
WOULD YOU LIKE
ME TO GO, TOO?
NO! NO, I
WON'T BE LATE.
WHY DON'T YOU STAY HERE
AND H UG MY JACKET
OR SOMETHING?
IS ANYTHING WRONG,
ROG ER, DARLING?
NO, DEAREST, I'VE
GOT AN APPO I NTM ENT.
WHILE YOU'RE GON E,
MY LOVE WILL GROW
AND GROW
AND WHEN YOU
GET BACK...
[laughs nervously]
U H...
HI, THERE, PROFESSOR.
AH, YES, I'VE BEEN
EXPECTING YOU.
YOU HAVE?
YES, I RATHER THOUGHT
YOU'D LIKE TO HEAR
HOW THINGS TURN ED OUT.
I KNOW HOW
THINGS TURN ED OUT.
THAT POTION SURE WORKS.
I KNOW, I KNOW.
HOW ARE THINGS
WITH YOU?
THINGS HAVEN'T CHANG ED
WITH ME IN YEARS.
PRETTY UG LY S ITUATION
WE'VE GOT...
WITH CH I NA,
DON'T YOU THINK?
YOU DON'T LOOK
SO GOOD, EITHER.
ME? OH, I'M
F IN E, F IN E.
I JUST DROPPED
AROUND TO TELL YOU
THAT THINGS
ARE F IN E.
I'M GLAD TO HEAR IT.
AH, GLOVE
CLEAN ER, HUH?
SAY, DO YOU SELL
MUCH OF THAT STUFF?
NOW AND AGAIN.
BY THE WAY,
WHAT'S IN IT?
NO TRACE, NO ODOR,
NO TASTE.
NO WAY TO DETECT
ITS PRESENCE.
AND IT'S SURE.
$1,000.
THAT'S WHAT YOU
CAME FOR, ISN'T IT?
ME? NO, NOT AT ALL.
PAIN LESS?
IT'S PERFECT
FOR ITS PU RPOSE.
THE ONLY THING
OF ITS KIND
IN THE WORLD.
I NTERESTING.
SHE LOVES YOU
AS I SAID
SHE WOULD,
DOESN'T SH E?
A CONSTANT LOVE.
AND NOTHING YOU
CAN DO TO H ER
WILL CHANG E IT.
SHE WORSH I PS
AND ADORES YOU
AND HANGS ON
YOUR EVERY WORD.
YES, YES, SHE DOES.
$1,000.
I AM GOING OUT
OF MY EVERLOVING MIND.
I CAN'T STAND
IT ANYMORE!
NATU RALLY.
ISN'T THERE SOME WAY WE
CAN QU I ET IT DOWN?
NO.
ISN'T THERE SOME POTION
THAT'LL TRANSFER SOME
OF THIS LOVE
TO SOMEONE ELSE?
LIKE A COCKER SPAN I EL?
NOT A CHANCE.
SHE'S YOURS.
SHE'S SO NICE TO ME.
SHE'S SO VERY GOOD.
I KNOW.
THE GLOVE CLEAN ER
IS THE ONLY WAY.
WELL, I CAN'T DO THAT.
U H, THERE M UST
BE ANOTHER WAY.
THIS IS THE WAY.
THE ONLY WAY.
$1,000.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE.
ALL THE TIME--
LOVE, LOVE, LOVE.
I DO KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE.
HOW DO YOU THINK
I CAME TO I NVENT
THE GLOVE CLEAN ER?
BUT THAT'S
ALL MY SAVINGS!
I KNOW. IT'S
ALWAYS THAT WAY.
NO TRACE, NO ODOR,
NO TASTE.
NO WAY TO DETECT.
ALL RIGHT.
AH, ALL
MADE OUT, EH?
ONE THING IMUST
CAUTION YOU ABOUT.
YOU MUST USE
IT IMMEDIATELY,
HEAR ME?
AND YOU M UST
USE IT ALL.
WHY, WILL IT SPO I L?
NO, BUT YOU WI LL.
ONCE YOU DELAY,
YOU'RE LOST.
IF YOU FAI L THE FIRST
TIME YOU TRY TO USE IT
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE
COU RAG E TO USE IT
AGAIN. NEVER.
GOODBYE, PROFESSOR.
FAREWELL.
ALWAYS THE SAME WAY.
FIRST THE STI M U LANT...
THEN THE CHASER.
MY DARLING!
WOO! PARTY.
I THOUGHT WE
OUGHT TO HAVE
A PARTY.
AFTER ALL, IT
ISN'T EVERYBODY
THAT'S BEEN MARRI ED
SIX MONTHS
LIKE THIS.
DARLING, WHAT
A LOVELY SURPRISE.
WHEN YOU WENT OUT
YOU SAID YOU MIGHT
BE LATE,
AND I NSTEAD YOU COME
BACK WITH CHAM PAG N E
AND FLOWERS!
G LASSES. CAN'T
HAVE A PARTY
WITHOUT GLASSES.
IT'S JUST LIKE
THE FIRST TIME.
ONLY THIS TIME YOU
DON'T HAVE TO BEG
TO STAY.
YEAH, LATER.
LISTEN, WHY DON'T
YOU S IT OVER THERE
AND I'LL BRING IT
TO YOU. OVER THERE.
ALRIGHT.
OH, DARLING,
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HAVE CAN DLELIGHT?
IT'S SO ROMANTIC. LET'S
HAVE CAN DLELIGHT, HUH?
SURE. SURE. CAN DLELIGHT,
SH MAN DLELIGHT, ANYTHING.
OH, DARLING, IT'S
SO WON DERFU L BEING
MARRI ED TO YOU.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
SO COMPLETELY HAPPY
IN MY WHOLE LIFE.
I'VE LIVED JUST
TO LOVE YOU.
ONLY YOU.
THAT'S N ICE.
SWEETEST, HOW
DID YOU HAPPEN
TO THINK
OF THE CHAM PAG N E?
IT JUST CAM E
TO ME.
I REMEMBER
THE FIRST TIME
YOU BROUGHT
ME CHAM PAG N E--
HOW YOU LOOKED.
YOUR EYES WERE
F I LLED WITH LOVE.
AND YOU WATCH ED ME
DRINK, AND SO SADLY
BECAUSE YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS GOING TO BE
OUR LAST
DRINK, REMEMBER?
I REMEMBER.
LOVER, LOVER,
MARSH MALLOW, COME HERE.
COME S IT NEXT
TO YOUR LE I LA.
COME ON.
OH!
THERE YOU GO.
BABY BU N NY.
I'VE GOT N EWS FOR YOU,
SWEET LITTLE RABB IT.
RABB IT.
OH!
OH, DARLING, WE WON'T
WORRY ABOUT IT.
WE DON'T
NEED CHAM PAG N E.
WE'VE GOT EACH OTH ER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I COULDN'T
HAVE DONE IT.
I COULDN'T HAVE
GONE TH ROUG H
WITH IT.
I COULD NEVER HAVE
GONE TH ROUG H WITH IT.
JUST THINK
OF IT, DARLING.
THIS IS ONLY
THE BEG IN NING.
WE'LL BE LIKE THIS FOR
THE REST OF OUR LIVES.
WON'T WE?
(male narrator)
MR. ROGER SHACKLEFORTH,
WHO HAS DISCOVERED
AT THIS LATE DATE
THAT LOVE CAN BE AS STICKY
AS A VAT OF MOLASSES,
AS UNPALATABLE AS A HUNK
OF SPOILED YEAST,
AND AS ALL-CONSUM ING
AS A SIX-ALARM FIRE
IN A BAMBOO AND CANVAS TENT.
CASE HISTORY OF A LOVER BOY
WHO SHOULD
NEVER HAVE ENTERED
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male announcer)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, YOU'LL
STAND IN THIS ALLEY
AT THE SHOU LDER
OF JACK KLUG MAN,
WHO PLAYS THE ROLE
OF A TRUMPET PLAYER
WHO HAS RU N OUT OF MUSIC
AND RU N OUT OF DREAMS.
"PO IG NANT" IS THE BEST WORD
FOR MR. KLUG MAN'S PERFORMANCE.
NEXT WEEK ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE,
A PASSAGE FOR TRUMPET.
I THINK THEY'RE
U N USUAL NOTES IN DEED.
WE HOPE YOU'LL BE
LISTENING TO THEM.
THANK YOU
AND GOOD NIGHT.
[curtain music]
(male presenter, off)
BE SURE TO SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS.
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS
OVER MOST OF
THESE STATIONS.