[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS,
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
I WANT JAKE ROSS'
SECRETARY, PLEASE.
WI LLIAMS, WE'RE
STILL WAITING
FOR YOUR MR. ROSS.
I'M TRYING TO GET HIM
RIGHT NOW, S I R.
JOAN I E, WHERE IS H E?
I KNOW H E'S
OUT TO LU NCH
BUT WE GOT A CON FERENCE
CALLED HERE FOR 2 :00.
IT'S NOW 2 :30.
NOW, WHERE IS H E?
ALL RIGHT,
CHECK AROUND.
CALL SARDI'S EAST
OR THE COLONY
AND TELL HIM
TO GET HIMSELF
OVER HERE IN A HURRY.
WELL, WHERE
IS YOUR PROTEG E
WITH THE $3 M I LLION
AUTOMOB I LE ACCOU NT?
HE'S DU E AT ANY MOM ENT,
MR. M ISRELL.
PROBABLY A
B IG LU NCH CROWD
OR SOMETHING.
DON'T BE
AN IDIOT.
MORE LIKELY,
A BIG MARTINI
OR THREE OR
FOUR OF THEM.
HE WAS TOO YOU NG TO
PUT ON THIS ACCOU NT.
I TOLD YOU THAT.
I KEPT TELLING YOU THAT!
HE'S MUCH TOO YOU NG
TO PUT ON THIS LARGE
AND IMPORTANT ACCOU NT.
[knock at door]
WE HAVE NOW
BEEN HERE 34 MINUTES,
MR. WI LLIAMS.
THIS IS A COM M U N ICATION
FROM JAKE ROSS.
WOULD YOU BE SO KIND
AS TO SHARE
ITS CONTENTS
WITH US?
I CAN GIVE YOU
THE SENSE OF IT,
MR. M ISRELL.
THIS IS JAKE
ROSS'S RESIGNATION.
HE'S MOVING OVER
TO ANOTHER AG ENCY.
AN D?
HE'S TAKING
THE AUTOMOB I LE
ACCOU NT WITH HIM.
THAT ACCOU NT REPRESENTED
A GROSS B I LLING
IN THE N EIGH BORHOOD
OF $3 M I LLION A YEAR!
AND HOW
MANY TIMES
HAVE YOU PROMISED
IT TO ME?
[clears throat]
THIS IS AS MUCH
A SHOCK TO ME
AS IT IS TO YOU,
MR. M ISRELL.
DON'T S IT DOWN
AND DON'T CON ME.
IT WAS YOUR PET PROJ ECT.
YOUR PET PROJ ECT!
THEN IT WAS YOUR
IDEA TO GIVE IT
TO THAT LITTLE
COLLEG E GREEN I E.
NOW, GET
WITH IT, WI LLIAMS.
GET WITH IT, BOY!
SO WHAT'S LEFT, WI LLIAMS?
NOT ONLY
HAS YOUR PET
PROJECT BACKFIRED
BUT IT SPROUTED WINGS
AND LEFT THE PREM ISES.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT'S
LEFT TO US, IN MY VI EW--
A DEEP AND AB I DING CONCERN
ABOUT YOUR J U DG MENT IN MEN.
THIS IS A PUSH
BUS IN ESS, WI LLIAMS.
A PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH BUSINESS!
[thudding]
PUSH AND DRIVE!
BUT PERSONALLY--
YOU DON'T DELEGATE
RESPONSIBILITIES TO
LITTLE BOYS.
YOU SHOULD
KNOW IT
BETTER THAN
ANYONE ELSE.
A PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH BUS IN ESS, WI LLIAMS.
IT'S PUSH,
PUSH, PUSH
[thudding]
ALL THE WA Y,
ALL THE TIME!
IT'S PUSH, PUSH, PUSH,
ALL THE WAY, ALL THE TIME
RIGHT ON DOWN THE LIN E!
FAT BOY, WHY
DON'T YOU SHUT
YOUR MOUTH!
MR. WI LLIAMS,
M ESSAG ES ARE
ON THE DESK.
THERE'S SOME
HOT COFFEE HERE.
CAN I BRING YOU SOME?
NO, NO, THANKS.
WELL, WANT
ANYTHING AT ALL?
YEAH, A
SHARP RAZOR
AND A CHART OF
THE HUMAN ANATOMY
SHOWING WHERE ALL
THE ARTERI ES ARE.
(male narrator)
THIS IS GART
WILLIAMS, AGE 38,
A MAN PROTECTED
BY A SU IT OF ARMOR
ALL HELD TOGETHER
BY ONE BOLT.
JUST A MOMENT AGO,
SOMEONE REMOVED THE BOLT
AND MR. WILLIAMS' PROTECTION
FELL AWAY FROM HIM
AND LEFT HIM A NAKED TARGET.
HE'S BEEN CANNONADED
THIS AFTERNOON
BY ALL THE
ENEM IES OF HIS LIFE.
HIS INSECURITY
HAS SHELLED HIM ;
HIS SENSITIVITY
HAS STRADDLED HIM
WITH HUM ILIATION;
HIS DEEP-ROOTED DISQUIET
ABOUT HIS OWN WORTH
HAS ZEROED IN ON HIM,
LANDED ON TARGET
AND BLOWN HIM APART.
MR. GART WILLIAMS,
AD AGENCY EXEC
WHO IN JUST
A MOMENT WILL MOVE
INTO THE TWILIGHT ZONE
IN A DESPERATE SEARCH
FOR SURVIVAL.
[train bell clanging]
HOW ARE
YOU TONIGHT,
MR. WI LLIAMS?
IN THE ABSOLUTE P IN K.
COLD WI NTER
THIS YEAR.
SEEMS TO GET
DARKER EARLI ER
THAN IT EVER HAS.
WELL, THAT'S THE
WAY OF THE WORLD.
THE RICH GET RICH ER
AND THE DAYS
GET SHORTER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
(Misrell)
A PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH BUSINESS!
PUSH AND DRIVE!
IT'S PUSH, PUSH, PUSH
ALL THE WA Y, ALL
THE TIME
RIGHT ON DOWN THE LINE!
THAT'S ENOUGH.
[dog barking]
(male conductor)
WILLOUGHBY! THIS
STOP IS WILLOUGHBY!
WI LLOUG H BY!
THIS STOP
IS WI LLOUG H BY!
WHAT DO YOU
M EAN, WI LLOUG H BY?
WHERE IS WI LLOUG H BY?
THAT'S WI LLOUG H BY
RIGHT OUTSIDE.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
THERE'S NO STOP ON THIS LIN E
CALLED WI LLOUG H BY.
AND LOOK AT IT OUTSIDE.
THE SU N IS OUT,
IT'S SUMMER.
THAT'S WHAT SH E
IS, M I D-J U LY.
A REAL WARM
ONE, TOO.
WAIT A MINUTE, IT'S NOVEM BER.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE ANYWAY?
WHERE IS THIS PLACE?
WHERE IS
WILLOUGHBY?
WI LLOUG H BY, S I R?
THAT'S WI LLOUG H BY
RIGHT OUTSIDE.
WI LLOUG H BY.
J U LY.
SUMMER.
IT'S 1 888.
REALLY A LOVELY
LITTLE VILLAGE.
YOU OUGHT TO
TRY IT SOMETIME.
PEACEFU L, RESTFU L,
WHERE A MAN CAN
SLOW DOWN TO A WALK
AND LIVE H IS
LIFE FU LL-M EASURE.
WI LLOUG H BY!
THIS STOP
IS WI LLOUG H BY!
WI LLOUG H BY!
THIS STOP
IS WI LLOUG H BY!
[cars rumbling]
(conductor)
WESTPORT SAUGATUCK
NEXT STOP!
WESTPORT SAUGATUCK!
HAVE A GOOD SLEEP,
MR. WI LLIAMS?
YEAH.
YEAH, I HAD A GOOD SLEEP,
BUT AN I DIOTIC DREAM.
I DIOTIC.
YOU EVER HEAR OF A TOWN
CALLED WI LLOUG H BY?
WI LLOUG H BY?
WI LLOUG H BY WHERE?
WI LLOUG H BY, CON N ECTICUT,
OR WI LLOUG H BY, NEW YORK.
NOT ON THIS RU N.
NO WI LLOUG H BY
ON THE LIN E.
WESTPORT SAUGATUCK
NEXT STOP!
WESTPORT SAUGATUCK!
AND WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS
FOR THIS EVENING?
TO GET QU I ETLY PLASTERED
AND THEN SING
OLD COLLEG E SONGS?
IT'S BEEN ONE
OF THOSE DAYS.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT IT.
BOB LAIR'S WIFE
CALLED ME.
SHE TOLD ME H E'D BEEN
IN THE MEETING WITH YOU.
YOU GOT... YOU GOT
HYSTERICAL OR SOMETHING?
SHE CALLED TO F IN D
OUT HOW YOU WERE.
THEY WERE ALL
VERY SOLICITOUS
ALL THE BOYS
AT THE MEETING.
THAT FREE-FLOWING
COM PASS ION
THAT IS
ACTUALLY RELI EF.
I'M THE VICTI M,
NOT THEM.
THEY'VE M ISTAKEN
AN I NTAKE OF BREATH
FOR AN OUTPOU RING
OF SYM PATHY.
WOULD YOU SPARE ME
YOUR LITTLE HOM I LI ES NOW?
PLEASE, AND
JUST GIVE ME
A S IMPLE AND DI RECT
AND HON EST ANSWER.
DID YOU WRECK A
CAREER THIS AFTERNOON?
DID YOU THROW
AWAY A JOB?
IT APPEARS NOT.
M ISRELL PHON ED BEFORE
I LEFT THE OFF ICE.
HE HAS FOU N D IT
IN THAT GREAT
OVER-S IZED HEART OF
HIS TO FORGIVE.
THIS SOMEWHAT OBESE,
G RACIOUS GENTLEMAN
WILL ALLOW ME TO
CONTIN U E IN
HIS EM PLOY
BECAUSE HE'S SUCH A--
HUMAN-TYPE FELLOW
WITH THE
SMALL, I NSIGN IF ICANT
PARENTH ETIC ADDITIONAL REASON
THAT IF I WERE TO GO
TO A COM PETITIVE AG ENCY
I MIGHT POSS I BLY TAKE A
LOT OF BUS IN ESS WITH ME.
GO ON.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL
OF IT.
OH, I'M
TIRED, JAN I E.
I'M TIRED,
AND I'M S ICK.
WELL, THEN YOU'RE
ON THE RIGHT WARD.
WE SPECIALIZE IN PEOPLE
THAT ARE S ICK.
AND TIRED, TOO, GART.
I'M S ICK,
AND I'M TIRED
OF A H USBAND WHO LIVES
IN PERMAN ENT SELF-P ITY
WITH A HEART
BLEEDING SENSITIVITY
THAT HE UNFURLS
LIKE A FLAG
WHENEVER HE DECIDES
THE COMPETITION IS--
IS A LITTLE TOO
ROUGH FOR HIM.
SOME PEOPLE AREN'T BU I LT
FOR COM PETITION, JAN I E
OR BIG,
PRETENTIOUS HOUSES
THEY CAN'T AFFORD
OR RICH COM M U N ITI ES
THEY DON'T FEEL
COM FORTABLE IN
OR COU NTRY CLU BS
THEY WEAR AROUND
THEIR N ECK
LIKE A BADGE
OF STATUS.
AND YOU'D PREFER--?
I'D PREFER
THOUGH NEVER
ASKED BEFORE
A JOB, ANY JOB,
ANY JOB AT ALL
WHERE I COULD
BE MYSELF!
WHERE I WOULDN'T
HAVE TO CLI M B
ON A STAG E
AND GO TH ROUG H
A MASQU ERADE EVERY
MORNING AT N IN E,
AND MOUTH ALL
THE DIALOG
AND PLAY
THE EXECUTIVE
AND MAKE BELIEVE
I'M THE BRIGHT,
YOU NG MAN
WHO'S ON
HIS WAY UP
BECAUSE I'M NOT
THAT PERSON, JAN I E.
YOU'VE TRI ED TO
MAKE ME THAT PERSON
BUT THAT ISN'T ME.
THAT ISN'T ME
AT ALL.
I'M--
I'M A
NOT-VERY-YOU NG
SOON-TO-BE-OLD
VERY U NCOM PETITIVE,
RATHER DU LL
QU ITE U N I NSP I RED,
AVERAG E-TYPE GUY.
WITH A WIFE WHO
HAS AN APPETITE.
AND JUST WHERE
WOULD YOU BE
IF IT WEREN'T
FOR MY APPETITE?
I KNOW WHERE
I'D LIKE TO BE.
WHERE'S THAT?
A PLACE
CALLED WI LLOUG H BY.
A LITTLE TOWN
I'VE MANUFACTURED
IN A DREAM.
TELL ME ABOUT
YOUR DREAM, GART.
IT WAS AN ODD DREAM,
VERY ODD DREAM.
WI LLOUG H BY.
IT WAS SUMMER, VERY WARM.
KIDS WERE BAREFOOTED.
ONE OF THEM HAD A F ISHING POLE.
IT ALL LOOKED LIKE
A CU RRI ER & IVES PAI NTING.
BAN DSTAN D, B ICYCLES, WAGONS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
SUCH--SEREN ITY.
IT WAS THE WAY PEOPLE M UST
HAVE LIVED A H U N DRED
YEARS AGO.
CRAZY DREAM.
YEAH.
YOU LET ME KNOW WH EN
YOU WAKE UP, HUH, GART?
NO, WAIT, JAN I E.
PLEASE, JAN I E.
YOU KNOW
WHAT THE TROU BLE
WITH YOU IS, GART?
YOU WERE J UST
BORN TOO LATE.
BECAUSE YOU'RE
A GUY
THAT COULD
BE SATISFIED
WITH A
SUMMER AFTERNOON
OR AN
ICE WAGON
BEING DRAWN
BY A HORSE.
SO IT'S MY
M ISTAKE, PAL,
MY ERROR
MY MISERABLE, TRAG IC ERROR
TO GET MARRI ED TO A MAN
WHOSE BIG DREAM IN LIFE
IS TO BE H UCKLEBERRY F IN N.
YEAH, MAYBE.
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
A PLACE, A TIME WHERE
A MAN CAN LIVE H IS
LIFE FU LL-M EASURE.
THAT'S WHAT
HE SAID, THAT'S--
WHAT THAT CON DUCTOR SAID,
A PLACE WHERE A MAN
CAN LIVE HIS LIFE
FU LL-M EASURE.
(modern conductor)
WILLOUGHBY?
WHAT?
LAST WEEK
YOU ASKED ME
ABOUT A TOWN
CALLED WI LLOUG H BY.
WELL, I
LOOKED IT UP.
EVERY OLD TIMETABLE
I COULD FIND.
NO SUCH PLACE,
AS FAR AS I
COULD SEE.
THANKS.
IT WAS A DREAM,
IS ALL.
PROBABLY WAS.
STAM FORD NEXT STOP!
NEXT STOP, STAMFORD!
[train horn blaring]
STAMFORD! STAMFORD
NEXT STOP!
STAMFORD!
NEXT STOP, STAMFORD!
STAMFORD, NEXT STOP!
(conductor of the past)
WILLOUGHBY!
THIS STOP
IS WILLOUGHBY!
WILLOUGHBY!
THIS STOP
IS WILLOUGHBY!
WI LLOUG H BY, S I R.
WI LLOUG H BY?
YES, S I R, WI LLOUG H BY.
WI LLOUG H BY!
ALL ON
FOR WI LLOUG H BY!
WILLOUGHBY! THIS
STOP IS WILLOUGHBY!
[band playing
Camptown Races]
CON DUCTOR!
CONDUCTOR!
CONDUC--!
YOU ALL RIGHT,
MR. WI LLIAMS?
YEAH, YEAH.
SURE, I'M ALL RIGHT.
WI LLOUG H BY.
NEXT TIME--
NEXT TIME,
I'M GOING TO GET OFF.
I'M GOING TO GET OFF
AT WI LLOUG H BY.
(Misrell over phone)
WHAT WE NEED
HERE, WILLIAMS,
IS A SHOW WITH ZAZ.
AN ENTERTAINER
WITH MOXIE.
WE'VE GOT TO TAKE
THE AUDIENCE BY
THE EARS
AND GIVE 'EM
A YANK,
JAR 'EM,
ROCK 'EM,
GIVE 'EM THE OL'
PUSH PUSH PUSH.
I UNDERSTAND,
MR. M ISRELL.
IT'S GOTTA
BE BRIGHT.
BRIGHT WITH
A PATTER.
THAT'S IT, COMEDY.
AND EVERYTHING
PUSH PUSH PUSH.
OF COURSE, NOW
IT'S GOTTA
BE BRIGHT.
PUSH PUSH PUSH.
THAT'S THE KIND OF
SHOW THE CLIENT
WILL LIKE.
I UNDERSTAND,
MR. M ISRELL.
I UNDERSTAND.
TOMORROW MORNING,
I WANT AT LEAST A
PRELI M I NARY IDEA FOR THE SHOW.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I WANT.
JUST A ROUG H
FORMAT WITH A
FEW DETAI LS
AS TO HOW WE I NTEG RATE
THE COM MERCIALS WITH IN
THE BODY OF THE SHOW.
I UNDERSTAND,
MR. M ISRELL.
I'LL DO THE
BEST I CAN.
DO MORE
THAN YOU CAN.
ASPIRE. DREAM BIG
AND THEN GET
BEHIND IT.
PUSH PUSH
PUSH PUSH!
YES, S I R!
[phone rings]
YES?
WELL, I HAVEN'T SEEN
THE RATINGS ON THE SHOW.
NO, NO.
WELL, THAT'S
THE TIME SLOT
THE SPONSOR WANTED.
[phone rings]
HANG ON A MINUTE.
YES?
THEY WHAT?
HOLD ON A SECON D.
H ELEN.
H ELEN!
WHAT F I LM OFF ICE
DID THE COM MERCIALS
ON THE BRADBU RY ACCOU NT?
THE N EGATIVES
ARE ALL SCRATCH ED,
THEY'RE SCREAMING
BLOODY M U RDER!
I'LL HAVE
TO CHECK, S I R.
MR. M ISRELL WANTS
TO SEE YOU.
I'LL HAVE TO
CHECK IT OUT.
MR. M ISRELL, S I R.
I'LL TELL YOU WH EN
I KNOW SOMETHING.
MR. WI LLIAMS!
MR. M ISRELL
SEEMED VERY INSISTENT.
[voices chattering
on phones]
MR. WILLIAMS!
MR. M ISRELL!
PUSH, PUSH, PUSH,
WILLIAMS!
PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH, WILLIAMS!
GET WITH IT, BOY!
PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH, WILLIAMS!
PUSH, PUSH, PUSH,
WILLIAMS!
PUSH, PUSH,
PUSH, WILLIAMS!
WILL YOU
GET ME WESTPORT,
CON N ECTICUT, PLEASE?
CAP ITAL 7-9899.
YES, PLEASE.
JAN I E, THIS
IS GART, HONEY.
I'M COMING HOM E.
WILL YOU STAY THERE?
I J UST--I J UST
WANT YOU TO
STAY THERE.
NO, HONEY,
LISTEN, PLEASE.
I'VE HAD IT, UNDERSTAND?
I'VE HAD IT!
I JUST CAN'T TAKE THIS
ANOTHER DAY, NOT
ANOTHER HOUR.
THIS IS IT, RIGHT NOW.
I'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
JAN I E, WILL YOU
H ELP ME, PLEASE?
WILL YOU
PLEASE H ELP ME?
[click]
JAN I E?
HOW ARE
YOU TONIGHT,
MR. WI LLIAMS?
[train horn blares]
(conductor)
STAMFORD NEXT STOP!
STAMFORD!
NEXT STOP, STAMFORD!
NEXT STOP STAMFORD!
STAMFORD NEXT STOP!
STAMFORD!
NEXT STOP, STAMFORD!
NEXT STOP--
... IS WI LLOUG H BY!
WI LLOUG H BY!
NEXT STOP
IS WILLOUGHBY!
WI LLOUG H BY?
YES, S I R.
[band playing Oh, Susannah]
HI, MR. WI LLIAMS.
HI, BOYS.
YOU CATCH SOME
B IG ONES TODAY, HUH?
I THINK TOMORROW
I'LL JOIN YOU.
PLENTY OF ROOM
AND LOTS OF F ISH.
[band playing
BeautifuI Dreamer]
[birds chirping]
H IYA, MR. WI LLIAMS.
WELCOM E.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU,
I'M GLAD TO BE HERE.
(man)
JUST J U M PED OFF
THE TRAI N, DID H E?
SHOUTED SOMETHING
ABOUT WI LLOUG H BY.
THEN RAN OUT
TO THE PLATFORM
AND THAT WAS THE
LAST I SAW OF HIM.
DOCTOR SAYS
HE MUST HAVE
DIED INSTANTLY.
THEY'RE GONNA TAKE HIM
INTO TOWN FOR AN AUTOPSY.
FU N ERAL PARLOR THERE
SENT THE AM BU LANCE.
POOR FELLAH.
(narrator)
WILLOUGHBY?
MAYBE IT'S WISHFUL THINKING
NESTLED IN A HIDDEN PART
OF A MAN'S M IND
OR MAYBE IT'S THE LAST STOP
IN THE VAST DESIGN OF THINGS.
OR PERHAPS, FOR A MAN
LIKE MR. GART WILLIAMS
WHO CLIMBED IN A WORLD
THAT WENT BY TOO FAST
IT'S A PLACE AROUND THE BEND
WHERE HE COULD JUMP OFF.
WILLOUGHBY?
WHATEVER IT IS, IT COMES
WITH SUNLIGHT AND SERENITY
AND IS A PART OF
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
IN THIS LI BRARY,
A CERTAIN PROFESSOR
SELLS THINGS.
O I NTM ENTS, SALVES, POWDERS,
SOVERE IG N REM EDI ES, N ECTARS,
CONCOCTIONS, DECOCTIONS,
AND POTIONS ALL GUARANTEED.
NEXT WEEK HE'LL
SELL ONE TO A LOVERBOY
SO THAT HE CAN SLI P
AN AFFECTIONATE M ICKEY
INTO THE CHAM PAG N E
OF HIS LADY LOVE.
IT SETS UP
A MOST B IZARRE
AND VERY U N EXPECTED
CHAIN OF EVENTS.
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE
NEXT WEEK,
THE CHASER.
[curtain music]
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH
STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE SAME STATIONS.