[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
MAPLE STREET, U.S.A.
LATE SUMMER.
A TREE-LINED LITTLE
WORLD OF FRONT-PORCH
GLIDERS, BARBECUES,
THE LAUGHTER OF CHILDREN,
AND THE BELL OF AN
ICE-CREAM VENDOR.
AT THE SOUND OF THE ROAR
AND THE FLASH OF LIGHT,
IT WILL BE PRECISELY
6:43 P.M. ON MAPLE STREET.
[strange whirring]
WHAT WAS THAT,
A METEOR?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
IT LOOKED LIKE.
I DIDN'T HEAR ANY
CRASH THOUGH, DID YOU?
NO, I DIDN'T
HEAR ANYTHING
EXCEPT A ROAR.
STEVE, WHAT WAS THAT?
I GU ESS IT WAS
A METEOR, HONEY. IT CAM E
AWFU L CLOSE, DIDN'T IT?
TOO CLOSE FOR MY MONEY.
MUCH TOO CLOSE.
(narrator)
THIS IS MAPLE STREET ON
A LATE SATURDAY AFTERNOON.
MAPLE STREET
IN THE LAST CALM
AND REFLECTIVE MOMENT
BEFORE THE MONSTERS CAME.
OPERATOR. OPERATOR!
OPERATOR!
STEVE, THE POWER'S OFF.
I HAD THE SOUP ON
THE STOVE
AND THE STOVE J UST
STOPPED WORKING.
IS YOUR PHON E
ALL RIGHT? I CAN'T
GET ANYBODY ON M IN E.
(man)
OUR ELECTRICITY ISN'T
GOOD. IS THE POWER OFF?
(woman)
OUR RADIO'S GONE DEAD.
I'LL CUT ACROSS
THE BACKYARD.
SEE IF THE POWER
IS STILL ON ON
FLORAL STREET.
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WHY SHOU LD THE POWER
GO OFF ALL OF A SU DDEN
AND THE PHONE LIN E?
MAYBE SOME KIND OF
AN ELECTRICAL STORM
OR SOMETHING.
NOW, THAT DON'T
SEEM LIKELY.
THE SKY'S AS BLU E
AS ANYTHING. NOT A CLOU D,
NO LIGHTNING, NO TH U N DER.
HOW COULD IT
BE A STORM?
CAN'T GET A THING
ON THE RADIO. NOT
EVEN ON THE PORTABLE.
WHY DON'T WE GO
DOWNTOWN AND CHECK
WITH THE POLICE?
THEY'LL PROBABLY
THINK WE'RE CRAZY
OR SOMETHING.
A LITTLE POWER FAI LU RE AND
EVERYBODY GETS FLUSTERED
AND EVERYTHING.
IT ISN'T JUST A POWER
FAILURE, CHARLIE.
IF IT WERE, WE'D STILL BE
ABLE TO GET A BROADCAST
ON THE PORTABLE.
I'LL TAKE A RU N DOWNTOWN.
MAYBE I CAN GET IT
STRAIG HTEN ED OUT.
[engine won't turn over]
I DON'T U N DERSTAND IT.
IT WAS WORKING F IN E BEFORE.
ARE YOU OUT OF GAS?
I JUST F I LLED IT UP.
WELL, WHAT
DOES IT MEAN?
IT'S AS I F
EVERYTHING STOPPED.
MAYBE WE'D BETTER
WALK DOWNTOWN.
WELL, LET'S BOTH
GO, CHARLIE.
YEAH.
MR. BRAN D,
YOU BETTER NOT.
WHY NOT?
THEY DON'T
WANT YOU TO.
WHO DOESN'T
WANT US TO?
TH EM.
TH EM?
WHO ARE THEM?
WHOEVER WAS IN THAT THING
THAT CAME BY OVERH EAD.
WHOEVER WAS IN THE THING
THAT CAME OVER. I DON'T THINK
THEY WANT US TO LEAVE HERE.
WHAT DO YOU
M EAN, TOM MY? WHAT
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THEY DON'T WANT US TO
LEAVE. THAT'S WHY THEY
SHUT EVERYTHING OFF.
WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
WHERE DID YOU GET
THAT IDEA?
ISN'T THAT THE
CRAZI EST THING
YOU'VE HEARD?
IT'S ALWAYS THAT WAY
IN EVERY STORY I'VE
EVER READ
ABOUT A SH I P LAN DING
FROM OUTER SPACE.
FROM OUTER SPACE, YET?
SAL, YOU BETTER TAKE HIM
U PSTAIRS, PUT HIM TO BED.
HE'S BEEN READING TOO MANY
COM IC BOOKS OR SEEING
TOO MANY MOVIES.
TOM MY, YOU STOP
THAT KIND OF TALK.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
GO AHEAD, TOM MY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
AND THEN YOU'LL SEE.
IT WASN'T A SH I P.
IT WAS A METEOR
OR SOMETHING.
LIKELY AS NOT, THAT'S THE CAUSE
OF THE POWER FAI LU RE AND
ALL THE REST OF IT.
M ETEORS CAN DO
CRAZY THINGS LIKE,
LIKE SU N SPOTS.
SURE THAT'S
THE KIND OF THING,
LIKE SU N SPOTS.
THEY RAISE CAI N
WITH RADIO RECEPTION
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
THIS THING BEING SO CLOSE,
THERE'S NO TELLING THE
SORT OF STUFF IT CAN DO.
YOU GO AHEAD, STEVE.
YOU AND CHARLIE
GO INTO TOWN,
SEE IF THAT ISN'T
WHAT'S CAUSING IT ALL.
MR. BRAN D?
MR. BRAN D, PLEASE
DON'T LEAVE HERE.
YOU M IGHT NOT EVEN
BE ABLE TO GET
TO TOWN.
IT WAS THAT
WAY IN THE STORY.
NOBODY COULD LEAVE.
NOBODY EXCEPT--
EXCEPT WHO?
EXCEPT THE PEOPLE
THEY'D SENT DOWN
AHEAD OF THEM.
THEY LOOKED JUST LIKE
HUMANS. AND IT WASN'T
U NTI L THE SH I P LAN DED THAT--
TOM MY, PLEASE, SON.
HONEY, DON'T TALK
LIKE THAT.
IT'S THE CRAZI EST THING I'VE
EVER HEARD OF. THE KI D TELLS
A COM IC BOOK PLOT
AND WE STAND
HERE LISTENING.
WAIT A MINUTE.
GO AHEAD, TOM MY.
WHAT KIND OF A
STORY WAS IT?
WHAT ABOUT THE PEOPLE
THEY SENT AHEAD?
THAT WAS THE WAY
THEY PREPARED THINGS
FOR THE LAN DING.
THEY SENT FOUR PEOPLE.
A MOTHER AND A FATH ER
AND TWO KIDS
WHO LOOKED J UST
LIKE HUMANS, BUT
THEY WEREN'T.
WELL, I GU ESS WHAT WE NEED
TO DO IS RU N A CHECK OF
THE N EIGH BORHOOD
AND F IN D OUT WHICH ONES
OF US ARE REALLY HUMAN.
THERE'S NO USE
STANDING AROUND MAKING
BUM JOKES ABOUT IT.
WON DER IF FLORAL STREET'S
GOT THE SAME KIND
OF DEAL WE HAVE.
WHERE'S PETE VAN HORN?
HAS HE COME BACK, YET?
[car trying to start]
(woman)
DOES YOUR CAR
START, LES?
NO DICE.
[tries again]
WELL, I DON'T
KNOW WHAT'S WRONG.
NOTHING SEEMS
TO BE WORKING.
CAN'T EVEN GET
THE CAR STARTED.
[car engine starts]
CAR STARTED SOMEHOW.
HE GOT H IS
CAR STARTED.
HOW COME HIS CAR J UST
U P AND STARTED
LIKE THAT?
ALL BY ITSELF.
HE WASN'T ANYWHERE
N EAR IT. IT J UST
STARTED BY ITSELF.
HE NEVER DID COME OUT
TO LOOK AT THAT THING
THAT FLEW OVERH EAD.
HE WASN'T
EVEN INTERESTED.
HE ALWAYS WAS
AN ODDBALL.
HIM AND HIS WHOLE
FAM I LY. REAL ODDBALL.
NOW, WHY DIDN'T
HE COME OUT WITH
THE REST OF US TO LOOK?
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO ASK HIM?
(Brand)
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE!
NOW, LET'S
NOT BE A MOB.
I JUST DON'T
U N DERSTAND IT.
I TRI ED TO START IT.
IT WOULDN'T START.
YOU SAW ME.
ALL OF YOU SAW ME.
[engine cuts out]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I SWEAR I J UST
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WELL, MAYBE YOU BETTER
TELL US. THERE'S NOTHING
WORKING ON THIS STREET.
NOTHING. NO LIGHTS,
NO POWER, NO RADIO.
NOTHING EXCEPT
ONE CAR. YOURS.
HOW DO YOU F IG U RE
IT STARTED, LES?
HOW DO YOU
EXPLAIN THAT?
WAIT A MINUTE, NOW.
JUST KEEP YOUR DISTANCE.
ALL OF YOU.
OKAY, SO I'VE GOT A CAR
THAT STARTS BY ITSELF.
WELL, IT'S A FREAK
THING, I ADM IT IT.
WHAT'S IT MAKE ME, A
CRI M I NAL OR SOMETHING?
I DON'T KNOW WHY IT
STARTS, IT JUST DOES.
WHAT'S THIS ALL
ABOUT, STEVE?
WE'RE ON A
MONSTER KICK, LES.
SEEMS THE GEN ERAL
I M PRESS ION NOW HOLDS
THAT MAYBE THERE'S A FAM I LY
THAT ISN'T WHAT
WE THINK THEY ARE.
MONSTERS FROM OUTER
SPACE OR SOMETHING
DIFFERENT THAN US.
F I FTH COLU M N ISTS
FROM THE VAST BEYON D.
NOW, DO YOU KNOW ANYBODY THAT
MIGHT F IT THAT DESCRI PTION
AROUND HERE ON MAPLE STREET?
THIS IS A GAG
OR SOMETHING?
WHAT IS THIS?
A PRACTICAL JOKE
OR SOMETHING?
[car engine starts]
THAT'S SU PPOSED
TO I NCRI M I NATE ME, HUH?
THE CAR STARTS
AND STOPS AND THAT
REALLY DOES IT, HUH?
REALLY DOES IT?
WELL, I DON'T U N DERSTAND IT
ANY MORE THAN ANY OF YOU DO.
LOOK, YOU ALL KNOW ME.
WE'VE LIVED HERE FOR FIVE
YEARS, RIGHT IN THIS HOUSE.
WE AREN'T ANY
DIFFERENT FROM YOU.
ANY DIFFERENT AT ALL.
THE WHOLE
THING IS J UST--
REALLY, THE WHOLE
THING IS JUST WE I RD.
WELL, IF THAT'S THE CASE,
LES GOODMAN, THEN EXPLAIN
WHY YOU--
EXPLAIN WHAT?
LET'S JUST FORGET IT.
WAIT A MINUTE.
LET HER TALK. GO
AHEAD, EXPLAIN WHAT?
WELL, SOMETIMES I
STAY UP LATE AT NIGHT
AND A COUPLE
OF TIMES--
WELL, A COUPLE OF TIMES
I'VE COME OUT ON MY PORCH
AND I'VE SEEN
LES GOODMAN HERE
IN THE WEE HOURS
OF THE MORNING
STANDING IN HIS YARD
JUST LOOKING UP
AT THE SKY.
THAT'S RIGHT. J UST,
JUST LOOKING UP
AT THE SKY
AS THOUGH HE
WERE WAITING
FOR SOMETHING.
AS THOUGH HE WERE
LOOKING FOR SOMETHING.
YOU KNOW, REALLY
THIS IS FOR LAUGHS.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M GU I LTY OF?
I'M GU I LTY
OF I NSOM N IA.
NOW, WHAT'S THE
PENALTY FOR THAT?
WELL, YOU HEARD
WHAT I SAID. I SAID
IT WAS I NSOM N IA.
I SAID IT WAS I NSOM N IA!
YOU SCARED, FRIGHTEN ED
RABB ITS, YOU.
YOU'RE S ICK PEOPLE,
DO YOU KNOW THAT?
ALL OF YOU.
AND YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE STARTING HERE
BECAUSE LET ME TELL YOU,
LET ME TELL YOU,
YOU'RE STARTING
SOMETHING HERE THAT--
THAT'S WHAT YOU SHOU LD
BE FRIGHTEN ED OF.
AS GOD IS MY WITN ESS,
YOU'RE LETTING SOMETHING
BEG IN HERE THAT'S--
THAT'S A NIGHTMARE.
IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM RIGHT
KEEPING A WATCH ON THEM.
THEY'RE OUR N EIGH BORS.
WE'VE KNOWN THE GOODMANS
EVER S I NCE THEY CAME HERE.
WE'VE BEEN GOOD FRIENDS.
LOOK, THAT DON'T
PROVE A THING.
ANY GUY WHO'D SPEND H IS
TIME LOOKING UP AT THE SKY
EARLY IN THE MORNING,
THERE'S SOMETHING
WRONG WITH THAT KIND
OF A PERSON.
SOMETHING THAT
AIN'T LEG ITI MATE.
U N DER NORMAL CI RCU MSTANCES
LET IT GO BY, BUT THESE
AREN'T NORMAL CI RCU MSTANCES.
LOOK AT THAT STREET.
NOTHING BUT CAN DLES.
IT'S LIKE GOING BACK
INTO THE DARK AG ES
OR SOMETHING.
STAY RIGHT WHERE
YOU ARE, STEVE. WE
DON'T WANT ANY TROUBLE.
BUT THIS TIME, ANYONE WHO SETS
FOOT ON MY PORCH, THAT'S WHAT
HE'S GONNA GET. TROU BLE.
LOOK, LES, I'M--
I'VE ALREADY
EXPLAIN ED TO YOU PEOPLE.
I DON'T SLEEP VERY WELL
AT NIGHT SOMETIMES,
SO I GET UP, I GO OUT,
I TAKE A WALK, I LOOK
U P AT THE SKY,
I LOOK AT THE STARS.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT HE DOES.
THIS WHOLE THING IS
SOME KIND OF MADN ESS.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
IT IS, MRS. GOODMAN.
SOME KIND OF MADN ESS.
(Charlie)
YOU BEST WATCH WHO
YOU'RE SEEN WITH, STEVE,
TILL WE GET THIS ALL
STRAIG HTEN ED OUT. YOU AIN'T
ABOVE SUSP ICION YOURSELF.
OR YOU, CHARLIE.
OR ANY OF US IT SEEMS
FROM AG E EIGHT ON UP.
WHAT I WANNA KNOW IS
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO.
JUST STAY AROUND
HERE ALL NIGHT?
THERE'S NOTHING
ELSE WE CAN DO.
ONE OF THEM'LL TI P
THEIR HAN D. THEY GOT TO.
THERE'S SOMETHING YOU CAN DO,
CHARLIE. YOU CAN GO I NSIDE
AND KEEP YOUR MOUTH SHUT.
YOU CAN QU IT S ITTING THERE
LIKE A SELF-APPO I NTED
HANGING J U DG E
AND JUST CLI M B INTO
BED AND FORGET IT.
YOU SOU N D PRETTY ANXIOUS
TO HAVE THAT
HAPPEN, STEVE.
I GU ESS WE OUGHTTA
KEEP AN EYE ON
YOU, TOO.
YEAH, I THINK MAYBE
EVERYTHING MIGHT AS
WELL COME OUT NOW.
YOUR WIFE'S BEEN DOING
A LITTLE TALKING, STEVE,
ABOUT SOME OF THE ODD
THINGS YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
YEAH?
WELL, GO AHEAD, DON.
TELL US WHAT SHE SAID.
GO AHEAD. WHAT'S
MY WIFE SAID? LET'S
GET IT ALL OUT.
LET'S PICK OUT
EVERY I DIOSYNCRASY
OF EVERY MAN,
WOMAN AND CH I LD
ON THIS WHOLE STREET.
AND THEN WE MIGHT AS WELL
SET UP SOME KIND OF A
KANGAROO COU RT.
NOW, HOW ABOUT A F I RING SQUAD
AT DAWN, CHARLIE, TO GET RI D
OF ALL THE SUSPECTS?
NARROW THEM DOWN FOR YOU.
MAKE IT EASIER. HUH?
RIGHT, DON?
WELL, THERE'S NO NEED
GETTING SO UPSET, STEVE.
IT'S JUST THAT--
MYRA'S TALKED ABOUT
HOW THERE'S BEEN
PLENTY OF NIGHTS
YOU SPENT HOURS DOWN
IN YOUR BASEM ENT
WORKING ON SOME KIND
OF RADIO OR SOMETHING.
WELL, NONE OF US
HAVE EVER SEEN
THAT RADIO.
GO AHEAD, STEVE.
WHAT KIND OF RADIO
SET YOU WORKING ON?
I NEVER SEEN IT.
NEITHER HAS ANYONE ELSE.
WHO TALKS TO YOU
ON THAT RADIO SET,
AND WHO DO YOU TALK TO?
WELL, I'M SURPRISED
AT YOU, CHARLIE.
HOW COME YOU'RE SO
DENSE ALL OF A SU DDEN?
WHO DO I TALK TO?
I TALK TO MONSTERS
FROM OUTER SPACE.
I TALK TO THREE-H EADED
G REEN MEN WHO FLY OVER HERE
IN WHAT LOOK LIKE METEORS.
PLEASE, STEVE, PLEASE.
IT'S JUST A-A HAM
RADIO SET, THAT'S ALL.
I BOUGHT THE BOOK
FOR HIM MYSELF.
IT'S JUST A
HAM RADIO SET.
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE THEM.
I'LL SHOW IT TO YOU. IT'S
DOWN IN THE BASEM ENT.
NO. NO, WE WON'T
SHOW THEM ANYTHING.
IF THEY WANNA LOOK I NSIDE
OUR HOUSE, LET THEM GET
A SEARCH WARRANT.
LOOK, BUDDY, YOU
CAN'T AFFORD TO--
CHARLIE, DON'T YOU TELL
ME WHAT I CAN AFFORD.
AND STOP TELLING ME
WHO'S DANG EROUS
AND WHO ISN'T,
AND WHO'S SAFE
AND WHO'S A MENACE.
AND YOU WITH HIM,
TOO, ALL OF YOU.
YOU'RE ALL STANDING
OUT HERE ALL SET TO
CRUCI FY SOMEBODY.
YOU'RE ALL SET
TO F IN D A SCAPEGOAT.
YOU'RE ALL DESPERATE
TO PO I NT SOME KIND OF
A FING ER AT A N EIGH BOR.
WELL, BELIEVE ME, FRIENDS,
THE ONLY THING THAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN
IS THAT WE'RE GON NA
EAT EACH OTHER UP ALIVE.
[footsteps approaching]
IT'S THE MONSTER.
HERE, WE MAY NEED THIS.
WHAT, A SHOTG U N? WI LL
SOMEBODY THINK? WHAT
GOOD IS A SHOTG U N?
NO MORE TALK, STEVE.
YOU'RE GONNA TALK US
RIGHT INTO A GRAVE.
YOU'D LET WHATEVER'S
OUT THERE WALK RIGHT
OVER US WITH YOU.
WELL, SOME OF US WON'T.
[gunshot]
[dog barking]
IT'S PETE VAN HORN.
PETE VAN HORN.
WELL, HE WAS JUST GOING OVER
TO THE NEXT BLOCK TO SEE I F
THE POWER WAS ON.
CHARLIE, YOU KI LLED HIM.
HE'S DEAD.
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHO HE WAS.
I MOST CERTAIN LY
DI DN'T KNOW WHO HE WAS.
WELL, HE CAME OUT
OF THE DARKN ESS.
HOW WAS I SU PPOSED
TO KNOW WHO HE WAS?
STEVE? YOU KNOW
WHY I SHOT HIM.
HOW WAS I SU PPOSED
TO KNOW HE WASN'T A
MONSTER OR SOMETHING?
I WAS ONLY TRYING
TO PROTECT MY HOM E.
I DIDN'T KNOW IT
WAS SOMEBODY WE KNEW.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
LOOK! CHARLIE?
CHARLIE, THE
LIGHTS JUST WENT
ON IN YOUR HOUSE.
WHY DID THE LIGHTS
GO ON IN YOUR HOUSE?
WHAT ABOUT IT, CHARLIE?
HOW COME YOU'RE THE ONLY
ONE WITH LIGHTS NOW?
THAT'S WHAT I'D LIKE
TO KNOW. YOU WERE SO
QU ICK TO KI LL, CHARLIE.
AND SO QUICK
TO TELL US WHO WE
HAD TO LOOK OUT FOR.
MAYBE YOU HAD TO KI LL.
MAYBE PETE WAS TRYING
TO TELL US SOMETHING.
MAYBE PETE LEARN ED
SOMETHING AND CAM E
BACK TO TELL US
WHO IT WAS AMONGST US
WE HAD TO LOOK OUT FOR.
NO, NO, IT'S
NOTHING OF THE SORT.
I DIDN'T KNOW
THE LIGHTS WERE ON.
I SWEAR I DIDN'T.
SOMEBODY'S PULLING
A GAG OR SOMETHING.
A GAG? A GAG? CHARLIE,
THERE'S A MAN LYING
DEAD IN THE STREET
AND YOU KI LLED HIM.
DOES THAT LOOK LIKE
A GAG TO YOU?
LOOK. LOOK, I SWEAR
IT ISN'T ME!
I SWEAR IT ISN'T!
I KNOW WHO IT IS!
I KNOW WHO
THE MONSTER IS!
I KNOW WHO IT IS THAT
DOESN'T BELONG AMONG US!
I SWEAR I KNOW
WHO IT IS!
ALL RIGHT, CHARLIE,
LET'S HEAR IT.
WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
COME ON,
CHARLIE, COME ON.
WHO IS IT,
CHARLIE? TELL US!
IT'S THE KI D!
IT'S TOM MY!
HE'S THE ONE!
WELL, THAT'S NOT TRU E.
IT ISN'T SO.
HE'S A LITTLE BOY.
IT WAS THIS KI D WHO KNEW
WHAT WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
HE WAS THE
ONE WHO KNEW.
HOW DID HE KNOW?
HOW COULD HE HAVE KNOWN?
(Man)
MAYBE TOMMY'S AN ALIEN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU PEOPLE?
NOW STOP!
(Woman)
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
[all yelling at once]
(man)
DON'T LET HIM
GET TO THE HOUSE.
(Woman)
YOU'RE RIGHT, IT'S HIM.
IT ISN'T THE KI D.
IT'S BOB WEAVER'S HOUSE.
IT ISN'T BOB WEAVER'S
PLACE. IT'S DON'S HOUSE.
IT'S THE WI LLIAMS' HOUSE.
IT'S THE KI D,
I TELL YOU.
IT'S CHARLIE,
HE'S THE ON E.
STOP!
[screaming]
IT'S STEVE!
STOP IT!
FOOLS!
[gunshots]
[screaming]
[glass breaking]
(man)
UNDERSTAND THE
PROCEDURE NOW?
JUST STOP A FEW
OF THEIR MACHINES
AND RADIOS
AND TELEPHONES
AND LAWN MOWERS.
THROW THEM INTO
DARKNESS FOR A
FEW HOURS
AND THEN S IT BACK
AND WATCH THE PATTERN.
AND THIS PATTERN IS
ALWAYS THE SAME?
WITH FEW VARIATIONS.
THEY PICK THE MOST
DANG EROUS EN EMY
THEY CAN F IN D,
AND IT'S THEMSELVES.
ALL WE NEED DO IS
S IT BACK AND WATCH.
THEN I TAKE IT THIS PLACE,
THIS MAPLE STREET
IS NOT U N IQU E.
BY NO MEANS.
THEIR WORLD IS FU LL
OF MAPLE STREETS
AND WE'LL GO FROM ONE
TO THE OTHER AND LET
TH EM DESTROY THEMSELVES.
ONE TO THE OTH ER.
(narrator)
THE TOOLS OF CONQUEST
DO NOT NECESSARILY COME
WITH BOMBS
AND EXPLOSIONS
AND FALLOUT.
THERE ARE WEAPONS THAT
ARE SIMPLY THOUGHTS,
ATTITUDES, PREJUDICES,
TO BE FOUND ONLY
IN THE M INDS OF MEN.
FOR THE RECORD,
PREJUDICES CAN KILL
AND SUSPICION
CAN DESTROY.
AND A THOUGHTLESS,
FRIGHTENED SEARCH
FOR A SCAPEGOAT
HAS A FALLOUT
ALL OF ITS OWN
FOR THE CHILDREN AND
THE CHILDREN YET UNBORN.
AND THE PITY OF IT IS
THAT THESE THINGS
CANNOT BE CONFINED
TO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK MR. RICHARD MATH ESON
LEN DS US HIS F IN E
WRITING TALENTS
WHEN WE BRING YOU A U N IQU E
AND MOST ARRESTING STORY
OF A MOVIE ACTOR
WHO F IN DS HIMSELF ON THAT TH IN
LINE BETWEEN WHAT IS REAL
AND WHAT IS A DREAM.
MR. HOWARD DU FF STARS
IN WORLD OF DIFFERENCE,
WHICH I THINK YOU'LL DISCOVER
IS A TELEVIS ION PLAY OF
DIFFERENCE, TOO.
THAT'S NEXT WEEK.
A JOU RN EY INTO THE
TWILIGHT ZONE.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
(male presenter)
BE SURE TO SEE
THE FUN-FILLED
FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS,
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE STATIONS.
THE TWILIGHT ZONE IS
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY THE NEWEST COFFEE
SENSATION ON THE
MODERN SCENE.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA COFFEE.
(man)
N.
(woman)
E.
W.
S.
(both chanting)
N-E-W-S. WE'VE
GOT NEWS FOR YOU.
(man chanting)
THERE'S A GREAT NEW
COFFEE WAITING FOR YOU.
? BRAND NEW SANKA ?
THE FLAVOR'S RICH.
AROMA, TOO.
? AROMA-ROAST SANKA ?
RICH NEW AROMA. OH!
RICH NEW FLAVOR. AH!
? SIP SERENE
THERE'S NO CAFFEINE ?
THE ONLY COFFEE ON
THE MODERN SCENE
THAT GETS THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
? AROMA FLAVOR ?
BUT NOT CAFFEINE.
? RICH NEW
AROMA-ROAST SANKA ?
THE COFFEE THE MODERN
WORLD DESERVES.
THE COFFEE THAT CAN'T
GET ON YOUR NERVES.
? GLORY BE
IT'S CAFFEINE FREE ?
THE PERFECT COFFEE
FOR MODERN LIVING.
DRINK ALL YOU WANT
WITHOUT M ISGIVING.
? RICH NEW
AROMA-ROAST SANKA ?
AROMA, FLAVOR. STILL
97% CAFFEINE FREE.
WILL WONDERS
NEVER CEASE?
? SANKA ?
AND THE PERFECT COFFEE
ON THE MODERN SCENE.
BRAND NEW
AROMA-ROAST SANKA.
GIVES YOU ALL THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
THE BEST AROMA,
THE BEST FLAVOR,
AND BEST OF ALL
NO CAFFEINE.
YES, THE HONEST-TO-GOODNESS
AROMA, THE FULL-TIME
HARDY FLAVOR.
ALL THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
AND GREATEST OF ALL,
YOU CAN DRINK
ALL YOU WANT.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA IS STILL 97%
CAFFEINE FREE.
SANKA COFFEE,
AROMA, FLAVOR,
BUT NOT CAFFEINE.
GO AHEAD,
INDULGE YOURSELF.