[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
1 2:00 NOON.
AN ORDINARY SCENE,
AN ORDINARY CITY.
LUNCHTIME FOR THOUSANDS
OF ORDINARY PEOPLE.
TO MOST OF THEM,
THIS HOUR WOULD BE A REST.
A PLEASANT BREAK
IN THE DAY'S ROUTINE.
TO MOST, BUT NOT ALL.
TO EDWARD HALL,
TIME IS AN ENEMY.
AND THE HOUR TO COME
IS A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
HEY, MISTER.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
ARE YOU SICK?
NO.
WE'VE BEEN
EXPECTING YOU, MR. HALL.
GO RIGHT IN.
HELLO, MR. HALL.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
ARE YOU ILL?
NO.
I'M JUST TIRED.
WELL, YOU'D
BETTER REST.
OVER HERE, MR. HALL.
SIT DOWN.
I THOUGHT
YOU SAID
YOU WERE TIRED.
I AM. I'M
THE TIREDEST
MAN IN THE WORLD.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
HOW MANY HOURS
I'VE BEEN AWAKE?
87 HOURS.
ALMOST FOUR
DAYS AND NIGHTS.
AND YOU CAN'T
GO TO SLEEP,
IS THAT IT?
NO, DOCTOR.
NOT CAN'T,
I MUSTN'T!
I MUSTN'T GO TO SLEEP
BECAUSE IF I DO I'LL
NEVER WAKE UP.
THANKS.
MM-HM.
YOU M IND IF I
WALK AROUND A BIT?
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
I CAN STAY AWAKE.
STAND ON YOUR HEAD
IF YOU THINK IT WILL HELP.
WHAT'S FUNNY?
YOU ARE.
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE
A PSYCHIATRIST?
WHY DO YOU ASK?
I EXPECTED
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
LIKE AN OLD MAN
WITH A WHITE BEARD
AND A GERMAN ACCENT?
MAYBE.
I KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT
EVERYBODY EXPECTS,
AND THEY'RE
ALWAYS DISAPPOINTED.
YOU KNOW,
I'VE OFTEN THOUGHT
OF WEARING A DISGUISE.
YEAH, NOW,
FEEL MORE COMFORTABLE?
LOOK, DOCTOR.
YOU CAN'T HELP ME.
I'M JUST
WASTING YOUR TIME.
YOU'RE SURE
OF THAT?
YEAH.
THEN WHY'D YOU
COME TO ME?
IT WAS FRED
JACKSON'S IDEA,
MY REGULAR DOCTOR.
I KNOW,
HE CALLED ME.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
NOT MUCH.
YOUR NAME,
EDWARD HALL.
AGE, 35,
OCCUPATION, DRAFTSMAN.
SINGLE, HEART
CONDITION, NO HISTORY
OF MENTAL DISEASES.
THAT'S IT.
ARE YOU GOING
TO TELL ME THE REST?
[sighs]
NO. NO, FORGET IT.
OKAY.
MR. HALL.
DO YOUREALLY THINK
RUNNING AWAY
WILL DO YOU ANY GOOD?
NOW DON'T
GET ME WRONG.
SOMETIMES RUNNING AWAY
IS THE BEST ANSWER.
BUT I DON'T KNOW
THAT YOURS IS THAT
SORT OF PROBLEM.
MAYBE IT IS,
MAYBE IT ISN'T.
YOU DO WHAT YOU LIKE.
YOU PROMISE
YOU WON'T PUT ME
IN A STRAITJACKET?
I DON'T PROMISE ANYTHING.
OKAY.
OKAY. IT DOESN'T
MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE.
[sighs]
CAN I OPEN THIS?
QUITE A DROP.
UH, MR. HALL,
I'LL, UH--
I'LL HAVE TO CLOSE
THE WINDOW.
I ONLY
WANTED SOME AIR.
WELL, I'LL, UH,
TURN THE CONDITIONER UP.
IT WORKS BEST
WITH THE WINDOWS CLOSED.
DID YOU THINK
I'D JUMP?
YOU M IGHT HAVE.
NOT A CHANCE.
I WANT TO LIVE.
THAT'S MY PROBLEM.
OH?
ALL RIGHT, MR. HALL,
SUPPOSE YOU TELL ME
ALL ABOUT IT. EVERYTHING.
START ANYWHERE.
OKAY, BUT I'M
WARNING YOU
YOU'RE GONNA THINK
I LOST MY MARBLES.
NO. MARBLES
CAN BE FOUND, MR. HALL.
GO ON.
DID YOU EVER LOOK
AT THIS PICTURE?
I MEAN,
REALLY LOOK AT IT?
(Doctor)
I THINK SO, WHY?
HAS IT EVER MOVED?
NO.
NOT TO MY KNOWLEDGE, ANYWAY.
I CAN MAKE IT MOVE.
CAN YOU?
YES.
BUT NOT REALLY.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
WE HAD A PICTURE LIKE
THIS IN OUR HOUSE.
NOT THE SAME THING EXACTLY,
BUT PRETTY CLOSE.
A BOAT.
(Hall)
MY MOTHER
USED TO TELL ME
TO LOOK AT IT.
SHE SAID IF
I LOOKED AT IT
LONG ENOUGH IT WOULD MOVE.
ALL I HAD TO DO
WAS KEEP LOOKING AT IT.
I DIDN'T BELIEVE HER,
BUT THE IDEA FASCINATED ME.
ONE NIGHT I SPENT
A WHOLE HOUR JUST
STARING AT THAT SILLY BOAT.
AND DID IT MOVE?
YES.
NOW, YOU UNDERSTAND,
THERE'S NOTHING
STRANGE ABOUT THAT.
IT WAS AN OPTICAL ILLUSION.
YEAH, I KNOW.
EXCEPT THAT AFTER A WHILE,
I COULDN'T CONTROL IT.
EVERY TIME
I LOOKED AT THAT BOAT,
THE SAILS WOULD FILL,
AND THEY WOULD BEGIN TO DIP.
I JUST COULDN'T STOP IT.
IMAGINATION IS STRONG
IN A GROWING BOY.
YEAH, I REALIZE THAT.
I REALIZED IT
EVEN THEN.
BUT THE POINT IS,
I GOT JUST
AS SCARED AS IF IT
WERE REALLY HAPPENING.
THE M IND IS EVERYTHING.
IF YOU THINK YOU'VE
GOT A PAIN
IN YOUR ARM,
AND THERE'S NO
PHYSICAL REASON FOR IT,
IT HURTS
JUST THE SAME,
DOESN'T IT?
GRANTED.
IS THAT HOW YOU MANAGE
TO STAY AWAKE?
HOW ELSE?
HOW MANY GRAINS A DAY?
I DON'T KNOW.
I HAVEN'T GOT
MUCH LONGER ANYWAY.
YOU WANT TO HEAR
THE REST OR NOT?
YES.
WHEN I WAS 1 5,
I DEVELOPED
A RHEUMATIC HEART.
THEY SAID I'D NEVER
REALLY GET WELL.
THAT I'D HAVE
TO TAKE IT EASY.
NO STRENUOUS EXERCISE.
NO LONG WALKS,
NO STAIRS, NO SHOCKS.
AVOID ANY KIND
OF SHOCK, THEY SAID.
THEY FORGOT
ABOUT MY IMAGINATION.
THREE YEARS AGO,
A WOMAN WAS KILLED BY A MAN
WHO WAS HIDDEN
IN THE BACKSEAT OF HER CAR.
YOU MAY HAVE
READ ABOUT IT. I DID.
ANYWAY, IT STARTED
ME THINKING.
MAYBE SOMEBODY WAS HIDING
IN THE BACKSEAT OF MY CAR.
MAYBE ONE NIGHT DRIVING
OVER LAUREL CANYON,
I'D LOOK UP IN
THE REAR-VIEW M IRROR.
AND I'D SEE SOMEBODY
OR SOMETHING
COMING UP
OUT OF THE DARKNESS.
I HAD TO DRIVE
THE CANYON TWICE A DAY.
IT'S A ROUGH ROAD.
ONE SLIP
AND YOU'RE OVER THE EDGE.
ONE NIGHT,
LIKE EVERY OTHER NIGHT,
I HEADED FOR HOME.
SUDDENLY, I
FELT UNCOMFORTABLE,
AS IF I WEREN'T ALONE
IN THE CAR.
IT WAS RIDICULOUS,
BUT I COULDN'T SHAKE
THE SENSATION.
I KEPT THINKING
THERE'S SOMEBODY BACK THERE.
I'LL LOOK
IN THE REAR-VIEW MIRROR
AND I'LL SEE HIS FACE.
THEN I'LL SEE
HIS HANDS REACHING UP,
HERE'S THE IMPORTANT
THING, DOCTOR.
I KNEW INTELLECTUALLY
THAT I WAS ALONE.
BUT I ALSO KNEW
THAT MY IMAGINATION
WOULD MAKE ME
SEE SOMETHING IF I
THOUGHT ABOUT IT LONG ENOUGH.
[eerie music]
[honking horn]
[brakes screech]
OF COURSE, THERE WASN'T
ANYONE ELSE IN THE CAR.
IT WAS ALL IN MY M IND.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DID THAT MAKE?
I CRASHED ANYWAY.
I WAS LUCKY.
THE SHOCK SHOULD
HAVE KILLED ME.
I COULDN'T
SURVIVE ANOTHER ONE,
THE DOCTOR SAID.
I COULD BE SURE
OF THAT.
AND HAS THERE
BEEN ANOTHER ONE?
NO.
BUT THERE WILL BE,
JUST AS SOON AS
I FALL ASLEEP.
THE GIRL WILL BE
IN THIS DREAM AGAIN.
AND IT'LL BE THE LAST SHOCK.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
I USED TO DREAM
IN SEQUENCE.
REMEMBER
THE ADVENTURE SERIALS
THEY USED TO HAVE
IN MOVIE THEATERS?
IT WAS LIKE THAT.
EVERY DREAM
WAS A CHAPTER.
I'D ALWAYS REMEMBER
BECAUSE WHEN I WOKE UP,
I'D WRITE DOWN
WHAT HAPPENED.
IT'S CRAZY, HUH?
NOT NECESSARILY.
IT COULD SIMPLY
BE THAT THE DREAMS
CONFORMED TO THE NOTES,
NOT THE OTHER WAY AROUND.
THEN YOU DON'T
THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
TO DREAM IN EPISODES?
I DON'T SAY IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IT ISN'T. BELIEVE ME.
FOR A LONG TIME,
I DIDN'T DREAM AT ALL.
THEN A WEEK AGO,
IT STARTED.
I WENT TO BED
AT AROUND 1 1 :30.
I WASN'T TOO TIRED,
BUT I NEEDED THE REST
BECAUSE OF MY HEART.
I DON'T KNOW
WHEN I FELL ASLEEP,
BUT ALL OF A SUDDEN,
I WASN'T AT HOME ANYMORE.
I WAS AT
AN AMUSEMENT PARK.
[merry-go-round
music pIaying]
[maniacal laughter]
(Hall)
IT WAS THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU SEE ONLY IN NIGHTMARES,
EVERYTHING WARPED
AND TWISTED OUT OF SHAPE,
BUT IT WAS REAL, TOO.
VERY REAL.
(Barker)
HURRY, HURRY, HURRY,
THIS IS WHERE YOU GET
THOSE BIG PRIZES.
SIX SHOTS
FOR A DIME.
HIT THE BULL'S-EYE
AND YOU GET A KEWPIE DOLL.
HOW ABOUT IT?
COME ON.
TEN CENTS.
TEN PENNIES.
(Barker 2)
HURRY HURRY,
HURRY, FRIENDS,
THE SHOW
IS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
SEE HER DANCE.
SEE HER WIGGLE.
THE MOST SENSATIONAL
AND ELECTRIFYING EXHIBITION
SINCE LITTLE EGYPT.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BE ABLE TO SEE ANYTHING
STANDING OUT THERE.
YOU'VE GOTTA GET
DOWN CLOSER.
RIGHT DOWN CLOSE.
THAT'S IT, NOT TOO CLOSE.
LET'S NOT
TRAMPLE EACH OTHER.
NOW, YOU SAY
YOU WANT FAT
ONES? WE GOT 'EM.
YOU SAY
YOU WANT THIN ONES?
WE'VE GOT THEM.
BLONDS, BRUNETTES,
REDHEADS, AND BELIEVE
ME, FOLKS,
IF THEY AIN'T UP HERE,
THEY AIN'T WORTH
LOOKING AT.
AND NOW, TO GIVE YOU
A LITTLE DEMONSTRATION
OF WHAT YOU'RE GOING
TO SEE ON THE INSIDE,
MAYA, THE CAT GIRL!
COME ON, BABY.
WE KNOW YOU'RE MODEST,
BUT WHY SHOULD
THE FOLKS OUT THERE
TAKE MY WORD FOR IT?
[sIow percussion music]
[maniacaI Iaughter]
(Hall)
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHO THE GIRL WAS.
I'D NEVER SEEN HER BEFORE.
BUT AS MUCH
AS I WAS DRAWN TO HER,
I KNEW I HAD
TO GET AWAY FROM HER.
THERE WAS SOMETHING
ABOUT HER EYES.
SOMETHING DEEP
INSIDE THOSE DARK CAT'S EYES.
MAYA.
WHY DID
YOU DO THAT?
WHY DID I DO WHAT?
RUN AWAY.
I FELT LIKE IT.
YOU DIDN'T FIND ME
NICE TO LOOK AT?
YEAH, MAYBE TOO NICE.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE BACK THERE
ENTERTAINING THE CUSTOMERS?
I'M FREE.
FOR THE NIGHT.
ARE YOU ALONE?
YES.
THEN COME WITH ME.
YOU WANT TO.
DON'T YOU, EDWARD?
HOW DO YOU KNOW MY NAME?
OH, I KNOW
A LOT OF THINGS. I'M MAYA.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
I'M NOT.
THEN COME.
YOU ARE AFRAID.
ONLY BECAUSE THIS
ISN'T HAPPENING.
THIS IS A DREAM.
I'M NOT HERE,
I'M AT HOME, ASLEEP
AND YOU'RE PART
OF THAT DREAM.
I KNOW THAT.
YOU DO?
OF COURSE.
COME.
[eerie music]
TAKE ME
IN THERE, EDWARD.
IT'S DARK INSIDE.
SOFT AND COOL
AND DARK.
PLEASE?
HOW CAN I ARGUE
WITH A DREAM?
[eerie music
and maniacal laughter]
WE'VE BEEN EXPECTING
YOU, MR. HALL.
WHAT?
YOU CAN
KISS ME NOW.
WHAT IF
I DON'T WANT TO?
OH, YOU WANT TO.
LOOK, WHO'S DREAM
IS THIS, ANYWAY?
[screaming in terror]
[maniacaI Iaughter]
(Hall)
THAT'S WHEN I KNEW
SHE WAS TRYING TO KILL ME.
AND YOU WOKE UP THEN?
YES.
MY HEART
WAS BEATING FAST.
I HAD TO LIE STILL
FOR AN HOUR WAITING
FOR IT TO SETTLE DOWN.
THE DOCTOR SAID
I ALMOST HAD IT.
TELL ME, DO YOU KNOW
WHO THE GIRL WAS?
NO IDEA.
SHE LOOKED FAM ILIAR,
BUT I KNOW I'VE NEVER
SEEN HER BEFORE,
EXCEPT MAYBE
ON THE STREET OR SOMETHING.
BUT YOU'RE SURE
SHE WANTED TO KILL YOU?
YEAH.
GO ON.
THE NEXT NIGHT
I PUT OFF GOING
TO SLEEP UNTIL 1 :00.
BUT IT DIDN'T MATTER.
THE DREAM WAS OUT OF CONTROL.
I WAS BACK
IN THE AMUSEMENT PARK.
[panting]
I WAS RUNNING.
(Maya)
EDWARD.
EDWARD!
GET AWAY FROM ME.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF, EDWARD.
IT'S ONLY A DREAM.
I'VE GOT
A HEART CONDITION.
I CAN'T STAND
ALL THIS EXCITEMENT.
THAT'S SILLY.
THERE ISN'T
ANY EXCITEMENT.
YOU SAID SO YOURSELF.
YOU'RE AT HOME,
ASLEEP IN BED.
NOW YOU CAN DO ALL
THE THINGS YOU CAN'T
DO WHEN YOU'RE AWAKE.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THE DOCTOR SAID--
LOOK EDWARD,
[rattIing]
[peopIe shouting excitedIy]
LOOK, EDWARD, LOOK.
[roller coaster rattling]
COME ON,
EDWARD, IT'S FUN!
COME ON.
(Hall, off)
I DIDN'T WANT TO GO
ANYWHERE NEAR THAT
ROLLER COASTER,
BUT I COULDN'T HELP MYSELF
I HAD TO FOLLOW HER,
EVEN THOUGH
I KNEW EXACTLY
WHAT IT WOULD MEAN,
I HAD TO FOLLOW HER.
[Iaughing]
HOLD ON, EDWARD.
[eerie music]
STOP IT! STOP IT!
THEY CAN'T. IT'S TOO LATE.
I'VE GOT TO GET OFF!
JUMP, EDWARD, JUMP!
(Maya)
(Doctor)
AND IS THAT IT?
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
IF I GO TO SLEEP
I'LL GO RIGHT BACK
TO THE ROLLER COASTER.
MAYA WILL REACH ME.
SHE'LL PUSH ME.
AND THAT'LL BE
THE END OF ME.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
IF I STAY AWAKE
ANY LONGER,
THE STRAIN WILL BE
TOO MUCH FOR MY HEART.
AND THAT'LL BE THE END OF ME.
HEADS, YOU WIN.
TAILS, I LOSE.
IT'S QUITE A CHOICE,
HUH, DOCTOR?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
OUT, TO GET
SOME FRESH AIR.
I WOULDN'T ADVISE IT.
WHAT DO YOU ADVISE?
A STRAITJACKET?
SO LONG, DOC.
YOU CAN'T DO
ANYTHING MORE FOR ME.
MAYA!
WHAT'S THE MATTER, HALL?
IT'S HER.
MY RECEPTIONIST?
I'M SORRY,
BUT HER NAME DOESN'T
HAPPEN TO BE MAYA.
[disturbing music]
[screaming]
MISS THOMAS?
YES, DOCTOR?
WOULD YOU COME
HERE, PLEASE?
I'M AFRAID HE'S DEAD.
BUT HE CAME IN
JUST A M INUTE AGO.
I KNOW.
WHEN HE CAME IN,
I TOLD HIM TO SIT
DOWN AND HE DID.
IN LESS THAN
TWO SECONDS
HE WAS ASLEEP.
AND THEN
HE GAVE THAT
SCREAM YOU HEARD.
HEART ATTACK?
PROBABLY.
WELL, I GUESS
THERE ARE WORSE
WAYS TO GO.
AT LEAST
HE DIED PEACEFULLY.
(male presenter, off)
THEY SAY A DREAM TAKES
ONLY A SECOND OR SO,
YET IN THAT SECOND,
A MAN CAN LIVE A LIFETIME.
HE CAN SUFFER ANDIE,
AND WHO'S TO SAY
WHICHIS THE GREATER REALITY?
THE ONE WE KNOW
OR THE ONE IN DREAMS?
BETWEEN HEAVEN,
THE SKY, THE EARTH,
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU
ABOUT NEXT WEEK'S STORY.
AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
(male presenter, off)
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
ONCE UPON A TIME,
THERE WAS A SHIP SAILING
FROM LIVERPOOL, ENGLAND
TO NEW YORK.
IT NEVER GOT THERE
AND ONE MAN ON BOARD
KNEW WHY.
NEXT WEEK WE TELL
THIS MAN'S STORY.
THE DISTINGUISHED ACTOR
NEHEM IAH PERSOFF
PLAYS THE ROLE
OF CARL LANSER,
A HAUNTED MAN
IN A HAUNTING STORY
CALLED "JUDGMENT NIGHT."
THIS SHIP SAILS
NEXT WEEK AND WE HOPE
YOU'LL SEE IT OFF.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
(male presenter, off)
BE SURE TO SEE
THE FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS
THE DANNY THOMAS SHOW,
MONDAY NIGHTS OVER MOST
OF THESE STATIONS.
(male presenter, off)
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
BROUGHT TO YOU
OASIS FILTERED CIGARETTES.
THE TOBACCO IS SOOTHED
WITH THE SOFTEST TASTE OF ALL
AND MENTHOL MISTING
MAKES IT SO.
THIS IS AN OASIS.
COOL. REFRESHING.
THIS IS AN OASIS, TOO.
JUST AS THE MIST
OF MORNING DEW
REFRESHES A FLOWER
AND KEEPS IT FRESH ALL DAY,
SO DOES THE TOBACCO OASIS
IS MISTED, GENTLY MISTED
ALL OVER WITH MENTHOL.
THE TOBACCO IS SOOTHED
FOR THE SOFTEST TASTE OF ALL
AND MENTHOL MISTING
MAKES IT SO.
THAT'S OASIS,
THE ONLY FILTERED CIGARETTE
THAT'S OASIS COOL,
OASIS MILD,
OASIS FRESH.
(jingle)
? TRYING OASIS, TRYING OASIS
MOST REFRESHING CIGARETTE
(male presenter, off)
THE TWILIGHT ZONE,
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY THE COFFEE
WITH THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN
AROMA, FLAVOR,
BUT NOT CAFFEINE.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA COFFEE.
[soft music]
(male presenter, off)
AND THE PERFECT
COFFEE ON THE MODERN SCENE
BRAND NEW
AROMA-ROAST SANKA
GIVES YOU ALL THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
THE TRUEST AROMA,
THE FINEST FLAVOR,
AND NO CAFFEINE.
YES, THE TRUEST AROMA,
THE FINEST FLAVOR,
SO GREAT,
SO WONDERFULLY RICH,
AND BEST OF ALL,
YOU CAN DRINK AS MANY
CUPS AS YOU WANT.
INDULGE YOURSELF,
IT'S SO GOOD,
AND SANKA IS STILL
97 PER CENT CAFFEINE FREE.
SANKA COFFEE.
AROMA, FLAVOR
AND NO CAFFEINE.
HOW DO THEY DO IT?