[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS
THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
HER NAME: X-20.
HER TYPE: AN
EXPERIMENTAL INTERCEPTOR.
RECENT HISTORY: A
CRASH LANDING IN
THE MOHAVE DESERT
AFTER A 31 -HOUR FLIGHT
900 MILES INTO SPACE.
INCIDENTAL DATA: THE SHIP,
WITH THE MEN WHO FLEW HER
DISAPPEARED FROM
THE RADAR SCREEN
FOR 24 HOURS.
WELL, HELLO, COLONEL.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
I'M FINE, LIEUTENANT.
I'M... I'M FINE.
UM... IS
MAJOR GART HERE?
WELL, OF COURSE.
HE'S HERE.
OF COURSE.
GO ON IN.
HE'LL BE GLAD
TO SEE YOU.
THANK YOU.
ISN'T THAT ONE OF
THE SPACE PILOTS--
THE ONES
THAT CRASHED?
YEAH, THAT'S
COLONEL FORBES.
(male presenter, off)
BUT THE SHROUDS
THAT COVER MYSTERIES
ARE NOT ALWAYS MADE
OUT OF A TARPAULIN
AS THIS MAN WILL
SOON FIND OUT
ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF A HOSPITAL DOOR.
(Gart)
WELL, THE PRODIGAL
COLONEL! WELCOME.
HEY, HOW ABOUT A SHOT
OF STRAIGHT ORANGEADE?
HOW ARE
YOU FEELING?
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
ONE MORE THERMOMETER
IN MY PUSS,
I'M GONNA
ABSENT MYSELF
WITHOUT LEAVE.
COME ON, WHAT'S
IT LIKE IN THE
OUTSIDE WORLD?
YEAH, IT'S FINE.
WELL, TELL ME
ABOUT IT.
TALK TO ANY
OF THE GUYS?
WELL, WHAT ABOUT
THE SHIP, CLEGG?
DID YOU
CHECK HER OVER?
IT'S FINE,
THE SHIP'S FINE.
NO, NO, THEY PUT
IT UNDER WRAPS.
HEY, YOU GOT
OFF ON A TOOT,
DIDN'T YOU?
YOU DON'T
LOOK SO GOOD.
HOW DO I LOOK?
A LITTLE HUNG
OVER MAYBE.
[chuckling]
OH, YOU
GOT ANOTHER
ONE OF THOSE?
HEY, STEADY,
COLONEL, STEADY.
BILL, SOMETHING
HAS HAPPENED.
S-S-SOMETHING I
JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WELL, GO ON.
FIRST, I WANT
TO GET ORIENTED.
I WANT YOU TO ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS,
ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
WHEN DID
I LEAVE HERE?
WELL, DON'T
YOU KNOW?
LOOK, I DON'T
KNOW ANYTHING ANYMORE!
LOOK, ALL I NEED...ALL
I NEED IS SOMEBODY'S
HELP, ALL RIGHT?
LOOK, AT 9:30
YESTERDAY MORNING,
I WALKED OUT OF
HERE, DIDN'T I?
YEAH, ABOUT THAT
TIME, I GUESS.
WHO DID I
WALK OUT WITH?
NOBODY WAS
WITH YOU.
THAT'S WHAT I MEAN.
YOU SAY NOBODY!
WHAT'S THAT SAY?
GO AHEAD, TELL ME,
WHAT'S IT SAY?
WELL, IN
EFFECT, IT SAYS
THOSE TWO INTREPID
VOYAGERS INTO
THE UNKNOWN
RETURNED FROM THE
UNKNOWN IN A SLIGHTLY
DENTED AIRCRAFT.
WHAT ABOUT
THE PICTURE?
WHO'S IN
(Gart, reading)
"COLONEL CLEGG FORBES
AND MAJOR WILLIAM GART
"TAKEN JUST BEFORE
THEIR HISTORIC FLIGHT
THAT ENDED IN A MYSTERIOUS
DISAPPEARANCE AND CRASH."
THAT'S WHAT
YOUREMEMBER, HUH?
YOU AND ME AND
THE X-20 TAKING OFF.
ABOUT FOUR HOURS UP
WE BLACK OUT
AND 24 HOURS LATER,
WE END UP IN A CRASHED
AIRCRAFT IN THE DESERT.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE WE'VE
BEEN OR WHAT'S HAPPENED.
IS THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, NOW, WHAT'S THE
MATTER? ISN'T
THAT RIGHT?
BILL--
THERE WERE THREE OF US
IN THAT AIRCRAFT--
YOU AND ME
AND A COLONEL
NAMED HARRINGTON.
OH, YEAH, HARRINGTON.
ED HARRINGTON!
NOW, LOOK,
HE WAS 36 YEARS OLD.
HE WAS MY BEST FRIEND.
I'D KNOWN HIM
FOR 1 5 YEARS
AND YOU'D KNOWN
HIM FOR FIVE.
THAT SHIP TOOK
A CREW OF THREE,
AND WE WERE THE THREE.
AND THERE
WERE THREE OF US
WHEN THEY BROUGHT US
TO THE HOSPITAL AFTER
PICKING US UP IN
THE DESERT--
YOU AND ME
AND HARRINGTON.
HARRINGTON AND I
WERE JUST SCRATCHED;
YOU WERE THE ONE
WITH THE BUSTED LEG!
YESTERDAY MORNING, THEY
DISCHARGED HARRINGTON
AND ME.
THERE WERE
THREE BEDS
IN THIS ROOM--
YOURS AND M INE
AND HARRINGTON'S.
CLEGG...
I DON'T
KNOW ANYBODY
NAMED HARRINGTON.
HE WASN'T ON
THE CREW
WITH US.
THE X-20
CARRIED TWO
MEN, YOU AND ME--
NOBODY NAMED HARRINGTON,
NOBODY ELSE AT ALL.
WHEN YOU
WALKED OUT OF HERE
YESTERDAY MORNING,
YOU WALKED
OUT ALONE.
THERE'S NEVER BEEN
THREE BEDS IN THIS
ROOM, ONLY TWO.
YOURS...
AND M INE.
I THINK YOU BETTER
BE LOOKED AFTER.
PLEASE.
I KNEW YOU'D
SAY THAT, BILL,
AND I DON'T BLAME YOU
FOR SAYING IT EITHER.
BUT... BUT...
LET... LET ME...
LET ME
DESCRIBE TO YOU
WHAT I REMEMBER.
LOOK, I'LL GIVE
YOU A BREAKDOWN
CHRONOLOGICALLY
OF EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED AS
OF YESTERDAY MORNING.
BILL...
YOU SAID
GOODBYE TO US
FROM THAT BED
AND... AND...
YOU SAID...
YOU SAID, "HARRINGTON,
LOOK AFTER FORBES.
HE DRINKS TOO MUCH."
THAT, THAT... THOSE
WERE YOUR EXACT WORDS.
AND...
AND I
STOOD RIGHT
AT THAT DOOR,
AND... AND I LAUGHED.
I SWEAR TO YOU, BILL,
I SWEAR TO YOU--
IT HAPPENED!
I KNOW IT HAPPENED!
[Iaughs]
I'M GONNA LET YOU HAVE
IT, FRESH, PUNK KID.
OH, I'M GOING TO FIX
THIS BABY'S WAGON!
I'M GONNA TELL THE
MEDICS HE'S A VERY
SICK COOKIE
AND OUGHTTA BE KEPT
UNDER OBSERVATION
FOR ANOTHER SEVEN YEARS.
AND EVERY SATURDAY NIGHT,
THE COLONEL AND I ARE
GONNA PHONE YOU FROM
WHATEVER BAR
WE HAPPEN TO BE
IN AT THE TIME,
AND IF YOU'RE NICE--
IF YOU ARE
REAL NICE...
WE'LL EVEN LET YOU
TALK TO OUR WOMEN.
WILL YOU
COME ON ALREADY?
I JUST CAN'T STAND
THESE LONG GOODBYES.
WOULD YOU BOTH
GET OUT OF HERE
AND LEAVE ME ALONE?
LET ME SUFFER
IN LONELINESS
ALL BY MYSELF, HUH?
(Harrington)
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
GUY IN THE MIDDLE THERE,
BUT WHO ARE
THE TWO SLOBS
ON THE SIDES?
WELL, WILLY,
WE'LL DROP BY
AND SEE YOU
TOMORROW, MAYBE.
WELL, GET LOST,
UM, WHO NEEDS YOU?
[all laughing]
[cheerfuI music]
(man)
HEY! YOU'RE FORBES AND
HARRINGTON, AIN'T YOU?
AIN'T YOU THE GUYS
THAT WAS UP IN SPACE?
YEAH, BUT WE
CAN STILL BUY
A COUPLE OF BEERS
FOR 30 CENTS
EARTH MONEY, HUH?
YOU BET YOUR LIFE,
BUT YOUR MONEY'S
NO GOOD HERE.
THE DRINKS ARE
ON THE HOUSE.
I DON'T GET TO SERVE
MANY CELEBRITIES.
NOW DRINK
UP, BOYS.
THANKS.
I DON'T EVEN CARE
THAT YOU CRACKED
UP THE SHIP
AND I'M
A TAXPAYER.
SAY, WHAT'S IT
LIKE UP THERE
IN OUTER SPACE?
WELL, IT'S...
IT'S LIKE, UH...
LIKE... WAY OUT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
WELL, I'LL
TELL YOU AFTER
I TASTE THE BEER.
HAPPY LANDINGS, CHAPS,
WHEREVER POSSIBLE.
WELL, THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S OKAY.
THAT AIN'T THE
LAST GLASS OF
BEER IN THE PLACE.
YOU SICK, ED?
NO...
NO, I'M NOT SICK.
I JUST GOT
A VERY FUNNY FEELING.
WHEW, I NEVER FELT
ANYTHING LIKE
THIS BEFORE.
WHAT KIND
OF FEELING?
IT'S LIKE
I DIDN'T
BELONG HERE,
LIKE IF I WAS
TO LET MYSELF
GO, I'D...
YOU'D WHAT?
LIKE I'D DISAPPEAR.
WHEW!
WOW...
HAPPY LANDINGS.
WELL, SURE.
I'M GOING TO GO
CALL MY FOLKS.
ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT, ED?
YEAH, I'M
ALL RIGHT.
[coin falls through slot]
[dialing]
HELLO, OPERATOR, I'D
LIKE TO MAKE A COLLECT
CALL PLEASE
TO DES MOINES, IOWA,
THE RESIDENCE OF
MR. JAMES HARRINGTON.
CLEGG!
YEAH?
COME HERE, PLEASE.
WOULD YOU COME
HERE QUICK?
WHAT'S TROUBLING YOU?
CLEGG, I JUST
CALLED HOME,
CALLED MY FOLKS.
MY MOM ANSWERED
THE PHONE.
I TOLD HER
WHO I WAS
AND SHE SAID SHE
DIDN'T HAVE ANY SON
NAMED ED HARRINGTON.
THAT'S WHAT
SHE SAID, CLEGG!
AND THEN I ASKED
TO TALK TO THE
OLD MAN.
HE GOT ON AND
KEPT TELLING ME
TO GET OFF THE PHONE.
HE DIDN'T WANT ANY
PRACTICAL JOKESTER
BOTHERING HIS WIFE.
HE SAID
HE DIDN'T HAVE
A SON AT ALL.
WHAT IS IT, CLEGG?
WHAT'S IT ALL MEAN?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST A
GAG, MAYBE.
NO GAG.
IT'S ALL PART
OF THIS FEELING,
THIS FEELING I...
I SHOULDN'T BE HERE,
THAT NONE OF US
SHOULD BE HERE.
IT'S AS IF...
AS IF WHAT?
AS IF MAYBE...
WE SHOULDN'T HAVE
COME BACK FROM THAT
FLIGHT AT ALL.
MAYBE SOMEBODY,
SOMETHING, MADE
A M ISTAKE
AND LET US GET THROUGH
AND WE SHOULDN'T HAVE.
ED, YOU STAY PUT.
I'M GONNA GET YOU
A GOOD STIFF DRINK--
NOW, TAKE IT EASY.
YOU STAY PUT,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU GOT A BEER
HERE, HONEY.
WHERE'S MY
BUDDY'S DRINK?
WHO?
MY BUDDY'S DRINK.
COLONEL HARRINGTON,
THE... HIS BEER...
THE BEER HE HAD
IN PLACE OF THE ONE
HE DROPPED ON THE--
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
YOU CAME IN
HERE ALONE.
YOU A WISE GUY
OR SOMETHING--?
[wrinkIing]
[soft wrinkIing]
YOU'RE CRAZY!
YOU'RE...YOU'RE CRAZY!
YOU'RE CRAZY,
YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU'RE... YOU'RE...
YOU'RE CRAZY!
OPERATOR, I'D LIKE
ADDISON AIR FORCE
BASE, PLEASE.
COMMANDING OFFICERS RESIDENCE.
WHAT?
WELL, CALL ME
BACK, WILL YOU?
[knocking]
ED, YOU...!
AMY! OH, AMY, HONEY,
I'M SO GLAD TO SEE YOU!
AND YOU,
COLONEL CLEGG,
ARE A DEVIOUS, MALICIOUS,
TWO-FACED, TWO-TIM ING--
NO, LOOK, I'M
IN TROUBLE, AMY.
I KNOW YOU WON'T
UNDERSTAND THIS,
BUT I THINK I'M
IN BAD TROUBLE.
I HAVE NO
DOUBT YOU ARE.
YOU SEND ME A WIRE
THAT YOU'RE GOING
TO MEET ME
AT THE BUS STATION
AT 1 2:00 TONIGHT.
WELL, I WAS THERE AT 1 2:00
AND I WAS THERE AT 1 :00
AND I WAS STILL
THERE AT 2:00.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
HOW MANY BARS I'VE
BEEN TO?
HOW MANY MOTELS?
AMY, PLEASE!
CLEGG...
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT... WHAT KIND
OF TROUBLE ARE
YOU IN?
PLEASE TELL ME.
I WANT TO KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
BEGIN TO TELL
YOU THIS.
BUT, WELL, I SENT
YOU THAT WIRE
BECAUSE I WAS
GETTING DISCHARGED FROM
THE HOSPITAL THIS MORNING.
AND ED AND
I WERE GOING
TO WAIT FOR YOU--
IT WAS IN
THE WIRE.
THE TELEGRAM!
WHAT WAS?
I WROTE DOWN THAT
ED AND I WERE GONNA
GET OUT THIS MORNING--
I WROTE DOWN
"ED AND I."
I'VE GOT IT
HERE SOMEPLACE.
YEAH, LOOK!
SEE, "I'M GETTING
OUT AT 9:00..."
"I'M..."
AMY, I...
I WROTE DOWN
THAT ED AND I WERE
LEAVING THE HOSPITAL.
I... I...
I WROTE DOWN
THAT ED AND I,
ED AND I WERE...!
ED-- WHO'S ED?
DON'T YOU KNOW?
I DON'T
KNOW ANY
ED. WHO'S ED?
ED.
HARRINGTON.
YOU KNOW HIM, AMY!
ED! YOU MET HIM
A HUNDRED TIMES.
ED. WE'VE BEEN TO DINNER
TOGETHER, WE'VE BEEN
TO DANCES TOGETHER!
ED! WE'VE
DOUBLE-DATED ED!
CLEGG, WHAT'S THE
MATTER WITH YOU?
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO YOU?
I DON'T KNOW.
I SWEAR TO GOD
[phone rings]
YES?
PUT HIM ON!
HELLO, GENERAL? THIS
IS CLEGG FORBES, SIR.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY
TO CALL YOU AT THIS
HOUR OF THE MORNING, SIR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
GENERAL--IT'S
ABOUT ED HARRINGTON.
ED HARRINGTON, SIR.
YOUREMEMBER ED.
WE WERE IN YOUR WING
AT THE FIELD SIR,
WE WERE WITH YOU
1 9 MONTHS, SIR.
HARRINGTON, SIR.
ED HARRINGTON!
ED HARRINGTON! WHY
DOESN'T ANYBODY
REMEMBER HIM?
I KNOW.
THIS IS A GAG,
ISN'T IT?
THAT'S WHAT IT IS,
ISN'T IT, AMY?
THIS IS A GAG.
OH, THIS IS A
BIG EARTHSHAKING,
HIGHLY COMPLICATED
AND FANTASTICALLY
CONCEIVED PRACTICAL
JOKE, ISN'T IT?
OH, HE'S
STILL AT THE BAR,
ISN'T HE, AMY?
THAT'S WHERE HE IS.
HE'S STILL AT THE
BAR, ISN'T HE?
HE'S STILL
AT THE BAR!
ED?
HARRINGTON!
ED!
HARRINGTON!!
[whimpers]
ED?
HARRINGTON.
HARRINGTON?
[weeping]
PLEASE, ED.
ED?
PLEASE COME BACK.
PLEASE, HARRINGTON.
PLEASE, ED.
PLEASE COME BACK.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I DID THEN.
I JUST RAN I GUESS
ALL THE WAY DOWN THE
STREET LIKE A CRAZY MAN.
SEEMS TO ME
I HEARD A...A
BURGLAR ALARM SOMEWHERE.
AMY.
I JUST LEFT AMY
STANDING THERE,
I GUESS.
I... I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO AMY.
CLEGG.
I DON'T KNOW
ED HARRINGTON.
I NEVER HEARD
OF HIM BEFORE.
I THINK HE MUST BE AN
ILLUSION OR SOMETHING.
OH, I KNOW HE'S
NOT AN ILLUSION.
I KNOW.
HE'S BEEN YANKED
OUT OF HERE.
HE'S BEEN
TAKEN AWAY.
HE TOLD
ME, REMEMBER?
ME MAYBE...
MAYBE SOMEBODY
OR SOMETHING--
MADE A M ISTAKE...
LET US GET THROUGH
WHEN WE SHOULDN'T
HAVE GOTTEN THROUGH.
THEY'VE GOT
TO COME BACK
TO GET US--
SOMEBODY UP THERE.
AW, BILL...
THIS IS WEIRD,
JUST PLAIN WEIRD.
LIKE I JUST
DON'T BELONG...
JUST LIKE I...
I DON'T BELONG.
AW, NO!
I DON'T
WANT THIS
TO HAPPEN!
BILL, I
DON'T WANT
IT TO HAPPEN!
I DON'T WANT IT
TO HAPPEN!
[shouting]
SOMEBODY GET HIM!
SOMEBODY...
SOMEBODY GET HIM.
MAJOR, YOU
SHOULDN'T BE
OUT OF BED!
WHY, IF
THE DOCTOR...
SOMEBODY'S GOT
TO HELP HIM.
COLONEL FORBES--
SOMEBODY'S GOT TO
HELP HIM RIGHT AWAY.
WHO?
[yells]
COLONEL FORBES!
[sighs]
YOU KNOW
COLONEL FORBES.
WHY, HE WAS BROUGHT
IN HERE WITH ME.
WHY, HE WAS RIGHT
OVER HERE IN THIS--
OH, MY DEAR GOD!
MAJOR, MAJOR, LET ME
HELP YOU GET INTO BED.
COME AHEAD, MAJOR.
AND I'LL... I'LL
CALL THE DOCTOR.
COME, MAJOR.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[shouting]
MAJOR!
MAJOR HANGERSON!
HOW ARE WE FIXED
IN THIS WARD HERE?
ROOM 1 5 DOWN HERE CAN
TAKE THREE PATIENTS, SIR.
IT'S EMPTY.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
(man)
MM-HMM, THAT WILL DO
FOR THE MALARIA PATIENTS.
ORDER SOME BEDS UP
FROM Q-M, WILL YOU?
YES, SIR.
(Serling, off)
ONCE UPON A TIME, THERE
WAS A MAN NAMED HARRINGTON,
A MAN NAMED FORBES,
A MAN NAMED GART.
THEY USED TO EXIST,
BUT DON'T ANY LONGER.
SOMEONE OR SOMETHING
TOOK THEM SOMEWHERE.
AT LEAST, THEY ARE NO LONGER
A PART OF THE MEMORY OF MAN.
AND AS TO THE X-20 SUPPOSED
TO BE HOUSED HERE IN
THIS HANGAR,
THIS, TOO, DOES NOT EXIST.
AND IF ANY OF YOU
HAVE ANY QUESTIONS
CONCERNING AN AIRCRAFT
AND THREE MEN
WHO FLEW HER,
SPEAK SOFTLY OF THEM
AND ONLY IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male narrator, off)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OFTWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU
ABOUT OUR NEXT STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
(male presenter, off)
AND NOW MR. SERLING.
THIS IS THE SEASON
OF GIFT-GIVING.
BIG GIFTS AND
LITTLE GIFTS,
EXPENSIVE ONES AND
NOT SO EXPENSIVE ONES.
WELL, NEXT TIME,
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
GIVES YOU ITS OWN
PECULIAR ODDBALL
BRAND OF GIFT-GIVING.
MR. STEVE COCHRANE
AND MR. ERNEST TRUEX
COMBINE TALENTS
TO TELL A STORY
ABOUT A LITTLE MAN
WHO HAS WHAT YOU NEED.
OUR NEXT OFFERING
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
BE SURE TO SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS.
THE DANNY THOMAS SHOW,
MONDAY NIGHTS
OVER MOST OF
THESE STATIONS.