Nobody ever went broke underestimating
the taste of the American public.
The ancient Egyptians
postulated seven souls.
The top soul and the first to leave
at the moment of death
is Ren:
the Secret Name.
This corresponds
to my Director.
He directs
the film of your life
from conception
to death.
"The Secret Name"
is the title of your film.
When you die,
that's where Ren came in.
Second soul
and second one
off the sinking ship
is Sekem:
Energy, Power, Light.
The Director gives the orders,
Sekem presses
the right buttons.
Number three is Khu:
the Guardian Angel.
He, she or it
is third man out.
Number four is Ba:
the Heart--
often treacherous.
Number five is Ka:
the Double.
The Ka, which usually
reaches adolescence
at the time
of bodily death,
is the only reliable guide
through the Land of the Dead.
Who's gonna live here?
A family. I'll have it
finished by October.
- I'm worried, Ade.
- Everybody's worried.
No. I am worried
all the time.
Number six is Khaibit:
the Shadow, Memory,
your whole past conditioning from this
and other lives.
Number seven is Sekhu:
the Remains.
I'm halfway to China.
There's nothing here.
40, 000 I had--
my share of the Bohack's haul
from the '70s.
Did you wrap it right?
It gets moldy--
it could've disintegrated.
- Wrap what?
- The money.
He knows I need that money
for my fucking retrial!
- Who?
- You know who.
No, I don't know who.
That's why I asked you.
- Malanga.
- Will you stop with that?
Pussy Malanga's dead
six years now.
I should dig him up
already!
Moles. They chewing
through your sprinklers too?
- Slog du in det ordentligt?
Det blir mÃ♪gligt--kan vittra sÃ♪nder.
- Slog in vad?
- Pengarna.
We'll look later.
You're gonna be late for your doctor's.
Come on.
Hello?
Let me ask you something:
ls your time more valuable
than mine?
Where's the baby?
Sorry, Ton'. The car seat,
the other stuff--
packin' it in there
takes forever.
You probably
remember that.
No, I don't.
I didn't do that crap.
How are you feeling,
Uncle Jun', huh?
He's late enough, Janice.
Come on.
A hello to your niece,
maybe?
Hi, sweetie.
How are you?
Help him get ready,
will you?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Jun'.
So? How's he doing?
He's Knucklehead Smith,
that's how he's doing.
He's paranoid. He doesn't remember
whether he ate or not.
The man is not
competent, Tony.
- Not again, come on!
- He has the money for assisted living.
He's got legal bills
up the ass.
He can sell this museum
and move to Green Grove.
Fuck assisted living, okay?
Remember what they did to Ma?
- She was thriving there, Tony.
- He stays where he is, Janice.
He's our uncle.
It's the least we can do.
So the split,
your friend in Jersey
says it should be the same
as the old business we do over there.
That's public works,
this isn't.
- I'll hold the line.
- Don't turn it into World War lll.
So day to day,
how are you getting along with Tony?
You asked me
to bury the hatchet, John.
I'm doing it
out of respect to you.
Am I still grieving
over my brother Bill?
It'll never go away.
I appreciate it, Phil.
- With me in here--
- I hear you, John.
Your bride--
she's a rock for you, kid.
Her brother's fitting me
for contacts.
When the trial starts,
I don't wanna be
reading documents
in the courtroom with glasses.
It looks weak.
Yes?
- Hey, Ton'.
- Hey.
My sports book
down in Roseville,
Bacala's still making
things unpleasant.
- God damn it.
- Listen, Tony,
I got you something.
For you, Carm, the kids--
David Yurman watches.
18-karat gold,
diamond center.
Why do I get the feelin'
there's a jeweler somewhere
filin' an insurance
claim today?
Actually,
that ain't what it is.
- My Aunt Edie died.
- No?
That one that moved to California
back in the '60s?
She was a great lady,
the only person in my life
who ever made me
feel special.
What are you gonna do?
Anyway, the silver cloud
is she did pretty well.
She was married
to Victor Borge's agent.
She left me an inheritance, Ton'.
Just over two mil.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
Well, congratulations.
Make sure you invest it.
Well, you know, that's kind of
what I wanted to talk to you about.
Deanne and me
and the kids,
you know how much
we love Florida, right?
What, do you wanna put some money
on the street down there?
I was thinking about buying
a place in Fort Myers.
- Retiring there, actually.
- Retiring?
What, are you
a hockey player?
I'm gonna be 50 in three years, Ton'.
My dad died at 52.
You took an oath, Gene.
There's no retirin' from this.
Well, I thought about that,
and there was Joe Bananas.
Come on, huh?
What about your sports book,
your other responsibilities?
What am I supposed
to do about those?
Benny? We know
Bobby wants it.
It's just-- we go back
a long way, Ton'.
Yeah, we do.
Fuckin' CYO Basketball,
do you believe that?
It'd mean a lot
to me and Deanne.
Well, let me
think about it.
Ooh, look at this one
with the pool.
Yeah, we could
go swimming.
Guess who's blocking
the driveway again.
Did you talk
to Tony?
It looks good.
He gave me a hug.
- Did he like the watches?
- Do I know my psychology?
The realtor called.
She's e-mailing some pictures.
- The one on River Road?
- The split level-- the four-bedroom.
They lost the buyer?
Hey, there he is.
Where are you goin'?
- Kevin's.
- Who else is gonna be there?
- Gene.
- I don't know.
What's with this hostility all the time?
You want a smack in the mouth?
I told you I'm not
getting high anymore!
- I believe you.
- Stop fucking touching me.
Watch your mouth
in front of your sister!
I have a right to know
who your friends are!
Hey!
Spicy shrimp hand roll,
that's Nori's favorite,
special yellowtail,
toro scallion and oysters.
You tell me
when you wanna stop.
Well, keep it comin'.
I don't know about you,
but ever since we found this place,
I catch myself
fantasizing about this.
Me too.
Sometimes during sex.
So I had a nightmare the other night.
Did I wake you up?
- No.
- Ade was in the house,
my spec house.
Was she gonna buy it?
We were just talking.
Speaking of which,
did you call that guy,
the inspector
at the building department?
- I will. I promise.
- He's coming on Friday, Tony.
That could be
my last chance to get
a reversal
on the stop-work order.
All right, I'll call.
I wonder where she is.
- Ade.
- I told you, she probably met some guy.
And not call anyone
for over a year?
What's this,
this sauce on the shrimp?
Shiromi, tekka maki,
salmon with tomato.
So I was over
by Ginny's--
that situation is
not going so well.
Johnny cooped up
and awaiting trial,
plus now they're fighting
an asset seizure.
They could lose everything--
the house, the condo at the shore.
You know Jimmy Petrille,
the rat that gave up John?
He's like an uncle to him,
his father's compare.
Why do you think I toss at night?
Ain't just the apnea.
I noticed you haven't been taking
your antidepressants.
And yet, the bonefish
are back in season.
We should count our blessings,
the kind of year I just had.
You're right.
We're very lucky.
$40 for a piece of fish
they just flew in first class.
I think we're
more than lucky.
Great food in there.
It's pretty good.
You wanna keep
this baggie or shall I?
- Nah, you keep it for lunch.
- Okay.
We're here.
Thanks for dinner, Hesh.
Grease is coming through
the bag as usual.
Chinese food--
it's part of the tradition.
What the--
Whoa! Whoa!
What the fuck
is this?
Come on, come on!
Hey, where are you goin'?
Get out of the car!
Get out of here,
get out of here!
- Take a hike, Jimmy.
- Open up, Eli!
- Get out!
- Open the fucking door!
- Get out of here!
- What do you want me to do?
- I can't do anything!
- Fucking Jew!
- Let's go, old man!
- Open the fucking door!
Holy shit, they're trying
to burn us out!
- Open the fucking door!
- Get out, Hesh!
- Leave me alone!
- Jerry warned you, Eli!
Jerry fucking told you
to stay out of Brooklyn!
What are you guys doin'?
You're gonna kill this guy.
Fuck you, Grandpa!
I tell you, one of the best things
about dropping the weight,
a whole new wardrobe.
I keep this up,
I'm gonna need
Clothing Anonymous.
You should have called your sponsor
before you bought that jacket.
Look at this guy.
"Members Only"?
How long have you been wearing that?
Cugino mio!
You look sharp.
How do you feel?
Two miles I walk
every mornin'.
You goin' to little
Tommy's communion?
I gotta talk to Aunt Lenore.
Say hello to Marie for me.
Hold on, let me
get that number,
- the custom cufflinks.
- Oh yeah.
What'd that prick want?
Really something, isn't he,
with that jerk-off face?
The eyebrows--
I fucking can't stand him.
I gotta tell you though,
he surprised me.
He's acting boss,
takes care
of John's business,
plus the wife
while John's in jail.
No complaints.
He's real old school.
Gotta take
my hat off.
Cocksucker
wanted me killed?
What's past is past.
Leave it alone.
Things are
going good now.
You and Phil settle
that office park shit?
We said
we'd revisit it.
Agent Harris,
where've you been?
I got some new federale
in my rear view for six months.
- Actually, I've been in Pakistan.
- Get the fuck out.
Seriously.
I was transferred to terrorism.
This is my partner, Ron Goddard.
Tony Soprano.
The terrorist
squad, huh?
- What, did you lose a little weight?
- Uh...
You look good.
Atkins, right?
I caught a parasite over there.
Doctors don't know what it is.
- What do they eat, tabbouleh?
- Actually, that's why I'm here.
I've been dying for a Satriale's
veal parm hero.
Fuck him. I hope that parasite
eats his asshole out.
I kind of feel bad
for the guy.
Shit, when did
this happen?
Hold on.
Ton' just come in.
It's Hesh.
Yeah.
Here, honey.
It's ice.
Tony.
Thank you.
Hey.
Beth, how're you doin'?
I've had
better weeks.
Could you get me
some coffee, sweetie?
- Anyone else?
- Hot water with lemon would be great.
My son-in-law and me,
we're having dinner Sunday,
Chinese restaurant near Mill Basin,
we get jumped by three guys in a Lexus.
- Chinks did this?
- Are you trying to be fucking funny?
- You want a smack in the mouth?
- What? I was serious.
They're with your cousin
Phil Leotardo.
I told you he was a prick!
- We were just with him.
- Let him talk.
I got some money
on the street over there.
Apparently, it got back
to Phil's guy
- Gerry Torciano.
- The Hairdo?
He claims that he felt
that Eli here was
some independent shy
trying to poach his customers.
- ls that a fucking catheter?
- Massive internal bleeding,
half his fucking skin
is sheared off his hips.
My daughter's
besides herself.
You send somebody to Brooklyn, and you
talk to Phil
- about this mook, this--
- Gerry Torciano.
Sorry I yelled
at you, kid.
I'm installing gable joists
in the rotunda.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to agree
with the original assessment.
Oh, for the love
of Mike!
This is pine, sir--
utility grade.
I know what it is.
I've been building houses for years.
Then you know that the code calls
for Doug fir grade,
stamped for all floor joists,
ceiling joists, lintels and rafters.
Get Pudgie Walsh on the horn.
He'll straighten this out.
Pudgie Walsh
retired, sir.
- I'm affirming the stop-work order.
- Oh, come on!
- ls there nothing else we can do?
- For God's sake!
You can schedule a further appeal.
But if I were you,
I'd think about starting over
with the proper lumber.
God, 15 times
I asked you!
Do you know what this does
to my cost basis,
- to start over with this?
- It's bureaucratic bullshit!
- ln my day, they'd turn a blind eye.
- I hired you to do a job!
Hired?
I'm not for hire.
You presented this
like we were partners.
- You don't listen to anybody, do you?
- Oh!
To hell with this.
No good deed goes unpunished.
Artie. Ho.
Menus.
- ls that Phil?
- My wife.
What's it take to get that guy
to return a phone call?
I want this Hesh thing
settled.
Gentlemen,
start your engines.
Jesus Christ, Artie,
I can recite that menu in my sleep.
Where did he get this bread,
the bread museum?
The antipaste?
Fuckin' Phil.
Now I gotta go see the optometrist
to get a message to John
about this.
Go through
Ginny's brother?
He's a stunad
of the first magnitude.
I need a back channel
to John, obviously.
What the fuck is it?
I can't catch
a fucking break!
This is Tony Soprano
talking about
the Angelo Giacolone murder.
The sound quality
is not good,
but I can back it up
in court.
He said--
You all right, Ton'?
Yeah.
That formaldehyde smell...
I knew this guy once,
Vietnam vet.
He drank formaldehyde
over there just to get high.
It's the alcohol.
Does he have to be here,
your fucking AA sponsor?
It ain't just that he helps me
with the disease, T.
This guy is great
at forging documents.
- He was a good kid, Raymond.
- The best.
At least he went fast.
Not like Dick Barone, poor fuck.
- Dick Barone died?
- Lou Gehrig's disease.
Did you ever think
what a coincidence it is
that Lou Gehrig died
of Lou Gehrig's disease?
You gonna make that same stupid joke
every time that comes up?
Sorry.
Everything's
so fucking morbid.
There's a man
lying dead over there.
I'm gonna go smoke.
- Hey, Tony.
- Hey.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
For you.
Your taste.
The inheritance.
I didn't want
to say nothing,
with your aunt and all,
but this is thoughtful.
- So that thing we spoke about...
- Still mulling it.
Yeah, whatever.
Sure.
All right.
Look at this guy.
Not a day over 76.
- Fucking ballbreaker.
- How are you, Rusty?
ls Phil Leotardo here?
'Cause I won't stay
- in the same room with that man.
- I haven't seen him.
So you hear about that guy
in Westchester?
Fucking captain,
doing his own radio broadcast
the last three years.
- W. R.A. T.
- Jesus Christ, another one now?
No wonder the papers are calling this
"The Year of the Rat. "
Standup guys like that,
they're a dying breed.
Amen to that.
What can you do?
Anyway, let me go
pay my respects.
All right, Rusty.
- You okay?
- I gotta get out of here.
He's thinking about it.
What do you want me to tell you?
How many years have we dreamt
about this, to get out of this shit?
Every time someone
we know gets arrested--
I know. Will you stop?
I'm worried, Gene.
We've already made the offer.
I'm doing
everything I can.
Why are you fighting?
We're not fighting, sweetie.
We're talking.
- How come you're not in bed, hmm?
- I don't know.
All I'm saying is,
he has to see
this is a huge
opportunity for us.
Give the man
time to process.
Oh my God,
this eel is delicious.
Okay, Spanish mackerel now.
Can I get
another sake, hon'?
Listen, I got some stuff
I gotta take care of.
You okay
to drive yourself home?
I don't have
my car, Tony.
Oh, yeah.
So take this one.
- Hey, Mrs. S.
- What is this?
Oh my God.
ls this the new Porsche?
Cayenne Turbo.
I got the 4. 5-liter V-8.
Wasn't sure about the color,
so I took a shot.
Tony, I love it.
It's gorgeous!
I still wish you'd talked to that guy
at the building department,
but oh my God!
What a car!
Ho, Joe College,
where's your mother?
She went to the outlet stores
with Aunt Ro.
ls that the jacket
we got you for Christmas?
I'm lending it to Matt.
Hey, how was the interview
for the internship?
Got moved
to next week.
Would you mind keeping me
in the loop, though, since it was
- my lawyer that set it up, huh?
- Okay.
- Matt don't have his own clothes?
- He's borrowing it for a party.
Oh, good.
You'll never see it again.
You have such a low
opinion of people.
Let me tell you
something, A. J.
I don't care
how close you are,
in the end, your friends
are gonna let you down.
Family. They're the only ones
you can depend on.
He was vital, my uncle,
alive.
For all his faults,
he was sharp in his day.
But now...
We stopped
at a light yesterday,
and I see this nanny,
black girl,
pushing a baby carriage.
Coming the other way,
there's another one
with this old lady
in a wheelchair
- staring off into space.
- The circle of life.
The circle jerk of life.
Where's the dignity?
lf you're lucky, in the end you can
let go of your pride,
let your loved ones
care for you.
I'd rather they hold
a pillow over my face.
I find it interesting
you would say that.
You tried to smother
your mother with a pillow.
- What?
- ln the hospital, after her stroke.
The fuck I did!
I grabbed a pillow,
but it was...
just to keep my hands
occupied.
Have you considered
getting your uncle
some live-in help?
We got a girl comes in days,
she's from Trinidad.
Does he have the means
for assisted living?
Did you just say to let your loved ones
take care of you?
- lf it's feasible.
- Well, he's my uncle.
I don't think that's what
we're talking about.
What are we
talking about?
The fact that you still,
after all this time,
cannot accept you had a mother
who didn't love you.
ln pitying your uncle,
the man she conspired with,
you're turning the blame
for what she did
back on yourself again,
after all this time.
What was your mother like?
Did she ever let you down,
hurt your feelings?
Of course she did.
She was controlling
and manipulative at times.
- She also never tried to kill me.
- I pushed her over the edge.
By placing her in a lovely
retirement community.
It's a nursing home!
It's less hurtful to believe
that they were right
to try and destroy you
than to accept the fact
that she didn't value you.
Hesh is a personal
friend of mine,
and the kid is
his son-in-law.
Now I know Phil's got
a lot on his plate, but come on.
I'll talk to John. I was taking
my sister there Saturday anyway.
How is Ginny?
Carmela says she's got her hands full.
The kid has the weight
of the world on her.
Ray-Bans.
Classic, affordable.
I just put those
on special.
You got something
a little more current?
Like those.
Armanis.
Flexible acetate frames,
rimless lenses.
You know what?
I left my wallet in the car.
I'll catch you next time.
Some people
from the lRS came by.
They want to inventory
the entire house.
Maybe I should
sell the car,
at least get some
liquidity out of it.
The Maserati?
Can't say I disagree.
That breaks my
fucking heart.
Christopher Moltisanti
came over to the house asking about it.
He'll pay cash, he said.
There's something else,
John,
Phil related.
The Hairdo, he's in a beef
with the Jew.
What?
God damn it, what?
The Jew's son-in-law.
It got physical.
Your friend from Jersey got involved,
but he can't get Phil to focus.
Do I not have enough
on my fucking mind?
The guy from Jersey
asked me to tell you.
Well, then call Phil
and have him fucking handle it!
Don't yell at my brother, John.
He's trying to do right by us.
The pictures
from Allegra's shower.
Noon he said, right?
Passive-aggressive
bullshit.
I recognize that in people
every time now.
There he is.
Ho, finally. I was starting to grow
mushrooms out my ass.
There's an image.
So Gerry filled me in
on the way over.
This whole thing was
a complete misunderstanding.
Yeah, this Eli kid, I had any idea
he was with you,
- I would have never...
- He didn't tell you about Hesh?
I asked who he was. He high-handed me.
I thought he was a civilian.
Still, to get dragged
by a car?
For the record, though,
the car thing was a hit-and-run.
So what do we do here?
- What did we say?
- 25 sounds right.
He's bleeding internally.
Pain, suffering--
So you tell me. 50?
Yeah, fair enough.
Could we segue now
into something more pressing?
The floor is yours,
Senator.
I spoke to John. The split on the office
park is way out of whack.
Same thing
as the Esplanade.
Apples and bowling balls, Tony.
With fuel costs now--
Like you're not
passing that on to the drivers?
65-35.
All right.
Why you always cave
for this prick?
I'm not caving.
It's a strategy.
Johnny's in jail.
You keep him happy,
he'll keep a lid
on Phil.
Tony B,
Phil's kid brother,
the bad taste
that left with Phil--
there are 200 soldiers
in his family.
I'm not scared of them.
- Tony left?
- Yeah.
I stopped by Stewart's.
I got a whole lunch set up.
Did Tony mention anything to you
about what we talked about?
About you
moving to Florida?
Did he say if he's leaning
one way or the other?
Listen, there's something
I need you to do.
I got a call from Fritzie
up in Boston.
There's a guy named
Teddy Spirodakis, owes some money.
- You want me to collect?
- That ship sailed. Final notice time.
Really?
You got a problem
with that?
No.
I just gotta run it by Vito.
He's my captain.
Believe me,
Vito will be down with it.
So this comes from Tony?
It's coming from me.
I'm not a fucking captain?
All right, okay?
- How soon?
- ASAP.
Like right away.
I'll call with the details.
Get it done.
I'll put in a good word to T.
about the Florida thing.
The rear deck, didn't they say
that would be refinished?
That's the old photo.
It's been completely redone.
The wiring in the pool house?
Tell them they can knock
two grand off the price
or they can sell to someone else.
Listen, you're responding
to their counter.
You should ask
for whatever you want.
Okay, we'll call you
tomorrow.
All right then,
good night.
What do you think?
That if we lose this house,
I'm gonna die.
Ton', what do you want
to do for dinner?
I'll be right down!
Well...
Hey.
Your new insurance card.
Oh, good.
Any thoughts
on dinner?
Whatever you like.
I know this is insane,
but I can't stop
thinking about Nori's.
I was just there.
- Today? With who?
- Nobody.
You went there
without me?
Yeah, I was hungry.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Come on, what?
- I don't know,
I just thought
that was our special place.
Well, it is.
Well?
- I went there alone, Carm.
- I know that. You said.
It just felt nice
to have something special, for us.
No kids around,
without my parents...
We can go
if you want.
No, no,
don't be silly.
Are you sure?
How's the car?
Teddy, right?
Yeah.
Hey!
- Carmela.
- Ginny, hi.
I tried calling,
but I kept getting the machine.
ls everything all right?
Truth is,
sometimes I don't answer the phone.
Goddamn creditors.
I was in the neighborhood. I thought
I might kidnap you for a spa date.
Well, that's
a nice surprise.
I thought maybe we'd drive up there,
maybe stop at Occitane.
ls that new?
Oh, the car?
Yes, yes.
Porsche Cayenne,
like the pepper.
It's beautiful, Carm.
Five minutes
at no incline. Then I switch to full
uphill for my cardio.
I was telling Tony
he should come with me.
- Do him good.
- It ain't just aesthetics, either.
God forbid he ever has
a heart attack.
Yeah.
Vito, you're in
the handicapped spot.
- That fucking guy is here again?
- The man's a former judge.
Hey, listen to this.
"lf your nose runs
and your feet smell--
you're built
upside down. "
Funny.
Hey, by the way,
your Florida thing...
Tony asked me
to speak to you...
that's a no-go.
- What?
- Can't be accommodated.
You're part of the team.
- But I just did that thing.
- That's not my department.
Well, can I talk
to Tony at least?
I wouldn't bother him.
He's out on the new boat.
Does he think
I'm gonna talk about shit up here,
with what I've done,
what I just did?
It's not so silly
when you think about it.
I'm a top earner now.
It's not out of the realm
of possibility
that I could be the boss
of this family one day.
I mean, God forbid
Tony ever gets...
cancer, coronary,
something like that.
- Yeah.
- Hey, big brother.
Listen, I know I was supposed to sit
with Uncle Jun' tonight,
but Tom just called
from location.
Apparently,
some smoke effect went awry
and he inhaled
noxious chemicals.
Well, go. Go.
The thing is,
Uncle Jun' doesn't want me to.
He's exceptionally agitated
today and he's been nauseous.
Well, did you call Janice?
I mean, her or Bobby should go.
- I'm all the way out here on a boat.
- They can't do it.
- What do you mean can't?
- I don't know.
She didn't elaborate.
It didn't seem like she wanted to.
- Aw, God damn it!
- I'm sorry, Tony.
All right, all right,
all right.
Mother--
I swear to God, I'm throwing
all this shit right in the garbage!
It's my hobby, Janice.
Why do you gotta belittle it?
Will you just
get ready please?
- You go. I gotta work.
- You can do your collections tomorrow!
I'm on a schedule!
It don't work that way.
This is why you can't
watch Uncle Jun'?
I told you last week,
we have Nica's preschool meeting.
- She's 15 months old.
- No one was more competitive
than your wife when
it came to this stuff with A. J.
A lot of good it did.
This child-- constantly wanting
the breast.
He doesn't want to be alone.
He says he doesn't feel good.
The school, they need to meet both
parents if it's an intact family.
So call the girl,
the nurse.
Miss Trinidad? Right. Every time
I call, a different person answers.
I'll go, Ton'.
I'm on it.
Fuck it! You wanna get something done,
you gotta do it yourself.
You were the one
who was opposed to assisted living.
You and I
are gonna talk.
You didn't have
to wear your fucking hat.
Shit.
So how about you?
Are you dating?
With my hours
at the body shop?
Ladies.
Dessert was on me.
Thank you, Artie.
It's nice to see you two
patch things up.
- So silly.
- I'm not even sure what happened.
Me and Tony didn't speak
for months.
You pick up
right where you left off.
Did Charmaine tell you?
We're getting back together.
No, she didn't
mention it.
- That's terrific!
- We're both very happy.
Jesus, will you
hear me out at least?
We buy here. Livingston,
North Caldwell maybe.
- Right near Tony.
- Oh.
Better schools,
new friends.
We got the money, baby.
$2 million.
It's not
the same, Gene.
It could be better.
The summers down there--
we were ignoring the negatives.
It's fucking brutal
with the bugs.
Tony and Silvio,
all they understand is appearances.
We'll buy a new car.
It'll raise my profile.
You watch,
I'll make captain.
I found this
under our son's bed.
Florida's any better?
It's the drug capital of the world.
Look, for Tony to--
Tony, Tony!
Why don't you kill him?
- Put a bullet in his fucking head.
- I can't do that.
What, you think I don't know
that you've done it before?
- He's the boss, Deanne.
- The boss of what?
He's a piece of shit!
ls our life that bad?
It's your money.
Your aunt's money.
It has nothing
to do with him.
There's this wonderful
Jersey contemporary
I want you to see with me.
It's cathedral ceilings.
You'll fall in love.
There's nothing
I can say.
Colonel Dax, you're
a disappointment to me.
You have spoiled
the keenness of your mind
by wallowing
in sentimentality.
You really did want
to save those men
and you were not angling
for Mireau's command.
You're an idealist
and I pity you as I would
the village idiot.
We're fighting a war, Dax,
a war that we've got to win.
Those men didn't fight,
so they were shot.
I apologize for not being
entirely honest with you.
I apologize for not revealing
my true feelings.
I apologize, sir,
for not telling you--
- Hello.
- Who's that?
- It's me.
- You can go to hell
before I apologize to you
now or ever again!
- What are you doing?
- I lost my uppers.
- Probably upstairs.
- God fuck it all!
Relax, will ya?
We'll find them.
The phone keeps ringing,
and then they hang up.
It's probably salespeople.
- I know who it is!
- Pussy Malanga, I know.
We'll get J. Edgar Hoover
right on it.
I'll tell you what, you go upstairs,
you look for your teeth.
I'm gonna fix you
something to eat, okay?
I had a banana
in there.
All right,
we'll find that too.
I got it.
We buy a vacation place
in Florida, a condo.
It's not the same.
I make another run
at Tony
- six months, a year from now.
- A year?
- You can go ahead even.
- What?
And let me tell you,
a year, two years from now
everything could be
different.
Tony could be gone.
- I, uh...
- Go ahead.
His master's voice.
Yeah?
Now?!
- Gene, this is Agent Sanseverino.
- Hello.
Where've you been, buddy?
Haven't heard from you lately.
Busy, you know.
My kid has some problems.
That's rough.
The thing is, Geno,
you gotta keep in touch with me.
You have a chance to help
in more important ways.
- What do you mean?
- We lost a major asset this month.
- The point is--
- Was Ray Curto a cooperator?
The way things are shaping up,
you're a designated hitter.
Look, Ron,
we've talked
about Florida, okay?
Gene, that's not
gonna happen.
Here among your friends
is where you're useful.
I told you, you tell your bosses,
I'd come back for any trial.
Florida's just one of those things
you gotta let go.
Okay.
So, the Feast of St. Joe's,
Tony gave some rulings on the unions.
Were any made guys
from New York there?
10 minutes, Uncle Jun'.
Who's down there?
Artie Shaw.
10 minutes.
Don't go anywhere.
I'm not.
I'm right here.
You got any wine?
Malanga!
Well, here I am.
ls that a Porsche?
Had my eye on it for months.
It's a gift from Tony.
I thought about a Boxster,
but I don't know.
The 'Vette felt
more like me.
You bought that
yourself?
The accountant says I'm better off
owning it outright.
Uncle Jun'!
Call 911!
911, where is
the emergency?
Number six is Khaibit:
the Shadow, Memory,
your whole past conditioning from this
and other lives.
Number seven is Sekhu:
the Remains.