Ah, stupid thing.
The pressure is shot.
Can you live with regular
instead of espresso?
Never mind, sweetie.
Thanks anyway.
Hey hey.
Sorry for the ambush.
I brung up your paper.
I am meeting
the new realtor.
Yeah?
Good luck.
Got a call from sergeant
danny over in newark p.d.
- yeah? And?
T? The feds are doing some
digging over by branford avenue.
Willie overall...
The bookie,
labor day, 1982?
Danny says he hears it's larry
barese that's been talkin'.
Lotta work
for a dead fuckin' bookie.
Come on, kid. Do it.
You made your bones
with that prick, eh?
Yeah.
Old zepupin's house.
You were shaky a little,
but you did good.
I remember
tellin' your old man.
25 years, T.
Possible there's
nothing left.
There'll be bones,
teeth.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna pack
our toothbrushes.
Call you in a few days
on the alternate cell.
Any emergencies,
call sil or bobby.
And if you need
more cash, call me.
I know the drill, tony.
You know, it's not like
I won a trip to paris.
You have everything?
Your razor?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think so.
I... I can buy
whatever I need.
- will you make sure you wear your sunblock?
- it's nothing.
A little gambling charge,
that's all. It's gonna be fine.
It's just... You know,
better safe than sorry.
I know, it's just... This
is what life is still like...
At our age?
My tomatoes
are just coming in.
It's good to see you.
- yeah.
You seem good, junior,
I gotta say.
You're not repeating
yourself so much.
You gotta get me
out of here...
The smell alone
in this fuckin' place.
What do you hear
from my nephew?
Tony? They sent me
a card for my birthday.
I'm still waitin'
for an apology. Tell him.
All right.
Which one of you's
gonna tell him?
We'll figure it out,
junior.
If you made
an appointment
with an outside dentist,
that might do
the trick.
What trick?
We'll meet you there
and sneak you off
in our car.
Dinner, 10 minutes.
So what do you think,
junior?
Enchiladas tonight.
Here's the electricians' union.
Don't let 'e
take my plate, kid.
Make sure there's enough
so everybody can buy in.
$60.
- for sodas and fuckin' candy?
- caffeinated sodas and sugar.
You know some of them
ain't allowed this shit.
Gets them all riled.
I could lose my job.
- fuckin' stick-up artist. I already gave you
my watch. - don't count my money, nigga.
You're makin' 500%
off these motherfuckers.
You're good
till lights out.
I'll steer people
away from the door.
All right.
No-limit five-card stud.
$40 buy-in to the house.
The white buttons are five
bucks. The red buttons are 10.
"red buttons."
what'd you say?
Today, we got coca-colas...
Fuck was I just sayin'?
- the soda, junior.
- what soda?
Right, the coke.
The real kind,
not the diet shit,
ice cold,
five buttons.
Plus, we got snickers,
kit-kats and sprees, also five.
Ll take some sprees.
Okay, ante up.
This is nice, huh?
A lile road trip,
just you and me...
All things considered,
of course.
Yeah, just like
the old days.
Willie-fuckin'- overall,
after all these years.
You remember drivin' around with that
prick in the trunk lookin' for a spot?
What was it, like a week
before a.j. Was born, right?
No, meadow.
- now she's gonna be a dr.
- yeah.
Remember we took you
to luger's after
me, puss, ralphie.
Chevy chase... Fuck ever
happened to him?
Let me ask you something.
You mentioned ralph before.
A few years ago, he had
that beef with johnny sack,
he made a crack about ginny...
Huge fuckin' mole
on her ass or some shit.
Yeah?
Who the fuck would tell
johnny about that joke?
How should I know?
Nine of clubs.
You know, I try
to be cooperative,
but it's that same
message over and over!
Walter,
what do you got?
Flush.
No, you don't.
George?
- uh...
- what?
- george, what do you got?
- hmm?
- your hand.
- he's got alzheimer's!
- help him, for christ's sake!
- pair of jacks.
Guy comes home with a
bouquet of flowers for his wife.
"I guess I'll have to spread
my legs now," she says.
"why?" he asks.
"don't you have a vase?"
high rollers only.
Keep walkin', professor.
I'm not here to gamble.
I'm here looking for keith.
Keith's busy. Take a hike.
We had
a chess match, keith.
The pride of rutgers...
Slits his wrists
in the faculty lounge
after he stabbed
the dean.
At least some of us
know when we need help.
Get the fuck out of here,
ya fuck...
What did the blind man say
when he passed the fish market?
I don't know.
"good morning, ladies."
what's going on, guys?
- they're gambling, warren.
- relax, brian.
What did we
say about this?
What?
It's a friendly game.
Corrado, it's too stressful. Lookt him!
He's not even playin'.
Come on, guys. Let's wrap it up.
I saw your girl today
at pet therapy.
Hodoes she keep
her coat so shiny?
...they can be unexpected,
frightening events.
But they're justutiful
part of the scenery. Park,
- crater lake is located high in the cascades
of south-central oregon, about
250 miles south of portland...
I brought you your tea.
You did a good job tonight,
kid. Here's your taste.
- that's all right.
Take it.
You earned it.
Time once, I was a kid.
You know, my oldan
was a stonemason.
He took me to work...
A job building a wall around
some rich lady's garden.
She mes home.
I help carry her groceries.
She goes to give me
a quarter,
which was a lot in
those days, but I say no.
She goes in. No sooner
does she close the door,
when... Crack! My old man gives
me a belt right across the mouth.
"what are you, a millionaire?
You no need-a money?
You no like-a eat?"
"what are you, a millionaire?
You no need-wow.ney?
Even still, he was right.
He made me
walk home that night.
11 fuckin' miles from
essex fells back to newark.
I'm from essex fells.
- a rich kid, huh?
Uh... Warren said I should
get my buttons back
on account of we weren't
really supposed to be gambling.
Tell warren
he can fuck himself.
Got a problem with that,
tell him to come see me.
Can I get a kit-kat
at least?
Do you believe this guy?
Get the fuck out of here?
Once in third grade...
I got a 96 on my spelling test,
highest mark in the class.
I was so proud.
I brought it home
to show my dad.
"what happened to thother
four points?" he says.
Fuck you!
Fuck... You!
... Uz f.m. Fredericksburg.
Your home
for classic rock.
96.9.
Paulie, we should stop.
- fuck are we?
- virgin.
You remember that place...
The dive with
the fuckin' massage beds?
It was in culpepper,
virginia.
- the havenaire.
- ah!
We met those 16-ye-old
hillbilly whores
near the taxi stand.
Yeah.
You want the old days,
let's go there.
We'll get a room, bucket
of ice from the machine,
bottle of scotch,
order up a couple steaks...
Heh heh heh.
Now you're fuckin' talkin'.
Excuse me!
This place, is it new?
I think maybe,
I don't know.
There was a motel
on this spot though, right?
- the havenaire?
- I don't know.
Fuckin' guy.
Mr. Spears,
you're all set.
Two king rooms, one night,
checking out tomorrow.
From 6:00 to 10:00 we offer a
complimentary buffet breakfast
in the courtesy room
off the lobby.
Sign there, please.
Can you have
room service send up
two fifths
of glenlivet?
I apologize, sir,
we don't serve bottles.
There is a minibar
in the room however.
- all right, a couple steaks then.
- with baked potatoes.
Wraps and salads only
after 11:00.
Buckingham's
is still open though.
You could get some nachos.
Your dad, boy.
Him and me made this
trip a thousand times
back in the '60s.
He had a piece
of that dog track, right?
Among other things.
This one time,
my first trip ever,
we're going
through georgia.
He's got a '59 eldorado
with the fins.
The biarritz,
he used to let me steer.
I'm like 20 at the time,
I'm a kid.
Neveanyway, I'm drivin',
we get pulled over.
State trooper with the hat,
fuckin' sunglasses.
I got no driver's license.
Of course not.
I'm shittin'
a brick.
This is the deep
fuckin' south we're in,
and we're italian.
I turn to your dad...
"what do I tell this prick?"
"relax," he says. "tell him
your cousin's on the job."
he gives me
a southern-sounding name.
The guy comes over.
"oh, my cousin's a state
trooper too," I tell him.
"maybe you know him."
"what's his name?"
"barney fife." pow!
The prick gives me a shot, I
don't know what the fuck hit me.
Your dad's fuckin'
pissing himself.
I mean, I never watch tv.
How the fuck do I know, right?
- so what happened?
- your dad had to "duke" the guy 100 fuckin' dollars.
Probably ath's salary
in those days.
You know, I remember you
around that time.
When I was bad,
my dad used to threaten me
he was gonna get uncle
paulie to come get me.
Fuckin' johnny boy, eh?
He loved you, my friend.
I remember the night
you were born.
Only time
I ever saw him cry.
Heh.
It's funny, you know, I...
Never knew where
I stood with him.
Like he didn't believe
in me or something.
Fucking kidding?
He trusted you enough
to give you
the willie overall thing.
- and you were what, 24?
- 22
so there you go then.
I tell the guy,
I said, "listen,
I don't mind paying
for the tailpipe,
but that fuckin' muffler's
still under warranty."
- all set?
- yeah.
- nice talking to ya.
- yeah, you too.
Enjoy miami.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
- what?
- you tell some fuckin' goober your life story?
We're supposed
to be laying low.
I'm gonna grab
some danish for the road.
- you have shit on your pants, don.
- please be patient with him.
Yes, ma'am.
Visiting day
at the zoo.
Don't feed the chedrools.
- uh, ma.
- how was church?
It was fine.
It was good.
You remember mr. Soprano?
Corrado, please.
Hello, my dear.
- how are you today?
- I'd complain, but who'd listen?
They have me on some new
medication. It makes me salivate.
I'll leave you two to visit.
I have some letters to answer.
- he's a good boy, this one.
- thank you.
I have this new medication they
put me on. It makes me salivate.
How are you feeling?
- fine.
- maybe you can clear something up.
Dr. Mandl says you've been acting
aggressively toward other patients?
First of all, that is
total fucking bullshit.
- carter...
- secondly, why don't you just lead off with that?
What are you
talking about?
Instead of pretending to
give a shit how I feel.
Now, apparently, you are becoming bully.
Dr. Mandl feels you're modeling
your actions on the wrong people.
- ally? Like who?
- you know who. That gangster.
You of all people should know not to
believe what you read in the paper.
All that crap
they wrote about daddy.
That was
"the wall street journal."
it was entirely different.
It's never enough, is it?
My whole time at m.I.t., you told
me to get out and make friends.
Now I finally do learn
to assert myself a little,
suddenly that's a negative.
Checking in... Spears.
- sil.
- I'll get us settled in.
- hey.
- it's not good.
The feds found a body.
Skeleton. They tentatively
I.d.'d it as the guy.
- ah, fuck.
- try and relax, huh?
How's paulie holding up?
Jaws are holding up fine.
He won't shut the fuck up.
- that's too bad.
- what the fuck's he gotta worry about anyway?
Scenario like this, the feds ain't
interested in him, believe me.
Look, I love the guy,
it's just...
- you know how he is.
- believe me, I hear you.
What else?
Let me think.
Um...
I looked in on carm
and she's okay.
All right, thanks.
Call me if you hear anything.
...use your hat!
- "and hope to hear from you soon."
"sincerely... " no.
"respectfully,
corrado soprano."
read it back.
"dear vice president cheney,
as a powerful man all too
familiar with accidental gunplay,
I am writing in the hope that
you will intervene in my case.
Like yourself, I was involved
in an unfortunate incident
- when a gun I was handling misfired."
- head up, yo.
- I's you, I'd lay off the card games awhile.
-  fuck's the matter?
The professor snitched
you out to dr. Mandl.
What do you do
with those, jameel?
Autographed pictures of the
man who capped tony soprano?
Shit, them motherfuckers
go right on ebay.
Come on now, sign.
That was our deal.
You wanna keep
getting them sodas?
Sick fuckin' world.
- for you.
- oh, wow.
I got one
for cristina and gia too.
Thanks.
Where's the dvd?
That never occurred to me.
I'll have sil fedex you one.
- long as you're here.
Salut'.
Hey, listen,
before the girls get here,
remember that cuban guy I was telling
you about? He knocks over trucks.
Last load was
american standard
sinks, toilets, tubs...
- no shit?
- mmm.
- all right, let's talk.
- I'll give you his number, you call him.
Now, check this out.
You're not gonna believe what I found
when we were moving into the new house.
Holy fucking shit.
Mickey pinto
took that in 1963.
Look at that hair.
Handsome fuckin' guy, eh?
That wristband,
the leather thing,
I remember getting
one just like it,
me and all my friends.
Wanted to be a tough guy
just like him.
That big one,
that's your uncle junior
and your old man
in front of satriale's.
There he is.
It's the biarritz.
We were just talking about that.
I tell you what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna have my daughter
scan them into the computer so I
can get a couple of copies for you.
Oh, that's my wife.
I gotta take this.
No, stay, stay.
It's all right, come on.
Uh, I gotta
empty my bag anyway.
Hey, honey, sweetie, h?
- gisays hi, guys.
- hello, gia!
He pisses in a bag now?
Jesus christ,fuckin.
Supporting them with
a huge warehouse covering 28 acres!
Stuffed to the rafters
with over 3,000 products
you can order
at rock bottom prices
and sell for profits
of up to 300% and more.
It's easy to wish
for a better life...
Just pick up the phone and
call this toll-free number... )
- hello.
- junior, it's pat.
You put any thought
to our plan?
What plan?
The dentist,
know, like we said
- who is this?
- it's pat!
The dentis remember? You were
gonna make an appointment.
You sneak me off,
- where would I lam it?
- um... A safe house, I don't know.
The time's not right.
I'm being watched.
Call back later.
- 'cause I'm headed back to sarasota soon...
...free to get started.
They give you plenty of ideas
and support and the
quality of the product
is even better than what you
see in the catalogs.
I decided I wanted something
where I was my own boss...
Back in the day...
'70s... Fuckin' '80s...
You didn't make a move
in north jersey
without this one
up your ass.
I wasn't even born yet.
Please. Wanna talk
about stand-up guys?
Sorry, beans.
Hey, carlo, can we get
some more champagne please?
Hey, remember that
yokel at the feast
mouthing off
to your cousin?
This maniac threw
a vat of hot oil
right from the zeppole
stand on this prick.
Oh my god.
Little powdered sugar,
he would've been done.
And ton', remember
when we all rented
that house
down the shore?
- with the bedbugs?
- summer of '78.
Carlo, silvio,
frankie napoli...
- place up the beach...
- yeah.
...sonny spinz
from the bronx rented it,
that's where
that hippy kid
"mysteriously" drowned
during that party.
Hey ton', you okay?
Yeah yeah.
You sure, T?
Yore being kinda quiet.
That's 'cause...
"remember when" is the lowest
form of conversation.
I told tommy deleo
you're the boss now.
This fucking deleo construction
has always been a problem.
Tell him I personally
am upset.
- nice gravy, huh?
- yeah.
Anyway, yo taste.
How's patricia?
You mind?
Go ahead.
Now I'll start by making a
mountain fold on each corner.
Folding the corners into
the center of the paper...
Touche, "captain blood."
checkers,
the thinking man's game.
You looking for a smack
in the fuckin' mouth?
Corrado?
Language, please.
- what do you want?
- if you'd move, perhaps I could reach the chess set.
And if I don't, what the
fuck are you gonna do then?
- you don't intimidate me.
- corrado!
- you're lucky she's here, you little prick.
- naturally.
You're only toughwhen ty
figure nearby
so things don't go too far.
Oh, how the mighty have f...
Corrado!
Get him! Get him!
How do you like that, huh?
Fuckin' smart guy!
How do you like that!
God, no!
I'm gonna kill this prick.
Would you describe mr.
Soprano as the aggressor?
Is he generally
a troublemaker?
Nah, he cool.
You just gotta know
how to talk to him is all.
That's a lovely watch
you're wearing.
Is that vintage?
Bulova, yeah.
Flea market.
Must have been
quite expensive.
Why am I the only caregiver
being interrogated here?
It wouldn't happen to be because of
the color of my skin, now would it?
Thank you for your
cooperation. You can go.
I'm gonna write a change
order for soprano's meds.
Yeah, I need a bridge loan.
If ya could.
- 200k.
- done.
What can il you?
I've been fucking mush lately.
It happens.
I lost the 1:00 game
by a field goal.
It was a pick 'em. Then the
4:00 game, I'm chasing the money,
I picked
the 49ers minus two.
Ah, fuck it,
you don't want to hear this.
It's been this way
the last couple months though.
- listen, this too shall pass.
- thanks, tateleh.
- any time.
All right.
Is this a nonsmoking room?
Go ahead.
Dinner was fun
the other night.
- yeah.
- how do you know per?
Who peter?
Beansie?
He's an old friend...
From the neighborhood.
So the other guy?
The one with, um...
White hair thingies?
What's his name again?
- paulie.
- right.
What is he,
like, your best friend?
- he say that?
- I just figured.
The way he was talking.
Honestly, I thought heas
your dad at first.
There was a time
when I wished he was.
He... He used to work
for my dad.
I know, he told me.
Corrado?
Corro?
- huh?
- it's time for group.
It's these new pills
last couple of days.
I got no pep.
Oh, that'll change. There's
a slight adjustment period.
But I'm sleeping all the
time now. I can't focus.
Just givit some time,
you'll feel a lot better
and your memory will
improve too.
You know
that's bullshit, right?
They're trying
to numb you out,
'cause of what you did
to the professor.
Where the fuck
is this guy?
West on 84,
beans said, right?
There.
What the fuck is this?
Ho! Ho ho ho!
God damn it.
Who's ramon?
Waiting long?
So everybody come tonight
except charo?
All right, hold
on, hold on, hold on.
I'm tony,
this is paulie.
This is esteban
and the rest of the guys.
So our friend in the wheelchair tells
us you get regular access to goods?
Okay.
I got a trailer
full of power tools,
coming in later on
this month.
Factory-sealed black
and deckers and makitas.
I can get r you
50Ā¢ on the dollar.
60 grand.
Well, 55 would work but that
includes shipping to jersey.
We look
like fucking u.p.s.?
Look, you send the truck up
north, we send it back-loaded.
I got a line on air
mattresses, pool toys,
and I can round the load
out with kerastase,
it's a french shampoo...
$20 a bottle retail.
Now yoget 5%
after sale,
but that's gonna
involve a little trust.
'sta bien.
All right.
We're looking for
a long-term relationship.
- we'll be calling.
- all right.
You okay, tĆ­o?
Corrado, how you
doing today?
I'm dying a slow death,
that's how I'm doing.
Just take
your meds, yo.
Real fucking
nazi now, huh?
Stop fucking pushing!
Ah! I wasn't!
yo, stop bumping
dickheads out there!
You should have
seen him out there.
The fuck can
handle himself.
He's got the gazzis
of a 20-year-old.
He's my friend, but, jesus,
what a fucking chiacchierone.
"yup-yup-yup-
yup-yup-yup."
heells me, "don't say nothing
to nobody." he's got prostate.
I say, "sure."
he tells everybody.
He was always like that.
Nah, he was
gary-fucking-cooper.
You forget.
One time, I fell asleep
while he was on the phone.
I wake up
20 minutes later,
and he was still going.
I gotta say...
It concerns me.
Lately.
Nah.
Come on, huh?
Hey, people live alone,
they get like that. It's sad.
I'm leaving
for my card game.
Are you two okay?
- dinner was great, hon.
- any time, you know that.
Thank you.
That's a great girl
you got there.
The way she stood by you.
Now you see, that's what
paulie doesn't got.
Now I'm speaking
to your point.
He's got no wife.
He's got no kids.
He's got no steady
income stream neither.
Which is coming
to an end. Barone,
I told him, if you
can't show legit income,
you're vulnerable
to the feds.
He don't do
shit about it.
I think you're worrying
for nothing, tony.
Things are going great.
Finally.
Maybe I'm just...
Waiting for the other
shoe to drop.
All I know is,
paulie gualtieri
is a stand-up guy.
Has he ever really been
put the test?
You know, he had this
painting of me in his house.
I was all dressed up
like a fucking general.
I heard out that.
Yeah, it pissed me off.
Thought it was
a fucking joke.
- but I don't think it was.
- he loves you, ton'.
You're all he's got.
You, the guys
and his image.
I love him too.
You always did.
Hey, sil.
I'm here with bobby.
- he just got a call frojenna.
- who?
Karen's sister.
Works in the courthouse.
Oh, yeah yeah.
And?
- are you sitting down?
- just fucking tell me.
Jackie aprile.
- what?
- you heard me.
Larry told them j.a.
Was totally responsible
for e death of a certain
african-american person.
- he covered your
- congratulations, anthony!
Yeah, well...
You got to wonder
what's next, huh?
Yeah,
but for tonight, huh?
All right, thanks.
Talk to you later.
Ha-ha-ha!
We're off the hook
on this willie overall thing.
Oh! Thank god!
That's fucking beautiful.
Yeah.
Know what we ought to do?
We ought to treat ourselves
before we leave.
I was thinking maybe we'd
do some sport fishing.
You serious?
Yeah?
What are you kidding,
the fucking marlin
they got out here?
We'll rent a boat.
Yeah. Sure.
"what's that got to do with
chien farming?" he asks.
The whore says, "last year,
I raised over 5,000 cocks."
- where you going?
- the head. I gotta piss.
- one more?
- yeah. One more.
Two fags decide
they want a baby.
So they jack off
in a cup,
use the sperm to get a lady
friend of theirs pregnant.
Nine months later,
they go to the hospital.
They see all the babies
in the nursery.
"look," they say.
"our baby's the sweetest one.
He's not even
crying at all."
ah... God damn it,
what t fuck is it?
"now he's not crying,"
the nurse says.
"just wait till we take the
pacifier out of his ass."
right, yeah.
Oh, fuck me!
Accident! Accident!
God fucking damn it!
Corrado,
what happened?
Oh, jesus christ
on the cross.
It's all right.
Come on.
I'm an old man. It was an
accident, for christ's sake.
You're on ditropan specifically
to avoid incontinence.
Not to mention celexa, which should
be curtailing your aggressiveness.
I'm taking my medication.
Ask hormel,
you don't believe me.
Jameel.
He's been let go.
Mr. Soprano,
there's a mutual trust
among the staff and our
patients regarding treatment.
That means you
have a choice...
You can either
wear depends
while you await transfer
to another facility,
or you can take your
medication as prescribed.
Here, corrado.
Time for your medicine.
Where the fuck
is my ipod?
Every day it's
your ipod, carter.
Just stop causing
a commotion!
What'd you do that for?
I should piss
myself again?
But I did the thing.
They're muscling me,
what do you want me to tell you?
I could have
gotten in trouble.
You don't even
give a shit.
Let's get
a card game together.
- they fired hormel.
- jameel?
Fuck him! You got me.
Maybe tomorrow, kid.
Don't know. I'm tired.
Old ironsides!
Ho! You're supposed
to say "who, beansie?"
yeah.
Where you been?
You didn't come
to lunch.
I brought you
these...
From keith.
He owed me money.
"hootie
and the blowfish."
thanks.
That was a nice lett
you wrote to cheney.
But he don't
read 'em himself,
they got computers
that do it.
I asked lynch,
the professor.
What are you talking
to him for?
He says we'll have a better chance
if we write him at his outfit...
Halliburton.
My father
owned umman ock.
My grandpa said my dad
lackedharacter.
Grandpa was a lion.
You're very smart,
anthony.
I'm sure you're very
good with spelling too.
Rigatoni a la paulie.
He-he!
But since you're eating it, maybe
it should be "rigatoni a la tony"?
Heh heh.
Ah!
Oh, madonn'!
What?
You're not hungry?
My fucking stomach.
You know, when you
went down below,
I thought I saw
a whale.
- no shit.
- it made me think of ginny sack.
That joke ralph made about
her, that was some funny shit,
no matter what john said.
You got to have
a sense of humor, right?
Yeah.
I heard she took
an office job.
- chubb insurance.
- heh heh!
It was you
told him, right?
I mean, it's no big deal.
I could hardly resist.
Grapevine, ton'.
I don't know.
Yeah.
He was a funny prick,
that ralph.
His "gladiator" fixation,
the time he hit georgie
in the eye with the chain.
Heh heh heh!
I'd have loved to have seen john's
face when he heard that crack.
Always fucking holier-than-thou
'cause he didn't fuck other women.
Mr. Broomstick-up-
his-ass.
Heh heh heh.
You know,
no offense, but... You ever had
yourself checked for tourette's?
What?
Tourette's syndrome...
Seriously.
"heh heh." it's like you
got a tick or something.
I dunno. It's like some
people grind their teeth.
When I'm nervous...
Tense or something.
Come on, you told
john about that joke, right?
- it wasn't me, ton'.
- no?
That's right.
You want a drink?
All right, stewarts.
- think fast!
- jesus! Ton'!
Fuck, that hurt.
What does it take
to get something to eat?
When my time comes,
tell me,
will I stand up?
Who was at the door?
"williams-sonoma.
From paulie.
The elektra semiautomatic
chrome espresso machine."
4a>od2- so?
- my god, tony.
This is, like, $2,000.
I mean, what is
wrong with that man?
What's wrong with him?
Nothing.
It's guys like him that allows
our whole lifestyle here.
Take me over
to jeanette's house.
Ah!
In an apparent escalation
of a mafia power struggle...
What year? Let me see,
'72, '73, back in
the feech lamanna days.
I'm on a roll. I mean, I haven't
lost a bet in fucking months.
...after a brazen
ambush by...
Hey, ton',
you see this shit?
Skip.
Hey.
Looks like phil's the main
guinea over there now, huh?
Anyway, we're at
maxwell's plum,
the saturday night
before the game.
Who walks in
but fucking namath?
Three sheets to the wind, fuckin'
staggering like aailor.
So I know the game is
going into the toilet.
I said to
my brother jerry...
He was just
a kid at the time...
"take this money down
to old caruso on the corner
and put it all
against the jets."
my brother was just recovering
from rheumatic fever...