Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People!
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?!
Are you worried?
KIRA'S IDENTITY
The victim was Mr. H...
at someone's face like Second Kira...
Matsuda will die.
It's him!
Don't screw around! Remember
the names of the people you hire!
I still have two hours.
I've confirmed Higuchi.
He's only got a bag on him.
I'm going after him.
I will... kill him...
Everything will be mine!
FRENZY
Cosme Misa...
Devilish charm...
Angelic shine...
- Misa's winning rouge...
- The commercial's going to end, Ryuzaki.
Oh, really?
If I reveal too much detail,
the people who were there
will know who Kira is...
So... I can't say any more.
Yes. Let's save that
revelation until the end.
Make speaker one Higuchi's car
and speaker two Sakura TV.
Higuchi's glued to
the TV in his car.
According to what you said earlier,
you've met Kira?
Yes. But at that time,
I didn't know who Kira was.
I think it takes
a lot of courage to appear
even though he's seen your face...
Are you sure about this?
Yes. As I was investigating,
I discovered the two things
that Kira needs to kill.
There are many rumors as
to what they might be,
but I've found out for sure.
A face and a name...
But Kira only knows one
of those things about me.
He feels safe enough to step forward
because he thinks he won't be killed
just because I don't know
his real name, huh?
Does that mean that there's nothing
remaining that connects him to his name?
If he already took his records
into account...
does that mean it's pointless
to go to Yoshida Productions?
Rem... What do you think?
What do I think? About what?
Who's Rem?
He's in his car by himself.
I don't think that there's
anyone else in that car.
He isn't using his cell phone either.
Could it be a radio or
something?
No. There's no radio in that car.
Only our wire-taps, cameras,
and tracking devices.
That was Wedy's job,
so I'm completely sure of it.
Could it be that there won't be
a record on him
even if I go to Yoshida Productions?!
Is he talking to himself?
There's no way I would know.
If he's smart,
he would've destroyed everything
that connected him to his name
before appearing on TV.
Also, don't you think that
it's suspicious
for Yoshida Productions to just
let me into their offices?
No, in this case, if there was a robbery,
the culprit would be me...
This sounds kind of bad...
It's all right. He'll go.
Even if he does have a record
at Yoshida Productions,
what if it's filed under an alias?
Yes, there's a big possibility
that he'd go that far...
It's probably Light and Misa's plan
to have Higuchi go
to Yoshida Productions...
But if he knows that you're Kira,
then he'll end up announcing
your name.
That is an inescapable fact.
All right, there's only an hour
left until the announcement.
You have to go.
Whether there's an alias on
his record or not...
there's no way that
you'll be suspected
if you kill him with
the Death Note.
Yeah. I know.
But just in case,
I should kill the people I called
from Yoshida Productions,
Misa, and her manager.
What?! No way, he said he'll kill me!
It's all right. He means after
he's killed Mr. Matsuda.
There's no point for him to do
that unless he's killed Mr. Matsuda.
That's true, but...
Think hard. You only have to kill him.
If you kill the people whom
you just called,
your call history
will implicate you.
Oh yeah...
Rem, you're really smart...
I'll kill them after
I erase my call history.
But the telephone company
will still have a record of it.
He can't be talking to himself...
Who's "Rem"? Who is he talking to?
If he is talking to someone,
it would have to be with...
A Shinigami...
“perhaps?
Maybe I should ask him...
How about returning ownership
of the notebook to me?
No. That would only
end miserably for me.
He says he has proof.
If he were to highlight
Yotsuba's growth,
no one would doubt him.
The person he says is Kira
will be marked as Kira.
Even if he doesn't have clear proof,
my life will be over...
I won't be promoted.
I won't even be able
to stay with Yotsuba...
We, at Sakura,
have structured this show
under the premise that
Kira is watching.
I will now speak directly to Kira...
Kira, turn yourself in.
He acts like an idiot,
but earlier, he faked his own death
by making it seem like he died...
I've got to kill him.
He's arrived at Yoshida Productions.
It's about to begin...
To the left of the entrance...
In the desk farthest back...
In the bottom drawer...
MANAGER
TAICHIRO YAMASHITA
Now then, show me how you kill!
I'm ready to apprehend Higuchi.
- Just give me the signal.
- All right.
TAICHIRO YAMASHITA
It's no good! He just made a note
of his name and is leaving.
He's not going to kill him here?
Ryuzaki! Shall I apprehend him?
I still don't know how he kills.
He might do something in his car.
Turn monitor one to Higuchi's car.
Higuchi is awfully calm despite wanting
to kill Matsuda as soon as possible...
You're right.
If he needed a name,
then he should have taken
the personnel file with him...
But he just put it back
in the drawer.
36... 37... 38...
39...
40 seconds...
Kira is a murderer,
so I cannot forgive him.
Damn it! Why isn't he dead?!
What does that mean?!
He said, "why isn't he dead?"
Did he already try to kill?
Was writing his name all
he had to do to kill?
What are you going to do?
Are you going to just
keep watching what he does?
It seems like he can will
a person to die
with just that person's name...
What's going on?
I can't determine how
he kills people...
But if I try to restrain him now
and try to get him to confess...
There are only ﬁfty minutes
until the Kira announcement!
Damn! I don't have any time!
He's making a phone call.
He's probably trying Misa again.
You're right!
C'mon!
I know his face...
If I go back to the ofﬁce,
there should be surveillance camera
videos of him sneaking in...
If I just had the Shinigami eyes...
Half of my remaining life, huh?
But if he makes the announcement,
my life is ﬁnished.
Well then, better to have a life
that's short and sweet.
Rem. Let's make the deal.
Deal? Who is this "Rem"
he's been talking to all this time?
Could Kira's power be
from heaven or something?
I don't want to think
that's the case.
Then what is Rem?
A Shinigami?
At any rate, we should watch him.
It looks like we can
still find out more.
We may be able to
find out how he kills.
Now I'm unstoppable...
With this, I have unlimited options.
I'm going after him!
Stop your car!
Pull over to the side of the road.
Pull over and stop!
This is bad. Higuchi has been
caught by a motorcycle policeman.
I'm going to pass him by.
I'll leave this to Aiber
and the others.
You were speeding.
Show me your driver's license!
Yeah... all right.
All screens on Higuchi's car...
Where did I put my license...?
I can't waste time
sticking around here.
YUKITO SHIRABA ACCIDENT
Hey!
Higuchi ditched the motorcycle cop
and is on the run!
What a bastard!
This is highway patrol...
The motorcycle cop just
rear-ended a truck! It's a collision!
A collision?! An accidental death?
This is bad.
Higuchi put his hand in his bag...
Did he do something then?
No, that aside, how did he obtain
the name of that
motorcycle cop?
Could it be that he killed him by
looking at his face like the Second Kira?
Rem... Deal...
No... If he could kill by just
looking at someone's face...
he should have immediately
killed Mr. Matsuda.
What's going on? But...
Everyone! It's too dangerous to
allow further action by Higuchi!
We will proceed to capture him.
Higuchi is now able to kill just
by looking at someone's face,
like the Second Kira.
We will capture him
with that in mind!
Watari, connect me to
the Director of the NPA.
Yes.
This is L. We have narrowed down
Kira to a single person.
Currently, he's heading from
Hibiya to Shibuya
on Highway Route One in
a red sports car.
We shall capture him.
So please instruct all units
not to approach that car.
Dad, after the next commercial,
commence stage seven.
All right.
Demegawa, during
the next commercial,
switch Matsuda and
the emcee with mannequins...
We'll make it seem as if
the broadcast is still continuing
using the audio we've prepared.
We'll leave the cameras
and everyone will withdraw.
Then Yagami, shall we go?
Yeah.
Sorry Misa, but I'm going to
restrain you for a while.
What?! What's this?!
Stop kidding around.
Ryuzaki, I never knew you
could pilot a helicopter.
It's just intuition...
Higuchi isn't heading
towards Sakura TV.
He's going the wrong way.
By his route, I'd say he's headed
to Yotsuba's main offices.
That's incredible courage.
No, I just did what
was appropriate.
If I go to the main ofﬁces
and ﬁnd a surveillance video
with him on it, I can kill him...
Wedy, everything relating to Matsuda
at Yotsuba's main offices
has been disposed of, right?
Yes. Is he headed there?
How convenient.
That'll give me time to
go ahead of him
and wait with Mr. Yagami.
Damn it! He's nowhere!
No, he's been erased from
these videos...
Did he come and erase himself?
Or has someone betrayed me...
No, doing that would not
absolve them of their crimes.
At any rate, I don't have time.
I've got to hurry!
The time for the announcement
is fast approaching.
Yes. I feel like saying it already.
I understand your feelings, but...
We'll have just one more
commercial break right now...
Damn it!
I'll just have to go to
Sakura TV and kill him.
Dad, Higuchi will arrive
at Sakura TV soon.
He'll be there in less than 15 minutes.
Are you all right?
I don't want my son to
ask me if I'm all right.
I'm all right, Light.
Is there anything more you want to
say before the announcement?
Well... I want everyone to think
about Kira after he's caught.
- Mr. Yagami, it's almost time...
- Kira is definitely evil.
Yeah...
Here...
Aiber hates guns,
so I'm the only one with one...
I'm no longer a police officer.
I'm not allowed to have this.
You're also not allowed to
use this in Japan.
Stubborn as usual, aren't you?
SAKURA TV
I made it!
Why isn't anyone here?
Are they being careful because
they're broadcasting the truth?
Oh well, this'll be easier
since no one's here.
We've arrived at Sakura TV.
I'm getting into position.
Let's go, Aiber.
Okay, Mogi!
We're getting lots of phone calls
and faxes showing support...
for what you're doing here.
Even the studio is empty?
Still, I've got to watch out
for the television cameras.
I'm sorry,
but due to certain circumstances,
- we must end this program here.
- What?!
Mannequins!
No way?!
Stop right there, Higuchi!
Don't move!
Give yourself up.
You must be making
some kind of mistake.
I have a meeting
with Mr. Demegawa and...
They're wearing helmets.
They've taken precautions
against Kira.
In that case...
I'm from Yotsuba Group's
development department...
Let me get you my card.
Chief!
Aiber!
Damn it!
I didn't want to use this, but...
Higuchi has a gun!
The Chief has been shot.
Higuchi is making an escape!
I'm all right. Sorry, Ryuzaki.
If we pursue him,
we can still catch him. Hurry!
This is bad.
He's escaped from Sakura TV!
We have no choice.
We shall proceed to capture
him as well.
Watari, are you ready?
- Yes...
- Yagami...
Hold on to this for self-defense.
It's Kira we're after.
No. Those aren't allowed
in Japan.
I'm sure Mr. Yagami
said the same thing.
Yeah...
What insane driving!
- Don't lose sight of him!
- Okay!
What was going on earlier?
I can only think
that was a trap...
We now end our current broadcast
to bring you the news.
The program ended,
but I wasn't the one who ended it...
Damn it... Who in the...
What is this?!
So it was a trap...
Police cars with tinted windows?
So the police were
still going after Kira!
What is going on? I told the police
not to take any action.
The only one who would do this is...
Yes... you're right.
Damn it!
I'll go this way!
Stop right there!
Don't come any closer!
Don't you come near me!
It's over...
Yes. It is...
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A ﬂeeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they driveled
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
This note will not take effect unless
the writer has the person's face
in their mind when
writing his/her name.
Therefore, people sharing
the same name will not be affected.