Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
LOVE
YAGAMI
If you're interested,
come here immediately.
Okay, Dad.
Just as I was thinking about
how to get in...
I never thought L himself
would ask me.
Now I can get inside information
about the investigation...
and about the fake Kira.
I need to ﬁnd out about Fake Kira
before anyone else at
task force headquarters does...
Thank you, Yagami.
Not at all.
Ryuga, we both want to catch Kira.
Please call me Ryuzaki here.
I'm Matsui.
I'm Aihara.
And I'm Asahi...
I see.
Well, would it be all right if
I'm Light Asahi?
Please do. I will call you Light here.
Now onto business.
Please take a look at
our current information on Kira.
I also want you to examine this video,
which was sent to the television station...
but was never released to the public.
Taking any material from this room
or taking notes is forbidden.
I understand.
We shall now begin.
Light...
THE PREVIOUS NIGHT
and ask Light Yagami
to investigate with us.
B- But wouldn't that make it difficult
for Light to help with the investigation?
That's right. Why do you want him
to work with us anyway?
We're only going
to hide that from him...
until we have him watch this tape
and ask him for his impression of it.
There's something amazing
about Light's reasoning skills.
When he sees this,
he may even deduce that
there is a second Kira.
But the only basis for
a second Kira is your explanation
that the victims of those killings
had committed minor crimes
that never would have been
punished by Kira.
That's not all.
The Kira that we've presumed until now
needed a face and a name to kill.
But judging from the fact that
Mr. Ukita was killed
as soon as he arrived at
the television station,
and considering how Kira practically
told me that he could kill me
if "L" appeared on
means that the Second Kira can kill
by just seeing someone's face.
So, I'll ask Light to look
at the investigative facts and the video.
If he suggests that there may
be a second Kira,
then he's almost completely cleared.
Ryuzaki, what do you mean?
If he's Kira, he'll want to kill me,
the one in charge of
the investigation.
At this rate, if I go along with
the Second Kira's demands
and appear three days later on TV,
I will die.
I don't think that Kira would miss
an easy chance to kill me.
So what you're saying is that
if my son doesn't deduce that
there is a second Kira,
then you'll continue to suspect him?
No. In that case, it will remain below
a five-percent chance.
And we'll tell him that
we are investigating the possibility of
a second Kira and have him assist us.
I trust you now believe
that I'm Kira.
- Could it be that the reason...
- On the given day and time...
why I feel so disgusted
when I watch this...
is because I'm the real Kira?
This is about more than just
tarnishing Kira's reputation.
So why isn't...
...anyone giving me any explanation
about this video?
That's strange...
Well, whatever the case,
I won't say anything careless
about this video.
If I leave the situation alone,
L will die.
Light, what do you think?
Did you get something from it?
Hmm?
Damn him!
There may be more than one person
who has Kira's power.
Kira's power?!
Light, what do you mean?!
There is a good chance that
this is not the Kira
we've known up to now.
Up to now, Kira's never used suspects
like these for his announced killings.
And if Kira needs a face
and a name to kill...
isn't it strange that he was able
to kill the detective and officers
who happened to go to
the television studios?
It's the same.
It's exactly the same deduction as L,
I mean Ryuzaki.
You did well, Light.
You should be cleared now...
That's right, Light.
I also think we are looking
at a second Kira.
I thought so...
So you knew, Ryuga,
I mean Ryuzaki?
Did you test me, knowing that?
I didn't test you.
It's not convincing if I'm the only one
who argues that there is a second Kira.
With you coming to
the same conclusion as I did,
my theory becomes more believable.
You've been of great assistance to me,
Light. Thank you so much.
So, it's decided.
We first have to stop the second Kira.
He obviously sympathizes with Kira,
and is not very bright.
I think he'll obey the real Kira.
So if we make a fake message
from the real Kira,
there is a good chance that
we can stop him.
As I expected of you, Ryuzaki.
I also thought that would
be the best idea.
Light...
I would like you to play
the part of the real Kira.
M- Me?
Yes. With your abilities,
you should be able to do it.
At any rate, we don't have
any time to waste.
Could you script a message
from Kira...
to air on tonight's news?
Damn him...
He planned from the beginning
to bring me here to play this role.
Ryuzaki, is this all right?
I think I've portrayed
Kira convincingly.
I think this is very good,
but if we don't remove the part
which says, "You're free to kill L,"
I'll die.
Well, when pretending to be Kira,
I thought that he would
demand that "L" be killed.
It's just a bit of a joke.
You can change that to
whatever you like.
Yes.
Mr. Aihara, the script is ready.
I leave it to you.
All right.
And now a shocking development.
In response to the video that was sent
and aired on Sakura TV a few days ago,
another person claiming to be
the real Kira has appeared.
He has ordered several
television stations to air his message.
The police department has
authorized us to broadcast this video.
Is this the real Kira?
Is this another Kira?
First, please take a look at the video.
I am Kira.
I did it! Kira responded!
I am the real Kira.
The Kira who was on Sakura TV
a few days ago is not.
I will show leniency
to the impostor
because I am assuming he did it
out of an attempt to help me.
But killing the innocent is
against my beliefs.
If the impostor truly sympathizes
with me and wants to help my cause...
I ask that he refrain from killing aimlessly
and accept my basic principles.
- If you ignore this warning...
- All right! The video, the video!
- and continue to be reckless...
- What are you planning to do?
I'm going to reply to him,
of course.
SEVERAL DAYS LATER
- What?!
- It's here!
I will bring the entire
envelope there, but...
for the time being, I'll play
a copy through the computer.
Mr. Kira, thank you for your reply.
I will do as you say.
- Wow!
- We did it!
"I will do as you say," huh?
I don't know if I can use him.
If he really knows Kira's feelings,
he would force L to appear
on TV and kill him.
Don't fall for something like this...
Damn it!
I want to meet you.
I don't think you have the eyes, but...
I won't try to kill you.
Please don't worry.
Is he stupid?
He talked about the Shinigami eyes
on a tape the whole world will see?
He just said that he didn't
have "the eyes," didn't he?
What could that mean?
Who knows...?
Please think of a We y We can meet
Without the police knowing.
When we meet,
we can conﬁrm each other,
by showing our Shinigami.
Shinigami?!
He's no good.
I have to do something fast
about this guy, or else...
What?!
Ryuzaki!
Are you all right?!
Sh...
Shini... garni?!
Are we supposed to accept
the existence of something like that?
Shinigami?
Are we supposed to accept
the existence of something like that?
Impossible...
There's no such thing...
That's right, Ryuzaki.
Shinigami don't exist.
Kira had those criminals in prison
write something about Shinigami...
So shouldn't we assume that
this is the same Kira?
It's the same person,
so they say the same things.
That can't be, Dad.
If this is the same Kira from before,
he wouldn't have replied to our video.
There is no way that the real Kira
would go through the trouble
of getting L to appear on TV,
only to stop trying to kill him.
Then maybe the real Kira and
the Second Kira...
already have established
a connection.
And decided to use the word "Shinigami"
to throw off the investigation.
That's also not possible.
It's as Light says.
If the two Kiras were connected,
I don't think that he would stop
trying to kill me.
Second Kira is acting
independent of the first.
They want to meet the real Kira.
That's right. They're acting
out of interest in Kira.
"Shinigami" probably refers to
their killing power.
"We can confirm our identities by showing
our Shinigami to each other,"
probably means...
"We can confirm our identities by
showing each other our killing power. "
That's right.
The word "Shinigami" is
a word that has
some meaning between
Kira and Second Kira.
We should try to get him to
tell us what it means.
So are you going to respond
and force him to be more direct?
If we don't ask him properly,
he'll know that we're not Kira.
No, I shall leave the rest to
Kira and Second Kira.
Leave it to them?
We can assume the second Kira is
satisfied after receiving a reply from Kira.
He thinks that
he's got Kira's attention.
And he also used a word that
only the two of them would understand.
This reply will air today on
Sakura TV's six o'clock news.
Of course, Kira should be watching
the exchange
between our made-up Kira
and the Second Kira.
From Kira's viewpoint, he'll want
to prevent the Second Kira from coming
into direct contact with the police.
Maybe this time,
the real Kira will respond.
But what if Kira doesn't reply?
Yes... I thought of what we could do
with the Second Kira in that case, but...
If he reveals more information that
Kira doesn't want the police to know,
and makes Kira more nervous
and furious,
in order to pressure Kira
into meeting him...
That would be interesting.
It would be more interesting...
if Kira gets scared and sends a reply
in order to avoid that.
Then there's a chance we could obtain
some physical evidence from Kira himself.
In the meantime,
let's focus on gathering all the information
we can from the Second Kira's package.
That's good...
Just like that!
That was great, just great, Misa.
That was wonderful!
I'm worn out...
Modeling sure uses a lot of energy!
Hey, Rem.
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Shinigami always have to have
a Death Note.
Soto give one to a human
to play with,
the Shinigami needs to have
two Death Notes...
That means that Ryuk,
who gave the extra Death Note to Kira,
was able to trick the Shinigami King
and get two, right?
Right.
Then you too?
No. The Shinigami King
isn't fooled that easily.
Then how?
I'll just say... I'm one of the few
in the Shinigami Realm
who know how to kill a Shinigami.
Oh, then you killed a Shinigami
and gave his notebook to me.
No. I didn't kill him.
I just happened to be around
when a Shinigami died...
So, tell me how to kill a Shinigami.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
The way to kill a Shinigami...
is to make them fall
in love with a human.
What a beautiful way to kill.
There once was a Shinigami
named Gelus
who used to watch a girl
from the Shinigami Realm.
Gelus was always looking
at that girl from the Shinigami Realm.
It's today, isn't it?
The end of her life.
She looks so healthy.
Why today?
Why...
today?
I wanted to know how
she was going to die too,
and decided to watch with him.
The girl was walking alone
at night on the street.
And then...
Suddenly from an alley,
a man appeared and confessed
his love for the girl.
I love you more
than anyone else in the world!
I'm always watching you!
I want to protect you forever!
It was a man she didn't know.
The girl turned him down, of course.
Then... I'll kill you...
Then kill myself-!
H- Hey.
Stop!
Gelus did something that
a Shinigami should never do.
Gelus used his Death Note
to save the girl.
But that was not good.
Shinigami shorten human lives.
They only exist to take lives.
At that moment,
Gelus became something which was
neither sand nor rust, and died.
Only his Death Note was left.
Then Gelus' remaining life span was
transferred to the girl whose life he saved.
Does that mean that the Shinigami
wouldn't have died
if he hadn't fallen in love
with that girl?
That's right.
So...
It was a Shinigami named Gelus
who saved me that day.
Yes.
Gelus was in love with you.
So that notebook is yours.
Yeah...
I see. In order to kill a Shinigami
you need him to fall in love with
a human and save that person.
What about you, Rem?
Are you in love with me?
Give it up. You can't kill me.
Oh? You figured it out?
But now I have something
I can tell Kira.
I wonder if he knows?
How to kill a Shinigami?
I asked him on TV,
"Please tell me how I can meet you,"
but he hasn't replied.
Maybe I should send him
another message.
This isn't good...
I can't leave the Second Kira
alone like this.
If the Second Kira makes
a fatal slip-up
and is caught by the police,
there is a chance that the police
will find out about the Death Note.
Welcome.
A strawberry sundae, please.
Certainly.
So what should I do?
How can I contact the Second Kira
without L noticing?
Thank you for waiting.
I want to meet Kira soon!
But at any rate...
What kind of a person are you,
Fake Kira?
What kind of a person are you, Kira?
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
If Fake Kira is caught, I'll have to
get my hands on his notebook.
In the worst case scenario,
I may have to kill everyone there.