Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
OVERCAST
Regardless of how she came to
her conclusion,
she knows the truth.
If she gives this information
to the police...
they'll ﬁgure out that
Light Yagami equals Kira.
I have to ﬁnish her off.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing...
I've been going over
what you just told me
and I think that we should investigate
that theory as soon as possible.
Really?
Yes.
Have you told this to anyone else?
No, you're the first.
You're lucky.
But how are you going to
eliminate her?
Wouldn't it be bad
if you did it here?
I've already ﬁgured that out...
without you telling me.
Wow! So out in the open.
Could you tell me the date
and time of the bus-jacking incident?
It was on December 20,
in front of Asagao Hill.
At 11:02.
Headed to Space Land.
December 20.
Headed to Space Land, right?
Yes.
SHOKO MAKI
SUICIDE JANUARY 1, 2007
COMMITS SUICIDE IN A WAY THAT NOBCDDY VVILL BE INCONVENIENCED AND HER BODY
WILL NOT BE DISCOVERED. DIES BY IMPLEMENTING THIS PLAN WITHIN 48 HOURS.
Now no one will ﬁnd her body.
Even if they do ﬁnd her,
they'll assume that she killed herself
because of her ﬁance.
Ryuk, what's so funny?
I'm very sorry for questioning
all of you individually.
Kira is not one of us.
Ryuzaki, how can you definitely
say that he's not among us?
To be honest, I set some traps
to check if you were Kira, but...
I didn't feel the need to
set them on any of you.
Excuse me.
After he told us to
turn off our cell phones...!
I got it.
I'm just about finished.
Enter with your key.
Watari is on his way.
I understand.
If it's all right,
I'll report this incident.
No, I'd like to report it myself.
After talking to you, I've decided to
do it as soon as possible.
I suppose you're right.
Just ten seconds until 1:15...
I want to see how this woman dies,
but I can't be caught following her.
Go on.. hurry to your death!
Kira will definitely
be caught, won't he?
What's wrong? The time has passed...
That's odd.
Why isn't this woman leaving?
My tests have proved that
I've proved many times that
I should be able
to control her within
these circumstances.
$0 Why?
Ryuk...
Come to think of it,
he was laughing oddly when
I was writing in the Death Note...
That's not all.
The way he laughed when I asked
for her name was also bizarre...
Both were times when something had
to do with her name...
An alias!
Thank you all for working so hard.
T- This person is Watari?
Um, where are your usual clothes?
If I had dressed like I usually do,
it would be like telling everyone
I'm Watari.
It would also give away Ryuzaki's
location in this hotel.
|- | see.
Showing my face in front of you
all means you've won Ryuzaki's trust.
|- | feel kind of honored...
Ryuzaki, I've brought what
you've requested.
Please pass them out to everyone.
Yes.
These are everyone's new police IDs.
New?
An alias.
That's the only thing it could be!
Ryuk can see her real name.
That's why he was laughing.
This woman was being careful
from the start.
That's right.
She believes that Raye died...
because he showed his ID.
That's why she's acting without
revealing her identity.
This isn't good.
It's even harder to ask
for the real name
of someone who has already
given an alias.
If I keep asking her persistently,
she'll get suspicious.
More importantly, it's suspicious
that I knew she was using an alias.
I should be getting back soon.
Someone might have come back.
Oh, yeah.
I suppose you're right.
Hopefully, someone did.
Yes.
Damn it...!
It would also be unnatural
to try to turn her back.
What should I do? At this rate...
Oh no...
If my father calls...
I promised her that I'd let her
talk to him!
It's all over if he calls!
What do I do?
What am I thinking about?
I can just turn off my cell phone.
Calm down.
I just have to ﬁnd out her name.
Her purse, her pocket,
she's got to have a driver's license...
or some sort of personal ID
on her somewhere.
She's a woman.
If it comes down to it,
I can use force...
That's stupid!
I can '1' do anything that'll
cause a stir here- -.
I've got to get her to
somewhere isolated.
Where? What explanation
can I offer...
...this extremely cautious woman?
No, I've got to change
my plan of attack...
I can do this.
I can get her name without
setting any alarms off.
Light.
We can do that eye deal anytime...
It's no different from putting
on contact lenses.
It takes just a few seconds.
I won't have my remaining life
halved by the likes of this woman.
No, I won't ever consider the deal!
Don't bother me.
Shut up, Shinigami!
Excuse me.
Yes?
Do you still have business
at the police department?
I'll be all right by myself.
I understand.
Our names and ranks are all fake.
Fake police IDs?!
Kira requires a name
and a face to kill.
We are challenging Kira
with that premise in mind.
This is only natural.
B- But a police officer
with a fake ID is...
No, if Kira needs a name to kill,
an alias would go a long way
in protecting our lives.
We should carry these around.
I think so, too.
Yeah.
When you have to give out
your name to strangers,
use the alias in your IDs.
Yes.
Please be careful not to use them
inside the police headquarters.
It could cause problems.
Understood.
Well then...
I want everyone to wear these belts.
Belts?
There is a tracking device
in the buckle.
This way, Ryuzaki will know
your whereabouts.
And when you press
the buckle twice...
My cell phone will ring.
And I'll call you back immediately.
In the morning, you will go to work
at the police department.
Later, using this method...
I shall confirm our hotel
and room number.
Please use this
for emergencies as well.
This is kind of cool.
It's like we're a special force
chasing Kira!
Matsuda!
This isn't child's play.
Don't joke around.
Okay.. -
Thank you very much.
Thanks to you, I have gained
confidence in my theory.
Not at all...
Since Ryuk brought up the eye deal...
There's no doubt.
She's using an alias.
At this rate, with her theory that
Kira was on the bus...
and given the people Raye Penber
was tasked to investigate,
the police will immediately suspect me.
Hey, she's leaving.
Is that okay?
It should be about ﬁve minutes until
she reaches the police headquarters...
Think...
How can I get her name
within ﬁve minutes?
She's going to
the police headquarters.
If someone from the task force
has returned, I'm ﬁnished.
Somehow, I've got to ﬁnd out
her real name and eliminate her...
Now there are only three minutes until
she reaches the police headquarters.
All right.
What are you going to do?
Excuse me.
Yes?
There's something I haven't told you.
Okay.. -
It's impossible to contact anyone
directly in headquarters.
I have to conduct this conversation
naturally and
connect it to something
that she'll latch onto.
Within that time,
I'll draw out her name.
I can do this.
What do you mean?
Don't you think that it's odd
that there's no one at headquarters?
Y- Yes.
I thought it was strange, but...
The team investigating Kira is structured
so no one knows who is involved.
If the general public knows how
the team is structured,
a tragedy like the one involving
your fiancé may happen again...
I understand.
That's why you were told
that no one was at the headquarters.
In other words,
you will never be allowed to talk
directly to someone from headquarters.
That's good, Light.
Why do you know so much?
She's pretty sharp.
I guess I have no choice.
I shall tell you...
It's because I'm a member of
the task force.
You're part of the task force?
Yes.
L is currently in charge
of the task force.
Yes, I thought so.
L was troubled because there weren't
enough detectives at headquarters.
Many quit because
they're afraid of Kira.
I'm just a high school student, but...
I've helped the police
solve two cases in the past.
So he was convinced by that...?
I can enter the headquarters
whenever I wish,
and I'm allowed to investigate
on my own.
In other words, the people who
are currently at task force headquarters...
are the chosen few who...
are trusted and highly qualified
I understand.
But just in case,
I think I'll visit the headquarters.
Thank you very much.
Please wait!
I just told you that
you can't talk to anyone.
I would like to talk directly to L.
Come to think of it,
who's at headquarters now?
Right now, no one.
That's not good.
Have at least one person
there at all times.
Understood.
Aizawa, if you could
stay there for today...
Okay. I can get there
quickly from here.
Ms. Maki, please wait.
It's impossible to meet L.
It's useless.
He might... allow me to meet him.
What?
I only followed his orders from
beyond a computer screen, but...
Two years ago in America
I worked on a case under L.
You worked under L?
Until three months ago,
I was an FBI agent.
This is it...
I can use this.
Is that so?
It's no wonder. Your actions are
not amateurish.
You move carefully and wisely
as you get to the heart of the matter.
I'd like to learn from you.
It's amazing how you can
line up all those lies like that.
I must approach this case
in my own way.
I have to suspect the police
and even the people within task force.
But I trust L.
I thought that
if I went to headquarters
and have them verify my name and face...
I'd be able to speak directly to L.
I see...
But why did you tell me that
you wanted to talk to L?
When I wasn't allowed to see
someone from the task force,
I was angry and then
I ran into someone
who claimed to be
the son of the lead detective...
No, that's not it.
I'll tell you the truth.
You seemed like L.
I felt that you two are similar.
Shall we investigate
the case together?
Huh?
Will you work as
a member in the task force?
Of course,
not just anybody is allowed.
But we need people like you!
You could be doing more than
gathering general information.
You were an FBI agent.
You're more talented than
our current detectives.
Even L trusted you.
To join the task force,
you need proper identification,
a recommendation from
a current detective on the team,
and finally L's permission.
You want me to join
the task force?
It's fate that we met here!
I'll recommend you!
Oh, sorry.
I just got a little excited...
N- No, it's okay...
Even if you can cooperate
with the investigation,
I understand you have personal
circumstances to attend to.
Especially since you live in America...
I was planning to continue living
with my fiancé in America,
he and I were to be
married this spring.
But now that he's dead...
I have no idea what I'll do now...
All right...
I've come this far,
I just have to push a little bit...
But you're still very young
and beautiful.
You shouldn't be involved
in such a dangerous investigation...
No! I don't have anything to lose.
I want to catch Kira!
It's all I want to do!
Please let me investigate with you!
Thank goodness.
Well, may I see something that may act
as some form of personal ID?
Well...
Yes?
Actually, that name I gave you earlier
was not my real name...
I'm very sorry.
That's all right.
Amazing! Who would have thought
you were being so careful?
You're one step ahead of me.
That's even further proof
that you're qualified.
Is a Japanese driver's license okay?
Yes.
I made it...
NAOMI MISORA DOB 2/11/1979
NAOMI MISORA SUICIDE 1/1/2007 COMMITS SUICIDE IN A WAY THAT NOBODY WILL BE INCONVENIENCED
AND HER BODY VVILL NOT BE DISCOVERED. DIES BY IMPLEMENTING THIS PLAN WITHIN 48 HOURS.
Excuse me, but why do you
keep looking at your watch?
Oh... this?
It's because...
I'm Kira.
What's the matter?
There's something I have to do.
Oh.
My father's cell phone is on now.
Don't you want to talk to him?
I have nothing I want to talk about.
Good bye, Miss Naomi Misora.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
that I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
I can kill criminals
currently being broadcast...
while masquerading as
a regular high school student.
Just watch, L!