Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
ALLY
Oh yeah! I gotta take off the belt.
What? Again?
He'll just have to get used
to our security system.
Enough!
How's this?!
Good morning!
What happened to your forehead?
Oh... this?
Well, I had a fight with
my wife and...
my kid is still young...
so it looks like I'll be commuting.
Yeah. You should live at home.
What a waste...
These rooms are amazing.
You should move here
with your whole family.
Don't lump me in with
a carefree bachelor like you.
Where's Ryuzaki?
He's on a date, the three of them
are in Misa-Misa's room.
Surveillance cameras, huh?
Well, I guess it can't be helped
since we believe that Amane
might be involved with second Kira...
And Matsuda,
stop calling her Misa-Misa!
Oh... yes.
Hey... this...
doesn't feel like a date.
Pay no attention to me...
Anyways, are you going to
eat that piece of cake?
Sweets are fattening,
so I try not to eat them too much.
If you use your head,
you can still eat sweets
without gaining weight.
Hey! You're making fun
of me again!
I'll give you the cake.
So will you leave me
alone with Light?
Even if I leave you two alone,
I'll be watching with
the surveillance cameras.
It's the same thing.
You pervert!
Will you stop doing sick things?
Call me whatever you like.
But I'm taking your cake.
Fine! I'll just close the curtains
and turn off the lights.
We also have infrared cameras.
Changing the subject...
Despite moving into fully
equipped headquarters,
you don't seem
very enthusiastic, Ryuzaki.
Enthusiasm, huh?
I don't have any
Actually, I'm kind of depressed.
You're depressed?
Yes...
All this time I thought
that you were Kira...
I'm just shocked that
my deduction was wrong.
But, I'm still suspicious of you,
hence these.
Kira can control people's actions...
In other words,
Kira was controlling you to
make me suspect that you were Kira.
You and Misa were both
controlled by Kira.
When I think about that,
everything matches up...
By that reasoning,
Misa and I were controlled,
but doesn't that still mean
that we're Kira?
Yes, I don't think
I'm wrong about that.
You're both Kira.
I think that when you were confined,
you were Kira.
And while you were confined,
criminals stopped dying.
You were Kira until then,
so it works out.
But after two weeks,
criminals began dying again.
Based on that evidence,
I think Kira's power can pass
from person to person.
That's an interesting idea.
But if that's true,
it won't be easy to catch Kira.
Yes. That's why I'm at a loss.
Even if we catch those
under Kira's control,
Kira's powers will be
passed on to others
and the former will have no memory
of their actions.
Which means that it's useless
to catch anyone...
But that's not definite yet.
So show some energy!
"Energy?"
I'm not feeling it. Why bother?
Trying hard to go after him
just puts us in danger.
Don't you think so?
Ryuzaki...
Nooo!
That hurt.
Stop messing around.
You don't feel like doing anything
just because I wasn't Kira...
and because
your deduction was wrong?
I may have phrased it wrong.
I meant it would be a waste for us
to make a move, so we shouldn't...
There's no way we can catch him
if we don't chase him!
Do you know how many
innocent people
you've involved in this case?!
Besides that, you're the one
who confined Misa and me!
I know...
But whatever the reason...
An eye for an eye.
It's not that my deduction
was wrong.
The fact is, the case isn't
going to be solved simply as
"Light Yagami is Kira" and
"Misa Amane is the Second Kira. "
So I'm a little disappointed.
I'm human. That isn't allowed?
No, it's not.
The way you talk...
it's almost like you won't
be satisfied unless I'm Kira...
"| won't be satisfied
unless you're Kira?"
That may be true...
I just realized...
I wanted you to be Kira.
An eye... for an eye.
I'll have you know
I'm quite strong.
Let's call the room and stop them!
- Yes?
- Please listen, Ryuzaki,
Misa-Misa is number one
in Eighteen Magazine's
reader popularity poll!
Yes, I see...
That means that it's been
decided that
she'll be starring as the heroine in
the next ﬁIm by the director, Nishinaka!
What's going on?
Matsuda's being an idiot again.
Well, Matsuda is a natural at that.
I can hear you...
TWO MONTHS LATER
Ryuzaki...
Ryuzaki, I know you're not into this
but come over here for a second.
Take a good look at this.
Isn't it unbalanced?
All three of them were prominent
Japanese businessmen.
They all died of heart attacks.
As a result,
Yotsuba's stock prices rose
but the other companies'
have plummeted.
In other words, they are deaths
that are in Yotsuba's favor...
Checking back,
there've been as many as thirteen
such cases in the past three months.
What do you think?
I can only conclude that
Kira is supporting Yotsuba.
Yes... But if that's true,
then punishing criminals
is not this Kira's true intent.
Yeah. He's punishing criminals
as a front and
killing people for
the benefit of this company.
What do you think?
Do you feel a little
more enthusiastic now?
It's amusing how well this has gone,
without arousing any suspicion...
Yotsuba's benefits and stock prices have
been increasing slowly, but steadily.
Yeah. It's all proceeding
according to our calculations.
I'm just worried about one thing.
Why did the three people
we decided to kill last week
die of heart attacks?
I thought we decided that one of them
was going to die from an accident?
That was probably because
we chose the accident to
occur on the Coastal Bay Route.
At the appointed time,
he wasn't at his home,
but had snuck off to Italy
with a woman.
In other words,
if the request is impossible...
Kira kills the person by heart attack.
It's like I told you last week.
If you request only accidental deaths
and death by disease,
they're finished in a natural way
in the shortest amount of time.
Anyway, the police should be
too busy
investigating the deaths of criminals.
If someone could trace the deaths
of those others back to us,
he would be a god.
Besides, we've already
taken precautions.
Chief! Oh, you too, Mogi!
Thanks for all your hard work today!
It's amazing!
With Light's help,
the theory that Kira is involved with
the Yotsuba Group has become stronger.
Yotsuba?
Yes...
That's probably the case, Matsuda.
We just heard from the Director that
Kira's offered bribes to politicians.
Kira said...
As long as the police
don't chase him...
he won't lay a hand
on any politicians.
The police caved in to Kira.
Mogi has already made up
his mind, but...
Aizawa, Matsuda...
if you really still
want to pursue Kira, then...
turn in your letters of resignation
to the NPA along with Mogi and me.
We can't seriously pursue Kira anymore
unless you quit the NPA.
What do you mean?!
It's simple.
We were told that we would be
fired if we were to pursue Kira with L.
So then, Chief, you really...
In a few hours,
I'm no longer going to be your chief.
But you all have your own lives.
Please think hard before
you make your decision.
That's right. Especially those who are
married and have children.
I think you all should
remain police officers.
I was alone to begin with...
and I'm grateful to all of you
for sticking with me this far.
But I can do this by myself.
I'll be sure to visit you all
at the police department
and bring you Kira's head as a gift.
Ryuzaki! As long as I'm here,
you won't be alone.
You have my promise!
That's right.
I'll have Light working
with me until I catch Kira.
But everyone else should
go back to being police officers...
But you told us that you needed
the help of the police in this case.
That's because the police
as an organization,
didn't bow to Kira and
hoped to arrest him.
I don't really think the help
of two or three civilians
who quit the police force can
really count as the police.
Also, the police have decided
that they don't want to
catch Kira, so that's enough.
It's true we wouldn't be of
much help not being police officers.
But what about our feelings?
We've risked our lives to catch Kira.
We at least have the right to decide
whether we stay here or
go back to the NPA!
I suppose you're right...
Then decide which you want to do.
But Chief,
if you quit the police force,
you'll be unemployed.
Even if we catch Kira,
what are you going to do afterwards?
Afterwards, huh?
I haven't thought about it,
but after we catch Kira...
I guess I'll be
looking for another job.
I've decided!
I'm going to quit the police force
and pursue Kira!
I still have to do my job
as Misa-Misa's manager!
Besides, if I went back to the NPA,
I'd feel like a loser...
Watch what you say, Matsuda.
How about if I stayed a police officer
and helped you in my spare time?
That's no good.
If you return to the NPA,
please don't come back here.
I won't leak information...
I won't give you any information.
As detectives,
you are free to pursue Kira.
But I don't think it's right
to give up your livelihoods
and harm your families
just to pursue Kira.
It's as Ryuzaki says.
No one will blame you if you quit.
That's right.
No one will think of you as a traitor!
But Chief, you have a family, too...
Our situations are different.
That's not fair.
I want to stay here, too.
I was prepared to die
at any moment.
And if I quit here,
how will I be able to face Ukita...
Damn it! Why can't a detective with
the NPA remain and pursue Kira?!
Ryuzaki.
In case anything happened
to a member of the task force,
even if they were ﬁred from the NPA,
you entrusted me to make preparations
so that ﬁnancial support would
be offered to their families,
so that they would never be in need
for the rest of their lives.
Why aren't you mentioning that?
Who asked you, Watari?
Pardon me.
Oh, so we've already been
taken care of financially?
Isn't that wonderful, Aizawa?
Ryuzaki... Were you watching to see if
I would quit the force to join you?
It's not like that, Aizawa.
Ryuzaki just doesn't like to
say things like that himself.
That's right.
No.
I was testing you.
I was watching to see
which you would choose.
Ryuzaki...
All right! I'll quit and
return to the NPA!
Aizawa!
I couldn't make a decision quickly
like you all and
I was leaning towards staying
a police officer.
Don't be so stubborn.
No! I quit!
This just made things clear for me!
I hate Ryuzaki!
I hate the way Ryuzaki
does everything!
But I like people
like you Mr. Aizawa.
I also can't stand
how he can say things like this
so shamelessly!
I quit!
Thank you very much for
your hard work.
I found another.
The branch manager of
Yotsuba's biggest rival bank,
died on September 7th when
he slipped on the steps of his home.
September 7th
was a Friday...
I checked once more and discovered
that the deaths
that are beneficial to Yotsuba
are concentrated around the weekend.
What? Really?!
At first, the times of death
were random...
but gradually,
they became concentrated
around Friday nights through
Saturday afternoons.
It's amazing you noticed that, Chief!
I told you,
I'm no longer the Chief.
No, you'll always be
the Chief to me!
This should be some sort of hint, Dad.
I haven't lost to you and Ryuzaki yet.
I don't want to be
dead weight here.
"Dead weight...?"
Is Kira someone from Yotsuba?
Or is Kira using Yotsuba?
I haven't figured that out yet,
but let's investigate this with
the assumption that this is Kira's doing.
Let's thoroughly investigate Yotsuba!
I've compiled a list of all domestic
employees in the Yotsuba Group.
Thank you very much.
Over 300,000, huh?
I'm impressed you compiled
the list so quickly...
That's amazing, Mr. Mogi.
Mr. Mogi's been amazing
since the very beginning.
Ryuzaki!
Is there anything I can do
besides being a manager?
You want to be useful?
Yes!
Then could you get me
another cup of coffee?
What?
And also for our guests over there.
Who are they?
When did they get in...?
They are our new members.
I'm Aiber. A con-man.
Pleased to meet you.
Wedy. I'm a thief by trade.
A con-man and a thief?
Yes.
Aiber has excellent social skills.
He's a con-man who can
cozy up to our target.
We'll use him for
infiltrative investigations.
Wedy is a thief who can crack
any lock, safe, or security system.
As proof, she entered without
any of us noticing.
We're going to be working together
with criminals?
They're criminals,
but not the type who
will surface and be killed by Kira.
Think of them as pros of
the underworld.
I see.
If we want to investigate Yotsuba,
we need people like them.
Let's all work together
and give it our all!
- Yes!
- Uh, yes.
Oh! It's Papa.
Papa!
Yumi...
Eriko...
What are you doing here?
At least tell me
if you're coming home.
I didn't buy enough
for your dinner.
I'll give you half of my croquette!
Sorry. I haven't had a break
for quite a while now,
so I got some time off.
Huh? Is a "time off" a vacation?
Yeah. That's what it is.
All right!
From now on,
I'm off every week.
So I can take you to the park...
or the zoo...
or even the amusement park...
What's wrong?
Mama, Papa's crying...
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
A secret meeting?
It sounds like they have one
every Friday night.
All right!
I'm on a roll today!