Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People!
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?!
Are you worried?
And when you know I'm Kira,
we'll get married!
And so...
Higuchi is Kira.
GUIDANCE
If the killing of criminals stops,
Higuchi probably has Kira's powers...
Still...
I knew that Amane would do
anything for Light Yagami, but...
I never thought
she would go this far.
If the killing of criminals stops...
it will become difﬁcult to deduce
the method of killing.
I have to think of a plan...
Misa, how did you get
Higuchi to say that?
Huh? He's totally in love with me.
I told him that I'd marry him
if he was Kira.
And he thinks that
I'm the Second Kira.
If I don't say this now,
I'll probably contradict myself later...
You idiot!
We told you to deny all of that.
B- But... now we know that
Higuchi is Kira...
we can just catch him.
I suppose you could call this
a victory, right, Mr. Matsuda?
In our current situation,
we still don't know how
he kills his victims.
Yes...
Before we catch Higuchi,
I want to know how he kills people.
If criminals stop dying,
we won't be able to figure it out.
Isn't that right?
Yes. Even if we're going to
arrest Higuchi,
we'll do it when we're sure
that criminals have stopped dying.
Please let me think for a moment.
Wed)’-
Yes.
What's the current situation?
Everything's going smoothly.
We should be able to track...
70% of the seven's actions with
our cameras while they're in the building.
What about outside of the building?
That's impossible with
just Watari and me.
How about just focusing
on Higuchi?
Higuchi?
I've only been inside
five of their houses...
But Mido, Namikawa, and Higuchi's
houses have serious security systems.
Especially Higuchi. He's...
recently constructed an underground
room that blocks out electronic waves.
It took me two days to break in.
Higuchi is definitely suspicious.
All right.
Then please install wire-taps,
tracking devices, and cameras...
in Higuchi's car,
rather than his house
What? After all this...?
Do you know how difﬁcult it is
to get inside someone's house?
Besides, how many cars
do you think Higuchi has?
Six.
All right. I just have to install them
in all of his cars, right?
Please do.
Whoa... I would have been in trouble
if he'd been wire-tapped earlier.
Yagami, sorry for coming
back to this topic, but...
I have to ask you again.
Ask me what?
Do you remember how to kill?
You're still saying that?
I'm not Kira. How many times do |...!
Just answer the question.
Do you remember?
I don't...
Misa, what about you?
I don't remember and I'm not Kira.
Yagami, please seriously
analyze and deduce...
what I'm going to say.
Your answer will determine
if we can catch Kira.
Light Yagami was Kira.
And Kira's power passed on
to someone else.
Right now, Light Yagami doesn't
remember that he was Kira.
Give me your thoughts based
on this premise.
Can you think about it in that way?
Yeah, I'll give it a try.
Light Yagami was Kira.
And Kira's power
passed to someone else.
Did it pass on through
Light Yagami's will?
Or was there someone behind
Light Yagami
who gave him Kira's power?
Did that person pass
Light Yagami's power to someone else?
Under those circumstances,
it would be Light Yagami's choice.
Of course it is.
If there was someone who was
moving that power from person to person
and didn't want the method
of murder to be discovered,
it's strange that he took so long to
move it from you to someone else.
If we acknowledge the existence of
someone watching us from above,
he would be impossible to catch...
and I'd either be dead already,
or be toyed with, forever...
in the palm of his hand.
It's highly unlikely
such a being exists.
Even if Light Yagami was Kira...
Kira's power can only move
by the will of the person who has it.
Yagami, thanks to you,
I feel 99% better.
We shall create a situation
where Higuchi cannot pass
his power on to anyone else,
and have him show us how he kills.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to trick Higuchi
using Sakura TV.
A hidden camera show?
What's that?
The Kira Special that Demegawa
airs every week...
We'll take up a three-hour time slot
and right at the beginning,
we'll say that at the end of the program,
we're going to announce who Kira is.
Will he believe that?
We're talking about
Sakura TV, right?
Besides, Higuchi might not
watch that program.
We'll contact Namikawa
and have him call Higuchi and say,
"This is bad. Turn on your
Higuchi will believe us when
he realizes that the person on
knows his secret.
I see. So we're going to use Aiber.
He'll reveal that he was
really a spy.
Not by a long shot.
We won't use Aiber.
The person who appears
on that show...
has to be someone who
Higuchi thinks he can kill...
In other words, someone whose name
he can easily look up.
Is there anyone who can do it?
Only Mr. Matsuda can do it.
Matsu!
Matsuda, huh?
Higuchi probably thinks that you
were listening in on their meeting.
He'll believe that the manager
he thought was dead would rat him out.
That's right.
I'll have Sakura TV prepare
the glass privacy screen and voice filter
they always use for witnesses.
Higuchi would probably realize from
the announcement and the silhouette
that it's Matsui, the manager.
We'll have the station make
a mistake and accidentally flash
the face of the person behind
the glass screen.
Wow! Sounds fun.
- Until the show ends,
- Kira's is identity will be revealed at the end
we'll keep saying that we'll reveal
the real name of H, who's Kira.
In this situation,
Higuchi will have to discover
his name as soon as possible.
We can anticipate Higuchi's actions.
And we'll be able to see
how Kira kills.
After that, we'll apprehend him.
Right now, the only problem
in this plan is...
if Higuchi can kill by looking
at someone's face like the Second Kira,
Mr. Matsuda will die.
Since you're still alive
and he still wants Misa,
that probably won't happen.
Well, this is a plan for when
the criminals stop dying.
We'll have to watch for two or
three days to see whether that happens.
In that time, Mr. Matsuda must
decide if he wants to do it.
I don't need two or three days.
Please let me do it.
What did you want to talk
to me about in secret?
Namikawa, who do
you think is Kira?
Why do you want to know?
Besides... he could be either of you.
No, Shimura's not Kira.
He was just crying to me
about how he can't keep up
with Kira's evil deeds any more.
Shimura, if Mido was Kira,
you would have been killed.
No, you and Mido would have
been successful on your own.
You two wouldn't need to hold
those stupid meetings with eight people.
Even I know that.
We're all cooperating because
we're afraid that
Kira's going to kill us.
But if we continue,
the world will some day find out.
No, it won't end until that happens.
So Shimura, let me ask you:
Who do you think is Kira?
Takahashi or Higuchi.
Takahashi is only there to make
Kira look smarter.
He needs someone around
who's less sophisticated than he is.
It seems everyone
already knows...
It's probably Higuchi...
Yeah. Higuchi is the one most
obsessed with money and status.
The way he always says things as if
he's not interested in success
is proof of that.
Still, he's always insulting people
and can't use people well.
That's why he was demoted from
being the head of development
to just a divisional head.
Was I the only one you called here?
I also called Ooi, but...
He said, "You can hold your silly
secret meetings by yourself. "
That sounds like the sort
of impatient thing he'd say.
We know Kida isn't Kira
because he provided the account
to fund and commission Coil.
Namikawa, during the meeting
after Hatori died,
you received a phone call.
Who was it from?
Shimura, you're really sharp...
Kira probably made you a member
because he appreciates your caution.
This is Namikawa.
This is L. Mr. Namikawa,
are you by yourself?
No.
Then chime in as you
see ﬁt once again.
There's no need for that.
There's someone who got suspicious
after you called me during the meeting.
Who's calling you, Namikawa?
It's L.
L, Mido and Shimura are here, but...
I don't think they're Kira.
They seem to be fed up with Kira.
Despite what they say,
they choose to stand back and watch
your face-off with Kira, just as I plan to.
That should be fine.
Tonight, I'm going to catch Kira.
I want you to help me a little.
Higuchi's done, huh?
You knew?
It seems even L can be tricked.
By your reaction,
now I'm 100% sure it's Higuchi.
Namikawa is pretty good...
I was expecting that
considering his looks.
No, Light just made a mistake.
We're going to set Higuchi
in motion with a special on Kira
on Sakura TV which
will air tonight at 7:00.
A few minutes into the program,
I want you to contact Higuchi and
tell him to watch that show.
I won't do anything to the six of you.
If the others who aren't there,
Kida, Takahashi, and Ooi,
try to do something, stop them.
Yes, all right.
So it really is Higuchi.
He'll probably be arrested tonight.
It's been three days since
I stopped killing criminals.
That should be good enough.
Now, If I many the Second Kira,
Misa Amane...
I'll have the Shinigami eyes.
And I'll control everything Yotsuba has!
Higuchi,
something horrible's happening.
Turn on Sakura TV.
KIRA'S IDENTITY
What is this?
It's probably a hoax. It's Sakura TV.
At the beginning of the program,
he said that he came across
a meeting of eight people.
Someone who knows
about the meetings?
Who is it? Did someone betray us?
And one of them was killed and
now there are only seven left...
The victim was Mr. H.
H...? Hatori...
If he knows this much...
is he one of the other six?
No, is he Coil?!
He was killed by Kira because
he wanted to leave the meetings.
No. There's no beneﬁt
for him to do this...
But, there's no one else who
knows about those meetings...
No... This guy is...!
I- It's him!
Misa's manager...
I think his name was Matsui!
How is he still alive?!
He just explained that he thought
he was going to be killed.
He took a chance,
pretended to fall out of the condo...
And escaped to a veranda
on the floor below.
No. Just in case, I went home,
I took his name from his business card
and wrote it into the notebook
Was he a former entertainer
who became a manager
under his stage name?
I don't know!
Furthermore, he says that
he's continued to investigate Yotsuba
and figured out who Kira is...
I'm contacting everyone right now.
All right. I'm going to hang up.
Are you all right from that
mishap just now?
Shall we stop?
No... I'm well aware of the danger...
For justice, even if I'm killed...
I shall give it my all until the end!
This is good. That is good!
Don't make the Kira announcement
until the end of the program.
I have to kill him.
If the Second Kira is Misa,
she knows his face,
so she should know
what his name is...
Here it comes!
What the hell? C'mon!
To be honest,
I've been debating whether
I should make
this announcement or not.
But now that I'm here,
I've decided it's my duty to reveal it.
This is not good.
- I don't know when he's going reveal it.
- The announcement will come soon.
Don't change the channel.
Cosme Misa...
Devilish charm...
Angelic shine...
Misa's winning rouge...
Now available for you...
Mido, it's me.
Something bad is happening
on Sakura TV.
Contact your father in
the House of Councilors.
Have the Ministry of Internal Affairs
stop this program.
I'm watching too,
but that's impossible.
No one takes this program seriously
so we'd just look suspicious.
Besides, there's nothing to
fear any more.
That guy just showed his face...
We can conﬁrm that
it's Taro Matsui.
Namikawa is telling everyone
to watch this show.
Somebody out of
the seven of us is Kira.
So, Taro Matsui...
will die soon.
That's right! I'm the only one who knows
that Taro Matsui is not his real name.
If I say that, then I'll reveal
that I'm Kira.
Everyone!
- You're right.
- Kira'ss identity will become clear soon!
- Talk to you later.
Stay with us!
Damn!
Ryuzaki. Mogi's in front of
Yoshida Productions,
and he's received a call
from Higuchi.
Yes. The next stage has come,
exactly as planned.
Moji, where's Misa?
Oh, Mr. Higuchi, a pleasure doing
business with you.
Misa is taking a much-needed
break right now.
She'll be back tomorrow...
I'm asking you, where is she?!
Well, that's private, she doesn't
want anyone to know...
I'm very sorry.
I can contact her tomorrow.
Damn it... I know his face.
I could kill him at any time
if I only knew his name...!
Was the previous manager
an ex-entertainer?
Pardon?
The guy by the name
of Taro Matsui!
Oh... | came in as a replacement,
so I don't know anything...
If that's the case,
please contact someone at the office...
Oh... but everyone's gone to Okinawa.
Could you call our president?
Wow. It's going exactly as we planned
and it's kinda scary.
Don't be scared. Be happy, Yagami.
I shall broadcast Higuchi's call to
Yoshida Production's president.
This is Higuchi from Yotsuba.
Taro Matsui's not the real name of
the guy who was with you earlier, was it?
- He's getting more and more direct.
- Ah, he was using...
- Higuchi is an idiot.
- his manager's name.
- It's proof that he's losing confidence.
- / see.
So what's his real name?!
I believe it was...
Yamada... no, Yamashita.
And his ﬁrst name...
I don't remember.
Don't screw around!
Remember the names
of the people you hire!
What's with that tone?
I have his personal history
back at the ofﬁce.
Then go back there and tell me.
Give me a break!
We haven't had a company vacation
in over two years!
If you want to know that badly,
I'll tell you the security code
for the ofﬁce's door.
You can go right in and look around.
Personnel ﬁles are in
the desk farthest back to the left.
They're alphabetized in
the bottom drawer.
It's probably Yamashita.
If he's going to say it
at the end of the program,
I still have two hours...
I wonder if he's gonna do it...
I've confirmed Higuchi.
He only has one bag on him.
I'm going after him.
Everything's going according
to plan, isn't it?
Yes.
I Will... kill him...
I've come this far,
I will not be stopped!
Everything will be mine!
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A ﬂeeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they driveled
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
- I don't want to have to use this but...!
- Higuchi has a gun! The Chief's been shot!
- This sounds kind of bad.
- Higuchi! Hold it right there!
- We'll get 100% ratings!
- Give it up!
- Think it over carefully.
- Stop right there!
I made it!
FRENZY