Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People!
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?!
Are you worried?
What's the meaning of this?!
Everyone. Shiniga...!
RENEWAL
I told you that this is
a live worldwide broadcast...
But... this is only being broadcast
in the Kanto region of Japan.
The ﬁrst victim was the perpetrator
of the random murders in Shinjuku.
- His crime was only broadcast in Japan.
- ... The suspect has died!
I have been able to
deduce this much...
You are in Japan and your first victim
was your guinea pig.
KIRA TASK FORCE HEADQUARTERS
Kira has found a way to obtain information
from the task force headquarters...
There are 141 people within
the police force alone...
who have access to classified
information on the Kira investigation.
But one of the 141 people
or someone close to them...
Kira is definitely among them!
FBI Investigation of Those Involved
with the Japanese Police
December 19. Kira began using
prisoners to conduct tests...
on the actions a victim
can take before death.
In order to eliminate
all of the FBI agents...
...he had to see how far he could
control the deaths of his victims.
Thus, I suspect that Kira
was one of the people
who was being investigated
by the FBI...
between the fourteenth
and the nineteenth.
AN IMPORTANT WITNESS
NAOMI MISORA
Raye Penber's fiancée?
Naomi Misora.
So that's it...
She worked under me on that case
and now she's in Japan.
She was with Penber.
She might have found a clue...
If that's the case,
did Kira get to her first?
LIGHT YAGAMI
Everyone. From now on,
we'll focus our investigation...
on the people Raye Penber
was investigating while in Japan.
Deputy Director General Kitamura
and his family,
and Detective Superintendent Yagami
and his family.
I also wish to place wiretaps and
surveillance cameras in both households.
Ryuzaki, are you telling me
that you suspect my son?
I suspect him.
CONTACT WITH LIGHT YAGAMI
I'm L.
Don't worry, Yagami.
Kira hates to lose, but most people
don't like to lose either.
It's not just Kira.
See? He's trying to win.
Yagami, I suspect that you,
may in fact be Kira.
I'm Kira?
Ryuga, is there any way that I can get
you to believe that I'm not Kira?
If you aren't Kira,
it will become apparent eventually.
KIRA MURDERS,
USING A TELEVISION STATION
- was sent these four tapes.
- no, seventy percent...
It foretells another death
to prove that he is Kira
...and also contains a message
to people all over the world.
I am Kira.
The anchor,
Mr. Kazuhiko Hibima,
will die of a heart attack
at exactly six o'clock.
Something terrible will happen
if we don't stop this broadcast!
You idiot!
Mr. Ukita!
Kira shouldn't be able to
kill without a name!
From what I just saw,
it's not entirely impossible that
he may only need a face to kill...
This is the police!
Stop this program!
There is a high possibility
that this Kira is a fake.
No, we should call him
the Second Kira.
Mr. Yagami. May I ask your son
to cooperate in this investigation?
LIGHT YAGAMI IS SUMMONED TO
TASK FORCE HEADQUARTERS
It's exactly the same deduction
as L, I mean Ryuzaki.
When we meet,
we can conﬁrm ourselves,
by showing our Shinigami to each other
What's wrong?!
If there is a code
that only people who have the so-called
Shinigami power can understand...
I can't decode it.
But we should thoroughly check out
the places listed in the diary.
Please be sure to
keep an eye on Light.
In the event that Light is Kira,
the Second Kira might try
to contact him in some way.
Also, Mr. Yagami. I would like Mr. Mogi
to keep watch over Light's activities.
MISA AMANE ARRESTED UNDER SUSPICION
OF BEING THE SECOND KIRA
Light! There you are!
I'm Light's girlfriend, Misa Amane.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Hideki Ryuga.
Huh?
Hideki Ryuga?
This may come as good
and bad news to you, but...
But Misa Amane has just
been taken into custody
under suspicion of being
the Second Kira.
There were hairs and fibers...
among other things,
attached to the masking tape sealing
the video tapes the Second Kira sent.
We discovered many matching samples
of evidence in her room.
MISA AMANE'S CONFINEMENT
Ryuzaki! What is this?!
Hurry up and kill me!
You're able to kill me
immediately, right?!
Is this because you admit
to being the Second Kira?
No! I don't know anything
about the Second Kira!
LIGHT YAGAMI IS CONFINED
AT HIS OWN REQUEST
For him to say that he may be Kira?
It's an act...
It's not that you may be Kira,
but that you are Kira...
Light, are you all right?
Yeah... I know I probably look
pretty bad in here,
but this pride,
I'll just have to get rid of it!
Ryuzaki! I know I agreed
to be detained and chose to do this...
But now I just clearly realized...
I'm not Kira!
Get me out of here quickly!
What's going on?
Two weeks worth of criminals
were murdered all at once yesterday!
I don't understand what's going on...
TWO PEOPLE RELEASED
It seems like all three of them
are at their limit...
Ryuzaki, why are you
still confining Light?
It's already been fifty days...
I'm going to kill you here
and then kill myself.
What are you talking about, Dad?!
- That's crazy!
- Stop it already!
- It would be better if we ran away.
- It's too late, Light...
Stop, Dad, I'm not Kira!
Light...
- from one murderer to another,
- Dad!
I'll see you in hell.
Stop!
It was a convincing performance.
As I promised,
I will end their confinement.
LIGHT YAGAMI IS SUMMONED AGAIN
TO HELP WITH THE INVESTIGATION
so that you and I will be together 24 hours
a day working on the investigation.
YOTSUBA
Checking back, there have been
as many as thirteen such cases
in the past three months...
Is Kira someone from Yotsuba?
I haven't figured that out yet,
but let's investigate this with the
assumption that this is Kira's doing.
Let's thoroughly investigate Yotsuba!
Please be sure not to act
out of panic or haste
and don't take matters into
your own hands.
My name is Taro Matsui.
An agent with Yoshida Productions!
How would you like to use Misa Amane
in your commercials?!
Ryuzaki, are you watching?
The eight who are here,
were having a meeting
to determine who
they would get Kira to kill.
If Matsuda dies that would justify
the suspicion against Yotsuba...
Is there anything I can do
to save myself?
Stupid Matsuda...
KYOSUKE HIGUCHI CONFIRMED TO BE KIRA
Good luck, Misa-misa!
I'll start planning the party
to celebrate when you
land this commercial!
It's my dream to become Kira's bride.
Because I'm the Second Kira.
Well, I'm Kira, so...
Marry me, Misa!
And so, Higuchi is Kira.
THE PLAN TO CAPTURE HIGUCHI
IS SET INTO MOTION
I'm going to trick Higuchi
using Sakura TV.
A hidden camera show?
Higuchi, this is bad. Turn on your TV.
So one of these people is Kira, right?
Yes. I have a lot of proof.
It's him!
How is he still alive?!
I've confirmed Higuchi.
I'm going after him.
I'm going after him!
Stop your car.
Pull over to the side of the road.
Rem. Let's make a deal.
"Deal?"
You were speeding.
Show me your driver's license!
Yeah... all right.
Hey!
Higuchi ditched the motorcycle cop
and is on the run!
This is highway patrol-!
Everyone! It's too dangerous to
allow further action by Higuchi!
We will proceed to capture him.
Higuchi is now able to kill by
looking at someone's face,
like the Second Kira.
We will capture him
with that in mind!
Stop right there!
Don't you come near me!
HIGUCHI'S CAPTURE
You may not believe me...
But if I write the name of someone
whose face I know in that notebook,
that person dies.
Yeah, there's one in Higuchi's bag.
What's wrong, Mr. Yagami?
A monster!
It's a Shinigami...
There are more than
two notebooks in existence!
This isn't ﬁnished yet...
THE DEATH NOTE AND
AN INQUIRY INTO ITS RULES
"How to use it...
"The human whose name
is written in this note shall die.
"And this last sentence...
"if the person using the note fails
"to consecutively write names
of people to be killed
"within thirteen days of each other,
then the user will die... "
Light Yagami and Misa Amane
are alive...
Thirteen days...
This is the only...
The following is the record which
contains everything
I have investigated
on the Kira incident.
The fact that you are
reading this message means
I am no longer alive at this moment.
I hereby leave this record
as my firm achievement.
It's been ten days since
Ryuzaki's secret funeral...
It looks like we aren't going to die...
We now know Watari's identity,
but in the end,
we didn't find out anything
about Ryuzaki...
It seems Watari was actually
an amazing inventor.
He created orphanages worldwide
with the fortune built on
numerous patents.
He's a hero! A hero!
But we can't continue investigating here
now that L and Watari are gone...
This is tough...
Hmm...
Light, how is it going?
I can remove the entire system
here by tonight.
I don't feel good about it.
It feels like stealing.
I've created a voice like
the one that Ryuzaki used.
We can act like he's still alive
and control the police
as we've been doing, but...
Who will replace L?
Where will we do it?
What'll we do with
the killer notebook?
What are you talking about, Light?!
The only one who can take on
the role of L is you!
If Ryuzaki was killed by Kira
for challenging him...
I don't feel comfortable about it.
Besides that, I'll be tricking
the people of the world...
I understand your feelings,
but you're the only one who can do this.
That's right. Ryuzaki even said so...
You'd be capable of succeeding L.
So easy...
It's no fun without Ryuzaki...
Yeah, all right. I'll do it.
But I won't do anything dangerous
like challenging Kira directly
in order to gain clues, like Ryuzaki did.
Is that okay?
Yes. That would be better and safer.
Ryuzaki might have been
too confrontational...
In that case...
I can do about the same work
with this computer and my own.
It's also possible to be L
from my room at home.
I'll also be Watari.
But it would be difficult to do this
with my mom and little sister around.
It would be good if I could rent
a one-room apartment.
There's nothing suspicious about renting
a room for my son to live on his own.
That's right.
Then the place he'll be renting out
will be the task force headquarters.
Yes.
All that's left is what to do
with the killer notebook...
There's no need to think too hard...
We'll just have one of the five of us,
one who we trust will never
use the notebook...
hide it somewhere
where no one can get to it.
Chief, please do this!
We can count on you!
You're a pillar of justice!
Me, huh?
All right...
Let's avenge Ryuzaki!
Yeah.
Yes. Kira's still here.
Let's catch him!
Well then, let's have a party to
celebrate Light becoming the second L.
Quit fooling around, now's not the time.
Now, now...
Light!
It's our first date in a while.
Enjoy yourself a little more...
Misa...
Let's live together.
Huh?!
Really?!
Yeah.
I've already rented an apartment.
All right! We're living together!
Misa wins!
"Wins?"
You know, against Kiyomi
and Mari and Yuri.
It's all right, Light.
You only used them to trick L,
didn't you?
I understand.
You won't see them anymore, will you?!
Yeah...
Hey...
So is your score
finally settled with L?
Yeah.
So I shouldn't expect
anything interesting anymore...
That's not true, Ryuk.
Hm?
From now on...
I'll show you the creation
of a new world.
Oh?
Papa!
Yotsuba's reconstruction
is just beginning.
Yeah.
Let's do our best!
Hm?
Hey... Namikawa?
Huh?! Impossible!
In April, 2012, Light Yagami,
age 23, joins the National Police Agency.
In the summer of 2012,
Kira's judgments
gain momentum.
The world screams in fear of Kira,
but privately it cheers for him.
Slowly, their true thoughts come out,
and some countries even express
their acceptance of Kira.
The world continues towards
a dark era where Kira is the law.
What is it, Roger?
L is dead.
TO BE CONTINUED
This single page Forever depressing
A ﬂeeting tactic in the eyes
Without petition evil against the law
chain it in prison
Poison the notebook fear the lust
Delusion of being deceived
perpetually drooling
Judgement is "crime control"
they drive/ed
Who has the Rx for that?
A decriminalized world
A sanctioned word
Taking in heat
Just like "Pirates of Death"
Atone with the game of laws
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
Billy in despair
Now, it's time for ethics
Now, the unstoppable Eraser Rain
The unstoppable Eraser Rain
PREVIEW
From where?
A kidnapping?
Who was kidnapped? By whom?
Are they joking?
But what's this strange feeling?
ABDUCTION