Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
FRIEND
I understand...
I can't be your boyfriend,
but I can play the part...
Thank you...
I'll work hard to make you love me.
I'll have her meet L to ﬁnd out
his name
and eliminate
the entire task force HQ
I'll kill her afterwards...
That's right.
She's the only person who knows
Kira's identity.
I can't let her live for long.
So you'll just act
like my boyfriend, huh?
That's a good start.
So then, could you show me
your Shinigami?
I suppose it's necessary
to make her trust me...
Yeah. All right.
Could you turn around?
Okay.
You can turn around now.
Hi!
Ooh...
He's a completely different type
of Shinigami from Rem, isn't he?
I already know your name. Ryuk.
Pleased to meet you!
Yeah, pleased to meet you.
Oh yeah, Light, do you know
how to kill a Shinigami?
You're already calling me
by my first name?
Then could I call you "Knight" instead?
Because you're like Misa's knight
in shining armor!
Light is fine.
Are you planning to check all
the videos of Aoyama
on the 22nd by yourself?
Yes.
It is very likely that Kira
and the Second Kira
made contact with each other there
on that day.
I want to check them all.
Also, Mr. Yagami...
Yes?
I would like Mr. Mogi to keep
watch over Light's activities.
"Light's activities?"
In the event that Light is Kira,
the Second Kira might try to contact him...
...in some way.
I understand.
So when does Ryuzaki sleep?
I saw him sleeping in that
exact same position the other day.
No, I'm serious...
So when a Shinigami has feelings
for a certain person...
and kills someone in order to
extend that person's life,
the Shinigami dies, huh?
Yes.
I can't imagine there's
a Shinigami who would do that.
That's right. It doesn't seem like
the kind of thing that you would do.
By the way, from where have you
been sending your tapes
to the television stations?
Umm... The first time was Osaka.
Then it was Tokyo.
This other time was from Nagano.
I used the Bullet Train so
my location couldn't be pinpointed.
So you still have videotapes
and envelopes
with your friend's fingerprints
on them, right?
Yeah.
Then you should dispose of
everything used to create the videos...
But only after sending one last video
from another location tomorrow...
You should say...
"| will stop trying to meet Kira. "
"I'd like to thank the police
for their advice. "
"But I'm going to help Kira
erase evil from the world. "
"I'm going to cooperate with him
and gain his acceptance. "
"| will begin by punishing criminals
that Kira hasn't punished yet. Also..
"| plan to make this world
a better place"
"by sharing this power
among those who are worthy. "
"Share the power?"
It's a line to throw off
the investigation.
There are already two people
with this power.
It's not too far of a stretch
that there may be more.
And if they believe that they'll multiply,
it will create panic.
Can you do it?
You don't have to ask.
Just tell me to do it.
I'll do whatever you say.
Also, one more important thing.
Okay!
If you're caught by the police...
if you're arrested as a suspect,
don't say anything about us
or the notebook.
There's no proof against you
as long as they don't get
a hold of the notebook and verify it.
Can you promise to do that?
I promise!
So then, we're officially boyfriend
and girlfriend, right?
Well, I guess so.
Now for my conditions.
Go on a date with me
at least once a week.
She really doesn't get it...
That's impossible.
W- Why?
It doesn't seem like
you'll understand unless I tell you.
L already suspects that I'm Kira.
What? L's pretty amazing...
Everyone's saying that
he doesn't understand or...
that he's stupid.
So he's actually figured out
that much...
But thanks to that,
I've also been able to get close to L.
Huh? L and Kira are
in contact with each other?
You're both amazing.
It's making me kind of excited.
Even if I'm Kira,
L thinks he's safe as long as
he hides his name.
He came out and told me he was L
in order to directly investigate me.
But he's only positive because
there isn't anyone else
who could possibly be Kira.
And if I play it right,
he'll trust me and
we'll investigate together.
So all you have to do is
take me to where L is, right?
It's not that simple.
It was difficult enough
for me to get close to him.
Besides, if suddenly,
someone close to me
steps into the picture,
and the actions of Kira and
the Second Kira change...
that person will be suspected
of being the Second Kira,
and I'll end up casting
more suspicion on myself.
It would be bad if we get together,
and he makes the connection
that we're intimate...
Do you understand
what I'm trying to say?
Kind of... So does that mean
we can't go on dates?
We can't meet in public because
you're afraid that he'll suspect you more?
No.
We should take some time
to think of a plan
so that you can see L
without him knowing about you.
Yeah.
I need you
in order to eliminate L.
I want to be able to keep
in direct contact with you.
Thank goodness...
So...
In order to make sure that
our meetings don't stand out,
I'm going to see other girls.
Huh? What do you mean by that?
You're going to date other girls?
Well, pretty much...
No way!
If I see you with another girl,
I'll kill her.
Scary...!
Listen, Misa sweetie...
"Sweetie," huh?
This isn't a game...
We're both risking our lives
to change the world, aren't we?
Yeah, but...
I love you more... than the world...
What are you talking about?
I thought your feelings towards me
were those of just a Kira admirer.
Besides...
This is the first time we've met.
Haven't you ever experienced
love at first sight?
Never...
Well, yes, I wanted to meet Kira out of
gratitude and approval, not out of love.
But, when I first laid eyes on you...
What's with this girl?
Popular as usual...
Then if you love me,
you'll obey me.
You told me before that
you didn't mind being used
and just earlier, you insisted that
you'd do as I say, right?
But I won't allow you to
date other girls.
Those are two different things.
I have both notebooks.
If you won't obey, I'll kill you...
I won't let you do that,
Light Yagami.
If you try to kill her,
I'll write your name in my notebook...
And kill you.
I can see her lifespan.
If she dies before that date,
I'll assume that you killed her.
Wouldn't you die if you
used your notebook to save her?
That's right! Then you'll die, Rem!
That's true...
But I don't care.
Is this Shinigami serious?
Then that means, from now on...
Light?
What is it, Mom?
It's already 11:30.
It's not nice to have
a girl stay out so late...
Yeah, you're right.
We ended up having
a long conversation...
Sorry, Mrs. Yagami.
I'm sorry for staying so late.
Light, see you later.
Yeah.
Light, walk her to the station.
It won't be good to walk
outside with her now...
It's all right! Good night!
She's cute.
Oh yeah. I was a bit worried at first,
but she sure is cute.
I like her!
That Shinigami is going
to kill me if I kill the girl?
Does that mean I have to deal
with her until she dies?
Not just that,
I'm forced to protect her so
she doesn't get caught by the police.
Thanks to you,
Light really became my knight.
So it seems.
But don't kill him for real, okay?
In order to kill a Shinigami,
that Shinigami
has to use the Death Note
to save a human's life that
it has fallen in love with...
I can't kill Rem
by using the Death Note
to control someone to attack Misa...
If Misa's put in danger,
I'll be suspected and killed.
Right now, she's an even
bigger nuisance than L is.
Sh-She's...
She does something
this conspicuous?
What'll happen if it's discovered
that I met up with someone like this?
Damn it! She's in the way
no matter how I think about it.
What do I do?
No... that aside, I should think
of a way to use Misa's eyes to kill L.
If I just eliminate L...
Good morning, Light!
Good morning.
Mom, Sayu, could you keep Misa
a secret from Dad?
All right.
I also want you to keep it secret,
not just from Dad,
but from everyone.
She's an up-and-coming model,
actually,
so it would be problematic
if people found out about us.
What?! Is that so?
I thought she was cute...
Just what I'd expect for your girlfriend...
I'll keep it a secret... for 5,000 yen.
Silly...
TO-OH UNIVERSITY
On page 246...
Misa's ﬁnal message
will arrive today.
Instead of going to
the television station,
it should be routed to
the task force headquarters.
I have to go to headquarters
in order to see L's reaction...
Yagami... Yagami...
You told me that you'd
go outwith me, right?
Yeah, I did.
That's why I'm sitting next
to you at this lecture.
Yes.
But you don't seem happy at all.
You've been completely
ignoring me.
That's not true at all.
I was just thinking about the Way
everyone's going to be talking about us.
To think that I'm going outwith you,
the famous Miss To-oh University...
It's obvious,
you really are beautiful.
Please don't think about such things.
I don't like being called Miss whatever.
Yeah. You're right.
What's with this woman?
She loves it.
Miss Takada, let's just take
things at our own pace.
Okay.
Hello.
Light, good timing.
A video message from
the Second Kira just arrived.
Another one? That was fast.
Yes. I think this is the last one.
Well, take a look at this.
I will stop trying to meet Kira.
I'd like to thank the police
for their advice.
But I'm going to help Kira
erase evil from the world...
I'm going to cooperate with him
and gain his acceptance.
I will begin by punishing criminals
that Kira hasn't punished yet. Also...
I plan to make this world
a better place
by sharing this power
among those who are worthy...
Watching this...
makes me feel that Kira and
the Second Kira have joined forces.
How do you know that
they've joined forces?
Didn't you sense it?
I thought you would
get the same impression.
First of all, his attitude towards
meeting Kira completely changed.
Also, he now says that he wants
to punish criminals
that Kira didn't punish
in order to gain his acceptance.
Why didn't he do this before?
He probably never thought
that far ahead, so...
It's likely that he's working with Kira,
and was told to say that.
He was also ordered to hide
the fact that they're working together.
I see.
That probably means that Kira isn't
thinking about his actions very much.
Yes.
Did Kira encounter something
he couldn't overcome?
He probably was trying to scare us
by making it obvious
that he'd recruited the Second Kira.
Their union is really threatening.
But this lessens the suspicion
I had of Light.
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?!
If Light was Kira,
then he wouldn't have sent
in a video like this.
He would have tried to threaten me, L,
into appearing on television again.
Maintaining that lie that
they aren't working together,
he would have placed all
the responsibility on Second Kira...
And this is what he'd have him say:
"| stopped because
Kira told me to,"
"but I don't think that warning
would come from the real Kira. "
"Kira would be happy if L died. "
"There's no way he'd stop me. "
Ryuzaki...
Yes?
I would never do that
if I were Kira.
Why?
I know your personality.
L would never go on TV,
no matter how he was threatened.
He wouldn't want to die
in someone else's place.
He would think of
some way to escape.
You figured it out.
Light, stop saying,
"if I were Kira. "
I don't like hearing it,
even hypothetically.
Oh, sorry, Dad...
But I want to tell Ryuzaki
what I think.
I have to pose the scenario
hypothetically
in order to solve this case quickly
and to clear my name.
Besides, it's because
I'm not Kira that I can talk in that way.
You're right.
You're not Kira.
Rather, it would be a problem
if you were Kira.
Because you're...
my very first friend...
Yeah, Ryuzaki, I consider you a friend too.
We have so much in common.
Thank you.
It's been lonely since you've been
taking breaks from school.
I'd like to play tennis with you again.
Yes. By all means.
Friend? Friend, huh?
Aren't you glad, Light?
That damn Ryuzaki
immediately noticed
the connection between
Kira and the Second Kira...
I've got to eliminate him quickly...
Oh I see...
This makes it all the more dangerous
for me to see Misa.
Light!
I just couldn't wait
two weeks...
I was just about to go
to your house!
T- This is the ﬁrst time
I've really wanted to hit a woman...
|- | just wanted to see you
so badly...
Well... Come over to my house.
Okay!
Another girl?
Welcome, Misa! I saw you in
a whole bunch of magazines!
Welcome.
Sorry for the intrusion.
Mom, please get some tea ready...
Rem.
You're Misa's ally, aren't you?
Yeah. I've watched her many times
from the Shinigami Realm.
I've developed a bit of
affection for her.
Affection, even though
you're a Shinigami?
You don't seem to like that
I said that I'd kill you
if you tried to kill her.
Does this mean that if
Misa's happy that you'll feel fine?
Well, you could say that.
I just don't want
to see her unhappy.
Misa is...
in love with me.
Light...
Misa.
Yes?
Would my happiness
make you happy?
Yes.
Then could you ask Rem
to kill L?
Rem wants you to be happy.
If L catches one of us,
we'll both be unhappy.
A Shinigami can't tell a person's name
to someone who has a notebook,
but there's no restriction
against Rem killing anyone.
Yeah. If you kill L,
I think I can love Misa more
and I would be very grateful.
Above all, it'll make us both happy.
Rem...
I want Light to love me.
Light and I will be grateful.
That would be... my happiness.
Fine.
Fine, Light Yagami.
I don't like you.
Even if this ends up lengthening
your lifespan, I won't die.
I'll kill L for you.
L means nothing to me.
All right!
Thank you, Rem!
That's my Rem!
L will die,
this easily?
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
This is all a wager now.
Tomorrow will be L's,
no Ryuga/Ryuzaki's,
...final day.
WAGER