We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
Since you first wrote down a name, how much time has passed?
35... 36... 37... 38... 39...
Near, it's my victory!
40!!
New World
We didn't die...
One minute has passed... and we didn't die!
That's why I said we wouldn't die several times.
Why...
Why won't they die!?
G-God! I did everything you told me to!
Lester, Gevanni, seize Mikami!
Gevanni, the notebook.
Please confirm this with your own eyes.
The first four are, without a doubt, the SPK members' real names.
And the only one here whose name isn't written down, is... Yagami Light.
Mikami also called you "God", and said he did as you instructed.
It's settled.
Trap!! This is a trap!
It's a trap set by Near in order to frame me!
Writing the names in the notebook and not dying, isn't that strange?!
That proves it's a trap!
Didn't I tell you that I modified the notebook so that we wouldn't die?
N-Not true!
You're wrong!
Unbelievable...
It's a trap... I don't even know that person!
Light-kun, it's too late... Near won.
And you just said, "It's my victory".
That's the same as a confession.
Light-kun...
Why?
S-Stop!!
Yagami Light, "L", Kira.
You have lost.
Just now, you proclaimed your victory...
Although originally you would have won, and I would have lost.
All this time we did exactly as you predicted, and altered the fake notebook.
Except, earlier, when I said that I modified the notebook, that applied to the real notebook as well.
The fake one was only slightly modified...
The real one was replaced entirely.
This is the real notebook.
Im-Impossible!!
With the same pen that Mikami used, in the same handwriting...
Everything looks identical.
Gevanni made this for us in one night.
Because I touched this notebook, I have been able to see the Shinigami.
Shinigami-san, a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Near.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ryuk.
He's having a conversation with Ryuk...
Being able to see him must mean it's true.
In this notebook, it seems that a number of pages have been ripped out.
If someone's name is written on a torn page, would they die?
Yeah, they'd die.
As I thought.
So there are a number of ways to use it...
I wonder just how many people you killed, and how many times we've been fooled...
Yagami Light...
You are Kira!
There's something wrong here...
Could it be that Mikami betrayed me?
You're wrong...
It was all thanks to Mello.
Saying this much, you should understand by now.
Mello?!
Please take a good look at this...
Takada's name is in the notebook!
I was the one who killed Takada, and that one is set for one minute later!
At that time, did Mikami also...
God, you said you were being watched and couldn't act!
With Takada in that situation... it was my duty to...
You IDIOT!! I told you NOT to do anything unnecessary until today!
That's right.
On the 26th, after the report featuring Takada's kidnapping, Mikami headed for the bank.
According to my investigation, Mikami only goes to the bank on the 25th of every month.
For someone as punctual as Mikami, going to the bank twice in two days is pretty unusual.
I followed him as he headed for the deposit boxes...
And only at that moment did he appear to be afraid of being tailed.
I was able to get into the deposit box, and inside, was the real notebook, with Takada's name written in it.
Yagami Light...
Even though you could kill someone with a piece of the note, you weren't aware that Mikami had done something on his own.
It was then that I realized the possibility of a fake notebook.
The biggest help in creating this scenario... was Mello.
Mello might have known this would happen...
By directly writing down your names in the notebook?
Yeah.
I'm the only one who can do it.
Mello knew this...
Alone, neither Mello nor I could surpass L...
But together... together, we are as able as L.
Together, we can surpass L!
And now as one... against Kira who L himself couldn't take down, it's us who has the evidence!
If you can talk your way out of this, by all means, please do...
That's right.
I am Kira.
So then, what will you do?
Kill me here?
Listen, I am Kira.
And also... God of the new world.
In the world we live in today, Kira is the law and protecting order.
Soon I will be justice.
The hope of all mankind...
Are you going to kill me?
Is that really okay?
In the six years Kira has existed, wars have ceased, violent criminals have almost died out...
But this world still rots!
There are too many rotten people...
Somebody has to do something!
At the time I obtained the notebook, I realized I had to do it!
No... Only I could do it!
I knew that killing people was a crime...
But there was no other way to correct things!
That was the purpose given to me!
Only I could do it...
Who else could have done it?!
To come this far?!
To be able to go on?!
That's right...
To create a new world... Only I can do it.
No... you are just a murderer.
And this notebook is the deadliest weapon in the history of mankind.
You lost yourself to the Shinigami and to the power of the notebook.
And you're mistaken, thinking of becoming a God. You're only a crazy mass murderer.
That's all there is.
Nothing more.
Like those fools would understand...
Near, the note you're holding...
And the one that Aizawa brought from the Japanese Investigation HQ...
Are they real?
Is he attempting to bluff?
I'm the only one who knows if it's the real thing.
If you want to defeat Kira, and prove that Aizawa's note is real...
You'll just have to write down mine or Mikami's name to find out.
If the note is real... or a fake?!
It's a hidden note!!
Matsuda!
You asshole!!
Matsuda! Who do you think you're shooting at?!
Don't fuck with me!!
What was it...
Your father... what did he die for?!
Father?
You mean Yagami Souichiro?
That's right, Matsuda!
Serious people like that, crowned with justice, always lose in the end...
Are you okay living in such a society?!
I know you'll understand, so kill them!
SHOOT THEM!!
You drove your own father to his death...
And now you're saying they are the fools?!
His blood!
Kill... I have to kill him!!
Matsuda!
Damn it...
What the hell is t-this?
Mikami... what the hell are you doing?!
Help!
Write!
Kill them!!
Near, it's over.
Yes.
Misa, where are you??
Where's Takada?!
S-Someone...
It hurts... What do I do?
Mi-Mikami is...
Hang on!
No, but...
At this rate...
Light-kun!
Light-kun! Hold it!
Mr. Aizawa!
He shouldn't have any more hidden notes.
And he can't get far with those wounds...
If we leave him alone, his movements will stop.
Near, I can't follow your orders.
I understand... I'll leave him to you.
You have lost, Light.
In the beginning, didn't I say... at the time of your death, I will be the one who'll write down your name in my notebook?
That is the deal made between the Shinigami and the first human to possess the notebook.
Once you enter a prison, there's no telling when you'll die.
It's annoying to wait... your life is already over... You die here.
It was good while it lasted...
We killed some boredom, didn't we?
We did various interesting things...
Yagami Light