Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Any human whose name is written in this notebook shall... die.
Please! Stop!!
Okay then, let's see what happens.
don't read this line
The Death Note... It's the real deal!
Don't assume that a human who has used the Death Note can go to Heaven or Hell.
I'm going to let the world know of my existence.
That there is someone who can, and will, pass righteous judgement!
And then, I'll become... the God of my new world!
Showdown
He was over-flooded with satisfaction and zealous, then finally his dream came true.
I could never tell what he was thinking, so I had to finish with him
Seriously? So, after that, what happened with your dad?
Yagami-kun? Could you please translate the previous passage into Japanese?
Yes.
Having finally made his dream a reality, he was overwhelmed by the sense of his own achievement and the joy it brought him.
Well done. A perfect translation, but I'd expect nothing less from you, Yagami-kun.
We'll leave it here for today.
Man, am I glad that that's finally over. This "school" thing really bores me.
Hey, Light.
Light, are you listening to me?
Don't talk to me. Other people can hear my voice, unlike yours.
Boring.
Hey, Light! We're all gonna head to th--
Sorry. I've got things to do.
You don't have "things" to do.
Aren't you just gonna go home like always?
What are you talking about? I do have "things" to do.
Very important things...
Yesterday the suspect, Yamada, in the Kabukicho district of Shinjuku, appropriated a knife with a blade length of approximately 12cm from the restaurant where he works and subsequently stabbed a junior employee in the stomach with it.
Hey... Hey, Light?
What?
What's with all the effort?
It's because I can't afford to waste any time.
The time that I have to write names in the notebook is limited from when I get home until I go to bed.
It's important that I maintain my grades, so I can't sleep in class.
I can't neglect my studies at home or cram school either.
Besides, losing sleep will affect my health and my mental capacity.
If I'm serious about changing the world into a purer place, no matter how much time I have, it will never be enough.
Huh? Onii-chan, why is your door locked?
..It's Sayu.
What is it?
Can you help me with my homework?
Oh.. Yeah, okay.
Right now, in Maths, we're doing quadratic equations.
Sorry to disturb you when you're studying, but I just don't get it.
Thanks!
Yes, yes.
Watch out, Light. If anyone touches that notebook in your drawer, they'll be able to see me.
You waited until now to mention such an important detail?
Damned Shinigami..
What's wrong, Onii-chan?
Nothing. Anyway, which bit are you stuck on?
Umm.. All of it?
ICPO, or Interpol, stands for International Criminal Police Organization
There have been 52 known cases in this week alone.
All of them involved heart attacks.
All of them involved criminals that are either already in jail, or being pursued by the police.
I think it's safe to assume that there are still many other deaths that we are yet unaware of.
In which case, the total could easily be over 100.
It's already started, Chief.
Sorry, I had to take a call from headquarters.
But they're all criminals who should have faced the death penalty sooner or later.
Why should we care?
Idiot!
It doesn't matter whether it's a criminal, death row prisoner or whatever! If you kill someone, then that's murder!
But surely it hasn't been confirmed as a homicide yet, has it?
Over 100 criminals dying of heart attacks, coincidences like that doesn't exist! It's obviously murder!
Do you honestly think it's possible to commit so many murders, in different locations, almost all at the same time?
We're treating this as an elaborate assassination plot that is being carried out by a large organization.
A large organization? Then, surely the FBI or the CIA must be involved!
What did you say?!
Whoa, whoa. Let's not mess around here.
The first thing we need to determine, is whether this is murder or just a coincidence.
But, the coroners have all ruled a verdict of "heart attack with no known cause".
Opening a police investigation into heart attacks is going to get us nowhere.
Jeez, if only they'd use a knife or something, then we'd have something to investigate.
Then it looks like we've got no choice but to bring in "L" again!
Chief, what's "L"?
Ah, I'd forgotten that it's your first time here at this conference.
"L" is someone whose real name and whereabouts are unknown. We don't even know what he looks like.
Yet, he always manages to solve every single case he takes on.
He's solved countless mysterious incidents all over the world.
He's the best of those hidden deep within the shadows.. Our trump card. That sums him up.
But I've heard that L is supposedly an extremely arrogant individual who'll only take on cases that interests him personally.
Exactly! We don't even have a way of contacting him!
L is already on the move.
L has already begun his investigations into these incidents.
Wa-Watari.
Huh? Watari?
He's the one man who knows how to contact L.
Nobody knows his true identity either.
Everyone, quiet please. L will now speak.
Greetings to all of you at the ICPO.
I am L.
What's with the secrecy? What're you planning to do in this isolated place, Light?
Anyone who touches the Death Note can see you, right?
I can't risk keeping such a dangerous article in a regular place.
Up until now, I'd been thinking that even if by chance this notebook was seen by my family, I could end the matter by saying I was "taking records of incidents to study for when I become a detective".
Right now, I'm walking a really thin line.
Just one mistake.. and I might have to kill off one of my own family.
The difficulty of this case is on a scale that I've never experienced before.. and, it's an atrocious murder case that I will never forgive!
In order to solve this case, I would like to have everyone in the ICPO, no, the organizations you all represent throughout the world, make the decision to lend their full support to me in this meeting.
In addition, I will require special cooperation from the Japanese police force.
W-Why Japan?!
Whether there's one or more culprits involved, the probability of them being Japanese is extremely high.
Even if they're not Japanese, it's likely that they are in Japan.
What are you basing this theory on?!
Why Japan?
I hope to be able to show you soon.. when I go head-to-head with the culprit.
Head-to-head?
In any case, I'd like the investigation headquarters to be based in Japan.
That was easier than I thought.
You mean you've managed to hide the notebook?
Yeah.. in this drawer.
Doesn't seem to be particularly hidden.
Isn't that key a bit of a give-away?
That's the whole point.
It's better that it is noticeable.
Isn't that just a normal diary?
I'm guessing that most people will have their curiosity satisfied by finding this inside.
But the real key.. is this.
Just an everyday item you'd expect to find on any desk.. The center of a ball-point pen.
And that's the key?
Yes. On closer examination, on the underside, you'll find a small hole.
The pen's center is inserted into the hole.
I see. A fake base, huh?
That, combined with the diary, means that it'll probably be safe.
It's not just that.
Even if someone does figure out that there's a fake base, there's no way they could get their hands on this notebook.
You see, this ball-point pen acts as an insulator preventing the flow of electricity round this circuit.
As the fake base is returned, the rubber stops the flow of electricity.
However, if someone tries to force the fake base open, the circuit will connect and the gasoline in this thin plastic bag will instantly incinerate the notebook.
All the evidence will be destroyed.
If I am asked about this I'll just tell them, "I didn't want anyone to read my diary."
It's a believable excuse. After all, it's human nature to hide your own diary.
I've heard that the main problem humans have with a Death Note is how to hide it.
Light, you're probably the first person to have given it this much thought.
Though that is a pretty risky setup.
One mistake, and you could end up in flames.
Risk? Sometimes you say some funny things, Ryuk.
This whole thing has been a risk from the start...
From the minute I found the Death Note.
Compared to that, this doesn't even qualify as a risk.
On the contrary, it actually protects me.
I mean, which do you think is better?
A death sentence? Or a small house fire?
Last night in a prison in western Tokyo, Kurotsukayama Naoki, aged 32, previously convicted for armed robbery, has been reported to have died of a sudden heart attack.
This sudden phenomenon of inmates dying from heart attacks appears to be continuing..
Man, this is incredible! Criminals are dropping like flies!
It's kinda scary, but at the same time, it's exhilarating!
I guess this means that we can't risk doing anything bad.
So, you reckon the police are probably behind this?
The police don't have that kind of power! Don't you know who it is?
Eh? What?!
It's "Kira" who's behind this. "Kira".
Wonder who'll be next?
"Kira, kill them all."
Do you want to send this mail?
Send mail
239: name Lococo
Kira, kill them all.
Check this out, Ryuk.
Websites like this have already started to emerge.
"The legend of Kira - Our saviour", huh? Pretty cool.
This about you?
Yeah.
Kira taken from the english word "Killer".
Can't really say that I appreciate that too much, but I guess that's what the world now knows me as.
I can get so many sites like this just from a mere search on the word "kira".
In the papers and on TV, it's still not been reported as anything but "a succession of strange deaths amongst the criminals".
But, the people of this world are already starting to become aware that there's someone out there judging them, in the name of justice.
Humans are like that, Ryuk.
This is unlikely, but if anyone asked if killing bad people was wrong in school, people would get on their moral high horse, saying "That's wrong!".
Of course, that is the correct answer to give.
Humans will always seek to maintain appearances in public.
But this is what they're really thinking.
Even if they're too scared to support me publicly, they can hide behind the anonymity of the Internet.
KIRA
Support for "Kira" is growing.
They don't have to say it, because they already know, someone is erasing the wicked.
The innocent are screaming inside; "Go for it Kira!", while those who are guilty, run and hide in fear.
This is how it should be.
It truly is progressing exactly as I'd planned.
Notice
The scheduled program
will be interrupted
for a special broadcast.
Apologies for the interruption, but we now bring you a live worldwide broadcast from the ICPO, Interpol.
Huh? What's this?
Interpol?
It looks like they're ready to begin.
I am the only person who can control the entire world's police forces, Lind L. Tailor.
I go by the code name.. "L".
Who the hell?
And so it begins..
But I don't understand. He's never shown his face before.
Why now?
I guess it means he's taking this seriously.
So, L... We've followed every single one of your orders, now it's time for you to fulfill those promises you made at the ICPO conference.
This successive murdering of criminals is unforgivable, and must not go unpunished.
I guarantee I will find and catch the ring leader, or "Kira".
He says he'll guarantee that he'll catch you.
Fool! There's no way he can catch me.
It's a Death Note!
As long as they don't find it, what proof will they have?!
Catching me is impossible! Absolutely impossible!!
I'd already anticipated that the police would get involved.
Kira, I can guess what your motivation might be, but what you're doing is evil!
I'm the evil one...?
I am justice!!
I save the weak from evil and will become the God of a world that everyone desires!
Those who try to cross God are the true evil ones!
I can't believe that you're this stupid, L.
This could have been fun, if you'd been a little smarter.
I'll show the world what happens when you cross me, L.
Five seconds... Four.. Three.. Two.. One..
What's the matter? Now, what do you have to say?!
I can't believe it...
I tested it just in case, but I never thought it could actually be true..
Kira, it seems you can kill people without having to be there in person.
I wouldn't have been able to believe this if I hadn't just witnessed it.
Listen closely, Kira; if you did indeed kill the "Lind L. Tailor" on screen, I can tell you that he was in fact a criminal that was due to be put to death today.
That was not me.
What?
You wouldn't have heard of him on the news or through the Internet. He was a criminal that was captured by the police in absolute secrecy.
Looks like not even you have information on these kinds of killers.
He definitely got ya this time.
But as for L, he certainly does exist, as my own persona.
Now, try and kill me!!
Y-You bastard...
Go on then!
What the hell's going on?!
Hurry up!
Are you trying to kill yourself, L?!
Kill me!
What's wrong? Kill me!
What's going on?
He's taunting Kira.
Go on! Kill me!
don't read this!
What's the matter? Can't you do it?
So, it seems you can't kill me.
So, there are certain people you can't kill. Thanks for the hint.
As a reward, I'll tell you one more thing.
We lied about this being a live worldwide broadcast.
This announcement is currently only being broadcast across the Kanto region of Japan.
We were planning to broadcast it at different times, across different regions, but it seems that there is no longer any need for this.
I know you're in Kanto.
Hey, this guy, L, is pretty good.
Your first killing was overlooked by the police as it was such a small incident.
However, your first victim was in fact the phantom killer in Shinjuku.
While the other high profile criminals were dying of heart attacks, this was the one incident that stuck out as being quite a heavy punishment for a relatively low profile crime.
In addition, that incident was only reported within Japan.
Otoharada Kurou
Just those pieces of information were enough for me to figure it out.
It means that you are in Japan, and that that criminal was your first "experiment".
Due to its large population, this announcement was first broadcast in the Kanto region.
And what luck! We found you.
To be honest, I'd never thought it would go this smoothly.
Kira, it seems like it won't be too long before I can sentence you to death.
Looks like L's lived up to his reputation.
Yes, he's been able to prove Kira's existence, the nature of his crime, and that he's somewhere in Japan.
Kira, I'm curious to know your true motives behind this, but I guess that can wait until I've caught you.
Let's meet again soon, Kira.
He thinks he's going to sentence me to death?
Interesting! I'll take you on.
So, both of you are trying to find someone whose name you don't know, and whose face you won't recognize.
And the first one to be found dies...
I knew it. Humans are.. so much fun!!
L..
Kira..
I'll hunt you down, and kill you!
I'm..
JUSTICE!
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
I'm not the one who's going to find L, I'll let the police do that for me.
Atrocious Serial Murder Case
Special Investigative Headquarters
And when they do, I'll erase him.
Looks like I'll be able to provide Ryuk with some more entertainment.
Next Time
The Deal