Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Love
Yagami
Light, Ryuuzaki has asked for your help with the investigation.
If you're willing to help, we need you to come here as soon as possible.
I understand, father.
And here I was thinking of how to start discussing the subject with them...
I never imagined that they would approach me with this first.
In this manner, I'll be able to investigate both the Investigative Headquarters and the fake Kira as much as I want.
Whatever it takes, I've got to find the fake Kira before they do.
Thank you, Yagami-kun.
No problem; after all, we both want to catch Kira, Ryuuga.
Please call me "Ryuuzaki" while you're here.
I'm Matsui.
I'm Aihara.
And I'm Asahi.
I see...
So, does that make me "Asahi Light"?
Yes, That is good.
While you're here, I'll call you "Light-kun".
Sorry for throwing you in at the deep end, but I need you to look over all the current material we have on the investigation, including the videos that were sent to the Japanese TV station.
I'm afraid that I can't let you take any of the material away, or make notes of it.
Understood.
In that case, let's begin.
Light...
Last night
So... we'll proceed by hiding the possibility of a second Kira, and by having Yagami Light assist us with the investigation.
B-But won't it be hard for us to investigate with him if we do that?
He's right. What's the point in him helping us in this investigation anyway?
No, we only need to hide this from him till we've heard his opinions on these videos.
Light-kun's skills of deduction are truly quite amazing.
If he sees these videos, he may be able to deduce that this is the work of a second Kira.
But the basis for claiming that there is a second Kira... you say that the victims of the predicted murders were ones Kira wouldn't normally have killed, "since they only committed minor crimes",
but that theory of yours is the only basis we have, isn't it Ryuuzaki?
That's not the only reason.
Up until now, we've assumed that Kira needs a face and a name in order to kill.
Yet, from the fact that Ukita-san was killed when he happened to rush to the TV station that time... and from the fact that Kira spoke as if they could kill L merely by having him appear on TV,
we can come to the conclusion that the second Kira can kill people merely by seeing their faces.
If, after reviewing the case and watching these videos, Light-kun is able to deduce that there is a second Kira, the majority of my suspicions against him will be lifted.
What do you mean by that, Ryuuzaki?
It's evident that Kira wants to kill the L who has been leading the police force.
If things continue to progress as they are, I will die after appearing on TV in three days' time.
I doubt that Kira would let an opportunity like this pass.
What if my son doesn't manage to deduce that there is a second Kira?
Does it mean that your suspicions will deepen?
No. If that happens, my suspicions will remain at 5% or lower.
We'll reveal to him that we're investigating the possibility of a second Kira, and have him assist us with that.
I believe that you have understood from this that I am Kira.
On the date and time specified...
Watching these videos... the terrible quality of them makes me feel sick... is that just because I am the real Kira?
This is far more serious than a simple drop in my image as Kira...
But why has no one offered any explanations for any of these videos?
There's something odd going on here...
Either way, I better not say anything stupid regarding this.
If I leave things as they are, L will die.
How is it going, Light-kun? Have you been able to deduce anything from this?
Why you--!
There's a possibility that there's more than one person who has Kira's power.
K-Kira's power? What are you saying, Light?
If nothing else, there's a high probability that this is not the same Kira that we've been dealing with until now.
The Kira we've been dealing with until now would not have utilized the suspects used in this broadcast.
Add the fact that if Kira does indeed need a name and a face to kill, it's strange that they were able to kill the policemen who merely happened to go to the TV station.
I-It's the same...
The same as L... I mean, that's exactly the same theory as Ryuuzaki!
W-Well done, Light!
The suspicions against you should now be lifted.
That's right, Light-kun. We also believe that there's a second Kira.
As I thought...
You already knew, Ryuuga? I mean.. Ryuuzaki.
You were testing me, weren't you?
I wasn't testing you.
If I were the only one to have come up with the "second Kira" theory, people may have trouble believing me.
Since you've come to the same conclusion as I did, it's become a much more convincing viewpoint.
Light-kun, you really are extremely helpful.
So, it's decided.
Firstly, we have to stop the second Kira.
Evidently, they sympathize with Kira, but they aren't very intelligent.
They might even obey the real Kira.
Thus, there's a good chance that we might be able to stop them by sending them a message from the real Kira.
I'd have expected nothing less from you, Ryuuzaki.
I was also thinking of that as the best course of action.
I'd like you, Light-kun, to play the real Kira.
M-Me?!
Yes. With your talent, it shouldn't be a problem.
Anyhow, we don't have a lot of time.
Can you write a response from "Kira" ready to be aired on this evening's news?
You bastard...
Is this what you planned all along? Is that why you brought me here?
Ryuuzaki, is this okay?
I really think I became Kira, just for a moment.
It's very good... but unless you take out the bit that says, "I don't mind if you kill L"... I'll die.
Ah, yes. If I were in Kira's shoes, in the current situation, I'm sure I'd order L's death.
It's just a joke. You can change it to whatever you want.
Yes...
Aihara-san, the report is ready.
Okay!
A terrible thing has occurred!
In response to the videos sent in by Kira and aired on Sakura TV, messages have been received from another person claiming that they are the real Kira.
They have demanded that the message from the real Kira is broadcast on all TV channels.
Police Headquarters have agreed for the video to be broadcast.
Is this Kira? Or are they both Kira?
First, take a look at this video sent in by Kira.
I'm Kira.
Yay! I got a response from Kira!
I am the real Kira, and those videos sent to Sakura TV were not from Kira.
Currently, I will tolerate the actions of the one that is taking my name.
They have worked on my behalf, and have tried to aid me.
However, taking the lives of innocent people is directly against my beliefs.
If the person taking my name holds the same beliefs as I, and is willing to help me, they must stop acting impulsively, and learn to understand my true intentions.
Let's see now... Video, video!
If you do not heed this warning, you will leave me with no choice but to pass judgement on you.
hidden lines
What are you planning on doing?
Naturally, I'm gonna send a response to Kira right away!
A few days later
Ryuuzaki! We've received a response from the second Kira!
What?!
It's here!
I'll bring the envelope and everything else over as soon as I can; for the moment, I'm sending a copy to your computer.
Kira-san, thank you for your response.
I will do as you ask.
We did it!
"I will do as you ask", huh?
I can't tell whether I can use them or not...
If they truly understood Kira's feelings, they should have enforced L's appearance on TV, and killed him!
Don't mess things up... Damn it!
I want to meet you, Kira-san.
I don't believe that you have the eyes, but don't worry, I won't kill you.
What is this idiot thinking?!
They're talking about the Shinigami's eyes on a video that's being broadcast to the entire nation!
Did they just say, "I don't believe that you have the eyes"?
Dunno...
Please think of a way that we can meet without the police finding out.
Once we meet, we can confirm our identities by showing each other our Shinigami.
Shinigami?!
This person is hopeless... If I don't do something fast...
What?!
R-Ryuuzaki!!
Are you okay?
S-Shinigami...
Are you trying to tell me... that such things exist?!
Are you trying to tell me.. that such things exist?!
S-Surely not...
There's no way that they exist...
He's right, Ryuuzaki. There's no way that Shinigami actually exist.
Kira used prisoners to write sentences about Shinigami...
If that's true, shouldn't we consider this to be the work of the original Kira?
The same words from the same person?
I doubt that, father.
The Kira we have dealt with until now wouldn't have replied to our video.
The real Kira wouldn't have bought this story. And they wouldn't have prevented L from going on TV to be killed.
Then, is there a possibility that the real Kira and the second Kira may already have joined forces, and are using the term "Shinigami" to confuse our investigation?
I don't think there's any chance of that happening.
Light-kun is correct. If Kira is involved, I doubt that they'd stop trying to kill me.
This second Kira appears to be acting on their own interests, rather than Kira's beliefs.
Basically, their desire to meet Kira.
Exactly.
They are acting on their own curiosity about Kira.
Perhaps "Shinigami" is referring to their ability to kill.
"Confirm our identities by showing each other our Shinigami", could mean that they'll confirm each other's identity by demonstrating their ability to kill.
You could be right...
At the very least, we can consider "Shinigami" as a common term of some significance between Kira and the second Kira.
We need to try to clarify that.
So, will we reply again to guide them?
If we probe too deeply, they may realize that we know nothing, and that we aren't really Kira.
No. From now on, we'll leave it to Kira and the second Kira.
Leave it to them?
I assume that having received a reply from Kira, the second Kira is now content about the current situation.
They believe that they've successfully appealed to Kira.
Plus, they are using words that only they would know the significance of.
We'll repeat this reply on the 6:00pm news on Sakura TV.
The real Kira will be watching to view the interaction between the second Kira and the fake Kira that we've created.
The real Kira would want to avoid any contact between the second Kira and the police.
If we're lucky, we'll get a response from the real Kira this time.
But what if we don't receive a response from Kira?
Well... I've tried to think of what the second Kira would do in this situation, and...
they would probably tell the police and the public further information that Kira would not want them to know,
to force Kira to seek an audience with them!
This could be very interesting!
It'll be even more interesting if Kira does fear such a response, and sends their own message by video.
If that does happen, we'll have more physical evidence against Kira.
Then, for the time being, let us pursue the second Kira.
That's good.
That's it, that's it!
That's good. That's so hot, Misa-chan!
Brilliant!
I'm so tired... Being a model is all about having stamina.
Hey, Rem?
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Shinigami need to have a Death Note.
For Shinigami to play with humans, they need to have two.
The Shinigami, Ryuk, who gave a notebook to Kira, tricked the Shinigami Overlord and got a second notebook, right?
That's right.
Did you do that too?
No. The Shinigami Overlord isn't that easy to trick.
So, how did you manage it?
I'm rare in the Shinigami world.
I'm one of the few who actually knows how to kill a Shinigami.
Let's leave it at that.
So, you killed a Shinigami, and gave Misa their notebook?
No... I didn't kill them.
I just happened to be there when a Shinigami died.
Hey, tell me how to kill a Shinigami!
You mustn't tell anyone.
The way to kill a Shinigami is... to make them fall in love with a human.
What a beautiful way to kill someone.
There was once a Shinigami named Jealous, who used to constantly gaze at one particular girl from his place in the Shinigami world.
From the Shinigami world, Jealous was always, always, watching that girl.
It's today, isn't it? That girl's life runs out...
She seems so full of life... I wonder why it's today...
I wonder... why today?
I also became curious as to how she would die, so I chose to watch with him.
She was walking alone late at night... and then.. suddenly a man appeared from an alley, and confessed his love for the girl.
I love you more than anyone in this world!!
I want to watch over, and protect you forever!!
The girl, having never seen the man before, naturally refused him.
Then... I'll kill you... before killing myself!
Hey! Stop that!!
Jealous did something that no Shinigami should ever do.
Jealous used his Death Note to save that girl...
But that is not allowed.
Shinigami exist solely to take human lives in order to increase their own.
At that moment, Jealous turned into sand, or rust... something I couldn't identify... and died.
All that remained was the Death Note.
Jealous's life was added to the lifespan of the girl he had been watching.
If he wasn't in love with that girl, he wouldn't have died?
That's right.
So, the person... who helped me back then... was Jealous, the Shinigami.
Correct.
Jealous was in love with you.
That's why that notebook is yours.
I see. You've got to make a Shinigami fall in love and help someone.
What about you Rem? You aren't falling for me, are you?
Give it up. You can't kill me.
Oh, so you guessed it?
But now I have something else I can tell Kira!
I wonder if they know how-to-kill-a-Shinigami?
I told them on TV to think up a good way for us to meet each other, but I still haven't had a response...
Maybe I should say something again!
This isn't good... There's no way I can leave the second Kira to their own devices.
If the second Kira makes a critical error, and gets captured by the police, there's a chance that they could find out about the Death Note.
Welcome.
A strawberry sundae please!
Coming right up.
But how.. should I contact the second Kira without L noticing...
Sorry for the delay.
I can't wait to meet Kira!
Still... I wonder what they're like... fake Kira...
I wonder what they're like... Kira!
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
May 22nd: At Aoyama, we looked at each other's notebooks.
If the second Kira gets caught, at the very least, I've got to get their notebook, and in the worst case scenario, kill anyone that happens to be there.
Next time
Confessions