Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Doubt
I've got to admit that I was rather surprised, Ryuuga, to be invited to play tennis with you so that we could get to know each other better.
Has this caused a problem for you?
Not at all... but were you aware of how skilled I am when you asked me to play?
That's okay, Yagami-kun.
I used to be the Junior Champion of England.
If I ask him, "Does that mean you're English?", will he think that I'm attempting to question him because I am Kira?
Never mind. I'll just give it a try.
Were you brought up in England?
I've lived in England for about five years.
But I wouldn't worry about it, there's nothing about that which will compromise my identity as L.
Oh, I see...
You're fine with the winner being whoever wins the first set of six games, I assume?
I've got it.
This is strictly a friendly tennis match.
I won't be able to use this to help me judge whether he's Kira or not.
But Kira does supposedly hate to lose...
Fifteen - love
Hey, hey, Ryuuga, you're getting serious already?
He who takes the initiative wins.
What do you mean, "you can't say"?!
I'm extremely sorry.
Under L's orders, I can't tell anyone outside the Investigative Headquarters, even if you are the Deputy Chief.
You can't even tell me what you're doing, and where?!
I'm extremely sorry...
Say, Yagami. It's already been four months since this case first came to light.
The public believe that the police are incompetent, and that L is incompetent.
Excuse me for saying this, Deputy, but can you honestly say that a police force that turns tail and runs scared of Kira is "competent"?
I'm sure you're well aware of how many of us remained at Headquarters.
If you're so concerned with public opinion, just make sure they don't find out the truth; that the majority of the police force, and especially the leaders, have fled from Kira!
Excuse me.
Yagami.
What's L like?
Can we trust him?
He's far more capable than we are.
Even now, he's making the moves personally, placing his own life on the line.
Are they meant to be amateurs?
Who the hell are they?
It's Yagami Light and Ryuuga Hideki.
Both of them enrolled with the top grades.
Don't worry, Yagami.
Although Kira hates to lose, the majority of people would want to win in a match, whether they are Kira or not.
Going all out for a win is in keeping with Kira's character? Is this it?!
But if I purposely lose for that reason — thinking that going for a complete victory is Kira-like — then my purposely losing will also be Kira-like, won't it?
It all comes down to the same thing.
There's no way he can use this match to create a profile of me.
The objective of this match lies elsewhere.
That's why, even at tennis... I will win this too!
See. I knew you would want to win.
Game count, four games all!
Somehow, both a referee and a linesman have appeared.
Senpai!
I thought I'd heard the name Yagami Light before, so I went and looked it up.
Turns out he was the Junior Champion in 2002 and 2003!
During the award ceremony, in his third year of Junior High, he announced; "I'm quitting this hobby at the end of Junior High".
Since then, he hasn't participated in any tournaments.
Hey, hey! Ryuuga-kun is managing to hold his own against a Junior Champion, so what does that make him?!
I can read you, Yagami Light.
I can read your feelings.
There's no way our friendship is going to deepen thanks to this tennis match.
This is just a ritual formality allowing us to acknowledge that we became better friends.
You believe that I'm using this match to advance my preparations in breaking you.
I bet that you'll try to make me say something that only Kira will know.
First you'll state that you need to know what information I have on Kira in order to trust me.
If we're going to talk about the Kira case, I'll have to at least request proof that he's actually the one in charge at the moment.
That's why... you'll request that I... provide significant proof from a third-party that you are L.
do not read this line
Basically... to take you to the Investigative Headquarters.
Basically... to take me to the Investigative Headquarters.
No matter what the situation, you can't win solely by defending.
To win, you need to attack!
Game, set; won by Yagami!
Six games to four.
Wow!
Amazing!
Wow! Amazing!
You're as good as I expected you to be. I lost.
That's the first time that I've gotten serious over something in a while, Ryuuga.
I'm thirsty, and I have a favor I'd like to ask of you, so shall we stop for a drink after this?
Well, seeing that I lost the game, ask away.
But there's just one thing I got to mention first.
What?
I suspect that you may be Kira.
If that's not a problem, feel free to ask me anything.
Me, Kira?
Well, when I say "suspect", it's only about 1%.
More importantly, I'd like to confirm both that you're not Kira, and also the rumors regarding your skills of deduction, before asking you to help with the investigation.
1%, huh?
That's an excellent way of putting it.
If they suspect me even in the slightest, they won't allow me near their Headquarters even if I ask.
You've made the first move.
You've got me.
This café is a favorite of mine.
If you sit here, people won't be able to overhear your conversations.
Thanks for showing me this place, it's nice.
You don't need to worry about sitting like that here.
I've got to sit like this.
If I sit normally, my investigative abilities decrease by 40%.
So, what's this favor you wanted to ask of me?
Oh, I think I'll leave that until you've confirmed that I'm not Kira.
You can go first. Ask me anything.
Okay. I don't mean to be rude, but would you mind if I tested your skills of deduction?
No, go right ahead.
It sounds fun.
Okay then. First, I'd like you to take a look at these.
These three are photos of letters; it's thought that Kira controlled criminals in a prison, and then, before they died, had them write these.
Please let me hear your opinions about them.
Interesting.
Honestly, this is child's play.
There are print numbers on the back of these.
If I create the sentence "L, did you know Shinigami only eat apples?" without even looking at them, it'll deepen your suspicions, right?
But just because I'm able to solve this simple puzzle, it won't prove that I am Kira.
If Kira can truly manipulate not only the time of death, but also the actions of people prior to death, it'd be amazing.
In fact, these messages contain hidden messages that seem to be teasing you.
If you take only the top letters from each sentence, and read from left to right, it creates another sentence.
Arranging it in the most natural way, it would be... "L did you know Shinigami only eat apples", I guess.
But there are also print numbers on the back of these photos.
If you place them in that order... "L, did you know that if they only eat apples, Shinigami", but this seems rather unnatural, and I find it hard to believe that this is what Kira wanted to say.
Incorrect.
There is in fact a fourth photo.
If you include this, it becomes something like this...
"L, did you know that if they only eat apples, Shinigami have red hands."
The fourth one is fake.
It isn't something that I've made a criminal write.
Is he stupid or something?
But my theory is perfect if there are only three photos.
No, it was incorrect.
There are in fact four. It would have been correct if you had accounted for that.
Despite the fact that the sentence didn't end, you decided that there were only three photos, and were unable to deduce that there may have been a fourth.
That is a fact.
You...
I get it. He's not trying to test my deduction skills; he's analyzing my reactions.
If I try to challenge him further, I'll be doing exactly what he wants me to...
Yeah... I wasn't able to deduce that much.
Either way, they aren't messages that will bring us any closer to Kira.
It's not like Shinigami really exist.
Yagami-kun, if you were L, and were with someone you suspected might be Kira, how would you go about proving it?
I'd make them say something that hasn't been broadcast to the public; something that only Kira would know.
What you are trying to do right now.
Amazing. I've asked many detectives this question, yet most of them need at least a few minutes before they can answer.
You however, were instantaneously able to think as Kira would if they were confronted with someone investigating them.
Your sense of reasoning is amazing.
If my ideas are too good, it seems like you'll get even more suspicious!
Yes, by 3%.
But at the same time, my desire to have you investigate with us has also grown. Even if you are Kira.
I'm in a position where it would still benefit me to have you investigate with us.
Do you understand this logic?
If I help with the investigation, there's a potential for it to move forward.
Also, if I'm Kira, I might somehow give myself away.
In other words, you can both investigate and interrogate at the same time.
I think that's a good idea... but I think that you're misunderstanding something here.
It's true that I'm interested in the Kira case, and that I also enjoy investigating as a hobby, but I'm not Kira, and I don't want to be killed by Kira.
Besides, you don't have any proof that you're not Kira!
In that case, it'd be strange for only one of us to be investigating the other.
There's nothing to prove that either of us aren't Kira, but since you claim to be L, we should at least be able to prove that.
For example, we could get my father or another member of the investigation to identity you in front of me.
If that's not possible, then I can't investigate with you.
You're talking a fair amount, Yagami Light.
Typical of someone who doesn't like to lose.
7%.
Maybe it really is...
I never said anything about not allowing you to meet the people at the Investigative Headquarters.
Huh?!
Currently I'm working both with your father and the others at the Investigative Headquarters.
So, if I take you to the Investigative Headquarters, I can get you to cooperate with our investigation.
Have I understood that correctly?
What the hell is this guy thinking?!
Excuse me.
Me too.
Yes.
Ryuuzaki! Something terrible has happened!
Light! Your father...
Yagami-kun!!
Father? A heart attack?!
Well, I'll see you tomorrow, and I'll bring some essentials.
I'll leave the rest up to you, Light.
Okay.
Are you sure you're just overworked?
Yeah. When I first went down I thought that it might be Kira... but it's alright.
I've probably been overdoing it recently.
All the more because you knew that your son was suspected of being Kira.
You even told my father that?!
Yes, I've told him everything.
Even the fact that I'm L.
He's right. He is L.
We call him "Ryuuzaki" so that outsiders don't realize it, but without a doubt, he is L.
He's the real L.
That's what father is saying.
So if nothing else, he's the L that's been controlling the police.
If I can erase him and everyone else on the investigation... wait. It's not going to be that simple.
There's no reason to rush.
I just need to investigate this situation thoroughly.
Either way, right now, I've got to be the Yagami Light who's worried about his father.
So, Ryuuzaki, have your suspicions about my son lessened now that you've had a chance to talk to him?
You say "suspicion", but it was only a very small amount.
Let me say it once more.
Kira has killed twelve FBI agents that were sent to this country.
They were all investigating people connected to the Japanese police force.
Out of all of them, Ray Penber's death stood out as being suspicious.
And I was one of the ones he was investigating...
I guess it can't be helped that I'm a suspect then.
It's as Ryuuga says; there's no one else to suspect.
Your reasoning is quite something.
It's always fast and precise.
Ryuuga, I'll cooperate with the investigation.
After all, my father proved that you're L.
I'll catch Kira, and prove to you that I'm not Kira.
Light. Right now, you should be concentrating on your studies in order to join the police force.
You can start investigating after that.
What are you saying, father?
Nobody knows how many years that could take.
In any case, I've already promised that... if anything happens to you... I'll make sure Kira is sentenced to death.
There's no way my son is Kira.
I'm sure this can't be an act.
No, it's too suspicious to be an act.
Listen up, Light. Kira is evil.
That's the truth.
But recently, I've been wondering what's really to blame... and it's the power to kill others.
Any human that comes across that power will be unhappy.
No matter how one uses that power, you can never build true happiness on the deaths of others.
Yagami-san is correct.
If Kira is just an ordinary person that somehow acquired these powers, they are indeed unfortunate.
Sorry to trouble you like this, Ryuuzaki.
I'll do my best to recover.
Umm.. Visiting hours are now over.
Ryuuga.
Is there any way that I can prove to you that I'm not Kira?
If you aren't Kira, then there's no need for you to do that.
Come off it!
Try thinking about how it feels to be the one accused of being Kira!
I would feel awful.
For example, you could lock me up for a month, without TV or anything, and keep me under supervision.
Is it normal for someone to want to clear their name this much?
No. I wouldn't do something that would infringe on your basic human rights like that.
And most importantly, it would be nonsense for me to accept the suggestion of someone who's a suspect.
I see.
It'll be alright.
If you aren't Kira, I'll find out sooner or later.
Plus, having witnessed your interaction with your father today, I thought that you might not be Kira.
Please take care of your father.
O-One last thing.
I said I'd cooperate with the investigation, but until my father gets better, I don't think I can do much.
I know.
Goodbye.
Ryuuga Hideki... Ryuuzaki... he's the L I've been fighting all along.
His real name is...
Yagami Light... are you not Kira?
Ryuk.
Huh?
I've never once thought of me finding this notebook as unfortunate.
I'm so happy to have this power... and I'll create a perfect world with it.
I don't care whether the notebook makes you happy or unhappy, Light.
But, I've heard that normally, people who are haunted by Shinigami, usually end up unhappy.
Well, Ryuk.
I guess you'll get to see a pattern that's not normal then.
I'm thankful for that.
What's going on?!
Is this the best plan ya can come up with?!
You better not be thinking that ya can get ratings by only airing programs about Kira!
The reason my channel has survived is because we air stories that other channels don't do!
Got it?
The problem is getting stories.
Someone bring me a good story!
You say that, but the police aren't saying anything; it's impossible.
Fool! If you don't have a story, who cares if it's a fake, just make one up!
Director Demegawa, there's a special delivery for you.
What's this?
Who's this from?
This is what I'm talking about.
This is the kind of stuff I need ya guys to come up with.
Along with proving
the fact that I am Kira
a message from Kira to the world
will also be broadcast.
If you don't air this,
I will kill off your company,
beginning with the president.
This is too much!
A message from Kira to the world
"If you don't air this, I will kill off your company, starting off with the president", apparently!
Like I'd dare to oppose this!
If this is real, it's going to be amazing!
I'm so excited, my heart's pumping like mad!
To Director Demegawa
- Sakura TV
I am Kira.
Proof is provided in video tape one.
Once you've ascertained that I am Kira,
please air tapes two to four on the
dates listed on the next page from your station.
By fore-warning people of these murders,
along with proving to society the fact that
I am Kira.
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
Given the current situation, there's a good chance that L will be buried within the next four days.
God is on my side after all.
Well, when I say "God", I mean "Shinigami".
Next Time
Charge