Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Charge
Next, about Misora Naomi, isn't it about time that we open up the investigation to the public?
If we do, we should try to avoid any connections being made to the Kira case.
Use an artist's impression rather than a photo.
But, it's already been four months since she vanished.
I can only imagine that she's dead.
Even if she's dead, it's strange that no one has been able to locate her body yet.
If we can find it, it may shed some light on this situation.
Ryuuzaki.
Sakura TV.
Something terrible is occurring.
Basically, we're presenting this broadcast as Kira's hostages, but also as reporters fulfilling their duties.
Please understand that we would never air this broadcast with an intent to deceive or with a wish to gain popularity.
Kira's hostages?
What's going on?
Four days ago, the director on duty received these four tapes.
Without a doubt, they have been sent by Kira.
Our ratings will rise by 60%... no, 70% at least!
The first tape contained predictions of the date and times of death for two suspects that were recently apprehended.
Yesterday both suspects died at exactly their predicted times of death.
If that is really true, it's definitely something only Kira can do.
We've received orders from Kira to play this second tape today at exactly 5:59pm.
We've been informed that this will contain a predicted murder as further proof that they are Kira, and also a message to the people of the world.
A-Are you sure that this isn't another joke?
Surely... no one would pull a prank that's this sick.
Here it is.
I am Kira.
If this video is being broadcast at exactly 5:59pm on the 18th of April, it should now be 5:59pm and 47... 48... 49...
Please change the channel to Taiyou TV now.
The main newsreader, Hibima Kazuhiko, will die of a heart attack at exactly 6 o'clock.
Change it.
No way...
You okay?!
Stop filming!
I said turn it off!
Get help!!
How dare they...
Change the channel back.
Hibima Kazuhiko continued to air his claims that Kira is evil.
Also, bring me another TV. No, make that two.
This is his due.
Yes.
Another sacrifice will have to be made.
The target will be someone currently live on NHN TV.
A commentator who's been negative about me, Kobaizumi Seiji.
Ryuuzaki!
Turn to channel 24.
Huh?! Pull yourself together!
Please change it back.
I think that, by now, you should all believe that I am Kira.
Kira said that they wanted to send a message to the world, but...
We've got to stop this broadcast, or there will be trouble!
I'll phone Sakura TV!
No good, my acquaintance at the station has his phone switched off.
No matter what part of the station I ring it's all busy!
Screw this...
Ukita-san!
I'll go to the station in person and make them stop!
Everyone, listen carefully, I don't want to have to kill innocent people.
I hate evil, and love justice.
I even regard the police as my ally, and not as my enemy.
Damn you, Kira...
My wish is to create a world without any evil.
If you all decide similarly, it should be easy to achieve.
If you cease your attempts to capture me, no innocent people will die.
Damn...
Even if you don't agree with me, as long as you don't go to the media, or express it publicly, I won't kill you.
Please try and wait a while; this world will become something that anyone would appreciate.
I will change this filthy world into a world that's build for gentle people.
Try to imagine this.
The police and I will creat--
Sachiko...
Darling, this is bad for your health. Please try to get some rest.
Sachiko... I'm the Chief of the Kira Special Investigation Unit.
Shit! It's shut!
Police! Open up!
Idiots!!
We interrupt this program to bring you live footage from outside the Sakura TV station!
Hello? Damn it! I can't get through.
Aizawa-san!
As you can see, someone has collapsed!
This is the scene occuring outside Sakura TV right now!
Ukita-san...
S-Shit!! Was it Kira?!
Aizawa-san!
Where do you think you're going?
To Ukita, of course.
You can't.
Please compose yourself.
Are you telling me to just shut up and watch TV?!
If this is Kira's work, and you go there, the same thing will happen to you.
If Kira doesn't have a name, they shouldn't be able to kill!
So why has this happened?!
Were the fake IDs useless?
Maybe... Kira already knew our names?
That's a possibility.
But if Kira did know that, it would have been a lot easier for them to kill us first.
According to my theory, Kira needs a name and a face, but having watched this, it seems that the probability of Kira being able to kill someone solely by knowing their face isn't zero.
According to my theory, Kira needs a name and a face, but having watched this, it seems that the probability of Kira being able to kill someone solely by knowing their face, isn't zero.
Right now, the only think that I can say, is that Kira is inside the station, or at least somewhere where they can monitor the people entering--
If you think that Kira is around that area, there's even more of a reason to go!
There's always the possibility that they set up surveillance cameras.
If you carelessly rush out there now, you'll only be killed.
You! I thought that you were risking your life to catch Kira!
Risking your life, and allowing someone to easily take it, are two completely different things.
Risking your life, and allowing someone to easily take it are two completely different things.
What?!
Try and hold back.
Now that Ukita-san has been killed, if you were to lose your life too...
To the police; please decide whether you will cooperate with me in creating a new world,
and announce your answer of "yes" or "no" in four days' time, during the 6 o'clock news on the 22nd of April.
I have prepared videos for both "yes" and "no" responses.
What the hell is going on?!
Hey! What do you think you're playing at?!
Where's the studio that's airing the Kira tapes?!
It's a patrol van! A patrol van has charged into Sakura TV!
That's one way of entering the station without revealing your identity...
But who is it?
Police! Stop the broadcast!
W-What's going on?
I'm telling you to stop the Kira tapes!
W-Wait a second Detective. If we stop this tape, we'll be killed by Kira...
Hand them over!
If you do that, you can save your life right now, if nothing else.
W-What are you thinking?! Are you insane?
This is the result of you covering the Kira case as though they are some kind of star.
"You reap what you sow", don't you agree?
I want all the copies as well.
Don't even think about trying to get out of this now!
O-Okay! I'll get them, I'll get them, so stop waving that pistol around!
Your eyes are crazy...
Finally, a single police car has arrived outside Sakura TV.
So we're not the only ones... there are still others in the force that want to stand up and fight!
Aizawa-san, you know the cell phone number of Deputy Chief Kitamura, right?
Aizawa, I thought that I told you not to call me.
This is L. I'd like to ask a favor of you.
Upon seeing this broadcast, people connected with the police will act, driven by their own sense of personal justice.
I'd like you to control this directly from the top, or this could turn into a disaster.
But on this case, we're...
Both of the policemen that rushed to the scene have collapsed!
W-We will also be evacuating the area!
Understood. L, please advise me on how I should command.
It's Chief Yagami.
Call him back, and hand me the phone.
Please hurry and let me talk to Ryuuzaki.
It's me. Yagami-san, so it was you in the patrol van.
Yes... I couldn't stop myself.
I've seized all the tapes, and I'll bring them over to you.
Are you alright?
I fell more than alright. In fact, I've never felt this alive before!
Never mind that, what should I do?
I think the front entrace is dangerous, but I should be fine in the car.
Please wait a minute.
Deputy Kitamura, Chief Yagami was the one who charged into the station.
How are your preparations proceeding?
We've done as you asked.
Yagami-san, please leave openly through the front entrance in five minutes.
Openly? Through the front entrance?
There are to be no gaps! Understood?!
Ensure that you aren't seen!
Kira won't be inside the station; if they're here, they're outside!
Thank you.
I'll drive myself.
Understood.
Listen up!
There's a good chance that Kira may be somewhere within visual range.
Devise methods of searching that ensures you can't be seen.
The police have ignored Kira, and have shown us that they are ready to fight.
I-It takes courage for me to say this... but what they are doing is right! This is right!
This is the position a constitutional nation should take!
My name is Tanakabara Kouki.
The announcer for NHN's "Golden news"... Tanakabara Kouki!
Chief!
Chief Yagami!
Ryuuzaki... I apologize for acting on impulse.
It seems I got a little too emotional.
Not at all.
All the envelopes and tapes sent by Kira are in here.
Thank you very much.
L-Let me rest for a while...
Yagami-san, I won't let this go to waste.
It's postmarked from Osaka.
However, Kira is able to manipulate people before death, so they wouldn't have to go to Osaka themselves to mail this.
Aizawa-san, can I ask you to analyze these?
I'm good at that. I'll do a thorough job.
Please do.
I'll confirm the contents of the copied tapes.
How is it, Ryuuzaki?
It was an interesting video.
If the police agree to cooperate with Kira, there are orders to broadcast video three, and if they refuse, video four is to be played.
On video three, there are detailed conditions regarding the cooperation.
In a nutshell, it's to report information on more criminals.
Even if they've committed less serious crimes, there are instructions to pick out those who harm others, and those that abuse the weak and vulnerable.
Kira will then decide whether to pass judgement on them or not.
In addition, as proof that the police are willing to cooperate, they order both L and a senior member of the police to appear on TV, and announce "We will cooperate with Kira".
By exposing the faces of myself and a senior policeman, should the police attempt anything funny, they would be able to kill us.
What about the contents of the fourth video, if we answer "no"?
It's more or less the same thing, but said in a different way.
The answer is bound to be "no", Yagami-san. Please authorize Sakura TV to play tape four.
I think that it's a great shame that you've chosen to answer "no".
Since this reply indicates that the police will persistently fight against me,
I will have to take the life of the Chief of the Japanese Police Force, or alternatively, the life of the person directing this investigation, known as L.
The Chief of Police or L?
Which one of you will pay the price for deciding not to help me create a peaceful world?
Please decide within four days.
God is on my side after all.
Well, when I say "God", I mean "Shinigami".
Looks that way.
Another Shinigami has come down to Earth, and that Shinigami's Death Note has passed into the hands of a human who supports Kira.
It's highly probable that this Kira has the eyes of a Shinigami.
In other words, this Kira's ability to kill is far greater than mine.
Given the current situation, it'll be fine to leave them alone for a while.
There's a good chance that L will be buried.
But, what I can't forgive, is that they've lowered Kira's dignity by using such inferior methods!
It'll also be problematic if the fake messes up, gets caught, and people find out about the Death Note.
I can't leave them to their own devices for too long.
Right now, the ideal thing for me to do would be... to help out with the investigation, and grasp both L's and the fake Kira's moves.
Ryuuzaki, it's just as we thought.
Of their own accord, world leaders have discussed this, and they want the real L to appear on TV.
That is the correct choice to make, but we still have three days, so let's try and think of some countermeasures.
I'd be pretty upset... if I was killed by someone who's merely jumping onto the "Kira" bandwagon.
What do you mean by that, Ryuuzaki?!
The probability of this Kira being a fake is extremely high.
No, a "second Kira" is probably a better description.
A second Kira?
What makes you think that there's a second Kira?
Please explain this to us.
Firstly, if you look at the first tape used to convince the TV station's employees,
it's noticeable that the victims of the predicted deaths, were only reported on the "Wide Show" or in women's magazines.
Wide Show is a news and gossip show that airs in Japan.
The real Kira wouldn't have bothered with such small fry.
But, if we think of them as a second Kira... it'd have been too risky for them to use any criminal that the real Kira may potentially kill before them.
Ryuuzaki, what are the chances of there being a second Kira?
This time it's over 70%.
Either way, I don't like their methods... It's unlike Kira.
"Unlike"?
Up till now, with the exception of those chasing after them, Kira has avoided sacrificing the innocent.
If we can catch one of the Kiras, I think that we'll get hints to help catch the other.
Yagami-san, would it be okay if we asked your son to help us in the investigation?
So, am I to understand that you no longer suspect him?
No, I can't say that I don't still suspect him, but I am counting on his skills of deduction.
So that's what you mean...
If this is what my son wants, I see no reason to stop him.
Thank you very much.
But, please don't tell him that we suspect that this Kira may be a fake.
Please give the impression that we're determinedly pursuing one Kira.
Hey, Misa... I kindly gave that Death Note to you, so why don't you use it more for yourself?
I am using it for myself.
After all, I support Kira!
So I want to know what kind of person Kira is.
And I want to meet and talk to them.
That's why I went through the trouble of sending those tapes to the TV station, and ensured that I could get Kira to notice me!
Kira will be interested. I'm sure of it!
That's a dangerous game you're playing.
You could be killed. You know that, right?
It'll be okay. I'm sure Kira is kind to innocent girls.
And if it does come to that...
Misa is stronger because she has the eyes!
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
I've got to stay one step ahead of the investigation in finding out about the fake Kira.
But still...
I wonder what they're like...
Fake Kira...
Next Time
Love