We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
So, you're saying that one of them is Kira, right?
Yes, and I've got plenty of proof.
The victim was Mr. "H".
Soon Kira's identity will become clear!
If Higuchi is similar to the second Kira and can kill someone solely by knowing their face, Matsuda-san will die.
I-It's him?!
Don't fuck with me! You should at least know the names of your employees!
I've still got two hours...
Higuchi's status confirmed.
He's got a bag with him.
I'm in pursuit.
I'll kill him for sure...
I'm going to have it all!
Frenzy
Cosme Misa.
Brilliant gloss.
The sparkle of an angel.
Misa's Cashmere Rouge.
The commercials are ending, Ryuuzaki.
Is that so?
I ended up drinking with the eight of them, including Kira.
That's fascinating.
I can't say any more right now, or those who were present at the time might figure out who Kira is.
Of course. Please take your time and reveal Kira's identity when you're ready.
Please set the channels so Audio One is streaming from Higuchi's car and Audio Two from Sakura TV.
It's as we thought. Higuchi's making sure to watch the TV even from his car.
Going back to what you said earlier, have you actually met Kira in the flesh?
Yes, although at the time, I hadn't realized who Kira was.
However, I think it's really brave of you to come onto the show, considering that Kira has seen your face.
Are you okay with this?
Yes. While I was investigating, I discovered that Kira needs two things in order to kill.
I know there are a lot of rumors around this topic, but I've figured it out.
A face... and a name...
But in my case, Kira doesn't know my name.
So, he's doing this because he thinks that I won't be able to kill him as I don't know his real name, eh?
Does this mean that he's destroyed all evidence of his real name?
If he's thought as far ahead as destroying his old records... even if I went to Yoshida Productions...
Rem, what do you think?
Think? About what?
"Rem"? Who's that? He got into the car alone...
I can't believe that there would be someone else in there with him.
He's not using a cell phone either... maybe he's using a radio or something?
No, there's no radio in that car. Only our bugging devices, cameras and transmitters.
I'm certain because Weddy placed those devices there.
Even if I go to Yoshida Productions, there's a chance that there won't be any records...
Is he talking to himself?
Why are you asking me? How should I know?
If he's smart, he'd have destroyed any evidence of his real name before going on TV.
Besides, isn't it a little careless of Yoshida Productions to allow me to just waltz in and look for it myself?
Then again, as the only person who was there, I guess I'll be held accountable if anything is stolen.
Somehow, this doesn't look good...
It's okay. He'll go.
Even if the records are at Yoshida Productions, it could just be another false name... then what?!
I'm guessing in this kind of situation, it's highly likely that he has gone that far.
I'm guessing it's Light and Misa's plan for him to go to Yoshida Productions...
But he knows you're Kira, and if things continue as they are, he'll reveal your name.
Those are the facts.
There's less than an hour before the big announcement!
All you can do now is to go and take a look.
Regardless of whether the name on the record is fake or not,
there's no way anyone would suspect you of killing people by using a notebook.
Yeah, I get all that.
But to be on the safe side, it would be best if I killed everyone that I've talked to at Yoshida Productions,
as well as Misa and her manager.
Wha--?! No! He's going to kill me?!
Stop panicking. He's talking about after he's killed Matsuda-san.
Unless he kills Matsuda-san, there would be no point in him doing that.
You're right, but...
Think carefully. He's the only one you need to kill.
If you start killing those you called earlier, your call records will make you look suspicious.
That's true... you're pretty smart, Rem.
Then I'll just manipulate them to delete all their incoming call records before I kill them.
However, the phone company's records will still remain.
There's no way he's talking to himself!
Who is this "Rem"? Who is he talking to?!
If he's really having a conversation with someone, it's with... a Shinigami... perhaps?
With someone like this, maybe I should act first...
How about you return the ownership of the notebook to me?
No, all that means is that I'll end up with a pitiful end.
He says that he's got proof.
Plus if they compare Yotsuba's growth against the deaths that have occurred, no one is going to doubt his story.
Anybody he says is Kira will be labeled Kira for life.
Even if they don't find any hard evidence... my life will be over.
Forget about promotions, I probably won't even be allowed to stay at Yotsuba.
Of course, our staff on this show have structured the program with the assumption that Kira will be watching.
Then, I'd like to address Kira directly...
Kira! Turn yourself in!
He pretends to be an idiot, but that night he managed to fake his own death to stay alive.
Whatever happens, I must kill him.
Higuchi has arrived at Yoshida Productions.
Here we go...
Left as you enter... the desk right at the far end... in the very bottom drawer...
Manager
Yamashita Yaichirou
So, how are you going to kill him? Show me!
We're prepared to apprehend Higuchi the moment you give us the signal.
Okay.
Yamashita Taichirou
It's no use! All he's done is make a note of the name, and now he's leaving!
He's not going to kill him here?
Ryuuzaki, should I apprehend him?
We've yet to confirm how he kills.
He might do something once he gets back in his car.
Bring up the inside of Higuchi's car on monitor one.
Higuchi seems surprisingly calm for someone who desperately wants Matsuda-san to be dead.
True... and if he needed the name, he could have taken the records with him instead of putting them back.
36... 37... 38... 39... 40 seconds.
Kira is a murderer! I'll never forgive him!
Shit, he won't die!!
What does he mean by that?! "He won't die"?
He's already attempted to kill him?
Could writing down their name be how he kills?
What should we do? Wait and see what he does?
I can only assume it means he can kill someone merely by knowing their name and wanting them to die.
What's going on? I can't determine how he's killing people.
If we apprehend him now and attempt to force a confession out, once again he'll...
There are 50 minutes left until the Kira announcement!
Damn it! There's no time left!
He's calling someone.
Most likely Misa-san again.
Bingo!
I know what he looks like...
If I go to the office, there'll be security tapes of that time he snuck in...
If I had the eyes of a Shinigami...
Half my life span, eh?
But if he does reveal my name, my life's as good as over anyways.
Then, I may as well live a short but fulfilled life.
Rem, it's time to do the deal.
"Deal"? Who is this "Rem" he keeps talking about?
Is Kira's power really something that's bestowed from above?
I wouldn't like to think so.
In that case, what the hell is "Rem"?
A Shinigami?
Either way, I think we should continue observing him.
We could learn a lot.
We may even discover how he kills.
Now I really am invincible!
Now I'll always have a trick up my sleeve.
We're going after him.
You in the Porsche! Stop!
Pull over to the side! Stop the car!
Bad news. He's been pulled over by a patrol bike.
I'll have to go past him. I'm leaving the rest to you and Aiber.
You were speeding. Let's see your license.
Ah, alright.
Show me the inside of Higuchi's car on full screen.
I wonder where I put my license...
I've got no time for this!
The name "Shiroba Ito" is a pun. "Shirobai" literally means "motorcycle policeman".
Shiroba Ito - Accidental death
You there!!
He's managed to shake off the cop! He's getting away!
What's up with this guy?
This is the Traffic Riot Police--
T-The bike has collided with a truck! It's a complete wreck!
A wreck?! An accidental death?
This is bad...
When Higuchi had his hand in his bag... did he manage to do something then?
More importantly, how did he manage to find out the name of that traffic cop?
Just like the second Kira, could he have known by just looking at him?
Rem... a deal...
No. If he can now kill knowing only the face, he should be able to kill Matsuda immediately, since he knows his face...
What's going on? But...
Everyone! I believe that it'll be too dangerous to allow Higuchi to act any further!
We're going ahead with his capture.
However, Higuchi is now able to kill just by looking at someone's face, similar to the second Kira.
We'll be making the arrest under that assumption!
Watari, put me through to the Director of the Police Department.
Yes.
This is L.
I've determined who Kira is.
He's currently driving a red Porsche 911 on National Highway Route 1 from Hibiya towards Shibuya.
We'll be apprehending him ourselves, but I need you to inform your men not to approach that Porsche.
Father, after these commercials, it's time for the seventh part of the plan.
Understood.
Demegawa! We'll put our plan into motion during the next set of commercials.
Replace Matsuda and the Presenter with mannequins, and we'll use the audio we prepared to complete the facade.
Then leave the cameras to continue filming and evacuate everyone from the building.
Well then, Yagami-kun. Shall we go too?
Yeah.
I'm sorry Misa-san, but I'm going to leave you immobilized for a while.
What's all this?! Stop messing around!
I'm surprised you can pilot a helicopter on top of everything else, Ryuuzaki...
It's simple.
Doesn't seem like Higuchi is heading towards Sakura TV. He's going in the wrong direction.
Considering his route, he's heading towards Yotsuba Headquarters.
You're incredibly brave.
No, I only did what one would expect...
If only I can get back to the office and watch him on the surveillance tapes, I can kill him.
Weddy, did you manage to destroy everything regarding Matsuda-san at Yotsuba Headquarters?
Yes. Is he heading for the Headquarters?
How convenient.
This gives Mr. Yagami and me time to get to the TV station before him and set up an ambush.
Shit! It's not here!
No... it should be on the tape. It's been erased!
Did he get in here and erase it himself?
Or is someone betraying me by helping him?
No, they would be arrested as well.
Either way, I don't have much time. I've got to hurry!
Finally, it's nearly time for the big announcement.
Yes. I really want to hurry up and get it off my chest.
I understand how you feel, but for now, we're just going to take a quick break.
Damn it! The only thing left is to go to Sakura TV and kill him.
Father, it seems that Higuchi is finally heading towards Sakura TV.
He'll be there in less than 15 minutes. Are you okay?
I don't need my own son to worry about me.
I'm fine, Light.
Have you got anything more to add before you make the announcement?
Let's see...
Everyone, think very carefully about what will happen once Kira has been caught.
Mr. Yagami, it's nearly time.
After all, Kira is evil.
Yes...
Here.
Aiber doesn't like guns, so I'm the only one carrying a gun.
I'm no longer a cop. I'm not allowed to carry one anymore.
You're not supposed to use yours in Japan either.
You're so stubborn...
Made it.
Why is no one else here?
Is this a precaution in case today's broadcast really is true?
Well, if there's no one around, it just makes this easier.
We've arrived at Sakura TV.
We're taking up our positions.
Let's go, Aiber.
Okay, Mogi!
We've received a lot of calls and faxes in support of your testimony.
Even the studio is empty?
But I still have to be aware of the camera positions.
We're very sorry, but due to various circumstances, we'll have to end this program.
What?!
Dolls?! It can't be!
Hold it right there, Higuchi!
Don't move!
Give up.
T-This has gotta be some kind of mistake... I've arranged to meet Demegawa-san.
They're all wearing helmets... must be countermeasures against Kira.
In that case...
I'm from the Yotsuba Group's developmental labs... let me just find you my card...
Chief!
Aiber!
Damn it... I don't want to use one of these, but...
Higuchi's got a gun.
The Chief has been shot. Higuchi managed to escape.
I'm fine... Sorry, Ryuuzaki...
If you hurry after him, you can still catch him.
Hurry!
This isn't good. He's escaped from Sakura TV.
There's no choice.
We've got to actively join this pursuit.
Watari, are you ready?
Yes.
Yagami-kun, please hold onto this for your own protection.
Our opponent is Kira, after all.
No... that's illegal in Japan.
I'm sure Yagami-san said the exact same thing.
Yeah...
Damn...
He's driving all over the place!
Okay, go now!
Okay.
What the hell was that about?! I can only guess it was a trap...
We take a break from our scheduled program to bring you the news.
The program stopped... but I wasn't the one who stopped it...
S-Shit... what's going on?!
What the--
So it was a trap after all!
All the patrol cars have tinted windows...
Have they secretly continued their Kira investigation?!
What's this? I thought I asked the police not to get involved.
The only person who'd do this is...
Yes, that's right.
Damn it! There!
It ends here.
Stay back! Don't come near me!
Guess it's over...
Yes... it is.
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
"Those whose names are written in this notebook will die."
"This note will not take effect unless the writer has the person's face in their mind when they write his/her name."
"Therefore, people sharing the same name will not be affected."
Next Time
Resurrection