We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
Activity
Hey, weren't these meetings supposed to be fortnightly? Seems they're getting more frequent than ever.
It can't be helped.
We've received a report from Coil which claims that Amane Misa may know L.
According to his report, "Amane Misa was questioned by L", but... here is where the problems arise.
"Based on what we know so far, it's fair to say that Amane idolizes Kira.
Furthermore, Yoshida Productions are pressing the Yotsuba Group to use her as a campaign girl.
I propose that the Yotsuba Group employ Amane in a commercial and utilize this opportunity to find out more about L."
Personally, I'm not entirely satisfied with this plan...
Why not? Sounds like a good plan to me.
No, what Ooi means is that Coil is the one who's supposed to be uncovering L's identity, yet he has entrusted this to us.
The original contract was for him to reveal L's identity.
Maybe Coil should be present at this meeting?
You could be right...
Kida-san, I thought the original agreement was that you'd avoid calling me unless absolutely necessary.
Is this urgent?
Understood. If that's the case, I've got an excellent idea...
Even though the meeting is over and I'm finally home, there's still criminals to take care of...
Being Kira is hectic business...
But it's about to get interesting...
Without a doubt, Amane Misa was the second Kira and was caught by L.
The fact that she escaped in that situation can only mean that she relinquished her ownership of the Note and lost her memories.
This is just too good an opportunity to pass up...
I'm going to take Amane Misa as my wife.
Money, power, and a beautiful wife.
I'll be the envy of everyone.
Once we're married, I'll spend plenty of money on her life insurance policy.
Surely, this degenerate wouldn't...
Rem, hide the notebook in the usual place.
Right now, the only thing I can do for Misa... is this...
Okay, let's take it from the next part...
Misa-san, you went to Tokyo specifically hoping to meet Kira...
Look here...
Misa-san, I know the line sucks, but try not to overreact.
Whaa? This is what's known as credible acting!
Never mind, let's just try this again.
Fine, fine, Mr. Ryuuzaki Director Sir...
If you don't start taking this seriously, you'll be feeling my foot.
M-Misa-Misa...
Your face looks strained. Just "Misa" is fine, Mochii.
I'm not cut out for this... but this is one of my duties too, and will aid in catching Kira...
Misa-Misa!
What's wrong, Mochii?!
Today's interview with the Yotsuba Group is of course an opportunity for you to appear in their commercials,
but it's also a part of our undercover investigation.
You don't need to tell me that, I already know!
Also, you better not mess up either. Remember, you're supposed to be a super-energetic manager!
Alright! I'll do my best!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Good morning!
I'm Misa-Misa's manager, Moji Kan'ichi, also known as Mochii.
Ooi-san, Shimura-san, nice to see the both of you again!
Pleased to meet you!
Go for it, Misa-Misa!!
Mochii can really pull some tricks when he needs to.
I'll go and prepare the celebrations for when you land this commercial!
I'm not cut out for this... am I?
I don't believe we've met before, have we, Misa-san?
I'm John Wallace, the main adviser of the Advertising Department. It's a pleasure to meet you.
Pleased to meet you too.
So, let me get straight to the point and be honest with you.
The decision to hire you to be in our commercials has more or less already been made.
But before we seal the deal, there's just one more thing I'd like to have confirmed.
Yes?
We've taken the liberty of doing some investigation into your background;
it seems that you idolize Kira for killing the thieves that murdered your parents,
and that you went to Tokyo specifically hoping to meet Kira.
W-Who... did you hear that from?
We can't reveal our sources, but our information is accurate.
Even your entire face screams "busted".
Coil... I had no idea that he'd found out so much already...
And... there's still something that you're hiding from us, right?
Something you wouldn't want the public to find out.
This is the point where I've got to start sweating and pause for a moment...
"Amane Misa was restrained by L". I'd like to hear the truth straight from your own mouth.
We can't afford to have the Yotsuba campaign girl turn out to be Kira.
Agreed. Please be honest with us regarding this.
I-I understand... I'll tell you everything.
It's true I was restrained... but I didn't know it was L's doing.
I was asked about Kira, but I'm not the second Kira, and they realized that I had no connection with Kira.
That's why I'm here right now.
Did you manage to see the face of the person restraining you?
No, I was blindfolded.
Yet, you must have heard their voice, right?
But their voice was coming out of some speakers...
Come on now, this seems more like an interrogation than an interview.
How long are you planning to keep this up?
I'm going to the toilet.
Certainly, it's true that we may have been going off on a bit of a tangent there.
Erm... would it be okay for me to go to the toilet too?
This is so nerve-racking...
But so far it seems to be going well... I've got to keep doing my best.
Even by touching this scrap of paper, her lost memories won't return... but at least Misa will be able to see me now.
W-What is this?! A ghost?!
Misa, right now you're in a dangerous situation where you could be killed by members of the Yotsuba Group at any moment.
I had to come and tell you this.
Calm down and listen.
"Calm down"? This ghost is much more likely to kill me!
I'm your ally, Misa.
My... ally?
I wonder if Misa-Misa is okay?
Maybe we should at least have made her wear a wire.
There's no doubt that it's a different person.
The Kira prior to my detention and the current Kira... they're definitely different.
The current Kira is killing off absolutely anyone who's been broadcast as a murderer, but...
those who had no murderous intent... those who killed unintentionally... and those with mitigating circumstances...
they were never judged by the previous Kira.
If I was Kira, I'd also judge in such a discerning way...
The basis of the previous Kira's judgments are terrifyingly close to my own ideals...
What am I thinking?
I'm not Kira.
Comparing myself to Kira? There's clearly something wrong with me...
Yagami Light is Kira.
What is Light currently doing?
What are you?
I can tell that you're not a stalker, but you don't even remotely resemble a human.
Of course. I'm a Shinigami.
There was once a time when we worked inseparably together.
Everything you're saying... I don't understand any of it...
Misa has met you?! Light is Kira?!
Death Note.
If you write a person's name in it, the person whose name was written will die.
Using that Note, Yagami Light passed judgment on criminals and became widely known as "Kira".
And you held the same power as Kira. No, a power even greater than that.
Using that power you were able to successfully approach Kira, in other words, Yagami Light.
Light is Kira? And Misa is the second Kira?
That's correct. Or more accurately, you used to be.
However, the current situation should all be a part of Light's plan.
Ryuuzaki... he's right!
Misa...
Do you still love Light enough to die for him?
Shinigami-san, you're the real deal.
You know everything about Misa! I'll believe everything you say.
Yes... I love him... to death.
The fact that Light was Kira, and Misa was Kira, that we both were Kira together... that's truly fantastic!
I believe it!
You never change, Misa.
And I doubt that those feelings you have for Light will ever change either.
So from now on, I'll accept that your happiness lies in being with Light, and supporting him.
Thank you, Shinigami-san!
I'm Rem.
Presently, the current Kira is a disgusting lowlife.
There's no telling what he might do. Be careful of him.
The same goes for any human who works for Yotsuba.
Just trust Light, and let him handle it his way.
Got it. All Misa has got to do is act natural, right?
That's right.
Once you return to the interview, you should be able to tell who Kira is.
Be especially wary of him.
I apologize for taking so long in the toilet.
I even fixed my make-up in there!
Once you return from the toilet, the man sitting in front of me will be Kira.
Rem...
The person sitting in front of Rem is Kira.
Higuchi is Kira?! It couldn't get any worse...
Misa-Misa is late...
She's back!
Heya!
Phew... I'm so tired.
Hey...
How did it go?
Yotsuba has decided to employ Misa in a multi-platform advertising campaign.
Is that so? That's good.
I gave them both my phone number and my e-mail address, and already three out of the seven have contacted me in private and asked me out!
Whaaat?!
Now I just need to accept their offers and begin investigating them, right?
Everything is going according to the plan!
No, that plan has been cancelled.
Why?! It's all gone so well!
This method places you in too much danger.
I won't tell you not to do the commercial, but from now on, you'll deny that you were the second Kira and were restrained by L.
You'll be guarded by Mogi-san, and you'll only work in your capacity as a "campaign girl".
Bu--
If Light says so, I'll do it.
Well, Misa is tired and she needs to be on location early tomorrow, so she's off to bed.
Thank you for worrying about me, Light... but I've thought of an excellent plan!
I'll definitely help you, Light!
Light? You want to sleep with me?
What are you talking about, Misa?
I know. We can do that after Kira is caught, right?
No need to get so embarrassed, Light!
You don't have to be embarrassed, Light-kun.
I'm not embarrassed.
Why are you taking it so seriously, Light-kun?
Cut!
That's a wrap!
Great job, everyone!
Yeah, nice work.
Well done, Misa-Misa!
I'm allowed to use the bathroom in this hospital, aren't I?
Sure! Off you go!
Just wait here a moment.
Yes?
Senpai! Good job at work!
Wow! Mori-chan, that nurse's outfit really suits you!
Oh, really?!
That went smoothly...
Wow! I knew you would have an amazing car!
If you like, I'll take you for a ride anytime. No, I'll just buy you one.
In any case, that nurse's outfit looks great, Misa-chan.
You like it?
You took a while...
Where's Misa?!
She's on a date...
Damn it!
Higuchi Kyousuke... since we had that reception... he has persistently messaged and asked me out... that dirty old man.
Misa-chan, why don't you give me your number?
You're just my type, I'll be really good to you.
Oi, Higuchi! Stop trying to get in before anyone else can!
It's truly horrible that Kira has to be someone like this.
Misa-chan, you fancy getting something to eat?
You're not planning to take me anywhere dubious are you?
Well, even if you do try anything funny, Misa can kill people, so she'll be fine.
What are you thinking, Misa?
Is this something Yagami Light has told you to do?
No. She must be attempting to tell me that if it comes down to it, I have to kill Higuchi...
You're so funny, Misa-chan. You can kill people?
It's true, because Misa is... the second Kira.
N-No way. Even if this girl used to be the second Kira, she can't still be, can she?
She should have no memory of it.
What's going on?!
There's no need to lie just because you're wary of me, Misa-chan.
I'm actually quite the gentleman.
Well, Misa has no interest in showing proof that she's the second Kira to anyone but Kira...
You'll only show it to Kira? Is that so?
Misa's dream is to become Kira's wife!
I'm absolutely certain that Kira needs Misa.
From the incidents at Sakura TV, it's evident that the second Kira has the Shinigami's Eyes.
If this is true, I've got to keep her by my side, no matter what.
Let's try a test...
Well, since I'm Kira, you'd better marry me, Misa-chan!
Really?!
Eh... Yeah, really.
Proof! We should show each other proof!
Impossible. It's far too dangerous to show anyone that you have the ability to kill people.
You think so? If Misa thought someone was Kira, she'd offer them proof of her own initiative.
Unless someone makes the first move, nothing will happen.
Well, kill someone then. I could be Kira you know.
Fine, but I only kill bad people.
I see... "Bad" people, huh?
Kaneboshi Ginzou. President of a large consumer financing company.
A notorious villain that collects what he's owed through cruel methods. In some cases, he's forced people to pay out of their own life insurance.
How about him?
Will you be able to check instantly if he's dead or not?
I just need to make a call.
Then, can you face that way for a moment?
Misa, you want me to kill Kaneboshi Ginzou, right?
That way, Higuchi will believe you.
I can do that...
Kaneboshi Ginzou
Okay. He should be dead by now.
It's Higuchi from Yotsuba...
The president has just collapsed and stopped breathing! This will have to wait!
See?
She killed the person I specified, right here and now...
Unless she has the power, it would be impossible.
That decides it!
If I'm Kira, you'll marry me, right?!
W-Why are you looking so serious all of a sudden?
Because I am Kira.
Then, prove it.
I've got to go home to kill, you understand that, right?
Well, that's no good. It could merely be a trick to get Misa to go back to your place.
I know! Why don't you try and stop the judging of the criminals?
If you really are Kira, you should be able to manage that.
And when Misa tells you to, you can begin judging them again.
I'll believe you if that happens, since only Kira should be able to control the judging of criminals.
I see... Nice idea...
Alright then.
I'm Kira. So in order to make you believe me, I'll stop judging criminals.
And once you realize that I am Kira, we're getting married!
So, as you can all hear...
Higuchi is Kira!
Thanks to this we know Kira's identity, and the judging of criminals that the Chief was so worried about will end too!
This is amazing, Misa-Misa!
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
Three days have passed since I stopped the judging of criminals.
That should be enough...
If I marry the second Kira, Amane Misa, I'll have the Shinigami's eyes. And I'll be able to control Yotsuba completely!
Next Time
Guidance