We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
I haven't seen you in a while.
I'm indebted to you for always taking care of my dad.
S-Sayu-chan... Wow, you've really grown up...
This is Yagami.
Deputy Chief... regarding the deal to exchange the Chief for the notebook...
That's now off.
What?!
Instead, we'll now exchange the notebook in return for Yagami Sayu.
Alone. With the notebook. Within two days. In LA.
Second-generation L... it's a pleasure to meet you.
I am the one at the center of the SPK.
Let me see... I'm N.
"N"? Is this a joke?
And yet... this feeling... What is it?
Impatience
N... this feeling... it's similar... to L.
I know we said we wouldn't be depending on L, and in reality, within America,
the CIA and FBI are already operating under my command, not L's.
However, the murder of the Chief of the Japanese Police Force is an unforgivable crime,
and I believe this case will potentially lead to the capture of Kira. Thus, we'd like to offer you our full cooperation.
"Lead to the capture of Kira"? What's with this guy?
This confidence...
Something wrong, L?
No...
The truth is that after the Chief was murdered, the people believed to be responsible abducted Deputy Chief Yagami's daughter.
They've demanded that we go to LA in order to make the exchange.
Exchange? For the notebook I presume?
Yes.
Alright. We'll gather as many agents as possible in LA without divulging too many details about the case,
and monitor the whole of LA with satellite cameras...
No.
Actually, I'll leave the command of this operation to you, L.
That's good. At least we're in charge.
But to say that America will no longer count on L...
Near, you're really fine with this? Leaving it in the hands of that fake L, who hasn't even been able to pursue Kira properly...
That's precisely why it's fine.
It means that there'll be gaps for us to take advantage of.
Of course, protecting human life is our first priority.
However, the SPK's main goals are ultimately to recover the notebook and capture Kira.
Light...
Even if you have to sacrifice my life... whatever happens... save Sayu.
Don't say such stupid things!
That might be fine with you, but do you realize how much the people you leave behind will suffer?!
I can't let you die in front of Sayu.
It's possible that at some point you'll lose contact with me.
If you find yourself in a situation where you have to make the decisions on your own,
you'll choose the option where neither you nor Sayu needs to die. Promise me this.
Light...
What?! No way?!
I can really go with you?!
Yeah. Your eyes might be needed again.
Yay! Thank you!
I'll pack my luggage straight away!
Hmm, I can't decide...
Hey Light, which one looks good?
If it comes down to it, I'll have no choice but to kill Sayu...
Father, I'll head to LA first and complete all the arrangements.
Ide-san and the rest can follow.
However, you should all take separate flights from each other,
and as an added precaution, Aizawa-san will tail my father and board the same plane.
Got it.
I'll cut my hair to disguise myself.
I'm counting on you all.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it? Are you part of the gang responsible for this?
Board flight SE333. I have your ticket.
Hurry, it's gate 18.
Okay...
A man has made contact at Narita. Should I apprehend him?
Aizawa-san, calm down. Apprehending him here and now will achieve nothing.
Just ensure you don't lose sight of them.
Damn it! The Chief and that man are boarding a different flight from the one we're supposed to be taking...
Since it's an emergency I can try and board it as a police offi--
Calm down, Aizawa-san!
We can't risk doing something that might get us found out.
Do you know the flight's destination?
It's bound for LA too...
I can't believe this, they even switched planes... this is bad...
Flight SE333, Flight SE333, do you read me? You are straying off your flight path!
This is Flight SE333 reading you loud and clear.
We're not straying off our flight path, I'm purposely heading this way.
What are you saying?! What's wrong with you?! Is this some kind of joke?
This is not a hi-jacking. I'm just making a small detour so that we can drop off one of the passengers.
Feel free to follow our progress on the radar.
However, should any attempt to interfere be made, I won't hesitate to crash this plane, taking all the passengers with me.
Light-kun.... I mean L, instead of going to LA, the Deputy Chief's plane is now heading in a different direction.
When they mentioned dropping someone off, they probably meant the Deputy Chief...
Damn it! What the hell is going on?!
I checked the entire flight crew for today, and never found anyone remotely suspicious!
The captain is a veteran of over 15 years... there's nothing suspicious about the co-pilot either...
Do they really have the power to control people like this?
Shit... I don't have a choice...
Chief? This is L. Let me speak to N.
Yes...
N, I'm sure you're aware of the situation.
Can I ask you to instruct the airline company, police and military to take no action?
What does L think they're doing?! They're so unreliable...
Understood, L. Once we've determined the landing point, we'll monitor the area via satellite.
If there's anything else we can assist you with, just let us know.
Take this computer terminal.
Put the wireless earpiece on.
Yagami, you're the only one who can hear my voice.
Listen carefully.
I'm the main culprit responsible for kidnapping your daughter.
I'm not even remotely interested in taking your, or your daughter's life.
Right now, the only thing I want is the notebook.
If you do exactly as I tell you, I won't kill either of you.
I've prepared a method of exchange that I think you'll find acceptable, and will be able to follow without qualm.
Just don't attempt to oppose me.
Exchanging my daughter's life for the notebook... with someone whose identity remains unknown...
When the pressure's on... which should I take?
As a police officer... as a human being... as a parent...
L, we have the landing area on satellite.
We'll rely all images we see directly to you.
Father...
What's going on? How are they planning to make the exchange in a place like this?
See that, Yagami? Enter through there.
Underground, huh?
This is getting interesting...
Damn, they're underground...
Of course, they must have figure that we'd use satellite.
Now we can't even monitor their movements...
This is bullet-proof glass. Understand?
Up until a few years ago, this place was used as a trading area for certain organizations... since then it's been altered slightly.
Put the notebook in here. When that's done, I'll release this lock.
Then, we'll both take a step back and rotate the glass. Notebook comes this way, girl goes that way.
If you fail to cooperate with the exchange, I'll shoot her.
L, what's your plan?
Don't tell me you think it's okay for the notebook to fall into the hands of someone you can't identify?
Y462, begin.
Alright, hand the notebook over. Open it up and pass it through the glass on the left.
Damn it! I've got no choice in this matter...
I've only just arrived in LA and I'm in no position to maneuver the world's police and military as L.
At this rate the notebook will...
Light, what's up? Are you okay? You look a bit pale...
Just shut up and do as you're told!
I mean, I need you to continue judging the criminals in Japan as normal.
They're closing in on us. You should realize how important it is not to neglect this now.
Erm... okay, but who are "they"--
Look, just do as you're told!
He's just taking it out on you.
There's still time... now that it comes to this, have I no choice but to kill Sayu?
Very well, let's test the notebook
"Test"?! You're going to kill someone--
We can't perform the exchange without testing it first.
You want your daughter to die?
I can't...
Only people from the police know about this incident... I wouldn't be able to lay the blame for Sayu's death on Kira...
What's going on?
Are you alright, Miller?
This is what happens when you try and make money from drugs that belong to the mafia.
He's finally been of some use to us.
Y462, the target is dead.
Looks like the notebook is the real deal.
In that case, let go of it. We'll exchange it for the girl.
Sayu... Father...
Oh, so they're okay then.
The culprits are getting into a helicopter. I guess that's their escape route.
So this makes it 100% certain that the exchange has gone through.
But we don't know what they intend to do from here...
We'll follow their helicopter as far as we can via satellite, and try not to lose them.
Easier said than done, but fine... We'll try our best.
It's no good. They've got us, L.
A missile?!
That type of missile is untraceable by radar.
The notebook's on a missile?!
The missile has been launched!
The helicopter or the missile?! Where's the notebook?!
Boss, I'm sure you're watching, but it's all gone according to plan!
Yeah, well done.
This will wipe out all my past failures, right?
Yeah, it'll all be wiped out...
Do it.
Near! The helicopter!
I thought as much.
This must mean the notebook is on the missile!
We have no idea where the missile is heading!
We've completely lost sight of it...
If they bring the missile down in an uninhabited area, it wouldn't be too hard to recover...
They've probably got a hold of the notebook by now.
If they have, then what's the first thing they'll do?
No, that's already obvious...
L...
Yes?
They got us.
"They got us"?
Yes.
They majority of the SPK members have been killed.
L, your team handed over the notebook without any attempt to stop it.
N. Do you mean that you could have prevented this under your command?
No, given the amount of preparation put in, no matter who was in charge, they would have gotten away with it.
But there's little point in bickering about that now.
We need to share our information and cooperate.
It's not as if I have absolutely no idea who's behind this.
The person I believe to be behind this goes by the name of "Mello".
Goes by the name of "Mello"?!
I don't have any photos of him, nor do I know his real name, but what I do know,
is that four years ago, he was at an orphanage called "Wammy's House" in Winchester, England.
"Wammy's House"?
That must have been set up by Watari.
I believe that Mello is playing a game with me... Who can defeat the last boss, "Kira", first.
Armo Jastin.
It's Armonia Jastin.
I went to the old man and told him I lost my notebook.
And when I told him what it looked like, he told me that was the notebook Ryuk dropped.
What should I do in this situation?
In that case, you'll need to get Ryuk to return it.
I thought as much...
I guess I better go then... to the human world.
I guess you better.
I guess so...
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
Calm down and listen carefully.
On November 10th at 23:59, all mafia members will die.
That instant will be your best opportunity to retrieve the notebook.
Next Time
Father