We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
The second L, as well as the one I suspect to be Kira, is... Yagami Light.
Good evening. This is Takada Kiyomi.
Messages from Kira will now be transmitted as the law to the new world.
I think we can use Takada Kiyomi in this investigation.
I'm sorry.
Kira?
Remove all bugs?
We have no choice...
Listen, Kiyomi.
I am Kira.
Yagami-kun is... Kira?
Ridicule
All the pieces are now in place.
At this stage, I should go to Japan.
Chief Lester.
Yes.
Can you come back to New York one more time?
One more time?
I am going to Japan as well.
So I will support you from New York?
No.
Then, why do you want me back in New York?
I have never boarded a plane alone in my life.
I want you to escort me to Japan.
Understood.
As I thought. We managed to get into Yoshida Productions and NHN.
Misa-Misa's infiltration was a huge success!
At this moment, getting into NHN is difficult.
But with this, they won't suspect a thing.
Yeah.
As her manager, Mogi-san will be able to get in as well.
We definitely want someone to be able to go in and out freely.
Of course, I'll be watching Takada.
This is Near. Let me speak to L.
This is L. What is it?
In order to capture Kira, I have come to Japan.
Japan? Why did he tell me that?
L. You should be watching Takada-san to aid your investigation on Kira, right?
Yes. I am currently in contact with her.
I see.
If you want to catch Kira, keeping an eye on NHN and Takada Kiyomi is common sense.
Well, please inform Takada that some members from the SPK has come to Japan to capture Kira.
What for?
It's bait for Kira.
Also, I would like her to know this as well;
The SPK has only four members, myself included.
Kira will not run away.
He will certainly try to kill us.
Then, we will get him instead.
"Get him instead", you say?
That's fine, Near!
I accept your challenge!
I am in Japan.
I am in Japan as well.
Then we are pretty close to each other. We could even meet.
That's right.
When the time comes, I'll count on you.
Alright.
That will be the time we settle this Kira matter.
Definitely.
Come to think of it, since that time, this has been a one-on-one fight with L.
Instead of going against L, I am going against L's successors.
That's fine, Near.
If you're going for it, I am going for it as well.
When we meet, we'll see who is better...
Who is at the higher position...
When the time comes, this fight will come to an end...
And I will stand on top.
First, let's revise what we have so far.
L is Yagami Light.
And he is Kira. We'll call him L-Kira for short.
Then the other, the one who is holding the notebook, and doing the killing, X-Kira.
X-Kira is doing the judgments, and definitely has the eyes of a Shinigami.
Then, L-Kira and X-Kira are using Takada as a bridge to communicate.
As for the actual method to beat Kira, there are two ways.
The first way will be to... kill both L-Kira and X-Kira, and take the notebook.
However, we will never do something like that.
Why is that?
That's not the way we work.
"We?"
That's right.
Killing someone to see if the judgments will stop.
That kind of trial and error is not L's, nor my style.
L would not accept that.
It would be meaningless as the successor to L.
Takada-san, I heard on the news that you're receiving countless fan letters daily.
That's right. It seems there are at least 200 of them each day.
200 of them? I'm getting jealous...
Don't.
Just listening to them without any pictures is pretty boring.
I think fan letters are something you should just skip through.
That's right.
Read the messages from now on in a calm manner so that people listening to this won't notice anything.
With the SPK on the move, right now, for your own safety,
instead of just waiting for his messages, you should go and tell him about your condition.
Light is making his move right now!
You should not be just the spokesperson for Kira.
Why don't you try to call out Kira from your side?
T has other missions: creating a perfect world.
I would like to have you carrying out the judgment of Kira.
It's okay.
It's you, so I'm sure you can do it well.
By doing that, information that you don't want the SPK to know can be passed on to Kira.
I got it.
I will do it.
He did it!
That's Light-kun for you! He's really good!
Eliminate. Eliminate. Eliminate.
Takada Kiyomi?
Yes?
I have a message for you.
Please send a fan letter than only I will recognize.
In it, include five pages from the notebook.
Until I receive it, carry on with your judgments.
And after I send it to you?
You will not use the real notebook, but carry out your judgments with a fake one.
Fake?
Yes.
Make a fake one that looks like the real one.
And use that for your judgments.
I received the order.
God... what are you thinking?
No, there is no need for me to think about that.
God is absolute.
I will just carry out God's will.
What's with this program?
This is the program that replaced "Kira's Realm".
Coming up with something like this is just like them.
In Today's Miss Takada, we will introduce the four bodyguards of Takada.
The winner of the 22nd World Female Karate Championships, Oyama Tatsumi.
Former CIA investigator, Hal Lidner.
If there is a SPK member among them, this Hal Lidner...
Looks like Near didn't make any effort to hide it.
In the Shinjuku business district, six people...
If I were to choose X-Kira, who would I choose?
Kira's existence, as well as Kira's teachings, are to be considered good, and should be infused into the minds of children.
Takada was chosen because she is a supporter of Kira.
X-Kira must have known that she is a supporter of Kira. A person that has a certain relationship with Takada.
Kira will not allow any criminal acts, no matter how small they are.
From now on, targets for his judgments will include all the humans in the world.
I definitely want to hear Kira's voice and thoughts one more time.
I think that Kira's teaching is the straightest path to world peace.
Young people with talent should not be allowed to waste them. They should use their talents to improve society.
If we don't have instructions or directions from Kira, I think it's necessary for us to make our own judgments based on Kira's way.
L-Kira is Yagami Light. Could X-Kira be Mikami Teru?
Takada Kiyomi...
Everything is making sense now.
That's why I ask, why am I not the main attraction?
I thought they said I'm the highlight of this year?
Well, highlight is highlight. The main attraction is something different.
That's why, you have to be more careful.
Takada Kiyomi!
What an idiot. She doesn't know she's just being used by Light in his investigation.
Stop that! If you go on, you might get killed!
I know that. That's why I am saying this softly.
Ah! She smirked at me! Misa is going to break her legs!
Ah! Don't!
What are you trying to do?
"What?"... I was just going to ask the same.
Lidner. She is my important friend.
Please don't be too hard on her.
Yes, Takada-sama. I'm sorry about that.
Mi... Misa-Misa! Are you okay?
This is so humiliating!
L, if mister Aizawa is there, is it possible for me to speak to him?
Near, this is Aizawa. What is it?
When L meets Takada, are there cameras and bugs used to record their conversation?
No... right now, only bugs.
I see. Right now, only bugs.
Thank you very much.
If they only use bugs, it's possible that X-Kira and L-Kira are communicating through Takada.
That means, Lidner is in a pretty dangerous situation.
To put things bluntly, the most important thing right now is to let L focus on Takada and Lidner.
And we have to use this chance to get Mikami.
How is it, Gevanni?
Mikami, right?
Well... it's amazingly simple to trail him.
He's not hiding or anything, and he has lived in the same room for four years.
And he seems to be leading a normal life.
He's doing his prosecution job normally as well.
I don't think he is X-Kira...
No, there is an extremely high possibility that Mikami is X-Kira.
Please pay more attention.
Watch him carefully until he goes back to his room.
Yes.
Really... don't make me do this again and again, NHN...
And I was only told "Please pay attention to what you say" again and again...
What is this?
Yes, I will ask her now.
Misa-Misa, Takada wanted to have dinner with you and talk girl-to-girl.
That Kiyomi... what is she...
Won't that be great? The show's host and highlight having dinner together.
Tell her I'm okay with it.
Hello.
Takada-sama, the dinner is confirmed.
Well, that's something I'm looking forward to.
Lidner, make sure we get a respectable room, and sit in with us for the dinner.
Yes.
Amane-san. Sorry for making you come at this late hour.
I can't really leave until I'm done with News 9.
Not at all. Misa is actually quite fine with this.
Well, what is it?
"What?"? I really don't know how to answer your sudden question.
He seems to be very busy these days. Do you manage to see him nowadays?
Of course I'm seeing him. He's still just like a boy in front of me.
What a woman!
Every night when he comes home, he's very sticky to me. It's very troublesome.
I see. So you are getting along well.
That's great.
Well, I would like to let you know something in advance.
I'm going to announce my engagement with him at the New Year Show.
Does he know about this?
Of course! You can't possibly get engaged with just one person consenting.
It's been a month since we agreed on that.
Will it be okay for me to announce that in the show, host?
I see.
If it can be done that is.
What do you mean by that?
Are you going to use your authority as the host to stop me?
Or could you possibly... try to get Kira to kill me?
No way. Kira decides who he wants to judge.
It has nothing to do with me.
I see you as a friend. Please don't say something as cold as that.
And no matter how bad a person it is, I don't kill people.
Well, fine. Although I like Kira, he's soon going to be caught by Light.
If he's caught, you'll get your share too.
You will definitely be... put to death.
Takada-sama! Are you okay?
Listen, Kiyomi.
I am Kira.
And you will be with me, as the goddess of the new world.
Amane-san.
Yes.
I am not happy.
Eh? Neither am I!
Looks like we can have dinner when you are a bit older and have more manners.
Look here, I'm older than you, Kiyomi-chan.
And to leave a table before the dinner ends, that's even worse manners, right?
Mochii!
Sorry to keep you waiting! How are you?
Are you okay?
Of course! I won!
Won?
It was an easy victory!
In tonight's meeting between Takada and Amane, their conversation was about "him".
In other words, who is the real girlfriend of Yagami Light.
Near.
From this, what I can say is...
Yagami Light has Takada and Amane in a love triangle.
Near, please be more serious.
I am not trying to make light of this situation.
It will not be easy for him to betray either.
No, they will follow him with their lives.
Please stop that!
What is it, girl? You are inviting me to do that by wearing such short skirts, right?
Someone...
Cell phone?
Mikami took out a notebook!
Eliminate.
He's writing something on it. Could it be...?
Mikami is getting off the train.
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
Mikami is speaking to himself. He's doing something with the trash paper at his feet.
Now, he went inside the gym.
I'll get inside the locker room.
Key to the briefcase... I'm opening it.
I got the note.
Next Time
Vigilance