Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Overcast Skies
No matter how this girl's managed to arrive at this theory, what she has deduced is the truth.
If the police hear about this, in no time at all, they'll realize that "Kira" is Yagami Light.
I got no choice but to finish her off.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
I was just going over your story again, and think it's advisable that we begin to investigate this immediately.
Really?
Yes.
Have you discussed this with anyone else?
No, you're the first...
That's pretty lucky for you.
But how are ya gonna get rid of her? Doing it here would be kinda risky.
I know; you don't need to tell me that, Ryuk.
I've already got it all figured out.
Wow, I didn't think you'd do it so openly.
Could you tell me when that bus hi-jacking occurred?
The 20th of December, on the 11:02 bus to Space Land from outside Asago Hill.
...The.. 20th.. of.. December.. to Space Land.. right?
Yes.
Maki Shoko
Suicide
1st January 2007, from 1:15pm onwards
Her behaviour becomes driven by the sole
thought of formulating the best method
of committing suicide, yet keeping the
body undiscovered so as not to cause
trouble for others. Within 48 hours,
executes this plan and dies.
At least this way, the body won't be found for a while.
Even if they discover it relatively quickly, it's conceivable that she did it as a result of her fiancé's death.
What's so funny, Ryuk?
Apologies for needing to question each of you separately.
Kira is not amongst us.
How can you be so sure, Ryuuzaki?
To be honest, I set up a trick to determine whether any of you were Kira or not.
But I haven't felt the need to use it on any of you...
Excuse me.
I can't believe that he told all of us to turn off our phones!
Understood. We're just finishing up here as well.
You can come in using your own key.
Watari is coming.
I understand. I'll pass on this information myself, if that's okay?
Thanks, but if possible, I'd like to tell them myself.
Having heard your opinions, I think it's best that I tell them as soon as possible.
You're right.
In just ten seconds it'll be 1:15pm.
I'd like to see how this girl dies, but it's not as though I can just follow her around.
Now, hurry up and die!
Kira will definitely be caught, don't you think?
Huh?
What's going on?!
The scheduled time has already passed...
This is weird...
Why hasn't she acted?
Suicide
I know that "suicide" already works as a method of death. I've already tested this on those prisoners, and they all hung themselves right on time.
I've experimented killing people within these boundaries a countless number of times already...
So, why?
Ryuk?
Come to think of it.. he was laughing more than usual when I was writing on that page from the notebook...
And that's not all. When I asked about her name, he started to laugh in an unusual manner.
Both times it had something to do with her name..
A fake name?!
Thank you all for your hard work, gentlemen.
T-That person is Watari?
Err, what's happened to your normal garb?
In that garb everyone knows that I'm Watari.
We don't want everyone to know that Ryuuzaki is staying at this hotel.
I-I see..
The fact that I'm now able to show you my face is a sign of Ryuuzaki's trust in you.
I guess that's sort of flattering...
Ryuuzaki, I've brought the items you requested.
Please hand them out to everyone.
Of course.
These are your new police IDs.
New IDs?
It's a fake name... It has to be!
Ryuk is able to see her real name, that's why he was laughing like that.
Right from the start, this girl has been extremely cautious...
That's it! She believes that Ray died because he showed his ID to someone.
This is why she won't reveal her real name.
This isn't good though...
It's going to be a lot harder to try extracting her real name now that she's given me a fake one...
If I keep asking her, she's going to become suspicious of me..
The fact that I even know it's a fake name is suspicious to begin with...
I'm going to head back. Someone might have arrived by now.
Eh?
Err.. yes, you're right.
I hope someone is back now.
Yes.
Damn... If I try to stop her, it'll look suspicious.
What am I going to do?! At this rate...
Oh, yeah! I promised to let her talk to my father if he calls me.
If he calls me now, it's over. What am I going to do?!
Wait.. what am I thinking?!
All I need to do is turn off my phone.
Calm down. All I need to do is confirm her name.
She's definitely got some kind of ID, a driver's licence perhaps, either in her bag or her pockets.
She's a girl.
If it comes down to it, I can take it by force.
No, don't be stupid. I can't risk making a scene in this kind of place!
It's got to be an area where nobody is around...
But, where?
And what reason am I going to use for taking a girl like her, with such a strong sense of justice, there?
No! I've got to think about this in a different way...
I can do it!
There's got to be a natural way to find out her real name...
Light, you can trade your eyes at any point, remember?
It's no different from changing contact lenses.
It'll be over in a few seconds.
There's no way I'm going to waste half of my life on a girl like this.
In fact... I don't ever want to do that trade.
Stay out of this and shut the hell up, Shinigami!
Excuse me...
Yes?
Have you still got business at Police Headquarters as well?
I can walk the rest of the way by myself.
I understand...
Police Inspector
Asahi Shijuurou
All the names and positions are fake.
Fake police IDs?!
In order to kill, Kira needs a face and a name; that's the premise we're pursuing Kira on.
It's only natural that we do this much.
But for a policeman to forge an ID...
No. If Kira does require a name in order to kill, these fake names could play a massive role in saving our lives.
We'd better hold on to these.
I agree.
Please, use those if you ever need to tell someone outside of this place your name.
Yes!
Also, take care not to display those within Police Headquarters.
It may prove to be bothersome.
Understood.
Next, I want you all to wear these belts.
Belts?
In the buckle, there is a communications device; this will allow Ryuuzaki to pinpoint your location.
If you press the buckle twice, my cell phone will ring.
And I will call you right back.
Firstly, you'll need to return to work tomorrow morning.
You will then need to use these methods to obtain hotel names and room numbers from me.
You can also use them in case of an emergency.
It's kinda like we're the special forces out to get Kira or something... cool, huh?
Matsuda! This isn't child's play!
Don't be flippant!
...Yes.
Really, thank you for everything.
Thanks to you, I now have confidence in my own thoughts.
No problem.
The fact that Ryuk asked me whether I wanted to trade my eyes, confirms that she's using a fake name.
At this rate, the theory that Kira may have been on that bus... and under investigation by Ray Penber will lead straight back to me!
At this rate, the theory that Kira may have been on that bus... and under investigation by Ray Penber, will lead straight back to me!
Hey, she's leaving. Are you okay with that?
I got approximately five minutes before she gets back to Police Headquarters.
I've got to think! Within five minutes... some way of finding out her name...
If there is someone at headquarters by the time this girl gets there, I'll be finished!
I've got to find a way of discovering her real name and disposing of her...
Less than three minutes away from headquarters...
In that case...
Oh... Whatcha going to do?
Umm...
Yes?
To be completely honest with you, there's some things I still haven't told you...
...Yes?
It's actually impossible for you to talk to anyone at headquarters.
Huh?!
Right now, I've got to engage her in some conversation that isn't too suspicious, and I can try to discover her name from that.
I can do it.
What do you mean by that?
Hasn't it struck you that it's rather strange that nobody's been there?
It does seem a little strange...
The investigation into Kira is currently operating using a system where nobody is told who is in it.
If the names of the investigators were to be made public, they may end up suffering the same tragic fate as your fiancé.
I can understand that...
That's why, at headquarters, they told you that nobody was in.
Basically, it's going to be impossible for you to ever speak to anyone there...
That's not bad, Light. I've come to expect nothing less.
How do you know so much?
This girl is shrewd.
I guess I'm going to have to tell you... I'm actually a member of the investigation.
You're a member of the investigation?!
Yes.
Right now, L is leading the investigation.
Yes, that's what I thought.
He's struggling with staff resources on the investigation. People are frightened of Kira and have been resigning.
I may only be a high school student, but in the past, I've helped the police with two incidents that have resulted in convictions.
And that's why you are on the team?
I'm able to go in and out of headquarters as I like, and can investigate whatever cases I want.
As a result, the investigative team is made up of people who have proved their ability, and are also people who we can trust.
It's a team that's made up only of specially selected individuals.
I see... but even if that's the case, I'll still try going to headquarters, just in case.
Thank you.
W-Wait!
Didn't I just tell you that you won't be able to speak to anyone?
If it's possible, I'd like to speak directly to L.
Come to think of it, what's happening at Police Headquarters right now?
Currently there's no one there.
That's not so good.
Take turns and ensure that there's always someone there.
Understood.
Aizawa, it'll be your turn today.
Yes! It's not far from here at all.
Maki-san, please wait!
It'll be impossible for you to see L. There's no way!
It's possible that he might agree to see me...
Even though I only took orders from a voice through a computer, I worked with him on case two years ago in America.
You worked for L?!
Up until three months ago, I was an FBI investigator.
This is it!
I can use this.
Is that so?!
I thought that the way you were investigating Kira didn't seem to be amateurish!
You remain discreet and wise whilst slowly closing down upon your target.
I could learn a lot from someone like you.
I'm amazed that you seem to be able to spout lies just like that.
In my own way, I decided that I shouldn't trust the police or any investigators on this case... but I can trust L.
I thought that if I went to headquarters first and had him confirm my identity, I'd be able to speak to him directly.
I see... but why did you tell me what you wanted to tell L?
While I was getting irritated by not being able to speak to anyone, someone appeared claiming to be the son of the Chief of Police...
No, that's not it...
Let me be honest...
I felt something... something about you was similar to L...
Would you like to investigate this with me?
Huh?
Would you like to become a member of the investigation too?
Of course, we can't just let anyone join... but we do need people like you!
You're not someone who should just be an informer.
You used to be an FBI investigator, and you are more talented than most of our current investigators!
Plus, you've already gained L's trust.
The only things you need to join the investigation are: a valid form of ID, a recommendation from one of the team members, and L's approval.
Me... as part of the investigative team?
It's got to be fate that I met you!
I'll recommend you.
Oh... I'm sorry. I got a bit carried away there.
Not at all.
Even if you only investigate whenever it's convenient for you, I'm sure that you've got your own life to deal with.
And since you live in America...
We were supposed to get married, and then move to America for good this spring.
But now that he's dead, I don't know what I'm going to do...
Good. Now that I've managed to get this far, I need to back off a little more.
But, you're still young and beautiful. I don't want you to get involved in such a dangerous case.
No! I have nothing left to lose now.
I want to catch Kira; beyond that, I want nothing.
Please, allow me to investigate with you.
I'm so glad.
In that case, can I see some ID?
Err...
Yes?
I'm so sorry, but the name I gave you earlier was a fake.
Huh? That's okay. That just shows how amazing you are.
You are one step ahead of me.
This just makes me think more highly of you.
Is my Japanese driver's license acceptable?
Yes.
Just in time.
Name: Misora Naomi
D.O.B.: 11th February, Showa 54 (1979)
Issued: 6th February, Heisei 14 (2002)
Expires: February, Heisei 19 (2007)
Misora Naomi
Suicide
1st January 2007, from 1:15pm onwards
Her behaviour becomes driven by the sole
thought of formulating the best method
of committing suicide, yet keeping the
body undiscovered so as not to cause
trouble for others. Within 48 hours,
executes this plan and dies.
Err, why do you keep checking your watch like that?
Oh, this?
It's because...
I am Kira.
What's wrong?
There's something I've got to do...
I should be able to get a hold of my father now.
Don't you want to talk to him?
I've got nothing to say to him now.
Goodbye, Misora Naomi-san.
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
Thanks to Ryuk's information and my earlier preparations, I've managed to keep up the appearance of a regular exam student.
ICPO is sending in 1,500 investigators to assist with the Kira case
Using the Death Note, I can continue to kill criminals whose information is being released.
I'll take it on, L
Next Time
Gaze