We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
Murder Intent
Near, it went smoothly.
I have done what you told me to do.
Yes.
T, that's all for today.
I have received all the messages.
I also have one thing to say.
Yes?
I have confirmed it.
Ah? An email?
Ah, she wants to meet you she says.
I'm so envious of you!
Yes! That's to say that Mikami has confirmed it!
All I need to do now is to wait for Near to request a meeting.
Near, this is my victory.
I have predicted how you are going to move very well.
This is Gevanni.
Near, I have checked the notebook and confirm it.
Mikami has written down a page per day for the last three days.
The names on them match the victims. Mikami did not act differently as well.
Understood. Well then, let's start.
Ah, it's Near.
Here it comes!
L.
What is it, Near?
I want to meet you.
What?
I have something I want to show you regarding the Kira Incident.
But wasn't I regarded as Kira by you? You should not want to reveal to me what you look like.
No, I have to reveal my face to show you what I want to.
And, by revealing my face, I can reveal something to you as well.
With that, we will be able to put an end to this.
That's fine then.
I want to put an end to this wrong idea you have of me quickly as well.
Near is doing this to show that Light is Kira.
If Light is Kira, he will be doing this to kill Near.
That will be the time...
And before that, I would like to make an agreement with you.
Yes. Just spell out whatever requests you have.
First of all, all members from each team are to attend this meeting.
Meaning, we will gather everyone who is after Kira at that moment.
I see. That will be fine.
From my side, it will be like I told you. Four people including myself.
That will make up the whole SPK team.
And as for the abducted Mr. Mogi, we will bring him along, while releasing Amane without revealing where we are going.
You can confirm our release of Amane before moving.
How is that?
What should we do?
Near. Roger that. With me included, we have a team of five over here.
No... with Mogi-san with you, I have only three other people with me.
Understood. Well then, next will be deciding our meeting place.
There's a Daikoku Wharf at the Southeast area. At the moment, it is not being used.
It is a place also known as "Yellow Box".
If this is good enough, we will proceed with the meeting.
How is that, Yagami Light?
With that, you should be able to do what you want to do as well.
One more thing. I would like someone in the investigation team to bring the notebook.
Why the notebook?
That's simple.
If all of you came over to meet me, there will be no one keeping guard on the notebook.
I can promise you this.
I will not attempt to take the notebook away.
To confirm that you are bringing the real one, and are indeed from the team,
I will just need Mr. Aizawa's confirmation, and I will believe in that.
I get it.
But, please make sure someone other than L is carrying it.
I still think that L is Kira.
I get it, but I will get to choose who carries it. Will that be fine?
Yes.
Then, we are only left with the day and date.
The day and date? Time is the important factor here.
If Mikami is doing his judgment from midnight, he must have picked out his targets during the day.
If we take this time into consideration...
3 days after today, on the 28th, at 1pm. How is that?
1pm? That's the time I expected.
Near knows how Mikami work.
Understood. On our side, any time is good.
Then, 3 days later at 1pm.
Yes.
Near!
Yagami Light!
I have predicted and read your moves. I am definitely going to win!
Takada-san, I'm sorry.
I am quite busy today...
Busy?
Are you saying you're not staying until the morning?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
My hands will be full over the next 2 to 3 days with police work.
What a pity...
Mikami and Takada have already been instructed on what to do.
This is the last instruction to kill Near.
Smoke? There's an attacker!
Takada-sama, are you okay?
Yes.
He's getting away! After him!
Takada-sama, let's get into NHN quickly.
Don't do that! With this kind of attack, it will be dangerous inside NHN!
Mello!
For the time being, it's better to get away from here.
Takada-sama, please get on the bike.
Quick!
Takada-sama, it's alright.
Get on the bike and get away...
Yes.
A team and B team, stay around Takada-sama. Other teams, please go after the attacker in the car just now.
Yosh, I have confirmed her safety.
Please help Takada-sama into the number 7 car.
This cannot be...! Takada-sama is...!
Damn!!
Idiots! Stop that!
What if you hit Takada-sama?
What are you doing?
One of the attackers is armed with various weapons.
The Takada Guard Team and the police are doing their best to find out where she is.
T-This is bad!
Is it Near again?
Near... He had arranged for us to meet in 3 days.
What will he gain from something like this?
No, rather than saying Near is behind this...
It's Near!
Those guys have been waiting for me...
How many guards does Takada have?
Hey, hey! Since when is Japanese allowed to have possessions of those nice arms?
And besides, you want to know where my accomplice has taken Takada, right?
You can't possibly fire at--
What an idiot. It's not like you were going to tell us a thing.
Going against Kira-sama is definitely a crime punishable by death.
This person... is one of the people Yagami-kun told me to be especially careful of...
Mello! Mihael Keehl...
Take off everything you are wearing and put them in there.
Hurry up.
You can have this blanket.
L, this time, the abduction of Takada has nothing to do with me.
Is that so? If that's the case, Mello...
Yes. To tell you the truth, the guard that I sent has already confirmed it was done by Mello.
For the trouble my guard has caused, I'm sorry.
Near, if it's you, can you get through to Mello?
No, that is impossible.
Although I do have a way to do that, Mello will not respond at a time like this.
Before I take off my underwear, can you pass me the blanket?
Very well.
The Guard Team has taken down one of the accomplices of the kidnappers.
They are currently still tracking where Takada-sama is.
So, it was no use after all, Light?
Yes... Takada-san's phone is off.
With no way to get in contact with Takada, there's nothing other to do than to wait.
There is no other way than this. I have to be the one to do it!
The identity of the man who was shot to death is still unknown.
Matt... I got you killed... sorry.
Light-kun!
It couldn't be!
Everyone, keep quiet!
Yes?
Yagami-kun, I...
Takada-san?
Takada-san, are you okay?
If she can contact me through her phone, that would mean... she's gotten away from Mello... or...
Yagami-kun! Help me!
It's okay now. Calm down and answer my questions.
I understand.
First of all, the place. Do you know where you are right now?
I don't know where I am.
I am locked inside a truck.
When we were at the expressway, I did saw a signboard stating "Nagano". Right now, we're in some building...
Takada-san. You're Kira's spokeswoman. Do you remember how I told you the possibility that your life would be in danger?
Yes. I remember that.
In those situations, I told you what you are supposed to do. Do you remember them?
I remember.
The things that Yagami-kun told me to do...
I have done them.
Done them?
Even when I was stripped naked, I did not resist, but did what Yagami-kun said, and placed staying alive as my top priority...
I have done them all.
Yagami-kun, I have done everything you told me to.
Come quickly! Save me!
Takada-san, you know what to do from now, right?
To do as much judgment as possible...
I know that, but Yagami-kun...
Can you do it?
I can...
Aizawa-san, Ide-san, let's go.
Matsuda-san will stay watch in HQ.
Roger that.
It's me.
Do as much judgment as possible.
Yes... yes... I understand.
The fact that she is telling me this, means that she has taken out the kidnappers.
If that's the case, she must be in a state where she can't move around.
Nakajima-kun, I am going to the actual scene of the case.
Yes.
Step on it. I've gotten her location.
Get on the freeway and head towards Karuizawa.
So it's Karuizawa...
Damn... that will take at least 30 minutes.
Please hurry up.
It's Mello, and we don't know what he'll do.
Yes.
Well, well. Aizawa and Ide are still too careless.
They just sat in the frontseats without me asking them to.
With that, I don't even have to do much.
This is...
Mello!
What's this?
Takada Kiyomi, suicide.
On 26th January 2013, at 2:32pm, burnt all her belongings and anything written down before burning herself to death.
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
With this, it's finished.
No... It starts from today.
The perfect world of Kira...
All who know of the notebook... will die!
Next Time