We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
And once you realize that I am Kira, we're getting married!
So, as you can all hear... Higuchi is Kira!
Guidance
If the killing of criminals cease now, there would be no doubt that Higuchi has Kira's power.
However... although I've always thought that Amane would go a long way to help Yagami Light out
However... although I've always thought that Amane would go a long way to help Yagami Light out,
I never realized she'd go this far.
Now that she's gone this far and stopped the killings... it'll become even more difficult to witness the actual method they use to kill.
I need to think of a plan...
Misa, how did you manage to get Higuchi to confess?
Huh? Oh, that guy's totally crazy about Misa.
I told him that I'd marry Kira.
Plus, he's already convinced that Misa is the second Kira.
Unless I say this now, I might end up contradicting myself later on...
Idiot!
Didn't I tell you to deny that, no matter what?!
B-But now we know Higuchi is Kira. All we've got to do is catch him.
This is what you might call "nice work", right, Matsuda-san?
Yet, as things stand, we're still no closer to discovering how he kills.
Yeah, that's right.
Before I capture him, I want to know how he kills...
And if the killing of criminals cease, you won't be able to see how he kills, isn't that right?
Yes. In any case, even though we're going to capture Higuchi,
that won't be until after we've determined that the judging of criminals has ceased.
Please allow me to think about this...
Weddy?
Yes?
How's the situation?
It's looking good.
The movements of those seven can be tracked about 70% of the time, while inside the company building.
What about outside of the company?
With just Watari and myself, it's impossible.
What if we were to solely focus on Higuchi?
Higuchi?
So far, I've only entered five of their houses, but Midou, Namikawa and Higuchi's houses have security systems that aren't normal.
In particular, Higuchi has recently build a basement that blocks electromagnetic waves.
It even took me a full two days to infiltrate that place.
Just as we thought, Higuchi is definitely suspicious.
Understood. In that case, install bugging equipment, transmitters and cameras in Higuchi's car rather than his house.
Eh?! After going through all that?!
Do you have any idea of how hard it is to break into someone's house?!
Besides, do you even know how many cars Higuchi owns?!
Six.
Okay, fine. You want me to do all of them, right?
Yes please.
Woah... if they had done that a little earlier, it would have been dangerous...
Yagami-kun... I'm sorry to bring this up again, but let me ask you this directly:
What is it?
Do you remember killing them?
You still insist on saying that?! I am not Kira!
How many times do I have to te--
Please, just answer the question.
Do you remember?
I don't remember.
What about Misa-san?
I don't remember anything because I'm not Kira!
Yagami-kun, I need you to consider these assumptions and analyze it earnestly.
Your answer may be the first step in capturing Kira.
Yagami Light was Kira.
Kira's powers were then transferred to someone else.
Now Yagami Light has absolutely no memory of being Kira.
That will be the premise behind this analysis.
Will you be able to think on that basis?
Yeah, I'll give it a try.
Yagami Light was Kira.
Kira's powers were then transferred to someone else.
Was this transfer done by Yagami Light's own will?
Or was there someone else behind Yagami Light, who bestowed Kira's power, and transferred that power from Yagami Light to another?
With those presumptions... it'd have been by Yagami Light's own will.
That's right...
If there was a human behind the scenes who could bestow and transfer that power... and they didn't want their methods discovered...
It's a little suspicious that they hadn't transferred until right at the very last moment...
And if we accept the existence of something that could look down on us from heaven, there would be no way to catch it.
I would either have died a long time ago, or I'd be spending eternity being toyed with in the palm of their hand.
There's no way that something like that exists.
Even if Yagami Light was Kira...
Only the current Kira can use that power.
Yagami-kun... thanks to that, I'm feeling 99% better.
We'll create a situation where Higuchi will not pass the power on to anyone else... and let him show us how he kills people.
What are you planning?
I'm going to use Sakura TV to trap Higuchi.
You mean Dokkiri TV?!
Dokkiri TV is the Japanese version of Candid Camera.
What's that?
We'll utilize the "Kira Special" that Demegawa continues to broadcast.
We'll arrange a three-hour show, and at the beginning of it, we'll announce that "We'll reveal Kira's identity by the end of this show!"
Is he going to believe that? After all, it's on Sakura TV, right?
Besides, Higuchi might not even watch that program.
All we've got to do is contact Namikawa and ask him to call Higuchi and say: "There's trouble brewing, turn on the TV".
If Higuchi sees someone who may know his secret, he'll believe it.
I see! You're planning to use Aiber.
You're going to reveal that in reality he was a spy!
No, you're totally wrong. I'm not planning to use Aiber.
The person Higuchi sees on TV needs to be someone that he thinks he'll be able to kill, otherwise there's no point.
To be blunt, it has to be someone whose name he thinks he could quickly and easily find if he tries.
Is there even such a person around?
It's got to be Matsuda-san.
Matsu!
Matsuda, huh?
Higuchi believes that you were trying to eavesdrop on their meeting,
so if the supposedly dead manager begins to threaten to expose everything, he'll believe it.
He's right.
We'll get Sakura TV to prepare a screen and a microphone the way they usually do with witnesses.
From the silhouette and from what's being said, Higuchi should be able to work out that it's "Manager Matsui".
Furthermore, we'll have the station "slip up" and momentarily reveal the face of the person behind the screen.
Cool! Sounds fun!
And he'll announce that by the end of the show, he'll reveal the full identity of "H", better known as Kira.
Kira's identity will be announced at the end of this show!
Placed in that situation, all Higuchi will be concerned about, is how fast he'll be able to find out the manager's real name.
We can predict Higuchi's actions.
And then, we'll be able to confirm exactly how he's been killing people.
If this plan has a flaw, it's that...
If Higuchi is similar to the second Kira, and can kill someone solely by knowing their face...
Matsuda-san will die.
But given that Matsuda-san is still alive, and that Higuchi wants Misa, I'd say it was unlikely.
We'll only be using this plan if criminals stop dying though.
We'll need to give it two to three days to be sure.
You can make your own decision on whether or not to go ahead with it during this time, Matsuda-san.
I don't need two or three days.
Please, allow me to do it.
So, what's the deal with this secret meeting then?
Namikawa, who do you think is Kira?
What's the point in asking that?
It could even be you, Shimura, or you, Midou.
No, it's not Shimura.
He came crying to me about how he could no longer go along with Kira's evil ways.
Shimura, if Midou was Kira, you'd be dead.
No, you and Midou would have had successful lives regardless of all this.
Neither of you would do something so stupid as to call an eight-person meeting to discuss murder.
Even I am able to figure out that much.
The only reason everyone's going along with this is because they're all scared of being killed by Kira.
But if we continue this way, we'll be caught sooner or later.
No, in fact, unless that happens, it'll never end.
Well then, Shimura, let me ask you the same question. Who do you think is Kira?
Takahashi or Higuchi.
Takahashi merely acts as a foil for Kira, it's necessary that Kira has someone who's not as smart as him.
Seems like everyone has already figured this out...
It's likely that it's Higuchi.
Yeah. Higuchi is the one who desires money and promotion the most.
He's always talking about how he doesn't care for promotion, but conversely this just shows how hung up he really is about it.
He berates people, but doesn't know how to manage them,
and as a result he has been demoted from Director of Development to merely the Head of a Development lab.
Am I the only one who you've asked to come here?
We asked Ooi, but he said that we're free to have our pathetic little meeting without him.
Typical of Ooi, always brash.
Since Kida had to organize Coil's commission, plus the finances for it, he's not Kira either.
Namikawa, after Hatori died, you received a phone call during the next meeting... who was it?
Shimura, you're really shrewd, aren't you?
Kira must have chosen you for your prudence.
Namikawa.
This is L. Namikawa-san, are you alone right now?
No...
In that case, please act naturally like before.
There's no need for that.
Currently, I'm with some people who've realized that the call I received from you during that meeting was odd.
Who's on the phone, Namikawa?
It's L.
L, I've got both Midou and Shimura with me.
It's unlikely that either of them is Kira, and both are annoyed with Kira.
Whatever happens, they're both happy to sit on the sidelines and watch this thing between L and Kira unfold, just like me.
That's fine.
Tonight, we'll capture Kira, but we'll need your help.
So, this is the end for Higuchi...
You knew?
I guess even L can be tricked.
Thanks to your response, I'm now 100% sure that it's Higuchi.
Namikawa's pretty good! Looking at his face, Misa thought he might be smart...
No, that was a mistake on Yagami-kun's part.
Tonight, we'll be using the "Kira Special" shown on Sakura TV at 7 pm to force Higuchi's hand.
I need you to contact Higuchi a few minutes after the program has started, and tell him to watch the TV.
I promise that the remaining six of you won't be adversely affected.
If Kida, Takahashi or Ooi attempt anything... I need you to stop them.
Okay...
Looks like it really is Higuchi.
He'll probably be caught tonight.
It's been three days since I stopped judging criminals.
That should be enough...
If I marry the second Kira, Amane, I'll have the Shinigami's Eyes, and I'll be able to control Yotsuba completely!
Higuchi, this looks bad. Turn on Sakura TV.
So, you're saying one of them is Kira, right?
Yes, and I've got plenty of proof.
What the hell is this?
It's bound to be fake. After all, this is Sakura TV we're talking about.
At the beginning of the program he stated; "I overheard a meeting between eight people".
Someone who knows about the meetings?!
Who?! Has someone betrayed us?!
And then one of them was killed, so now there's only seven.
The victim was Mr. "H".
"H"? Hatori...
Knowing this much, he's either one of the other six... or Coil.
Mr. "H" was killed because he wanted out of those meetings.
No, none of them would gain a thing from doing this.
Yet, there shouldn't be anyone else who'd know about these meetings...
T-This guy...
I-It's him?!
He used to be Misa's manager, I think his name was Matsui. Why the hell is he still alive?!
He gambled on faking a fall from a high rise apartment, because he thought he was going to be killed,
and escaped by landing on the veranda on the floor below, or so he said earlier.
No, afterwards I wrote the name on his business card into the Death Note, just in case...
Why is he still alive?!
Perhaps he was in the business previously, and kept his stage name when he became a manager... or something...
I don't get it!
In addition, he says that he's been investigating Yotsuba and knows who Kira is.
I'm in the process of contacting everyone now.
Okay, I'll hang up for now.
About the accident just now, are you alright? Would you like to stop?
No, I knew that I'd be letting myself in for trouble from the beginning.
Even if I die, I'll try my best until the end - in the name of justice!
Nice, nice... as long as you ensure you don't make the announcement until the end of the program.
I've got no choice but to kill him!
The second Kira, Misa, will know his name as well as his face...
It's here!
What the hell is going on?!
It's taken me a while to come to this decision and make this announcement, but ever since I found out the truth,
I've felt that as a human being, I must persevere.
This is bad... I could be exposed at any moment.
That announcement isn't far off now. Stay tuned!
Cosme Misa. Brilliant gloss.
An angel's sparkle. Misa's Cashmere Rouge.
Midou? It's me. Sakura TV is causing trouble.
Your father is in the House of Councillors, right?
Get him to put pressure on the Ministry of Public Affairs and put a stop to this program.
I'm watching it too, and it would be impossible.
No one is going to believe this, and doing that will just make it look suspicious.
Anyway, there's no need to worry.
His face was on TV, so we were able to identify him as Matsui Tarou.
Namikawa contacted everyone and told them to watch the TV.
Since one of us seven is Kira, Matsui Tarou will soon be dead.
I see! As Kira, I'm the only one who's realized that "Matsui Tarou" is a fake name!
If I tell them that, they'll know I'm Kira.
Everyone! Soon Kira's identity will become clear! Stay tuned!
Guess you're right. See ya.
Damn it!
Ryuuzaki, Higuchi is calling Mogi-san, who's outside Yoshida Productions.
Yes, here it comes. Just as we planned.
Moji! Where's Misa?!
Ah, Higuchi-sama, thank you so much for doing business with us!
Misa is currently having one of her rare days off, so she has gone out.
She should be back tomorrow morning...
I'm asking you where she went.
I'm sorry, but she said it was private and left without telling anyone.
I'm terribly sorry. I'll be able to contact her tomorrow.
Damn it! I know his face. If only I knew his name, I could...
Her former manager, was he in show business?
Huh?
"Matsui Tarou", remember?!
I replaced him, so I can't really tell you more.
For such inquiries, you should try calling the office.
Oh! But they're all presently in Okinawa. Maybe you could try the President?
This is going so precisely as planned, it's almost scary.
Let's not be scared. Just sit back and enjoy this, Yagami-kun.
I'll relay the call between Higuchi and the President of Yoshida Productions.
This is Higuchi of the Yotsuba Group.
That guy who used to work for you, Matsui Tarou, was that his real name?
He's getting more and more direct. Higuchi is such a fool.
Ah yes, he was using a stage name when he was a manager, Higuchi-san.
It shows that he's getting desperate.
What's his real name?
I think it's Yamada... no, wait! It's Yamashita.
As for his first name... I can't remember.
Don't fuck with me! You should at least know the names of the people you employ!
Hey, there's no need for that kind of talk.
If you go to the office it should be in the records.
Well, go and tell me.
Gimme a break, we're on the first staff trip we've had in two years!
But if you insist, I'll give you the combination code to access the office.
I don't mind if you go and check it out yourself.
The records are kept in the bottom drawer of the far left hand side desk as you enter.
They're ordered alphabetically. I think it should be Yamashita.
If they're planning on announcing it at the end of the program, I've still got two hours.
I wonder if he'll make a move...
Higuchi's status confirmed.
I'm in pursuit.
Until now, everything has gone exactly as we predicted.
Yes...
I'll kill him... for sure!
After coming this far, I'm not going to be defeated... I'm going to get it all!
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
Now, I'm the greatest!
Damn it. I don't want to use this!
The Chief has been shot!
Hey, Higuchi!
We'll have 100% of the viewers for sure!
Think carefully.
Made it, just in time!
Next Time
Frenzy