We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
Near, isn't it about time you tell me your thoughts regarding all this?
Given the rather "convenient" interaction between Kira and the Japanese police during this incident,
at the very least, I can conclude that Kira and the Japanese police are working together.
"Working together"?!
And if that's true, then Kira is... the second-generation L.
I-It can't be...
Are you serious?!
Near!
Yes, but I'm only around 7% certain.
Commander Lester, when investigating, once you've decided on something,
you must believe in it absolutely, and if you're wrong, then "sorry" should suffice.
Justice
"Recently, crime has decreased in Japan, because if you do something bad, your name will be put on the Internet, and you'll be killed by Kira.
Name?
That's what my dad says."
Unless you give me your name, we can't file a record.
H-Have mercy! Anything but my name!
I'll expose all your names on the Internet!
Kira-sama, please kill me
I want to announce, here and now, that Kira is Justice!
Kira's Realm
It's an undeniable fact that I've been appointed by Kira to be their spokesman.
There may be those who'll attempt to take my life...
But I'm prepared to lay down my life in order to bring you the words of Kira!
New Japanese Investigative Headquarters
"Kira's Realm"?
What a distasteful title...
What's this world turning into?
Investigating Kira is an inexcusable thing! I'll even go as far as saying that it's a crime!
We'd really be better off if they killed this guy...
The police, members of the public, criminals... whoever's investigating Kira, report them!
Well, it's time for the President's press conference.
I wonder what's happening? They said it's going to be a "message to the world"...
All you lot seem to do is watch TV.
We, the United States of America...
Don't tell me...
...hereby acknowledge Kira and will not oppose them.
Goddamn it!
Success!
Even America is finally accepting Kira.
W-What the hell is he saying?!
Do they fear Kira?!
Mr. President!
Explain yourself!
When was this decision made?!
Can you give us more details?!
Are you saying that Kira is Justice?!
"Justice"? I'm not saying that.
But, it's a fact that thanks to Kira's powers, war has ceased.
Organized crime, and not just in our own country, has also been obliterated.
If we openly oppose Kira, we will be killed. That much is certain.
So, while we won't acknowledge them as justice, we'll no longer take any measures to try and catch Kira.
Isn't that the same thing?!
Didn't you just say that you acknowledge Kira?!
Explain yourself!
Are you running away?!
And you call yourself this country's representative?!
I can't believe this... this is America we're talking about... and that was a presidential statement!
Um, can I be serious for a moment?
What's with the sudden change?
So, you normally aren't serious?
Do you really believe, from the depths of your heart, that Kira is evil?
What?!
What do you mean, Matsuda?!
To be honest... I just can't believe that they're completely evil.
You believe that Kira is Justice?
I don't know...
But I believe that Kira is fighting against evil.
It's also an undeniable fact that the world has become a better place for those who live honest lives.
You're wrong, Matsuda!
This is all just build on the fear of being slaughtered. This isn't real peace.
I know! I know that much, but... I also understand the feelings of those who proclaim Kira to be their savior.
I've always been in a weak position...
But I'm a cop! I can't acknowledge Kira.
I know that, and I want to catch them, because it's my job.
I've got to be crazy doing this without even being able to fully oppose Kira.
I don't think that is crazy, Matsuda-san.
What are you saying?! Even you, Light?!
Even Kira must realize that what they're doing is evil; yet, they've still decided to sacrifice themselves to change the world.
That's the type of justice Kira has chosen.
I'm assuming that's what Kira probably is thinking.
But it's not our job to decide whether Kira is good or evil.
We only have to catch Kira.
If we catch Kira, then Kira is evil.
If Kira takes control of the world, then Kira is Justice.
However, henceforth, things will accelerate and the world will rapidly turn toward Kira.
Kira will definitely become Justice.
What's going to happen to us now?
I guess we'll have to disband. Thanks to that chicken of a president.
No... he's not even a chicken. He's lower than a maggot.
This isn't a joke. There's no way acknowledging Kira is the right thing to do.
You're alive?!
Near!
What should we do?
Let them in.
Mello... welcome.
Put the gun down!
Everyone, please lower your guns.
Shedding blood here will only be a waste of our time.
But he killed our colleagues!
Please don't make me say this again and again; or objective is to capture Kira.
Killing Mello now would achieve nothing.
Okay...
Has this gone exactly as you expected it to so far, Near?
Yes. You must have heard it from Lidner... about what happened with the second-generation L.
Thanks to everything you've done, I've been able to narrow down Kira quite a bit.
Near!!
I'm not a device for you to solve your puzzles with!
Mello, if you want to shoot me, go ahead.
Mello! If you shoot Near, we'll have no choice but to shoot you.
If you both die here, what will that achieve?
It'll only make Kira happy!
You're right. Near, I only came to get back that photo you have of me.
Alright. This is the only photo... there are no copies.
I've dealt with anyone who would have known your face, at Wammy's House and elsewhere.
I can't say this with 100% certainty, but you won't be killed with that notebook.
Is that all you wanted, Mello?
Near...
I have no intention of cooperating with you.
I know that.
But... it'd be annoying to leave here with only this photo to show for it.
The murderer's notebook... it's a Shinigami's notebook.
Those who have the notebook can see the Shinigami.
Bullshit!
Who the hell is going to believe that?
I'll believe it.
What can Mello achieve by lying about that?
If he was going to lie, he'd lie about something more meaningful.
Therefore, Shinigami exist.
The notebook I had was once in the possession of someone other than a Shinigami.
And at least one of the rules written in there is fake.
That's about as much as I can tell you.
Near...
Mello...
Which of us will catch Kira first...
It's a race, huh?
We're both heading toward the same goal. I'll be there waiting for you.
Fine.
A fake rule...
Given what's already happened, things such as heart attacks and being able to manipulate people before their deaths must be true.
"Burning or shredding the notebook"? The notebooks still exist and there's no way to test that.
Which means...
The fake rule must be the one that states you'll die unless you write a name in the notebook within 13 days of the last.
Gevanni, get me L.
Of course.
It's Near!
Yes?
L, we caught Mello... but he got away.
However, I was able to question him a little.
So, you mean he didn't get away, you "allowed him" to get away? Am I right?
No, he really did get away.
Incidentally, he mentioned that that notebook was bound to a Shinigami.
Have you been able to verify the existence of such a being?
Yes. Shinigami do in fact exist.
I thought you wouldn't believe me even if I told you, so I never said anything.
There are a lot of things I'd like to ask that Shinigami.
I don't wanna be asked.
What bothers me the most are the rules written in the notebook, and the fact that there may be a fake rule.
There's a fake?
Yes.
L, I'd like to hear your thoughts on this. If there was a fake rule, which would it be?
By the process of elimination, it would have to be the one that says you'll die if you don't write a name within 13 days of the last.
So, you think that after all... so do I.
Shinigami, were there any fake rules written in the notebook?
Nope. There weren't.
There's a Shinigami with you, isn't there?
Yes.
Oh, really? I think I'm beginning to understand this now.
Kira is there, and is telling the Shinigami to lie.
This dude is amazing. He's spot on!
Even if there was a fake, and the Shinigami is lying, it doesn't mean anything, does it?
No, it would make Light's detainment pointless as well.
If it's not true that you need to continue to write in the notebook to stay alive,
then there's no meaning to the fact that he did nothing for 13 days.
T-That's different. There's no way Light-kun could be Kira.
Before he died, the Deputy Chief himself confirmed that Light-kun doesn't have a notebook.
In that case, how about we verify it like this?
I will write Mello's name in the notebook.
Then if I die 13 days after Mello, Kira wins. I don't care.
W-What? This is about winning and losing now?!
Verifying the "13 days" rule can only be a positive thing for the Kira investigation. There are no negatives.
Please allow me to lay down my life for this.
If I'm the only one to reject this idea, what sort of impression will that give the others?
Please give us a while. We'll need to review this proposal.
I'd like everyone to give me their honest opinions.
"We can't do this out of respect for human life"...
That's easy for me to say, but I was the one detained, and it'll sound suspicious coming from me.
It's strange. Killing Mello would avenge the Deputy Chief, so if Near wants to do that, I'm inclined to let him.
I'm against it.
I believe that no one here is Kira, and ultimately, killing people with the notebook is not something we should be doing.
Yeah, we should try to follow in the Deputy Chief's footsteps.
I'm also against the idea of verifying it.
Near, there's no way we can go ahead with verifying the notebook.
As I thought... Lastly, let me ask you one more thing.
To all of you at the Japanese Investigative Headquarters... have you ever thought, even once, that your "second-generation" L might be Kira?
If there's anyone there who, having heard the conversation up to this point, is willing to cooperate with my investigation in any way,
then ring the number I'm about to give you.
You'll be able to reach me.
Light-kun can't be Kira. No, I don't even want to think that!
But if the "13 days" rule is fake, he's not completely above suspicion.
Near... I've got no choice now but to kill you!
It's me.
This is Kira.
I-Is this some kind of joke?!
I'll let you decide when you compare tomorrow's events with the death list I'm about to read you.
Mr. President, first, I'd like to thank you deeply for your approval of me.
However, that's not enough.
I would like you to bring a swift end to the actions of the SPK, the organization out to get Kira, by ordering their dissolution.
Additionally, I would like you to use the police force, CIA,
FBI, and any other secret organizations to determine the whereabouts of the SPK members.
And when you uncover them, I would like you to tell me immediately via a communication point that I'll specify later.
Mr. President, whether you live a long life or not, is up to you.
Please remember that.
Understood.
Demegawa-san! Please wait!
Why are you going to New York all of a sudden?
I'm going to crush an organization that dares to oppose Kira-sama!
A live report!
The President dropped me a line under orders from Kira!
Even I don't know what's going on, and I don't even care!
Our viewing figures are going to go up by 100... no, 120%!
Now, everyone, the age of Kira is upon us!
The previous L suspected Light-kun too.
But if I was to suggest the need to investigate him again, then if he really is Kira, I'll just be killed.
"13 days" rule, eh?
Aizawa, we've known each other for a long time now... I know what's worrying you.
You've got to do what you believe in.
I never fully trusted L.
Even now I'm doing this because I want to work with you, not Light-kun.
Ide...
I'll contact Near without Light-kun finding out.
Got it.
No matter what you do, I'll ensure that no one finds out.
Light-kun... you're not Kira...
I want to believe that...
This is terrible! Live on TV, Demegawa's...
I, Demegawa, have finally tracked down the base of an evil organization that seeks to capture our God, Kira!
And along with my brothers, we have them surrounded!
Currently, they appear to be hiding in this building!
Witness the power of the people!
The power of Justice!!
When Near comes running out, I'll write his name in the notebook.
Light! Misa will give it her best!!
Near... at this rate we really will get dragged out of here...
L...
What's the matter, Near?
Is this one of Mello's plans to destroy the SPK?
Or does the SPK operate in such ways that allow even members of the public to track down their location?
You... how dare you lie to me so blatantly?
I win, Near.
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
As I thought! I can really use him!
Someone who genuinely worships Kira, a man who can understand, just by being given the notebook, that they are the chosen one.
There were no mistakes in my plan.
Next Time
Transfer