Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Negotiation
20th December - 11:50 am
You over there.
Yes?
The truth is, I actually came to Japan on a top secret mission, so if you could refrain from mentioning to the Japanese police that... err..
I understand.
I won't tell anyone that I've met you... including my father.
In that case, I'd better get going.
It's just as I thought.
I don't want anyone to know that I've encountered the FBI either.
If my father were to find out, L would definitely be informed.
He doesn't even suspect me slightly, and now this incident will be dismissed as a mere accident by the police.
Welcome home.
Yeah, I'm back.
What's up? What's with the big sigh?
Did something happen, Ray?
Yeah, I was caught up in a random bus hi-jacking.
A bus hi-jack?
A criminal, who attempted to rob a bank two days ago, decided to try his luck at a bus hi-jacking this time.
Japan's a scary place these days...
And you just happened to be on that bus?
Yeah.
In the end, the culprit jumped off the bus and ended up being hit by an oncoming car.
That culprit... did he die?
I think so...
I didn't have time to see things right through to the end though.
Ray...
What if that wasn't just a coincidence?
What do you mean?
I mean... you were investigating someone when you got on that bus, right?
And somehow, a criminal has ended up dead.
That's...
Hey, I know that you were a brilliant FBI investigator, but right now, you're just my fiancée.
You've got to remember that you're no longer an investigator.
"I won't get involved in the Kira-case."
"I won't do anything dangerous."
You promised me those things before coming here, and that's why I brought you with me, so we can visit your parents in Japan.
I know, Ray. It's just a habit.. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Sorry, you don't need to worry about it that much.
Once we start a family, you'll be too busy to remember what it was like to be an investigator.
You won't have the time to slip into old habits.
More importantly, you've got to help me think of a way to impress your dad.
Huh?
You gonna write the name of the agent you've just identified?
Not yet. It'll be a week before I'll write his name.
If he were to die immediately after encountering me, it'd look suspicious.
It's better for me to wait till his investigation progresses further, and allow him the opportunity to investigate as many people connected to the police as possible.
For the time being, I'll bait L with some more prisoners...
L, there's been another victim that's left some sort of suicide note.
Send me the images.
Shinigami...
L, did you know
Are you trying to tell me that Shinigami actually exist?
Watari, tell the police to continue surveying the prisons. We may see more prisoners leaving notes behind.
Understood.
27th December - 3:00 pm
Wow, it's pretty busy around here.
Is this where it's going to happen?
Finally I'll be able to show you the results of the investigations and experiments I've been carrying out these past few days.
Experiments?
Yeah.
With the aid of the Death Note, I've been able to identify several different methods of killing people by utilizing some of the local criminals as my test subjects.
Accidental Death
26th December              8:30 pm
Death from being run over by a car.
If the cause of death and any further details are written in the Death Note first, and the name is added afterwards...
Hanekuroda
That person will still die exactly as it is written.
Eeh? Even I hadn't realized that...
He's here.
Right on time.
Ray Penber-san.
Turn around, and I'll kill you.
I'm Kira.
If you even think about turning around or putting your hands in your pockets I'll kill you instantly.
This can't be real!
But wait... This voice... I've heard it before.. somewhere...
First, I'll prove to you that I am Kira.
You see that cafe over there?
There's a guy wearing glasses working there. I'm going to kill him.
Y-You're kidding?!
Don't do it!
I thought that I should at least kill one person for you to take me seriously.
It couldn't be helped.
That man has a record of physically abusing women, but due to lack of evidence he's never been convicted for it.
It's only right that those who cause suffering to society should receive judgement.
I'm sure that L's told you that I'm only able to kill people if I know their faces.
To put it simply, I can kill anyone who's around us.
If you've got any requests, just go ahead and ask. I'll kill them.
S-Stop!
I believe that you're Kira.
In any case, I'm sure that it'd be much more painful for you to lose someone dear to you than to lose anyone here.
I'd like you to consider that person as the one really being held hostage here.
Impossible! Not her...
That's correct. I've done some research on you.
If you go against any of my orders, I'll kill everyone. Including your family.
And of course you.
I understand. What do you want from me?
I take it you've brought your laptop with you?
Do you have all the files of all the investigators assigned to Japan on it?
Going to work, I've always got my laptop with me, but I don't have any of those files.
Then, please take this envelope.
First, take out the transceiver and put the ear piece on.
A transceiver? This is practically a toy...
Yet, this way, there'll be no record of communication, and even underground, as long as we're close enough, we'll be able to talk.
He's thought this through...
Next, please get on the Yamanote line.
The Yamanote line is a train line that circulates around central Tokyo.
I don't care whether you take the inside or the outside track.
I'll be constantly observing you from a distance.
Even while you are on the train, look straight ahead.
Please remember that I can kill you at any time.
Once you've boarded, sit at a corner seat by the door.
If there isn't one free, we'll wait until there is one.
I'm going to ask you several questions.
If I get an answer that completely conflicts with my expectations, I'll kill your girlfriend.
How many FBI agents have entered Japan, and how are they organized?
Answer quietly into the transceiver.
I heard that there are twelve of us, divided into four teams.
In that case, take out the contents of the envelope.
What the hell... is this?
I'd like you to write the name of your direct superior, who should have all the names of the investigators, in the top box.
What's going on? What's he trying to do?
But right now, I've got no choice but to do as he says.
If he only has their names, he shouldn't be able to kill them.
Next, I'd like you to open up your laptop.
Your superior should be sending you some files soon.
They should be the files containing the names and faces of all FBI agents that have entered Japan.
W-What's this?
Like before, I want you to write each name in a box while concentrating on each of their faces.
I don't get it.
Kira, what are you trying to do?
What are you doing?
Seems like you've finished your work.
Please place the papers and the transceiver back into the original envelope, and leave it on the wire rack.
Once you've done that, remain on the train for a further 30 minutes without moving.
Then, once you're sure that no one will notice you leaving the envelope, disembark the train at a station.
Why... why can't I remember whose voice this is?
4:41 pm
Kira!
What on earth are you?
Yagami... Light!
Goodbye... Ray Penber.
The papers Ray Penber wrote on, were torn out pages from the Death Note.
Basically, he killed his own teammates without even realizing it.
Penber's superior died after sending the files to all members of the team.
All the investigators on the team died of a heart attack after receiving those files.
L, you've got a call from the Director of the FBI.
It's me.
I've just heard that all our investigators that we sent to Japan have been found dead.
All of them died of a heart attack.
I can only assume that they must have been killed by Kira.
I'm sorry to have to do this, L, but we're going to have to cut off our investigations in Japan.
Chief Yagami is on the line for you.
L, I've just spoken to the Director of the FBI.
It seems that you've been using the FBI to investigate us and those who are connected with us.
Yes.
What is the meaning of this?
Do you mean to say that you actually suspected us?
I decided that it was a necessity in order to narrow down Kira's identity.
This is unacceptable!
You can't treat your allies as spies!
I guess we can't trust L after all.
But this means that Kira must have killed FBI agents too.
Kira will kill anyone who opposes them, even if the person isn't a criminal.
Kira is a real monster!
There's another prisoner who has left a suicide note.
L, did you know?
Shinigami..
only eat apples
Damn you, Kira!
He's dead.
Ray is..
No! He was killed by Kira.
What's this "family meeting" about?
Even if I tried to hide it, you'd all eventually find out, so I'll tell you now.
I'm currently heading the investigation into Kira.
Really? Wow, you're really amazing, dad!
That's just the start of my problems.
Huh?
To tell you the truth, yesterday, twelve FBI agents that were sent to Japan to investigate Kira.. all died.
You mean they were all killed by Kira?
And to put it bluntly, if I go after Kira, I may die.
It's the most horrific crime I've ever seen.
A lot of my staff are leaving.
You should quit as well, dad.
I don't want you to die!
She's right. Your life is far more important than your job!
No. There's no way I'm stepping down from this case.
We must not bow to evil.
Dad...
Dear...
I think that's very honorable of you, father. I'm very proud of you.
But if anything happens to you... I'll make sure that Kira will be sentenced to death!
Kira is willing to kill those who oppose them even if they aren't criminals.
We could all be killed.
I'd like you to think of your lives, families and friends.
Anyone who wants to leave is free to do so. There'll be no risk of demotion, I promise you.
Only those of you who have the conviction to fight Kira, even if you have to sacrifice all the things I've just mentioned, should stay.
That is all.
What should we do?
Yes, yes. That's him.
I remember him telling everyone to get down.
But I don't remember the rest of the passengers.
Is that so? I understand. Thank you.
If my thinking is correct... Kira may have been among those passengers.
In that case, I should be able to use this bus as a route to get to Kira.
Five, huh?
Six people, including myself.
No. In fact, I'd like to think of it as six people willing to stand up to evil.
I'm willing to trust the six of you who have shown yourselves to have a great sense of justice.
Wait a second!
L may have just said that he trusts us, but we don't trust L!
L, we've all decided to put our lives on the line to catch Kira.
You should know what that means!
Yet you've only ever given orders without revealing your face.
We can't work with someone like that!
L, if you're serious about joining forces with us to catch Kira, will you come here and join us?
I just said that I would trust you.
I would like the following
events to be kept secret
between the eight of us.
I'd like to meet you six,
trustworthy people as
soon as possible.
But before that,
I want you to leave
the building and
discuss whether
you choose to
trust me or not.
Why is he asking for our support now, at the risk of exposing himself?
They say that he's solved countless cases on his own.
He should be able to solve this one on his own too.
Besides, judging by his past actions, we may end up dealing with a fake.
A fake, huh? Could be possible...
I-I want to trust L.
I believe that L's skills will be invaluable to us in this case.
Me too.
L's said from the start that this case would require the co-operation of the police.
Isn't it conceivable that... L was actually waiting for this to happen?
"For this to happen"?
There were people on the case, right from the start, who were suspicious of L.
People were resigning left, right and center, and information was somehow being leaked.
It would have been impossible for him to command the investigation with trust.
You mean L's been waiting until only those dedicated individuals he could trust, and whom are willing to stand against evil remained at headquarters?
Either way, if you're going to join forces with L, I quit.
Don't worry. I won't try to follow any of you, or try to find L.
I choose to trust L and work alongside him.
Me too.
I'm currently in a room at the Teitou hotel.
I'll be switching between hotels in the city every few days.
I'd like to request that my hotel room be used as the real headquarters during this investigation.
If you agree to these stipulations, I'd like you to split into two groups, and, leaving a gap of at least 30 minutes between the two, come up to my room before midnight.
Kira, right now it seems that we are moving towards each other at an even rate.
Alright then.
I'll expose myself as L, in front of people, for the first time.
If you find out about this, I can guarantee that you'll try to move in on me.
Bring it on!
I've done quite a lot over the last few days...
I've got to think hard.
Did I make any mistakes?
How should I proceed from here?
The real battle starts now, L!
Please come in.
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
If this woman had spoken to the police before I got to her...
But it seems that gods other than the Shinigami are on my side...
Next Time
Open Seams