We've always been this to free all the pain
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Benri benri banzai
Banzai, you're so useful!
ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
Hora BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
Hey! You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
BIRIBIRI ikarasu ka?
You gonna piss me off, make me tremble with rage?
Ningen
Human!
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guilt never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
urami ni wana, dare daun
Who fell down the trap of resentment?
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern; the guild never fades.
fuanzai ippai hanzai kienai towa ni
WHAT'S UP
What's up? So much ground for concern!
fuanzai ippai
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
Aa ningen... ningen FUCKER!
A-A human... human fucker!
HEY HEY!
Ningen SUCKER!
Human sucker!
WHAT'S UP PEOPLE?!
Misa is going to announce our engagement at the New Year Show.
Although Mira likes Kira too, he'll soon be caught by Light.
You'll also definitely be... put to death.
Please send me a fan letter than only you and I could recognize.
In it, include five pages from the notebook.
Until I receive it, please continue with your judgments.
And after I send it to you?
Make a fake copy of the notebook and continue your judgments using it.
What's wrong, lady?
You are inviting me to do that by wearing such short skirts...
Someone...
Eliminate.
Mikami is getting off the train.
Vigilance
The man who was harassing a girl in the same car as Mikami just collapsed.
It happened a few seconds after Mikami wrote something in the note.
This probably means...
This settles it.
Yes.
In any case, we must first get close to Mikami.
But in order to do that, we must be wary of something.
That is... the existence of the Shinigami.
If the Shinigami finds out that we are trailing Mikami, we have to assume that it will warn him.
But only those who've touched the notebook can see the Shinigami.
It's difficult to avoid something that can't be seen.
Even if it's difficult, please do it.
Understood.
Today, Light-kun will meet with Takada in this room again.
Right after the secret meeting began, Takada received a phone call from Kira, and the hidden cameras had to be removed.
My first thought was that this would allow communication through written messages.
It's alright.
Other than the bug attached to me, there's nothing else in this room.
Ah, all that's left is the bathroom then.
Why is Light-kun so insistent on the cameras and bugs?
No... to begin with, why is Kira allowing this meeting?
Something doesn't make sense here.
If by any chance they are communicating through written messages... what can be done is...
Yagami-kun. I spoke privately with Amane-san yesterday.
About what?
This puts Light-kun in a pinch!
What are you so happy about, Matsuda?
Amane-san said she would announce your engagement at the New Year Show.
Pinch! Pinch! Big pinch!
Matsuda, shut up!
Ah no... It's just that I haven't been able to...
But to me there isn't anything special.
That Misa... doing such useless things... no, Takada is to blame as well.
Women are such unreasonable creatures.
Nothing special...? I wonder if that's true.
She was the one carrying out Kira's judgments before T.
She had obtained Kira's power from somewhere that I wasn't aware of, and because she knew I was Kira, it couldn't be avoided.
Had that not been the case, I wouldn't have chosen such an airheaded person like her.
Amane-san was carrying out Kira's judgment... but now I am... there was no choice with Amane-san, while I was chosen by Yagami-kun.
Takada-san, please believe me. Right now, there's only you.
"There's only you"? That doesn't sound like Yagami-kun at all. Such a common line.
Indeed, it doesn't sound like Light-kun. It's just a poor excuse.
That's because I didn't try hard enough to be your benefactor.
Then... between Amane and Takada, who is he really interested in?
I wonder how many women have heard you say that?
That would be... both of them.
Takada-san, do you really think I'm that kind of person?
Both of them!? How can anyone allow that kind of thing?
Hey! It's not me that's...
I'm sorry.
Shut up!
From now on I'll believe what you say, but if you're lying, the consequences will be heavy...
Because I'll tell Kira.
Kira?
I understand that Kira has become a necessity in this world,
but recently I've been thinking about whether the day that you and I can be together will ever come.
One way or another, I hate Kira for choosing Takada-san as his representative.
Although it's alright to kill evil people, we aren't bad people.
We should have the right to be happy.
In order for us to become happy, Kira must disappear.
Yes... if only Kira didn't exist.
It could be done if Kira were to be caught.
That's right.
For us to be happy... Kira must be caught.
Takada-san, are you serious?
Yes.
In order to do that, we'll need your cooperation. It'll also be dangerous.
It means that I'll be going against police policy, and you'll be going against Kira and the world.
Is it okay if it comes to that?
That was amazingly well put.
Fine.
If cooperating with you means that we can both be happy...
That's just like Light-kun... a complete turn-around!
To think that he was able to change his two-timing relationship with Misa-Misa into cooperation with Taki!
Mikami just muttered to himself!
Muttered to himself?
Yes. Because of the distance, I wasn't able to make out what he said, but I managed to get an image of his lips.
This is an image from the roof of the prosecutor's office where Mikami works, during his break.
This is the place. He seems to have said something.
Play it again in slow motion.
"Shi-ni-ga-mi?", isn't it?
He seems to have reacted to some scrap paper under his foot.
He just sighed...
From here, it looks like he's saying a bit more.
I'll zoom in on his lips.
Th-at-shi-ni-ga-mi-has-n't-a-pp-ea-red-sin-ce-he-ga-ve-me-the-no-te-book.
That Shinigami hasn't appeared since he gave me the notebook.
Mikami was given a notebook by a Shinigami, however, the Shinigami hasn't been with him since then.
I see.
Well then, Yagami-kun, will that be all for today?
Yeah.
It's finally over! Today was pretty busy.
It's pretty tough to do this for hours.
Couldn't tell by the smile on your face.
I'll be back after I check out of the hotel.
Thanks for your hard work!
Aizawa-san has it pretty tough, having to check in and out of the hotel.
It's gone! The nail mark that was supposed to be...
Two of the four notes have no nail marks.
The room is still as it was... room service hasn't been in here yet.
Why have the memos been changed to new ones?
They're communicating in writing!
Yes?
What? You want to see Near? And speak to him in person?
Mr. Aizawa, it's been a while.
And, I'm pleased to meet you.
Being blindfolded, I can't really say things like "pleased to meet you".
He didn't bring any weapons or cameras with him.
Then it won't matter if you take off your blindfold.
Near, I believe in you now.
L is meeting Takada every night.
I know that.
What about this then?
They have been communicating with notes.
There's no doubt.
Mr. Aizawa, please do not do needless things on your own.
Needless things?
Yes.
We're at the point now where we don't need further proof of Kira's identity.
To stop Kira, it is up to me to expose him, and let him suffer a total defeat.
Mr. Aizawa, I'll be honest with you.
You people are already out of the picture.
But, if you still want to capture Kira despite knowing that...
Then please, continue to watch him as you are now.
Just... keep watch?
Yes. However, there is reason to keep watching L, and that has been written into my scenario.
I hope you can help me this way, in order to defeat Kira.
And after that, please witness... the end of Kira.
This past year has been a dramatic one for me.
I'm the host for this year's New Year Show, Takada Kiyomi.
Please show your support.
Well, the New Year Show is finally going to begin.
Matsuda, come look at the situation with judgments and check the list of deaths.
That can wait until the performance of our Misa-Misa, the main act.
W-What the...?
We are the SPK.
We'd like you to come with us.
Now, there is something I must apologize to everyone for...
Our main act for this year, Amane Misa-san, has yet to arrive at the studio.
But...
What is going on?
There's been no word from Mogi either.
Hurry up and let me go back to NHN!
If you don't do that, Misa will be seen as someone who backs out at the last minute!
Misa-Misa, please stay calm and quiet.
What is with you, Mochii?
This is to capture Kira.
What has that got to do with Misa?
We considered using guns to get you to come with us as a last resort.
But you didn't resist at all... that really helped us, Mr. Mogi.
I would've resisted if Aizawa hadn't told me what happened.
Still...
After hearing about the memo pads... it really is...
What's going on?
Near.
What is it, L?
We lost track of Mogi and Amane Misa.
Yes, we've invited them over here.
What did he say?
Why is that?
This is just in case.
Near, abduction is a crime.
Please stop at once.
But Mr. Mogi and Amane accepted happily.
I will connect you to them now...
Mogi-san, Misa-san... this is L.
Light!
I heard that you both put yourselves in Near's custody willingly. Is this true?
Yes.
Mogi...
Misa was opposed to it! But Mochii said that it'd be better to keep quiet...
Otherwise, everyone will be killed.
I understand. Since both of you agreed, it's alright.
Amane Misa, highly suspected of being the second Kira, is now a captive.
Yagami Light, you should know the meaning of this move.
Quit messing around! You think you can get away with not bringing out Misa-Misa!?
That's right! Bring her out!
Lidner and the others seem to have carried it out smoothly.
It's past 9pm.
Okay, I'll make my move.
Mikami has a fixed routine and goes home at almost the exact same time every day.
And every Monday and Thursday, he will definitely be at this gym at about 2100 hours.
Yes. In the four years he's been a member, he's always maintained this routine.
He doesn't rest, even on New Year's Day.
I signed up too, and found that out.
Then he should be going this Monday the 31st too, right?
Yes... for a person who'd go even on New Year's Day, New Year's Eve will not be an exception.
Gevanni...
Is it possible for you to touch the notebook on the 31st in the gym?
Yes.
I can deal with the security in the hotel, and there are no surveillance cameras in the locker room either.
Then I'll be counting on you.
If there is indeed a Shinigami, there's a possibility that I will die, isn't there?
Yes. I am getting you to do this in order to confirm it.
And if you do not see a Shinigami after touching it, I will need to observe what happens to determine whether it is following him.
If you're too afraid, I'll get Lester to do it.
I understand. I'll do it.
If there is indeed a Shinigami around...
No, if that's the case, maybe I'm already...
At this point, I only have to touch it!
I've succeeded in touching the notebook!
At this time and place, I have not seen a Shinigami.
Commander Lester, please connect me to Mr. Mogi.
Mr. Mogi, according to the rules of the Death Note, how long can someone be manipulated before their death?
According to the data from the Yotsuba Incident, 23 days.
Are you sure?
Yes. The killings from the Yotsuba Incident were enough to prove it.
Thank you very much.
From now, there is a possibility that Gevanni is being controlled to say that a Shinigami is not around.
We'll arrange for a showdown with L after 24 days... and we'll carry it out if Gevanni is still alive then.
January 3rd
Takada-san, the New Year's Show must have been hard on you.
Yeah... to think Amane-san just disappeared like that.
Give T instructions to contact you once he has confirmed everything.
Once the message comes, give me a call or send me an email, saying "I want to see you as soon as possible".
January 6th
Photos?
Yes. I want to see exactly how it was written.
Whether there were any patterns as he wrote the names, and exactly what kind of notebook it is.
I would like to see all the details for myself.
How is it, Near?
Yes. Gevanni has done a fantastic job.
The handwriting matches that of Mikami's prosecution reports.
Without a doubt, this was written by Mikami.
Yeah.
If that's the case, it can be done.
To be continued
Towa ni utsu kono ichi peeji
This one page of everlasting depression;
hakanai senpou sono meni
a fleeting tactic in your eyes.
Aigan sezumo hou ni aku tsunagou rou he
Let's intertwine evil with law, pass no plea and go to jail.
Nooto ni moudoku bonnou ni osore idaku
Deadly poison within the Note harbors fears of carnal desires.
Oouso no mousou ni yodare ga taema naku
Incessant drool at false fantasies;
sabaki hanzai toukatsu to hozaku
judgment; never-ending talk of uniting crime.
Dare ga dakaisaku nodo wakaru?
Who would know of a path to salvation?
Menzai no waarudo
World of acquittal,
seisai no waado
words of retribution!
Eru netsu masani "desu paireetsu"
This fire I feel, I truly am a Death pirate!
Aganau houritsu geemu
Redeem the game of law!
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
Zetsubou za birii
Despair the Billy,
iza rinri
here are the morals!
Saa tomerarenai eraser rain
Come, relentless eraser rain.
tomerarenai eraser rain
relentless eraser rain.
Preview
The Guard Team was attacked!
Takada-san, are you alright?
Is it Near again?
No... the way it was carried out, rather than Near, it could be...
Mello?
Next Time
Murder Intent