Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Gaze
This is... the footage from CCTV cameras that happened to capture the FBI agents who died in Japan on film.
Show me the following scenes involving Ray Penber one more time: him at the ticket barrier, boarding the train, and his death scene, please.
Okay...
Err...
It's just under there.
Oh, you mean these?
Let's see... Ray Penber arrived at Shinjuku station via the west entrance at 15:11. At 15:13, he boards the Yamanote line.
Even if he was following someone, it's difficult to tell due to the fuzzy images.
And then at 16:42... huh? Ah, thank you!
Err.. and then at 16:42, he died on the platform at Tokyo station.
Just as I thought; it's odd.
Huh?
What's odd, L?
Have you figured something out?!
Judging from this footage, from the time he boarded and the time he died, Ray Penber was on the train for an hour and a half. The Yamanote line only takes an hour.
The important thing to note here is the envelope.
Envelope?
Both by the ticket barrier and on the platform, he seems to be carrying an envelope or something similar.
Oh, y-you're right!
He does, he does!
But in the moments preceding his death... it vanished.
Great job on noticing that, Ryuuzaki!
There's nothing that fits that description in the lost property lists.
In that case, it must have been inside the train.
And in this final video of Penber... it looks to me as if he's frantically trying to see inside the train.
Is it possible that it's a hint?
If that was Kira, don't you think it'd be interesting?
I-It can't be?!
I doubt it too.
If Kira is able to manipulate deaths from a distance, they wouldn't bother coming to the scene.
But if that's what we're supposed to believe, they may have done something extremely daring here.
You okay, Light?
You've been continuously writing criminals' names into the Death Note for four days now, and you've barely slept.
Why'd ya need to schedule deaths up to four weeks in advance?
Basically, if I ever end up in a hospital or something, people won't be able to say, "the instant Police Chief Yagami's son was hospitalized, the killings stopped".
Oh, right. I got ya.
More importantly, are you certain that it's fine to write these on a date before the actual date of death?
Shinigami don't use it in such a way, so I can't say for certain; but logically, writing it before the date of death should be fine.
You're so unreliable.
That's right!
Yes... yes... please hold.
Ryuuzaki, it's Ukita-san at the Police Headquarters.
He says he's received an interesting call from a member of the public.
In that case, pass them the number to phone five, and tell them to call that instead.
Matsuda-san, you can turn on your cell phone... no... I meant please switch it on now.
Okay.
Hello, head of Kira Incident Public Information Hot-line, Suzuki speaking.
Ray Penber's fiancée?
Misora Naomi... where have I heard that name before...
It's her... from the Los Angeles BB serial killer case.
I see... the girl who worked for me on that case... in Japan...
She disappeared a few days after her fiancé died.
Anyone would be depressed if their fiancé just died.
She wouldn't have... committed suicide?!
No. The Misora Naomi that I knew was strong of heart and a brilliant FBI investigator.
If anything, she would have been trying to catch Kira.
Apparently she was with Penber.
She might have discovered something...
So, does this mean that Kira beat me to it?
Everyone. From now on, we'll only be investigating those who were under surveillance by Ray Penber.
The subjects of our investigation will be two police officers and their immediate family.
Who are the two police officers?
Deputy Kitamura and his family, and.. Chief Yagami and his family.
I'd also like to be able to set up cameras and bugging devices in both households.
I've got to ensure that if anyone ever checks this PC it won't give me away.
Now, all that's left is to hide a piece of the Death Note somewhere...
You know, you've got some pretty skilled hands there.
I bet that makes you popular with the ladies, Light.
It's got nothing to do with having skilled hands.
It's more about looks rather than skill.
Why, Ryuk? Don't the girls go for you?
Surveillance cameras! Ryuuzaki?!
That's out of the question.
If it gets out, it'll become a civil liberties issue; we'll all be fired!
I thought that we would put our lives on the line here, not just our jobs.
Ryuuzaki, what's the probability of Kira being among them?
10%... No, 5%.
You're going to do all that based on just a 5% probability?
Up until now, we haven't encountered anyone even remotely suspicious.
Even if there is just a 1% probability, it's worth investigating it thoroughly.
Chief!
I regret that my own family falls under suspicion.
Very well, please set it up.
In exchange, I'd like the whole house covered; from the bathroom to the toilet. I don't want to find a single place overlooked!
Thank you. I intend to.
Chief! What are you saying?!
He's right! You've got a wife and daughter!
I realize that! I know what I'm saying.
However, if we don't do this thoroughly, then there's no point in doing it at all!
Just shut it!
Sorry...
No, it's fine.
I'm sorry.
Well, the least I can do is to have only Yagami-san and myself carry out the surveillance of his family.
Watari, how long will it take to set up surveillance cameras and monitors?
Once we know the times during which each of the houses will be vacant, we can set them up any time from tomorrow onwards.
See ya, Light.
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
Huh? Nobody is home?
I'm home.
Hey, Light, doesn't seem like anyone is home; it's been a while, so how about we play some video games?
Hey, Light... let's play some games.
You listening?
Light?
I-I had no idea... that he was doing something like that!
Has he got something in his room that he doesn't want anyone to see?
If you take into account that he's seventeen, it's nothing to be that suspicious about.
I've done that myself in the past for no particular reason.
Have you spoken to him about the investigation?
Don't be stupid!
I would never discuss un-released, top-secret information!
Besides, I'm hardly ever at home, and when I am, I'm usually tired, so I go straight to bed.
I see...
Where you going, Light?
Hey, Light! Why are you ignoring me? I'm starting to feel a little pissed here...
Hey, Light.
It doesn't appear to be any bugs in these clothes.
Light-ooo!
Ryuk, it's possible that surveillance cameras or bugs no, probably both... have been set up in my house.
Huh? But that piece of paper in your door was still there...
That bit of paper is merely a decoy to fool people into thinking that that's how I tell if someone has been in my room.
In reality, the first clue is the door knob.
The door knob?
When that door closes, the handle naturally returns to a horizontal state.
It's impossible for it to go any higher.
However, when I close the door, I always purposely lower the handle 5mm from it's highest point.
Thus, when I go to open the door, if the door knob is all the way up, there's the possibility that someone has been in my room.
But I can't determine that for sure with just that piece of information.
That's why I've set up a piece of mechanical pencil lead as well.
Piece of mechanical pencil lead?
It's by the hinge.
I've placed it on the top of the hinge at such an angle that it'll break if the door is opened.
The lead will definitely break if the door has been opened.
Normally, I remove it myself before I enter the room, but today it was already broken.
Oh, that? I remember you setting that up.
The door knob and the piece of lead... Without a doubt, someone has definitely been in there.
It could have been your parents?
If it was my parents, or even my sister, they wouldn't have noticed that piece of paper.
It's suspicious because the piece of paper was replaced.
Welcome!
You buying books so that you can swat up on wiretapping and surveillance?
Now that I think about it, Ryuk, what's going to happen with your apples?
Apples?
Ah! If you saw it through a surveillance camera, it wouldn't be visible once I'd eaten it, but until then, it would look as though it was floating in mid-air!
Just as I thought.
Shinigami can't die, so you aren't going to starve to death.
There won't be any problems with not giving them to you, right?
W-Wait a second, Light.
For me, apples are like... Let's see... it's like alcohol and tobacco are for some humans.
If I go without them for a long time, I'll get withdrawal symptoms.
What kind of symptoms?
My body will start contorting randomly, or I'll start doing handstands...
I'd rather not see that.
Right?!
Listen up, Ryuk. I've already given L the hint that "Shinigami only eat apples."
When did you--?
If you really want to eat apples, you'll first need to memorize the positions of all the cameras.
There may be an angle from which you can safely eat your apples.
Okay, let's go, Ryuk!
Okay, here goes the camera search!
This could be fun too!
Wait... I was supposed to be searching for cameras...
I can't believe that my son, who's so serious, would go and look at those sorts of magazines.
That's normal for a 17-year-old.
But to me, it seems as though he's using it as some kind of excuse, i.e. "I check to see if anyone has been in my room because I read dirty magazines".
Ryuuzaki, don't tell me, you actually suspect my son?!
Oh, I definitely suspect him, alright.
That's the reason I set up cameras and wires in you and the deputy's houses.
I've found a camera within the air conditioner!
So, I was right; there are cameras.
That means they must have wired the place as well.
Even if it's for the sake of the Kira investigation, I doubt that the Japanese police would go this far.
Is it possible that L instigated this?
If so, how many people have they narrowed it down to?
If they haven't narrowed it down to just the people that were being investigated by Ray Penber, it's doubtful that they would take these measures so far.
Argh, I've been tricked by the cover again.
No! In these circumstances, it's best that I imagine that I'm the only one under surveillance and act accordingly.
It's okay. I've even prepared magazines such as this especially for such an occasion.
Light...
Onii-chan, it's dinner time!
I... love you.
Wow! You're so cool, Ryuuga Hideki!
There's definitely no one this cool in my class!
Sayu! Eat your dinner!
Later.
Aizawa-san, are the Kitamura family watching TV right now?
Yes. Except for the deputy, they're all watching while eating dinner.
They're watching channel four.
Watari, quickly contact the TV station, and ask them to broadcast that tape.
Understood.
That's right, I've...
NKK News Flash
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case.
Huh? What's this?
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case?
The ICPO have decided to send 1,500 investigators from the most developed nations into Japan to assist with the Kira case.
1,500 people! Wow.
There should be cameras in here too.
It doesn't matter whether that piece of news is real or not, all they want to do is to see what my reaction is.
L, you're using the same trick that you used at the beginning.
That's really stupid of the ICPO.
Huh?!
There's no point in making an announcement like that.
If they are going to send in investigators, they should do it quietly.
Even the FBI, who were investigating in the utmost secrecy were killed.
This is just going to be a repeat of what's already happened.
So this is probably a plan by the police to unnerve Kira by broadcasting it in such an exaggerated manner.
But I think it'd be fairly obvious to Kira.
Your son is very clever.
Yes... well...
Thanks for the meal.
Onii-chan! You're eating potato chips after dinner?!
Your cool style will go to waste if you get fat!
It's a late night snack to aid me with my studies.
L-Light... I've found all the cameras.
Even Shinigami get tired if they work so hard.
I'll explain it now.
It's rather complicated, so make sure you get it all.
I don't want to explain it again.
Okay, time to study hard!
There's a hell of a lot of cameras.
I can only imagine that whoever placed them here was prepared to be caught if necessary.
There's 64 in total.
Just as I thought, this is L's work.
Just like the time he blithely allowed a condemned criminal to call me out the first time; I can see that he knows no limits.
In such circumstances, where can I eat my apples?
It's impossible of course, Ryuk.
I forgot... we can't talk inside the house.
Let me know tomorrow when we get outside.
Okay. This problem is correct.
Judging by the positions and number of cameras present, it looks as though they want to get this over with within a few days.
A normal person may slip up within this period, but it won't be that easy, L.
This is as far as it goes!
I've already scheduled deaths up to three and a half week in advance in the Death Note, but L already knows that Kira can manipulate the time of death.
In that case, criminals will need to continue to die while he can see that I'm not watching any new broadcasts containing their information.
Oh, crap! The withdrawal symptoms are starting to kick in...
I'll show you, L!
Thanks to Ryuk's information, and the preparations I made earlier, I can convince everyone that I'm nothing but a hard-working exam student,
Thanks to Ryuk's information, and the preparations I made earlier, I can convince everyone that I'm nothing but a hard-working exam student.
And at the same time, while information on the criminals is still being broadcast, I can use the Death Note... to kill them!
Using my right hand to continue solving problems, I can use my left hand to write names... and to take out chips to eat.
After dinner, without switching on the TV or the PC, your son studies continuously.
It's less than ten days to the exams.
And now a criminal, whom I could never have known about, will die of a heart attack in forty seconds.
L himself will be the witness to my alibi.
Right, just a little more!
Ryuuzaki.
What's up, Watari?
Two criminals just reported on tonight's nine o'clock news... a bank employee under investigation for embezzlement, and a bag-snatching thief being held in police custody... both died earlier from heart attacks.
It's Kira!
At that time, your wife and daughter were watching a soap opera.
When that finished, they switched off the TV and haven't watched it since.
Your son has been studying from 19:30 till now.
Kira needs a name and a face in order to kill.
"Anybody who wasn't watching that news broadcast can't be Kira?"
That must mean my family is innocent!
Today, Kira seems to have gone for extremely minor criminals immediately after their information was released.
And the Yagami household seems entirely too innocent on the first day of surveillance...
Light! Are you up yet?!
Yeah, I'm up!
Today is garbage collection day, so if you have any, bring it down.
What a bother...
What are you on about?
You're always telling me that you don't need to be told.
Yes, yes...
The weather looks good again.
You really don't care what you have to do to get this job done, do ya?
Either that, or you're extremely generous...
That small TV cost you 39,800 yen, didn't it?
39,800 yen is about 350 US dollars
Good morning!
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
Heisei 19 Tokyo University Admission Ceremony
This is good.
This is nothing to lose heart about.
This is proof that they haven't figured anything out.
This is now a direct competition of bluffing and knowledge.
Next Time
Contact