Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Decisions
I relinquish all ownership of this notebook.
I'm counting on you... take care of Misa.
Stalker-san?
Hey, Stalker-san? Where are you?
Why don't you stop playing games now?
Stalker? What's she talking about?
She's suddenly undergone a complete change in attitude...
Just as I thought, as long as I have Ryuk's Death Note, even if I discard Rem's Death Note, I won't forget about Rem.
But still, Rem... it's thanks to you bringing another Death Note into the human world that I've ended up in this...
You really sure about this, Light?
Yeah.
You know, I never guessed the notebook I gave you would end up discarded in the ground somewhere.
Listen Ryuk... for the moment, I've only hidden it in the ground.
I will discard it... the very next time the word "discard" escapes my mouth.
Regardless of the context in which I say it, when I say that word, I'll mean it in relation to discarding the notebook.
Got it.
Stalker-san? This is a felony, you know, please stop...
Stalker-san? Hey?
She's been like this ever since she passed out...
Jeez, she really thinks she can feign innocence, doesn't she?
Ah, I know!
For now, why don't you just take off my blindfold?
Stalker-san, I really want to see your face.
Matsuda-san, call Mogi-san.
Here.
Mogi-san, when you arrested Amane Misa, you said it was on suspicion of being the second Kira, didn't you?
Yes, exactly as you said.
We covered up her eyes and mouth from behind, and said clearly, so she could hear, "we're arresting you on suspicion of being the second Kira".
She didn't attempt to resist the handcuffs or the blindfold. She seemed pretty resigned.
I'll give you my autograph and shake your hand.
Oh, I know! I'll kiss you on the cheek!
Hey, Misa won't run away!
We've been discussing the second Kira for a while already... why has she started talking about a stalker now?
Amane Misa.
Stalker-san, what do you want?
Have you finally decided to release me?
Before you fell asleep, you were denying everything, and even went as far as saying "kill me", yet, now we have a senseless struggle like this?
What are you talking about?
Stalker-san, you were the one who knocked out and brought Misa here.
What? You want to do an "Investigation of Amane Misa" or something?
Do you know why you're tied up like that?
Why? It's because Misa's an idol, right?
But you know, Stalker-san, you're the first to have gone this far for me...
Damn it, Amane!
Stop messing around!
I-I'm scared... what's going on?!
I don't want this!
Let me go! Let me go!
Umm... that's right. I have to go to the bathroom again.
Bathroom! I want to go!
You went to the bathroom only four minutes ago.
Please try to hold it.
What?! If I didn't say, I'd have to go here!
You'll get to see Misa wet herself again, won't that be fun?!
You pervert!
I'm... a pervert?
Amane, let's be serious and continue our discussion from before you fell asleep.
Do you know Yagami Light?
How did you get to know him?
Why wouldn't I know my own boyfriend?!
Before, she didn't confess a thing, yet now she's openly calling him her boyfriend?
What's going on?
It's Light-kun.
Turn off the video and audio.
Understood.
Yes?
Yes, I understand.
I'm in room 2801 at the K.
K is the abbreviated name of the hotel.
My son is coming here?
Ryuuzaki, it's as I said on the phone...
I... might be Kira.
D-Don't be stupid! What are you saying?! Light?!
What's happened?! Huh?!
I have no proof that Yagami Light is Kira.
Yet, you're saying "I might be Kira"... it's an act.
It's not that you "might be" Kira, you are Kira.
What on earth are you trying to do?
Father, if Ryuuzaki is L, it's not an exaggeration to say that he's the best detective in the world.
That same L is labeling me as Kira. I have to be Kira.
W-What are you saying?! Light?!
The person who the FBI investigator Ray Penber was investigating from the time he came to Japan until he died...
The person who was in Aoyama on the 22nd of May...
The person who Amane Misa, the suspected second Kira, immediately made advances on after coming here from Kanto...
they're all me.
If I were in L's shoes, I'd deduce that I was Kira.
This means that subconsciously, I might have become Kira.
Light...
I see... subconsciously, huh?
I don't even understand myself anymore.
Even though I'm not conscious of it, I could be killing people while I sleep or something!
That you haven't.
What do you mean, Ryuuzaki?!
To be honest, there was a period of five days where we set up surveillance cameras in your room.
Cameras?
Yes.
You slept normally at night.
Having seen that criminals continued to die, despite you having no access to information about them,
I concluded not that you were innocent; merely that, if you were Kira, you would not give yourself away on camera.
"If you were Kira, you wouldn't give yourself away", huh?
That could be true.
If I'm honest, I've sometimes thought that some criminals would be better off dead.
I think anyone who thinks this way could become Kira.
Light-kun! I'm exactly the same.
I often find myself thinking that certain people would be better off dead, but that doesn't mean we would really go and kill them, right?
Besides, criminals that you had no knowledge of continued to die.
The surveillance cameras proved this!
N-No... at the time, we didn't have enough manpower, and only watched his movements inside of the house.
It's not like we watched him 24/7 over those five days, so he may have had a way of killing people when he was out of the house.
Did you predict that things would turn out this way, Yagami Light?
But, if we detain him like Amane, and criminals continue to die... that would make Yagami Light not Kira, right?
Is that your plan?
Somehow I don't like the way this conversation is heading, but...
Fine.
We'll restrain Yagami Light, and imprison him long term.
W-What?!
Light-kun... imprisoned?
If we're going to do this, we'll start now, by making sure he never goes anywhere I can't see him.
T-This is stupid! There's no way my son could be Kira!
My son would never--!
It's okay, father.
Light?!
I can't continue chasing Kira, when deep down, I don't even know whether I'm Kira or not.
In return, until you have absolutely no doubt about whether I'm innocent or Kira, no matter what happens or what I say, don't let me out.
I understand.
Yagami-san, can you come up with an excuse for Light-kun's absence for your family?
I mean... please do so.
A-All of a sudden, you can't expect me to--!
In the first place, I can't understand why my son has to be imprisoned!
You're being stubborn, father.
This is the only method by which I'll be able to convince myself.
Are you serious, Light?
Yes.
By sealing away my freedom, I'm going to win against the fear that Kira lurks inside me!
Aizawa-san, I'm counting on you.
Okay.
Imprisonment: Day One
Now all that remains is to discard the notebook.
I'm gonna be stuck with no apples to eat again?
Ryuuzaki, I want you to remove me from the investigation.
Chief!
The one currently imprisoned under suspicion of being Kira is my own son.
I have no right to be here.
Even when we were discussing his imprisonment, I tried to prevent it due to my own personal feelings.
That's right.
You shouldn't let your personal feelings get involved.
I-If it turns out that my son is Kira, I don't know what I'd do.
Yes... it's not unimaginable that you may think to kill your son and then yourself.
I agree, it's better that you aren't here.
Ryuuzaki, I'd like you to imprison me as well.
Right now, I'm calm.
But I have no idea what I might do, due to feelings for my son.
I thought that you might say something like this, so I've asked Watari to make the necessary arrangements.
But, though you will be imprisoned, you will have your cell phone turned on, now and again as usual, and will continue to communicate with your family and the outside world.
Light-kun won't be informed of this, and if he talks to you, we need him to think that you're still part of this investigation.
Even while you are imprisoned, you will be kept up to date with the investigation at all times.
Is that fine with you?
I owe you one, Ryuuzaki.
Imprisonment: Day Three
Stalker-san, I want to take a bath.
I'm guessing you know where I live anyway... fetch me a change of clothes...
Things are getting super crazy around here again...
I just feel really bad for the Chief.
Ryuuzaki, how is it going?
Were there any reports of new criminals that were likely to be targeted by Kira yesterday or the day before?
And if they were reported, have they been killed by Kira?
There have been reports of some likely criminals, but ever since you were imprisoned, not a single criminal has been killed.
They've stopped being killed?
Really?
Yes.
I see... looks like they're finally going to decide that I'm Kira.
I really want to eat an apple...
What's going on?
I thought that even if I imprisoned Yagami Light, the killings would continue.
Yet, they've completely stopped.
It looked as though he was voluntarily offering to imprison himself, but the way this is going, he'll end up as Kira.
Now the question remains, whether or not he was conscious of being Kira.
Even if he is Kira, does he think that pretending to be unaware of it will make it alright?
This isn't like Yagami Light... no, it isn't like Kira.
Imprisonment: Day Five
It's no good, Light.
If I don't eat an apple soon--!
In any case, the only thing to do is to be patient... even if there's nothing to do.
Stalker-san... you won't be able to sell a video of me just sitting down.
Yagami-san seems to be in a much worse condition than Light-kun or Amane.
Well, of course!
During the five days Light-kun has been imprisoned, not a single reported criminal has died.
In this kind of situation, it's harder on the parent than the suspect.
As a result, this has pretty much decided that Light-kun is Kira.
Yagami-san...
What is it?!
Is it good or bad news?!
...umm, no. I think it would be better if you don't think too much about this.
No matter what you're thinking as you sit there, it won't affect the end results.
Why don't you rest in a more relaxing environment?
Don't be ridiculous!
There is no such thing as a relaxing environment in my current circumstances!
This is the most relaxing place for me now.
No matter what the result is, when I leave here, it will be with my son!
I understand.
Imprisonment: Day Seven
Light-kun, it's only been a week, but you look exhausted.
Are you okay?
It's probably about time... now that I've gotten this far...
Yeah.
Even I can't say that I look too good at the moment... but such meaningless pride... I'll discard it!
Alright.
Gotcha!
See ya.
Huh? Why am I doing this?
Ryuuzaki!
I know I chose to be imprisoned and go through with this, but I've just realized, there's no point in this!
Because I am not Kira.
Hurry up and let me out of here!
I can't do that.
Until I'm sure whether you're Kira or not, no matter what you say, I won't release you. That was the promise.
There was something wrong with me that time!
Do you actually believe that it's possible to do what Kira does and not be aware of it?!
I am not conscious of being Kira, therefore I am not Kira!
I also believe that Kira cannot be unaware of who they are, but if you are Kira, then it all adds up.
As soon as we imprisoned you, the killings stopped.
Listen carefully, Ryuuzaki, there's no way I'm lying.
I'm not Kira!
I can only imagine that I've been set up!
What's going on, Yagami Light?
What you're saying is all over the place... but why do I sense I'm getting close to the root of the problem?
Hurry up and let me out!
This is a waste of time!
No. I can't let you out.
Damn it! How did it turn out like this...
What's going on? This isn't like Light-kun.
He's contradicting himself and isn't being logical at all.
Now that the murdering of criminals has stopped, there's no way we can release him.
Even I have realized that much.
Well, no matter what anyone says, at this rate, Yagami Light will be confirmed as Kira. We can close the case, and everyone will be happy.
Imprisonment: Day Fifteen
What's going on?!
Two weeks' worth of criminals were taken out in one shot yesterday!
Yeah... Kira is back.
Kira Returns
Have you told the Chief?
No, not yet.
Chief! Kira is on the move!
What?!
Kira was just resting.
The judgment of criminals has begun again!
I-Is this true, Matsuda?!
S-So my son... I can't say I'm happy that the killings have started again, but this means that the suspicions surrounding my son...
no, I know Ryuuzaki won't say he's completely "white"...
Let's go with "grey" then.
Hear that Chief?!
Yeah.
So, he was mainly "black" before...
Thank goodness.
I'm sure that it's a "grey" that's nearly indistinguishable from "white".
Next, we should tell Light-kun--
Matsuda!!
I mean, Matsuda-san, please stop.
"Matsuda"?
Please don't tell Light-kun.
W-Why?
Light-kun...
What is it, Ryuuzaki?
No criminals have been judged for over the past two weeks now.
Why don't you just admit that you are Kira?
You're being stupid, Ryuuzaki.
You're wrong.
I'm not surprised that you think I'm Kira from the way the investigation has been going, but this is a trap!
I'm not Kira!
Use the zoom or whatever to look closely at my eyes!
Are these the eyes of someone who's lying?!
Amane, are you sure you don't know who Kira is?
This, again?
Misa would like to know that herself.
Kira is a superhero that killed the criminal who murdered Misa's parents.
I have no idea what's going on...
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
N-No way!
Wait, father!
If we die now, we'll never know the truth!
Are you going to believe L over me?
Father!
Next Time
Execution