Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
I won't let anyone get in my way
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai. Yume, visou ni kaeru
The recent past tells me of the future. My ideals become my dreams.
Daremo ga nozonda owari wo...
The ending that everyone desires.
Hirogaru yami no naka kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
In the shadows that keep expanding, we exchange revolutionary vows.
Dareni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
I won't let anyone get in my way
Itsuka boku ga misete ageru hikari no kagayaku sekai wo
Someday I'll show you a world that shines in the light.
Open Seams
I'm L.
This guy is L?
That's not quite the image I had of him...
The name's Yagami, I'm with the police force.
I'm Matsuda.
I'm Aizawa.
I'm Mogi.
I'm Ukita.
Sorry we're late.
Currently, the five of us..
Bang!
What the hell are you playing at?
If I was Kira, you'd be dead by now, Yagami Souichirou-san.
In order to kill, Kira needs a face and a name.
All of you should know this by now.
Try not to carelessly reveal your names.
Let's try to value our lives.
I've heard that the face is essential, but I've heard nothing about Kira needing to know the victim's name as well...
All the high profile criminals whose real names are unknown or were reported wrongly have escaped Kira's wrath.
It's an issue that's also been discussed at Investigative Headquarters.
Standing around there chatting is all very well, but please come this way.
Umm.. okay...
I must ask you to switch off all cell phones, laptops and other transmission devices and leave them on the table there.
L! Are you trying to suggest that we'd use our cell phones to let people listen in on this?!
Let's just forget about that now and do as he asks.
We've known from the start the he's the cautious type, but it's hard to tell if he really trusts us or not.
No... it's just that I can't stand people's phones going off while I'm trying to talk.
I'd better tell you this now.. I don't want anyone making notes for anyone of what's being discussed here.
Please, sit down.
Err... L?
Please, from now on, call me "Ryuuzaki" instead of "L", just to be on the safe side.
In that case.. uh, Ryuuzaki...
If you already know that Kira needs both a name and face, why don't we just withhold criminal information from the media?
Surely that will reduce the number of victims?
If we did that, members of the public would end up being killed.
Members of the public?
Why?
Kira is immature, and is a bad loser.
Immature?
Bad loser?
Yes.
I know, because I'm also immature and hate to lose.
Ryuuzaki, could you explain that better for us?
When I used that TV broadcast to challenge Kira, despite the fact that Kira had only killed criminals up until then, they killed the fake version of me without any hesitation.
And when I disclosed the fact that I knew they were from the Kanto region of Japan, they immediately began to kill mainly Japanese criminals as if to say, "So what?".
Instead of backing down from my provocations, they have been aggressively returning them.
If you try to withhold information from someone who acts like this, what do you think will happen?
Well, that's..
If there are no proper criminals to kill, they'll go after the petty ones, if there there aren't any of them, they'll be targeting the innocent.
Everyone on this planet is being held hostage.
"I'm not the one who's in the wrong here. Those who try to hide the criminals from me are the ones who are in the wrong."
That is how Kira thinks.
If anything, we should really be thinking of ways of using the media to our own advantage.
For example?
Well, how about this?
"The Americans are angered by the murders of their FBI agents. The entire world turns against Kira. Approximately 1,500 investigators from powerful nations enter Japan."
Kira will have a lot more than the FBI to deal with this time.
They'll begin to perceive absolutely everyone to be their enemy.
Feeling trapped, Kira will give us some kind of reaction.
I-Interesting...
They'll think that there are 1,500 people after them, even though in reality there's only seven!
And since the investigators don't exist, they can't kill them!
This could really work!
In that case, let me tell you some of my thoughts regarding this case.
Kira is a loner.
Somehow, they were accessing information from the previous headquarters.
How can you tell that they're a loner?
Hang on a minute Aizawa. Let's listen to all of Ryuuzaki's reasonings first.
In order to kill, they require both a name and a face.
They can also manipulate the time of death, and to some extent, the victim's movements prior to death.
Having absorbed what I just said, please listen closely to the following.
On the 14th December, twelve FBI agents entered Japan.
On the 19th December, Kira is evidently using prisoners as test subjects in order to study how they could manipulate the victim's movements before death.
To put it simply, during these five days, Kira became aware of the FBI's presence in Japan, and felt threatened by them.
From this we can deduce that to kill the FBI agents whose names and faces they didn't know, Kira found it necessary to experiment to see how far they could manipulate someone's death.
And then on the 27th December... was able to put files containing the names and faces of everyone involved into the hands of every agent on the team, and succeeded in killing them all.
As a result, it's almost impossible to tell whose files I looked at in order to kill the agents.
But.. the fact that I encountered Ray Penber must never be discovered by anyone.
Huh? Not using the Death Note today?
This is for those "exams"?
It's too late to still be trying to study for them.
Then what?
The period from the 19th to the 27th December... is when I've been most active.
During this time, as far as we can tell, 23 people have died of a heart attack.
These 23 people were all either suspected criminals or previous offenders, either guilty of lesser crimes or only suspected of wrongdoing.
This is clearly different from Kira's previous targets.
That's true.
This suggests that for Kira to kill the FBI agents, it was necessary to manipulate these people.
They killed 23 people to make it harder for us to identify who was actually killed as part of the plan.
In reality, it's likely that Kira only used a few of them.
The fact that there were eight days between the tests being performed, and Kira acting,
indicates that they allowed the agents to investigate as many people as possible to draw suspicion away from themselves.
Consequently, Kira must be someone that was under investigation by the FBI between the 14th and the 19th.
I've compiled data from the FBI and other necessary information together, although, I'm afraid that I won't let you take them away from here--
Amazing!
This is amazing!
If we know this much, we should be able to make progress, even if it's just the seven of us!
We've got to check up on the past movements of the FBI and the heart attack victims.
We should split into two groups.
There aren't a lot of people who had access to police information and were investigated during that period.
So, any questions?
Then, Ryuuzaki, let me ask you one thing. You said that like Kira, you hate to lose.
Doesn't the fact that you've had to show us your face mean that you've lost to Kira?
That's right.
That I've had to show my face and allowed twelve FBI agents to die, are my losses.
But I will win in the end.
This is the first time that I've had to lay down my life in a contest.
As people willing to place our lives on the line, let's show Kira... that justice will always prevail.
Y-Yes, that's right!
Justice will triumph!
Let's try our best!
Alright! Let's do this, Ryuuzaki!
When I first saw him, I wondered whether he was the real thing, but now I'm sure that he's the real L.
First, I'd like to determine that Kira is not amongst us by having a one-on-one discussion with each of you.
He still doesn't trust us...
It's a reasonable request.
If Kira really is getting information from the police, there's a high possibility that he could be here.
Of course! If they stayed on the case, they'd get to see Ryuuzaki's face, wouldn't they...
This is what it means to put your life on the line...
So far so good...
Just one more... if only there was one more conclusive fact..
If there was a hole in my plan... if a single fact gets out... it could cost me my life.
Just one thing...
You finished studying then?
I guess..
It's okay, there were no holes in my plan.
The riskiest incident was the bus hi-jacking.
But there's no way that they'll be able to connect that to Kira, since L and the police believe that Kira can only kill via heart attacks.
On the other hand, if that fact was found out, it would become a massive hole in my plans...
What? Now?
Dad's working all night without a change of clothes, so we should take some over.
But I promised to go to the New Year's festival with my friend!
I'll go.
It'll be nice to have a change of scene.
Lucky! Thank you, onii-chan!
I guess this means that you get to go spy on Police Headquarters.
Even if I go, I'll only get as far as the reception desk.
You're taking a page with you?
You're going to kill someone in the open?
I've made a habit of doing this every time I go out... just in case...
That day... I remember Ray saying he was going to Shinjuku.
On that same day, four relatively innocent people died of heart attacks around Shinjuku station...
...and that bus hi-jack!
It can't be just a coincidence.
Kira...
can kill people by means other than just a heart attack.
The number you have dialled is unavailable..
That's not like dad...
I wonder if there's an important meeting going on or something?
I'm begging you, please let me speak to the Investigative Headquarters in person.
Like we keep saying, there's no one there at the moment.
No one at headquarters?
His cell phone redirects to the answering machine too. What's going on?
Is there a way in which I can contact them?
This is extremely important; it's about the Kira investigation.
The Kira investigation!
Well, I'll try ringing headquarters again...
I'm Chief Yagami Souichirou's son, Light.
I've brought him a change of clothes, but seeing that he doesn't seem to be around, could you look after them for me?
Ah, Light-kun, good to see you again.
Err.. I'm sorry I...
I was also here that time your advice helped us in solving that insurance money killing case, last year.
Ah, is that it? Sorry about that.
Should I write my name here?
Have you been trying to rationalize the Kira investigation too, Light-kun?
Yes. If all goes well, I'll solve it before L does.
Solve it before L?
I'm sorry, but it really does seem like there's nobody at headquarters.
Please, try to believe me.
I'll pass on your message.
That's no good. I've got to speak to them directly!
Excuse me. My father's the Chief Investigator for the Kira investigation.
If you like, I could try to get a hold of him.
I won't be able to do that immediately though, his cell phone is switched off.
After the deaths of the FBI agents, a lot of people have been resigning within headquarters because they fear Kira.
I can imagine it being a very hectic time for them.
Light-kun, you shouldn't tell members of the public things like that.
People are already gossiping about this.
Besides, this person can be trusted.
I can see it in her eyes. She's an intelligent and prudent person.
Because of what happened to the FBI, you've realized that there's a problem within the police force, and that's why you wish to speak directly to headquarters.
Right?
I figure that my father will eventually pick up his voice-mail and call me back.
If you don't mind waiting, you can speak to him directly then.
Are you sure that's okay?
Yes. Of course, I can't give you my father's number, but you're welcome to use my cell phone to talk to him.
Anyway, it won't mean much until you decide to trust me or my father.
What's with the sudden cheerful demeanor?
Thank you.
Looks like you've fooled her, Light!
You've certainly got a lot of courage to try and get involved with the Kira investigation.
Not really.
According to your thinking, Kira... um, could I at least ask you for your name?
It's written as "god of the night" (夜神), and then the character for "moon" (月), except you read it as "light".
Unusual, huh?
I'm Maki Shoko.
Spelt with the characters "interval" (間) and "tree" (木), and then "illuminate" (照) and "child" (子).
So, it's Maki-san, right?
Maki-san, according to my theory, Kira can manipulate people before killing them.
Me too!
I've been thinking the exact same thing!
"Kira can manipulate people before killing them", but that's not all. If I'm right... Kira can kill people using methods other than heart attacks.
Who is this woman?!
I don't think anyone else has realized yet, but if we assume this to be true... I think Kira knows they'll be caught.
I haven't thought that far ahead yet, but if that's true, the murders that Kira really wants to hide... will be by methods other than heart attacks?
Yes, and I think someone I know met Kira.
Kira?!
I'm sorry.. it's true that if you told the police that, they'd never believe you.
Yes, that's why I wanted to speak to someone in the investigation directly, and explain that I've got a reasonable case.
But, in that case, wouldn't it be better if the person who met Kira talked to the police?
That person is no longer with us...
He was one of the FBI agents who came to Japan.
An FBI investigator... who met Kira?!
Surely not?!
He was also my fiancé.
He said that he was randomly caught up in a bus hi-jacking, but if my theory is correct, he met Kira on that bus.
Ray... Penber!
What's wrong?
It's nothing.. I had no idea that you'd lost your fiancé.
So, why do you think he met Kira on that bus?
After being caught up in that bus hi-jacking, he died eight days later along with eleven other FBI agents.
Two days earlier, the culprit of the bus hi-jacking committed a bank robbery, and in the end he died in an accident.
It's not something that has been seen before.
I can only imagine that the bus hi-jack was set up, so that Kira could obtain information on the FBI agents in Japan that they intended to kill.
And the culprit ended up dead in an accident.
Basically, heart attacks are not the only way that Kira can kill!
The bus hi-jack culprit didn't die of a heart attack. Therefore, Kira must be able to kill via methods other than heart attacks?
Yes.
I think your story requires a few leaps in logic...
No, the only explanation is that the culprit was being manipulated by Kira.
Why's that?
Ever since he told me about the bus hi-jacking, something has been on my mind.
Finally, I asked him about it when he was in a good mood.
Although he didn't give me a name, he very clearly said...
What?
That he had no choice but to show someone on the bus his FBI ID.
The investigation was kept secret from the Japanese police, so there were orders that they were to never show their ID.
So, the fact that FBI agents were in Japan must have come from that.
Wow! She's right.
So this is the "hole" that Light has been worrying about.
I see. A truth that only you could know, and vengeance for the fiancé that was taken from you, have led you to this answer...
That Kira can kill people through other methods than just a heart attack.
Yes.
You have incredible powers of deduction, yet you are blinded by personal feelings.
It feels like this is very much aggressive intuition.
However, there are ample reasons to justify investigating this theory.
Your testimony will be very important.
Yes.
If you're right, it'll be like you said.
Kira will soon be caught.
After all, the person who your fiancé showed his ID to in the bus... is Kira.
Yes.
That was close.
If this woman had got to the police before I got to her...
But it seems that gods other than the Shinigami... are on my side.
To be continued
Darenimo mirenai yume wo mita
I've had dreams that no one else could have.
Iranai mono wa subete suteta
I've thrown away everything that I don't need.
Yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Those feelings I can't rid remain in my heart.
Mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
Even though I'm stuck between ideals and reality,
Gesei no kase ni, ashi wo toraretemo
and my legs are bound by the shackles of sacrifice.
Afureru shoudou osaekireba
If I can hold back these overwhelming urges,
Tsuyoku motomeru kokora ga arukara
I still have a soul that yearns for more.
Itsuwari, Osore, Kyoshoku, Urei
Lies, fear, pretension, grief.
Samazama na negative ni
I'm not so weak,
Torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
that I'll become lost in these negative feelings.
Kodoku mo shiranu trickster
A trickster that doesn't know loneliness.
Preview
Do you want to see how this woman is going to die?
It's not like I can go chasing after her..
Now, hurry up and die!
Next Time
Overcast Skies