Very handsome armor
Not a scratch on it.
People have been swinging
at me for years,
but they always
seem to miss.
You've chosen your
opponents wisely then.
Aah aah!
Why didn't you
get up and fight?
I'm a coward.
My father always says so.
Gods, who is that?
They call him the Mountain,
the hound's older brother.
- Sansa: And his opponent?
- Littlefinger: Ser Hugh of the Vale.
"The lineages of the great
houses of the Seven Kingdoms."
Did jon Arryn tell you
what he wanted with it?- He d.
There was one phrase
he kept repeating:
"The seed is strong."
You might want to visit
a certain armorer in the city.
My observers saw Lord Arryn
visit this armorer.
- Jory: Find anything?
- King Robert's bastard son.
Sam's no different
from the rest of us.
There was no place for him in
the world, so he's come here.
He's our brother now and we're
going to protect him.
- Aah!
- And now you've woken the dragon--
Uh!
I am the wife
of the great Khal
and I carry his son
inside me.
The next time
you raise a hand to me
will be the last time
you have hands.
What is it you hope
to accomplish?
The king called on me
to serve him.
You're just a soldier,
aren't you?
- I was also trained to kill my enemies.
- As was I.
This man
came into my house
and conspired
to murder my son.
In the name of King Robert,
seize him.
♪ Game of Thrones 1x05 ♪
The Wolf and the Lion
Original Air Date on May 15, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Does Ser Hugh have
any family in the capital?
No.
I stood vigil for him myself
last night.
He had no one else.
He'd never worn
this armor before.
Bad luck for him--
All the knights
draw straws, Lord Stark.
Aye.
But who holds
the straws?
You've done
good work, sisters.
Life is strange.
Not so many years ago
we fought as enemies
at the Trident.
I'm glad we never met
on the field, Ser Barristan.
As is my wife.
I don't think the widow's life
would suit her.
You're too modest.
I've seen you cut down
a dozen great knights.
My father once told me
you were the best
he'd ever seen.
I never knew the man to be
wrong about matters of combat.
He was a fine man,
your father.
What the Mad King did to him
was a terrible crime.
And that lad--
he was a squire
until a few months ago.
How could he afford
a new suit of armor?
Perhaps Lord Arryn
left him some money?
I hear the King wants
to joust today.
Yes, that will
never happen.
Robert tends to do
what he wants.
If the King got what
he wanted all the time,
he'd still be fighting
a damned rebellion.
It's made too small,
Your Grace. It won't go.
Your mother was
a dumb whore
with a fat ass.
Did you know that?
Look at this idiot!
One ball and no brains.
He can't even put a man's
armor on him properly.
You're too fat
for your armor.
Fat?
Fat, is it?
Is that how you speak
to your King?
That was funny, is it?
No, Your Grace.
No?
You don't like the Hand's joke?
You're torturing
the poor boy.
You heard the Hand.
The King's too fat for his armor.
Go find the breastplate
stretcher-- now!
"The breastplate stretcher"?
How long before
he figures it out?
Maybe you should
have one invented.
All right, all right.
But you watch me out there--
I still know how to point a Lance.
You have no business jousting.
Leave that for the young men.
Why, because I'm king?
Piss on that. I want to hit somebody!
- And who's going to hit you back?
- Anybody who can.
- And the last man in his saddle--
- Will be you.
There's not a man
in the Seven Kingdoms
would risk hurting you.
Are you telling me those
cowards would let me win?
Aye.
- Drink.
- I'm not thirsty.
Drink.
Your King commands it.
Gods,
too fat for my armor.
Your squire...
A Lannister boy?
Mm. A bloody idiot,
but Cersei insisted.
I have Jon Arryn
to thank for her.
"Cersei Lannister will make
a good match," she told me.
"You'll need her father
on your side."
I thought being King meant I
could do whatever I wanted.
Enough of this.
Let's go watch 'em ride.
At least I can smell
someone else's blood.
- Robert?
- What?
Oh.
An inspiring sight
for the people, eh?
Come, bow before your King!
Bow, you shits!
- Where's Arya?
- At her dancing lessons.
The Knight of the Flowers.
Thank you, Ser Loras.
Don't let Ser Gregor
hurt him.
- Hey.
- I can't watch.
100 gold dragons
on the Mountain.
I'll take that bet.
Now what will I buy
with 100 gold dragons?
A dozen barrels
of Dornish wine?
Or a girl from
the pleasure houses of Lys?
Or you could even
buy a friend.
He's going to die.
Ser Loras rides well.
Such a shame,
Littlefinger.
It would have been so nice
for you to have a friend.
And tell me, Lord Renly,
when will you be having
your friend?
Loras knew his mare
was in heat.
Quite crafty, really.
Ser Loras would
never do that.
There's no honor in tricks.
No honor and quite
a bit of gold.
Sword!
Leave him be!
Stop this madness
in the name of your King!
Let him go!
I owe you my life, Ser.
I'm no Ser.
Remove his hood.
♪ on that Eve,
the captive Imp ♪
♪ downwards
from his horse did limp ♪
♪ no more would he
preen and primp ♪
♪ in garb of red and gold. ♪
This isn't the Kingsroad.
You said we were
riding for Winterfell.
I did...
Often and loudly.
Very wise.
They'll be out
in droves,
looking for me
in the wrong place.
Word's probably gotten
to my father by now.
He'll be offering
a handsome reward.
Everyone knows a Lannister
always pays his debts.
Would you be so good
as to untie me?
- And why would I do that?
- Why not?
Am I going to run?
The hill tribes would
kill me for my boots.
Unless a Shadowcat
ate me first.
Shadowcats and hill tribes are
the least of your concerns.
Ah, the eastern road.
We're going to the Vale.
You're taking me
to your sister's
to answer for my
imagined crimes.
Tell me, Lady Stark, when was
the last time you saw your sister?
Five years ago.
She's changed.
She was always
a bit touched, but now--
you might as well
kill me here.
- I am not a murderer, Lannister.
- Neither am I!
I had nothing to do with the
attempt on your son's life.
- The dagger found--
- What sort of imbecile
arms an assassin
with his own blade?
- Should I gag him?
- Why?
Am I starting
to make sense?
Rodrik!
My Lady, this way.
Untie me.
If I die, what's the point?
Ah!
Rodrik?
I'll be fine, My Lady.
There's no need
to bloody yourself.
Your first?
You need a woman.
Nothing like a woman
after a fight.
I'm willing if she is.
Bran.
The Iron Islands.
A Kraken.
We do not sow.
- Lords?
- The Greyjoys.
Famed for their skills
at archery,
navigation
and lovemaking.
And failed rebellions.
A stag--
a crowned stag
now that Robert's King.
- Good.
- Words: Ours is the fury.
- Lords: The Baratheons.
- Mm-hmm.
The Westerlands.
- Sigil: A lion.
- Mmm.
A Lannister
always pays his debts.
No.
A common saying, but not
their official motto.
The Lannisters.
- We're still on their words.
- I don't know them.
You do know them.
Think.
"Unbowed, unbent,
unbroken."
- That's House Martell.
- "Righteous in wrath."
- House Hornwood.
- "Family, duty, honor."
Those are Tully words--
your mother's.
- Are we playing a game?
- Family, duty, honor...
- Is that the right order?
- You know it is.
Family comes first?
Your mother had
to leave Winterfell
to protect the family.
How can she protect
the family
if she's not
with her family?
Your mother
sat by your bed
for three weeks
while you slept--
and then she left!
When you were born,
I was the one
who pulled you
from your mother.
I placed you in her arms.
From that moment
until the moment she dies,
she will love you.
Absolutely.
- Fiercely.
- Why did she leave?
I still can't tell you,
- but she will be home soon.
- Do you know where she is now?
Today?
No, I don't.
Then how can you promise me
she'll be home soon?
Sometimes I worry you're too
smart for your own good.
I'll never shoot
another arrow.
And where is that written?
- You need legs to work a bow.
- Hmm.
If the saddle Lord Tyrion
designed actually works,
you could learn to shoot a bow
from horseback.
Really
Dothraki boys learn
when they're four years old.
Why shouldn't you?
Shh, keep it down.
You're not supposed to be
inside the castle walls.
I thought you were supposed to be
an important person around here.
Important enough
for the likes of you.
You're not the only nobleman
in my life, you know.
Who, the Imp?
I'd call him
half a nobleman.
Jealous?
Why should I be jealous?
Anyone with a few coppers in his
pocket can own you for the night.
What's a dwarf like
down below?
I've always wondered.
- Might surprise you.
- Hmm?
He's good
with his fingers too.
And his tongue.
Generous tipper.
I guess gold is cheap
for a Lannister.
You are jealous.
I'm a Greyjoy.
We've been lords of the
Iron Islands for 300 years.
There's not a family in Westeros
that can look down on us,
not even the Lannisters.
And what about
the Starks?
I've been Lord Stark's ward
since I was eight years old.
A ward--
that's a nice word for it.
Your father rebelled
against King Robert
- and if he does it again--
- My father fought
for the freedom
of his people.
What did your father do?
Fucked a cook and whelped a whore.
You're a very serious boy.
- I'm not a boy.
- Oh yes, you are.
A serious boy
with a serious cock.
I don't want
to pay for it.
Then get yourself
a wife.
Come on.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
How is your son,
My Lord?
He'll never
walk again.
But his mind is sound?
So they say.
A blessing then.
I suffered an early
mutilation myself.
Some doors
close forever...
Others open
in the most unexpected places.
May I?
If the wrong ears heard
what I'm about to tell you,
off comes my head.
And who would mourn
poor Varys then?
North or South, they sing
no songs for spiders.
But there are things
you must know.
You are the King's Hand
and the King is a fool--
your friend, I know,
but a fool--
and doomed
unless you save him.
I've been in the capital
a month.
Why have you waited so long
to tell me this?
I didn't trust you.
So why do you trust me now?
The Queen is
not the only one
who has been
watching you closely.
There are few men of honor
in the capital.
You are one of them.
I would like to believe
I am another,
strange as that may seem.
What sort of doom
does the King face?
The same sort
as Jon Arryn.
The tears of Lys,
they call it.
A rare and costly thing,
as clear
and tasteless as water.
It leaves no trace.
Who gave it to him?
Some dear friend, no doubt.
But which one?
There were many.
Lord Arryn was a kind
and trusting man.
There was one boy.
All he was
he owed to Jon Arryn.
The squire, Ser Hugh?
Pity what happened
to him,
just when his life seemed
to be going so nicely.
If Ser Hugh poisoned him--
who paid Ser Hugh?
Someone who could afford it.
Jon was a man of peace.
He was Hand for 17 years--
17 good years.
Why kill him?
He started
asking questions.
Man's voice:
He's found one bastard already.
He has the book.
The rest will come.
Man #2: And when he knows
the truth, what will he do?
The gods alone know.
The fools tried
to kill his son.
What's worse--
they botched it.
The wolf and the lion will
be at each other's throats.
- We will be at war soon, my friend.
- What good is war now?
We're not ready.
If one Hand can die,
why not a second?
This Hand
is not the other.
We need time.
Khal Drogo will not make his
move until his son is born.
You know how
these savages are.
"Delay," you say.
"Move fast," I reply.
This is no longer
a game for two players.
It never was.
The first to arrive
and the last to leave.
I admire
your industry.
You do move quietly.
We all have
our qualities.
You look
a bit lonely today.
You should pay a visit to
my brothel this evening.
First boy is on the house.
I think you're mistaking
business with pleasure.
Am I?
All those birds that
whisper in your ear--
such pretty little things.
Trust me,
we accommodate
all inclinations.
Oh, I'm sure.
Lord Redwyne likes his boys
very young, I hear.
I'm a purveyor
of beauty and discretion--
both equally important.
Though I suppose beauty
is a subjective quality, no?
Is it true that
Ser Marlon of Tumblestone
prefers amputees?
All desires are valid
to a man with a full purse.
And I heard the most awful
rumor about a certain lord
with a taste
for fresh cadavers.
Must be enormously difficult
to accommodate that inclination.
The logistics alone--
to find beautiful corpses
before they rot.
Strictly speaking,
such a thing
would not be in accordance
with the King's laws.
Strictly speaking.
Tell me--
does someone somewhere
keep your balls
in a little box?
I've often wondered.
Do you know I have no idea
where they are?
And we had been so close.
But enough about me.
How have you been
since we last
saw each other?
Since you last saw me
or since I last saw you?
Now the last time
I saw you,
you were talking
to the Hand of the King.
- Saw me with your own eyes?
- Eyes I own.
Council business.
We all have so much
to discuss with Ned Stark.
Everyone's well aware
of your enduring fondness
for Lord Stark's wife.
If the Lannisters were behind
the attempt on the Stark boy's life
and it was discovered
that you helped
the Starks come
to that conclusion...
To think a simple word
to the Queen--
- one shudders at the thought.
- Ooh.
But you know something?
I do believe that I have seen you
even more recently
than you have seen me.
- Have you?
- Yes.
Earlier today,
I distinctly recall
seeing you talking to Lord Stark
in his chambers.
Was that you
under the bed?
And not long after that
when I saw you
escorting a certain
foreign dignitary...
Council business?
Of course you would have friends
from across the Narrow Sea.
You're from there
yourself, after all.
We're friends,
aren't we, Lord Varys?
I'd like to think we are.
So you can imagine
my burden,
wondering if the King might
question my friend's sympathies.
To stand at a crossroads where
turning left means loyalty to a friend,
turning right
loyalty to the realm--
- Oh, please.
- To find myself in a position
where a simple word to the King--
What are you two
conspiring about?
Well, whatever it is,
you'd best hurry up.
My brother is coming.
To a small council meeting?
Disturbing news
from far away.
Haven't you heard?
Off with you.
No begging.
I'm not a beggar.
I live here.
D'you want a smack on your ear
to help you with your hearing?
I want to see my father.
I want to fuck the Queen,
for all the good it does me.
You want your father, boy?
He's lying on the floor
of some tavern,
getting pissed on
by his friends.
My father
is Hand of the King!
I'm not a boy.
I'm Arya Stark of Winterfell
and if you lay a hand on me,
my father
will have both
your heads on spikes.
Now are you going to let me by
or do I need to smack you
on the ear to help
with your hearing?
You know I had half my guard
out searching for you?
You promised me
this would stop.
They said they were
going to kill you.
- Who did?
- I didn't see them,
- but I think one was fat.
- Oh, Arya.
I'm not lying!
They said you found the bastard
and the wolves are fighting
the lions and the savage--
something about the savage.
- Where did you hear this?
- In the dungeons,
near the dragon skulls.
What were you doing
in the dungeons?
Chasing a cat.
Pardon, My Lord.
There's a night's watchman
here begging a word.
He says it's urgent.
- Your name, friend?
- Yoren, if it please.
This must be your son.
He has the look.
I'm a girl!
Did Benjen send you?
No one sent me,
My Lord.
I'm here to find
men for the Wall,
see if there's any scum
in the dungeons
that might be fit for service.
Oh, we'll find
recruits for you.
Thank you, My Lord.
But that's not why
I disturb you now.
Your brother Benjen,
his blood runs black--
makes him as much
my brother as yours.
It's for his sake
I rode here so hard
I damn near
killed my horse.
There are others
riding too.
The whole city
will know by tomorrow.
Know what?
Best said
in private, My Lord.
Go on.
We'll talk more later.
Jory, take her
safely to her room.
Come along, My Lady.
You heard your father.
How many guards
does my father have?
Here in
King's Landing? 50.
You wouldn't let anyone
kill him, would you?
No fear on that count,
little lady.
- Well?
- It's about your wife, My Lord.
She's taken the Imp.
You're far from home,
Lady Stark.
To whom do I speak?
Ser Vardis Egan,
knight of the Vale.
Is Lady Arryn
expecting your visit?
There was no time
to send word.
May I ask, My Lady,
why he is with you?
That's why
there was no time.
- He is my prisoner.
- He doesn't look like a prisoner.
My sister will decide
what he looks like.
Yes, My Lady.
She will at that.
The Eyrie.
They say it's impregnable.
Give me 10 good men
and some climbing spikes--
I'll impregnate the bitch.
I like you.
Lord Stark, your presence
has been requested
in the small council chamber.
A meeting has been called.
I need to see
the King first-- alone.
The King is at the small council
meeting, My Lord.
He has summoned you.
- Is it about my wife?
- No, My Lord.
I believe it concerns
Daenerys Targaryen.
The whore is pregnant.
- You're speaking of murdering a child.
- I warned you
this would happen.
Back in the North, I warned you,
but you didn't care
to hear.
Well, hear it now.
I want 'em dead,
mother and child both.
And that fool Viserys
as well.
Is that plain enough
for you?
I want them both dead.
You will dishonor yourself
forever if you do this.
Honor?!
I've got Seven Kingdoms
to rule!
One King,
Seven Kingdoms.
Do you think honor
keeps them in line?
Do you think it's honor
that's keeping the peace?
It's fear--
fear and blood.
Then we're no better
than the Mad King.
Careful, Ned.
Careful now.
You want
to assassinate a girl
because the Spider
heard a rumor?
No rumor, My Lord.
The princess is with child.
Based on whose
information?
Ser Jorah Mormont.
He is serving as advisor
to the Targaryens.
Mormont?
You bring us the whispers
of a traitor half a world away
and call it fact?
Jorah Mormont's
a slaver, not a traitor.
Small difference, I know,
to an honorable man.
He broke the law, betrayed
his family, fled our land.
We commit murder
on the word of this man?
And if he's right?
If she has a son?
A Targaryen at the head
of a Dothraki army...
- What then?
- The Narrow Sea still lies between us.
I'll fear the Dothraki
the day they teach
their horses to run on water.
Do nothing?
That's your wise advice?
Do nothing till our enemies
are on our shores?
You're my council.
Counsel!
Speak sense to this
honorable fool.
I understand your misgivings,
My Lord.
Truly, I do.
It is a terrible thing
we must consider,
a vile thing.
Yet we who presume
to rule must sometimes
do vile things for
the good of the realm.
Should the gods
grant Daenerys a son,
the realm will bleed.
I bear this girl no ill will,
but should
the Dothraki invade,
how many innocents will die?
How many towns
will burn?
Is it not wiser,
kinder even,
that she should die now
so that tens of thousands
might live?
We should have had them
both killed years ago.
When you find yourself
in bed with an ugly woman,
best close your eyes,
get it over with.
Cut her throat.
Be done with it.
I followed you
into war--
twice,
without doubts,
without second thoughts.
But I will not
follow you now.
The Robert I grew up with
didn't tremble at the shadow
of an unborn child.
She dies.
I will have no part in it.
You're the King's Hand,
Lord Stark.
You'll do as I command
or I'll find me a hand who will.
And good luck to him.
I thought you were
a better man.
Out.
Out, damn you.
I'm done with you.
Go, run back
to Winterfell!
I'll have your head
on a spike!
I'll put it there
myself, you fool!
You think you're too good for this?
Too proud and honorable?
This is a war!
I'll go ahead
with my daughters.
Get them ready.
Do it yourself.
- Don't ask anyone for help.
- Right away, My Lord.
Lord Baelish
is here for you.
His Grace went on about you
at some length
after you took your leave.
The word "treason"
was mentioned.
What can I do for you?
When do you return
to Winterfell?
Why? What do you care?
If you're still here
come nightfall,
I'll take you to see
the last person Jon Arryn
spoke with before falling ill.
If that sort of thing
still interests you.
I don't have the time.
It won't take more than an hour.
But as you please.
Round up all the men we have
and station them outside
the girls' chambers.
- Who are your best two swords?
- Heward and Wyl.
Find them and meet me
at the stables.
You bring him here
without permission?
You pollute my home
with his presence?
Your aunt has done
a bad thing, Robin,
a very bad thing.
You remember her,
don't you?
Isn't he beautiful?
And strong too.
Jon knew it.
His last words were
"the seed is strong."
He wanted everyone to know
what a good, strong boy
his son would grow up to be.
Look at him,
the Lord of all the Vale.
Lysa,
you wrote me about
the Lannisters,
- warning me--
- To stay away from them!
Not to bring one here!
Mommy?
- Is that the bad man?
- It is.
He's little.
He's Tyrion the Imp
of House Lannister.
He killed your father.
He murdered
the Hand of the King!
Oh, did I kill him too?
I've been a very busy man.
You will
watch your tongue!
These men are knights
of the Vale.
Every one of them
loved Jon Arryn.
Every one of them would
die for me.
If any harm comes to me,
my brother Jaime will see
that they do.
You can't hurt us.
No one can hurt us here.
Tell him, mommy!
- Tell him!
- Shh shh shh, my sweet boy.
He's just trying
to frighten us.
Lannisters are all liars.
No one will
hurt my baby.
Mommy...
I want to see
the bad man fly.
Perhaps you will,
my little love.
This man is my prisoner.
I will not have him
harmed.
Ser Vardis,
my sister's guest
is weary.
Take him down below
so he can rest.
Introduce him to Mord.
You go sleep,
dwarf man.
Sleep good,
little dwarf man!
Lord Stark's lucky
he still has a head.
Robert will rant for a few days,
but he won't do anything.
He adores the man.
You're jealous.
Are you sure
this won't hurt?
Only if I slip.
- And you'd prefer me like this?
- Mm-hmm.
If you want hairless, maybe
you should find a little boy.
I want you.
My brother thinks that anyone
who hasn't been to war isn't a man.
He treats me as if
I'm a spoiled child.
Oh, and you're not?
Loras Tyrell,
the Knight of the Flowers?
How many wars
have you fought in?
Oh, and how much did your father
spend on that armor of yours?
Hold still.
All I ever hear from Robert and
Stannis is how I'm not tough enough,
how I squirm
at the sight of blood--
you did vomit when that boy's eye
was knocked out in the melee.
His eye was dangling
out of the damn socket!
He shouldn't have entered the melee
if he didn't know how to fight.
Easy for you to say.
Not everyone is such
a gifted swordsman.
It's not a gift.
No one gave it to me.
I'm good because
I work at it--
every day of my life
since I could hold a stick.
I could work at fighting
all day, every day,
and still never
be as good as you.
Yes well, I guess
we'll never know.
- Everywhere?
- Everywhere.
So how did it end up?
The Targaryen
girl will die?
It needs to be done,
unpleasant as it is.
Robert's rather
tasteless about it.
Every time he talks
about killing her,
I swear the table
rises six inches.
It's a shame he can't muster the
same enthusiasm for his wife.
He does have a deep, abiding
lust for her money.
You have to give it
to the Lannisters--
they may be the most
pompous, ponderous cunts
the gods ever suffered
to walk the world,
but they do have outrageous
amounts of money.
I have an outrageous
amount of money.
Not as much
as the Lannisters.
But a lot more than you.
Robert's threatening
to take me hunting with him.
Last time we were out there
for two weeks.
Tramping through the trees
in the rain, day after day,
all so he can stick his spear
into something's flesh.
Oh. But Robert
loves his killing.
- And he's the King.
- Hmm.
- How did that ever happen?
- Because he loves his killing.
And he used to be
good at it.
Do you know
who should be king?
- Be serious.
- I am.
My father could be
your bank.
I've never fought in a war before,
but I'd fight for you.
I'm fourth in line.
And where was Robert in the line
of royal succession?
Joffrey is a monster.
- Tommen is eight.
- Stannis?
Stannis has the
personality of a lobster.
He's still
my older brother.
- What are you doing?!
- Look at it.
You cut me.
It's just blood.
We've all got it in us.
Sometimes a little spills.
If you become King, you're
going to see a lot of this.
You need to get used to it.
Go on. Look.
People love you.
They love to serve you
because you're kind to them.
They want to be near you.
You're willing to do
what needs to be done,
but you don't gloat over it.
You don't love killing.
Where is it written
that power
is the sole province
of the worst?
That thrones are only made
for the hated
and the feared?
You would be
a wonderful King.
I'm sorry your marriage
to Ned Stark didn't work out.
You seemed
so good together.
I'm glad I could do something
to make you happy.
Without a Hand,
everything will fall to pieces.
I suppose this is where
you tell me
to give the job
to your brother Jaime.
No.
He's not serious enough.
I'll say this for Ned Stark:
He's serious enough.
Was it really worth it?
Losing him this way?
I don't know.
But I do know this:
If the Targaryen girl convinces
her horselord husband to invade
and the Dothraki horde
crosses the Narrow Sea...
We won't be able
to stop them.
The Dothraki don't sail.
Every child knows that.
They don't have discipline.
They don't have armor.
They don't have
siege weapons.
It's a neat
little trick you do:
You move your lips and
your father's voice comes out.
Is my father wrong?
Let's say
Viserys Targaryen lands
with 40,000 Dothraki
screamers at his back.
We hole up
in our castles--
a wise move--
only a fool
would meet the Dothraki
in an open field.
They leave us
in our castles.
They go from town to town,
looting and burning,
killing every man who can't
hide behind a stone wall,
stealing all our crops
and livestock,
enslaving all our women
and children.
How long do the people of the
Seven Kingdoms stand behind
their absentee King,
their cowardly King
hiding behind high walls?
When do the people decide
that Viserys Targaryen
is the rightful monarch
after all?
We still outnumber them.
Which is the bigger number:
Five or one?
Five.
Five...
One.
One army--
a real army
united behind one leader
with one purpose.
Our purpose died
with the Mad King.
Now we've got
as many armies
as there are men
with gold in their purse.
And everybody wants
something different.
Your father wants
to own the world.
Ned Stark wants to run away
and bury his head in the snow.
What do you want?
We haven't had a real fight
in nine years.
Back-stabbing doesn't
prepare you for a fight.
And that's all
the realm is now:
Back-stabbing
and scheming
and arse-licking
and money-grubbing.
Sometimes I don't know
what holds it together.
Our marriage.
Ah, so here we sit
17 years later,
holding it all together.
Don't you get tired?
Every day.
How long can hate
hold a thing together?
Well, 17 years
is quite a long time.
Yes, it is.
What was she like?
You've never asked
about her, not once.
Why not?
At first, just saying
her name even in private
felt like I was breathing
life back into her.
I thought if I didn't
talk about her,
she'd just
fade away for you.
When I realized that
wasn't going to happen,
I refused to ask
out of spite.
I didn't want to give you
the satisfaction
of thinking I cared
enough to ask.
And eventually it became clear that
my spite didn't mean anything to you.
As far as I could tell,
you actually enjoyed it.
So why now?
What harm could Lyanna Stark's
ghost do to either of us
that we haven't done to each other
a hundred times over?
You want to know
the horrible truth?
I can't even remember
what she looked like.
I only know she was the one
thing I ever wanted...
Someone took her
away from me,
and Seven Kingdoms couldn't
fill the hole she left behind.
I felt something
for you once, you know?
I know.
Even after we lost
our first boy.
For quite a while, actually.
Was it ever
possible for us?
Was there ever a time,
ever a moment?
No.
Does that make you feel
better or worse?
It doesn't make me
feel anything.
She looks like him,
don't she, My Lord?
She has his nose,
his black hair.
Aye.
Tell him when you
see him, My Lord.
If it please you,
tell him how beautiful she is.
I will.
And tell him I've been
with no one else.
I swear it, My Lord,
by the old gods and new.
I don't want no jewels
or nothing,
just him.
The King was always
good to me.
When Jon Arryn
came to visit you,
what did he want?
He wasn't that sort
of man, My Lord.
He just wanted to know
if the child was happy,
healthy.
He looks healthy
enough to me.
The girl shall want
for nothing.
Brothels make a much better
investment than ships,
I've found.
Whores rarely sink.
What do you know
of King Robert's bastards?
Well, he has more
than you, for a start.
- Ned: How many?
- Does it matter?
If you fuck enough women,
some of them will give you presents.
And Jon Arryn tracked
them all down. Why?
He was the King's Hand. Perhaps
Robert wanted them looked after.
He was overcome
with fatherly love.
Come.
- Jory!
- My Lord.
Such a small pack
of wolves.
Stay back, Ser.
This is the Hand of the King.
Was the Hand
of the King.
Now I'm not sure
what he is--
lord of somewhere
very far away.
What's the meaning
of this, Lannister?
Get back inside
where it's safe.
I'm looking
for my brother.
You remember my brother,
don't you, Lord Stark?
Blond hair,
sharp tongue, short man.
I remember him well.
It seems he had
some trouble on the road.
You wouldn't know what
happened to him, would you?
He was taken at my command
to answer for his crimes.
My lords!
I'll bring the City Watch.
Come, Stark.
I'd rather you die
sword in hand.
- If you threaten My Lord again--
- Threaten?
As in, "I'm going
to open your lord
from balls to brains and
see what Starks are made of"?
You kill me,
your brother's
a dead man.
You're right.
Take him alive.
Kill his men.
Yah!
My brother, Lord Stark--
we want him back.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==