Cleaned, corrected & sync adjusted by Tronar
This is the second time this week...
I had to pay for a sitter
'cause he was workin' late.
With all that money he make,
you can afford it.
Lord.
What's up, Bubs?
Hey.
There you go.
- What you got?
- I got some starters.
My fault, A.
- Should've never left you alone, homie.
- No, shit.
Man, you ain't pull up when you did,
I'm gone.
Listen, what I want to know is how
we fucking come back on this cocksucker?
We don't. Not now.
You feel me?
Listen, Stringer,
your advice was good advice...
you know what I'm saying?
I wanna let you know that.
What I want you to do now
is put the word out there.
I want you to let him know
we willing to squash this, if he is.
And then what the fuck if he ain't?
No, this nigger live in the town, too.
He gonna listen, if we parley.
And then when he creep out
of his hole, and shit.
- Boom.
- Okay.
- Smoke him.
- Say no more, got you.
- Put that out there, yo.
- All right.
About them police, though,
they was on your ass after the game?
Yeah, man, it was like two cars.
See, if they on you, then they got a name.
If they got a name,
then they know you got no license.
But they don't want no traffic charges,
you know what I'm saying?
They don't want no humble shit.
I think they was trying
to see where I might go.
Where the fuck was you
gonna take their asses?
I was taking them to the barbershop.
I was going to get a haircut.
Get a fade?
I know, B, but these motherfuckers
are on us. Fuck.
They always have been on us,
we just gotta be careful.
You not been talking on any phones.
And you not been touching any drugs.
And from now on,
you are not doing the money runs.
Me and Bey, we gonna take care
of that shit...
until this whole thing cool off.
- Let me get that pager.
- What's up, you serious?
Serious. I'm gonna get you
a New York supply number only.
Any of these motherfucking local cats...
wanna talk to you, they gotta talk to me.
We gotta build a wall around you, B.
Another month on a fresh phone?
They ripped out the pay phones
in the low-rises.
Now they're walking a block or two.
How much longer
until you bring this case in?
The quicker you can the better
for everybody. Yourself included.
Look at this.
Judge Gwynn sends his regrets.
He can't make lunch.
Like I suddenly got the plague.
There's your new phone. 30 days.
A few weeks ago, when Burrell
wanted to take down the wire...
you were the one breaking off on his ass.
Jimmy, there's a lady here.
Rhonda talks more trash than both of us,
Your Honor.
I have never been
anything other than ladylike, Your Honor.
Detective McNulty is going out of his way
to insult an officer of the court.
- McNulty, I hold you in contempt.
- Who doesn't?
What's with him?
- You haven't heard?
- No.
- What's wrong with the picture?
- Don't know.
- Phelan isn't in it.
- What, he's up for election?
I thought judges had 15-year terms.
They do, but Phelan was named
to finish Halpern's term...
which only had two years left.
So he has to run on his own in the primary.
What, he's not on the ticket?
Why the fuck not?
Maybe it's the company he keeps.
Fuck.
No, see, you ain't thinking about
how much room the baby gonna need.
Specially when he get to growing...
'cause there are things we got to have.
Like a real crib, a play desk...
and you know, he got to have
one of them Little Tikes cars.
I'm not saying your place
ain't nice enough...
'cause for you, it do just fine,
but if we gonna be a family...
we need at least one more room, if not two.
So you add the bedroom set,
a nice bedroom set like the one they got...
down at that baby store on Howard Street,
and that's a room right there.
And I think we might
get some better furniture...
and put your stuff in the other bedroom...
like it was a den...
'cause the sofa you got seen better days...
I think you know that much.
Dee, where you goin' at?
I told you I need money
for the new bedroom set. Dee!
- Why you holler at me?
- Yo, man, we getting down to it.
I get to you when I get to you.
That's the main stash house.
Say what?
The incoming call is the guy who runs
the main stash for Barksdale's people.
- Who is he?
- We don't know.
So, y'all are just guessing
he's on the stash, right?
No, he's on it.
Lester was checking the logs
when he picked up the pattern.
Every time they get down
to the ends on a package...
somebody in the tower
hits that pager number.
Then, within a half-hour
every fucking time...
a call comes back to the tower pay phone
from that number in Pimlico.
Which is?
It's a pay phone at a Mondo Mart
in Reisterstown on Cold Spring Lane.
You see it now?
When the supply gets low,
they page this mope...
who always calls back from a pay phone
way the fuck out in north-west.
Same phone, same pattern.
So y'all think that
he's taking the re-up order...
and that the stash is somewhere
near the Mondo Mart, right?
- You are on it, Detective Sydnor.
- Okay, so what do you do with this?
What do we do?
We're gonna be sittin'
on that phone in Pimlico...
all day and night
waitin' on Mr. Mondo Mart.
- Herc, too.
- Herc's out this whole week.
- In-service training.
- That's too bad.
So, instead of three eight-hour shifts,
you two are gonna have to pull 12 hours.
Just fucking kill me now.
- Heard from Omar?
- Nope.
I'm gonna go try to scare him up.
Where you gonna be?
Everyone on the wire keeps talking about...
how this kid's all tore up
about the dead stickup boy.
- I'm gonna see for myself.
- All right.
- You need us, we're on the radio.
- Okay.
Hey, what up, man?
This first time,
I can go four ounces of rock...
but hey, if the shit is right,
then next time I can step that up.
Almost ain't worth it for four.
Just this first go-round.
You do right by me,
I'll turn around and come back on it.
Where your money at, man?
We good.
So, where the shit at?
Ain't nobody been there but you.
Nobody came in my house but you.
Everybody.
Nobody but you. You're the only person
that came in my house.
So, what you got goin' for you?
Ain't got nothing left, burnt it away.
Family?
Mother dead. Father, who the fuck know.
Brothers, sisters?
A sister, she lets me stay in the basement...
but she lock the door so I can't go upstairs.
About the best she can do for me.
Got a kid, a son.
Imagine me bringing life into the world.
- What's his name?
- Keyshawn.
His mother took him up Jersey way,
said I wasn't fit to be with the boy.
- I didn't disagree.
- Well...
at least you got your health.
Here's to health.
I got the bug.
Had it since '94.
Gave that shit to my old lady.
Worried about passing it on to my baby girl.
No, I was spared that at least.
Damn, how do you carry it?
- You ask her forgiveness?
- Of course.
- What she say?
- What she needed to say.
Look, forgiveness from other folks is good...
but ain't nothing but words
coming at you from outside.
You wanna kick this shit,
you got to forgive your own self.
Love yourself some, brother.
And then drag your sorry ass
to some meetings.
- Meetings?
- What the fuck you wanna hear?
That you're strong enough
to do this by yourself?
Getting clean's the easy part.
Now comes life.
It's this one here with the orange cord
coming out of the back.
They're pirating juice from the other house.
You fucking gotta be kidding me.
Now I'm policing for BGE?
They're not there yet,
but when this kid here posts, snatch him up.
Park our asses outside this shit-hole and
wait for some little project yo to raise up?
Mrs. McNulty raised no fools.
Four Faidley's crabcakes in the bag...
24 Dutch beers in the box.
Faidley's? You all right, McNulty.
I don't care what all them
other fucks downtown say about you.
11-35, what's up?
Our friend wants to meet. Same spot.
- Copy that, 15 minutes.
- What's the deal with the yo-boy?
- What'd he do?
- Stumbled into my world.
- Five minutes, come on.
- I have to go.
- Shardene.
- I said, I have to go.
- I can't have five minutes?
- No, not right now.
Fuck!
How close did you get?
Y'all be chalking that nigger if Wee Bey
ain't pop up at the last second like...
Remember when we last talked?
You were gonna lay back,
let us work our case.
I said, I'd do what I can.
Still, I thought I might let y'all know
Avon's people got in contact...
talking about they want to end the beef.
- They offered me some kind of amnesty.
- Amnesty?
Look, I chill out on the manhunt
and stop hitting them in the head...
for their product,
they gonna call off the bounty.
Take the truce, Omar.
I might, if they ain't trying to play me.
- They said they want to parley on it.
- Parley?
Look, I don't know, man, but right now
I need some assistance from y'all.
Yo, son, I go to the ER,
and word get back to Avon...
you know he gonna have his henchmen
waiting in the parking lot for me.
Look, I know y'all friendly
with a couple of doctors, right? Right?
He says he can buy weight.
Says he runs with some decent-size locals.
- Like who?
- Avon, something... Barksdale.
Avon Barksdale?
Run it through the DECS and HIDA.
See what comes back.
I'm gonna check around,
see if anybody's working...
these names you gave us.
If you full of shit, pal,
I'm gonna know it quick.
But what happens to me
while you checking?
Eager Street. City jail, motherfucker.
Blue came home last week.
I ain't seen him since.
Yeah.
I can't believe it.
- Damn, Carv, you's triflin'.
- Yeah, I admit it, I'm disgusting.
Cheese puffs and fucking Ring-Dings?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- The big fuck from the high-rise...
- what's his name?
- Little Man.
- Yeah, him.
- All right.
- Yo.
- Be ready, we're on it.
Look at this pretty motherfucker.
Too fucked up to drive home, McNulty?
Hey, Bunk.
Kid gave us a murder.
More than that, he's put in Stringer Bell.
Yeah?
Picks out Wee-Bey, Bird
and Stinkum from photo arrays.
Puts them all up at the Greek's...
the night they grab up Omar's boy, Brandon.
Puts Bell in the truck, too.
Says, "Stringer told me
to point out the stickup boy."
- Jeez, what do you have over him?
- Not a fucking thing.
Kid was ready, barely had to push him.
- Whose case?
- Norris's.
- How old?
- 16.
Lives in a shit-hole vacant over on Argyle.
When I grab him up,
I swear he's halfway into a nod.
Using?
When they kill the stickup boy
the fuckers dump the body in the alley...
behind where this kid and all the other
low-rise hoppers lay their heads.
Can you imagine?
All he can think about.
You tell him he's gonna have to testify?
Not yet, we'll get there.
Problem is, what do we do with him now?
- Yeah.
- Big boy picking up.
Okay.
- You holler at me, right?
- Where you at, man? We on our way down.
First thing tomorrow, man.
- Yeah?
- It's him, stay on it.
All right.
I didn't do nothing, man, get me outta here.
The 2-2, grounded slowly towards third,
and it gets through at the last moment.
Where my phone call at?
Suzuki's at the plate, here's the pitch.
Line drive, up the middle,
a base hit for Suzuki.
Suzuki's very patient at the plate.
Yeah, man, it's me.
Guess who's up in here.
Pimpin'-ass Orlando, from the club.
Yeah. Courtside.
- So, how long you been slingin'?
- Since I was, maybe, 12.
And how long were you
with Barksdale's crew in the low-rises?
With D'Angelo? Not long.
He came down from the towers
at the beginning of the summer.
Before that I worked for Ronnie Mo.
D'Angelo ever talk to you
about what happened in the 221 building...
with Pooh getting shot?
How about anything else like that?
- Like what?
- Killings, murders.
He say anything about a girl getting shot
in an apartment up on the Eastside?
He...
No, Dee, he was good to me. He all right.
But D'Angelo, he was who you called
that night when you saw...
the stickup boy at the Greek's, right?
Yeah, but he didn't go up there.
It was mostly those tower boys.
And Stringer.
You said Stringer was in the truck.
He called you over,
asked you to point out the stickup boy.
All of it corroborated by the beeper logs...
and the pen registers
from the project pay phones.
Stinkum's dead.
We've already got Bird for the Gant killing.
- This ties them all in.
- D'Angelo, too.
Maybe, but since he didn't show
at the Greek's...
he tells the jury
he didn't see the murder coming.
It's enough to charge him, anyway.
Parents?
Alcoholic mother.
In the wind, no fixed address.
Says he's got a grandmother
on the Eastern Shore...
but he hasn't seen her in years.
- How about a hotel room?
- On whose dime?
No way the Deputy approves the manpower
to stash a 16-year-old...
much less the room service.
McNulty, Line 2.
How about you run this up to front office?
See if the state's attorney will kick in.
He's a kid, Cedric.
Even if we clear the money,
do you really wanna put a juvenile...
in a hotel for six months
waiting on a trial date?
I think you all need to get
with Grandma down on the shore.
Now? She's doing this right now?
They don't have to set a hearing date
or something like that?
Christ, yeah, okay. Yeah.
I fuckin' need a fuckin' lawyer.
What?
Still, you can see that
they got the security bars...
and look there.
Cameras that see over the yard
out to the street.
And I checked with Verizon,
there's no phone service at that address.
That's a telltale right there.
So what? We try to write a warrant
for this place, right?
Right?
- What are you seeing?
- No pattern, really.
Except this cluster of old storefronts...
and warehouses
on the west side of downtown.
Around Paca, Utah, Howard Street, mostly.
- Storefronts?
- Vacants, usually.
Three different holding companies.
- Detective Pryzbylewski.
- What?
You have a gift for the paper trail.
Tomorrow calls for some street work,
though. Are you street ready?
You know the Lieutenant has me in-office.
I don't have my gun until the grand jury.
- You won't need one.
- On the street? No gun?
No gun. Not for this.
Furthermore, Mr. McNulty,
having utilized his sons...
in an act of police work
involving a criminal suspect...
actually lost track of them
in a crowded municipal market.
This is simply unacceptable, Your Honor.
Be that as it may,
an emergency ex parte order...
is an extraordinary request, Mr. Palmer.
You actually want me to limit visitations
to afternoons only, and you want...
Mrs. McNulty present at all visitations?
Come on.
It is not a single lapse, Judge.
Mr. McNulty has time and again
failed to properly care for the children...
when they're in his custody.
I have a list of recent events, Your Honor,
that justify an order.
Ms. Pearlman, you have a response
you'd like to offer up here?
Nope.
Nothing?
If this were possession with intent,
I'd be a prosecutor with a plan.
But a domestic order hearing?
Your Honor, I'm officially clueless.
In fact, as an employee of the state,
I should not actually be here.
All right, listen up, people...
before you have me make a ruling
on an emergency petition...
everybody here just needs
to take a deep breath.
Literally, come on.
Now, then, is Mr. McNulty capable...
of having a civil conversation
with Mrs. McNulty?
Yes, Your Honor.
And is Mrs. McNulty equally capable
of having a conversation with Mr. McNulty?
- Yes.
- Good, then I'm going to lunch.
Let's see when I return
if we can't busy this court...
with something just a little more engaging
than the problems of the McNultys.
Look, the charge is on me.
I understand that, I'll carry that.
But the least our people can do...
is throw down a little something
to pay the bondsman.
That's the deed of transfer for the club.
The other thing is a license transfer
application for the liquor board.
They're both backdated
and notarized for last week.
What?
A front has to be clean.
And right now, you ain't that. Sign.
I want my bail paid.
You send me a bondsman, I'll sign.
Is that what you want me to tell him?
That I asked you to sign and you wouldn't?
You wanted to be in the game, right?
Now you're in the game.
Unbelievable. You show up with her?
Elena, you went for an emergency ex parte.
I grabbed whatever lawyer
was standing around.
She was standing?
Ask her if she wants the pictures back.
Let's see, I've got her at the restaurant
with you pulling out her chair.
I've got her at the motel parking lot
with you opening the car door for her...
because you're such
a fucking gentleman now.
I can't believe you hired Buckman.
Son of a bitch never made
a case that counted.
He caught your cheating ass.
Elena, why are we here?
Because you can't have
Sean and Michael around criminals.
You can't lose them
in a Baltimore market. That's why.
He wasn't a criminal.
I know the guy.
It was a game we were playing.
It was daylight on a crowded street.
They could've been following AI Capone.
It would've been fine.
Look, Elena, these are my sons.
I love them. Do you hear, I love them.
I'm not gonna let them get hurt.
I love you, too.
Still do.
Does she know
about the detective and the pictures?
No, why would I tell her about that?
And are the two of you still...
No.
Yes.
A little.
Come on, let's make nice for the judge.
Okay.
We know we have a month more to go
and we're not gonna let up.
We are going to raise more,
we are going to spend more...
and on Election Day,
we are going to be out there...
pushing the vote in every precinct.
You ready?
Come on, we'll get dinner first.
Ain't so hungry.
Come on.
How much were you using?
I'm asking if you're gonna be sick in my car.
A cap now and then.
You just snorting?
You'll be all right in a day or two. Come on.
This nigger coming or what, man?
Said he would, if I guaranteed a parley.
And I'm here on it.
Of course, he said you would be
paying my fee rather than his own self.
Your fee?
I'm doing like one of them
marriage counselors.
Charge by the hour to tell some fool
he need to bring some flowers home.
Then charge another hour telling the bitch...
she ought to suck some cock
every little once and a while.
To keep a marriage strong like that.
Speaking of cocksuckers.
- Don't believe we met.
- Proposition Joe.
You ever steal from me,
I kill your whole family.
All right. You all both here on my guarantee,
so respect that shit and say what you feel.
I'm up out of here.
I got a man who say he gonna
give you your life back.
Who, Barksdale?
My man say, "Tell that motherfucker that...
"if he can find a way
not to dip in our pockets...
"we're gonna call this shit even."
You all aced Bailey,
and what you did to my boy?
So, y'all think after what you did to Brandon
we supposed to find some even on this?
I don't know shit about shit, all right?
I'm just the messenger.
Whatever, man.
You know there's dead on both sides, right?
And there's gonna be a whole lot more
if this beef keep up.
But the truth be told, there be more soldiers
on one half than the other.
You know what I'm saying?
Look here, son, you tell Barksdale...
that he's been paid back
for what he did to my peoples.
But as for his product,
a man's got to earn a living, you know?
I don't know nobody called Barksdale, B.
The man I'm talking about can't have
his shit taken like that. That won't do.
All right, tell him to throw me
some cash then, and we'll see...
About $5,000 or $10,000.
You know what I mean,
for my retirement, homes.
- $5,000 if you can keep quiet about it.
- Send my money through Joe, man.
You go through Joe,
you're not gonna see $2,000 of that.
- Why don't you tell my man where you at...
- No.
We gonna figure
something else out, you hear?
I'll be in touch, homes.
How careful is Stringer Bell?
"I don't know no one named Barksdale."
Shit.
Still, we got him tied to the Brandon killing.
That can be enough for one day's work.
Did what I could for y'all.
You sure, right?
Yeah, I spent a summer here
when I was nine.
When was the last time they saw you?
When I was nine.
- What's that?
- What?
That noise.
It's crickets.
- Cricket.
- Crickets.
- He try to go in my pockets again?
- This nigger is talking about $5,000, B.
Shit.
What's up, baby?
Antwon said to bring these up.
You want anything else?
No, we cool.
I'm saying though,
how we supposed to pay that?
He talking about going through Joe,
but I'm like, fuck Joe.
Thank you, you know what I mean?
You look good and your services
are appreciated.
Keep them tips,
I hope you making them, baby.
Make the motherfucker come down to the towers...
to get the rest of his money,
know what I'm saying?
If he's stupid enough to come
to the towers, he gonna get got.
It's a wrap. How we supposed to pay that?
All right.
Y'all think you can hang, but, look.
No, you see, I went to journalism school.
All right? Northwestern.
So you all can't stay with me on this...
Girl, you talking like
you some crusty old reporter.
- Excuse me?
- Bitch, you work at a TV station.
It's the same thing, all right?
Look, come on, stop talking.
Here we go.
- Bring it.
- Come on, Kima.
I gotta work tomorrow.
Candy ass.
That's all I have to say.
- Okay, you see?
- I'm with you.
All right.
Look at Tanya.
And she run a damn art gallery.
You see, police in this town ain't about shit.
- Guess not.
- Thank you.
Can't hold a liquor.
Can't hold a donut.
And if you ask me, I guess we...
ain't good in bed, either.
Don't go there, Officer. Don't go there.
Kima, how did you know
you wanted to be a cop?
I mean, how did you choose that?
When you were little,
did you think about it at all, or...
Come on, Kima.
I remember when I was in the Northeast,
still field-training as a cadet.
I didn't know if I was gonna
stick with it or not.
And then we got this one call.
We chased this purse-snatcher
up into these apartments.
I got separated from my FTO.
Shit, I ain't even no police yet.
You know, I'm just a trainee. And I'm alone.
Anyway, I mean,
I don't know how, but I find the guy.
So I catch him and I hold on to him
and I manage to get to my radio.
We in the middle of this parking lot
and we're rolling around...
and this motherfucker's
steady kicking my ass trying to get away.
I look over and I see these black patents
and these uniform blue pants.
I look up and it's Charlie Smoot...
Charlie fucking Smoot.
You know, this guy's a legend.
He looks down at me and he smiles,
you know real quiet-like.
And he drops his cuffs.
He says, "Here you go, rook."
That's all he says.
"Here you go, rook."
And then he dropped
the bracelets and walked away.
I mean, I know you don't like it.
But shit, I was proud.
God damn.
Lester says we ain't gonna
write a warrant on this place.
- How do we not with all this PC?
- We're on the main stash, right?
Why would we kick the door in...
when all we have to do
is park a van down the street...
follow the entire Westside drug supply
in and out of the place?
We're gonna start picking up
pieces of Barksdale's world...
we never even knew about.
Been hell looking for you people.
What the hell's the name
of this unit anyway?
Shit, Kima in the house.
What's up, Wig?
State police, CID, out of Pikesville.
Name of Troy Wiggins,
but pay no attention to the man...
because he about 90-95% pure bullshit.
Kima, she just talk like that
because I had her when she was good.
Shit, you the ugly-ass motherfucker
turned me the other way.
Shit, all right.
Here's the thing, boys and girls.
I'm doing a reverse buy-down
in Arundel, right?
And I get this Westside asshole
nibbling on four ounces, right?
- A whole four ounces?
- I know, he ain't much, but...
I get him in the boat
and he starts flopping around...
saying he can buy weight from some
motherfucker, name of Barksdale.
I never heard of no Barksdale.
But I put the name into DECS.
And the computer has Avon Barksdale
entered as an active Baltimore city target.
So I go down to City Narcotics, and Dawson,
he sends me down here to see y'all.
So what's the name of your fish?
Wendell O., as in...
oh-shit-l-tried-to-buy
from-a-state-police Blocker.
That wouldn't be
Wendell "Orlando" Blocker, would it?
Yeah. You on it.
Orlando.
They keep that back room locked.
And even if I do get back there
on an errand, then they kind of shut down.
They get real quiet.
You said you heard one say
something about...
making someone come into the towers.
- Yeah.
- Which one was talking?
He was tall, I think.
All right, but who else was there?
I don't really see that well
without my glasses.
Where are your glasses?
You can't see faces without those?
You don't wear those while you're working,
do you, darlin'?
Would you? I gotta live off drinks and tips.
- No way.
- Why not?
Because a player wouldn't be
the name on the liquor license.
He'd have a connect for Barksdale's coke.
He wouldn't walk into state troopers.
He got a charge and now
he's talking out his ass.
You're never gonna get Avon
or Stringer in the same room as the dope.
- We make this case on their voices alone.
- So maybe he can't buy from Barksdale.
Maybe he can only buy
from Savino or Wee-Bey.
Fuck him, then.
We already got Wee-Bey tied to a murder,
and Savino's the runt of the litter.
We can take what Orlando
gives us about the club.
The money laundering, maybe, or the girls.
For that kind of cooperation,
I'll drop a few years and call it fair.
- Daniels in here?
- Yeah.
Call from Deputy Commissioner for you.
You want it in here?
No.
He doesn't miss much.
- I need some help here.
- Come on, Bubs.
You got me coming across town
in the middle of a fucked-up workday...
just so you can hold $10,
that shit ain't right.
Hold on, I don't need $10, okay?
I don't know. I need a place of my own.
All right? Some bed,
some sheets, some clothes.
I definitely need some new clothes.
How long you been clean?
Three days.
You serious about it?
Who knows?
What the fuck am I gonna do
with a clean informant?
Did you think about that?
All right, I'm on it with you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What the fuck, give me some love.
Okay, I mean, I think I can get,
you know, a mattress, my own place...
everything for like a couple hundred dollars.
All right. We'll talk.
I gotta be somewhere tonight,
so hit me on my page tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I got you.
- The cooperator says he can buy weight.
- Not from Barksdale or Bell.
How can you be sure?
How much dope or coke do you think
gets Avon Barksdale into the room?
A kilo? 2 kilos? 20 kilos?
We are not going to buy
our way up the ladder here.
These people do not touch the drugs.
They don't go near the drugs.
The wire is what gives us Barksdale.
It gives us the whole crew.
Day by day, piece by piece.
Buy-bust, Lieutenant.
It's what I asked you for months ago.
It's what we do successfully...
time and again to make these cases.
Why New York?
Must be something happening out there.
Too big a town, you know what I mean?
- You don't believe in the truce?
- That's why I asked for that money.
If he had said,
"We ain't paying, just be happy to live"...
I'd have been like, they keeping it real.
But he say, come on down for $5,000.
I'm, like, man, please.
Look here, homes, I ain't asked for much,
but I'm a little light on traveling money.
I'm saying, I could go around the block
and get myself paid, but I'm thinking.
You keep in touch with my pager.
We're gonna need you for the Gant trial.
Go easy, Omar.
Stay free.
You be picking me up outside
the cut-rate on Lex and Fulton.
I be up there after 10.:00, right?
That'll work.
Listen up, people.
We've got $30,000 in buy money,
courtesy of our friends over at DEA.
But the thing is,
they can't have that money walking on them.
Definitely not.
So Kima will be in the car for the buy,
fronting as our Cl's girl.
Looking the part, too.
Now, where's your weapon gonna be?
He might pat me,
so it has to stash in the car.
I figure when Savino
gets in the car at the cut-rate...
I'll be going in back.
It'll be up under the rear seat.
And we probably can't be close enough
for an eyeball on this...
but the car will be a live wire.
And Kima will be throwing us
20s whenever she can. Rhonda.
I only want to remind Mr. Blocker here...
that his plea agreement
is contingent on cooperation.
And a buy-bust on Savino Bratton
is less cooperative...
than a buy-bust from someone
higher up on the food chain.
If you can get Savino
talking about Avon or Stringer...
that's better for us and better for you.
They already know that he got jacked
on a reverse buy, right?
- Why wouldn't they assume he's snitching?
- I need money for a lawyer, right?
That's the story.
He got popped and now he needs
to get right back into it...
to pay the bondsman and the lawyer.
All right. Let's make this work.
Careful. That's my career
you're holding there.
- You got a unit?
- Parked in the mezzanine.
- Give me the keys, man.
- No, I'm driving, motherfucker.
Come on, man.
Death row here.
Ain't up.
Death row.
My girl. Half the money's hers.
Baby, since we going down North Avenue...
stop by the carry-out
so I can pick me up some cigarettes.
They're going up North, stay loose.
Shit. It's too loud.
Does any unit have the eyeball?
Negative, 11-35.
Come on, Greggs, tell us
where the fuck you are.
Pull in there.
- What?
- Pull in there.
Don't fuck with this count.
I'll be right back with your shit.
Where are we?
That sign said Longwood,
but I could swear this was Warwick.
Hoppers be turning the sign poles
to fuck with you all.
I make it we're on the north side of Warwick,
in an alley...
I don't know, shit.
Half a block west of Longwood, maybe?
I hope you all copy that.
Yeah, that puts us about eight blocks away.
I'm pushing in a little closer.
All units be advised.
Warwick near Longwood
in the north side alley. Or near that 20.
This got the right feel for you?
You creeping closer?
He better not be long,
because I don't know where the stash is...
and if they dragging us all over
this part of town...
- What's that?
- What?
Something ain't right.
- Shit ain't right.
You snitching motherfucker.
Signal 13, signal 13!
Gunshots...
Gunshots. Go city-wide. 11-35.
Signal 13. Warwick...
near Longwood, officer down.
Two males, black hoodie,
both of them, one is...
Signal 13, Warwick, near Longwood,
in the alleys. Check the alleys...
Northside, 2800 block. Nothing.
We got an officer down,
she's a number one, female undercover.
Unit 833, bearing east
on 3100 block of Baker. Clear.
2900 is dark.
11-35, 10-38 is responding.
10-4.
11-71, does anyone have a visual?
Does anyone have a visual?
- Foxtrot.
- What are we looking for?
11-35 to KGA.
We can't find the officer down.
We need Foxtrot...
looking for a green Lincoln Town Car with a
brown vinyl roof, parked in those alleys.
Foxtrot en route, 3-1-4.
3-14, be advised, we have a signal 13.
7820, rear odd-side.
3300 block of Baker. Clear.
Visual, rear even-side
of Warwick and Longwood.
Signal 13, signal 13. Officer down.
SUV, west on Warwick, make the next right.
Be advised, no movement at scene.
In here. Call for a medic.
We got an officer down, we need a medic.
7820, 10-23, give us DV in here.
10-4.
Where the fuck is the medic?
Signal 13, we got an officer down.
10-38 is responding.
Do we have a description?
Any unit on scene?
Do you have a description of the suspect?
That's a 10-47.