[Lightning crashing]
[footsteps approaching]
Well, hello there, traveler.
I see your car broke down
on this lonesome country road,
a place so remote that no one
can hear your screams!
[Footsteps retreating]
Pretend I didn't say that.
Come in, come in, but be warned,
if you enter you may be
subjected to my tales.
Tales designed
to sell my merchandise!
[Evil laughter]
Sorry, I was thinking of
something funny I heard earlier.
[title music]
Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com
You've come to
the Mystery Shack after-hours,
a time when only our creepiest
and most cursed
objects are for sale,
like that thing there!
[Thunder cracking]
No, not a fan?
Too many orifices?
All right, I can tell
what you're looking for
is this disembodied hand.
Why is it so expensive?
Well, [chuckles]
that's quite a tale
and it's called Hands Off!
No, seriously, hands off,
that's not for sale.
All right.
Hands Off!
Swap meet!
Swap meet! Swap meet!
Look at all these
priceless treasures.
Bobbly-heads!
They agree with everything I say.
Professor glasses!
They make me look like a genius.
[Groans]
Look at these faux-gold beauties.
They're mob-boss quality.
All right, kids, prepare to watch
the delicate art of the deal.
Hey, hag-face! How much
for the junk watches?
They are not for sale.
Not for you, Stan Pines!
The wind whispers your
name! [Wind blowing]
[chimes tinkling]
Shh... Shush, you guys.
All right, I get it, you're creepy.
Anyway, less talky, more watchy!
Get your hands off my watch!
Ugh!
Yeesh! Freak show.
Wow, someone needs to work
on their social skills.
And their observation skills.
Boom!
Good job, heisting hands.
Mwah, mwah.
Grunkle Stan, are you seriously
shoplifting from a witch?
That sounded like a curse.
"That sounded like a curse!"
Hey, anyone want to buy a wet blanket?
We got a wet blanket for sale!
[laughter]
I can't survive in this market.
[Alarm beeping]
Ha, curse.
Yeah, right.
Ah!
Wait, is this curse ugly or normal ugly?
Looks like I got off scot-free.
[Screaming]
All right, kiddos, breakfast time.
Prepare your mouths for...
[Waddles oinking]
Whoa! Whoa-ah!
No hands!
Grunkle Stan, what
happened to your hands?
So I might have got cursed a little,
but the watch looks nice, right?
Foolish man, thieving
hands find wicked face!
You must return what isn't yours...
That's better.
I told you, Grunkle Stan,
you got to give that
watch back and apologize.
What? That old crone
should apologize to me
for denying my right to buy cheap junk.
I don't need hands,
I've got self respect.
Mabel, sweetie, will you
make your uncle some hands?
La-la-la.
Hands makeover!
Say hello to your
"new hands"! In quotes.
Nice work, kid.
See, hands are overrated.
I'm ready to take on the day!
Ma'am.
[Screams]
[groans]
Hey, Mr. Pines.
Should we play toss me a
dozen eggs like we always do?
No, Jimmy, wait!
Not today!
Let's find that witch.
MABEL: According to
the swap meet pamphlet,
the hand witch lives in
a horrible hand witch lair
- on Hand Witch Mountain.
- STAN: Stop saying hand witch!
Grunkle Stan, did you
just tap my shoulder?
Kid, I can't tap anything.
Guys, can you stop
tapping both my shoulders?
[Hands tapping]
[screaming]
Hands! Lots of hands!
Ah!
[Screaming]
[evil laughter]
Look at this touching scene.
Up top!
You guys, you guys get me.
All right, you horrible
wench, you got me.
Stealing is wrong, etcetera, take it.
Now can I have my hands back?
I have a certain gesture
I'd like to share with you.
Alas, your hands cannot
be gotten so easily.
The spirits say, um...
that the curse can only
be broken by a kiss!
ALL: What?
It's all right, kids.
Just look away.
A kiss on the lips!
What? Forget it! I'm not
kissing any of that mess.
I don't need my hands that bad.
Yeah, you're just making stuff up now.
- Let's go, kids.
- No, wait! Don't go!
You're right, you're right.
I was just making all that stuff up.
Just trying to get
something going, you know.
So hard to meet people these days.
[Snaps fingers]
So this was all just
a ploy to get a date?
I'm desperate, okay?
But every time I bring someone back here
without keeping their hands
hostage, they just run away!
Well, yeah, look at this horror show.
It's creepy even for a cave!
You just need to redecorate.
For example...
a handelabra!
Ooh, the hand witch likes.
Then watch me work.
Home makeover!
[Music]
Redecorate.
Redo you.
Change it around.
You got to do it to make it work.
Okay. Time to take a look
at your fantastic new cave.
[Gasps]
MABEL: Men will definitely
tolerate you now.
And I left a book of pickup
lines on the end table.
Blah! Oh, my goodness!
I can't believe this is the same cave!
Oh, my goodness!
I just can't find the words.
How about "Here's your hands back"?
Oh, right.
[Snaps fingers]
[tapping]
Shaky, Scratchy.
I've missed you old rascals.
You're all right, sister.
- Will you be my boyfriend now?
- No, never.
Well, I learned nothing.
[sighs]
Back to my crippling loneliness.
Hey, I'm lost in these mountains.
Could I crash here for the night?
Please, come in. Uh...
[clears throat]
"Girl, are those space pants?
Because your butt looks
out of this world."
- Wow. Thanks for noticing.
- Yes!
All right, I get it.
You don't want the hand,
you're a savvy customer.
But perhaps you'd be
interested in buying, um...
this magic pig.
Sure he doesn't look magic,
but there is a very interesting story
I'm about to make up about him,
and it's called Abaconings!
"The What-The-Heck-A-Hedron!
Solve this test of intelligence
and your photo could be on this box."
Whoa. That's false
advertising I can get behind.
[Buzzing]
Come on.
Ugh!
MABEL: Ooh, that's a bummer.
This is May May and The Hogg
coming at you on the AM.
[Oinks]
Whoa!
Not sure we can say that on the air.
Don't touch that dial, truckers,
'cause The Hogg just ate it.
[Honking, farts]
Mabel, could you knock it off?
I'm trying to solve
this intelligence puzzle,
but it seems impossible.
[Buzzing]
Maybe you're just not smart enough.
We'll see about that.
Buried near the falls is
the legendary percepshroom.
To increase brain power, grind it up
and apply to the forehead overnight.
Tomorrow, I own you!
[Snoring]
[sniffs]
[oinking]
Ha-ha!
I feel smarter already.
The digits of pi are 3.1...
Um...
415926 etcetera.
What? Who said that?
Mabel?
Whoa! Dipper, look.
Greetings, friends. It
is I, Waddles the pig.
- What?
- Waddles, what happened to you?
Have you been possessed
by the spirit of a nerd?
I understand my
transformation may be vexing,
but I have prepared a presentation.
Forgive me. My pig arms
are cute and useless.
The brain goop! You ate it
and built all this, didn't you?
This isn't right!
The pig goes oink. The pig goes oink!
Now the pig goes wherever he can shine
the light of knowledge into
the darkness of ignorance.
Whoa! What the
heck-a-hedron!
How did you do that?
I can teach you, Dipper. I
can teach you many things.
From the secrets of
astrophysics to the...
Hey, hey!
[oinking]
Man, I am loving this new Waddles.
Yeah, he's, uh, he's
definitely... different.
[Bleats]
Dude, that rocket cart is amazing!
You and me should go invent stuff.
Uh, Waddles, don't you
want to stay up here
and record some morning pranks with me?
Mabel, this pig's got a gift.
He needs to share it with the world.
I'm sorry, Mabel.
There is more to life
than making fart noises
and laughing at those fart noises.
I see that now.
[chuckling]
Yeah, you guys just go on without me.
[Sighs]
[farts]
Oh, my kite got stuck in a tree.
I hate everything!
I bet we could be of service.
Ah! An affront against nature!
Ha! Forget kites.
Here, take this rocket pack I invented
and explore the heavens yourself.
Forget that, Grenda is gonna look
at cute boys through skylights.
I rule the sky!
Dude, that rocket pack
we made was amazing.
Don't forget the laser
gun we made for Candy.
[lasers firing]
CANDY: That's to my enemies!
[laughter]
Welcome to May May and The Hogg AM.
Top story today,
coping with crippling loneliness
after losing my co-host.
♪ Loneliness! ♪
What did that nasty goop do to you?
You're not happier like this, are you?
[Crash]
Ha-ha. This is your
greatest invention yet.
It could solve every problem of mankind.
And bring me many potatoes,
delicious potatoes.
Yummy yummy for my fat little pig tummy.
What the heck is going on here?
Mabel, you are just in time to
behold our greatest achievement.
The smarticle accelerator!
Solving that brain puzzle was
just the tip of the iceberg.
With this, Waddles will be able to solve
all the greatest
puzzles of the universe.
The origin of life. The
meaning of existence.
Why dudes have nipples.
Soon your pig is gonna be world famous,
meeting with scientists, presidents.
I wonder if I can
teach him to wear pants.
The whole world?
But when will you have time
for us? I'm your best friend.
I'm still your friend, Mabel.
But I'm helping people now.
But what about helping me?
Do you really want to spend
your whole life in meetings
with dumb smart guys?
This brain junk has made
you forget who you are.
Don't you remember us?
♪ Remember those times ♪
♪ Don't forget to
remember those times ♪
♪ Just remember to
It all makes sense now.
What good is helping the world
if I can't help my favorite
person in the world?
It's a good thing I
built in a dum-dum switch.
Waddles! Waddles, don't! Wait!
I'm sorry, Dipper.
In my last eight seconds of
consciousness, I want you to know
that science is a horizon to search for,
not a prize to hold in your hand.
Also I miss getting my tummy tickled.
[oinking]
Oh, Waddles.
[Electrical crackling]
No! Our invention!
I know what will make you feel better.
A simple hug from a simple pig.
Yeah, guess so.
[Oinks]
[laughs]
Good pig. Ugh.
You know what? You're right.
Don't buy the pig.
In fact I'm better off
leaving it with my niece.
[Arrow twanging]
No shooting in the house, sweetie.
But perhaps I could interest
you in something else.
Like these spooky movies!
Movies are great.
You watch the movie, you scare the girl,
the girl snuggles up next to you.
Next thing you know, you got to
raise a kid, your life falls apart.
Forget that last part.
This next tale is called Clay Day!
GIRL: [on TV] You did
it, Shimmery Twinkleheart!
No, you did it, Cinnamon.
Because you believed in yourself.
Everything about this is bad.
Well, that just put me 90
minutes closer to death.
It's time you kids learn to
watch the classics from my day.
Ooh, old people movies.
Get ready for references
we don't understand
and words we can't repeat.
You're no match for Loinclothiclese.
I've come for the golden pants.
[roars]
[screaming]
Oh, no! Mabel!
Well, your sister is broken.
Oh, Grunkle Stan, I
should have told you before
that Mabel has a childhood terror
of old-timey
stop-motion animation.
It's like her number one
fear since we were kids.
[Chuckles] Come on, those hokey
old things, how scared could she be?
The Cyclops! His face
is made of nightmares!
Kid, it's just a movie.
It can't hurt you.
No talking.
They wait for you to talk and
then crawl inside your mouth!
Why did you have to show her that tape?
There's got to be a way
to get her over this!
Huh...
All right, if we can just
get the director to show her
the models are fake, maybe
she'll finally calm down.
I don't know, dude.
According to the internet,
special effects genius Harry
Claymore is some kind of recluse.
Man wants his privacy.
I can respect that.
Well, everyone over the fence.
You see, Mabel, those monsters
are just tiny clay figures
moved around one frame at a
time by an antisocial shut-in.
Those people are called animators.
Hello? [echoes]
Mr. Claymore?
We want to get a look at your figurines.
We're not paparazzi.
Aha!
See, Mabel, it's all
just special effects.
You can come out.
MABEL: No!
Kid, listen to me.
For the last time, there is
nothing here to be afraid of...
[roars]
[screaming]
[groans]
It's slowly...
swiping at us!
Let's escape by standing still!
Oh, it didn't work!
[Screaming]
Whoa!
[Screams]
[roars]
[screaming]
[groans]
How is this happening?
What do they want?
HARRY: I'm afraid they want you.
Harry Claymore, master of special
effects, circa 1970 something.
Alas, my effects are more
special than you know.
What? But how are these things real?
- What about stop motion?
- What?
Do you really believe someone
moves these figures one frame at a time?
I'm not a masochist.
I used black magic to make
them animate themselves.
It was great at first, but one day...
No!
Where's the heart?!
HARRY: Now that they were out of work,
they went mad and enslaved me!
And now they will turn you
into unholy beasts of clay
to join in their mischief!
Well, Mr. Pines, at least you'll finally
get to work with your favorite director.
And by work, I mean, suffocate
inside a big wad of clay.
DIPPER: Help!
- Somebody help us!
- Help!
Oh, what do I do?
How can I defeat those monstrosities?
Hey, I changed it into something I like.
Whoa. I think I have an idea!
Hey,
one-eyed-clops!
Yeah, I'm talking to you, dum-dum!
Come at me!
[Yells]
Ah!
Wipe that face off your face.
Oh, I've got big plans for you!
Hey, skeleton dorks!
It's "clayback" time!
Whoo-hoo-hoo.
Dude, you conquered your fear.
That's right. Because
she believed in herself.
Can it, Twinkleheart!
Just start pounding those skeletons!
Mabel, you did it!
So you're not scared anymore?
Oh, I'm scared twice as much
now, but now I know it's rational.
Kid, I'm sorry I doubted
you. You were right.
Stop motion is pure evil.
And probably really expensive.
Incredibly expensive.
This is an impressive fight though.
I'm glad I'm facing towards it.
ALL: Yay!
That was the best part.
Well, I think today we learned
that you can remold your fears.
I'm just glad none of
us got turned into clay.
Holy Toledo!
Who wants to see me
change into most anything?
[Humming]
I can walk through walls. Whoa!
We're safe now, kids. We're safe.
I don't get it.
You don't want the pig,
you don't want my tapes...
What are you gonna buy?!
How about this delicious potion?
Here, have a free sample.
You should have bought my merch
when you had the chance, buddy.
But that's OK.
I'll have some new for sale very soon...
[laughter]
And here we have our latest attraction:
The legendary Cheapskate!
I saw it blinking.
Ha! Just an optical illusion.
Come along, everyone.
Step right up!
[laughter]
That's right, I'm a jerk.
Hey! Wanna play
Tic-tac-toe?
Hey! I wanted to be X's!
Let me be X's.
Trust me, just let her be X's.
[sighs]
Yay!
Actually, I'm sorry.
I changed my mind.
I'll be O's.
OK, you're gonna hate me right now...
but is X's still a possibility?
I don't think you're
playing this right...
Sync & corrections by XhmikosR
www.addic7ed.com