sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[snoring]
Ahh!
Morning, Dipper.
Guess who.
Oh, what joy.
If it isn't Mr. Upsidedownington.
How long has it been?
Third grade maybe?
That's right, and I'm
here to deliver you
an Upsidedownington-tastic message!
Is it the message that
we're getting too old
- for this sort of thing?
- Um, kinda, actually.
It's that we're exactly one
week away from our 13th birthday!
Whoa! Our birthday's
coming up already? [gasps]
Soon we're gonna be actual teenagers!
Finally I can stop
reading pre-teen magazines,
and start reading
post-pre-teen magazines.
PG-13 movies, here I come.
And just one more
year until high school.
High school, Dipper!
Where girls become women,
and they teach us stuff about...
- you know what.
- Trigonometry?
- Oh, yeah, baby.
- That's not the only good news coming up.
In one week, my senior citizen
ponytail kit is coming in the mail.
_
I'm... I'm kinda going
through some things.
In one week, my grandma
is finally letting me
eat crackers on my bed.
The future is coming for us all, dudes.
- The future.
The future!
[chuckles]
I'm sorry, I can't take you seriously
- with that face on your chin.
- [goofy voice] What face, Dipper?
You're doing the voice, so you
obviously know what I'm talking about.
[goofy voice] I don't know
what you're talking about.
[both laughing]
There is something wrong with you.
MABEL: There's something
wrong with both of us.
[title music]
2x17 - Dipper and Mabel vs The Future
Alright, party planners!
In one week, we become teenagers,
and summer vacation winds to an end,
so we need to throw the
greatest party of all time!
I'm talkin' piñatas with
tinier piñatas inside.
Boom, dreams comin' true.
I'm talkin' inviting
everyone in town! Let's see.
Where do we stand with the gnomes?
Not so fast, goofus and girl goofus.
After that zombie incident,
no one's throwing
another party at my house.
I keep finding little bits of
the undead in the couch cushions.
But Grunkle Stan, we
need some roof to raise.
Dude, you can rent out the
Gravity Falls high school gym,
and have your party there.
That place is empty all summer long.
The gym's a great idea, Soos.
To the high school!
[loud crash]
FORD: Dipper, my face is on fire!
I'll just be a sec.
- Hey, Uncle Ford, are you okay?
- Oh, yes, I'm fine.
I just said that to make
sure you'd come in here quickly.
- But your face is on fire.
- Yes. It's much faster than shaving.
Now listen, Dipper.
I have a very important
mission, and you are
the only one who can help me.
Remember the rift in dimensional
space-time I showed you?
It's cracking.
This is what Bill has been waiting for.
If it breaks, it'll cause
reality as we know it
to become completely unraveled.
A hypothetical and catastrophic event
I call Weirdmageddon.
Bill is out there,
and he'd use any trick
from deception to outright possession
to make this happen.
But for the sake of
humanity, we mustn't let him.
- What do we do?
- We patch the rift.
I'll explain on the way.
- Wait. What about Mabel?
- It's okay, Dipper.
You should totally go with Grunkle Ford
to save the world or whatever.
- Are you sure?
- We're gonna be doing birthday junk all week.
Plus, I packed those walkie-talkies.
Here's one for my party mission,
and one for your smarty mission.
[laughing]
Ahem. I did mention that
the fate of the universe
is at stake, didn't I?
Hurry! We haven't much time!
Okay, Dipper, it's your
first big mission with Ford,
a chance to prove yourself.
Don't mess this up.
Ow! Ah. [chuckles]
I'm all right.
Aah!
[crashing]
_
Whoa, Soos, I thought you
said this place was empty.
- My dogs, what up?
- Wendy, what are you doing here?
Ugh. High school registration.
Oh! You know, I'm only a year
away from high school myself.
Would you say your experience
is more rom-com or wacky romp?
More like teen horror movie.
High school is the worst.
Classes get super hard,
your body just flat-out turns
against you, and worst of
all, everybody hates you.
Can't do it. Can't do another year!
My hormones are like a sweaty cage.
Why aren't they singing
about following their dreams?
TV taught me that high school
is like some sort of musical.
TV lied, man.
If you can avoid growing up, do it.
I'd give anything to be 12 again.
Anyway, what are you guys doing here?
[nervous chuckle]
Just looking for a place
to have my 13th birthday party.
Wendy Borduroy?
I-I mean Corduroy.
[laughter]
Corduroy.
See what I mean?
Master Mabel to Dippity
Dog. We can have our party
at the gym, but we gotta
talk about high school.
I'm starting to think it's might not be
the awesome future we
were expecting. Over.
[static]
I'm going through a bad patch, Mabel.
We'll talk when I get back...
[static]
Dipper? Come in, come in?
Hey, I know what will
make you feel better.
Let's deliver some invites
to your friends, huh?
Yeah!
_
[static]
Mabel? Mabel, you there?
[frustrated groan]
Listen, Dipper, in order
to seal the rift for good,
it's going to take an adhesive
stronger than anything on Earth.
- Something... extraterrestrial in origin.
- W-What do you mean?
Tipper, look at the peculiar shape
made by those cliffs.
Does it remind you of anything?
Hmm...
Shut... up!
According to my research,
the entire valley
of Gravity Valley was formed
when an extraterrestrial object
crash landed here millions of years ago.
FORD: Did this craft cause
the town's strange properties?
Or, did the town's strange
properties attract the craft?
- The answer is still unknown.
- But that's crazy!
Where did the saucer go?
Sometimes, the strangest
things in the world
are right under our noses.
And our feet, in this
particular instance.
Now, you might want to stand back.
This magnet gun could rip the fillings
out of a man's mouth
- from a hundred feet.
- Aah.
I used to raid this
thing for parts for years.
FORD: Where do you think I got
the materials to build my portal?
You... I... words, not
working from mouth.
- Now, come. And take this.
- Whoa, Whoa!
Don't worry, I've been
down here countless times.
All the aliens have been
dead for millions of years.
Probably.
I can't believe there's been a giant UFO
under the town this whole time.
I wish my mind could be where
yours is right now, Tipper.
When confirmation of extraterrestrials
still had that punch.
Now it's just sort of, meh.
McGucket and I used to
come down here all the time
to raid their tech ad
study their language.
This is so cool!
[laughs]
The substance we need to seal
the rift is an alien adhesive,
strong enough to keep the
hull of a spacecraft together.
Just one dollop of this adhesive
should be enough to seal
a crack in space-time.
Also, if it touches you, it will seal up
all the orifices in your face,
so try so avoid that.
Now, use your magnet gun
and follow me!
- Hup.
- Great Uncle Ford!
Your turn!
Say "hup". It helps!
[deep breath] Okay, just put on
magnet, leap down hole.
Turn on. Come on already!
[powering up]
Magnet!
Hunh!
Aah!
A little help?
Oh, hi, Mabel.
You're just in time for
our one o'clock boy talk.
If you think that's good, boom!
Me and Dipper's 13th birthday jam!
Oh, man, your birthday's
on the last day of Summer.
- I'm not gonna be here.
- What?
Marius is flying me out to Austria
to hang out his castle
or whatever that week.
He's co clingy!
You're gonna be out of
town for my birthday?
But at least you can come, right, Candy?
Sorry, Mabel, my parents
send me to music camp
this time of year.
There is no escape from music camp.
So neither of you are gonna
be at my birthday party?
And you won't be able
to wish me good-bye
at the end of the Summer?
- CANDY: I'm sorry, Mabel.
- Summer happens so fast.
[cell phone ringing]
Ugh, Marius, now's not the time!
I think I need to radio
for emotional backup.
Dipper, please come in.
Our party mission is
going down in flames.
Over. [static]
Oh...
This is their storage facility.
This place would have
been heavily guarded,
but now everything's defunct.
Go ahead, flip any switch.
They've all been busted
for millions of years.
Clara, did you eat my farm?
[mooing]
FORD: The glue should
be around here somewhere,
so keep your eyes peeled.
Dipper, let me ask you something.
- Have you thought much about your future?
- No, not really.
I mean, beyond graduating
high school with a high GPA
so I can get accepted to
a good technical college
with a photography and
media production minor
to start my own ghost hunting show.
[chuckles]
It's like talking to a
younger version of myself.
If you're so sure of
what you want out of life,
why wait? Why put up with
the drudgery of school?
Huh, trust me, I'd love to fast
forward the whole thing, but
it's not like I have a choice.
Dipper, I've been thinking.
I'm getting too old to investigate
Gravity Falls on my own.
I need to train an apprentice
to help me fight monsters,
solve mysteries, and protect this town.
And I think I'd like
to keep it in the family.
- What are you saying?
- I've read your additions to my journal,
and I'm impressed with your potential.
What would you say to
staying in Gravity Falls
after the Summer ends and
becoming my apprentice?
- W-What about school?
- Dipper, I have 12 PhDs. Your parents
would be thrilled I could give
you such an advanced education.
[sighs] There's also Mabel.
She'd be all alone in California.
Mabel will be fine on her own.
She has a magnetic personality.
I watched her become pen pals
with the pizza delivery man
in the 60 seconds he was at the door.
Gosh, we've never
really been apart before.
And isn't it suffocating?
Dipper, can you honestly tell me
you never felt like you were
meant for something more?
I hav... I don't know.
Sounds like a dream come true,
but I'm not sure I have what it takes.
I was tricked by Bill,
I was wrong about Stan's portal.
Heck, I can't even operate
this magnet gun right.
[straining]
Ha! Yes!
Dipper, you found the adhesive!
- I did?
- Oh-ho, you really did it, kid.
Huddle in, let's get a picture of this.
[alien noise]
Uh, Uncle Ford, you said
everything down here is dead, right?
Yes, unless somehow
we reactivated the...
[gasps] security system.
- What do we do?
- Listen to me very carefully.
I've studied these.
They're security droids,
and they detect adrenaline.
You simply have to not feel any fear,
- and they won't see you.
- What?
It's okay.
I've done it before.
Just take a deep breath,
focus on your intellect,
and control your fear.
Wh-Wh-What?
That's crazy! I...
Follow my lead!
- Great Uncle Ford...
- Focus, Dipper!
[heartbeat]
I, uh...
I-I-
- I can't.
- Get down!
- Aah! No! Nooooo...
- Wait! No!
Stay back! It's too dangerous.
Sealing the rift is
what's important now.
Take this! You're gonna
have to do it without me.
Use the adhesive.
Fix the rift!
Save the universe, Dipper.
Great Uncle Ford!
Hang on, I'm coming for you!
Don't worry, I'll get you out of there!
Where's that thing taking you?
FORD: It's an automated prison droid.
And wherever it's going,
I'm not coming back.
What?
[gasps]
No, no, no.
Don't worry, I'll think of something!
Dipper, what on earth are you doing?
[powering up]
Hold on, Great Uncle Ford.
I'm getting you out of
this one way or another.
[click, powering down]
Oh, no...
[fizzling]
[beeping, buzzer blares]
Come on, come on!
Aah...
Let go of my uncle!
Ohh. Aah!
Aah...
- Oh, no.
- Aah!
[crying out]
Great Uncle Ford!
Okay, let's try magna-pulse.
[groaning]
Huh?
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no!
Come on, wake up, man.
We gotta get out of here before...
Hey, I'm warning you!
I have a magnet gun!
Oh, yeah?
You think you can scare me?
Do your worst!
Nothing in this universe
is gonna take away my uncle.
So go ahead, give me what you got.
[panting]
[Ford laughing, coughing]
I thought I was a goner, kid.
Are you all right? What happened?
The orb didn't detect any
chemical signs of fear.
It assumed the threat was neutralized
and then self-disassembled.
[chuckles]
I... I did it?
You did it.
This is what I was talking about.
How many other
12-year-olds do you think
are capable of doing
what you've just done?
[sighs]
Hey, everything all right, pumpkin?
I just can't believe
the Summer's almost over.
And now that I know how
awful high school's gonna be,
I'm in no hurry to
start that train wreck.
Ah. Nobody likes getting older.
But just because you're growing up
doesn't mean you have
to grow up, you know?
I mean, look at me.
I'm pushing 70,
and I still eat ice cream for dinner.
But I don't wanna say
good-bye to Gravity Falls.
Hey, at least whatever
happens after this Summer,
you'll still have your
brother along with you
through thick and thin.
Not everyone can say that, you know.
Yeah. At least when I go home
I always have Dipper.
Good old reliable old...
[radio static]
DIPPER: Are you okay?
Let's get you out of there.
Listen to me, Dipper,
this town is a magnet
for things that are special.
And that includes you and me.
It brought both of
us here for a purpose.
Stay here with me, Dipper.
Become my apprentice.
Don't let anyone hold you...
[coughing]
- I'll do it. I'm gonna stay.
- Excellent.
Now, who wants to save
the world, apprentice?
[both laughing]
[radio static]
Mabel, I just had the
best day of my life.
UFOs are real, and
there's one under the town,
and I saved Great
Uncle Ford's life and...
Hey, are you okay?
Tell me it's not true, Dipper.
Tell me you were joking.
[radio static, gasps]
MABEL: Ford's apprentice?
Seriously?
Look, I was thinking, and this is
a huge opportunity for me.
Well, it's a horrible
opportunity for me!
I had the worst day of my life.
When we turn 13, the Summer ends,
and I have to leave everything behind.
You're the only person I could count on,
and now you're leaving me, too?
Look, I've been thinking about it.
I won't be gone forever, okay?
I'll still visit you at home
and we'll chat online...
we'll make it work.
I don't want it to work.
I just wish Summer could last forever.
But it can't, Mabel.
Look, things aren't gonna
stay frozen this way.
It's part of growing up.
Things change.
Summer ends.
- Ugh!
- Unh!
Mabel, wait!
I didn't mean it like that!
Mabel, come back!
[music]
Only party chocolate
can cheer me up now.
Nerd bucks?
Chewed up pens?
Ugh, wrong backpack.
It's not fair.
I just wish Summer could last forever.
MAN: That might be possible.
Sweater Town is not accepting
incoming calls right now.
M-M-Mabel, it's me.
What? Who said that?
- I-I can help.
- The time travel guy?
What are you doing here?
You said you don't want
Summer to end, right?
- Did I hear that right?
- Yeah.
Why are you asking?
Look, maybe it's against
the rules, but you once did
a favor for me, so I
thought I could help you out.
It's called a time bubble,
and it prevents time from going forward.
Summer in Gravity Falls can
last as long as you want it to.
Really?
But how does it work.
I just need you to get a little
gizmo for me from your uncle.
Something small... he won't
even know it's missing.
Huh, maybe Dipper has something
like that in his nerd bag.
Let me guess.
Mabel didn't take it well?
I... I don't know.
Maybe I'm making the wrong decision.
- I need to think about this.
- Dipper, right now we need t
o focus on the mission.
Now, come on. I've got the glue.
Hand me the rift and let's make history.
What?
Oh, no, the rift!
Huh. That's odd.
- Is this it?
- Yes, that's it!
Just hand it over and I'll do my thing.
Unless you're ready
to leave Gravity Falls.
Just a little more Summer.
- Oops!
- What?
[maniacal laughter]
Oh, no! Wait, wait, wait!
[snap]
Oh...
[maniacal laughter]
At last. At long, long last!
The gate between worlds is open!
The event one billion years
prophesized has come to pass!
The day has come.
The world is finally mine!
[wind whistling]
[maniacal laughter]
[all gasping]
What's going on?
What is that?!
We're too late.
It's the end of the world.
[maniacal laughter]
[wind whistling]
[car alarm blaring]
[cracking]
[people screaming]
[helicopter passing overhead]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~