ANNOUNCER: MAJOR SUPPORT
FOR "THE VIETNAM WAR"
WAS PROVIDED BY MEMBERS OF
THE BETTER ANGELS SOCIETY,
INCLUDING JONATHAN AND JEANNIE LAVINE,
DIANE AND HAL BRIERLEY,
AMY AND DAVID ABRAMS,
JOHN AND CATHERINE DEBS,
THE FULLERTON FAMILY CHARITABLE FUND,
THE MONTRONE FAMILY,
LYNDA AND STEWART RESNICK,
THE PERRY AND DONNA
GOLKIN FAMILY FOUNDATION,
THE LYNCH FOUNDATION,
THE ROGER AND ROSEMARY ENRICO FOUNDATION,
AND BY THESE ADDITIONAL FUNDERS.
MAJOR FUNDING WAS ALSO PROVIDED
BY DAVID H. KOCH...
THE BLAVATNIK FAMILY FOUNDATION...
THE PARK FOUNDATION,
THE NATIONAL ENDOWMENT FOR THE HUMANITIES,
THE PEW CHARITABLE TRUSTS,
THE JOHN S. AND JAMES L. KNIGHT FOUNDATION,
THE ANDREW W. MELLON FOUNDATION,
THE ARTHUR VINING DAVIS FOUNDATIONS,
THE FORD FOUNDATION JUSTFILMS,
BY THE CORPORATION
FOR PUBLIC BROADCASTING,
AND BY VIEWERS LIKE YOU.
THANK YOU.
ANNOUNCER: BANK OF AMERICA PROUDLY SUPPORTS
KEN BURNS' AND LYNN NOVICK'S
FILM "THE VIETNAM WAR"
BECAUSE FOSTERING DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVES
AND CIVIL DISCOURSE AROUND IMPORTANT ISSUES
FURTHERS PROGRESS, EQUALITY,
AND A MORE CONNECTED SOCIETY.
GO TO BANKOFAMERICA.COM/
BETTERCONNECTED TO LEARN MORE.
(people cheering, turkeys gobbling)
("Blues Run the Game" by
Simon and Garfunkel playing)
♪ Catch a boat to England,
baby, maybe to Spain ♪
♪ Wherever I have gone
♪ Wherever I've been and gone
♪ Wherever I have gone the
blues run the game. ♪
TIM O'BRIEN: I grew up in
a small farming community
in southern Minnesota called Worthington.
Small town America... at
least my small town...
had great virtues.
It was a safe place to grow up.
There was Little League
baseball in the summer,
and there was hockey in the winter.
SIMON AND GARFUNKEL: ♪ When I ain't
drinkin', baby, you are on my mind. ♪
O'BRIEN: Everybody knows everyone
else's business and their faults
and what's happening in their marriages
and where the kids have gone wrong.
It was full of the Kiwanis
boys and the Elks Club
and the country club set and
the kind of chatty housewives
and the holier-than-thou ministers.
SIMON AND GARFUNKEL: ♪ Wherever
I've been and gone... ♪
O'BRIEN: I remember the day
my draft notice arrived.
It was a summer afternoon,
maybe June of '68.
And I remember taking that
envelope into the house
and putting it on the kitchen table
where my mom and dad were having lunch.
And they didn't even read it.
They just looked at it
and knew what it was.
And the silence of that lunch...
I didn't speak, my mom didn't
speak, my dad didn't speak...
was just that piece of paper
lying at the center of the table.
It was enough to make me cry
to this day, not for myself,
but for my mom and dad,
who both of them had been in
the Navy during World War II,
had believed in service to one's
country and all those values.
HOWARD TUCKNER: ...considers all
civilians potential enemies...
O'BRIEN: On the one hand I did think
the war was less than righteous.
On the other hand I love my country.
And I valued my life in a small
town and my friends and family.
And so the summer of '68, I
wrestled with what to do,
was for me, at least, more torturous
and devastating and emotionally painful
than anything that happened in Vietnam.
In the end I just capitulated.
And one day I got on a bus
with other recent graduates,
and we went over to Sioux
Falls about 60 miles away,
and raised our hands and got in the Army.
But it wasn't a decision, it was
a forfeiture of a decision.
It was letting my body go,
turning a switch in my conscience,
just turning it off,
so it wouldn't be barking at me saying,
"You're doing a bad and evil and
stupid and unpatriotic thing."
Last week's casualty figures in
the Vietnam War released today
showed 299 Americans killed, the
lowest figure in two months.
("Revolution 1" by the Beatles playing)
(music continues, crowd shouting)
♪ You say you want a revolution ♪
♪ Well, you know
♪ We all want to change the world ♪
♪ You tell me that it's evolution ♪
♪ Well, you know
♪ We all want to change the world ♪
♪ But when you talk about destruction ♪
♪ Don't you know that you
can count me out, in ♪
♪ Don't you know it's
gonna be all right ♪
NARRATOR: By June of 1968,
the spirit of revolution...
over the Vietnam War, over
injustice, over human rights...
seemed to have spread everywhere.
The pressure to bring an end
to the war was building.
President Lyndon Johnson
had already decided
not to run again,
assassinations and unrest
had staggered the nation,
and the country was preparing
to choose a new president.
Meanwhile, American and North
Vietnamese diplomats in Paris
were getting nowhere.
The communists insisted there could be
no substantive negotiations
until the United States stopped
all bombing of North Vietnam.
LENNON: ♪ With minds that hate...
NARRATOR: The new secretary
of defense, Clark Clifford,
who had turned from hawk to dove
after just a few months in office,
begged the president to call a total halt.
"We can only hope for success
at the bargaining table,"
he told Johnson.
"We are in a war we cannot win."
The president refused to stop the bombing.
Over the following months,
there would be reports of
progress on the battlefield
and in the countryside.
But that progress came so
slowly and at so high a cost
in human lives that the war against the war
intensified back home,
pitting classes and generations
against one another,
spreading distrust of political
leaders who seemed unable
or unwilling to bring
the fighting to an end.
Young men from all over the
country would continue
to face questions and choices
their fathers and grandfathers
had rarely had to face
when asked to fight in other wars:
What obligation did a
citizen owe his country?
What should one do when
asked to fight a war
in which one did not believe?
How was a soldier to distinguish
between a shadowy enemy
and the Vietnamese civilians he
was supposed to be defending?
LENNON: ♪ Shoo-bee-do-wop
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh.
NARRATOR: The coming summer of 1968
would be one of the most consequential
in American history.
LENNON: ♪ All right, all right,
all right, all right, all right ♪
♪ All right, all right
♪ Shoo-bee-do-wop
(song fades out)
Earlier this year, top U.S. leaders vowed
that the U.S. Marine outpost at Khe Sanh,
then under a 77-day enemy siege,
would be defended at all cost.
(jet engine roars)
(explosion)
MAX CLELAND: Johnson had
said in the fall of '67,
and as we went into '68,
"I don't want no damn Dien Bien Phu."
So the whole American military,
from the Joint Chiefs on down,
whether they believed in
saving Khe Sanh or not,
were hell-bent for leather
to make damn sure
the siege was broken.
Now the telltale moment
of that is that a week
after the siege was broken,
they plowed the base
under and abandoned it.
That was Vietnam in a microcosm.
(helicopter blades whirring)
NARRATOR: There was a new
commander in Vietnam now,
General Creighton W. Abrams,
a hero of World War II,
a soldier's soldier, one reporter said,
who "could inspire
aggressiveness in a begonia."
LEWIS SORLEY: Some newsman
once described him
as looking like an unmade
bed smoking a cigar.
He's gruff.
He drank a lot.
He's grumpy in the morning.
Sometimes staff officers would
schedule appointments with him
in the morning
for, with generals who
were causing him trouble.
NARRATOR: Abrams was a welcome
new face for the American war.
Reporters found him more frank
and open than his predecessor.
"The overall public affairs
policy of this command,"
he told his subordinates,
"will be to let results
speak for themselves."
"Occasionally," one officer
said, "we are allowed
to state frankly that we didn't
do a damn thing this month."
Many soldiers would believe
for the rest of their lives
that if Abrams had taken command sooner,
the outcome could have been different.
VINCENT OKAMOTO: You're
told very succinctly,
"We need to rack up as
much body count as we can.
How many gooks did you kill today?"
And it was the kill ratio that determined
whether or not you called
it a victory or a loss.
So if you killed 20 North Vietnamese
and lost only two people,
they declared a great victory
for that particular firefight.
NARRATOR: Lieutenant Vincent Okamoto
was born during World War II
in a Japanese-American internment camp
at Poston, Arizona, the seventh
son of Japanese immigrants.
All six of his brothers
had served in uniform...
two fought with the celebrated
442nd Regimental Combat Team
in Italy and France,
the most highly decorated
unit of that war...
and so, when Okamoto's country
went to war in Vietnam,
he believed he should go, too.
He was now a platoon leader with
Bravo Company, 2nd Battalion,
27th Regiment, 25th Infantry
Division, based at Cu Chi,
some 20 miles northwest of
Saigon, an area honeycombed
with miles of Viet Cong tunnels.
OKAMOTO: My parents are
Japanese immigrants.
I had rice literally every day of my life
until I went into the military.
So we were conducting a cordon
and search of a village.
Didn't find any weapons,
didn't find any communist
literature or whatever.
So we took a prolonged lunch break.
Everybody wants to get out of the sun.
Well, my RTO, my medic and I
went into this particular
house, and there was...
there were three women, and a babe in arms,
and a kid about four years old.
And she was cooking... rice.
Well, here, here's Okamoto, Mrs.
Okamoto's son,
that hadn't had rice now... hot,
steamed rice... for months.
I'm looking at it, it
looks pretty good to me.
So I-I get my interpreter.
I said, "Hey, tell this woman, the grandma,
"that I'll give her a pack of cigarettes,
"my C-ration turkey loaf,
and a can of peaches
for some of that steamed rice
and that fish and vegetables."
It was great.
And I asked for seconds.
My RTO says, "Damn, ain't
these people poor enough
without you eating their food?"
I said, "You know, hell,
they got enough rice here
to feed a dozen men."
And then, it just dawned,
they did have enough rice
to feed a dozen men.
So I had my interpreter ask the woman,
"Who's all this rice for?"
(speaking Vietnamese)
"I don't know, I don't know."
So we started looking around again.
We found a tunnel mouth.
I was given a grenade.
After the smoke cleared,
we pulled, I think,
seven or eight bodies to the town square.
And we wanted to see who
would cry over these people.
And then we'd have more people to question.
The women that lived in that house,
and I had eaten their rice,
they're all squatting down, wailing.
And you couldn't identify these, these...
they're just charred bodies.
Um...
And I think that was the first time I knew
that I personally had killed people.
I got an "Attaboy" from the supervisor.
But, uh...
it wasn't something that you
can say had glory in it,
or you felt a real sense of accomplishment.
NARRATOR: Over that summer,
Okamoto was wounded two times
and made 22 helicopter assaults,
four of them as commander of Bravo Company.
On the morning of August 23,
he made his 23rd assault.
Nineteen helicopters ferried
the first and second platoons
to a new landing zone near Cambodia.
Their task was to dig in, stay put,
and somehow block a battalion
of North Vietnamese troops,
who were trying to escape
across the border.
Okamoto's unit was reinforced by a platoon
of mechanized infantry,
three APCs, and a tank,
but they were still badly outnumbered.
He and the fewer than 150
men under his command
spent the rest of that
day and all of the next
preparing as best they could for an attack,
setting Claymore mines
and hanging three coils of razor wire.
OKAMOTO: August the 24th,
about 10:00 that night,
we got hit with a very
heavy mortar barrage.
(shouting, explosions)
Within the first I would say ten seconds,
all three of those armored
personnel carriers and tanks
were knocked out with
rocket-propelled grenades.
NARRATOR: Trip flares briefly
lit up the landscape.
Scores of enemy troops were running at them
through the elephant grass.
(gunfire)
VC mortar shells blasted two
gaps in the razor wire.
If Okamoto and his outnumbered
men couldn't plug them,
they were sure to be overrun.
He and the four men closest
to him held their M-16s
above their heads and fired blindly.
The enemy kept coming.
OKAMOTO: I had my four people.
And through the light
of the flares, I said,
"A couple you guys go and
man the machine guns
out on those APCs."
Well, the response I got was, like, uh...
"Fuck you, I ain't going up there."
So I ran to the first armored
personnel carrier, and I...
pulled the, the gunner
out of the turret, dead.
I jumped in there, manned the machine gun,
and fired until it ran out of ammo.
NARRATOR: Okamoto moved to
the second disabled APC
and then the third, emptying their guns.
OKAMOTO: And they were still coming at us.
So I crawled out there, till I
was about ten meters from 'em.
And I killed 'em with hand grenades.
NARRATOR: Two enemy grenades fell near him
and he managed to throw both back.
But a third landed just beyond his reach.
Shrapnel fragments peppered
his legs and back.
OKAMOTO: I just knew for
sure I was going to die.
"Okamoto, you're not going
to make it out of here.
"Mom's going to take it hard,
but, you know, you're not going
to make it out of here."
And that's liberating.
When you know you're going
to die, you don't...
the fear leaves.
At least in my case, I
was no longer afraid.
I was just mad because here
are all these little guys
trying to kill my ass.
And if that's the case,
then I'm going to make it as
tough on them as I possibly can
before I go down.
I killed a lot of brave men that night.
And I rationalized that by telling myself,
"Well, maybe what you did... just maybe...
saved the lives of a
couple of your people."
NARRATOR: During the night, the
enemy had slipped into Cambodia,
dragging as many of their
dead with them as they could.
A third of Okamoto's company had been lost.
("The Lord Is in This Place" by
Fairport Convention playing)
For his efforts that day,
Vincent Okamoto received the
Distinguished Service Cross,
the Army's second highest honor.
Before his tour of duty ended,
he would become the most highly
decorated Japanese-American
to survive the Vietnam War.
OKAMOTO: You know what?
(sighs)
The real heroes are the men that died.
19-, 20-year-old high school dropouts.
They didn't have escape
routes that the elite
and the wealthy and the privileged had.
And that was unfair.
And so they looked upon
military service as...
(sighs)
...like the weather.
You had to go in, and you'd do it.
But to see these kids, who
had the least to gain,
there wasn't anything to look forward to;
they weren't going to be rewarded
for their service in Vietnam.
And yet their infinite patience,
their loyalty to each other,
their courage under fire
was just phenomenal.
And you would ask yourself,
"How does America produce
young men like this?"
HUY DUC:
NARRATOR: At first, Radio Hanoi
had portrayed the Tet Offensive
as a series of "tremendous victories"
in which "hundreds of thousands
of people have risen up
and destroyed enemy positions."
"But after a couple of weeks,"
one North Vietnamese remembered,
"we didn't hear any more news.
"The Saigon regime was still there
"and the U.S. planes were still bombing.
It was obvious the radio
wasn't telling the truth."
Casualty figures were never revealed,
but to North Vietnamese citizens
secretly listening to reports
on the BBC and Radio Saigon,
it was clear that they had been heavy.
PHAM LUC:
HUY DUC:
NARRATOR: In late August 1968, Le Duan
and the North Vietnamese leadership
launched still another offensive.
The result was the same
as Tet and Mini-Tet.
They lost 17,000 more men.
Thousands of fresh recruits
had to be ordered south
to replace them.
"The war began to seem like an open pit,"
one North Vietnamese remembered.
"The more young people were lost
there, the more they sent."
The sons of some party officials
and their friends were sent
abroad to escape the draft.
University students were exempted.
People with money bribed recruiters
to overlook their offspring
or paid physicians to declare
them unfit to serve.
HUY DUC:
NARRATOR: Most draftees were poor
people from the countryside,
especially receptive to the slogans
and promises of the revolution.
Thousands of replacements made their way
down the Ho Chi Minh Trail
past burned-out vehicles
and military graveyards,
the stones neatly marked
with the names of the dead
and the date each had died.
They encountered small
groups of wounded men
moving in the other direction.
Those without arms walked.
Legless men rode in camouflaged trucks.
There were blinded soldiers
and others who had been
hideously burned by napalm.
"You'll see all kinds of
pleasures in the South,"
the weary wounded told the young
men moving toward the war.
"Everyone was frightened," a
political officer remembered,
"especially when we met those men.
It was like looking at our future selves."
The youngest delegate of
the New Jersey delegation
casts his vote for the next
president of the United States,
Richard Nixon.
We've got 18.
David, we doubled it, 18.
NARRATOR: Richard Nixon
had been a prominent
and controversial figure
in American politics
for more than two decades.
He'd been a congressman and senator,
best known for his fierce anticommunism,
then served eight years
as Dwight Eisenhower's vice president.
He narrowly lost the presidential race
to John Kennedy in 1960
and was defeated again two years later
trying to become governor of California.
His career seemed to be over.
But then, in one of the most
extraordinary comebacks
in U.S. political history,
he had outsmarted and out-maneuvered
and out-campaigned his rivals
to win the 1968 Republican nomination.
MAN: Richard M. Nixon...
(cheering and applause)
His pick for vice president
was the tough-talking
but largely unknown governor
of Maryland, Spiro Agnew.
Nixon made the case for himself
as the man who could bring a
fractured America together
and bring an honorable end to the war.
When the strongest nation in
the world can be tied down
for four years in a war in
Vietnam with no end in sight;
when the richest nation
in the world can't manage
its own economy;
when the nation with the greatest tradition
of the rule of law is plagued
by unprecedented lawlessness;
when a nation that has
been known for a century
for equality of opportunity
is torn by unprecedented racial violence;
and when the president of the United States
cannot travel abroad or
to any major city at home
without fear of a hostile demonstration,
then it's time for new leadership
for the United States of America.
(cheering)
Good evening from Chicago,
where the 35th National
Democratic Convention
opens tomorrow with the promise
of turmoil inside this hall
and a threat of violence without.
JOHN LAURENCE: Both sides moved in
their troops on a balmy Sunday morning
for the confrontation of Chicago.
Some 6,000 crack Army troops,
riot trained and ready for action...
The Army soldiers moved out to
secret locations around the city
after one of the largest troop
movements in domestic history.
NARRATOR: Some 15,000 protestors
had gathered in Chicago,
most to register their
anguish over the war...
Some bent on disrupting the convention.
Richard J. Daley, the
Democratic mayor of Chicago,
was determined that there
be no trouble in his city.
Twelve thousand Chicago
policemen were on alert.
In addition to the 6,000 U.S. Army troops,
there were 6,000 more
armed National Guardsmen
and a thousand intelligence
agents from the FBI,
the CIA, and the military.
Mayor Daley cordoned off
the Chicago Amphitheater
where the convention was being held
and denied the protestors permits to march
or to sleep in the city's parks.
INTERVIEWER: Are you planning
to go without the permit
if you don't get the permit?
RENNIE DAVIS: Given the fact
that for many months we
have notified this city
and this nation that we wish
to hold a demonstration,
an assembly in Chicago
to register our convictions about the war,
the tens of thousands of people
coming to the city of Chicago
constitute a permit.
Our fight is with the militarism
that is developing in this country
in the response to legitimate
political and social grievances
by bringing in troops
rather than dealing with the
real issues and real problems.
CRONKITE: In the name of
security, freedom of the press,
freedom of movement, perhaps as far
as the demonstrators
themselves are concerned,
even freedom of speech have
been severely restricted here.
A democratic convention is about
to begin in a police state.
There just doesn't seem to
be any other way to say it.
JOHN BAILEY: Will the
delegates please be seated.
NARRATOR: Vice President Hubert Humphrey,
President Johnson's chosen
successor, was the frontrunner.
He had always been a hero to
his party's liberal wing,
but because he had loyally
supported the president
and the war, many delegates,
and most of the demonstrators
outside the convention hall,
backed his antiwar rival,
Senator Eugene McCarthy.
(muffled shouting on megaphone)
On the second night of the convention,
the police drove hundreds of demonstrators
out of Lincoln Park with
clubs and tear gas.
(sirens wailing)
JOHN CHANCELLOR: The delegates wearing
bands of black crepe on their arms...
NARRATOR: The next afternoon,
the Democrats heatedly debated
a plank in the party platform
calling for an end to the war.
When Humphrey supporters voted it down,
the antiwar delegates erupted.
CHANCELLOR: ...who have joined New York
in this extraordinary demonstration
of antiwar sentiment on
the convention floor.
("Street Fighting Man" by
the Rolling Stones playing)
DOUGLAS KIKER (on TV): The demonstrators
resisted when police attempted to arrest
a young man who tried to
rip down an American flag.
PROTESTOR: Watch... watch these fuckers.
Don't turn your back on these fuckers!
MICK JAGGER: ♪ Everywhere I
hear the sound of marching... ♪
PHILIP CAPUTO: The cops were all...
they were guys from the neighborhoods...
Italians, Polish guys, Irish guys.
Probably some of them had been in Vietnam.
And if they hadn't been,
they certainly had cousins
or brothers who were.
NARRATOR: Philip Caputo, who had
fought with the Marines in Vietnam,
was now a reporter,
assigned to cover the
conflict in American streets.
Get a picture of them throwing the rocks!
CAPUTO: So all of a sudden
the streets are filled
with these kids who don't
look like college kids
are supposed to look in the cops' view.
(protestors shouting, sirens wailing)
(explosion)
And some of them were committing vandalism
and yelling obscenities.
And I think a lot of policemen saw that
as abusing the privileges that
they had and scorning them.
They are provoking us
but we do not want to confront
them now... move back, please.
JAGGER: ♪ Well, then
what can a poor boy do ♪
♪ Except to sing for a
rock 'n' roll band ♪
♪ 'Cause in sleepy London town
♪ There's just no place for
a street fighting man ♪
(police chanting): Move back! Move back!
(screaming)
That's a report, on film, from
Grant Park, downtown Chicago.
NARRATOR: That evening,
thousands of demonstrators,
barred from getting anywhere
near the convention,
were marching toward
Democratic Party headquarters
in the Hilton Hotel on
Michigan Avenue instead.
ALINE SAARINEN: The marchers seem
to have come from everywhere
and now are coming up
south on Michigan Avenue
back toward the point where
the police were blocking them before.
NATIONAL GUARDSMAN: Get your hands up!
Hands up!
Come on!
(shouting)
Come on now! Go! Go!
I place before you for the
Democratic nomination
as president of the United States
the name of Senator Eugene J.
McCarthy of Minnesota.
(cheers and applause)
Downtown Chicago at Balbo
and Michigan Avenues,
there has been in progress for
some time a peace demonstration.
The police have come to put it down.
The National Guard has been called to help.
(crowd chanting "sieg heil" at police)
(chanting continues)
(siren wails)
(screaming)
MAN: Get him!
Get him! Get him!
GABE PRESSMAN: ...people screaming...
JAMES WILLBANKS: I turned
on the television.
I don't think I was too
particularly thoughtful
as a junior in college,
but I thought the country was
coming apart at the seams.
It looked like we were
devolving into madness.
And I couldn't tell, was it
protestors or the police
or was everybody insane?
(crowd chanting)
(gavel pounding)
NARRATOR: At the convention
there was more confusion.
Some antiwar delegates once pledged
to the murdered Robert Kennedy
now threw their support
behind yet another candidate,
South Dakota senator George McGovern.
ABRAHAM RIBICOFF: And with George McGovern
as president of the United States,
we wouldn't have to have Gestapo tactics
in the streets of Chicago.
(crowd reacts boisterously)
PRESSMAN: The persistent
chanting by the crowd,
"The whole world is watching."
NARRATOR: LBJ, watching
the chaos on television,
considered flying to Chicago
and getting back in the race himself.
Mayor Daley told the president
he'd have enough delegates
to win the nomination,
but the Secret Service warned it
could not guarantee his safety.
RON FERRIZZI: I got to Australia the
last week of August 1968... R&R.
I never really wanted to go on R&R.
I felt that, how can you relax?
So I turn on the TV and the first scene...
The TV gets bright.
The first scene on... it was the camera...
was a close-up, was over the
shoulder of this storm trooper
who had a kid by the scruff of his shirt.
And he smacks him with his bat.
And there's blood and
everything and all this jumble.
And then the camera pans
out and it's far away.
And these riots and there's
fighting going on.
And I go, "Oh, my God,
the Russians invaded Czechoslovakia."
And then ditto, ditto, ditto,
"Chicago Democratic Convention,
United States of America."
And I said... you know,
at that moment my...
I-I was politicized.
("For What It's Worth" by
Buffalo Springfield playing)
♪ There's somethin' happenin' here ♪
♪ What it is ain't exactly clear ♪
FERRIZZI: At that moment in time,
I realized that anybody who
really cared for America
was sent halfway around the
world chasing some ghost
in the jungle, killing
somebody else's grandmother
for no reason at all.
BUFFALO SPRINGFIELD: ♪ What's that sound,
everybody look what's going down ♪
FERRIZZI: And, in the meantime,
my country's being torn apart.
So I saw somebody who looked like my dad
hitting somebody who looked like me.
Oh, my God, whose side would I be on?
BUFFALO SPRINGFIELD: ♪ There's
battle lines being drawn ♪
♪ Nobody's right if everybody's wrong ♪
♪ Young people speakin' their minds ♪
♪ Getting so much
resistance from behind ♪
♪ It's time we stop
NARRATOR: In the end,
Humphrey won the nomination
on the first ballot.
He told the press how pleased he was,
but he confessed to his wife
that the convention had left him
feeling heartbroken, battered, and beaten,
as if he'd survived a shipwreck.
A presidential commission would
declare what had happened
in Chicago a "police riot,"
but in a Gallup poll,
56% of Americans approved
of the way the police had
handled the demonstrators.
And when Richard Nixon
chose to open his campaign
with a motorcade through the Chicago Loop,
nearly half a million Chicagoans
turned out to cheer him.
MICHAEL HOLMES (on tape): Hello, Mom, Pop.
I really can't tell you too
much about this country
except the rice paddies stink.
And it's just miles and miles
of nothing but rice paddies.
And they got dikes in them.
Real cool looking.
We go through them with our APCs
and tear them down and everything else.
("Road to Marscota" by
Peter Walker playing)
NARRATOR: On August 29, the day after
police and demonstrators clashed
in Chicago, 20-year-old
private Michael Holmes
arrived in Vietnam.
He was born and brought up in
the tiny town of Williamsville,
in the heart of the Missouri Ozarks.
His father and mother ran the general store
where Michael worked
every day after school.
He floated the rivers,
hunted deer and squirrels,
and was going steady with
a girl named Darlene.
He had trouble keeping up in high school,
did not complete community
college and, as a result,
was immediately drafted into the Army.
In Vietnam, he was assigned to
F Troop, 17th Armored Cavalry,
196th Light Infantry Brigade,
stationed at an isolated firebase
22 miles south of Danang called Baldy.
HOLMES (on tape): So you ask
what the size of Baldy was.
Well, it's just about
as big as Williamsville
and maybe a little bit bigger.
I sent you a picture of me and
a bunch of the other guys.
It's not really that bad.
It's... in a way I like it.
It's just being away from home
and everything that I don't like.
NARRATOR: In Williamsville, family
and friends gathered to listen
to Michael's reports from Vietnam
and to fill him in on what
was happening back home.
WOMAN (on tape): We're all down here
at your dad and mother's tonight
and we thought we'd all
say something for you.
And you could hear our voice
and feel like you's back home.
And we're looking forward...
HAROLD (on tape): Hello, Mike.
I've been doing a lot of
squirrel hunting lately,
and killing quite a few.
Well, the Ozarks really look
beautiful this time of year.
Looking forward to seeing you.
JERRY (on tape): Uh, this is Jerry, Mike.
I think Ricky and Carol broke up, Mike.
Ricky, he's really prowling now.
GLENDA (on tape): Mike, this is Glenda.
Um, I got a boyfriend,
and his name's Danny.
And...
GLEN (on tape): Mike, this is Glen.
All these other boys been
talking about hunting,
I'm gonna talk about girls.
(chuckling): Girls and fast cars.
Gene Bilbury got him a new Bonneville.
MICHAEL'S MOTHER (on tape):
Michael, this is Mother.
The picture you sent us was real
good, it looked just like you.
I even liked that moustache,
and I didn't think I would.
And we miss you a lot.
MICHAEL'S FATHER (on tape):
This is your dad talking.
We think that you'll be okay,
just don't be nosing around
where you don't have any business
and get hold of a booby trap or something.
This is about the end of this
tape, so goodbye for now.
HOLMES (on tape): We burned down
a whole lot of hooches today
of these people who don't
cooperate with us, you know.
Yeah, I don't I don't really understand it
because if, if they are, you know, not VC,
and we do that to them,
you know, treat them bad,
then they're gonna turn VC.
The Army does everything backward.
NARRATOR: One morning that fall,
several APCs from F Troop
moved cautiously up Highway
One toward Danang.
Michael Holmes rode in the second vehicle.
(explosion)
His APC hit a 300-pound bomb
buried beneath the road.
Three of his friends died instantly.
Holmes was thrown clear
and woke up five hours
later in the hospital.
HOLMES (on tape): Hello, Mom, Pop.
This is me.
Up to this point I didn't know
if there was really a
war going on over here.
I just thought maybe they was
playing a game or something.
But I could've reached out and
touched two of those people.
I knew them real good.
And please don't worry
about me getting hurt
because I'm not hurt all that bad.
Two more Purple Hearts and
I'm out of the field,
and I think maybe I get to get
out of the country altogether.
NARRATOR: Six months later, Michael
Holmes was on patrol, walking point,
when he was killed by a
North Vietnamese soldier.
LIZ TROTTA: This is Long An province.
Since 1962, it has been an
important testing ground
for the pacification program.
Amidst the flat rice fields and
coconut trees lies Loc Tien Mot.
The hamlet chief says only more
troops will make his people safe
from the Viet Cong.
During the night, he adds,
the guerrillas go from house
to house collecting taxes.
The government may have left
its traces of pacification.
The Viet Cong have not left.
Liz Trotta, NBC News, South Vietnam.
NARRATOR: Since the Viet Cong
had been so badly weakened
in the Tet Offensive and the two
offensives that followed it,
General Abrams believed
that hundreds of thousands of ARVN troops
could now be freed to
secure the countryside
and win support for the
government in Saigon.
But permanent security was not possible
unless the Viet Cong
political infrastructure...
the tax collectors and village chiefs,
runners and spies and sympathizers...
were killed, captured,
or persuaded to defect.
To do that, the CIA had
created the Phoenix Program.
RICHARD THRELKELD: The villagers
of Thuy Xuan have been assembled
in the village schoolyard,
where teams of government
interrogators are trying
to pick out from among them
the members of the Viet Cong
who live here.
This sort of Phoenix
exercise is a weekly event
in districts throughout South Vietnam.
NARRATOR: After recovering from his wounds,
Lieutenant Vincent Okamoto
became an intelligence officer
attached to the program.
The Phoenix Program was
premised on the fact
that the North Vietnamese coming
down the Ho Chi Minh Trail,
when they went into South Vietnam,
they were strangers,
just like the Americans.
They didn't know the terrain,
they didn't know the people.
So in order for them to
function operationally,
they needed the Viet Cong infrastructure.
And so the project was
to eliminate those guys.
And I think it made a great deal of sense.
STUART HERRINGTON: The communists
thought Phoenix was very effective.
They saw it as a significant threat
to the viability of the revolution
because to the extent that you
could take a sharp pointed knife
and carve out the Viet Cong,
the shadow Viet Cong,
the shadow government,
then their means of control
over the civilian population
in the South was dealt a death blow.
NARRATOR: The pressure the Phoenix
Program put on the Viet Cong
caused dangerous signs of what
one communist official described
as "wavering" among his
followers in the Mekong Delta...
depression, discouragement,
and widespread drunkenness
even among men going into battle.
But Phoenix's targeting was only
as good as the intelligence
upon which it was based,
and that varied widely.
DAVID CULHANE: This film, made
by a CBS stringer cameraman
some weeks ago shows
South Vietnamese forces
interrogating an old man
identified as a minor VC official.
NARRATOR: In the Phoenix Program,
Americans served in an advisory capacity;
most of the day-to-day
enforcement was left to
the South Vietnamese Provincial
Reconnaissance Units...
the PRUs...
who sometimes were more interested
in settling old scores than
in rooting out communists.
OKAMOTO: It was scary because
it was subject to abuse,
and was abused.
Again, the geniuses in Saigon
would use their computers
to come up with the blacklists.
You get the list, and you check
with other intelligence officers
in the district.
And you try to pool that information.
Next night, or a couple nights later,
a bunch of cowboys from the
PRUs would go out there.
And, you know, knock on the door,
"April Fool, motherfucker!"
And boom.
There wasn't any real accountability.
NARRATOR: Later, the director
of the Phoenix Program
admitted to Congress that
no one knew how many
of the more than 20,000 who had
been killed were innocent.
And although the program did succeed
in degrading the Viet Cong infrastructure,
the government of Nguyen Van Thieu remained
as unpopular as ever.
A poll taken in the Delta
province of Long An
would show 35% of the people
ready to vote for Thieu,
20% favoring the National Liberation Front,
and 45% backing someone, anyone,
opposed to both the Viet Cong
and the American-backed regime in Saigon.
MAN: In Vietnam there's a wound
that does not cease its bleeding.
I'm talking about the scream
of death and the wound of war.
We did not come to talk with you, Mr.
Humphrey.
We have come to arrest you.
Now you've had equal time.
Shut up!
(mixture of boos and cheers)
NARRATOR: Hubert Humphrey's
presidential campaign was in trouble.
Richard Nixon was comfortably
ahead in the polls
and refused to debate.
"I've come to the conclusion
that there's no way to win the war,"
he told three of his
speechwriters in private.
"But we have to say the opposite,
just to keep some bargaining leverage."
Compounding Humphrey's problem
was a third-party candidate,
George Wallace,
the segregationist former
governor of Alabama.
He was sure to peel away some white voters
who normally voted Democratic.
Humphrey had confided his
doubts about the war to Johnson
early on, but had always
remained stubbornly loyal to him
in public.
Now his advisors told him
that if he wanted to win
he had to break with the president
and make a bold gesture
toward ending the war.
On September 30, he called for a total halt
to the bombing of North Vietnam.
HUMPHREY: I would stop
the bombing of the North
as an acceptable risk for peace
because I believe it could lead
to success in the negotiations
and thereby shorten the war.
This would be the best
protection for our troops.
NARRATOR: Johnson felt
betrayed and refused to speak
to his own vice president for a time.
But on October 31, just five
days before the election,
the president himself made
a surprise announcement.
He was stopping all
bombing of North Vietnam.
There had been real
progress in Paris, he said.
Hanoi had agreed for the first
time to talk with Saigon,
and the United States had agreed
to include the Viet Cong.
It suddenly looked as
if peace were possible.
Humphrey was jubilant.
His poll numbers rose overnight.
He was confident he would now
be able to overtake Nixon.
But then, on November 2,
with just three days to go until
Americans went to the polls,
President Thieu suddenly announced
that the South Vietnamese
government would not attend
the proposed talks after all.
A representative of the Nixon campaign
at the candidate's personal
direction had secretly contacted
the Saigon government
urging Thieu to stay away from the talks,
promising that once Nixon was elected,
he would drive a harder bargain
with Hanoi than Humphrey would.
Thanks to a CIA bug planted
in Thieu's Saigon office
and an FBI wiretap on the
South Vietnamese embassy
in Washington, Johnson got
wind of what had happened
and called his friend Everett Dirksen,
the Republican Senate minority leader,
to warn him that the Nixon
people were committing treason.
LYNDON JOHNSON: I'm reading
their hand, Everett.
I don't want to get this in the campaign.
DIRKSEN: That's right.
And they oughtn't to be doing this.
This is treason. I know.
And I think it would shock America
if a principal candidate was
playing with a source like this
on a matter this important.
Yeah.
I know this...
that they're contacting a foreign power
in the middle of a war.
That's a mistake.
And it's a damn bad mistake.
RICHARD NIXON: Mr. President?
JOHNSON: Yes.
This is Dick Nixon. Yes, Dick.
I just went on Meet the Press
and said that I had given
you my personal assurance
that I would do everything
possible to cooperate
both before the election and if
elected, after the election.
I just wanted you to know
that I feel very, very strongly about this
and any rumblings around
about somebody trying to sabotage
the Saigon government's attitude
certainly has no...
absolutely no credibility
as far as I am concerned.
That's, that's...
I'm very happy to hear that, Dick,
because that is taking place.
My God, I would never do
anything to encourage Saigon
not to come to the table because basically,
that was what you got.
Well, that's good, Dick.
We've got to get this
goddamned war off the plate,
the quicker the better, and the
hell with the political credit.
Believe me.
Thank you, Dick.
NARRATOR: Nixon was lying
and Johnson knew it.
But to go public with the information,
the president would have
to reveal the methods
by which he had learned
of the Republican candidate's duplicity.
He was unwilling to do so.
Nixon's secret was safe.
The American public was never told
that the regime for which
35,000 Americans had died
had been willing to boycott peace talks
to help elect Richard Nixon
or that he had been willing
to delay an end to the bloodshed
in order to get elected.
REPORTER: At 10:45 this morning,
Eastern Standard Time...
NARRATOR: On Election Day, Richard
Milhous Nixon won the presidency
with 43.4 percent of the vote.
Hubert Humphrey received 42.7 percent.
The Nixon campaign's secret
maneuvering may have helped him
win the election, but the
president-elect's fear
that that maneuvering
might someday be exposed
would be part of his undoing.
Thieu waited several
weeks after the election
before agreeing to send
a delegation to Paris.
There, everything stalled over
the seating arrangements.
The North Vietnamese had
insisted on a square table,
with separate sides for all
four parties to the talks...
Hanoi, the Viet Cong, Saigon,
and the United States.
Saigon refused to take part
unless Hanoi and the Viet Cong
sat on the same side of the table.
The standoff went on for ten weeks.
It was the Soviets who finally
came up with a solution:
a round table.
(gunfire)
RADIO OPERATOR: Type of injury
is urgent, shrapnel wounds.
(gunfire)
The area is insecure.
MEDIC: Keep your head down.
RADIO OPERATOR: Got some fire.
KARL MARLANTES: You have these
19-year-old kids with these huge hearts.
They will do what you ask them.
The issue is are you asking them
to do something worthwhile?
That's up to the adults.
And that's where the failure comes.
The failure isn't the kids
saying, "I'm not gonna do this."
Because that's not the way they are built.
19-year-olds don't know
to take a raincoat on
when it's raining, all right?
That's-that's why they're
so good at being warriors.
They'll do it.
They won't even ask you a question.
"All right, we'll do it."
The responsibility is on
the grownups to make sure
they're not being wasted
because they'll do what they're
told, and they'll do it well.
NARRATOR: Karl Marlantes was
born in Astoria, Oregon,
the son of a veteran of
the Battle of the Bulge.
He had joined the Marine
Reserves the summer before
his freshman year at Yale,
eager to prove himself
and defend his country.
When he became a Rhodes scholar,
the Marines allowed him to
defer going on active duty,
and instead of serving in
Vietnam, he went to Oxford
in the fall of 1967.
A few months after he got there,
he wrote to his parents back home.
MARLANTES: "It is with
a little apprehension
"that I write this letter.
"I have given up my scholarship,
"and I will be on active duty as of May 3.
"As you know, I feel the U.S.
is absolutely wrong
"to be in the war.
"A lot of people are dying
for no good reason.
"I can only feel an increasing
rage and frustration.
And a complete feeling of helplessness."
"I have, in effect, been hiding,
and I'll not do it anymore.
"I guess I'm about to do
a highly immoral thing.
"I will be taking part
"in one of the greatest
crimes of our century,
"and I will be doing so out
of frustration, bitterness,
"and a sense of the absurd that
I have only come to appreciate
"in its entirety in the past year.
From now on my logic will be changed."
"I can do something.
"That is, I can do my
very best to get 40 kids
"out of Vietnam alive,
"and if I have to turn into
an evil machine to do it,
then by God I will."
It was my friends, guys
that I trained with.
I felt like I was going
to let the side down.
That by not joining in with
them and sharing the burden
that I wouldn't be a decent person.
It's a mixed bag because I went
over there and killed people
for, you know... is that why I did that?
O'BRIEN: Do you go off and kill people
if you're not pretty sure it's right?
And if your nation isn't
pretty sure it's right?
If there isn't some
consensus, do you do that?
I was at Fort Lewis, Washington,
and Canada was, what, a
90-minute bus ride away.
I wrote my mom and dad and asked for money.
I asked for my passport.
And they sent them to me
with, again, no questions.
Like, "What do you want the passport for?"
They just sent it.
And I kept all this stuff stashed,
including civilian clothes
stashed in my footlocker,
thinking maybe I'll... maybe I'll do it.
("Bookends Theme" by Simon
and Garfunkel playing)
It was this kind of "maybe" thing going on
all throughout this training
as Vietnam got closer
and closer and closer.
What prevented me from doing it?
I think it was pretty simple and stupid.
It was a fear of embarrassment,
a fear of ridicule and humiliation.
What my girlfriend would have thought of me
and the people in the Gobbler
Cafe in downtown Worthington.
The Kiwanis boys and the country club boys
and that small town I grew up in,
the things they'd say about me.
"What a coward and what a
sissy for going to Canada."
SIMON AND GARFUNKEL: ♪
It was a time of innocence
O'BRIEN: And I would imagine my mom and dad
overhearing something like that.
SIMON AND GARFUNKEL: ♪
Long ago it must be
O'BRIEN: I couldn't summon
the courage to say no
to those nameless, faceless
people who really, in essence,
this was the United States of America.
And I couldn't say no to them.
And I had to live with it now
for, you know, 40 years.
That's a long time to live
with a failure of conscience
and a failure of nerve.
And the nightmare of Vietnam
for me is not the bombs
and the bullets.
(voice breaking): It's
that failure of nerve
that I so regret.
HAL KUSHNER: In the fall of 1968 was
probably the toughest time we had.
Our daily life was a continuing
struggle for survival.
Our food ration was three
cups of rice per day.
We slept on a large bamboo pallet.
Sometimes there were ten or
12 people on one pallet.
And we were sick.
We were very sick.
Four people died within...
a month.
And then two more died
very shortly after that.
NARRATOR: Thirteen Americans would die
during Captain Hal Kushner's
time in jungle prison camps
in South Vietnam.
He was a doctor but had no medications,
no antibiotics or saline solution
with which to treat his comrades.
All he could do was bury
each in a bamboo coffin
and make sure the spot was
marked with a heap of stones
daubed with Mercurochrome.
KUSHNER: We had nothing to eat.
And I thought that I was just going insane.
So we were sitting around
and with this little fire.
And we saw the camp commander's cat,
who had free rein of the camp.
And he came down to our area.
And we were starving to death.
So someone suggested, "Let's eat the cat."
So we killed the cat.
And we cut the head off
and we cut the paws off.
And we had this little
carcass of about two pounds.
And one of the guards came down,
and we told him it was a weasel,
and we threw a rock at it and killed it.
And then he looked around
and someone had neglected
to bury one of the paws.
And he saw the paw.
And he knew instantly that it
was the camp commander's cat.
And things got very serious.
And they lined us up and
they said, "Who did this?"
Nobody said anything.
I thought they were going to kill us all.
Just execute us.
And one of the people who
was a ringleader in this
said he did it.
And I said that I did it also.
And we all said we did it.
"I am Spartacus," you know?
It was that.
So they called that person and me out.
And the guard kicked him and
beat him to the ground,
and just beat him unmercifully.
And they hit me in the face
with fists and didn't beat me
as badly as they beat him.
And then tied me with commo
wire very tightly to a hooch
and left me for a day.
And with the carcass of the
cat draped around my neck.
And I was so crazy I thought,
"Maybe they're going to
let me eat this cat."
But I had to bury it.
So, the fellow that they beat
very badly died two weeks later.
But to me the tragedy of it
was we didn't get the cat.
CHARLES COLLINGWOOD: For the
capital of a nation at war,
Saigon abounds with a
phenomenal number of young men
of draft age in sharp, civilian clothes.
Saigon cowboys they're called.
It's a war profiteer's economy,
fanned by the forced draft
of American money.
They count it a good year in Saigon
when the prices only go up by 25%.
NARRATOR: Years of American presence,
and the tens of billions of U.S.
dollars that came with it,
had transformed much of South Vietnam,
creating a false economy
that was utterly dependent
on that presence becoming perpetual.
GEORGE LEWIS: Since the U.S. began
its big buildup in the mid-'60s,
millions of dollars worth of
goods have entered the country
each month.
Some economists say ten
percent or more of the cargo
is diverted into black market channels.
NARRATOR: With so much money
flowing into the country,
corruption and crime inevitably grew.
Government officials were on the take.
So were many ARVN officers.
Policemen could not be trusted.
PHAN QUANG TUE: Who benefit from
the financial aspect of the war?
Generals.
Don't deny that.
Then they get the money,
then they become richer.
We have a term, and I call it,
they were war profiteers,
from Thieu and Ky down to every echelon.
HERRINGTON: The Vietnamese had a saying:
a house leaks from the roof on down.
(saying phrase in Vietnamese)
And that was, of course, their
way to elliptically refer
to the ever-present, nagging
problem of corruption.
JOE GALLOWAY: They were stealing
from us and selling to anybody.
Two-man helicopter, you want one of those?
They got it in a box in the back.
Probably get it for 12,000 bucks
if you negotiated strongly.
The corruption was endemic.
And we tolerated it.
NARRATOR: Tons of American goods
piled up on Saigon's docks.
Some Gis took advantage, too.
U.S. products flowed out
the back doors of PXs.
In just one year,
the black market cost the U.S.
military $2 billion.
COLLINGWOOD: The impact of the war
has disrupted the ancient patterns
of Vietnamese life.
The cities are crowded to the
bursting point with people
uprooted from the land
and the ancestral values
of a rural-oriented society
but who have found nothing to replace them.
NARRATOR: Before U.S. troops arrived,
eight out of ten South
Vietnamese lived in villages.
By the end of the 1960s,
almost half would be
crowded into urban areas.
Saigon's population
tripled to three million.
Half the refugees had no permanent shelter.
Cholera and typhoid killed thousands.
Hungry children roamed the
streets, scavenging, begging,
searching for jobs to
do or pockets to pick.
Tens of thousands of young
women left their village homes
and came to Saigon to become
bar girls and prostitutes.
The communist government in Hanoi
tried to make the most of it,
accusing the United States and
its puppet government in Saigon
of destroying Vietnamese
culture in the South.
But the citizens of Saigon were far freer
than the North Vietnamese.
The South Vietnamese people
could express their views,
for and against their government,
in the pages of hundreds of
newspapers and magazines.
And they held demonstrations denouncing
the rampant corruption and
demanding religious freedom
and better treatment for veterans.
For all of its problems,
one man remembered,
Saigon was "filthy and free."
(car horn honking)
NGUYEN NGOC:
(gunfire)
NARRATOR: In the densely
populated Mekong Delta,
the war in the countryside
suddenly intensified.
General Abrams assigned the commander
of the 9th Infantry Division,
General Julian J. Ewell,
the job of destroying
the remaining Viet Cong
south of Saigon.
His operation was called Speedy Express.
"The hearts and minds approach
can be overdone," Ewell said.
"In the Delta the only way to
overcome VC control and terror
is by brute force."
Patrols would pursue the
enemy around the clock.
The night sky was filled with helicopters,
some armed with instruments
that could detect
traces of carbon and ammonia
that meant human beings were below,
though not which side they were on.
In areas designated "free-fire zones,"
anyone out after curfew could be shot.
During the day, anyone
seen running was targeted.
Colonel Robert Gard was one of
Ewell's artillery commanders.
ROBERT GARD: If someone was told that
anyone who runs away should be assumed
to be an enemy, I certainly
would disagree with that.
That's totally improper.
People run away because they're afraid.
I've seen instances of farmers,
when you descend in a helicopter suddenly,
and they freeze, and they're
frightened, and they run.
You can't just make a blanket judgment.
NARRATOR: General Ewell boasted of
his unit's statistical record...
10,899 Viet Cong killed in six months
with a loss of only 242 Americans,
an astonishing kill ratio of 45-to-1.
GARD: To say that we killed
only enemy combatants,
and to talk about ratios of 40-to-1
simply defies my imagination.
NARRATOR: At Abrams' recommendation,
Ewell was promoted,
but the Army Inspector General
would eventually estimate
that more than half of
the roughly 11,000 kills
claimed by the 9th Infantry
had been unarmed, innocent civilians.
No one was ever held accountable.
("Don't Think Twice, It's All
Right" by Bob Dylan playing)
♪ It ain't no use to sit
and wonder why, babe ♪
♪ It don't matter, anyhow
♪ And it ain't no use to
sit and wonder why, babe ♪
♪ If you don't know by now
♪ When your rooster crows
at the break of dawn ♪
♪ Look out your window
and I'll be gone ♪
♪ You're the reason I'm travelin' on ♪
♪ Don't think twice, it's all right. ♪
CAROL CROCKER: I think moving away
from one's family's ideologies
is a scary balance on a
very tricky precipice
because they have been the focal point
of how we judge how we're doing.
And I was now trying to judge
my decisions and my actions
on the basis of my own
ideas and own thoughts.
NARRATOR: The war was
already uncomfortably close
to Carol Crocker.
Her brother Mogie had volunteered to fight
and had been killed in Vietnam in 1966.
She was still grieving.
That fall, Carol had entered
Goucher College in Baltimore,
an all-women's school with a
long conservative tradition.
CAROL CROCKER: We dressed for dinner.
We had an 11:00 curfew.
Obviously no boys or men
were allowed in the dorms.
That was the rule.
("Piece of My Heart" by Big
Brother and the Holding Company)
It could not have even been
any later than the beginning
of the second semester that most
of the rules that were in place
and had been in place for many,
many years, no longer existed.
JANIS JOPLIN: ♪ Oh, come on,
come on, come on, come on ♪
♪ And take it
♪ Take another little piece...
CAROL CROCKER: The challenge
to campuses countrywide was
how do we maintain our student body
to behave in a civil
manner, and teach them,
and not have them try to burn us down?
If that means not dressing
for dinner, so be it.
JOPLIN: ♪ If it makes you feel good
♪ Oh yes it did.
CAROL CROCKER: Our guy friends,
we were spending time and talking
and they were scared.
And they were worried.
And they weren't sure what
they were going to do.
And more discussion was happening about
whether this was a valid war.
And this was really, for me, the
first time I opened my ears
to the war in a way other than
that it was about my brother's death.
I honored him.
I respected him for doing
what he believed in.
But I did not agree with him.
JOPLIN: ♪ Come on, come on,
come on and take it. ♪
NARRATOR: Eva Jefferson was a
sophomore at Northwestern.
A serviceman's daughter, she
had entered college convinced
the American government would
never mislead its citizens.
But for her, too, things
had begun to change.
Earlier that year,
when a handful of black
Northwestern students decided
to occupy the bursar's office
demanding African-American
studies, she joined them,
then called her parents to
tell them what she'd done.
EVA JEFFERSON PATERSON: And I said,
"Mom and Dad, guess where I am?
We just took over the bursar's office."
They were horrified.
And upon reflection, of
course they were horrified.
And they said, "If you
don't get out of there
we're going to cut off your money."
So that was the moment
in my own consciousness
when I became independent.
I thought, "Well, they're
going to cut off my money.
C'est la vie."
NARRATOR: "The University met
all our demands in three days,"
she remembered.
"If you asked for black studies on Friday,
you got it on Monday."
PATERSON: It felt like something
was happening that was profound,
that was irreversible.
But also you're 18, 19 years old.
It's exciting.
I felt as though a revolution was coming.
And I thought the revolution
would be won by our side.
NARRATOR: Relations between parents
and children, brothers and sisters,
were changing everywhere.
ANNE HARRISON BOWMAN: When I stood in the
living room and I was hugging two brothers,
it didn't matter to me about their choices
or that they were on two
different sides of the fence.
All I knew was that they
were both my brothers
and they were both back in the
same room and there we were.
NARRATOR: Captain Matt
Harrison, Jr.... Chips...
had graduated West Point,
served a tour in Vietnam
and took part in two of the
war's bloodiest battles...
Hill 1338 and Hill 875.
He was back stateside
in the autumn of 1968,
when the family began to worry
about his younger brother, Bob,
whom his siblings sometimes called Robin.
MATT HARRISON: He and I were just
great pals since we were growing up
because we moved every year or two years.
And, you know, new set of friends
but always had my brother.
BOWMAN: Bob was in ROTC
and polished and buffed his
shoes and had short hair
and said "Yes, sir" and "Yes, ma'am."
And then we moved to California
his senior year in high school.
And he was the consummate blond
surfer boy and cutting school.
And he was immediately very popular
and having a great time.
NARRATOR: Robin did not go to West Point,
entered Marin Junior College instead,
and then shocked his family by signing on
with the Marine... not the Army... Reserves.
HARRISON: At some point Robin
became convinced that...
that the war was wrong, and not
only wrong, it was immoral.
So he quit going to the Reserve weekends,
and because of that he was activated...
and was very likely now he was
going to be going to Vietnam
as a Marine Corps rifleman.
I didn't think being a
Marine Corps rifleman
was a very safe occupation.
And I didn't think Robin
would be a particularly good
Marine Corps rifleman.
And so I just thought that this
was a very bad outcome for him
and for the family.
NARRATOR: Matt Harrison knew
that under military regulations,
if one brother was already
in a combat zone,
a second brother need not
accept assignment there.
So to keep Robin out of the war,
he volunteered for a
second tour in Vietnam.
HARRISON: I was back in Vietnam
I think in less than 30 days.
I was a seasoned veteran.
I was going to go command a company.
My chances of getting hurt were
a lot less than Robin's were.
And if I did choose to make it a career,
the fact that I had had a second tour
as a rifle company commander
was going to be good for me.
And so, you know, it
wasn't entirely selfless.
I honestly don't remember a
tremendous amount of dialogue
between my mom and dad.
I think they felt like if Bob had gone,
he would have been killed.
Whereas I think they felt that
Chips was going to be okay.
I can't imagine, having
had a son now go to Iraq,
how my mother could have gotten
through every single day at all,
without believing very firmly
that he was going to be fine.
NARRATOR: Matt Harrison's
decision to serve a second tour
did not fully protect his brother Robin.
He went AWOL, was court-martialed
and sentenced to three months hard labor.
The sentence was suspended.
He returned to the Marines,
served as a chaplain's assistant,
applied for conscientious objector status,
and then went AWOL again.
VICTORIA HARRISON: I remember the
FBI coming and knocking on the door
and looking for him.
They asked if Robert Harrison was there
and I just knew this wasn't good
and said "No" and slammed the door.
And Bob went out the back
and ran out to the main street.
And as I understand it,
got in a car and left
and that was the last I saw of him.
BOWMAN: I don't think a military
mom at the time would want
to announce, "My son has gone AWOL.
"My son has run to Canada.
"My son is all the words that
were associated with it,
a deserter, a coward."
All of the things that
these guys were called.
I don't think that's what those
guys thought they were doing.
I do not think they thought
they were deserting.
they were cowards.
In fact, I think they thought
they were very brave.
NARRATOR: When Matt Harrison
assumed command of Alpha Company,
2nd Battalion, 14th Regiment
of the 25th Infantry Division,
his Army had changed.
HARRISON: I was commanding
a company of draftees,
almost none of whom wanted to be there.
They didn't want to be in the Army
and they certainly didn't want to be
an infantryman in Vietnam.
There were times when it was very difficult
to keep the men under control,
particularly if we had taken
casualties on the way
into a village.
One of the things I learned
is the veneer of civilization
is very thin... very thin...
on me, probably on you,
and I think on everybody.
I just saw over and over again
some nice young guy out
of Huron, South Dakota,
who back in Huron helped old
ladies across the street
and went to church every Sunday.
It did not take long for that
veneer of civilization to erode.
And he was now capable of doing things
that just simply are inhuman.
I was not willing to allow
it to happen on my watch
and I didn't think it was
good for the soldiers
to do those kinds of things.
Now, I'm not saying that we
didn't do some horrific things.
We did.
But there's a difference
between being spontaneous
and being premeditated.
NARRATOR: Many years later,
Robin Harrison, still adrift,
got caught up in the world of drugs
and died 10,000 miles from home
in a hotel room in Hong Kong,
another casualty, his
brother Matt believed,
of the war in Vietnam.
("Magic Carpet Ride" by
Steppenwolf playing)
♪ I like to dream
♪ Yes, yes, right between
my sound machine ♪
♪ On a cloud of sound I
drift in the night ♪
♪ Any place it goes is right
♪ Goes far, flies near, to
the stars away from here ♪
♪ Well, you don't know...
MERRILL McPEAK: I dropped
a bomb one afternoon
that must have had a broken
fin or something on the bomb.
It just went crazy, went
over and hit, you know,
a mile away from where I was aiming.
And it started a series
of secondary explosions,
meaning that I had hit an ammunition dump,
or a cache of ammunition or something.
So it cooked off for 15 minutes.
As we were leaving, the
thing was still blowing up.
The best result I achieved in a year,
it was a result of a gross miss
from what I was aiming at.
Now that's the exact reverse of
how you want to use air power.
NARRATOR: Major Merrill McPeak
was a crack fighter pilot
when he arrived in Vietnam in late 1968.
At first, he had helped provide
air support for the Army,
with a guaranteed number of
sorties per day, he remembered,
"whether or not they had
anything in front of them
worth blowing up."
MERRILL McPEAK: At the end of any
sortie where we dropped bombs
on what we called "trees in contact"
because there was nothing
important down there,
we would always get back a
list of bomb damage assessment
from the forward air controller.
And it would be, like, "12
supply sources destroyed,
two structures collapsed."
All these metrics.
It was phony.
Just a waste of time.
NARRATOR: Then, McPeak was
assigned to a top-secret squadron
seeking to pinpoint men and supplies
moving on the Ho Chi Minh Trail in Laos.
He and his fellow pilots
called their unit Misty,
after its radio call sign.
McPEAK: I spent four months in Misty.
And that was the best
four months of the war,
as far as I'm concerned,
because what we were doing
was simple, straightforward,
and made sense.
We want to stop traffic from
A to B down this dirt road.
That I can understand.
Somebody in Saigon wasn't saying,
"Go bomb trees at
such-and-such a location."
We went out and actually found the target.
NARRATOR: It was dangerous work.
One out of five pilots was shot down.
(radio chatter)
Misty put up seven sorties
a day from dawn to dusk,
on the lookout for signs
of human activity...
gardens, encampments, roadside
trees coated with dust,
or wet roads on either side of fords
that signaled a truck convoy
had recently passed through.
McPEAK: I have enormous respect
for those truck drivers.
They left their homes in the North,
and they weren't drafted for a year or two.
They just left and didn't know
if they were ever going to come back.
NARRATOR: Although McPeak and his
fellow pilots did not know it,
among the drivers threading their way
down the Ho Chi Minh Trail by
night were hundreds of women.
NGUYEN NGUYET ANH:
NARRATOR: For three years, Nguyen
Nguyet Anh drove her section
of the Trail, ferrying
arms and supplies south,
then heading back north with
cargoes of wounded men.
NGUYEN NGUYET ANH:
McPEAK: They drove in stages.
So they knew 15, 20 clicks of the road.
And they drove from A to B and back to A.
And then they rested, during the daytime,
and then the next night, they
drove from A to B and back to A.
They had kind of memorized the
road, which was very important,
because they were running
without lights at night.
(jet engine roars)
McPEAK: One time I stumbled across
a bunch of trucks backed up,
and that was a great morning for me.
Occasionally one of 'em would break down,
in a spot where the trucks behind it
would get trapped and
couldn't back out of there.
So you try to strafe the last
truck, so that it can't move.
And these are one-lane roads.
So once you get the back truck disabled,
then you just call in fighters.
You're shooting fish in a barrel.
NARRATOR: As she drove the Ho Chi
Minh Trail, Anh thought constantly
of her fiancé Tran Cong Thang,
an army engineer she'd fallen in
love with four years earlier.
He was also stationed
somewhere on the Trail.
NGUYEN NGUYET ANH:
TRAN CONG THANG:
NARRATOR: Over 20,000 engineers,
soldiers, and truck drivers died
along the Ho Chi Minh Trail.
72 military cemeteries would
eventually be required
to hold their remains.
TRAN CONG THANG:
McPEAK: We dropped more
tonnage of munitions
than the United States
dropped in World War II,
most of it aimed at the Ho Chi Minh Trail.
We did not stop traffic down the trail.
And that is a big disappointment for me.
To this day, it irritates me.
The real failures were
made at the policy level.
We were fighting on the wrong side.
The South, the government
in the South was corrupt.
And its people knew it.
And we knew it.
I'll tell you something,
those truck drivers fought very well.
I would have been proud to fight with them.
So one of the things you got
to do when you go to war
is pick the right side, okay.
Get the right allies.
NARRATOR: Merrill McPeak would
serve 37 years and retire
as Air Force chief of staff.
Nguyen Nguyet Anh and Tran
Cong Thang were reunited
after the war and married.
The peace we seek to win
is not victory over any other people,
but the peace that comes
with healing in its wings;
with compassion for those
who have suffered;
with understanding for
those who have opposed us;
with the opportunity for all
the peoples of this earth
to choose their own destiny.
("Lonely Road" by the Sandals playing)
NARRATOR: Like Lyndon Johnson,
Richard Nixon had an ambitious
agenda for his presidency...
easing a quarter of a century of
tensions with the Soviet Union
and opening the door to China,
whose existence the United
States had refused to recognize
since the communists took over in 1949.
But as it had with Johnson,
the ongoing war in Vietnam
threatened all those plans.
37,563 Americans had died there
by the time he took the oath of office.
"I'm not going to end up like LBJ,
"holed up in the White House,
afraid to show my face on the street,"
Richard Nixon told an aide.
"I'm going to stop that war.
Fast."
Nixon's national security
advisor was Henry Kissinger.
A refugee from Nazi Germany, he
had taught government at Harvard
and was already a well-known
advocate of a foreign policy
based on pragmatism, not ideology.
"Give us six months," Kissinger
told a group of Quakers
demonstrating on Pennsylvania Avenue,
"and if we haven't ended the
war by then, you can come back
and tear down the White House fence."
In February of 1969, the North
launched yet another offensive.
This time, they killed 1,100
Americans in just three weeks.
Nixon did not feel he could retaliate
by resuming the bombing of the North
for fear of provoking the
antiwar movement at home.
So in March, he secretly ordered
B-52s to begin attacking
the North Vietnamese bases within Cambodia,
which had offered sanctuary
to the enemy for years.
The American public was told
nothing about the bombing.
Congress was kept in the dark, as well.
Even members of Nixon's own cabinet
were not initially informed.
When theNew York Ti mes finally
discovered what was happening,
the White House denied any
bombing was taking place
and ordered that illegal wiretaps be placed
on the telephones of 17 reporters
and government officials
in an effort to find out
who had leaked the story.
"We will not make the same old mistakes,"
Henry Kissinger had joked to an aide
shortly after coming to Washington.
"We will make our own."
The war went on.
(helicopter blades whirring, men shouting)
(gunfire)
MARLANTES: There's basically
two sides to heroism.
One is that I want to be special.
I want people to look at me,
I'm an important person.
I've done heroic deeds.
The other side is simply
somebody's got to do something
to save these people, my platoon
or my company, from destruction.
The exact same act can be done
with one attitude or the other.
NARRATOR: After leaving Oxford,
First Lieutenant Karl Marlantes
found himself executive
officer of Charlie Company,
First Battalion, Fourth
Marines, Third Marine Division,
just south of the DMZ.
His unit was fighting the same sort of war
over the same terrain that
Marines had been fighting now
for four years.
MARLANTES: You would hear,
"Well, it's going to be
Operation Purple Martin I
or Operation Scotland II."
And, and it'd be like, "Yeah, whatever."
What that meant to us was that someday soon
some choppers are going
to show up and drop us
into the jungle someplace
or a valley north of us
or wherever it was going to be.
And then we'd be off the hill
and we'd be humping, as we called it.
NARRATOR: On March 5, 1969,
Marlantes' company was ordered
to attack a regiment of
North Vietnamese regulars
dug in on the slopes of a hill
the Americans called 484.
A few days earlier, his
unit had taken the hill
and then, under heavy
fire, had abandoned it.
This time air strikes meant
to soften up the enemy
hit the wrong hill.
Charlie Company was ordered
to advance anyway.
Marlantes led the way.
MARLANTES: It was a very steep hill.
And you don't charge because
you have a lot of weight.
And we had started walking up
and we had probably gotten
about a third of the way up the hill
and then they unleashed on us.
We were in the middle of
this horrible shit sandwich.
(gunfire, explosions)
NARRATOR: The Marines took
what cover they could.
Marlantes realized that if
they continued up the slope
they would face machine gun fire,
but if they stayed where they were,
mortar shells would surely find them.
(explosion)
MARLANTES: And then I stood up
and went up the hill.
And I thought it was...
I was all by myself.
And I was running at this point
because I wanted to cover
that ground fast as I could.
And I caught some movement
out of the corner of my eye,
and I rolled to the ground
to come up with my rifle
to shoot the person.
And it was a kid from my platoon.
And then I looked behind
him, there was more kids.
They had all come behind me.
It felt to me like I was there for a week
but I think I was probably by myself
four seconds, five seconds.
The entire platoon just
stood up and out they came.
It remains to me a moment that is just
almost inexpressible of the
heart that these kids had.
(explosion, gunfire)
And then we just hit those bunkers.
NARRATOR: The Marines cleared
the bunkers one by one.
For his bravery, Marlantes
was awarded the Navy Cross.
MARLANTES: Combat is like crack cocaine.
It's an enormous high but
it has enormous costs.
Any sane person would never do crack.
Combat is like that.
You're scared, you're
terrified, you're miserable,
but then the fighting starts...
(gunfire)
...and suddenly everything is at stake...
your life, your friend's lives.
It's almost transcendence
because you're no longer a person.
You lose that sense; you're just...
you're just the platoon.
And the platoon can't be beat.
And not to mention there's a savage joy
in overcoming your enemy,
just a savage joy.
And I think that we make
a big mistake if we say,
"Oh, war is hell."
We all know the "war is hell" story.
It is.
But there's an enormously
exhilarating part of it.
(explosion)
("Tell the Truth" by Otis Redding playing)
♪ Tell the truth
♪ Tell the truth, girl, now
♪ You know you got me
doin' everything crazy ♪
♪ That you want me to do
♪ Yes, you have, girl
♪ Don't you, don't
you, don't you know ♪
♪ You got to tell the truth, yeah ♪
♪ Baby, baby, baby, babe
♪ Why don't you tell
me the truth, now? ♪
♪ You know you got me doin'
♪ Everything crazy that
you want me to do ♪
♪ Yes, you have, yeah, watch it ♪
♪ Loving you is just a little
bit easy to start it ♪
♪ So hard to stop
♪ If I could
♪ Baby, baby, you know I would
♪ I'd build a stone wall around ♪
♪ If I thought that it
would do any good, mama ♪
♪ Tell me the truth, yeah
♪ Lit-lit-lit-lit-little girl,
just tell me the truth now ♪
♪ Yeah, huh
♪ You know you got me doin'
everything foolish ♪
♪ That you want me to do, oh
♪ Oh, play it
♪ Come on, yeah
♪ Tell me, tell me,
tell me the truth now ♪
(saxophone solo)
♪ Lovin' you
♪ Is easy to start
♪ Hard to stop
♪ But I'm gonna just
tell you this, uh ♪
♪ Baby, you know I would
♪ I would build a stone wall around ♪
♪ If I just thought that
it would do me some good ♪
♪ The truth now
♪ Tell 'em, tell 'em,
tell 'em, tell 'em ♪
♪ Tell, tell me the truth now
♪ Just tell me the truth now
♪ Got to tell me no lie
♪ Tell me the truth now.
ANNOUNCER: LEARN MORE ABOUT THE FILM
AND FIND ADDITIONAL RESOURCES
AT PBS.ORG/VIETNAMWAR
AND JOIN THE CONVERSATION
USING HASHTAG VIETNAMWARPBS.
"THE VIETNAM WAR" IS AVAILABLE
ON BLU-RAY AND DVD.
THE COMPANION BOOK, SOUNDTRACK,
AND ORIGINAL SCORE FROM THE FILM
ARE ALSO AVAILABLE.
TO ORDER, VISIT SHOPPBS.ORG
OR CALL 1-800-PLAY-PBS.
EPISODES OF THIS SERIES ALSO
AVAILABLE FOR DOWNLOAD
FROM iTUNES.
ANNOUNCER: BANK OF AMERICA PROUDLY SUPPORTS
KEN BURNS' AND LYNN NOVICK'S
FILM "THE VIETNAM WAR"
BECAUSE FOSTERING DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVES
AND CIVIL DISCOURSE AROUND IMPORTANT ISSUES
FURTHERS PROGRESS, EQUALITY,
AND A MORE CONNECTED SOCIETY.
GO TO BANKOFAMERICA.COM/
BETTERCONNECTED TO LEARN MORE.
ANNOUNCER: MAJOR SUPPORT
FOR "THE VIETNAM WAR"
WAS PROVIDED BY MEMBERS OF
THE BETTER ANGELS SOCIETY,
INCLUDING JONATHAN AND JEANNIE LAVINE,
DIANE AND HAL BRIERLEY,
AMY AND DAVID ABRAMS,
JOHN AND CATHERINE DEBS,
THE FULLERTON FAMILY CHARITABLE FUND,
THE MONTRONE FAMILY,
LYNDA AND STEWART RESNICK,
THE PERRY AND DONNA
GOLKIN FAMILY FOUNDATION,
THE LYNCH FOUNDATION,
THE ROGER AND ROSEMARY ENRICO FOUNDATION,
AND BY THESE ADDITIONAL FUNDERS.
MAJOR FUNDING WAS ALSO PROVIDED
BY DAVID H. KOCH...
THE BLAVATNIK FAMILY FOUNDATION...
THE PARK FOUNDATION,
THE NATIONAL ENDOWMENT FOR THE HUMANITIES,
THE PEW CHARITABLE TRUSTS,
THE JOHN S. AND JAMES L. KNIGHT FOUNDATION,
THE ANDREW W. MELLON FOUNDATION,
THE ARTHUR VINING DAVIS FOUNDATIONS,
THE FORD FOUNDATION JUSTFILMS,
BY THE CORPORATION
FOR PUBLIC BROADCASTING,
AND BY VIEWERS LIKE YOU.
THANK YOU.