Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
GLARE
That was footage that was coincidentally
captured on surveillance cameras
of the FBI agents who died in Japan.
Please show me only
the scenes of Raye Penber
passing the ticket gate,
riding the train, and then dying.
Yes.
Let's see...
It's right below that.
Oh, this?
Raye Penber enters through the ticket
gate of Shinjuku Station at 15:11.
At 15:13,
he rides the Yamanote Line.
Even if he was following someone,
it would be difficult...
to conclude anything from
this blurry video.
And at 16:42...
Oh, thank you very much.
And at 16:42, he gets off and dies at
the Tokyo Station Platform.
It's strange, isn't it?
What's strange, L?
Did you notice something?
Judging by this footage,
from the time that Raye Penber got
on the train until his death,
he had been riding for an hour and a half.
The Yamanote Line only takes an hour.
That envelope is especially strange.
Envelope?
He's holding that envelope
as he enters the ticket gate
and reaches the platform.
I- Indeed.
He's carrying it.
He's carrying it!
But by the time he dies...
It's gone!
Ryuzaki, it's amazing you noticed that!
Envelope isn't on the list of
articles he left behind.
Which means it was left in the train.
And this video of Penber's
final moments...
It looks to me as if
he's desperately trying
to look inside the train.
If so, could there be a hint there?
Wouldn't it be interesting
if Kira was there?
C- Couldn't be!
I don't think so either.
There's no reason for Kira,
who can control death from a distance,
to come to the scene of the crime.
But despite that, he may
have tried something bold.
Light, are you all right?
You've been writing criminals'
names in the Death Note
for four days already
without sleeping.
Why do you have to set up a death
schedule for several months ahead?
Quite simply...
Suppose I get hospitalized.
People will say that...
"As soon as Chief Yagami's son
was hospitalized,
"criminals have
stopped dying, haven't they?"
So that's why...
But are you sure
any date before the end of
their predestined life span is all right?
Shinigami never use it that way,
so I can't say for sure, but...
In theory, any time before
their natural deaths should be all right.
You're not much help.
You can't.
No, I'm not.
Yes, please wait one moment.
Ryuzaki.
Ukita at the NPA has received
a phone call he's concerned about.
Then have him give the telephone
number of number five
and have the informant
call that number.
Matsuda, you can turn on
your cell phone.
I mean, please turn it on.
Oh, yes.
Yes, this is Suzuki, head of the Public Information
Processing Unit for the Kira Case.
Raye Penber's fiancée?
Naomi Misora...
I've heard that name somewhere...
It's her... from the Los Angeles
BB murder case...
So that's it... She worked under me on
that case and now she's in Japan.
She's been missing
since the death of her fiance.
Anyone would be depressed
over the death of a fiance...
Could it be...
...suicide?
No, the Naomi Misora I knew
was very strong-willed,
an excellent FBI agent.
She would likely be thinking
of catching Kira.
She was with Penber.
She might have found a clue...
If that's the case,
did Kira get to her ﬁrst?
Everyone, from now on,
we'll focus our investigation
on the people Raye Penber
was investigating while in Japan.
He was investigating two people
in relation to the police
and the people around them.
Who are they? Who are those two?
Deputy Director General Kitamura
and his family, and...
Detective Superintendent Yagami
and his family.
What?!
I also wish to place wiretaps and
surveillance cameras in both households.
I have to make sure this computer
is clean in case anyone examines it.
I just have to hide a clipping
of the Death Note in here...
You sure are skillful
with your hands.
You're popular with the girls,
aren't you?
That has nothing to do with skill.
It's more about looks than skill.
Ryuk, you aren't popular, are you?
Surveillance cameras? Ryuzaki!
That's way out of the question!
It would become a civil rights issue
if this is discovered...
and we'll all be fired!
Weren't you willing to risk
more than your jobs?
I thought we were
putting our lives on the line.
Ryuzaki...
What is the possibility that
Kira is among them?!
Ten percent...
No, five percent.
No way! All that for only a five-percent
possibility is a bit much.
No... Of the people
we investigated so far...
there wasn't anyone who even
seemed the least bit suspicious.
I think we should look into it
even if there's only
a one-percent chance of finding Kira.
Chief!
I never thought that my family
was under suspicion...
Fine.
Please place them!
In return, install them in every part
of the house! Even the bathroom, the toilet!
Don't miss a single corner!
Thank you very much.
That's what I was planning to do.
Chief!
What are you talking about?!
That's right! You have a wife
and daughter, don't you?
I know!
There's no point in doing this
unless we're thorough!
Just be quiet!
Soffy...
No, it's okay...
I'm sorry...
Well, out of courtesy, only Yagami and I
will conduct surveillance on his home.
Watari, how long will it take to set up
the wiretaps and camera monitors?
Starting tomorrow...
I can set them up at any time once
we know when both families will be out.
See you later, Light.
Yeah, see you tomorrow.
What? No one's home yet?
I'm home...
Hey Light, no one seems to be home.
Wanna play a game together?
It's been awhile.
Hey Light, let's play a game.
Are you listening to me?
Light?
C- Couldn't be.
I never knew he went to
those lengths!
Could he have something in his
room he doesn't want anyone to see?
If you keep in mind that
he's only seventeen,
there's nothing suspicious
about his behavior.
I also did that for no apparent reason.
Have you ever talked to him
about the investigation?
Of course not!
I'd never tell him about anything
classified that hasn't been broadcast.
Besides...
Lately I haven't been returning
home regularly,
and when I do, I'm too tired...
and just go to sleep.
I understand...
Light, where are you going?
Hey, Light, you've been ignoring me!
I'm getting mad.
- There don't seem to be...
- Hey, Light!
any taps planted on these clothes.
Light...
Ryuk, there's a possibility that there are
wiretaps or surveillance cameras,
no, likely both,
placed within the house.
Huh? But that piece of paper
was still in your door, wasn't it?
That piece of paper was
a fake to make people think
it was there to see whether anyone
had entered the room while I was gone.
The real detector is,
first of all, my door handle.
Door handle?
When that door is closed,
the door knob naturally rises
to a horizontal position.
It won't rise any higher.
But whenever I close the door,
I purposefully lower the door knob
to five millimeters below
its highest position.
In other words, when I open the door,
if the knob is all the way up,
chances are that someone
was in my room.
But I can't rely on just that.
So I also put a mechanical
pencil lead in place.
A pencil lead?
On the hinge.
After I close the door,
I place a mechanical pencil lead
on the hinge at an angle
so that it will break
if the door is opened.
The lead is sure to break
I've always taken it out myself
when I entered,
but today, it was broken.
Oh, that. I remember you doing that.
The door handle and the pencil lead.
I have no doubt that someone went in.
Isn't it probably your parents?
My parents and sister probably
wouldn't notice the piece of paper.
It's suspicious because someone
took the time to put it back.
Welcome.
Are you planning to buy a book
to research wiretaps and surveillance?
Ryuk, by the way,
what will happen to your apples?
Apples?
Oh! From the surveillance camera...
if I put the apple in my mouth
no one can see it,
but it'll look like it's floating in air
if I'm just holding it.
I thought so...
Shinigami cannot die,
so they won't starve either.
In other words, there's no problem
if I don't give you any apples.
Whoa, wait just a minute, Light!
Apples are to me...
W- Well... What cigarettes and liquor
are to humans.
I'll get withdrawal symptoms
if I don't have any for a while...
What kind of symptoms?
My body twists around wildly,
and I'll do handstands.
I don't want to see that...
Right?
Ryuk, listen.
I've given L the hint that
Shinigami love apples.
When did you...
If you really want to eat apples...
find out where all the cameras are.
There might be a place where
you can eat apples without being seen.
All right, Ryuk, let's go!
Yeah!
Finding cameras.
This is also interesting!
Oh right, I have to find cameras...
I can't believe my diligent son
is looking at a magazine like that!
It's normal for a 17-year-old.
But to me, it seems like
he's making an excuse, as if to say,
"| was checking to see
if someone was in this room...
"because I have magazines like these. "
Ryuzaki, are you telling me that
you suspect my son?
I do suspect him.
That's why I placed wiretaps
and cameras in your house
as well as
the Deputy Director Generals house.
I found a camera in the air conditioner.
$0 there were cameras. -.
That probably means
there are wire taps as well.
Even if this is for the Kira case,
I can't believe the Japanese police
would go this far.
This is L's doing...
If that's the case,
how far has he narrowed it down to?
He must be down to at least someone
that Raye Penber was investigating
or he would have never gone this far.
Tricked by the cover again!
No, in this case, I should act as if...
I was the only one being suspected
and being watched.
It'll be all right.
I've been preparing for
something like this...
That's why I got
these magazines.
Light...
It's time for dinner...
I...
love you.
Hideki Ryuga, you're so dreamy!
There's nobody in my class like him!
No one at all!
Sayu...
Eat your dinner.
I will later!
Mr. Aizawa, are the Kitamuras
watching television now?
Yes.
Aside from the Deputy Director General,
the four of them are watching
television as they eat.
It's channel four.
Watari, order the various television
companies to broadcast our banner.
Understood.
NKK NEWS FLASH
Huh? What?
"In response to the Kira murders,
"the ICPO has decided to dispatch
1,500 investigators
"from various developed
countries to Japan. "
1,500 investigators?
Wow!
There should also be cameras
in the living room.
Whether this news is real or not,
it's being shown to me
to get some kind of reaction...
L... It's the same trick you
used the ﬁrst time.
The ICPO sure is stupid.
There's no point in making
this announcement.
If they're going to send them in,
they should let them come in
and investigate in secret.
Even those FBI agents investigating
in secret were killed.
The outcome will be the same.
This is just an overblown attempt
to shock Kira into exposing himself.
But, it just might be completely
obvious to Kira.
Your son is very smart.
Huh? Yeah, well...
Thanks for dinner.
No way! Are you eating potato chips
after dinner?
You look so fit right now...
do you wanna get fat?
It's just a late night snack
while I study for exams.
L- Light...
I found all of the cameras...
I guess even Shinigami get tired
when they try hard...
I'll explain now.
It's a bit complex, so pay attention.
I don't want to explain it again.
All right, time to study hard!
There are so many cameras.
Whoever put them here must've
expected you to find some.
There are 64 in all.
It's deﬁnitely L.
He had no qualms putting
a death row inmate in his place
when he challenged me.
He knows no limits...
So where am I going to eat
apples in this situation?
Obviously that's impossible, Ryuk.
Oh, yeah you can't talk to
me in this house, can you?
Tomorrow, tell me when
we go outside.
Okay, I got this one right.
Judging from the number of cameras,
he's planning on making
his decision in a short amount of time...
A normal person would
probably give himself away, but...
you're messing with
the wrong person, L...
this is as far as you'll get.
I've written down criminals
in the Death Note.
So they will continue to die
over the next three weeks, but...
Kira has already shown L that
he can control the time of death.
So in this case...
Current criminals being
broadcast on the news...
have to die while I'm not
receiving any knowledge of them.
Oh no!
My withdrawal symptoms!
Just watch, L!
With Ryuk's information
and my prior preparations,
I can kill criminals
currently being broadcast
while masquerading...
as a regular high school student.
I'll solve equations
with my right hand...
and write names with my left.
TAYOSHI MURAO
Grab a potato chip...
And eat it!
After dinner, your son has
continued studying
without turning on
a television or computer, hasn't he?
It's because the Entrance Exams
are less than ten days away...
Now a criminal which I should
have no knowledge about...
will die of a heart attack
in forty seconds.
The witness to my alibi is L himself.
All right, just a little more!
Ryuzaki.
Watari, what is it?
Two people just broadcast on
today's nine o'clock news,
a bank clerk on suspicion of
embezzlement during questioning...
And a purse snatcher
in a detention center...
just died of heart attacks.
It's Kira!
During that time in your home...
your wife and daughter were
watching a drama.
As soon as that was finished,
they turned off the television
and didn't watch anything afterwards.
From just past 7:30 until now,
11 o'clock,
the only thing your son has
done is study.
Kira needs a face
and a name to kill...
Those who did not watch
the news, can't be Kira, huh?
This means my family is innocent, right?
Kira killed people with minor crimes as
soon as they were broadcast, didn't he?
Even if it is the first day
the cameras were installed,
the Yagami household is
so clean, it's almost funny.
Light, are you awake?
Yeah, I'm up.
Today is trash day, so bring out
any garbage if you have any.
What a pain!
What are you talking about?
I always say you should be doing
this without me reminding you!
Yeah yeah...
The weather today is nice.
Well... I don't know if you'll do
just about anything if it's for yourself
or if you're just a big spender, but...
didn't that mini-LCD TV
cost 39,800 yen?
Good morning.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
that I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
TO-OH UNIVERSITY ENTRANCE CEREMONY
This just proves that
they don't have anything on me.
It's just a contest
between L and me, a match of wits.