Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change the dream
Into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
What?!
There were another
23 heart attack victims yesterday?!
As soon as we began to suspect
that Kira was a student,
the timing of the killings changed as
if to contradict our theory.
Does that mean that Kira knows
what the police know?
When L discovers that information
from the investigation was leaked,
he's bound to search for leads on me
within the police force.
Someone's been following you
all this time.
That's a problem...
I'll get rid of him soon, Ryuk.
A Shinigami's eyes...
...can see a human's name
and lifespan above their heads.
into Shinigami eyes.
The price for a Shinigami's eyes...
is half of that human's remaining lifetime.
So...
Light, what'll it be?
PURSUIT
I haven't seen Ryuk around lately...
Did he really lose his Death Note
in the Human World?
The Death Note was probably picked up
by a human before he got to it.
Couldn't be...
If that happened to him, he'd have to
follow that person around
until that person dies
or the Death Note is destroyed.
Yeah... I can't picture Ryuk
doing something so tedious.
But I've heard that he was
carrying two Death Notes.
Seriously?
Why would he need two?
I have no idea what drives him to
do what he does.
In order for me to gain
the eyes of a Shinigami...
I have to offer half of my life.
Is that right?
Yeah.
So what'll it be?
Do you wanna make
a deal?
Ryuk.
This deal...
is out of the question.
Listen.
I want to create an ideal,
new world free from criminals.
I also intend to reign as
the god in that world for a long time.
I would consider it if
it lengthened my life,
but it's not worth talking
about if it's going to shorten it.
You, of all people,
should know that.
Yeah, I just felt I should tell
you a deal like this exists.
I don't want you to complain that
I didn't tell you about this earlier.
If you didn't tell me
about this earlier?
Don't you think
you're too late already?
You should have told me this
when we first met
or included this when you were writing
instructions in the Death Note...
Yeah. I guess you're right.
Even though I'm a Shinigami,
he's never been afraid of me or
tried to kiss my butt when
it comes to things like this.
He just gives me a hard time...
Well?
You sure there isn't anything else you
want to tell me ahead of time?
Ryuk, the Shinigami?
Nope, there's nothing else...
Probably...
I see.
How disappointing.
"Disappointing"?
I may have seriously
considered the deal
if you offered me wings
rather than eyes.
Wouldn't flying around in the sky
with wings be godlike?
It's a dream that man
has had since ancient times.
You'd stand out if you sprouted
wings and started flying around.
I'd bet you'd get arrested
by the police just for that.
Ryuk, that was a joke.
However, if I continue to
cut deals for eyes and wings...
I'm going to end up becoming
a real Shinigami.
That could be amusing,
don't you think?
Don't worry.
Even without all that,
you're already...
a fine Shinigami!
The Shinigami Realm is
rotten these days.
They all live vacant lives
and only take human lives...
just because they don't want to die.
No one even knows...
why we exist.
I doubt there's any reason
at all for our existence.
You're much more of
a Shinigami than they are.
Well, from what you're saying, it sounds
like I'm doing a lot more work.
But don't lump me together
with the Shinigami.
I am using this Death Note
as a human for humans.
But, I wouldn't say that
the Shinigami Realm
is meaningless to humans either.
What do you mean?
Well, think about it.
Whenever a Shinigami like you
comes to the Human World
once every hundred, no,
every thousand years,
the Human World
changes greatly.
The Shinigami Realm's existence
is fear-fully meaningful.
I- Is that so?
You just told me that
the Shinigami Realm is rotten.
When you return there,
from this world,
how about using what you've
learned here to try to change it?
Light... you just may be
quite the positive thinker.
Of course, I am.
If I wasn't, I wouldn't be
trying to use
the Death Note to try and
make the world a better place.
That's it!
I've got it!
What's up?
What did you get?
How to find out the name of
the guy who was following me today.
How are you going to do it?
I'm going to use the rules of
the Death Note to my advantage.
If I write the cause of death...
I have an additional
6 minutes and 40 seconds
to record specific conditions
and time of death.
I wonder how free I can
be with these conditions?
I'm going to test it out.
THE FOLLOWING MORNING
Yes, it's me.
Another six inmates?
All heart attacks?!
It's Kira.
What?
Three of them exhibited bizarre behavior
before they died?!
What do you mean?!
They didn't just die from
simple heart attacks?
Well, they died of heart attacks,
but before one of them died...
he drew a strange symbol
on the wall with blood from his finger.
Another left a letter that doesn't seem
like a will or anything meaningful.
The third escaped just to go
to the employee bathroom.
Watari, what is it?
More victims, but their circumstances
are unlike those we've had before.
Unlike those before?
I shall send you an image of
the picture and letter left at the scene.
If you could.
A note describing a fear of Kira.
This can be taken as
something a criminal might do, but...
Kira can control the time of death.
If he can control actions
right before death as well...
that would mean that...
Chief!
Regarding these current victims.
Don't let the media know anything
aside from the fact that
they died of heart attacks.
It's possible that Kira
was performing some kind of test.
If that's the case, we'd only
be giving him the results.
I see...
|- | understand.
Performing tests on criminals?
That's horrible...
He's playing with peoples' lives
as if this is a game.
This is unforgivable!
If Kira is using criminals
as test subjects...
What is he trying to achieve?
Look at this, Ryuk.
The results of yesterday's test have
already been input into Dad's computer.
KIDNAPPING MURDER
What do you mean by that?
One escaped...
and went to the bathroom
I had designated in the Death Note.
Another drew the same symbol
I had drawn in the Death Note.
These three did exactly what I wanted.
I purposely wrote very difficult tasks
for the other three.
DIES IN FRONT OF THE
EIFFEL TOWER FRANCE, TODAY AT 6 P.M.
It's physically impossible to go from
a prison in Japan to France in an hour.
So this never happened and ended
as just a regular heart attack.
The next was to "draw a picture of L's face
on the prison wall," but...
One can't draw the faces...
of people they don't know.
I see.
HEART ATTACK WRITES A NOTE STATING "I KNOW
THAT L IS SUSPICIOUS OF THE JAPANESE POLICE." DIES AT 6 P.M.
I thought this one might work,
but it didn't happen.
Which means that people can't write
about things they don't know or things
they didn't come up with on their own.
In short, it means that even
the Death Note can't do the impossible.
But as long as it's something
the person is realistically likely to do,
I can control them as much as
I want before he dies.
You've figured that out...
But what are you trying to do, Light?
L and the police will never
figure out my true goal.
The great detective
is probably trying
to decipher the picture and
the letter those criminals left.
They're absolutely meaningless
fnal words...
If Kira used those criminals as guinea pigs,
he's about to start something.
If he moves now,
there is the chance that...
the FBI will notice someone
acting suspiciously.
But if he has a different goal in mind...
the letter and picture might
be some kind of message...
Is this it?
L DO YOU KNOW
Well... It's time for the main act.
The "main act"?
Yesterday on the news...
There was a drug addict who tried
to rob a bank,
WANTED CRIMINAL
KIICHIRO OSOREDA
I'll use him.
It's last minute, but I'm sure
I can find someone...
I'll try to ask out a few.
Ask out... "a few"?
Yeah... Ryuk, I may not look it,
but I'm pretty popular.
Hello? Huh, Light?
Good morning...
He's still following me, isn't he?
That's perfect.
If my shadow wasn't here,
there would be no point in what
I'm going to do next.
Light!
- A date?
- Yeah.
It's a date,
no matter how you look at it.
Even to my shadow...
It's not a normal date, is it?
You said you found a way
to find out your shadow's name, but...
What do you plan to do?
Huh? Ryuk, didn't you see
what I wrote in the Death Note?
Nah. It would be boring to peek.
Then just be patient and
watch what happens.
Sorry, did I keep you waiting?
No, not at all!
Anyway, I haven't been to
Space Land since junior high!
I'm so excited!
And I get to be alone with you!
Y- Yeah.
On weekdays, he only goes
to school and his prep courses.
An occasional date on his days off.
He's a normal...
...no, he is a serious
high school student.
Light Yagami, son of Chief Yagami...
No grounds for suspicion.
At any rate...
Today is my last day of
following him.
Light...
Didn't you say that you weren't going out
until entrance exams were over?
Yeah, but I did score number one
in the practice exams.
Your attitude's awful!
It's him! He's here!
Aside from him,
there are seven passengers.
This is going to work out perfectly.
I'm taking control of this bus!
A hijacking!
At a time like this?
Don't make a fuss!
I'll kill anyone that moves.
Driver, you know the phone number
for Space Land's offices, don't you?
- Call them!
- Yes...
T- This is Sasaki, the driver of
bus number 174!
Tell them what's happening!
An armed man has
hijacked our bus!
Give me that.
You hear that? Listen carefully.
Bring Space Land's profits from yesterday
to two bus stops away from there.
Have a woman bring it
by car, alone!
Do it before this bus gets there!
If you try anything funny...
or call the police,
I'll kill all the passengers one by one!
Yuri, don't worry.
I'll look for the chance
to grab his hand...
that's holding the pistol.
That's dangerous. Don't do it.
If it comes to that, I'll do it.
It's all right.
We don't have to pass notes.
As long as we whisper, he won't hear us
over the sound of the bus.
Do you have proof that
you're not his accomplice?
A- Accomplice?
It's pretty common.
The culprit pretends he's alone
and just in case...
he'll leave someone to
keep watch in the back.
What's wrong?
Oh no, do you really think...?
I- I have no choice.
There is no way that
Light Yagami could be Kira.
Kira could kill the culprit
with a heart attack.
Here's proof.
Take a look.
FBI?!
I see, L's using the FBI to investigate
those connected to the Japanese police force!
His name is...
Raye Penber.
I trust you.
I won't ask why an FBI agent
is on board with us... but...
- Do you have a gun?
- Yes, I do.
So if something happens,
I can rely on you, right?
Yes.
Shut up!
Do you want me to beat you to death?
That man! He was on
the Japanese news two days ago.
He's a drug addict who tried
to rob a bank,
killed three civilians,
and ran away.
He's very dangerous.
Every thing will be all right.
He'll never point his gun at us.
Hey, you! Don't move.
What's that piece of paper?
Hey you!
You were planning something back here
with notes, weren't you?
Not good!
If he sees that note from earlier...
He'll discover that Light was planning
to jump him when he had the chance!
MINAMI PARK BUS STOP 11:27
SPACELAND BUS STOP
All right!
W- Who the hell are you?!
You in the back!
W- What are you trying to pull?
H- How long were you
hiding back there?!
Huh? You mean me?
You can see me right now?
D- Don't move!
I- I'll shoot!
You monster!
This isn't good!
He's hallucinating!
Everyone, get down!
Oh, I get it!
That note that Light just dropped...
was cut out of the Death Note.
He has this guy touch the note
and how, only he can see me.
That's so smart.
D- Don't come near me!
Sorry, pal.
I'm a Shinigami,
so that's not gonna kill me.
"Anyone who touches the Death Note
will be able to see me...
"I'm always hovering behind you. "
"Shinigami can't die from gunshots..
That's all stuff I've told Light...
Pretty impressive,
how he put it all together.
It's not surprising he's the nation's top
exam scorer...
He even used this hijacking
to get the name of the guy
who was following him...
without a lot of hassle.
Stop the bus and open the door.
SPACELAND
11:45 on the dot.
Right on schedule...
Wanted criminal, Kiichiro Osoreda,
accidental death.
At 11:31 a. m., he will get on
a bus heading to Spaceland
from the bus stop near
the eastern entrance of the park.
He will enter with a gun,
but will see a phantom from another
world and fires all his bullets at it.
Then, he will flee from the bus...
Immediately afterwards, at 11:45
the same day,
he will die in an accident.
The Death Note never deviates.
You're next, Raye Penber.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
I REQUEST THAT THE FOLLOWING EVENTS
REMAIN A SECRET BETWEEN THE EIGHT OF US.
The remaining agents will
all die of heart attacks.
Farewell, Raye Penber.
TACTICS