Easy easy banzai Easy easy banzai
Easy easy banzai Human
Wanna get them mad? Get them mad?
Get them mad? People
What's up? Full of causes for concern
Crime won't disappear Forever
Hey Hey! A hymn to humanity
Love has gone People, are you worried?
Hey Hey! Subservient People!
WHAT'S UP, PEOPLE?!
Are you worried?
How many seconds has it been
since you wrote down the first name?
35...
36...
37...
38!
39!
I win, Near!
40!
NEW WORLD
We're not dead...
A minute's passed...
But we're not dead!
I've been telling you that
nobody would die.
W- Why?
Why won't they die?!
G- God!
I did as you told me!
Rester, Gevanni, apprehend Mikami.
Gevanni, the notebook.
See for yourselves.
KANZO MOGI - TOUTA MATSUDA
HIDEKI IDE - SHUICHI AIZAWA
Light Yagami.
Mikami called you "God,"
and said that he did
as you told him to...
This proves it.
It's a trap!
This is a trap!
Near set the whole thing up
to frame me!
It's strange that no one's dead
even after their names
were written in the notebook.
That proves that this is a trap!
But I told you that nobody would die
because I tampered
with the notebook.
N- No...
This is impossible!
This is a setup.
I don't know that man.
Light, it's too late.
Near wins.
A second ago,
you said, "| win. "
That's as good a confession as any.
Light...
W- Why?
S- Stop it!
Light Yagami... L...
Kira...
You lose.
You claimed your victory
a moment ago.
To tell the truth, you might actually
have won, and I might have lost.
Things turned out exactly
as you had expected...
And we tampered with
the fake notebook.
But when I said that
I had tampered with it,
I was referring to
the real notebook as well.
We only switched a part
of the fake notebook.
But as for the real one...
We replaced the whole thing.
This is the real notebook.
I- Impossible!
We used the same pen as Mikami,
copied Mikami's handwriting to perfection,
and made the inside and
outside look exactly the same...
Gevanni was able to
do it overnight.
Since I had already touched
the real notebook...
I could see the Shinigami...
Mr. Shinigami, pleased to meet you.
I'm Near.
Nice to meet you. I'm Ryuk.
He's talking to Ryuk...
He can see him,
so he must be telling the truth...
The edges of this page of
the notebook are clipped.
Would someone die if his name were
written on this clipped portion?
Yeah. They'll die.
I thought so...
You probably found many ways
to use this...
I wonder how many times you've killed
and deceived us with this...
Light Yagami. You are Kira.
There's got to be
some sort of trick behind this...
Could Mikami have
double-crossed me?
You're wrong.
I owe this to Mello.
I'm sure you understand
what I mean by that.
Mello?!
Take a good look at this...
KIYOMI TAKADA SUICIDE
BURNS TO DEATH
A plan to kill Takada...
JANUARY 262:33 PM
a minute after I did!
Could it be that Mikami did
the same thing at that time?!
G- God, I thought that you were being
watched and couldn't take action...
I thought it was my job to take care
of Takada in a situation like that...
Idiot!
I've been giving you orders to not
make any unnecessary moves until today!
That's right.
On the 26th, right after Takada's
kidnapping was broadcast...
Mikami went to the bank...
According to my findings,
Mikami goes to the bank
every month on the 25th.
It is very odd for someone
as methodical as Mikami
to go there for two days in a row.
I followed Mikami to
a safe deposit box.
It was only at this time that
Mikami seemed nervous about
someone possibly following him...
It was easy to open the safe.
Inside it...
The real notebook was there and
Takada's name was written in it...
Light Yagami.
You didn't notice that Mikami
took the liberty and made a move...
because you had just killed her
with a clipping from the notebook...
This is when I noticed the possibility
of a fake notebook...
Thanks to Mello...
who was the one
who created this situation.
Mello may have known about it...
...by having his name
written in the notebook?
Yes...
Then I guess I'm going to
have to do it.
Mello knew...
He knew that alone, we aren't able
to attain our goal, to surpass L.
But together...
Together we can stand with L.
Together we can surpass L!
And right now, we are
confronting Kira who defeated L...
with solid evidence!
Let's see you talk your way
out of this if you can.
That's right...
I'm Kira.
That's right. I'm Kira.
So what are you going to do?
Are you going to kill me here?
Listen... I'm Kira.
And...
I'm the god of the new world!
Kira is the law of
the world right now.
Kira is maintaining order.
I am now Justice.
The human race and
the world's only hope.
Are you going to kill me?
Is that really the right thing to do?
Since Kira appeared six years ago...
wars have stopped and global crime rates
have decreased by 70 percent.
But the world is still rotten!
There are too many
rotten people...
Someone's got to do it.
From the moment I got hold of
the notebook, I knew I had to do it!
No, I was the only one
who could do it!
I know that killing people
is a crime...
But this is the only way
to fix the world!
This is a duty given to me!
I'm the only one who can do this!
Could anyone else have done it?!
Could they have done this much?!
Could they have continued on?!
That's right...
I'm the only one who can
create the new world...
No. You are just a murderer.
And this notebook is
the worst murder weapon in history.
You've yielded to the power
of the Shinigami and the notebook.
You're just a crazy serial killer
who has confused himself with a god.
That's all you are...
Nothing more, nothing less.
They're all fools who don't understand.
Near.
The notebook you have right now,
and the notebook that
Aizawa brought from the Japanese
Task Force Headquarters...
Are they real?
Is he blufﬁng now?
Only I know where
the real notebook is...
If you're going to defeat Kira...
even if it's just to test out
the notebook that Aizawa's carrying...
you should write either
my name or Mikami's in it.
To see if the notebook is real...
or fake!
He's hidden
a piece of the notebook!
Matsuda!
You idiot!
Matsuda! Who do you think
you're shooting at?!
Stop messing around!
What was it all for?
What in the world did
your dad die for?
Dad?!
Oh, you mean Soichiro Yagami?!
That's right, Matsuda!
Overly earnest people with
a strong sense of justice like him
are always going to lose.
Are you okay with
a world like that?!
Kill the others if you understand!
Shoot!
You let your father die...
How can you act as if
it were nothing?!
He's writing with his blood!
I'm going to kill you!
We have to kill him!
Matsuda!
Damn it...
What... the hell is this?!
Mikami... What are you doing?!
Write!
Kill.. them!
Near, it's finally over, isn't it?
Yes.
What happened to Misa?!
What about Takada?!
S- Somebody...
What in the world should I...?
M- Mikami is...
Stop the bleeding!
No, but...
There's nothing we can do...
Light!
Light! Wait!
Mr. Aizawa!
He probably doesn't have
any more notebooks hidden.
He can't go very far
with those wounds.
He'll stop on his own
if we leave him alone.
Near, I'm not taking your orders.
I understand. I'll leave it to you.
You lose, Light.
I told you when we ﬁrst met,
that I'd be the one writing
your name...
in my notebook when you die.
That's the rule between
the Shinigami who brings the notebook
into the Human Realm...
and the ﬁrst human
who picks up the notebook.
If they put you in prison,
who knows when you'll die?
And that would be too much of
a pain to wait around for.
It's all over for you.
You should die right here.
We were able to ease each other's
boredom for a long time.
It was a lot of fun.
LIGHT YAGAMI