Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
EXECUTION
Use it just like that to kill
the criminals who are broadcast.
Then, you can use the notebook
however you want.
Those are the conditions.
If everything goes according to
Light Yagami's plans,
this is sure to save Misa...
This is a good deal
for both of us, isn't it?
Or I guess as you would say...
it's good business.
FIFTIETH DAY
There's no reason for you
to stay there like that.
It's been over a month since Kira
started to kill criminals again...
I am sure that my son isn't Kira...
Now, all that's left
is for you to be sure...
I get out when my son does...
The Chief sure is stubborn...
Light, are you all right?
Yeah. I'm all right, but... Ryuzaki...
criminals have stopped dying
since I've been conﬁned.
I think it's highly likely that
Kira is someone
who knows about my situation.
- If we go with this line of reasoning...
- No.
Criminals are not dying
because you are Kira.
No! I'm not Kira.
How many times must
I say it until you'll understand?
Kira should know that killings
have begun again...
It doesn't seem like he knows...
This is cruel, Ryuzaki...
You still haven't told Light that
criminals are being killed again...
Amane...
Yes?
I know you're tired,
but are you all right?
Are you stupid?
There'd be something
wrong with me
if I was all right after
all these days...
Yes, that's true.
Let me go...
I want to see Light...
Light...
it seems like all three
of them are at their limit...
Ryuzaki, why are you
still detaining Light?
You should let him go already!
If you do, the Chief
will come out too.
Criminals are still being killed
even though Misa and Light aren't
able to obtain any information.
We know at least that much.
No.
All we know is that Amane harbors an
unnaturally strong love for Light Yagami.
Ryuzaki... Sorry, but I think
that you're doing this
because you don't want to admit
that you were wrong about Light.
I figured you might think that.
As Light has said, Kira's killed
Lind L.Tailor and the FBI agents.
If Kira could kill under surveillance and
without obtaining information,
there would have been no need
to kill Tailor and the FBI agents!
No matter how hard we investigate,
he can't be traced.
Kira doesn't kill without a reason.
You even said so yourself.
I see...
If he could kill
in these circumstances,
he shouldn't have had a problem
with leaving those FBI agents alone...
It's already been fifty days...
There's no reason to be doing this.
Besides that, we should be thinking
of ways to catch the real Kira.
I understand.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it?
Will you return to
task force headquarters?
I want you to hear my theory
on what's happening.
But ﬁrst, I want to talk to you
as Light's father.
All right.
THREE DAYS LATER
I never thought that you would
be an old man, Mister Stalker.
I'm not a stalker. I'm a detective.
A detective?!
I remember now!
I was told that I was being arrested
for being the Second Kira or something...
That was for real?
No way...
The police wouldn't
tie me up like that...
Anyways, it's kind of funny how
my hands and feet are restrained
even though you're going to let me go?
Be quiet.
- Light!
- Misa?
I was dying to see you!
Dad, what's going on?
Huh? Dad?
Oh no!
I called your dad a stalker and
other rude things like that...
Pleased to meet you.
My name is Misa Amane.
I'm currently going out with Light-!
I leave it to you, Chief.
What's wrong?
Hurry up and get in.
We're finally cleared
and are free to go, right?
No...
You two are now...
being taken to your execution.
An execution ground has been prepared
in an underground facility.
I volunteered to escort you there.
- Our execution?
- What?!
- What are you talking about, Dad?
- This is a joke, isn't it?
L has decided that
Light Yagami is Kira
and Misa Amane is
the Second Kira.
L's declared that if you were executed,
the killings would stop.
Haven't the killings stopped?
No, they're still continuing.
Continuing?
That's not what he told me...
L was trying to get
a confession out of you.
That's not the problem here.
L's suggestion that the killings
would stop if you two were eliminated...
was immediately accepted
by all the top officials of the UN
and the Japanese government.
Kira will be eradicated in secret.
That's crazy.
Wait, Dad, I'm not Kira!
That's right, sir.
What are you thinking?!
He's your own son!
This is not my decision, it's L's.
He has solved many difficult cases
in the past and never been wrong.
Dad...
Do you believe L over me?
L says that if the killings don't stop,
then he'll take responsibility
and end his own life...
L... What are you thinking?
I understand that from the facts
that we have up to now,
this may seem like
the only logical assumption...
But this is wrong!
Why did L come to this conclusion?
Something's strange...
This isn't like L at all...
L's always used hard evidence
in all of his cases.
Why would he let
this one end like this?
We're almost there.
Where are we?
Why did you bring us out to
the middle of nowhere?
What are you going to do?
Are you going to let us go?
Nobody will see us here...
I decided to bring you here
instead of the execution ground.
Light...
I'm going to kill you here
and then kill myself.
What are you talking about, Dad!
- That's crazy!
- Stop it already! You're crazy!
You're going to kill your child
and kill yourself?
If you want to die, then why don't
you just die by yourself!
If you do this, then you'll be
no different from Kira.
No... I'm different from Kira.
I have a responsibility as a parent
and as the Detective Superintendent!
Dad, Misa's right!
If we die here,
we'll never uncover the truth!
It would be better if we ran away!
It's too late, Light...
Either way, you'll be executed...
At least this way... it'll be...
by my own hand.
Stop, Dad! I'm not Kira!
If I die here,
we all fall into Kira's trap!
Don't you see?!
Amane... I'm going to die here
with my son.
I have no reason to kill you.
The police will probably
find this car soon.
You'll be executed
at the planned site.
Light... from one murderer to another,
I'll see you in hell!
Dad!
Stop!
Light... from one murderer to another,
I'll see you in hell.
Dad!
A blank?
Thank goodness...
"Thank goodness?"
What are you doing, Dad?
Forgive me, you two...
This was the only way to
free you from confinement...
But please understand...
I did this because I believe
that you're not Kira...
Were you watching, Ryuzaki?
I did as you said,
and as you can see,
I'm still alive.
Yes, it was a convincing performance.
If Amane were the Second Kira,
who can kill just by
knowing a person's face,
then she would have killed you
before you fired.
Also, if Light were Kira,
the Kira I know would even kill
his parents if he was in trouble.
In Light's case, I cannot deny
the possibility
that he may have discovered
it was all an act halfway through.
But as I promised,
I will end their confinement.
Also as promised,
even though she insists that
those tapes were just occult videos,
we have various pieces of evidence
and a confession that
she sent the Kira videos.
So Misa Amane will remain
under surveillance
until Kira is caught and
his case is resolved.
What's with that?
Do you still suspect me?
Well, you get to return to
your normal life.
If you're not guilty,
you can think of the surveillance
as police protection.
I see. Since I'm not the Second Kira,
I should think of it like
I have some bodyguards.
Also Light...
I will make arrangements so that you
and I will be together 24 hours a day,
working on the investigation.
All right, Ryuzaki.
Let's catch Kira together.
Yes. I'm looking forward
to working with you.
Is this really necessary, Ryuzaki?
I'm not doing this
because I want to.
Huh? Is this what you meant by being
together with him 24 hours a day?
Two guys chained together
is kinda gross...
Ryuzaki, is that what you're into?
I told you I'm not doing
this because I want to.
But, Light belongs to Misa...
If you're together with him
24 hours a day,
then when will I have the time
to go on dates with him?
Dates will be with the three of us.
Huh? Are you telling me
we have to kiss in front of you?
I'm not telling you to do anything.
But I will be watching.
What's with that?
You really are a pervert, aren't you?
Light, please silence Misa.
Misa, don't be selfish.
You were definitely
the one who sent the tapes,
just be grateful that you're allowed
as much freedom as this.
Huh? What are you talking about?
I'm your girlfriend, aren't I?
Don't you trust your own lover?
Girlfriend? You said you fell in love
with me at first sight...
It's one-sided and
you won't leave me alone.
So then, you took advantage
of that fact and kissed me?
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
About this "love at first sight" thing...
It happened in Aoyama
on May 22, didn't it, Misa?
Yes.
Why did you go to Aoyama
on that day?
What did you wear?
I told you, I just happened
to go there.
How many times have I told you?
I don't really remember how
I felt that day or what I wore!
Is it so wrong for me to be
hanging out in Aoyama without a reason?
So when you came back
from Aoyama,
you were in love with Light and
- knew his name.
- Yes.
You don't even know
how you knew his name.
Yes. That's right.
Then, how would you feel
if Light was Kira?
Huh? If Light was Kira?
That's right.
That would be wonderful!
I've always been grateful to Kira
for punishing the man
who murdered my parents.
If Light were Kira,
I'd love him more...
Even though I love him
so much already!
We're talking about Kira, here.
You'd love him even more?
Don't you feel afraid at all?
That's supposing if Light is Kira, right?
He's not scary at all.
I'm one of those people
who accept Kira.
I'd think of ways I could help him.
You'd probably get in his way
rather than help him...
According to this,
there's no mistake that
you are the Second Kira,
but it's so clear-cut that
I don't want to believe it.
Good. Don't believe it,
because I'm not Kira!
Anyway, you'll remain
under surveillance.
When you go out, contact us using
this room's extension.
From now on for private
and work-related affairs,
Mr. Matsuda will accompany you
as your manager, Matsui.
I've already paid off your agency
- to agree to this.
- Hey there, I'm Matsui.
I haven't told the police,
so be sure not to give yourself away.
This old man's gonna be my manager?
How awful...
No way!
What's wrong with me, Misa-Misa?
Cut it outwith all this dating,
kissing, and Misa-Misa talk!
This is the Kira case! Understand?!
Take it seriously!
Sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I know we're taking it seriously, but...
Amane, go to your room now.
What?
No questions, c'mon.
Light! Let's go on a date,
even if it's the three of us!
Light, are you serious about Amane?
No... As I said earlier,
it's one-sided...
Then could you act as
if you're serious?
I'm sure that Amane's connected
with the Second Kira
from the video incident.
And also from the way she loves you...
Are you asking me to become
intimate with her
so I can find out information
about the Second Kira?
Yes. I think you can do it.
And we could get the clues to solve
this case from Amane.
This is why I released both of you.
Ryuzaki...
Even if it's for the Kira case,
I could never toy with
a woman's emotions like that.
I'm sorry,
you need to understand.
To me, taking advantage of another
person's feelings is unforgivable,
and the most despicable thing
a person can do.
There's something wrong...
I can only assume that
his personality has changed...
Is this really an act?
At this rate, it sounds like Amane
was being controlled by Kira, but...
Light Yagami as well...
What's wrong, Ryuzaki?
Nothing. You're right.
But, it would be helpful if
you could make sure
she doesn't leak any information
about the investigation.
Ryuzaki, can't we change this system
of changing hotels every few days?
Yes. I've also been thinking about that.
That's why... construction
started on this immediately after
my first meeting with Mr. Yagami
and the others,
when we decided
to investigate together.
It will be completed in
just a few more days.
This is it.
It has twenty-three floors
above the ground and two below.
It's built so you can't see it
from the outside,
but there are two helicopters
on the roof.
What?!
That's amazing...
I would like all of you to spend
as much time here as possible.
Even if the number of investigators
increases on this case,
we can accommodate
about sixty people.
Misa will get her own floor
so that should keep her happy.
This is really amazing...
but to go to these lengths...
By the way, Ryuzaki, where's the money
to pay for this coming from?
As you can see,
I want to solve this case,
no matter what.
That's what it means.
No, you didn't answer the question.
Yeah, that's right.
The mass murders are bad enough,
but I can't forgive the one who
put my dad and me through all of this.
I want to solve this,
no matter what.
"No matter what"? Then how about
getting closer to Misa
and get her to reveal...
I can't do that.
That's against my code.
I see... That's too bad.
Sorry, I just feel very motivated.
Ryuzaki, Chief Yagami, Light...
Let's all try to catch Kira,
no matter what!
Excuse me...
But you didn't include me...
It seems we're all here.
Then let's begin our meeting.
For the further advancement
of the Yotsuba Group...
and for our company to become
the greatest corporation in the world...
Who shall we kill?
It's tough to kill someone
every week...
This may be irrelevant,
but why has Kira
started killing like this?
Takahashi,
haven't you figured it out?
This is the most advantageous
course of action for Kira.
Advantageous? The fact that
Kira has begun a killing service...
is advantageous, Higuchi?
I think you should keep quiet.
You might be killed
for being such an idiot.
The eight of us here are still young,
but all of us have a chance of
landing in the CEO's chair before long.
And since we started these meetings,
our salaries have been raised well
above the other employees.
It's kind of odd that Kira
would back a single company.
No matter how I think about it...
one of us here has to be Kira.
TAKESHI OOl... EIICHI TAKAHASHI...
MASAHIKO KIDA... KYOSUKE HIGUCHI...
Humans...
are disgusting creatures...
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
This is not good.
The way you talk, it's almost like
you won't be satisfied unless I'm Kira...
Stop messing around, Ryuzaki!
ALLY