SUB CREATED BY SALILA
Strange not seeing
your name up there.
"To improve is to change."
"To perfect is
to change often."
You know your Churchill.
It's inscribed on the watch you gave
me when I left for Glendon Hill.
Was it? Nancy arranges
all the gifts.
She knows you well.
As much as I am
enjoying this little...
I got you two more votes.
Partridge and Krauss.
Is this Raymond's way of
extending an olive branch?
It's a start.
Two votes is a twig.
It's not a branch.
Which is why I'm here.
Well, the vote's at 5:00.
We have less
than three hours.
Two hours and 49 minutes. We
have made more happen in less.
Is that the watch'?
No. Ifs nicer.
So, why did Raymond
have a change of heart'?
If the government grinds to a
halt, that benefits no one.
We want the President
focused on China,
not distracted by
furloughs and protests.
You take direction
from Jacqueline.
She's not gonna
like that very much.
Bossing you around?
Having me around.
Oh, I don't blame her.
Ashleigh will start the
interview with questions about
how you and your husband
met, your early marriage.
Fine.
Then she'll move on to
more specific questions
about your recent transition.
All right.
She's gonna ask about
you having no children.
I thought we'd agreed
to take that off the table.
We did.
But they insisted.
Now I can speak to Ashleigh
directly and fight for...
No. It's fine. I've been
asked the question before.
I know how
to answer it.
It'll be quick
and painless.
And I'll confirm that with
Ashleigh when she gets here.
I like it.
Maybe something
less neutral.
I'm sure you'll look good
in whatever you choose.
I'll be downstairs.
Disori owes you for
the overpass funding you secured.
Yes, he does.
I'll call him.
Where's Doug?
He's doing the rounds, making
sure our hard-won stay hard.
Birch and Womack are doing the same.
But we're still 15 short.
Got relationships
with most of these folks.
Money's not enough. I already
tried the D-trip route.
Retirement age is the main
sticking point, correct?
Old people vote.
I'll target the AARP. That'll
take most of the heat off.
We're wasting time.
I gotta get to work.
Take Remy with you.
Shouldn't we
divide and conquer?
It's harder to say no
twice than once.
I'll stay
out of your way.
Like you did on
the Watershed Act?
We're on the same side
of the fence this time.
You're late to the party.
Well, think of Remy
as the guy
who shows up with a six-pack after
the liquor store is closed.
Who's on your plate?
Donald Blythe.
Do you really think that's
the best use of your time?
lf l can get him
to turn his people.
That's a lot of eggs
to put in one basket
We only have one basket.
Jacqueline, may I use your
office, for old times' sake?
I serve at the pleasure
of the Vice President.
Two hours and 17 minutes.
Normally, all I need to sway Donald
Blythe is patience and time,
neither of which
I have right now.
Tick took.
Donald.
Good to see you.
Mr. Vice President.
Please, it's always
"Frank" to you.
I came because
you asked me,
but don't mistake
that for false hope.
If you have other people
to lobby, you should.
Ten minutes.
It won't change anything.
Well, at the very least,
enjoy the free coffee.
I don't drink caffeine.
Then decaf.
Still has caffeine.
Well, enjoy
the free oxygen.
It's gets stuffy over there
in the Longworth Building.
Coffee for me, and...
Seltzer water,
if you have it.
I'm sure we do.
Now I can understand
if you might hold a grudge.
I don't hold
grudges, Frank.
I just don't negotiate with people
who are fundamentally deceptive.
I never lied
to you, Donald.
You promised to seek my counsel,
which you never once did.
We had to move the Education
Bill in a direction
I knew would
make you unhappy.
I saw no reason
to frustrate...
You eviscerated
the unions.
You federalized
performance standards.
If we hadn't done that,
the bill would've
been dead in the water.
And now you want to cut the
pathetic level of funding
you did manage to pass.
Isn't some funding
better than none?
A flat line will send a louder
message than life support.
Look, I'm impressed with the little
coalition that you've cobbled together.
But we...
Not so little.
Twenty-eight votes.
And you need them all.
Well, really only half.
Half of zero
is still zero.
I had to pull every
trick in the book
to get Entitlement
through the Senate.
If it fails in the House,
we don't get a round two.
This is a one-time deal.
It should never have passed
the Senate to begin with.
Can we start over?
May I offer you an apology?
Deaf ears, Frank.
I withdrew myself from
the Education fight,
and that is
my cross to bear.
But I will be damned if I will
make the same mistake twice.
This sort of stubbornness makes
you no better than the Tea Party.
Except for the fact that we
happen to be right.
Just a few
more minutes, Donald.
You haven't even had
your seltzer yet.
They have seven other data centers
spread across the Northeast.
Those aren't
good odds.
Well, if we
can access one,
I should be able to
talk to the other seven.
And they all
look like that,
Fort Knox wrapped
in a nuclear bunker.
How do we get in?
Well, we don't.
You do.
What?
How'? What's my reason?
You're writing a story
on cyberterrorism.
It's free publicity.
But if they're
so secure, I'm...
They give tours all the time,
mostly to prospective clients.
Then why haven't you
done it yourself?
Because I run
a white hat firm.
And if I were to show up in the
tour logs before a breach,
it would raise alarms.
Okay, once I'm in?
These are what
the servers look like.
You're gonna get inside
one of these cages.
You will have this.
You slide it
into the server.
Voilà.
It's that simple?
Yeah. Well, your part,
not mine.
The codes
extremely complex.
How do I do it without
them noticing?
How you get good
at anything?
Practice makes perfect.
We've got a problem.
Everyone,
stop what you're doing,
head into the nearest
office and shut the door.
You, stay exactly
where you are.
Retirement age
is a done deal,
but I might be able to redistribute
some appropriations...
That's not
what I'm after.
You can't fix a
wrecked car with new hubcaps.
How about a sister bill,
one that focuses
entirely on education?
My coalition is fighting for
the integrity of the party.
We're not just focused on education.
I'm sorry, Donald.
Excuse me for a moment.
Nancy, I said
no interrup...
When?
But the vote is
in less than an hour.
I don't care
what protocol it...
Quarantine. There's white
powder in the mail.
We're locked in?
Sir! Close the door now!
Look, I have to...
Now, sir! Please!
I should call my wife.
And I should call Claire.
Should I tell Connor?
No. It's better
the press doesn't know.
The field tests should
come in before the vote.
And as soon as the Kelly's
in, I'll come home.
How's it looking?
Shaky. We may lose this one.
That could make for
a tough interview.
Well, I didn't want to
do it in the first place.
Well, we're committed now.
I better get back
to the Holy Crusader.
Let me know as soon as
the tests have cleared.
If we're lucky,
it'll be anthrax,
and I won't live long enough
to see the bill fail.
Don't say that.
We're gonna be fine.
How many of these quarantines
we've been through?
I've lost count.
Wish me luck with Donald.
Heels crossed.
It's ripping the caucus apart.
Of course.
We take a united
stand on our version of the bill.
Some of us have to
stay on our feet.
This is about party unity.
It's about
abandoning our base.
No, that's what
the freeze is.
Our base doesn't benefit
from sword-rattling.
It gets left
bleeding on the field.
My district has the third largest
number of seniors in the country.
If we raise the age of retirement,
the AARP will raise hell.
I spoke with the President
of the AARP this morning.
He'll be receiving a $45
million endowment next week.
Voters will
still revolt.
The midterms are gonna be ugly.
Many of us, and I can
certainly speak for myself...
The choice is between immediate
discontinuation of services
and an age bump
five years from now.
You're comparing theoretical
discomfort to imminent pain.
I just feel like we're losing
touch with our core values.
The Education Bill
is a good example.
We all followed
Frank's lead,
hoping it would buy us
traction with the Republicans.
Would you excuse me?
Just one moment.
Does the press know?
Not yet.
Can you keep in
touch with him?
I need to pummel our lunch
guests into submission.
You've got 'em close.
But relax. Listen more.
They want their hands held,
not someone in their face.
I know how to whip votes.
Best caviar in D.C.,
ladies and gentlemen.
We can't let you pay for that.
Then don't eat it.
But if you do,
I won't tell anyone.
You were saying about
the Education Bill?
No, Marjory, honey.
Remember, we just talked about it.
I was telling you...
Right. Nothing
to worry about
If you have any questions, ask Molly.
She knows what's going on.
I will call as soon
as I know anything.
I love you.
How's Marjory?
She's okay.
Long call.
You know,
she gets emotional.
Molly took a semester
off to be at home.
I told her she needs to
head back in the spring.
I don't want her mother
dragging her down.
Must be hard on you.
Harder on the girls, I think.
Is she lucid'?
About half the time.
Just enough to be aware
of how quickly she's going.
Awful.
I feel terrible saying it,
but part of me is looking
forward to her not being lucid.
At least then she won't
realize what's happening.
I should have thought
of this before.
Appeal to the heart,
not the brain.
Forgive my ignorance,
but has there been any
progress with research?
Some.
Genetic testing,
vascular manipulation,
but it's slow.
They won't come up with
anything in time for Marjory.
We're focusing on
quality of life.
Look, I know you have
work to do, so...
I'm no longer the Whip.
That's Jacqueline's job.
I just agreed to meet with you
because we have a history.
She would be tougher
to say no to.
But it still would've
been a "No."
Yes.
I admire your
convictions, Donald.
You're a rare
breed nowadays.
It didn't sound that way
when you were comparing
us to the Tea Party.
I was being unfair.
You're not a reactionary.
You're a progressive.
I see where this is going.
How do you mean?
When you've been in the
wasteland as long as I have,
you become immune to flattery.
Oh.
I know you think I'm
fundamentally deceptive,
but I am capable of
a genuine compliment.
Then I will take it as one,
but it won't
soften my resolve.
If it did, you wouldn't
deserve the compliment
in the first place.
If you vote "No," I won't
hold it against you.
We're all in this together
through the midterms.
But if you stick with me,
we can show both the Republicans
and the American people
that we're capable
of more than stagnation.
And that's worth something,
even it if hurts.
Who can I count on?
Copy that.
The fact that there is
still a door between us,
I take, is a bad sign.
One tested negative,
one inconclusive, sir.
That means we have to take
the samples to the lab.
So, how much longer?
Another three
or four hours,.
We have an important
vote going to the ﬂoor.
I have to be talking
to my people.
The vote is delayed, sir.
We're evacuating this
side of the capitol.
So no vote?
No! until we get
the all-clear.
Good things happen
to good people.
Another thing, sir.
Ali cell phone service,
Wi-Fi, land lines...
We'll be blocking them,
in case there's a
legitimate security threat.
I need to be able
to call my wife.
I apologize, sir. We can
have someone notify her.
No. It needs to be me.
She gets very anxious if she
doesn't recognize the voice.
Congressman, I have strict
instructions not to...
Figure it out, unless you want me
to get the White House involved.
PH find a way, sir.
There are advantages
to being Vice President.
Ma'am? We'll have to ask you lo
remain up here for a little while.
Is it the quarantine?
The Capitol is
being evacuated.
We expect everything
to be fine.
It's just
standard procedure.
You won't be able
to get through.
Communications
are being jammed.
You mean I can't even
speak to Francis?
Not until the all-clear.
How long?
Four hours
is the estimate right now.
We're supposed to
tape in 25 minutes.
Nothing we can do.
You okay?
Yes.
I'll go talk to Emma.
You know, I'm fine.
Thank you.
Em.
So, we might
have a problem.
It's all over the news.
It could be a while.
Can we get audio
from the Vice President?
Communications are being jammed
until the evacuation is over.
Have you spoken
to Ashleigh?
She thinks we should get a sat
truck down here. Wait and go live.
I can't guarantee
when that will be.
The Vice President is
quarantined in the Capitol,
and we have an exclusive.
The network will broadcast
whenever the hell we tell them to.
They're holding off until you get here.
You should do
the interview solo.
I'd rather wait.
Who knows whether
we'll win the vote?
If we lose, I don't want my
face on national television.
This could be
a silver lining.
I don't know, Francis.
I'm sure you'll
be terrific.
Let me run it past Connor.
Okay.
Thank you. We're done.
Sir, we were able to get
Mrs. Blythe.
Oh, Donald...
Marjory?
Hello?
Yes, it's me,
sweetheart.
It's hard to hear you.
We're still stuck
inside the office.
What office?
At the Capitol.
It's going to be
a little while longer.
But why are you there?
It's Sunday.
No, it's Friday,
sweetheart.
Donald?
I'm here.
Who is this man with me?
He's a police officer.
They're using walkie-talkies
so we can speak.
Who am I talking to?
It's your
husband, ma'am.
I'm not married.
It's me. It's Donald.
Turn it off.
I don't know that man.
Marjory...
She went into
the other room, sir.
Okay. Thank you.
If you could stay
with her, please.
Yes, sir.
Drink?
Sure. Why not?
For all we know, it could
be midnight before he's out.
And then he still needs
to manage the vote.
We're fine
if it's 2:00 a.m.
When
everyone's asleep?
People would
stay up for this.
The whole point
was primetime.
Then we
do it tomorrow.
We've already set aside
half a day for this.
The Vice President
can't rearrange
his entire schedule
for an interview.
I don't see
any other options.
I spoke to Francis
over the radio.
We think I should
do it alone.
Just you?
Mrs. Underwood and
Ashleigh, one-on-one.
Maybe we can broadcast his
voice from the Capitol.
Francis doesn't want the entire
interview to be about the quarantine.
Neither do I.
That's just spectacle.
The quarantine is news.
We have a unique opportunity.
Fine. We're done.
What? Cancel the interview.
No reschedule.
Come on, Connor.
Please pack up
everything and leave.
Okay. Let me
call Ashleigh.
I thought I'd get
used to it, but no.
Hurts every time.
You spend 30 years
with someone,
and then they don't have
a damn clue who you are.
Ugh. I really shouldn't...
If we never did anything
we shouldn't do,
we'd never feel good about
doing the things we should.
Excellent point.
And if these are our
last moments on Earth,
I don't know about you, but I'd
rather go out with a buzz on.
To Marjory.
You love her dearly.
More than anything.
I can't imagine what
I'd do without Claire,
or if she didn't
remember who I was.
Hopefully,
you'll never have to.
Well, it makes me angry that
you do, that anybody does.
No sense being angry over
what you can't change.
How much funding does
Alzheimer's research get?
Just under $500 million.
Well, I'm no expert, but that
sounds inadequate to me.
It is.
For every $100 we
allocate to research,
we spend nearly
$30,000 on care.
We ought to change that.
I tried. My bill didn't
even leave committee.
Who opposed it?
Howard Webb.
Ugh...
Appropriations.
He didn't even
put it to a vote.
I've never been
fond of Howard.
That makes two of us.
What was his argument?
He didn't feel
he owed me one.
"Fiscally irresponsible,"
is all he said.
Walk me through
the specifics of your bill.
I see what you're doing.
Doing what?
You're disgusting, Frank.
Excuse me?
Using my wife.
Donald, what are
you saying?
You think I'll
give in on Entitlement
if you slap some extra Alzheimer's
funding on the table?
I was not suggesting
that at all.
Bullshit, Frank.
You think as little
of me as you want,
but I do not barter
with people's health.
Then why are you trying to
raise the age of retirement?
Medical research we can afford.
Medicare, we can't.
There are realities,
Donald.
Don't talk down to me
about realities.
My wife is dying.
That's a reality.
Other people will die, too,
if your package succeeds.
That's a reality!
God damn it! I wish I wasn't stuck
in this fucking room with you.
Donald?
I'm done talking.
One more time.
I've got it. I want it
to sound more natural.
Francis and I wanted to devote
our lives to public service.
And we didn't feel that
we could both do that
and be the parents
we wanted to be.
And by making
that choice,
it allows more time for us to
be in the service of others.
Good. That sounds good.
We need you,
Mrs. Underwood.
Keep Derek
at the Capitol.
I want quotes from evacuees
and Homeland Security.
And Sarah should be finishing
that history of biohazard scares.
I'll be there soon.
I have to go.
No. We're not done yet.
This is a major story.
I'll come back tomorrow.
You've come here
two days in a row,
and this is how
patterns emerge.
The FBI likes patterns,
and we do not give the FBI
what the FBI likes.
I can't disappear all day
in the middle of...
I have eight reporters
out in the field, okay?
Stop.
Tell me why
I purchased Cashew.
I don't know.
Companionship?
Yes.
More importantly,
a reminder that
lam never more than one wrong
move away from life in a cage.
You stay.
I'll walk you through every
line of code I intend to write,
every attempt I make
to breach the wall.
If we get caught, you don't
get to plead ignorance.
We go down together.
No, I didn't sign up
for Bonnie and Clyde.
You need me for this one thing.
Just like I need you.
But whatever you've done
before me, that...
You know where I live.
And you know who I am.
Sit down.
The sooner we start,
the sooner we finish.
The Capitol
is still on lockdown,
as HazMat crews continue a
thorough sweep of the building.
Earlier this morning,
a white powder-like substance was
found in a package...
...mailed to the office of
Majority Whip Jacqueline Sharp.
Are we free to go?
HAZMAT CHEF:Almost, sir. Less than an
hour. I've got a message from your wife.
What is it'?
She's doing the interview
live right now.
Congressman Donald
Blythe and 14 of Miss Sharp's staff.
The secrets...
Mrs. Underwood,
I so appreciate
you taking the time to speak
with us today in what,
I am certain, is a very
stressful situation.
Thank you, Ashleigh.
Have you spoken with
your husband today?
Yes, I did. And he's
in very good spirits,
and in good hands with
the Secret Service.
Of course, he's very disappointed
he couldn't be here.
Well, our thoughts
are with him and everyone else
quarantined at
the Capitol today.
Thank you.
I'd like to begin
with Claire Underwood
before you met
your husband, in Texas.
And I have
a couple of pictures.
Oh, no.
Yes.
Oh, my goodness.
That was Red.
An accomplished rider?
An enthusiast.
This one's from
a couple of years later.
Oh, my goodness.
You like those penny loafers?
Those are...
Those are two
very different girls.
Which one are you
more comfortable being?
My family's ranch.
That was home for me.
You didn't like
the prep school?
No. I think I
preferred the dirt.
You grew up in Dallas, though.
Um, Highland Park.
Yes. My father, well,
he was a businessman.
So' we lived in the city,
but we're ranchers.
I mean, we go back three
generations, our family.
Your parents
were very wealthy.
We were comfortable, yes.
They made sure
I wanted for nothing.
It was a very
happy childhood.
What is your most vivid
memory from that time?
My most vivid memory.
Wow. Um...
Probably when I was
about nine or 10,
my father took me to Dealey
Plaza, where Kennedy was shot.
And he said, "Claire,
a great man died here."
And I remember
not fully comprehending
the meaning of death yet.
And I asked him how he
died, and he told me.
And I remember feeling
so sad, so angry.
It seemed so unfair.
I started to cry, and
my daddy picked me up.
And he wrapped his arms
around me, and he said,
"Don't be sad,
sweetheart.
"He made the world
a better place,
"but sometimes that
comes at a price."
I guess that was
the most vivid memory.
We are
only eight votes away.
I'm sorry.
I've made up my mind.
Me, too. I've gotta stick
to my guns on this one.
You would rather let
the government shut down...
Hey, don't put
that on us
just because we're on the
ass-end of the whip list.
Don't get us wrong. We have a
lot of respect for you, Jackie.
You're doing a fine job
since Frank's gone.
Different styles,
but a fine job.
Excuse us just a moment.
They're not
taking me seriously.
'Cause you're not Frank.
You mean because
I'm not a man.
No. I mean Frank.
They're used to being
offered something.
Ask them what they want.
I know Paul needs help with
a waste-treatment facility.
You're being just as
condescending as they are.
Take some good advice
when you get it.
I was right earlier,
wasn't I?
Paul, Remy tells me you need
a waste treatment plant.
We've had some trouble getting
matching federal funds.
Ben, you mentioned once a
winery museum in your district?
We are making some great wines
in Long Island these days.
I've tried some.
It tastes like piss,
compared to what
we have in Napa,
the sort of piss that belongs in
Paul's waste treatment plant.
Jackie. We have a
possible terror attack,
and you're holding out
your plates for more pork.
You should be ashamed
of yourselves.
In my caucus, people are
rewarded for good behavior,
not trading their
votes for ransom.
When we walk in there,
I expect the both of you
to vote "Yes,“
without a moment's
hesitation.
Thank you for your
change of heart.
Six more to go.
You left Texas and spent the
last two years of high school
at the prestigious
Phillips Academy.
And then,
on to Radcliffe.
Yes.
Where you would meet
the future Vice President.
Back then, just a
dashing law student.
I never dreamed he would become
Vice President, of course.
Some people think that
your marriage may be a bit more
calculated than you let on,
that perhaps he needed
your family's money.
No. That's just not true.
Your father did contribute
an awful lotto his campaign.
Yes, he did. Because he
believed in Francis.
Would he have won
that campaign
had it not been for your
father's contributions?
I don't know. I mean,
it certainly helped.
But I like to think that it was
Francis' ideas and leadership
that convinced voters,
not just TV commercials.
You've been
married 27 years.
That's right.
You were just in school.
I mean, you married so young.
We did.
But when you've
found the one...
Well, Francis was the one.
You call him Francis.
Well, back home,
they call him Frank, still.
But he likes that
I call him Francis.
He said that it makes him
sound more sophisticated.
Is it hard being
a politician's wife?
It's thrilling.
Not without
its challenges.
Always in the background,
subsuming your goals
for his goals.
No, I don't see it that way.
We're two very
independent people
who have chosen to
live our lives together.
I support him.
He supports me.
Which, you know, goes back
to the political partnership.
Well, my husband happens
to be a politician,
and I happen to do
political work.
But our partnership
extends far beyond that.
Children.
Was that a sacrifice?
Because you haven't had any.
Francis and I wanted to devote
our lives to public service.
And we didn't feel that
we could both do that and be
the parents we wanted to be.
So, we made the choice.
We've heard that
answer before.
Sorry?
You have given the exact same
answer in previous interviews.
Because it's the truth.
Forgive me,
but career and timing,
uh, those are often
very convenient answers.
It is true that
whatever it takes
for people to get
from "maybe" to "yes"
never arrived for me.
Never felt the pressure?
No maternal instinct?
No.
And it was a choice?
It wasn't because you
couldn't have any?
Well, Francis and I did
what was right for us.
Because it is unusual,
I mean, even now, for politicians
at the executive level
not to have children.
Yes, it is.
In your husband's
second congressional campaign,
there was a Republican,
a pro-family candidate,
who made some pretty
unsettling accusations.
Well, Francis is a Southern
Democrat, and we have thick skins.
He suggested,
in order to keep your husband's
political career on track...
Children are the center
of many people's lives.
And I think they just
want to make sure that
their representatives will fight
for their children's dreams.
And Francis has, again and
again, proven that he will.
And he will continue Io
do so as Vice President.
He claimed that you may have been
pregnant during the campaign.
Was there a pregnancy?
Have you ever been pregnant?
Break. Now.
That's not gonna happen.
Yes.
During the campaign?
Before.
Was it a miscarriage?
No.
Did you...
Did you terminate
the pregnancy?
If I said "yes,"
my husband's political career
would be in jeopardy.
My faith would
be questioned.
Likely, my life
would be threatened.
But I won't feel ashamed.
Yes, I was pregnant. And,
yes, I had an abortion.
Can you excuse me
for one moment?
Of course.
We'll have more of
our live interview
with Claire Underwood
in a moment.
That took a lot of guts.
Yes, it did.
No. It'll look like I am ashamed.
I'm not. And I won't.
Nothing you can say
will make this any better.
I'd rather deal
with the damage...
I'm not going
to run from this.
She's gonna ask why
you had the abortion.
I haven't had one.
I've had three.
Three? No.
You need to stick to one.
Okay, fine.
Tell me what you'll say.
Well, I can't use
the real reason.
The first two, I was a
teenager, and I was reckless.
What about the third?
Well, the article that
she showed, it's right.
I was on the pill.
It didn't work.
We talked about
having a baby,
and then we
decided against it.
Why?
Because we were focused
on the campaign.
How many weeks in'?
Sixteen.
You can't say any of this.
Go upstairs.
I'll deal with Ashleigh.
If we're going to continue,
we've got about 20 seconds.
Connor, I...
Please, trust me.
You'll be making
a big mistake.
Are you willing to discuss
the circumstances?
I became pregnant as a
result of a sexual assault.
Are you saying
that you were...
Raped.
You've never spoken
publicly about this before.
No one ever asked.
Can you
tell us what happened?
It was college.
A classmate,
we were dating.
And it happened on a...
We had a fight, and he
forced himself on me.
Did you tell anybody
about it? Did he...
Was he charged?
No.
Because at the time, I felt
that I was somehow at fault.
I knew I wasn't, but I just
didn't want to be stared at.
I didn't want to be known as
"the girl who got raped".
And when I became pregnant,
I wasn't going to
drop out of school.
I wasn't going to let
this man ruin my life.
So' I made a choice.
I ended it.
But if you never
told anybody about it,
the assailant could
still be out there.
Can you tell us
anything about him?
I saw him for the first
time in almost 30 years,
just a few months ago.
Where?
At a commissioning ceremony
that Francis and I attended.
Did you speak to him?
Briefly. Francis
pinned stars on him.
He was being commissioned?
General Dalton McGinnis.
And for the record,
Francis has always known
about the assault.
He just didn't
know the name.
And he's been nothing but
supportive all these years.
We're gonna have to
reach out to the General, um,
for a response to
what you just said.
Would you mind if
we took a quick break?
Absolutely.
We'll be right back with
Mrs. Claire Underwood.
Take all the time
you need.
The lab tests all came
back negative, sir.
What was it?
Talcum powder
laced with ﬂour.
It was pesticide from the wheat
that gave us the false positive.
So, are we free to go?
Yes, sir.
Nancy, tell 'em
I'm on my way down.
I already did.
Mind if
I use your phone?
Of course.
And, Donald? I'm gonna get
you that research funding,
no matter how
the vote goes.
It's your call, because I'm
still voting against it.
I understand.
You have a brave wife, Frank.
So do you, Donald.
Frank!
How'd you do?
We're down to four.
How about Blythe?
He won't budge.
What did you offer him?
Alzheimer's research.
He was insulted.
The vote's in 45 minutes.
I need to get to Claire. Who
should I call from the car?
We've exhausted
our options.
It's either Blythe's people,
or it won't pass.
They're too loyal to him.
Okay. Go.
I'll figure it out.
I can stay if
you need me.
No, get to your wife.
I know where to find you.
Nancy, I need every
ream of paper you have.
And get me dollies.
Almost done.
Twenty more minutes.
I hate lying.
Did he do it?
Yes.
Then don't feel bad.
What if he denies it?
Then we'll
cross that bridge.
Connor?
Give us one more minute.
We have a young woman on
the phone, a private.
She says she was also
assaulted by the General.
Two years ago.
She wants to share her story,
but she won't give her name.
We can't put her on
if she's anonymous.
You want me to
convince her?
She's frightened.
Is she still on the phone?
WOMAN OVER PHONE:
I've never told anyone.
It took me almost half my life
before I could say anything.
But you can say
something now.
I don'! know.
Just think of how many
others there must have been.
But you want me to talk.
Well, would you have called
if you didn't want to?
I didn't think
I'd have to use my name.
Listen, I understand you're
afraid of the consequence.
I'm a private.
He's a general.
And my husband is the Vice
President of the United States.
We will protect you.
I promise you that.
What's your name?
Private Megan Hennessey.
What is this?
The names of every
person in America
who will lose home care
when the freeze sets in,
who will lose half
their welfare benefits,
who will go on furlough,
who will lose
their student loans,
transportation services,
post-combat counseling.
Shall I go on?
This is about the big
picture, Jacqueline.
This picture looks
pretty big to me.
I can't vote
for the package.
Then don't.
Just get four of
your people to do it.
And then work with me
after we avoid the freeze.
I'm not Frank Underwood.
At least two other girls
that same year.
If that was true for all
the years he's served...
It's just staggering.
And I felt so helpless.
And he keeps rising in the ranks.
The system protects him.
Why do you think
no one has ever reported him'?
Do you wanna
join her?
We know
it won't do anything. No.
Chain of command.
It's inexcusable that you're willing
to put your life on the line
to defend our freedom,
and yet you don't feel the
freedom to come forward.
I love my country. And I
love sewing in the Marines.
But not like this.
Private Hennessey,
thank you for your courage
in joining us tonight.
It was Mrs-
Underwood who gave me the courage.
And Mrs. Underwood,
thank you for your honesty.
Sir, your wife
is on the phone.
You've given us
a great deal to think about.
Thank you, Ashleigh.
And that concludes
our live one-on-one
exclusive interview
with Claire Underwood.
You can watch the entire
interview on our website.
And as always,
we invite you to give us
your thoughts and your comments
on Facebook and on Twitter.
But for now, thanks for
watching, and good night.
And we're out.
This is going to make waves
like you never imagined.
Thank you.
Where's Carter?
You'll be
reporting to me now.
And who are you?
Carter's boss.
You're doing
good work, Gavin.
But you can't be
assaulting the target.
That could compromise us.
I don't even know why you're
going after this guy.
He's small-time.
That's not your concern.
He couldn't write a line
of code to save his life.
He intends to commit
an act of cyberterrorism.
Well, that's intention,
not capability.
He's not a real threat.
Maybe Carter talked
things outwith you.
I won't.
How much longer?
Until what?
Until I can stop.
Do you prefer prison?
I've given you eight
child pornographers,
three botnet masters...
But you still haven't
given us AV unit.
Well, Hold Carter
I don't know where he is.
Yes, you do.
I don't.
Nobody does.
Then what about your
friends in DecSec?
I'm not giving
you my friends.
Then you can
keep doing this.
You're a productive
asset, Gavin,
but the moment you stop
being productive,
no lawyer can help you.
Wish we had the real
thing right now.
Always prepared.
Francis.
I've missed this.
So have I.
Shouldn't you be on the phone
getting your accolades?
That can wait
till tomorrow.
Sing me something.
What do you
want to hear?
Anything.
♪ Polly, pretty Polly
Would you take me unkind?
♪ Oh, Pally, pretty Polly
♪ Let me set beside you
And tel! you my mind
♪ Well, my mind is to marry
And never to part
♪ My mind is to marry
♪ The first time I saw you
You wounded my heart
♪ Oh, Polly, pretty Polly
Come go along with me
♪ Before we get married
Some pleasures to see
Some pleasures to see I