SUB CREATED BY SALILA
Evelyn.
Mr, Danton.
Remy.
How are you?
I'm okay. I'm good.
Been a while.
Yeah, it has.
Good morning.
Mr. Vice President.
Chief Whitehall.
Is Andrew Jackson
going to be joining us?
No, I'm sorry.
That's a terrible oversight.
Doug, will you remove that?
Why don't we take
the photograph first?
Thank you.
Please, have a seat.
Let's talk
federal recognition.
Your tribe has
waited long enough.
Who is it?
It's me. It's Lisa.
Can I come in?
Temp jobs, mostly.
Clerical work.
Right now, I'm doing part-time at
a dentist's office, reception.
You deserve better.
It is what it is.
This is the first time
I've had Starbucks
since I can remember.
It's a luxury
for me these days.
Maybe there's something
for you at Glendon Hill.
That's nice of you to say,
but I'm not the right fit
for a place like...
Sure you are. 20 years' experience
in the non-profit sphere.
We coordinate all
the time with NGOs.
You'd be
a valuable asset to us.
Claire should have
never let you go.
Yeah.
Well, I'll hold my tongue.
She and I don't talk.
We had a falling out.
Loyalty isn't her thing.
No, it is not.
I don't think
she's loyal to anyone.
Except maybe her husband.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
What do you mean?
Nothing I know for certain,
but spend a decade working
for someone and...
She threaten you
or anything?
No. She just wouldn't leave.
It's not like I wanted
to call the cops.
She's not a bad person.
No, no, but...
I tried to talk to her.
Then she lit up a pipe.
Meth?
Yeah.
When we were roommates,
that's all it was.
I used to be
really deep into that.
Heroin, too.
And then I found
the fellowship...
What can I do?
I'm sorry. I shouldn't...
No, I'm glad
you came here.
I know
you're late for work.
I'll call in sick.
Don't do that.
It's fine. I'll go.
Stay here. I mean,
don't go back there.
Are you sure?
Keys.
In case you need
to come and go.
I'll be back around 7:30.
Thank you.
You don't have to thank me.
All the President has to do
is pick up the phone,
and the bridge is approved.
If the President had
wanted to be involved,
he would have
already made that call.
It's his initiative, Linda.
Was his initiative.
We're in a trade war now.
But that doesn't mean we
have to abandon good policy.
It's inconsistent
with his current stance.
The Committee on Foreign Investment
has 30 clays to approve.
There's only six days left. They
won't act without a directive
from the President
of the United States.
I'm confused.
You've been
the biggest proponent
of a strong position
against China.
That is not true. I advocated
the opposite early on.
You seem fixated
on this bridge.
Is something
else going on here?
Unemployment is at 9.2.
Inflation is skyrocketing.
We're on the verge
of losing our majority.
The President needs to offer
a piece of good news.
A bridge? That's
a drop in the bucket.
Jobs, infrastructure, deficit reduction.
You think...
You're still not being
straight with me.
I have no
ulterior motive here.
But if you feel
that strongly,
and the President
feels that strongly,
then I'll back off.
I won't mention it again.
I think that's
a wise decision.
We should be
a united front.
I couldn't agree more.
Thank you.
Why does everything have
to be a struggle?
Can't some people
just say yes for once'?
Sir?
I need the President's schedule
for the next two days.
She change her mind?
What do you think?
So what's
our next move?
I'll focus on the bridge. You
talk to the Indian Affairs.
The sooner that Whitehall's
tribe gets recognized,
the sooner they can break
ground on that casino.
Yes, sir.
Maybe it'll help me, you know, if I
talk about it more, in the open.
I mean, that's what
your interview did.
When I called, when I could
say those things out loud...
Well, we don't want you
lo feel obligated.
I know the press
hasn't left you alone.
If they're gonna keep
taking pictures of me,
I should at least
say something.
Well, it's only gonna
become more intense
as McGinnis gets closer
to his court-martial.
Yeah, I know.
I'm prepared.
If you come and speak to the
Armed Services Committee,
tell your story,
I feel confident we
can get it to a vote.
There'll be too much
coverage to ignore it.
And you think
it will pass?
We need to get it
through committee first.
But let's be clear, Megan.
It's not just the testimony.
We'll need you lo do
a media avail after.
Photo ops,
a statement.
Okay.
You won't be alone. I'll be
standing right next to you.
And so will I.
Okay.
Do you think we're
doing the right thing,
hauling her in
front of the cameras?
We have to trust her when
she says she wants to.
But it's very important that the
White House backs us up on this,
not just you.
I'm not sure if Garrett
will gel involved publicly.
Well, can you
talk to him?
We haven't been doing much
talking about anything lately.
Things haven't
gotten any better?
We haven't said a word to
each other in almost a week.
I've been there.
It's awful.
With Frank?
Sure.
What did you do?
We saw someone.
You mean a therapist?
Weren't you
worried about exposure?
He was a minister. He
wasn't exactly a therapist.
It was more like a spiritual
guidance type thing.
The only difference was
he had a degree.
I could put you
in touch'
It's too risky.
Just a suggestion.
Let me know if you
change your mind.
Thanks.
In the meantime, can you
try to talk to Garrett?
We really need his
support with this.
I will.
Yes?
Show him in, please.
Remy.
So formal.
Would you have a seat?
You shouldn't keep
your interns so late.
You and I might not have
lives, but they do.
When there's work to be done, we work.
They know that.
Why am I here at
10:00 at night?
Where is the GOP
getting their money?
That is a 25-million-dollar
question, isn't it?
You must have an idea.
What makes you think that?
Because you know things.
That's why Glendon Hill
made you partner.
Most of our clients
are Democrats.
I'm just as much
in the dark as you are.
I'm losing in
my district, Remy.
And I wish I could help you.
Even if I pull off a win,
it doesn't matter.
The GOP takes the House,
I lose my spot in the
leadership, this office,
everything I've worked for.
I feel for you.
But you want information
I don't have.
Are you upset about the last
time we saw each other?
Not at all.
I made myself clear.
Can we talk?
No work, no politics.
We can talk about
whatever you want.
I've never been with anyone
for more than six months.
When I was in the Army,
I was always on the move,
and since I've been in Congress,
I just haven't had time.
I wasn't asking to
marry you.
Just to be more than
company for a night.
Do you still want that?
I'm here, aren't I?
There would have to be
clear boundaries.
Whatever we have
privately couldn't
affect our professional
relationship.
Then we shouldn't be having this
conversation in your office.
I'm glad we
had this meeting.
If you'd like to have
another, just call me.
We can leave the
secretaries out of it.
I'll review this and
have Linda get in touch.
Thank you, sir.
Good morning,
Mr. President.
Hi, Frank.
I left my bourbon
at home,
but you have some
time for coffee?
I'm fine. You go ahead.
I wanted to talk to you about
the Port Jefferson Bridge.
Linda told me
you two spoke.
Have you reconsidered?
No, it's not
the right time, Frank.
We'll find some other project
to showcase our program
once tensions subside.
During the campaign,
you repeatedly promised to
address critical infrastructure.
We're well into
your second year.
This project
is ready to go.
You don't want to have to
start from square one.
Well, I'm
thinking midterms.
We have to
project consistency.
Except people don't vote
for consistency.
They vote for
concrete progress.
Linda mentioned that you seemed
obsessed with this bridge.
I'm beginning to
think she was right.
The back-stabbing,
vomit-inducing bitch.
Is she right, Frank?
Tell me why this bridge
is so important to you.
I wanted to insulate
you from this.
From what'?
You asked me to backchannel
with the Chinese,
and I have continued
to do so.
No. I told you
to stop backchanneling,
and you did anyway, without
informing me? Frank...
I needed to
distance you.
There are issues that a
president cannot be aware of.
What issues?
But what
I can tell you
is that the building of this
bridge directly affects
our ability to combat the
Republicans in the midterms.
Are the Chinese...
Mr. President,
you are asking questions you
do not want the answers to.
How much danger
are we in, Frank?
None, if we end this
conversation right now.
Sometimes I feel like
I'm losing control of my own
goddamn administration.
You're under pressure, sir, but
you're not losing control.
You have people who are
looking out for you.
Me, Linda, your wife.
Might be losing
control of her, too.
I shouldn't have said that.
Of course she
wants the best for me.
Has Claire said anything?
I mean, I know they talk.
Not much.
Just that things
have been a little rocky.
That's an understatement.
You have the most
difficult job on Earth.
It would take
a toll on any marriage.
Which is why
I'm urging you
to reconsider your
decision on the bridge.
And I'd say that
not as your Vice President,
but as your friend,
because I care
about you.
All right, I'll have
another look at it.
Thank you, Mr...
Thank you, Garrett.
Mr. Frost.
Morning.
We filed all of
our paperwork back in 2006.
We dotted all of our I's and
crossed all of our T's.
There's over
317 applications.
Each one requires at least
a year to review.
You need more researchers.
It's not just personnel.
There's travel, filing,
administration.
Name the figure.
Twelve, 13 million.
That requires
an appropriation
from Congress.
The Vice President can
make that happen.
But first we need you to
recognize the Ugaya tribe.
Our policy is first
come, first serve.
There are applications
which we have to...
Daniel Lanagin
dis-enrolled us.
We lost our right
to BIA benefits.
Is this more about
starting a casino?
It's about correcting
an injustice.
I can't be getting involved
in inter-tribal conflicts.
Yes, you can.
If you want
that appropriation.
Two months. Maybe less if
all the ancestry holds up.
Lanagin knows.
And what did he say'?
He wants to meet.
But on his turf
this time.
I need a way to
get to Missouri
without attracting
any attention.
Womack's district's in Kansas City.
it's not far from the casino.
See if he has any events coming up.
Rallies, fundraisers.
How's it coming with
co-sponsors for Claire's bill?
Terrific. We're making
great progress.
One speech. It'll send
a message to Congress that...
And a message to the Joint
Chiefs that I'm trampling on...
Twenty four thousand
assaults last year.
Only 3,000 reported,
because they're...
I know the figures.
Do you know how many suicides
result from the trauma that...
It's not a question
of statistics.
This bill will save lives.
Can we discuss
this later?
I had to schedule this
meeting, Garrett.
It's the middle of the day, Patricia.
You know very well how my...
Don't make me lobby you when I go home.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
Mr. President.
The Secretary-General
is here.
Two more minutes.
It's 12:30. He was
scheduled for 12:15.
I'll go.
You were supposed
to tell me to stay,
but it's nice to know I'm
worth at least two minutes.
Hi, Tricia.
No, please,
don't worry about it.
Oh, that's awful.
Yes, of course. Let me
grab his number for you.
Mmm-hmm.
Right.
His name is
Dr. Thomas Larkin
at 202-251-6258.
And if you'd like, I can
give him a call beforehand
and let him know
you'll be reaching out.
Okay. Well you let me know
if I can be of any help.
Good night, Tricia.
What do you think?
We'll see.
The idea is to take color
theory and turn it on its head.
Break all the rules.
They're gorgeous.
Who'd you say
your client is?
I didn't.
I was just wondering
if maybe I knew him.
You don't.
Let's say he's a collector always
on the lookout for new talent.
I understand you work
for Adam Galloway.
Yeah.
It's a way to
pay the bills.
I mean, Adam's
a good photographer
if you like
that kind of thing.
I'm much more
interested in form.
How much for
all of them?
What?
I'd like to buy them all.
Missouri is the
Show Me State for a reason,
and we need to show
the rest of America
that we can keep
our leadership intact.
It is a pleasure to look out and
see a room full of smiling faces.
That's not something you see every day
in Washington, D.C.
What did your editors say?
Five thousand words.
This should be twice that.
I can probably
get them to eight,
but I'm gonna need
the First Lady, too.
Separate interviews.
Let me talk
to Mrs. Underwood.
Hey, how come you're coming
to me with this instead of Connor?
Between you and me, he's out.
Got a job at SpaceX.
His choice,
or was he pushed out?
People don't like working with me, Matt.
You may be the only one.
No, I don't
like you, either.
I might if you get me
the First Lady.
They'll both be speaking
to Armed Services tomorrow
along with Megan Hennessey.
She's the one who the general was...
That's right.
I'll set up a one-on-one,
texture for your piece.
All right.
Let me know, man.
Anything for
the Times, Matt.
the Times, huh?
And we get shut out
of donor meetings.
The magazine. And yes.
Raymond Tusk. Your boss went
to see him last October.
It's in his congressional
travel report.
Before my time.
You said they
didn't communicate.
I said not to
my knowledge.
We're in Missouri.
He's not
one of the donors.
I can quote you on that?
If you spell my name right.
Now, normally, I don't
quote northern writers.
But every now and then,
one of them says something that makes
a lot of sense.
And this Emerson fellow
you've probably heard of
once wrote that, "The only way
to have a friend is to be one."
And I think you all know
what kind of a friend
that Terry has
been to this district.
So I'm proud to introduce him
today and to call him my friend.
Would you please welcome
the Majority Leader,
Representative Terry Womack.
Thank you,
Mr. Vice President.
And I would like
lo thank all of you.
We all set'?
I told the press
you're having some
private meetings
with contributors.
Thank you.
AW protests?
Oh, we're good,
except for Ayla Sayyad.
Thank you.
What's going on?
Potential blind spot.
Tell me on
the way to the car.
Mr. Vice President.
Thank you.
Calm down. Now.
Welcome.
What a pleasant
surprise, Raymond.
Mr. Vice President.
I was expecting to see you
privately today, Daniel.
When it's
a serious matter,
I invite all the chiefs
lo the circle.
Nice pool.
I've never swum in it.
The chlorine hurts my eyes.
You're welcome to take a
dip in it if you'd like.
Another time.
Well, Raymond tells me
you're a ribs man.
Well, I've got three of the
choicest pieces of meat
you'll ever see in
your life coming out.
You do not want
to pass on this.
I won't be here long.
So, the Ugaya band.
Tip of the iceberg.
Mmm.
They're not
a real tribe.
They're
about to be.
No, they're a bunch
of troublemakers
with too much
hope on their hands.
Once they get recognized, they're
gonna have their own casino.
In two years?
At best?
Well, you better enjoy
this pool while you can.
I don't think your casino can
stand that sort of competition.
Who do you think Whitehall called
as soon as he left the BIA?
You offered them a casino
two years from now.
We offered what
they really want.
Re-enrollment
in my tribe.
The tip of your iceberg
is melting, Frank.
And you do not have time
on your side.
So, how about this?
You help me repair my
relationship with Garrett.
Dan and I here get the money flowing
back in the right direction.
How about this?
I get the BIA to
investigate both of you.
Connection to
Feng, launder...
You could.
But you won't.
You don't dare.
My money has been going
to the Democrats for nine years.
You were the Whip
for all of them.
You implicate us,
you implicate yourself
and everyone in
the leadership.
Ah, here comes the steak.
Oh.
Now, you are going
to enjoy this, Frank.
There you go.
Thank you.
Now, dig in, Frank,
before the flies get to it.
I'll pass. Thanks.
Are you sure?
This is soy-fed
Matsusaka beef.
You know, my ancestors
would have prayed to this heifer
to honor her spirit.
But at 200 bucks a pound,
I figure, fuck tradition.
Come on. Live
a little, Frank.
Mr. Vice President.
Not my
vice president.
You're on sovereign land.
Dogs are so predictable,
aren't they?
Setup a meeting with Walker.
Tonight, if possible.
I should be
back by 6:00.
Lanagin didn't budge?
He re-enrolled them. We have to
get the bridge approved now.
I'll call Linda.
Bypass her.
I don't want her
in the meeting
I'm on it.
Thanks.
Meechum, get in touch
with the plane.
Have them make ribs
for the flight back.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Vice President,
do you have a moment?
I'm sorry. The President
asked to see me.
No, he didn't.
You requested the meeting,
and I took it
off the schedule.
You did what?
Let's go
in your office.
You lied, Frank.
You said you would
let the bridge go,
and then you
went behind my back,
just like you're
trying to do now.
I do not require
your permission.
No, but you
should involve me.
The President and
the Vice President
have issues they must
discuss privately.
When you are secretive,
it prevents me from being
able to do my job.
And when you
cancel meetings,
it prevents me from
being able to do mine.
Which is why I wanted to talk,
so we can work things out.
We should be working together.
I will not waste my time
inflating your sense
of self-importance!
Excuse me'?
How many elections
have you won?
How many congressional
committees have you chaired?
Would you even be working
in the White House
if I hadn't recommended you
during the campaign?
I returned that
favor and then some.
Look where
your desk is now.
And I'd say we're even.
And if you want
to maintain my respect,
you're going
about it all wrong.
I asked you in here
to work out a solution...
You didn't ask.
You demanded.
I will not be
left out of the loop.
I'm the President's
Chief of Staff.
Oh, you call this being Chief of Staff?
Micromanaging his datebook?
I'd say that's more
of a glorified scheduler.
The White House
would fall off its rails
without me doing my job.
Are you certain about that?
Yes, lam.
I look out for
the President 24/17.
I keep him informed. I keep
his priorities straight.
We did just fine before you
became Vice President, Frank.
All right. Let's go over to
the Oval Office right now
and ask the President
to choose.
His Chief of Staff
or his Vice President.
I know what the answer would be.
You want to go?
I didn't think so.
Now I will see the President
tomorrow morning, schedule or no.
And please, turn out the
lights before you leave.
I thought you went home.
No, not yet.
Do you have a moment?
Is there something wrong?
I know you are reconsidering the
bridge project, and I wanted...
I'm reviewing it.
I'll make my decision soon.
But you already
made a decision, sir.
I'm concerned that you
are over thinking this one.
If we backtrack...
Did I not make
myself clear?
I'm just trying
to offer my advice, sir.
Which I have heard, and which
I don't need to hear again.
But thank you.
I know the Vice
President spoke
to you yesterday,
and in fairness...
You know I value
your input, Linda.
When I say I've heard it, you
need to know I mean that.
Of course, sir.
Is there anything else?
No, sir. Good night.
Good night.
You disappointed me.
I told you
it would take time.
Any leads?
I've been going over
his state senate days.
It's a slow process.
I have to be thorough.
So how is it that I've
found more in two days
than you have
in two months?
What do you mean?
I've had to do
your job for you.
You found something?
I'm the one who's supposed
to ask that question.
What'd you find?
Maybe I can help.
Are you working for Frank?
Yeah, as his
communications director.
No, are you working for him?
Come on.
He couldn't pay me a fraction
of what you're offering.
Don't lie to me.
Look, if you've lost
confidence in my ability...
Stop fucking around.
You made
the wrong choice, Seth.
I don't think so.
You're nothing.
You're a parasite.
So are you, Danton.
Justin a nicer suit.
Do you know
what it might be?
Keep your ear
to the ground.
That was Seth.
He thinks Remy
may have something on us.
What?
He doesn't know.
Do you think
it could be...
No.
If it's anything,
I'm sure it's innocuous.
Nothing we can't weather.
But my bet is they're bluffing,
just to make us paranoid.
But he's a dangerous man,
isn't he, Raymond?
We can be dangerous, too,
when we need to be.
♪ Lord, I just can't keep
from crying sometimes
♪ When the world's
filled with sorrow
♪ And my eyes are
fined with tears
♪ Lord, I just can't
keep from crying
♪ Sometimes I
Don't stop.
I used to be a call girl.
I had to get away from it,
and that's why I came here.
There's a lot of stuff
you don't know about me.
You don't have to say
anything you don't want to.
When you tapped on my
shoulder on the bus,
there was something...
Your eyes.
That sounds really, really dumb.
No.
I don't know. I felt like I
wanted to tell you everything.
That I could trust you, even
though I didn't know you.
You can.
I've never
trusted anyone.
Have you ever loved anyone?
No.
I've never expected much
from the world.
It's ugly.
It's not a fair place.
I'm happy to
have what I have.
I'm glad I have this.
I've thought it
all out.
And there's a way to do it so
we don't risk any exposure.
Do we have to
talk about this now?
I'm beat.
My brain is...
Yes, we do.
Because it's our marriage.
If we're gonna survive
the next two years or six,
we need to do something.
We should be each
other's support system,
not cause
each other stress.
The foundation of this White
House is not brick or mortar.
It's us, Garrett.
This is important to me.
And I want it to
be important to you.
I have to trust that
whatever you're managing,
to whatever extent
you choose not to inform me,
that I'm neither at risk
nor passively condoning
something blatantly illegal.
Any risk falls
solely on me.
And you can't be accused of
condoning what you're not aware of.
Being not aware is
just as egregious.
Not in this case.
I'm steering the ship away from
the rocks, not toward them.
Then I'll call the Committee
for Foreign Investments.
You're making
the right decision, sir.
I have another difficult
decision to make.
Linda submitted
her resignation.
I was furious with her.
It was a very
manipulative move.
I can speculate
as to why she made it.
Well, are her
complaints valid?
I have a very biased view
on that subject.
Well, I've heard hers.
Give me yours.
Well, Linda and I
don't always agree.
But she's been
very loyal to you
and a more than competent
Chief of Staff.
So you think
I should keep her'?
Do I think she oversteps sometimes?
Yes.
Does she wrongly equate her
advice with mine? Often.
But the question that occurs
to me is not about Linda.
Let's say you
refuse her resignation.
If this gets out,
and it could,
won't you be sending a signal
10 anybody who works for you
that you can be leveraged?
She offered her
resignation.
Shes already gone,
even if she stays.
Megan? They're ready.
I don't know.
My hands are shaking.
You can do this, Megan.
I'll be there.
I get panic attacks
sometimes.
You afraid
you'll get one?
Yeah.
Okay. Well, why don't we ask
for a couple of more minutes?
It's not about that.
They just come.
I can't control them.
I don't want to do this.
Okay, Megan,
there's some
of the most senior Congressmen
and women in the room,
and the press, they've shown
up just to hear from you.
I know.
Okay, I don't want
to pressure you'
but a lot of planning
has gone into this.
Please don't
make me do this.
We're not making
you do anything.
Then can I just go back
home? Back to Chicago?
Listen, you have nerves.
That's understandable.
I don't want to
fucking do it, okay?
I understand. It's okay. But
if you back out now, Megan...
This isn't about me at all, is it?
This is not good for us.
It hurts us. It makes
us look unorganized.
This is about your
fucking moment to shine.
You don't fucking
care if I do...
I do care. I do care.
It is about me
and about you.
For whatever reason, we both decided
to share what happened to us,
and it mattered,
and people listened.
So let's go in and
finish what we started.
I can't. I'm not the right person.
Come on, Megan.
Do you know what I did last night?
Let's go.
I picked up some guy in
a bar. Total stranger.
I let him fuck my brains
out at the hotel.
Night before, same thing.
I can't stop.
It's my only way
to fucking...
Jesus, I fucking hate this
when my hands shake like this,
and I can't...
It's okay.
I'm not who you want
to be your poster girl.
You don't have to be.
I'm sorry I'm letting you down.
It's okay.
You're not letting me down.
It's okay. It's okay.
When will it
become official?
The President will
make his can this afternoon.
Official approval will be
announced in the morning.
No revisions
to the agreement?
None.
Everything is as spelled out
in the proposal.
Then I will uphold
my end of the bargain.
The money will
be cut oft.
You required proof.
Now, we want some.
What sort?
Of your commitment. You kill
your co-venture with Tusk.
That was never
part of the deal.
It is now.
The refinery can't proceed
while we're in a trade war.
We want you to
kill it for good,
and we want you
to kill it today.
Make the call to Tusk.
It's business hours.
Is this a business call?
No.
I was hoping it wasn't.
What are you
doing tonight?
Just about to
get on a plane.
Where to?
Boundaries, remember?
Work-related.
I don't take vacation.
Can you tell me
when you'll be back?
Tomorrow.
It's a quick trip.
Do you want to
have dinner?
I'd like that.
Bring your carry-on.
You could stay over after.
Yes?
Do you
have a moment?
Absolutely.
The President accepted my
resignation an hour ago.
Yes, I know.
I almost told him
that I'd changed my mind,
but I realized it wouldn't
make any difference.
For whatever it's worth,
I did bring up your loyalty and
how good you are at your job,
not that he needed
me to remind him.
And I will always be
grateful you recommended me.
It has been quite a ride.
Shorter than
I would have hoped,
but I have
a long career ahead.
No doubt.
And just so you know,
I don't plan
on making any fuss
in the press.
You'll hear nothing but
my praises if I'm asked.
I have something for you.
A few weeks ago,
the President told me
about a dinner
he had at your house.
He went on and on about
your Civil War models.
How much fun he had painting
the toy soldiers with you.
This was given to me by the
Director of the Smithsonian.
It's the first Medal of Honor
awarded to a Hispanic-American,
Corporal Joseph De Castro.
He fought for the Union.
Linda, I don't know
what to say.
It's clear the President
sees you as a friend.
I've never been
that to him.
But his job is bigger
than friendship.
It's bigger than
you and me.
I just hope you'll look out for
him the way I've tried to do.
I will.
And I'll treasure this.
Goodbye,
Mr. Vice President.
I've never thought higher of
her than I do at this moment.
She lost,
but she played to win.
Underwood got to Feng.
The refinery's dead.
Grayson played us.
We're running
out of options.
What do you
think, Jean?
Fuck him.
Do it.
Thank you.
Thank you for
doing this, Sandra.
Richard.
How are you,
Richard?
He has his good days and his bad.
This is a good day.
He would love to spend a few minutes
with you after your meeting.
Of course.
The reverend's
in here.
Mrs. Walker.
Hello.
Mr. President.
Reverend.
How can I help?
We should really get a
fan in here, Francis.
Well, the AC is all
the way up to full blast.
I mean from the
fumes, the glue.
Oh, that's half the fun.
Megan Hennessey
bailed on us today.
Why?
Her nerves got to her.
And she decided she didn't
want to be in the public eye.
Well, we can sympathize with that.
It's Doug.
Yes?
Seth.
I'll call you back.
When?