That's right.
Just a few more.
We're nearly done here.
Police.
Oh, hello, who have I reached?
Meeker County sheriff's.
I'm looking for Gloria Burgle.
- Speaking.
- My name is Larue Dollard.
I work for
the internal revenue service.
I am in receipt
of the documents you sent.
But I have a few questions.
Who is this?
Agent Dollard. IRS.
The envelope you sent was
addressed to me specifically.
You included a note.
IRS? I never sent
anything to...
Well, it has your name on it.
Look,
this is my last day, so...
Are you working a case involving
Emmit Stussy or Stussy lots Itd?
How did you get this number?
Again, it was on
the note you sent.
Spreadsheets, uh, contracts,
loan agreements.
Not sure how you found me.
He's protected, I think,
Mr. Stussy,
possibly even
at the highest levels.
My investigation was kiboshed
last year from DC,
so, we should proceed
with the utmost...
Look, Mr. Dollard.
I don't know what to tell you.
We did have a case
involving Mr. Stussy but...
Well, that case is closed now.
Deputy, I'm looking at evidence
of a vast financial conspiracy
involving blatant tax fraud
and the repurposing of corporate
funds for personal gains.
It looks like,
in the last year,
Mr. Stussy has borrowed
upwards of $200 million
with the sole intent
of lining his pockets
and the pockets of his partners,
a Mr. Sy Feltz
and one V.M. Varga.
Say that name again.
Uh, V.M. Varga?
I'm not sure
what the "V.M." Stands for.
Don't move.
I'll be right there.
Oh, wait. What's your address?
Two hearts,
three clubs, four spades,
five no trump.
Last one.
There.
Well...
You should be happy,
Mr. Stussy.
Your first action item
is complete.
The accumulation of wealth.
I'm just so tired.
It's perfectly natural.
You see it all the time
in the wild.
The smaller animal going limp
in the jaws of the larger.
Genetic instinct.
At some level,
food knows it's food.
Yes.
Oh...
The strategist. I was
wondering when you might call.
Yes, I have it.
All of it, as long as you
live up to your end of the...
Fine.
The same charming locale?
No, I'm not familiar with that
address but I'm sure I can find it.
Just so you know,
I will be coming
with what in military terms
is referred to as a
"fire team" so no business...
Back up. Back up!
My dear, I'm afraid
you'll have to excuse me.
Don't... don't make me.
I'll shoot.
I am not food.
No, of course not.
You lied to me.
There are no hordes coming.
No mongrel hordes.
It's you! No!
Now, now, now. No.
Now, come on.
Give Mr. Stussy some room.
He's earned the right
to be testy.
After everything
he's been through.
I'm done.
Give me back my papers
and get out!
Are you a fan of progress,
Mr. Stussy?
- Technology?
- No more talking.
You know, in the old days,
only the strong were rich.
It was all a question of
how much you could carry.
But then the Medicis
invented banks,
and wealth and pornography.
This is what
drives innovation.
Of course, technology has
other benefits as well.
Safety, for example, a safer car,
the artificial heart.
And, well, how a handgun
might be equipped
with a fingerprint scanner.
To keep it from being used
by anyone but its owner.
That's right.
You can feel it, can't you?
On the grip.
Go on, have a look.
I'll wait.
Progress in all things,
you see.
All right, wipe everything.
We were never here.
- She called?
- Yeah, we have a stop to make.
This is a mistake.
No trace, I'm afraid.
We need those drives.
Vamanos.
Swango.
- I'll go.
- No.
El Nino?
Two elevators.
It's yours.
What the shit?
Excuse me.
This is not...
You can't just...
Thank you so much.
Emmit, my dear Emmit.
How are you?
You look...
Well, I know this can't be
easy for you.
You work for Varga.
All this time.
Like a fire door that leads
to another fire.
Emmit, you need to
listen to me very carefully.
The Stussy corporation, having sold all
its assets this morning to realignment
for $100,000, and may I say,
very generous of you,
but your company is now carrying a debt
load of over three hundred million.
You'll need to file
for chapter 11 immediately.
But don't worry.
Your personal wealth,
the profits you've made
as a partner in this venture,
have all been
carefully hidden. So...
Not all bad.
Mike and Mike
will show you out.
And you're saying
this proves...
Until 18 months ago, Stussy lots was
a traditional real estate concern.
They owned two dozen parcels
around Minnesota,
ground and elevated lots.
They charged
a standard fee for parking,
monthly rates
and hourly meters.
Then the books show
a million dollar loan
from this company
called Narwhal.
As far as I can tell,
the corporate ID number is fake.
So, four months ago,
new incorporation papers
were filed with the city,
adding V.M. Varga
as a partner at Stussy lots.
British fella? About six foot?
Country of origin
isn't listed on the form.
But that sounds like the man
that I met.
So, are we talking about
money laundering or...
That's what I thought
at first, but no.
This is something different.
It's more of a leveraged
buyout or bleed out,
in which an outside entity
acquires a healthy company,
borrows millions of dollars
in its name,
which is pocketed
by the partners.
Then they sell the company,
now laden with debt,
for a fraction of the price.
And that's a crime?
Not when it's done properly.
No.
What's that?
I was saying, morality aside,
one company buying another
and strip-mining it for profit
is perfectly legal as long as one
follows the letter of the law
and pays
the appropriate taxes.
- Which they didn't.
- Correct.
There is evidence that every
dime borrowed by Stussy lots
in the past four months
was funneled into
dozens of off-shore accounts in
the name of all three partners.
- Mr. Stussy, Mr. Feltz...
- And this V.M. Varga.
- Who blew in on the wind last year.
- That's how it looks.
Uh...
Oh.
Bur...
Burgle.
What?
We got five bodies
on the third floor.
Gunfire in both directions.
Just straight up carnage.
Chief's thinking
an ambush scenario.
Ambush by who?
Don't know him.
But you're gonna recognize the next one.
Told you.
Wait till you see
who we think the target was.
- It was her.
- What was?
Who sent the note to the IRS.
Connecting the dots,
Nikki Swango.
- Why would she?
- They killed her man.
You need to issue a bolo.
What are you gonna do?
Someone's gotta warn Emmit.
What now?
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Fucking...
Fuck.
Oh, jeez. Oh, jeez.
Are you as low as you can go?
What?
I asked if you still feel
you've got room to fall,
or whether this is bottom.
Honestly...
If you'd asked me yesterday,
I'd have said
I couldn't go lower
than sitting in jail,
staring at a life behind bars,
or the electric chair.
But now, here we are today,
lower still.
Oh, I've been watching.
This Varga fellow
plucked you like a chicken.
But he's gone now.
So, I'm gonna finish the job.
Please, wait, I got...
What? Kids?
People who love you?
I don't think
that's true anymore.
Type of man who would
poison his best friend,
kill his own brother.
No.
I didn't... I didn't...
- I didn't mean to...
- Oh, you didn't mean to. Oh.
See you later then.
At least, let me call my wife?
You smashed your phone.
Oh, yeah.
He's a kitten now, Ray.
In case you were wondering.
He's a...
I looked in his eyes.
My Ray.
Who never got to say goodbye.
Who you left bleeding
on the floor,
sadness in his eyes,
your own brother.
Do it.
Shoot me.
Put me out of my...
"Though thou exalt thyself
as the eagle,
"and though thou set
thy nest among the stars,
"thence will I bring
thee down, sayeth..."
What?
"Though thou exalt thyself
as the eagle,
"and though thou set
thy nest among the stars,
"thence will I bring
thee down,
"sayeth..."
Shit. Back in your car. Move.
It's not...
We're fine.
Not a parking lot, folks.
- Side of the road.
- I know.
It's kind of a long story,
but in the end of it,
we all go home, so...
Thanks for stopping,
it's real Christian of you.
Step away from the car, ma'am.
Is everything okay, officer?
- License and registration.
- Of course.
You, too, ma'am.
Uh, my purse is in my truck,
you want me to...
Hold on.
There you go.
So, it's registered to the company,
but it's my company, so...
Ma'am.
Stay put.
- I'll get the license.
- Officer.
- She's...
- Ma'am.
- I'm serious.
- You should, because she's...
- This is silly, I mean, we're just...
- She's got a gun.
- Sir, step out of the car.
- No.
I'm... she's the one
you should...
Out of the car, now.
Damn it.
Ma'am, do not take
another step.
Honest, listen,
I'm not the...
She's the one, I'm harmless,
you should...
For Christ's sake, shoot her.
Okay, then.
So, I've been trying to decide what
to tell you about your grandpa,
his demise, the root cause.
He wasn't really my grandpa.
Listen to me, he was one of god's
creatures same as you and me.
And what happened to him,
that should never happen
to anyone.
It was that stoner, you said.
It was and it wasn't.
And I wanna say more, I do,
but there's violence to knowing
the world isn't what you thought.
- And you're just a boy...
- I'm 13 now.
You're still a boy.
You've got your
whole life to be grown,
only a few more years
to be young.
So, for now,
just know that sometimes the world
doesn't make a lot of sense.
But how we get through it is,
we stick together.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Good. Eat your popsicle.
Bless us, Oh Lord,
for this bounty
we're about to receive.
Bless our family and friends.
We've had some dark times
and made mistakes, but...
Now we see the light.
- Amen.
Can you hand me
those carrots there, Stella?
- There you go.
- Thank you. Thanks.
Terrific.
How are you there, friend?
Good as new.
Here you go.
Look at us, together again.
Whoops, the salad.
Oh, shoot, it's in the fridge.
No, I'll go.
You want some?
- Chris honeycomb.
- Gloria Burgle, Minneapolis office.
Are you sure it's him?
Face recognition picked him up
coming in from Brussels.
He's been here overnight.
Oh, that this was
my salvation.
A weary traveler, I.
Agent Burgle, department
of homeland security.
Ah, the nation state
defending its borders.
And me, a simple salesman.
- What do you sell, Mr...
- Rand. Daniel. I sell accounting software.
In Brussels.
Is that where you live?
Good lord, no.
I'm a citizen of the air,
madam.
Moving, always moving.
You don't remember me, do you?
Surmise.
Because I haven't greeted you,
I don't remember you.
Do you?
We may have met once
in my younger days.
Are you familiar with
the Russian saying,
"the past is unpredictable"?
- I'm pretty sure you made that up.
- Possibly.
But which of us can say with
certainty what has occurred,
actually occurred,
and what is simply rumor,
misinformation, opinion?
A photograph is considered
proof in a court of law.
Well, photographs
can be doctored.
One's eyes can be deceived.
We see what we believe,
not the other way around.
Six people dead,
including a state trooper.
$200 million unaccounted for.
Those are facts.
And you at the heart
of the morass.
What else
am I supposed to see?
A man wakes up one morning
and decides to kill
four men over a certain age,
all with the same last name.
That didn't happen.
And yet,
if evidence is collected,
if confessions are made,
if a verdict of guilty
is entered in a court of law,
then its happening becomes
as the rocks and rivers,
and to argue that it didn't happen
is to argue with reality itself.
Did you know
Emmit Stussy was murdered?
Three months ago.
Killed in his own home.
Pitchfork peasants.
- What?
- I said,
it is a dangerous world
for men of standing.
Human beings, you see, have no inherent
value other than the money they earn.
Cats have value, for example,
because they provide pleasure
to the humans.
But a deadbeat on welfare?
Well, they have
negative value.
So, ipso facto,
Emmit's death is more tragic
than the death of a wasteling.
That's...
You can't believe that.
Oh, it's true.
It's true whether
I believe it or not.
Did you kill him?
Emmit?
From Brussels?
They got phones in Belgium,
yeah? E-mail?
Mr. Varga.
You're asking me if there
are phones in Belgium?
Let me tell you
what's gonna happen next.
Three agents
from homeland security
are gonna put handcuffs on you
and take you to rikers.
And then we're gonna charge you
with felony money laundering
and six counts of conspiracy
to commit murder.
And then I'm gonna go home to my son,
it's his birthday tomorrow.
I promised I'd take him
to the state fair.
You ever guess a pig's weight?
Or eat a deep fried
Snickers bar?
There's no better way to spend a Saturday
in this, our great American experiment.
So, while you're eating mashed
potatoes from a box in a dark room,
think of me among
the Amber waves of grain.
No.
That's not what's
gonna happen next.
What's gonna
happen next is this.
In five minutes
that door is going to open,
and a man you can't argue with
will tell me
I'm free to go.
And I will stand
from this chair
and disappear into the world,
so help me god.
Rikers and Snickers bars.
You'll see.
Agent Burgle.
Gloria.
Trust me.
The future is certain.
And when it comes,
you will know without question,
your place in the world.
Until then, we've said
all there is to say.
Any further debate would be
simply wasting our breath.
And if there's one thing
I can't abide, it's waste.
Goodbye.