George Michael Bluth had never been
more popular. No.
He was surrounded by people
who were thrilled to be in his company.
Carlos was just... tickling me.
They're almost out of root beer.
So I got you one with
the last bit of root beer
because I remember that
somebody was saying that, um,
George Michael likes root beer.
And as his business was taking off...
I do. Thanks a lot.
You guys don't have to
do all this, you know?
This was just a little
get-together for my girlfriend
to show her I'm doing well, you know?
- ... So was his romantic life.
- Show her I'm an adult.
Hey, stop it!
You're dead, man, you are so dead.
That was the last root beer snow cone.
I got that for him, Carlos.
Teach you for being such a kiss ass, Terry.
And it was an ex-Bluth Company employee...
Come on, you guys, not cool.
Who was the most grateful
to be in his company.
- Want any of these?
- No, I'm fine.
You know, I really appreciate
you guys doing all this.
I just wish I understood...
why.
That's why... because you could ask us
why we do this, and mean it.
The fact that you could
be so down to earth...
And look so young.
While you're starting this giant company.
You created an opportunity many of us
thought we'd never have again.
See that's the part I
don't understand, Carlos.
You know my name! What's his name?
- You're the kiss-ass, Carlos.
- What's his name?
Okay, guys, I'm gonna learn all your names.
- I promise.
- George.
- And that's when he heard what
- Rebel.
- Had become his name.
- What is all this?
Oh, it's just a little surprise.
- You did this for me?
- Yes!
Well... well, they did it for me, but...
but only because they knew I
wanted to do something for you.
Maybe we could talk without your friends.
I mean, these guys aren't
really my friends, you know.
I barely know their names.
I mean, I know Carlos, but...
only because of that old song
"Carlos the Tickle Monster."
Wait, what song is that?
Oh, god, I knew he made that up.
But it did help me remember.
Anyway, don't worry about these
guys... they're not listening
to a word we're saying.
How about that kiss?
We need to talk.
Now the story of a family
whose future was abruptly cancelled
and the one son who had no choice
but to keep himself together.
It's George Michael's Arrested Development.
George Michael's life was very different
months before developing
the software program that would
change his life.
♪ Those balls in the air ♪
♪ Those balls in the air. ♪
And...
that's where the song should've ended.
So I guess we all got
a little carried away.
Are you sure? We all
ended at the same time.
Yeah, well, it's because
you all sped up together.
Now, you know if I was
playing in your band, I would say,
"Hey, you know, let's do
the whole fast and loose
with tempo thing."
But this is about my demo tape
to Juilliard and they've got
to dig what I do so much
that they start an entire
department for wood block.
So I'm sorry guys.
And you're leaving, okay.
They left early.
Proves my point.
She was cute.
They were playing way
too loud anyway, right?
Could you even hear the wood block?
Right at the end.
We could record you separately,
and then mix it louder on the computer.
Well, then I'm not playing in a band.
I mean, the whole point of the band
is to showcase my amazing internal clock.
You know, that's something
you have to be born with.
Or bred with.
Which was the case with George Michael.
Who, as a small child,
appeared in a promotional video
for a developmental tool called "BabyTock"
BabyTock! will give your
child a head start at math.
And if I were a doctor,
I would guarantee you
that it would also boost
their brain power 110%.
That's a lot of brain power.
You've been using BabyTock!, correct?
- For how long?
- For two months.
But George Michael really
enjoys listening to the sound.
And would you say it's...
changed the power of his brain?
Uh, well, that's impossible...
To deny.
I've always wanted a smart baby.
This thing really works, George.
In fact it came from something that didn't.
So we're stuck with 5,000 of
these worthless corn-ballers?
When they were looking to
recoup some of their costs
after an ill-fated foray
into the fry-at-home snack-food market.
Whoa, whoa.
They're not worthless.
You know? The timer still works.
There's no numbers on it,
but it's very loud, so...
Perfect for those who
like the sound of a clock,
but don't know their numbers.
That's good.
We'll sell this to baby...
Mother of!
We should put these in cribs.
That's not a half puny thought.
And that Julliard thing is
confidential from my Dad by the way.
He's never gonna want me to pursue
- a career in...
- Hitting a block of wood.
Music, yes
You know, he still thinks of
me as the same George Michael
that I was before my life
blew apart, you know?
Before the world cracked me open
and I became the guy that
you're looking at now.
George Michael 2.0.
God, I hate my name.
The last five years
had been a whirlwind for George Michael.
He celebrated going off to college
- at a party with his family.
- Hey! Next week, huh?
- Congratulations!
- Thanks.
- We are so proud.
- We have a little something for you.
Oh, no, you don't have to do anything.
I mean, you threw me this... meeting.
Little something-something...
to buy a car.
Oh, God, really?
- No!
- Yes.
Maeby!
But the party wouldn't last long.
You know what?
I am done with this family.
I hope you've saved some money,
'cause you're going to need every dime now.
What's this?
Return it... or rip it up.
- Michael.
- Come on.
Give it a rip.
Rip it up... right down the center.
That's it. Rip it.
Couple more.
Did you get it?
Proud of you.
Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday, George Michael.
- Happy birthday.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- * Happy birthday to you... *
- But don't worry.
Michael did make sure his son got a car...
Get out of here.
As he sent him off to college.
And although he arrived at college
without his possessions,
he was finally at a place where he felt
he'd fit in.
Hey, hey, check it out.
N... no.
No, no.
What?
In his Freshman year, George Michael
- hit the ground running.
- Sorry.
He was breaking some of the old taboos.
- Let's make it a... Pepsi.
- Drinking Pepsi in the morning.
So, it's a breakfast combo with a Pepsi.
Sometimes having eggs at night.
How about some eggs?
Oh, excuse me, I forgot it wasn't morning.
He was soon finding that others
enjoyed his sense of humor.
I forgot it wasn't morning.
A present from his Uncle Gob elevated
- his newfound confidence.
- Hi.
My uncle is a magician.
Before diminishing it.
But before he knew it
sophomore year was upon him,
- and everything got turned up to 11.
- Boom!
And that's what we call
only being behind by three.
So then that stuff's all going
on with this Sitwell company.
And then... we end up playing
them in a softball game.
Highlights... loyal friends.
I'm like, "How can that...?"
Romance.
Becky.
Betrayal.
Becky?
What's up, Ray?
You guys broke up.
Oh, thanks, Ray, I almost forgot.
The triumph of friendship.
- What's up, Ray?
- Hey.
Oh, thanks, Ray, I almost forgot.
You know who I was thinking
about before you sat down?
- What?
- Becky.
Do you remember?
And as surely as stability returned,
junior year ushered in a
new era of experimentation...
It's all about the science of kissing
between a man and a woman.
That always has fascinated me.
Oh, good. Sheila will take you.
As George Michael tried to compensate
for the lack of income from his father
by volunteering for experiments.
Hi.
So I don't run off?
- I hope you're not feeling too awkward.
- Oh, don't be crazy.
- Okay.
- Now when the mouth to mouth test begins,
I'm gonna be yelling out letters
that indicate mouth movements.
What I need you to do is just give me
on a scale of one to
ten your pleasure level.
- Fine.
- Ten being the most
pleasurable, one the least.
Let's hope we get to ten.
- Well, work our way up to it.
- Bringing in the mouth unit!
And that's when he realized
what the straps were for.
Is that...? Okay, I guess it's
not, uh, not gonna be a person.
- And C?
- I think one on C.
- M? M?
- Oh, one on...
- M?
- One for sure on... one.
- And Z?
- One.
- N?
- F? F?
- One. One.
But it wasn't until his year abroad
that George Michael got
an education in life.
Because after a year of trying
not to be an imposing guest
in his new country,
he was ready
for a summer that would end up
turning his life upside down...
when the woman whose
children he was nannying...
opened him up sexually.
Hey, hey, did Ernesto get his 4: 00?
The drones are coming.
Nothing matters now.
- Why do you kiss like this?
- Like what?
The teeth, they must not be used like this.
It was actually a jaw and lip
retraction issue, but
she had neither a command
of the language nor the data that we do.
You make love like a boy.
Spanish, speak to me in Spanish.
Because the only way that college credit is
actually activated is if I have...
- Tómame.
- Cook... cook at...
- Cooking at you?
- Overpower me.
Oh, yes, make me cry.
You're a terrible mother.
And so it was a very
different George Michael
that returned to school for senior year.
Eager to unleash his new
overt sexuality on an unsuspecting campus.
Hey, man.
It gets better.
And for George Michael,
senior year did get better.
- He was like a king
- I sort of feel like a king
- returning to his castle...
- Returning to his castle.
Only to discover that they thought
he was two kings.
Welcome to your castle.
And they had doubled
the size of his castle.
Double castle.
Can't wait to meet Michael, George.
It would be the perfect backdrop
to unveil George Michael 2.0.
Todo mio.
Todo mia?
Mio.
But George Michael's development was about
- to be forestalled.
- Hey.
- Dad.
- Pete died.
Oh, God.
- Uh, who's, uh, Pete?
- Don't worry about it.
Don't you worry about it.
I like this.
- I like the mustache.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh... it's kind of fun.
- That's great.
Probably gonna want to shave it off
before the start of next quarter.
Otherwise, they're gonna
think you're a musician, huh?
But I love it... dude.
I'm never going to be
louder than an electric guitar.
Maybe using a band to showcase
my wood block skill is a dumb idea.
Too bad there's no such thing
as an electric wood block.
That sounds like a mother of an invention.
And so they set to work
inventing a downloadable app
that would allow one to
play an electronic version
of a wood block on their smartphone.
You see, that's important.
Well, that's what it is.
So it's basically like you'll always
have a wood block with you.
I can't believe nobody's ever done this.
A quick something search
would have shown the guys
that there were already three
wood block apps on the market.
So, there are three on the market.
- Which they did.
- Así estamos en la jungla.
But even after doing that search,
they were undeterred.
Download them. Come on, let's do it.
I hope we're not doing this on my account.
No, we're doing it so that we can see
what the competition is like.
No, I mean on my iTunes account.
It's 99 cents.
Yeah, times three.
And soon, they realized
what kind of competition
they were up against.
Well, these are a joke.
I know. Where are the mallet options?
There's no choice of
wood weight or grain type.
There's no diameter hole option.
I mean, what is this, BabyTock?
- BabyTock?
- You know, the sharp
metal box that you put in the crib.
Is that not a well-known...?
- But this is fine.
- And they set to work.
No, I understand that. I get that.
But it just seems like
you're leaving a hole
just right in the middle of the block.
It won't be a block on anything 3G.
Although some of the work had
to happen outside the room.
Buddy, is that schoolwork?
Which was challenging.
And soon, they were
close to finishing an app
they had decided to call...
Woodblock.
It's taken.
Blockwood.
And that's when he came up with...
Block of Wood?
- Which was also taken.
- Wow.
- Block-block?
- No.
People are going to think we're
in the chicken-noise business.
How is that a chicken noise?
You know... well, it's kind of hard to do
in these matador pants, but, you know...
- Block-bl...
- Fakeblock is available.
Do you want Fakeblock?
Oh, uh, okay. They have Fakeblock.
Okay, yes, we'll take that.
No problem. That's no problem.
Could you hang on to that for me, please?
And I'll call you back. Thank you.
It's $5,000 for the domain name,
and then there's this
whole XML Web site fee.
I got the last one.
That was 99 cents.
Times three.
And George Michael realized
he needed to bring in some cash.
We actually have a variety of subjects
that high school students need tutoring in.
If you want to just
take a look at that list
and let me know if there's anything there
- that you've handled before.
- There was...
although George Michael
couldn't imagine it was the same Maeby.
Is this "F" in "Maeby F."
her last name or her grade?
Oh, it's her last name.
But her most recent grade is...
well, this just shows
an Elvis Presley head.
So, that bad?
I'll take her.
Stay on top of her.
You may need to ride her pretty hard.
Hey, you must be...
What?
- This is the girl you broke up with?
- Huh?
I can't wear this.
Yeah, well, we dated for
a while, but, you know,
I was a kid, and I didn't know
how to kiss yet. I don't know,
for whatever reason, I listened to my dad
who said we shouldn't make it work.
- Was she your first?
- Cousin? No.
Why would you... why would
your mind go right to...? No.
No, it's just that he was right.
We were kids. I wasn't yet O.S.
- Overtly sexual.
Right. As I live and breathe. Crazy.
That's just crazy.
Okay, so listen.
After I let her in, you go
and try and keep my dad out.
All right? I can't let him
get in the way of this one.
Hey, you must be...
But first, he had to cover his tracks.
- What?
- This had to look like fate.
- George Michael?
- Huh?
What is this? Maeby, what are you...
doing here?
- As I live and breathe.
- But for the phrase, "as I live
- I thought you were the girl.
- And breathe," he nailed it.
I'm supposed to tutor a kid from...
High school. Yeah. That's me.
Crazy. That is just crazy.
And even though George
Michael wanted to seduce her,
he couldn't helpbut challenge
her strategy for staying in high school.
But still, I mean, you have
to make a living, right?
Don't you need an education?
Well, don't forget... I'm a Harris.
- Harris?
- Yeah.
Someone who "inharris" a lot of money.
Yeah, well, you know,
I wouldn't put all my Anns in that basket.
You know, it's fine. You don't get it.
You've never been a risk taker.
I like to with people.
That's what I do.
- I'm making a statement.
- I love it.
You know, I knew you were cool
when I saw you wearing that shirt.
Thanks.
More betrayal.
Oh, no, I get it, too.
No, I love... I love it, too.
You know, I... I love to... love now.
George Michael found himself
less overtly sexual than he'd hoped.
I made a 40-year-old woman cry in Spain.
I love making love to Spanish women.
Get out.
And George Michael slipped
back into seduction mode.
Oh, a man, a woman...
a bedroom.
Let's solve for "X."
I don't know what you're talking about.
Well, you know, in algebra,
you have an unknown element,
and, uh, we call it "X," and then you have
to solve for it to find
out what number "X" is.
"X" isn't a number.
So you don't even really know the basic...
But in that moment, the urge to educate her
was more powerful than
the urge to kiss her.
Let me show you. I'll just
show you some stuff real quick.
All right, so if you take
something like this... 3X+1=10...
And with the algebra lesson complete,
George Michael pivoted back
to his overtly sexual seduction.
Therefore, when I say,
"You and me in a bedroom,
let's solve for 'X, '" I'm...
I'm stating it as a kind of formula.
Yeah, let's get wasted.
Let's drink that formula.
It's not that kind of formula.
No, I'll show you what
a formula is real quick,
'cause that's very important.
- But when the door opened,
- Dad?
George Michael's window
of opportunity closed.
Bad news... P-Hound is
yanking our chain again.
- Uncle Michael.
- Oh, my God.
And after a brief
reunion, George Michael had
another opportunity to impress his cousin.
He's got this privacy software,
keeps people from stealing
your stuff. Tell her, pal.
So its privacy software
that's also anti-piracy?
George Michael weighed his options.
Maeby had chastised him
for not taking risks,
and what would be a bigger risk
than perpetuating a lie about software
just to ignite the passions of a woman?
Of course, it would be a lie,
and since Maeby wouldn't know it was a lie,
he wouldn't appear to be taking a risk.
Perhaps the bigger risk
was to tell his father
he was lying.
That he came up with it
because he wanted his father to leave
so he could enjoy what
remained of his senior year.
After all, he wondered, wouldn't that be
the course of action taken
by an overtly sexual man...
a man who owns a pair of matador pants?
He had not responded now for 41 seconds,
according to his unfailing internal clock,
and it was time to come clean.
Well, thanks. Yeah.
It's a... well, it's just a Boolean-driven
aggregation, really, of what
programmers call "hacker traps."
And he found himself
suddenly and effortlessly
tapping into a long-inbred
instinct for lying.
A Bluth taking his first steps in deceit.
But the more he talked,
the more he actually
started to like the idea.
So, you know, in other words, when...
when you have friends over,
you know, and you're...
you're listening to music and they want
to steal your music and
copy your movies or...
or just look at your photos,
you know, this prevents that.
It just neutralizes that so
it's not even a threat anymore.
It's called Fakeblock.
- Great name. Right?
- Yeah, well, you know,
it's super low-hanging fruit.
Someone's going to do it.
We're just trying to
be those guys, you know?
And, impressed with his
- own invention...
- It's a fake profile
that leads hackers away
from your actual data.
He set about making an
impossible dream a reality.
You mean something that keeps
everything on the Internet private
and protects everyone's digital rights?
Yeah, I mean, think about it.
Everyone has something
that they want removed from the Internet.
George Michael certainly did.
And if the new software served
no other person than removing this...
it would be worth it.
Ay, dios mio.
I mean, if we could
make something like that,
it could be bigger than Facebook.
I mean, who wouldn't
want something like that?
You think you can do it?
No.
No, of course not. No.
I mean, this is my chance with Maeby,
and I can't even get rid of my own father.
You know, what if we just did
a vote... just the roommates?
We do a quick vote, and
it's, "Ciao, Fathero."
He's going to know who voted against him.
Not if I get him to vote against himself.
Why would he do that?
No, he wouldn't. He... I...
I was just leaning back,
so it looked like I...
I got this chair again, didn't I?
Maybe I just need to be clear and just say,
"I'm putting up a wall.
We need to rework our whole system here."
Sounds like you guys are working
on your privacy software, huh?
And, long story short, Michael did end up
embracing the voting-out-a-roommate idea.
And it's, "Adios, brothiero."
It cannot fail.
That was fun.
Did he look betrayed to you?
He kind of always looks that way.
I'm going to catch the bus.
- Bye.
- Well, uh, okay. Hey, listen.
Are you going to come by on Thursday or...?
Um, I don't think so. I
have this thing in L.A.
Well, can you blow it off? I
mean, you know, you might want
to get "graduating high
school" out of the way.
Well, I'm getting a lifetime
achievement award at this gala.
Well, you might want to get that
out of the way, too, I guess.
Yeah.
Hey, you want me to go
with you to that or...?
Yeah, I can pick you up at your place.
Oh, they're actually
shooting a thing at my place.
As it turns out, they'd end up
- just clubbing a Thing.
- Oh!
You know what? Yeah, that
might actually be a good idea.
Because I can't bring
any of my friends without
getting permission
slips from their parents.
Well, that's not really a problem for me.
Yeah, 'cause you just
betrayed yours, right?
Awesome.
George Michael and Maeby arrived
at a hotel busy with three separate events.
No, no, no...
Well, it's really nice to be
out with you as adults, you know?
In Spain, they don't even
eat dinner until after 11:00 p.m.
Wow, Spain really changed you.
Well, you grow up very quickly in Spain.
Oh, my God, I know this guy. Hey.
Hey, man. Hey.
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
What are you on?
Oh, he's nobody.
Oh. It's Justin.
That's David Henrie.
He's Justin from Wizards of Waverly Place.
Hmm.
It's on a lot in Spain.
Well, I'm going to go mingle
with a bunch of 13-year-olds
who think they can still play fifth grade.
- Have fun.
- I'll catch up.
And George Michael set out
to re-unleash his overtly sexual persona.
Well, gentlemen, start your engines.
Buenas noches, pequeño Scarlet.
I will be needing a room, please.
How many nights?
Two. Sorry. No, just one night.
I thought you were saying how many people.
- And how many beds?
- Two.
- No. Uh, one bed.
Why give her the option?
Keep it real simple.
One bed, one night, two
people, let's solve for "X."
I hate young Hollywood.
It's called Fakeblock, Mort.
- It's going to blow Schnoodle out of the water!
- And it was on his way back
- to Maeby that he heard her say...
- Fakeblock's the next big thing.
- It's called Fakeblock!
- What's this? You're talking... talking about Fakeblock?
- Oh. How does your privacy software work?
- Huh? It's private.
And that's how George
Michael not only met Rebel...
I don't want people to
know that I'm doing this.
But finally found a way to prove
to Maeby that he was a risk taker.
Yes. Yes. George Maharis.
Only to discover, moments later...
- Perfecto!
- ... that she was dating
- an even bigger risk taker.
- De nada.
That's my undercover cop boyfriend.
I'm trying to get him in bed.
Boyfriend?
So funny that didn't come up in the car.
So, how does it work?
Huh? How does what work?
Your privacy software.
How does it protect you from piracy?
Oh, I don't know.
Don't worry about it.
No, no, no. No, you
really piqued my interest.
I'm sorry.
And discouraged that he'd lost Maeby,
he tried to salvage his night
by taking a picture of Gibby from "iCarly."
As he was doing this,
however, this happened.
The explosion caused an electrical surge
rendering the Schnoodle
software inoperable.
Which, to those who saw him,
seemed like a genius act of cyber sabotage,
which led to this.
- What happened?
- Ah, it's dead.
That geek Maharis
destroyed the whole thing.
And you know why? Just because he could.
Those Internet geniuses...
that's what they do. I'm ruined.
I'll probably never get
to drive the Schnoodle car.
We should work together.
- No.
- Smart.
And a few days later,
it would lead to this.
I'm John Beard. Here's
your 15 seconds of news.
Fakeblock's mystery man, George Maharis,
may have just found a way to screw a cap
on the Internet, and
investors are lining up
to fill the company's tank with money,
even though he himself remains anonymous.
That's all the news
that's fit to pump. I quit.
By the time
George Michael returned tocampus,
even his roommate had heard
of George Maharis' Fakeblock.
This George Maharis guy stole our name,
but we have it registered,
so we can sell it to him for a fortune.
No, I am George Maharis!
I'm behind the whole thing.
I... I wanted to impress Maeby,
so I told her that I created
this privacy software.
Why would you do that?
You know, it's like the
time that you told that girl
that you were George Takei's son.
Well, it's too late.
This thing's taking off.
They're saying Fakeblock
knocked out Schnoodle.
That was a coincidence. It
must have been a power surge.
Well, we got to get something... at least
get our five grand back.
Well, I put in the five grand,
you put in three dollars.
Well, you may have put in
the most money to Fakeblock,
but I put in the first three dollars,
so that makes you a hop-on.
No, you're the hop-on, Paul,
and I know exactly who
you're trying to hop on to.
- Maeby.
Yeah, well, you know
she's dating a cop, right?
- Yeah, she likes risk takers, like the P...
- Hi.
Hound...
Keep moving. Can you believe this?
- Maeby was excited...
- Fakeblock! It's exploding!
- ... but George Michael knew
- I got my PR company fanning it
the stakes were too high
for him to continue the lie.
And I even cashed in a favor
to get us mentioned on "Mad Money."
You know, I think we just might want
to slow down a little bit
on the whole Fakeblock thing
'cause I'm still not 100% finished with it.
Well, how finished are you with it?
200%? 500%
I also feel like I'm not 100% finished
- with your math tutoring.
- And then Maeby said something
- that made his change his mind.
- Do we have those books here?
I trust you, George Michael.
I would not get into bed with you
on this thing if I didn't trust you.
No. Yeah, of... of course
you can trust me in bed.
No, I mean, I trust you
not to take advantage of me.
No. I wouldn't. We would...
we would just lie there.
We'd just lie there? I mean,
I'm talking about business.
So am I. That's why we
would just lie there.
Okay. 'Cause I was going to say,
when you become an Internet billionaire,
you could do whatever
you want with me in bed.
It was that. That's what
made him change his mind.
- I will. I will.
- And if it was so wrong to lie,
surely he would receive some sort of sign.
Oh, hey, I should get this.
- But that wasn't it.
- Hi, Uncle Gob.
That was his uncle Gob wanting
to meet him at a gay club
- to tell him his father
- I need to see you tonight.
- Was anxious to see him.
- It's about your father and you.
Really? Is... is he upset?
- Do I seem like a clown to you?
- I got it.
George Michael was
worried, and even more so,
when he caught up with
his uncle at a magic club.
That Fakeblock thing will scrub it away.
You know about Fakeblock?
You know that's my software.
I wonder if my dad
thinks I'm blowing him off
because that's starting to take off now.
Well, you should go
find out 'cause I do know
that your dad is really,
really, really upset with you.
He is upset? I asked you that.
That was literally the
first thing I asked you.
So you're giving me these crazy...
Mad?
So, it was a very shaken George Michael
who arrived later at the Ealing Club...
What do you mean, I'm already
up there? Obviously, I'm not...
as a frustrated Andy
Richter was having trouble
already up there because I'm here.
Getting into the club he was a member of.
It's my stupid brother!
He looks just like me.
I'll just go up, I'll find
him, I'll... Oh, come on.
Oh, hey, Donny!
Hey, I had you for a semester at Openings.
Yeah, okay, all right.
Hey, come. I'm... I'm his guest.
Is this man your guest?
Oh, no, no. I'm just meeting my dad here.
Oh, screw this. I'm going up.
- Oh, come on.
- Going up, going up.
Oh, come on!
Oh, some Openings child you are, man!
And George Michael girded himself
for his first meeting with his father
since he voted him out of the dorm.
Hi. Yeah, just a sea-breeze, please.
Make it a strong one.
Put some stank on that.
George?
George Maharis?
And that's when he heard
the name he'd forgotten
he'd given out as his own.
So he tried not to act surprised to hear it
when he saw it was Rebel.
I see you.
Unfortunately, that meant being stuck
affecting a blasé attitude.
Rebel Alley?
We spoke three days ago.
I know, I know. I remember.
- Are you a member here?
- No, I'm not.
No, I just walked in past
the big black security guard.
All of which now worked against him.
Okay, you know what?
I was trying to be nice,
but you're just a jerk.
You're a bigger jerk than
Andy Richter over there!
Loosen up, bitch.
I'm Andy Richter!
I probably make, like,
$8,000 a day or something.
Hey, I'm... I'm sorry. I... I...
You know, I'm in the
middle of a whole thing
with my dad right now, and I, um...
I didn't mean to be...
however I just came off.
Badly.
Well, I'm sorry, you know.
I've never met a beautiful actress before.
Oh, so you do know who I am?
God, of course I know who you are!
You were in the remake
of "Dangerous Cousins."
I signed up to Netflix
because of that movie.
Uh-huh.
I think I was thrown that you
were interested in who I am.
Well, you are George Maharis.
- Everyone's talking about your software company.
- Oh, yeah.
I'm sure women are just
throwing themselves at your feet.
Well, you know, I, uh... I
prefer a woman who aims higher.
- That was funny.
- Yeah, I know.
- That was good. That was...
- Smooth.
Smooth. Hey, we have
the same taste in words.
Okay, should we get a drink? I'm buying.
I don't want you to think
I'm after you for your money.
George Michael was
thrown by what was clearly
Rebel's stated interest in him.
George Michael? George Michael?
Which is perhaps why he ignored the page...
- George Michael?
- ... that he assumed
- was from his father.
- George Michael?
Is George Michael here?
Oh, God.
Just remind me not to go in the men's room!
Uh, would you excuse me?
I... I'm just gonna use the men's room.
- Okay.
- And while checking
his messages, he got some good news.
Hey, buddy, it's Dad. Um, I am having
real trouble getting up there.
Uh, this traffic is unbelievable.
We got a light aircraft right
in the middle of the freeway.
Call me back when you get this?
But while Michael was
leaving a second message,
George Michael left one for him.
Oh. Hey, hang on. This is you.
Hey, it's me. You know what?
I bet we're sitting in the exact
same traffic; this is a mess.
Now hoping to ensure
that his father didn't
make it to their meeting.
Maybe that's better. Oh,
God, they're forcing us off.
Oh, God, they're forcing us off,
but you know, we can
just do this another time
if that works. Maybe that's better.
Oh, they're closing the
lanes. Oh, this is beautiful.
Same traffic. Unreal.
Unreal. Kind of looking around for you now.
Maybe you're right near me.
Anyhow, if you get this,
maybe we will just meet... somewhere else.
Gonna hang up now.
I'm going to video this
and send it in to the news.
Glad you're getting some footage of this,
'cause I can't really
get a good angle myself.
They're forcing us off here
like a bunch of animals.
You know, maybe we'll do this
another time, 'cause this is...
It's sad to say, but it's left me...
animals. You know maybe
we'll do this another time.
It's sad to say,
but it's left me pretty shaken up.
God, I just hope there
are no kids on that plane.
'Cause, you know, they don't
have any choice in the matter.
Well, I'll tell you what.
I feel worse for the parents, okay?
Probably the kids thought
that they could fly the
plane all by themselves.
Bet you 500 bucks they find
a dead kid behind the stick.
You know, or maybe on the dead dad's lap
whose only fault was
loving that kid too much
and letting him fly the plane.
Next thing he knows,
he's bouncing of the top
of the Sports Chalet onto
the express lane of the 605.
- I'll bet you 500 bucks.
- Michael was hurt
- and on his way out...
- See you. I'm out of your hair.
When he heard something
that cheered him up.
The guy that was harassing
Rebel... he's on his way down.
Say, Rebel?
Hey, Andy Richter.
Michael Bluth. How you doing, Andy?
Oh, yeah. I... I'm Andy.
So, I know him. Can I
get on your membership,
- and can you vouch for me? Okay?
- Oh, yeah, sure.
Whatever you want... it's on Andy.
Thank you.
It's on this rich hole.
Bye.
But before Michael could find Rebel,
he ran into the man, that at that point,
he still thought was her lover.
Ron!
- Hey.
- No, no. It's Michael.
Michael Bluth... doing the
film about my family and...
Yeah, when are we gonna get
your kid's signature, though?
- Yeah, I'm working on it.
- Oh.
- And I... I got a hold of him.
- Oh, oh.
And we're gonna meet here tonight,
but I think that he's blowing me off.
Well, yeah, kids will be kids, right?
Well, you know, a month
ago, I would have told you
that he and I were exactly
the same, that we were twins.
But now, I wouldn't even
think of my son as my brother.
You know, the thing is...
He's busy.
George Michael finds himself the subject
of a lawsuit over the ownership
- of Fakeblock.
- Could you put in a good word
on the missing Lucille 2 case?
That's a career maker.
That's an O.J.
You just need one of those. Huh?
Uh, excuse me, uh, but was
it or was it not my client
who put up the initial seed
money for the block software
that served as the underlying
architecture of Fakeblock?
- It was 99 cents.
- Times three.
Times three.
Can I say something to my client?
Take to the sea!
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -