All right, Morty, you ready
for our adventure
to the Lost City of Atlantis?
Ready as I'll ever be, Rick.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Hello. I'm Rick K-22.
This is my Morty.
We're going from reality to reality
asking Ricks to contribute
to the Citadel of Ricks
Redevelopment Fund.
What are you, stupid?
We're done with the Citadel of Ricks.
I was never on board with it
in the first place.
That's why I murdered everyone
in charge and left it to rot.
Oh, that was you.
- They tried to murder him first.
- Aw, geez.
Well, you'll be happy to know
that the council's gone now.
Yeah, he knows.
He murdered them.
- You want to rein in your Morty?
- Every day.
The Citadel of Ricks
Redevelopment Fund donates...
Morty, he's not gonna donate.
You're pitching the Policeman's Ball
to a black teenager here.
- Let's go.
- You don't have to be a dick.
I think you know that's not true.
Geez. I didn't know there were
still Ricks and Mortys
living on the Citadel.
I wonder what their day-to-day
lives are like.
Well, you can keep wondering that
while we go on a fun, fresh,
self-contained adventure to Atlantis.
Anyone continuing to explore
the Citadel is either stupid
or one of the unfortunate millions
held hostage by their terrible ideas.
Man, I'm glad I'm not one of them!
♪ Somewhere out on that horizon ♪
♪ Out beyond the neon lights ♪
♪ I know there must be somethin' better ♪
♪ But there's nowhere else in sight ♪
♪ It's survival in the city ♪
♪ When you live from day to day ♪
♪ City streets don't have much pity ♪
♪ When you're down,
that's where you'll stay ♪
Citadel Morning News.
News about the Citadel in the morning,
pretty self-explanatory.
Good morning. I'm Rick D-716B.
- And I'm Rick D-716.
- Must be nice.
Coming up, gravity outages
in East Sanchez Heights.
And is your uranium-powered
cellular matrix
making you sick?
The answer may not surprise you.
It's... Yes, it's uranium.
Those stories and more
after this break.
60 iterations off the central finite curve,
there's a Rick that works
more with wood
than polarity plating.
His name is Simple Rick,
but he's no dummy.
He realized long ago
that the greatest thing
he'd ever create
was his daughter.
I love Daddy!
We captured that moment.
We run it on a loop
through Simple Rick's mind,
and the chemical it makes
his brain secrete
goes into every Simple Rick's
"Simple Wafers" Wafer Cookie.
Come home to the impossible flavor
of your own completion.
Come home to Simple Rick's.
Just one day remains before
our newly democratic Citadel
elects its first President.
It's anyone's race among
the Rick candidates.
But a certain other
candidate should be getting
at least one vote for most adorable.
That's right. The Morty party
candidate's still in the race,
and you just gotta love him for that.
Here you see him in his
little Morty suit waving.
Isn't that adorable?
Little jackass.
Uh, yeah, I think we actually have
the audio for his speech here.
"Aw, geez. Aw, man.
I'm gonna lose the election and stuff."
We had a good run, sir,
but I think it's time
to pull out of the race.
I feel pretty confident
about tonight's debate.
You shouldn't, sir.
You should be terrified.
Maybe you should find
a little faith, young man.
You don't pay me to have faith.
And we're the same age!
- Aah!
- Whoa!
Oh. Sorry. I-I was expecting...
A Rick partner?
Lesson one, rookie,
expect the unexpected.
Now, get in.
Mortys are human!
Get the fuck off the car,
you Rickless fuckin' animal!
- Whoa!
- The election's
got these yellow shirts more riled up
than a picture-day Jessica.
That's pretty harsh, sir.
So report me.
Nobody gives a fuck.
Look, I'm just saying,
it makes me a little sad
to hear a Morty cop
calling Mortys animals.
Well, it makes me sad
to hear another Rick cop
buying into his sensitivity training.
Well, I'm glad to know
there's more like me.
Oh, there was one.
Why do you think that seat was empty?
Robbery at Fifth and Avenue.
Fifth and... That's Morty Town.
Unit seven responding.
Ohh!
Good idea, Rick.
This is a great adventure.
I love being your new Morty.
I love being your new Mor...
Farty.
Very amusing, Mr. Smith.
Almost as amusing
as when your first Rick
was decapitated on Zorpantheon Nine.
Or was that your third Rick?
How many Ricks have you had?
- Five.
- I see.
So you are top
of the class in something.
Tomorrow you'll be transferred
to your new Ricks.
Hopefully they will be your last.
Yes, Slow Ri... Tall Morty?
Di... Did I gradgitate this time yet?
Anything's possible, Tall Morty.
I guess we won't be seeing
each other after this, huh?
I say we make our last day count.
I say... we go to the Wishing Portal.
- That's a myth.
- It's not a myth.
My first Rick's fourth Morty
knew a Rick whose Morty went there.
If we're not here for graduation,
our butts are gonna
wind up in Morty Town.
I thought your last Rick
fused you with a lizard,
not a chicken.
Okay, fine. I'm in.
Me too.
- What the hell?!
- I thought I saw a fly.
Listen up, fuck nuts.
I've been your supervisor
for five years,
but all shitty things
must come to an end,
and I have been promoted
to regional manager.
Yeah, I feel the same way.
May be never meet again.
Of course, that makes
the position of supervisor available,
so, as of next week,
the ass you'll be kissing
will be that of...
K-83, affectionately known as Cool Rick.
I know I'm new to the Citadel,
and some of you might not
think I put in my time,
but what can I say?
I'm Cool Rick!
Yo! Ha! Ha! Check me out!
All right knuckleheads, any questions?
All right, then, back to work,
you gold rickers.
No Ricks, no families,
high off their asses,
and running amuck.
Mortys are raised to be sidekicks.
Without a side to kick,
they just start kicking.
They were...
They were about my height,
around 14 years old.
Oh, their... their shirts were yellow!
Yeah, make sure you get that down.
Any mutations, augmentations?
Uh, three eyes? A tail?
Maybe a buzz cut?
No. Just four normal Mortys.
- Normal?
- Put it in your blog.
Let me turn over a few rocks.
Aw, geez.
Hey, what's goin' on, fellas?
Aw, geez, man.
Nothing, man.
We're just hanging out and stuff.
I hear that. Aw, geez.
I guess I'm supposed to be figurin' out
who robbed the store across the street.
But, aw, geez, I don't know.
Aw, geez man, that sucks
that your Rick's making you do that.
He's not my Rick.
He's my partner.
Aw, geez.
Well, maybe the uniform
makes a big difference.
Who am I to say?
To me, you just look like a sidekick.
Call me a sidekick one more time!
- Call me a sidekick!
- Hey, man! Come on! Aw, geez!
Wanna see how I paint a wall?!
It was the Morty Town Locos, man!
The... The Morty Town Locos!
Aah! Aah!
Do you realize how many
codes you just violated?
Aw, geez, Rick.
What do I know about knowin' stuff?
Get in the fuckin' car.
More lasers.
You could take more time to answer
the question if you like.
Okay, Juggling Rick,
how would you solve
the Citadel's financial crisis?
First off, can I just say
that I believe this Citadel
is the greatest in the entire multi-verse.
Now, I believe the answer
to your question
has three parts.
First, education spending
must get much higher.
But it has to be
balanced with defense...
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Can we fact-check this please?
Never mind.
Who am I kidding?
This race is over.
And that's how you run a Citadel!
Candidate Morty, the number
of displaced Mortys is soaring
while Rick satisfaction
levels are plummeting,
and the divide between the two
groups has never been wider.
Solve that one real quick.
I don't see a divide between
Ricks and Mortys.
Oh, shocker.
I'd like to offer a re-buttal.
Gentlemen, gentlemen, I think
we can all agree on one thing.
Well, it came out as two things,
but you get the idea.
You guys finished?
The division I see is between
the Ricks and Mortys
that like the Citadel divided...
and the rest of us.
I see it everywhere I go.
I see it in our schools
where they teach Mortys
we're all the same,
because they're threatened
by what makes us unique.
I see it in our streets where
they give guns to Mortys
so we're too busy fighting
each other to fight real injustice.
I see it in our factories
where Ricks work for a fraction
of their boss' salary
even though they're identical
and have the same IQ.
The Citadel's problem
isn't homeless Mortys
or outraged Ricks.
The Citadel's problem
is the Ricks and Mortys
feeding on the Citadel's death.
Holy shit.
He's headed for the flavor core!
But I've got a message for them,
from the Ricks and Mortys
keeping it alive,
a message from the Ricks and Mortys
that believe in this Citadel
to the Ricks and Mortys that don't.
You're outnumbered.
Holy shit.
I don't believe it.
I-I can't believe it.
I know. That's why you're fired.
Sounds like you're looking for work.
I can offer you a very enticing
compensation package.
First, let's talk benefits.
Daddy loves you.
That's Daddy's good girl.
Your life is a lie, man.
All your life's are lies!
Don't you get it?!
They told us we were special
because we were Ricks,
but they stripped us of everything
that made us unique!
We know how you feel.
We're working-stiff Ricks just like you.
But our assembly line is justice.
What are your demands?
I-I-I want a portal gun.
Unregistered, untraceable,
with enough fluid to take
me off this goddamn prison!
- The media's outside.
- Well, keep 'em there.
Anyway, so, yeah, the suspect
says the Citadel's a lie,
built on lies, and some other shit.
I say appreciate the life you have,
because it can always be worse.
Back to you, Ricks.
Thank you, Rick 0716-C.
- That fuckin' guy.
- Tell me about it.
Meanwhile, in election news,
an unexpected turn of events
as Morty from the Morty Party
soars to the top of the polls.
- Morty! Morty! Morty!
- Yes.
Morty, what's your original reality,
and where's your Rick?
Gosh, we moved around so much,
it's hard to remember.
I see every Rick as my Rick.
I hope they see me as their Morty.
Another? Please?
With less water?
Hey, cheer up, pal.
A Morty's gonna be president.
Imagine this kisser getting
blamed for everything.
I guess I should've had more faith.
It's not faith you need.
It's fear.
What's this?
It's secrets.
Wh-Wh-Wh-What do you think it is?
Look at how I'm dressed.
Having taken aim at the system,
are afraid at all for your safety?
I'd rather live in hope than fear.
If I had to fear anything,
I'd fear other people being afraid.
Of fear. Itself.
But, no, I'm not afraid.
Hey, Rick, man,
when there's a Morty president,
you gonna lick my balls or what?
Sheeeet, grandson,
you keep me peelin' skrabquams
and slippin' nib nibs,
I'll lick whatever ain't nailed down.
Hands in the air!
What the hell, man?!
What the hellin' hell?
You guys doing a little
chemistry homework
- with Grandpa?
- Is this what I think it is?
Bootleg portal fluid.
I guess his math was off.
Search the place.
Are... Are you... my new... R-Rick?
It's okay, Morty.
Jesus.
He stabbed me.
He got me bad, Morty.
Shh. It's okay. You're okay.
You were right.
Everything I learned
at the academy was...
Doesn't matter.
Nothing's wrong with putting
your faith in a Morty.
You just gotta pick the right one.
Why is there a crib in here?
Something they do.
To make you feel bad.
Boy, I got us knee-deep
in paperwork, huh?
Go to the car and grab a medi-pack.
Let me worry about this.
- What happened?
- Same old story.
Mortys killing Mortys.
Almost... got it.
Hey!
Y'all get the hell away
from my damn mega fruit!
Sic 'em, boy!
I don't wear this dag-nab hat
and commit to this rural character
so you can eat for free
while you come of age!
I bet the Wishing Portal
leads to a reality
where they're... where all...
where it's a bunch of French
toast with boobies.
I bet it leads to a place
with a bunch of fry...
fly... flies everywhere.
Yeah, I bet it goes nowhere.
I bet it's a big hole
where the Citadel dumps
all its broken dreams.
Slick, why do you have
to be so dramatic?
You wanna know why?
Because of this.
I'm part of an experimental
line of Mortys
with a drama implant.
How do you think it feels, Fat Morty,
to know that no matter where I go,
I'll always be the one
that makes everybody sad
and a little bored?
Slick, that implant
isn't who you are, okay?
You also roll up your sleeves.
I thought I was Left-Handed Morty.
Then you should use your left hand
to eat more vegetables.
Hey, there. How you doing?
Great to meet you.
I'm a plumber, sir.
I'm a Rick, and I'm a plumber.
That doesn't sound like Rick work.
You didn't come to the Citadel
to be a plumber, did you?
Ha! Ha! I sure didn't, sir!
Mr. Morty! Mr. Morty!
I cloned myself so you
could kiss me as a baby!
This is just like a Morty baby!
Hey, did you, uh,
end up getting a new job?
Yeah, I did.
Assassinating you.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
I'm...
Aw, man. Aw, geez. Aw, hah.
You look like you could
use a good time.
One dance for $10, two for $25.
No, thank you. And bad math.
Ha! Ha! Yeah! This is a good time!
- What is this place?
- The Creepy Morty.
What is it your kind's always saying?
"Don't think about it."
Come on. There's someone
important I want you to meet.
Ah, Bubbala!
How'd it go with the Morty Town Locos?
They had a little accident.
They won't be causing
any trouble anymore.
Those were bad Mortys.
Very bad Mortys.
Big Morty likes to contribute
to keeping the peace in Morty Town.
Think of him as a "drug lord"
and us as cops on his payroll.
- Morty...
- Which Morty?
M-M-My partner.
Morty, you're right.
Morty Town is bad.
But that doesn't mean
that we have to be.
Hey, what's going on here, Morty?
- Which Morty?
- The cop, morons!
Don't worry about Rick, Big Morty.
He's new.
He doesn't understand how it works.
That's what you said
about your last partner.
Why would you say something
like that, Big Morty?
You're fucking things up
for both of us here.
Wrong. He's fucking things up
for both of you.
Unless he takes the money.
Big Morty, you're under arrest.
S-Smartest man in the universe.
They're just props!
Th-They're just props!
Not so big now, are ya?
I never was!
It was figurative!
That's enough.
If we don't kill him, he'll talk.
If you do, I'll talk.
O-One thing's for sure.
Y-Y'all don't have to worry
about Cowboy Morty talkin'.
This little cowpoke's gonna
mosey up on out of here.
You told me to put my faith
in the right Morty.
I've got faith in you, partner.
Do the right thing.
Oh, Grandpa Rick,
I-I don't wanna be
on the Citadel anymore.
I wanna be a regular kid.
I-I wanna to go to school
and throw balls around
and masturbate.
What the hell happened in there?
Same old story.
Ricks killing Mortys.
Okay, man, okay,
we got your portal gun.
What the hell's he doing?
- Where... Where am I?
- A bad place.
But you're going to a better one soon.
Hey! Hey!
- No, no, no, no!
- Whaa...
God damn it!
A portal to the blender dimension?
That's the oldest trick in the book!
I'm a Rick!
I'm more Rick than any of you!
Then you should know you just
killed your only leverage!
Then comes and get me, motherfuckers!
Stop. I'm Rick D. Sanchez the Third,
owner of this here wafer establishment,
and I say that the Rick
in there is right.
He's more Rick than any of you.
He's a terrorist!
What Rick isn't?!
The Citadel was founded
by Ricks for Ricks to be free!
What's your name, young man?
- Rick. And I'm...
- The same age as me, I know.
- How long have you worked here?
- 15 years.
What the hell have we become?
Whatever time you were gonna
make him serve, he's served it.
It ends now.
- Come with me, friend.
- Where are we going?
To your new life.
Which starts with walking
the fuck out of here.
Yo J-22, give 'em hell!
There's a Rick that held
a factory hostage
after murdering his boss
and several co-workers.
The factory made cookies,
flavored them with lies.
He made us all take a look
at what we were doing.
And in the bargain, he got
a taste of real freedom.
We captured that taste,
and we keep giving it to him
so he can give it right back to you
in every bite of new Simple Rick
Freedom Wafer Selects.
Come home to the unique flavor
of shattering the grand illusion.
Come home to Simple Rick.
It is real.
After you.
There it is. The Wishing Portal.
They say for your wish to come true,
you have to give up
something really important.
For me, that's my panini maker.
I wish for a million sandwiches.
And, yes, I see the irony.
I guess I wish I had something cooler
than this dumb-ass surfer necklace.
I wish incest porn had...
had a more mainstream appeal.
For... For a friend of mine.
None of those things
are gonna happen, you know.
Morty wishes never come true.
Not on the Citadel.
Then why did you bring us here?
Because I wish that would change.
I wish anything about
this life would change.
Well, I hope you're putting something
pretty goddamn important in there.
Me too.
But I doubt it.
- No!
- Slick!
M-Maybe...
Maybe it went somewhere nice.
Garbage dump.
Stand back.
He had to be stopped.
He... He cou... He c...
couldn't be allowed to win.
Then you should've worked
on your aim, bro.
He's alive? No, no, no.
You gotta listen to me.
I-I worked for him.
I was his campaign manager.
That Morty is not what he seems.
Yeah, well, no Morty
seems like a president.
- He... won?
- Yeah.
It was a blowout.
I would hardly call it a blowout.
It was almost close enough
to trigger a recount.
Jesus. What are you,
joke security now, too?
Why am I still here?
I heard he confessed to everything.
Your case has been reviewed.
You're free to go.
But... I violated at least
a dozen departmental codes.
New department. New codes.
New Citadel.
Did we miss graduation?
Where are the new Ricks?
No graduation. No new Ricks.
The school's curriculum is changing.
To what?
I don't know, and I don't have to know.
I've been fired.
Good luck, turds.
Holy crap. Slick's wish came true.
Sorry I'm late, Mr. President.
- Had a little crisis at work.
- Worth it!
It's no problem.
Uh, a little more off the top.
You were saying, Garment District Rick.
We were saying, "President" Morty,
that we don't care
who sits in that seat.
A Rick, a Morty, a goddamn Jerry,
doesn't matter.
We've been running the Citadel
since before the council,
and you'll find that we're
still running it now.
Does he really speak for everyone here?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Well, I think it's important to be clear.
Raise your hand if he speaks for you.
Is... that enough off the top?
I don't know. Is it?
- Yes, yes, goddamn, yes.
- I think it's great.
Good.
This seems like a good time for a drink
and a cold calculated speech
with sinister overtones.
A speech about politics...
about order...
brotherhood...
power.
But speeches are for campaigning.
Now is the time for action.
♪ Ah-ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ Ah, ah-ah ♪
Whoo! Yeah!
- Atlantis, baby!
- That was amazing.
You got some of that mermaid puss.
I'm really hoping it wasn't
a one-off thing
and I can see her again.
By the way, hey, um,
still not curious about
what might've happened
at that crazy Citadel place?
Psh. Not at all, Morty.
That place will never have
any bearing over our lives ever again.
Unlike that mermaid puss! Yeah!
We're going back for seconds!
We're gonna do that shit
every week, man!
- That was Atlantis!
- Oh, shit!