Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
... Aang can save the world
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
We're heading to Ba-Sing-Se
Why would we go to the
Earth Kingdom capital?
The city is filled with refugees
uh... what's Suki up to?
Actually, she and the other
warriors left to fight in the war.
My name is Jet.
The Fire nation killed my parents.
I was only 8 years old.
That day changed me forever.
All those people...
Jet, you monster!
This was a victory Katara!
The Fire nation is gone and this
valley will be safe.
- Tell me where Appa is!
- I traded him!
He's probably in Ba-Sing-Se by now!
Waterbending bomb!
Sure, 5000 year old maps from the spirit
library, just splash some water on 'em.
Sorry.
So, did you figure out
what route we're gonna take?
Okay. We just got out of the
desert, so we must be around here,
and we need to go to Ba
Sing Se, which is here.
It looks like the only passage
connecting the South to the North...
is this sliver of land
called the Serpent's Pass.
You're sure that's the best way to go?
It's the only way,
I mean it's not like
we have Appa to fly us there.
Shush up about Appa. Can't
you at least try to be sensitive?
Katara, it's ok.
I know I was upset about
losing Appa before,
but I just want to focus
on getting to Ba Sing Se,
and telling the Earth
King about the solar eclipse.
Oh, well, ok. I'm glad you're doing better.
Then to Ba Sing Se we go,
no more distractions.
Hello there fellow refugees!
So, are you guys headed to Ba Sing Se too?
Sure are, we're trying to get
there before my wife Ying has her baby.
Great, we can travel through
the Serpent's Pass together.
The Serpent's Pass?! Only the
truly desperate take that deadly route.
Deadly route. Great pick, Sokka.
Well, we are desperate.
You should come with us to Full Moon Bay.
Ferries take refugees across the lake.
It's the fastest way to Ba Sing Se.
And it's hidden, so the
Fire Nation can't find it.
Hmmm, peaceful ferry ride...
or deadly pass?
I can't believe how many people's lives
have been uprooted by the Fire Nation.
We're all looking for a better life.
Safe, behind the walls of Ba Sing Se.
Who would have thought, after all these years, I'd
return to the scene of my greatest military disgrace...
as a tourist...
Look around, we're not
tourists, we're refugees.
I'm sick of eating rotten food, sleeping in the dirt.
.. I'm tired of living like this.
Aren't we all?
My name's Jet, and these
are my freedom fighters,
Smellerbee, and Longshot.
Hey
Hello
Here's the deal.
I hear the Captain's eating like a king, while
us refugees have to feed off his scraps.
Doesn't seem fair, does it?
What sort of "king" is he eating like?
The fat, happy kind.
You want to help us "liberate" some food?
I'm in.
I've told you already,
no vegetables on the ferry!
One cabbage slug could destroy
the entire ecosystem of Ba Sing Se.
Security!
Ah! My Cabbages!
Next!
Um, four tickets for the
ferry to Ba Sing Se, please.
Passport.
Uh, no one told us we
had to have passports.
Don't you know who this is?
He's the Avatar!
Ah, I see fifty Avatars a day, and
by the way, not a very impressive costume.
Besides, no animals allowed.
Do I need to call security?
That won't be necessary.
Next!
I'll take care of this.
My name is Toph Bei Fong,
and I'll need 4 tickets.
Oh! The Golden Seal of the Flying Boar,
it is my pleasure to help
anyone of the Bei Fong family.
It is your pleasure. As you can see I am blind,
and these three imbeciles are my valets.
But the animal...
Is my Seeing-Eye Lemur.
Well, normally it's only
1 ticket per passport, but,
this document is so official,
I guess it's worth 4 tickets.
Thank you very much.
Alright, we scammed that lady good!
Tickets and passports please.
Is there a problem?
Yeah,
I've got a problem with you.
I've seen your type before,
probably sarcastic, think your hilarious, and
let me guess, you're traveling with the Avatar.
Do I know you?
You mean you don't remember?
Maybe you remember this.
Suki!
Sokka, it's good to see you!
You look so different without
your makeup, and the new outfit.
That crabby lady makes all
the security guards wear them.
And look at you sleeveless guy.
Been working out?
I'll grab a tree branch and do a few chin
touches every now and then, nothing major.
Are the other Kyoshi warriors around?
Yeah, after you left Kyoshi, we
wanted to find a way to help people.
We ended up escorting some refugees,
and we've been here ever since.
Hi Momo, good to see you too.
So why are you guys getting tickets for the ferry?
Wouldn't you just fly across on Appa?
Appa is missing. We hope
to find him in Ba Sing Se.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Are you doing okay?
I'm doing fine. Would everybody
stop worrying about me!
Avatar Aang, you have to help us!
Someone took all of our belongings.
Our passports, our tickets.
Everything's gone!
I'll talk to the lady for you.
No passports, no tickets!
But she's pregnant, and all of their stuff was stolen.
You have to make an exception.
No exceptions!
If I just gave away tickets willy nilly
to anyone, there would be no more order,
and you know what that means.
No more civilization!
What if we gave them our tickets?
NO!
But...
NEXT!
Don't worry, you'll get to the city safely.
I'll lead you through the serpents pass.
I can't believe we gave up our tickets, and
now we're going through the Serpent's Pass.
I can't believe you're
still complaining about it.
I'm coming too.
Are you sure that's a good idea?
Sokka, I thought you'd want me to come...
I do, it's just...
Just what?
Nothing. I'm glad you're coming.
This is the Serpent's Pass?
I thought it would be more windy,
you know, like a serpent. Hmm,
I guess they misnamed it.
Look at this writing, how awful.
- What does it say?
- It says, "Abandon hope".
How could we abandon hope?
It's all we have.
I don't know. The monks used to
say that hope is just a distraction.
So maybe we do need to abandon it.
What are you talking about?
Hope isn't going to get us into
Ba Sing Se, and it's not gonna find Appa.
We need to focus on what we're doing right
now, and that's getting across this pass.
Ok, if you say so.
The fire nation controls the western lake.
Rumor has it they're working on something big on the other
side, and they don't want anyone to find out what it is.
I'm okay.
They've spotted us! Let's go, let's go!
Suki, are you ok? You have
to be more careful! Come on.
Thanks for saving my life Toph.
Hey no problem Sokka.
Suki, you shouldn't sleep there.
Who knows how stable this ledge
is? It could give way at any moment.
Sokka, I'm fine. Stop worrying!
You're right, you're right. You're perfectly
capable of taking care of yourself...
Wait!
Oh, never mind. I thought
I saw a spider, but you're fine.
Guards coming!
You know, it's o. k. to miss Appa.
What's going on with you?
In the desert, all you
cared about was finding Appa,
and now it's like you
don't care about him at all.
You saw what I did out there.
I was so angry about losing
Appa, I couldn't control myself.
I hated feeling like that.
But now you're not letting
yourself feel anything.
I know sometimes it hurts more
to hope, and it hurts more to care.
But you have to promise
me that you won't stop caring.
C'mon, you need a hug.
Thank you for your concern Katara.
It's a beautiful moon.
Yeah, it really is.
Look, I know you're just trying
to help, but I can take care of myself.
I know you can.
Then why are you acting so over protective?
It's so hard to lose
someone you care about.
Something happened at the North
Pole, and I couldn't protect someone.
I don't want anything
like that to ever happen again.
I lost someone I cared about.
He didn't die, he just went away.
I only had a few days to
get to know him, but he was...
smart, and brave, and funny.
Who is this guy? Is he taller than me?
No, he's about your height.
Is he better looking?
It is you stupid!
Oh!
I can't.
I'm... sorry.
No, you shouldn't be.
So, Smellerbee, that's an
unusual name for a young man.
Maybe it's because I'm not a man.
I'm a girl!
Oh, now I see! It's a beautiful
name for a lovely girl!
I know. You're right. As long as I'm confident with
who I am, it doesn't matter what other people think.
Thanks Longshot.
From what I heard, people eat
like this every night in Ba Sing Se.
I can't wait to set my
eyes on that giant wall.
It is a magnificent sight.
So you've been there before?
Once, when I was a different man.
I've done some things in
my past that I'm not proud of.
But that's why I'm going to
Ba Sing Se, for a new beginning.
A second chance.
That's very noble of you.
I believe people can change
their lives if they want to.
I believe in second chances.
Everyone single file.
Aang, I need help.
What is that thing?
I think I just figured out why
they call it the Serpent's Pass.
Suki, you know about giant sea monsters.
Make it go away!
Just because I live near the
Unagi doesn't mean I'm an expert!
Oh great and powerful sea serpent, please accept
this humble and tasty offering. Thank you.
Sokka!
I'll distract him.
Katara, get everyone across.
Toph, come on. It's just ice.
Actually, I'm gonna stay on
my little island where I can see.
Ok, I'm coming!
You're doing great! Just
follow the sound of my voice!
It's hard to ignore.
You're almost there.
Help! I can't swim!
I'm coming Toph!
Help!
Oh Sokka, you saved me.
Actually, it's me.
Oh, well... heheh... You can
go ahead and let me drown now.
There's the wall!
Now it's nothing but
smooth sailing to Ba Sing Se.
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
The baby's coming!
What!? Now!?
Can't you hold it in or something?
Sokka, Calm down. I helped Gran-
Gran deliver lots of babies back home.
This isn't the same as delivering an
arctic seal! This is a real "human" thing!
It's called a baby, and I helped
to deliver plenty of those too.
Aang, get some rags. Sokka, water.
Toph, I need you to make an earth tent.
A big one.
Suki, come with me.
You know, as soon as I saw your
scar, I knew exactly who you were.
You're an outcast, like me.
And us outcasts have to stick together.
We have to watch each other's backs,
because no one else will.
I've realized lately, that being
on your own isn't always the best path.
You're doing great Ying.
Sokka! Where's that water?
Get ready to push.
One, two, three... PUSH!
It's a girl!
So, you want to go see the baby? Or are
you going to faint like an old lady again?
No no, I'm good this time.
Aang, you have to come see this.
She sounds healthy.
She's beautiful.
It's so... squishy looking.
What should we name her?
I want our daughter's name to be unique.
I want it to mean something.
I've been going through
a really hard time lately.
But you've made me... hopeful again.
I know what I want to name our baby now.
Hope
That's a perfect name. Hope.
I thought I was trying to be strong, but really
I was just running away from my feelings.
Seeing this family together,
so full of happiness and love,
it reminded me of how I feel about Appa...
and how I feel about you.
I promise I'll find Appa as fast as I can.
I just really need to do this.
See ya in the big city.
Say hi to that big fuzzball for me.
You'll find him Aang.
I know.
Thank you Katara.
You ready Momo?
Sokka, It's been really
great to see you again.
Whoa, hold on. Why does it
sound like you're saying goodbye?
I came along because I wanted to make sure
you got through the Serpent's Pass safely.
But now I need to get back
to the other Kyoshi warriors.
So you came along to protect me?
Listen, I'm really sorry about last night.
We were talking, and saying things, I just
got carried away and before I knew it I...
You talk too much.
Sorry Momo, Appa's gonna have to wait.
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk