Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
... Aang can save the world
This drill is a feat of scientific
ingenuity and raw destructive power.
Once it tunnels through the wall,
our troops will storm their city.
The Earth kingdom will finally fall,
and you can claim Ba Sing
Se in the name of your father.
Nothing can stop us.
Hmm. What about those
muscle-y guys down there?
Please
the drill's metal shell is impervious
to any earthbending attack.
Oh, I'm sure it is War Minister Ching.
But just to be on the safe side?
Mai, and Ty lee, take the earthbenders out!
Finally, something to do.
Aang, what are you doing here?
I thought you were looking for Appa?
I was, but something stopped me.
Something big.
Now what's so big that Appa has to wait?
That
We made it to Ba Sing
Se, and we're still not safe.
No one is.
What are you people doing here?
Civilians aren't allowed on the wall.
I'm the Avatar.
Take me to whoever's in charge.
It is an honor to welcome
you to the outer wall young Avatar,
but your help is not needed.
Not needed?
Not needed.
I have the situation under control.
I assure you the Fire Nation
cannot penetrate this wall.
Many have tried to break through
it, but none have succeeded.
What about the Dragon of the West?
He got in.
Well...uh...technically yes.
But he was quickly expunged.
Nevertheless, that is why
the city is named Ba Sing Se.
It's the impenetrable city.
They don't call it Na Sing Se.
That means penetrable city.
Yeah, thanks for the tour,
but we still got the drill problem.
Not for long. To stop it, I've sent ...
an elite platoon of earthbenders
called the Terra Team.
That's a good group name, very catchy.
Ready! Attack!
We're doomed!
Get a hold of yourself man!
You're right, I'm sorry.
Maybe you'd like the Avatar's help now?
Yes, please.
The question is, how
are we gonna stop that thing?
Why are you all looking at me?
You're the idea guy.
So I'm the only one who
can ever come up with a plan?
That's a lot of pressure.
And also the complaining guy.
That part I don't mind.
So, Mr. Lee, and Mr... umm Mushy is it?
It's pronounced Moo-shee.
You telling me how to do my job?
No, no.
But may I just say that you're like a
flower in bloom, your beauty intoxicating.
You're pretty easy on the
eyes yourself handsome.
Welcome to Ba Sing se.
I'm gonna forget I saw that.
I think Lee would make a
good Freedom Fighter.
He's just trying to find
his way in the world, like us.
You don't know anything about him Jet.
I know he didn't get
that scar from a waterbender.
Besides, I thought we
were going straight now?
We are, and the new Freedom
Fighters could use a guy like Lee.
What do you think Longshot?
I can respect that.
What's wrong with him?
He doesn't look injured.
His Chi is blocked.
Who did this to you?
Two girls ambushed us,
one of them hit me with
a bunch of quick jabs,
and suddenly I couldn't earthbend,
and I could barely move
and then she cart wheeled away.
Ty-Lee
She doesn't look dangerous, but she
knows the human body and it's weak points.
It's like she takes you
down from the inside.
Yes.
What you just said,
that's how we're gonna take down the Drill.
The same way Ty lee took
down all these big earthbenders.
By hitting its pressure points!
We'll take it down from the inside.
Once I whip up some cover, you're not
gonna be able to see, so stay close to me.
Run!
Hey, look at that dust cloud.
It's so...poofy. Poof!
Don't worry Princess.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Everyone into the hole!
It's so dark down here,
I can't see a thing.
Oh no, what a nightmare.
Sorry.
There!
Toph, Come on!
No way am I going in that metal monster.
I can't bend in there.
I'll try to slow it down out here.
Okay, good luck.
I need a plan of this machine.
Some schematics that show what the inside looks like.
Then we can find it's weak points.
Where are we gonna get something like that?
What are you doing!?
Someone's gonna hear us!
That's the point.
I figure a machine this
big needs engineers to run it,
and when something breaks...
They come to fix it.
Hi!
This'll work, thanks!
It looks like the Drill is
made up of two main structures.
There's the inner mechanism,
where we are now,
and the outer shell.
The inner part and the outer
part are connected by these braces.
If we cut through them,
the entire thing will collapse.
So, you guys got plans
once you're inside the city?
Get your hot tea here!
Finest tea in Ba Sing Se!
Oh! Jasmine, please.
Blaugh! Ugh. Coldest tea
in Ba Sing Se is more like it.
What a disgrace!
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
You and I have a much better chance of
making it in the city if we stick together.
You want to join the Freedom Fighters?
Thanks, but I don't think
you want me in your gang.
Come on, we made a great team looting that Captain's food.
Think of all the good we could do for these refugees.
I said no.
Have it your way.
Hey!
What are you doing firebending your tea?
For a wise old man, that
was a pretty stupid move.
I know you're not supposed
to cry over spilled tea, but
.. that's so sad.
Wow, it looks a lot thicker
in person than it does in the plans.
We're going to have to work
pretty hard to cut through that.
What's this we stuff? Aang and
I are going to have to do all the work.
Look, I'm the plan guy, You two are
the "cut stuff up with waterbending" guys.
Together, we're Team Avatar!
C'mon team, don't quit now, we're...
I mean, you're almost there.
At this rate, we won't do enough
damage before the drill reaches the wall.
I don't know how many more
of those I have in me.
Do you hear that? We took it down.
We better get out of here fast!
Congratulations crew, the Dill has
made contact with the wall of Ba Sing Se.
Start the countdown to victory!
C'mon brace, budge!
This is bad, really bad.
We're putting everything we've got into busting
these braces, but it's taking too long!
Maybe we don't need to
cut all the way through.
Toph has been teaching me that you shouldn't
give 100% of your energy into any one strike.
Sokka, take a fighting stance.
You've gotta be quick and accurate.
Hit a series of points,
and break your opponent's stance.
And when he's reeling back,
you deliver the final blow
His own weight becomes his downfall.
Literally.
So we just need to weaken the braces,
instead of cut all the way through.
Then I'll go to the top of this
thing, and deliver the final blow.
And boom, it all comes crashing down!
Everyone inside that wall,
the whole world, is counting on us.
The whole world, minus
the Fire Nation that is.
C'mon twinkle toes, hurry up!
That's enough, we need
to get to the next one!
War Minister, an engineer was
ambushed! His schematics were stolen!
War Minister, a brace on the starboard side has
been cut clean through! It's sabotage sir!
Let's go ladies.
Good work Team Avatar. Now
Aang just needs to ... DUCK!
Wow Azula, you were right,
it is the Avatar! ...and friends.
Hey
Guys get out of here, I
know what I need to do.
Wait! You need this water more than I do!
Follow them, the Avatar is mine.
Slurry pipeline? What does that mean?
It's rock and water mixed
together, it means our way out.
Ughh, disgusting!
Come on, you heard Azula.
We have to follow them.
She can shoot all the lightning she wants at
me, I am not going in that wall sludge juice.
Why don't you try blocking
my chi now circus freak!
Katara, keep that up.
The pressure will build up in the drill, then when
Aang delivers the final blow, it will be ready to pop!
This looks like a good spot Momo.
General Sung, tell your soldiers
to stop shooting rocks down here!
Soldiers, whatever you do, don't
stop shooting rocks down there!
Good technique little sister!
Keep it up! Don't forget to breathe!
You know, I am just about sick and
tired of you telling me what to do all day.
You're like a chattering Hog-Monkey!
Just bend the slurry woman!!
You guys need some help?
Toph, help me plug up this drain!
What I'd give to be a metal bender.
Momo, get out of here!
Thanks Momo, I owe you one.
Now all I need is a...
Actually, that is what I needed for once.
Here it comes!
We lost.
Last call for Ba Sing se!
Jet, relax! So the old
guy had some hot tea. Big deal.
He heated it himself!
Those guys are firebenders.
What a handsome baby.
Thank you.
I just want to say, good effort
out there today Team Avatar.
Enough with the Team Avatar stuff.
No matter how many times you
say it, it's not gonna catch on.
How about...
the "Boomerang Squad",
see it's good cause it's got "Aang" in it.
Boomer- Aang
I kinda like that one.
Let's talk about this on
our way into the city.
The "Aang Gang"?
Sokka
The "Fearsome Foursome"?
You're crazy.
Why? We're fearsome!
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk