Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world
needed him most...
an airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
... Aang can save the world
I came along because I wanted to make sure
you got through the Serpent's Pass safely.
But now I need to get back
to the other Kyoshi warriors.
You stole Appa! Where's
he? What did you do to him?
I traded him.
He's probably in Ba-Sing-Se by now!
He is here. I can feel it.
I am Long Feng, head of the Dai Li.
I understand you've been
looking for your bison.
It would be quite a shame if you
were not able to complete your quest.
No, stop sinking!
Don't make me put this down!
Put a muzzle on him!
I'm sorry Appa.
Ransack his saddle. Who knows
what treasures are stashed in there?
He's tied up good, he can't hurt you.
What's your father going to do when
he finds out we lost a sand sailor?
Nothing. It's the one
we stole from the Hammi tribe.
Did you empty the saddle?
That's it! Nothing but garbage!
It doesn't matter.
We'll still make a profit from selling
him to those beetle-headed merchants!
How's his temper?
Pretty good.
Uh, most of the time.
I bet someone will pay a
fortune for him in Ba Sing Se.
All right. You've got a deal.
Appa...
He's your problem now.
What...
We need the shirshu spit darts!
Got em'!
Ok big fella, you're gonna
take a nice little snoozle.
Appa...
No...
NO...
We've gotta get rid of this
one! He's too much trouble.
We could sell him for parts.
Oh. I understand you've
had a rather hard time lately.
That's too bad.
You probably felt you had no
choice but to behave outrageously.
Like a wild animal.
But don't worry, you won't anymore.
Because I am going to break you.
Hungry?
Don't worry, I'm going to feed you too.
But not yet.
First I am going to show
you how you'll earn it.
Or course, when you perform,
the hoops will be flaming.
And if you are careful,
you won't get burned.
You're about to be sorry.
It's obvious that whoever
your previous owner was,
he had no idea how to handle you properly.
I am gonna get a bag of sizzle-crisps.
Stay here and stay away from that monster.
Behave yourself, or you'll regret it.
He's a difficult creature,
stubborn and willful.
I need more time with him.
It's too risky right now.
Too Risky? What are you talking about?
This is the circus, home
of fear and danger.
I want the Wind Buffalo to perform tonight.
If you don't behave yourself,
you'll regret it.
Let's go!
See ya later buddy.
Ladies and gentleman, now
for something truly special.
A noble beast so magnificent and rare,
it hasn't been seen by
human eyes in generations.
I give you the Wind Buffalo!
Up!
Up, you insolent cow!
Run away! Get away from him.
Go. You can do it.
Get back here, you stupid beast!
Chose well.
A sky bison is a companion for life.
Ugh! I guess this mean
we'll always be together.
Always.
It's some kind of monster!
Uncle?
What are you looking at?
Is there something out there?
It's nothing. Go back to sleep.
Must have been some fight.
Wait. Let me see that.
No. It couldn't be.
Appa, oh no.
It's gonna be ok Appa.
I have to leave, but I am
gonna be back soon with help.
No sudden movements.
He's been lost for awhile,
and he looks like he's hurt.
He's shy around people and scared.
Stay low, and stay quiet.
I can't believe you found
the Avatar's bison.
Didn't you just see the
Avatar a few days ago?
Yes, so he can't be too far from here.
It's our responsibility
to get Appa back to him safely.
This could be our most
important mission yet.
Give him some space!
Appa.
Appa, it's me, Suki.
I'm a friend.
I want to help you.
You're hurt. We can help you feel better.
And we can help you find Aang.
My, my, you're easy to find.
It's really astounding my
brother hasn't captured you yet.
What do you want with us?
Who are you, the Avatar's fan girls?
Oh, I get it! Good one azula!
If you are looking for
the Avatar, you're out of luck.
I knew this was a waste of time.
No avatar huh?
Well that's ok, any friend
of the Avatar, is an enemy of mine.
You're so colorful, it's
making me nauseous.
You're not prettier than we are!
Afraid of fire I see. That's good,
you should be!
Go Appa! Fly away from here!
Get out of here.
Get out of here! You have to find Aang!
We'll be ok!
Don't you know that fans
just make flames stronger?
Hello. I am Guru Pathik.
I know I am not the person you expected.
And I didn't expect to be
licked by a giant tongue just now.
The world is full of surprises.
Oh, dear.
You've been through so much recently.
Hurt and betrayed,
so twisted up inside.
You're still full of love.
But fear has moved in
where trust should be.
I've been expecting you and the
young Avatar for quite a long time.
I had a vision many years
ago of helping him.
That's why I came to the
Eastern Air Temple.
Ahh. Your emotions are so turbulent.
Like swirling storm clouds.
Let the clouds in your
mind be gentle, peaceful ones.
Someone looks very well-rested,
judging by your bed head.
I have prepared a message for Aang.
May I attach it to your horn?
You and the Avatar's energies are mixed.
You have an unbreakable bond.
By reading your energy,
I can sense where Aang is.
Funny, what invisible
strings connect us all.
I will see you again, great beast.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk