Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
...Aang can save the world
Even though I was born blind,
I've never had a problem seeing.
I see with earthbending.
Look here, sugar queen, I gave up everything I
had so that I could teach Aang earthbending,
Well, look at this. Enemies
and traitors all working together.
Today's the day!
Can you believe it?
After all that time
searching for a teacher,
I'm finally starting earthbending!
And this place...i-it's perfect!
Don't you think?
Sokka
Oh, you're still sleeping, huh?
Sorry!
Good morning earthbending student!
Good morning sifu Toph.
Hey! You never call me sifu Katara.
Well, if you think I should
Sorry, snoozles. We'll do our
earthbending as quietly as we can.
So what move are you
going to teach me first?
Rockalanche? The trembler? Oh!
Maybe I can learn to make a whirlpool out of land!
Let's start with move a rock.
Sounds good! Sounds good!
The key to earthbending is your stance.
You've got to be steady and strong.
Rock is a stubborn element.
If you're going to move it, you've
got to be like a rock yourself.
Like a rock. Got it.
Good. Now the actual motion
of this one is pretty simple.
Okay, you ready to give it a try?
I'm ready.
Rock beats airbender!
I got you, dad!
My beloved Lu Ten, I will see you again.
Uncle! You were unconscious.
Azula did this to you.
It was a surprise attack.
Somehow, that's not so surprising.
I hope I made it the way you like it.
Good
That was very, uhh... bracing!
So uncle, I've been thinking.
It's only a matter of time
before I run into Azula again.
I'm going to need to know more advanced firebending
if I want to stand a chance against her.
I know what you're going to say: she's my sister
and I should be trying to get along with her.
No, she's crazy and she needs to go down.
It's time to resume your training.
I don't understand what went wrong.
He did it exactly the way you did.
Maybe there's another way. What if I
came at the boulder from a different angle?
No, that's the problem.
You've got to stop thinking
like an airbender.
There's no different angle, no clever solution,
no trickity trick that's going to move that rock.
You've got to face it head on.
And when I say head on, I mean like this!
I've been training Aang for a while now.
He really responds well to
a positive teaching experience.
Lots of encouragement and praise.
Kind words.
If he's doing something wrong, maybe
a gentle nudge in the right direction.
Thanks Katara. A gentle nudge.
I'll try that.
Keep your knees high, twinkletoes!
Rocklike!
You're awfully cute, but unfortunately
for you, you're made of meat.
Just a bit closer...
Gotcha!
You are one lucky little meat creature.
Lightning is a pure
expression of firebending,
without aggression.
It is not fueled by rage or
emotion the way other firebending is.
Some call lightning the cold-blooded fire.
It is precise and deadly, like Azula.
To perform the technique
requires peace of mind.
I see. That's why we're drinking tea:
To calm the mind.
Oh yeah, good point!
I mean, yes.
There is energy all around us.
The energy is both yin and yang
positive energy and negative energy.
Only a select few firebenders
can separate these energies.
This creates an imbalance. The
energy wants to restore balance ...
and in a moment the positive and negative
energy come crashing back together.
You provide release and
guidance, creating lightning.
I'm ready to try it!
Remember, once you separate
the energy, you do not command it.
You are simply its humble guide.
Breathe first.
This time we're going to try something a
little different. Instead of moving a rock,
you're going to stop a rock.
Get in your horse stance!
I'm going to roll that boulder down at you.
If you have the attitude of an earthbender,
you'll stay in your stance and stop the rock.
Like this
Sorry Toph, but are you sure this is really
the best way to teach Aang earthbending?
I'm glad you said something.
Actually, there is a better way.
This way he'll really have to sense
the vibrations of the boulder to stop it.
Thank you Katara.
Yeah, thanks Katara!
I guess I just panicked.
I don't know what to say.
There's nothing to say.
You blew it. You had a perfect
stance and perfect form ...
but when it came right down
to it you didn't have the guts.
I know. I'm sorry.
Yeah, you are sorry. If you're
not tough enough to stop the rock,
then you could at least give it the pleasure of smushing you
instead of jumping out of the way like a jelly-boned wimp!
Now, do you have what it takes
to face that rock like an earthbender!?
No. I don't think I do.
Aang, it's no big deal. You'll take a break
and try earthbending again when you're ready.
Besides, you still have a lot
of waterbending to work on, okay?
Yeah, that sounds good.
Yeah, whatever, go splash
around until you feel better.
Why can't I do it? Instead of lightning,
it keeps exploding in my face!
Like everything always does!
I was afraid this might happen.
You will not be able to master lightning until
you have dealt with the turmoil inside you.
What turmoil?
Zuko, you must let go of your feelings
of shame if you want your anger to go away.
But I don't feel any shame
at all! I'm as proud as ever!
Prince Zuko, pride is not
the object of shame,
but its source.
True humility is the
only antidote to shame.
Well, my life has been
nothing but humbling lately.
I have another idea.
I will teach you a firebending
move that even Azula doesn't know,
because I made it up myself!
You probably think I
deserve this, don't you?
Look, I'm sorry I hunted you, but
that's just the natural order of things!
Big things eat smaller
things, nothing personal!
But this time it didn't work out that way.
I admit it. You're cute.
Okay, you've convinced me.
If I get out of this alive, it's a comically
correct vegetarian existence for me.
No meat. Even though meat is so tasty.
It looks like my karma
is already paying off!
That's okay! I got it!
Now come back boomerang.
You know this block you're
having is only temporary, right?
I don't want to talk about it.
You do know that's the problem, don't you?
If you face this issue
instead of avoiding it...
I know I know I know I
know, I get it, alright!
I need to face it head-on, like a rock.
But I just can't do it! I don't
know why I can't, but I can't.
Aang, if fire and water are opposites,
then what's the opposite of air?
I guess it's earth.
That's why it's so hard
for you to get this.
You're working with your natural opposite.
But you'll figure it out. I know you will.
Think fast!
Excellent.
You have the reflexes of
a waterbending master.
Thanks Katara.
Sifu Katara.
Fire is the element of power.
The people of the Fire Nation have desire and will,
and the energy and drive to achieve what they want.
Earth is the element of substance.
The people of the Earth Kingdom are diverse and strong.
They are persistent and enduring.
Air is the element of freedom.
The Air Nomads detached themselves from
worldly concerns and found peace and freedom.
Also, they apparently had
pretty good senses of humor!
Water is the element of change.
The people of the Water Tribe
are capable of adapting to many things.
They have a deep sense of community and love
that holds them together through anything.
Why are you telling me these things?
It is important to draw wisdom
from many different places.
If we take it from only one
place, it becomes rigid and stale.
Understanding others, the other
elements, and the other nations ...
will help you become whole.
All this four elements talk
is sounding like Avatar stuff.
It is the combination of the four elements in
one person that makes the Avatar so powerful.
But, it can make you more powerful too.
You see, the technique I am about to teach you
is one I learned by studying the waterbenders.
Aang! I found these nuts in your bag.
I think you would't mind. And besides,
even if you did, you're too much
of a pushover to do anything about it.
As a matter of fact, I don't mind.
I'm happy to share anything I have.
You know, I'm really
glad you feel that way,
because I also have this
great new nutcracker.
Actually, I'd prefer if you didn't.
..That's an antique,
hand crafted by the monks.
..lt's a delicate instrument!
It's not the only delicate
instrument around here.
Hey Aang, have you seen...
Meditating here!
It's important. It's almost
sundown and Sokka isn't back yet.
I think we should search for him.
We'll find him faster if we split up.
Okay karma person or thing,
whoever's in charge of this stuff,
if I can just get out of this situation
alive, I will give up meat and sarcasm. OK?
OW! That's all I got!
It's pretty much my whole identity!
Sokka, the meat and sarcasm guy!
But I'm willing to be Sokka
the veggies and straight talk fellow!
Deal?
Aang! Thank goodness!
Have you got any meat?
Sokka! Are you okay?
Stop, stop! You're going to pull my fingers off
and I don't think the rest of me is coming!
Hmm... I bet I can airbend you out of here.
Seriously Aang, I know you're new at it, but I could
use a little earthbending here. How about it?
I can't.
I can't do it.
Well if you can't earthbend
me out of here, go get Toph.
I can't do that either.
You can't? Why not?
It would just be really...uncomfortable.
Uncomfortable? Well, I wouldn't
want to make you feel uncomfortable.
Thanks Sokka.
This whole earthbending
thing really has me confused.
There's so much pressure. Everyone
expects me to get it right away.
It puts me in a really awkward position.
Awkward position?
I think I know the feeling.
If I try, I fail. But if I don't
try, I'm never going to get it.
I feel like I'm caught between
a rock and a hard place.
How about that.
Aang, this is my friend Foo Foo Cuddlypoops.
Foo Foo Cuddlypoops, Aang.
Aww, what a cute name for a
little baby sabertooth mooselion cub.
Really? He looks nothing
like a sabertooth mooselion.
It's hard to tell before their
giant teeth and horns grow in.
Whatcha doin' out here, little
guy? Did you lose your mama?
Waterbenders deal with the flow of energy.
A waterbender lets their
defense become their offense,
turning their opponents'
energy against them.
I learned a way to do this with lightning.
You can teach me to redirect lightning?
If you let the energy in your own
body flow, the lightning will follow it.
You must create a pathway from your fingertips up
your arm to your shoulder and down into your stomach.
The stomach is the source
of energy in your body.
It is called the sea of chi.
Only in my case, it is
more like a vast ocean.
From the stomach, you direct
it up again and out the other arm.
The stomach detour is critical.
You must not let the lightning pass through your heart
or the damage could be deadly.
You may wish to try a physical motion
to get a feel for the pathway's flow.
Like this.
Now, are you focusing your energy?
Can you feel your own chi flowing in, down, up, and out?
I think so.
Come on. You've got to feel the flow.
Excellent! You've got it!
Great! I'm ready to try
it with real lightning!
What, are you crazy?
Lightning is very dangerous.
I thought that was the point: You
teaching me how to protect myself from it.
Yah, But I'm not going to
shoot lightning at you!
If you are lucky, you will never
have to use this technique at all.
Well, if you won't help
me, I'll find my own lightning.
Hey there? We found your cub!
See? We have no problem with you!
We're friendly.
Aang, this is bad!
You gotta get me outta here!
This is really bad!
Please, Aang! You have to earthbend
me out, there's no other way!
Oh no
Whoo-hoo! Look at me!
Please don't leave me again.
I won't.
What are you doing here?
Just enjoying the show.
What?
You were there the whole time?
Pretty much.
Why didn't you do something?
Sokka was in trouble!
I was in trouble!
You could've gotten him
out and helped us get away!
I guess it just didn't occur to me.
Enough! I want my staff back!
Do it now.
What?
Earthbend, twinkletoes.
You just stood your ground
against a crazy beast,
and even more impressive,
you stood your ground against me.
You've got the stuff.
But...
Do it!
You did it!
You're an earthbender.
I can't believe it!
Aww, this is really a
wonderful, touching moment.
So, could you get me out of here so
I can give you both a big, snuggly hug?
No problem, Sokka!
Actually, you should probably let me do that.
You're still a little new to this.
You might accidentally crush him.
Yeah, no crushing please.
You found him!
The whole time that I was in that
hole, not knowing if I would live or die,
it makes a man think about
what's really important.
I realize...
Hey Katara, look what I can do!
You did it!
I knew you would!
You tried the positive
reinforcement, didn't you?
Yep. It worked wonders.
Appa! Appa! I can earthbend now!
The key is being completely rooted!
Physically and mentally unmovable!
You've always thrown
everything you could at me!
Well I can take it!
And now I can give it back!
Come on! Strike me!
You've never held back before!
-=To be Continued=-
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk