"Zombie attack"?
Never works.
They don't take orders.
"Blood rain"?
Ew. Mess up my suit.
Ha. no, thank you.
"Demon caterpillars"?
Snap!
There must be a perfect way
to exact vengeance
on the pines family.
It's not enough to harm 'em.
I need to take somethin'
from 'em,
somethin' that will give me
ultimate power.
Wait, of course!
( Whispers )
it's perfect.
Man on TV:
You've gone too far
this time, ducktective.
( Quacking )
( Doorbell rings )
Welcome to a world
of mystery--
Stan pines?
The tax collector!
You found me!
Uhh!
( Panting )
( Grunting )
Which one of these
is the trap door?
Mr. pines...
I'm from the winninghouse
coupon savers contest,
and you are
our big winner!
В™єв™є
heh?
My one and only dream,
which was to possess money,
has come true!
We're rich!
I'm gonna get a Butler!
I'm gonna buy
a talking horse!
Just sign here
for the money.
You bet!
Uhh! ha!
Stanford, you fool!
You just signed over
the mystery shack
to widdle ol' me!
В™є achacha cha cha в™є
( gasp )
liddle ol' me.
Ah, might wanna take
another look there.
"The shack is hereby
signed over to...
Suck a lemon,
little man."
Ahhh ha-ha-ha!
Uhh! how dare you!
( Laughing )
I am not a threat
to be taken lightly!
Unh unh!
Come here, hon,
i need your arms.
I'll get you,
Stanford pines.
I'll get you all!
Want to see
what else is on TV?
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, all right.
Should be fun.
My favorite part's
the theme song.
В™єв™є
little guy
to black space nine.
It's a "pawn,"
that's not your color,
and stop stealing
the tiny horses.
They like it better in here.
Don't you, babies?
( Whinnies )
And...
checkmate!
What? boo!
Ohh!
Dipper wins again!
Yo, Mabel, can you pass me
that brain in the jar?
The lady one.
I got it.
Thanks, but Mabel's taller.
What?
no, she's not.
We're the same height.
We've always been.
Better check again, dude.
Yup. she's got exactly
one millimeter on you.
What?!
whoa...
Don't you see
what's happening, Dipper?
This millimeter
is just the beginning.
I'm evolving into
the superior sibling.
Bigger...
Stronger...
Like some kind of
Alpha twin.
Alpha twin!
C'mon, guys, nobody
even uses millimeters.
It only makes you taller
than me in Canada.
You know, Dipper,
I've always wanted
a little brother.
Who knew
i already had one!
Hahaha! yeah!
I was awoken
by the sound of mockery.
Where is it?
Show me the object
of ridicule!
I'm taller than Dipper.
By one millimeter!
Hey, hey.
Don't get...Short
with your sister.
Hahahahah!
Now, grunkle Stan...
I hope you don't
think...Little of him!
Haha! yeah!
And, and, uh...
He's short!
Hahahaha!
hahahaha!
Dudes, maybe you should
lay off a tiny bit.
Hah! "tiny!"
Soos is in on it now!
Ahahahahahhaha!
ahahahahahhaha!
No, I didn't mean that.
Dipper will forget.
He's got a--3-2-1...
Short-term memory!
Hahah!
hahah!
Pow!
we are on fire!
( Slap )
Ow...ooh...
that's...aww...
I high-five hard.
Ugh...
stupid Mabel.
I'm not short!
Unh. unh.
Oh, come on!
There's gotta be some way
to get taller.
Let's see...
"Legends of miniature buffalo
and giant squirrels
"have led me to believe
"there are height-altering
properties
hidden deep within the forest."
Hmm...
Unh! whoa!
Ohh ow ow oh ow ow.
Ugh.
Ohh.
Whoa.
( Shrieks )
Huh?
( Growling )
huh!
Is that mountain lion tiny
or just far away
in perspective?
( Reow! )
Perspective!
perspective! aah!
Oof! hahaha!
( Purrs )
It still hurts,
but less!
Whoa.
What the heck.
Unh.
Smaller.
Bigger.
Too big!
I've been buying
big clothes.
I'll grow into them.
Hey, guys.
Notice anything
different about me?
Holy hot sauce!
You've grown
an extra millimeter!
Wha-wha-whhaaat?
What can I say, sis?
Growth spurt.
Eh, mine happened first.
I'm gonna be taller
in the end.
It's science, Dipper.
What? but we're
the same height now.
Alpha twin!
Oh, yeah?
Something tells me
I've got another growth spurt
coming on right now.
Give it up, Dipper.
( Gasps )
what happened!?
You know...
Puberty and stuff.
It doesn't make any sense!
Just a second ago
you were--
wait a minute.
This is some kind
of magicky thing,
isn't it?
Was it a wizard
or something?
There's a wizard
in this closet,
isn't there?
Isn't there?
What? No!
You're telling me
there is not a wizard
in this closet?
You're telling me
that if I open this door
right now--
fine! open it!
An invisible wizard!
Really, Dipper?
( Doorbell rings )
Oy. you.
Howdy, Stanford!
Listen closely.
Inside this jar,
i have 1,000 cursed
Egyptian super termites.
Hand over the deed
to your property
or I'll smash this jar
with a bat
and they'll devour
the shack with you inside.
Hey, what's that?
Huh?
( Gasps )
oh, no!
Aaahh!
get it off!
Ha ha ha!
Hey, Soos, get in here!
I wanna
take pictures of this!
You may have won
the battle,
but Mark my words,
Stanford,
your family
has a weak spot,
and I'm gonna to find it.
Aaughh!
my hair!
Does he only respond
to incantations?
Expecto wizarium!
Wizzle...
wizar...
It's not a wizard!
I grew myself using
this magic flashlight!
Let me see that thing!
Auugh!
I'll be back for you later!
Ahhh! oof!
Whoa!
huh?
( Car alarm blaring )
Huh? uhh.
Huh?
Aah!
It's okay.
It can shrink things, too.
Normal-hand-karate-chop!
Hey!
( Grunting )
Aaaaagh!
Wha?!
Ohhh!
Hey, give it back!
Whoa! never!
( Both grunting )
Curse the pines family!
Curse Stan!
Curse Dipper!
Curse....
My, my,
what delightful manner
of doohickery is this?
Maybe he didn't
see us use it
and doesn't know
it's a magic flashlight
that can grow
and shrink things.
Really?
Click. boop.
Hoo hoo.
Both: no, no, no, no!!!
Aah!
aah!
( Deep, bellowing laugh )
Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee.
( Air horn blows )
Friends, I wish
i was a highway
so I could have the honor
of being rode upon
by automobiles as fine
as these ones right ch'er.
( Snarls )
Engine possum
at no extra charge.
I want that thar car!
( Cheering )
Yeah, me, too!
Say there, son,
what's in the jar?
That's my widdle secret!
All: ahh!
( Giggles )
Mouth-breathing fools.
Mother.
( Both grunting )
You two.
What-- what are you
going to do with us?
Why, Mabel,
i wouldn't hurt a hair
on your itty bitty head.
If you agree
to be my queen!
We live in a democracy.
And never!
Maybe you'll change
your mind after this.
No! I will fight you
until the day I...
( Gasps )
gummy koalas!
( Munching )
As for you, boy...
Tell me,
how exactly
did you come upon
this magic item, hmm?
Did somebody
tell you about it?
Did you read about it
somewhere?
Lean closer
and I'll tell you.
( Chuckles )
well, don't mind if i--
( air horn blasts )
aah!
( Heavy breathing )
Grrr!
I could squash you
right now!!
Steel yourself, Gideon.
You can use them.
Soos, this maze of mirrors
is your best idea
that I'm
taking credit for yet!
We're gonna make a fortune!
My ears always been this big?
( Phone rings )
I'm comin'!
One day...
( Phone rings )
( Groans )
Gideon: Stanford pines.
Listen to me very closely,
i have your niece and nephew.
Hand over the deed
to the mystery shack
right now
or great harm
will befall them.
This is Gideon,
by the way.
( Laughing )
Oh, yeah.
This has gotta be
your worst plot yet.
They're fine.
I saw them playing
in the yard minutes ago.
I have them
in my possession.
You don't believe me?!
I will text you a photo.
"Text" me a "photo"?
Now you're not
even speaking english.
But--
hello? hello?!
Gahhhh!
Aah.
( Maniacal laughter )
What am I doing?
I don't need ransom.
I have this!
I'll shrink Stan
and take the shack
for myself!
You'll all be helpless
to stop me.
And if any of you
step out of line...
Smash!
( Maniacal laughter )
Bud gleeful:
Gideon!
The ice cream truck
is here!
Oh! coming!
Hehehe!
Guard them, cheekums.
I'm coming!
( Panting )
( Squeaking )
We got to get out of here
and save Stan.
I know!
I will see you later.
Ok, how are we
going to do this?
Gideon's got magic
and like a zillion
inches on us.
On the bright side,
at least we're finally
the same height again.
Actually...
( Grunting )
You're still taller?!
Argh!
how did this happen?
I guess
it's another mystery.
Just another reason
we gotta get
that flashlight back.
Cheekums, to freedom!
To freedom!
Ohh!
You're just
a big ol' dummy-dum!
I have a plan.
( Grunts )
( Munching )
Clean me!
Father, could you
give widdle ol' me
a "wide"
to the mystery shack?
Ohhh, I'd love to,
sugar pie,
but I have
a heck of a lot
of cars to sell, I do.
( Laughing )
No, no!
Don't tickle me!
No!
Never!
never tickle me!
What have I told you?
What have i--
look at me.
What have I told you?
Tickling
is no laughing matter.
There we go.
Do you still need a ride?
I'll just take the bus!
Raah!
Hyah!
Precious memories.
Just keep vacuuming...
Just keep vacuuming.
C'mon! uhh.
( Grunting )
We need to get higher.
Yeah, especially you
'cause you're short.
Mabel! up there.
Uhh.
unh.
What cute little thing
are you off to,
you cute
little cutey-face?
I'm going to annihilate
my archenemy's entire family!
Ohh! okay!
( Weakly )
yaayyy.
He's heading to shrink Stan!
Oh, flying discount dollar,
if only you could fly us
back to the mystery shack.
Maybe it can.
Oh!
oh!
( Gasps )
My sky-high prices!
Yeah!
whoo-hoo!
Down there!
Uhh.
uhh.
Yay!
whoo!
To the mystery shack!
( Shouting )
Yeah!
whoo-hoo!
yeah!
We're just in time.
But how are we
going to stop him?
( Pecking )
Aah! shoo!
Aah! Aah! Ow, ow.
Leave that to Mabel!
( Laughing, humming )
I'm comin' for ya,
Stanford-- ohh!
I'm sorry,
gummy friend!
It's for the greater good.
Ow! one of those
infernal gummy koalas
has gotten
into my perfect hair!
Ew! aw!
I can't defeat Stan
looking like this!
Unh. whoo! Ha.
Whoo-ee! ( Laughs )
Quick. get in front
and I'll re-grow you.
Okay-- wait.
You're gonna grow us back
to the equal height, right?
Dipper, that doesn't
matter right now!
Well, if it doesn't matter,
then why don't you
just do it?
Aah! why are you
acting so weird?
Why can't you just accept
that I'm a little bit
taller than you?
Oh, I'm acting weird?!
You're the one who keeps
calling me names and stuff!
Oh, what?
You mean like little--
don't say it!
Gideon:
little Dipper.
( Gasps )
aah!
I daresay you
would have defeated me,
if it wasn't
for your sibling bickering!
Aah! the shack is mine,
Stanford pines!
No!
( Gideon laughing )
Well, well, Stanford,
it appears I've finally
gotten the best of--
huh?
what?
All right,
something's definitely
different here.
Uhh!
ohh!
Whoa!
whoa!
Tell me where Stan is!
Never!
you'll never find Stan.
On the second door
to the left down the hall.
Uh, wait,
why did I say that?
Stanford,
I'm coming for ya!
( Grunting )
Pffft!
I guess I kinda soosed
that one up, didn't I?
It's not your fault,
Soos.
I'm the guy who put together
that shrinking device.
I guess it's just...
You kept teasing me,
Mabel. Like, all day.
What was that all about?
I guess it's that...
You're better than me
at like everything.
And you always rub it
in my face.
Chess, checkers,
ping pong.
I guess I finally felt
like I was winning
at something for once.
Aw, man,
now I feel like a big jerk.
Don't you mean...
A little jerk?
Ohh!
( Both laugh )
All right,
i walked into that one.
Are we cool?
We're cool.
Am I cool?
You're cool, Soos.
Yes!
( Gasps )
Stanford!
Oh, hi, Gideon!
I've been looking
for someone to try out
my new mirror maze.
Then again,
you're an idiot.
That's the end
of the sentence.
You come back here!
Try and find me, twerp.
Ha ha ha!
Unh!
Let's get that flashlight
before Gideon gets Stan.
There it is!
( Grunting )
Whoa, his hair's so shiny.
No! don't look
directly at it!
This neck is really squishy.
Hey, look!
I'm making fat angels!
Ew! termites!
Tell my story!
Ohh.
Hey, there you are!
Thought you could get away
from me, eh, corn chip?
( Munching )
Ehhhh!
oh!
Aah! uhh!
Stan: ah ha ha ha!
No!
Hey,
watch the merchandise!
( Grunting )
You little troll!
These mirrors
cost me ten--
I mean, uh, twenty--
five-- five hundred--
five hundred dollars each.
And you're paying
for all of 'em!
Au contraire,
it'll be you who pays.
Grunkle Stan is doomed!
Not completely doomed!
To his armpit!
Uh-uh.
Just...unh, c'mon!
( Grunting )
Whoa,
what is that thing?
Finally,
after all these years,
after every humiliation!
Your business, your family,
everything will finally be mine!
You have no one
to protect you now!
Prepare for
the wrath of Gideon glee...
Gideon glee..
( Laughing )
( Continues laughing )
Uh, I don't even know
how to respond to this.
Hee hee, no!
( Laughing )
stop it!
Look, uh, kid.
I think this rivalry thing
is getting to you.
Ha. I understand.
I mean,
I'm a formidable foe,
what can I say.
No--ah hahahahah!
Hey, now.
Come on.
You'll get me
one of these days.
Maybe, you know,
run your evil plan
by some friends
next time, huh?
Workshop it.
But first get your issues
in order there.
( Laughing )
Get...up, up.
Over the carpet,
there we go.
Uhh.
around the end table,
and, uh, out the door.
Whoa, whoa!
( Laughing )
My light...
You're the light
of my life, too, pal.
Whoo!
freak show.
After you.
It's okay.
You can go first
if you want-- whoa!
Hey! you let me
keep my extra millimeter.
You earned it.
Ah, thanks,
"little brother"--
stop it.
I guess we should
destroy this thing.
You know, so it doesn't
fall into the wrong hands
and junk.
Seems like the smart thing
to do.
Unh!
Die, die!
Soos:
there you dudes are!
I been tryin'
to get your attention!
Glue.
lots of glue.
Oh, son, don't you mind
that Stanford pines.
You'll get your revenge
one of these days.
No! it's not
just about revenge!
I want that shack.
The physical building.
But why?
Because it holds a secret
you couldn't possibly imagine.
( Laughs evilly )
Uh, sweetie,
you want some ice cream?
Did you pick out
all the nuts?
Mm-hmm.
Ah!
( Snorting )
( Maniacal laughter )
Lil' more?
That's good.
( Doorbell rings )
Mr. pines,
I'm from the winninghouse
coupon savers contest
and you
are our big winner!
( Birds chirping )
I guess we'll have
to give the prize
to our runner-up winner...
Fiddleford h. Mcgucket?
( Laughter )
How would you like
ten million dollars?
It's my dream come true!
Hahaha!
( Munching )
Cross this town
off our list.