Are you ready for
the ultimate challenge?
I'm always ready!
Then you know
what this means!
Both: syrup race! Ahh...
Go, sir syrup!
Go, mountie man!
Go go! Go go!
Almost...Almost...
Yes! ( coughing )
I won!
( Coughing )
bleah.
Ho ho, no way!
Hey, Mabel,
check this out.
Human-sized hamster balls?
(Gasps) I'm human-sized!
No, no, Mabel. This.
We see weirder stuff
than that every day.
We didn't get any photos
of those gnomes, did we?
Nope, just memories.
And this beard hair.
Why did you save that?
Mm-mm-mm.
Uhh! good morning,
knuckleheads.
You two know
what day it is?
Um...happy anniversary?
Mazel tov!
Baah!
It's family fun day,
genius!
We're cuttin' off work
and havin' one of those,
ya know,
(sniffing)
bonding-type deals.
Grunkle Stan, is this
gonna be anything like
our last family bonding day?
You call that Ben Franklin?
He looks like a woman!
( Siren wailing )
uh-oh!
Ohh! the county jail
was so cold.
All right, maybe I haven't been
the best summer caretaker.
But I swear, today we're gonna
have some real family fun.
Now, who wants to
put on some blindfolds
and get into my car?
Yay!
yay!
Wait. what?
В™єв™є
в™єв™є
( tuning radio)
( Tires screech )
whoa! Whoa!
Blindfolds never lead
to anything good.
Wow. I feel like
all my other senses
are heightened.
I can see
with my fingers.
( Laughing )
Oh!
oh!
Grunkle Stan, are you
wearing a blindfold?
Ha ha! Nah,
but with these cataracts,
i might as well be.
What is that,
a woodpecker?
( Kids scream )
Okay, okay,
open 'em up.
Ta-da! it's fishin' season!
Fishing?
what are you playing at,
old man?
You're gonna love it!
The whole town's out here!
Here, fishy-fishies!
Get into the pan.
Say "cheese."
Aaaah!
Uh, is this good?
No!!!
I'll show you how
a real man fishes!
Grr! aaah!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Hyeah! uhh!
All:
dead! dead!
Dead! Dead!
Get him!
That's some quality
family bonding!
Uncle Stan, why do you
want to bond with us
all of a sudden?
Come on,
this is gonna be great!
I've never had
fishin' buddies before.
The guys from the lodge
won't go with me.
They don't like
or trust me.
I think he actually wants
to fish with us.
Hey, I know what'll cheer
you sad sacks up.
Pow! pines family
fishin' hats.
That's hand-stitching,
ya know.
It's just gonna be you, me,
and those goofy hats
on a boat for ten hours!
Ten hours?!
I brought the joke book.
No. no!
There has to be
a way out of this.
Man: I seen it!
I seen it again!
( Panicky grunting )
Hoo hoo hoo!
The gravity falls
gobblewonker!
Come quick before he
scramdoodles away!
( Yipping )
ha ha hoo-ah!
Aw. he's doing
a happy jig.
No!!! it's a jig
of grave danger!
Hey! hey!
Aaah!
Now, what did I tell you
about scaring my customers?
This is your
last warning, dad.
But I got proof this time,
by gummity!
Behold!
It's gobbledywonker
what done did it!
It had a long neck
like a gee-raffe,
and wrinkly skin like--
like this gentleman
right here.
Huh?
It chopped my boat up
to smitheroons!
It shim-shammed over
to scuttlebutt island!
Ya gotta believe me!!!
Attention, all units.
We got ourselves
a crazy old man.
( All laughing )
Aw, donkey spittle!
Banjo Polish...
( Laughter continues )
Well, that happened.
Now, let's untie this boat
and get out on that lake!
Mabel, did you hear
what that old dude said?
"Aw, donkey spittle!"
The other thing--
about the monster.
If we can snag a photo of it,
we could split the prize
fifty-fifty.
That's two fifties!
Imagine what you could do
with five hundred dollars!
Not so high and mighty anymore.
Ohh.
aha-ha ha ha ha!
( Crash )
Mabel: hey, boys.
You can look...
But you can't touch.
Squeak! squeak!
Squeak! Squeak!
Squeak squeak...
Both: awesome!
Mabel. Mabel?
Dipper, I am one million percent
onboard with this!
Grunkle Stan!
Change of plans!
We're taking that boat
to scuttlebutt island,
and we are gonna find
that gobblewonker.
Both:
monster hunt!
Monster hunt!
Monster--
old man: Monster hunt!
Monster--eh--
I'll go.
( Boat horn blows )
You dudes say something
about a monster hunt?
Zeus!
what's up, hambone?
Kapoosh!
pow! explode!
Dude, you could totally
use my boat for your hunt.
It's got a steering wheel,
chairs-- normal boat stuff.
All right,
let's think this through.
You kids could go
waste your time
on some epic
monster-finding
adventure,
or you could spend the day
learning how to tie knots
and skewer worms
with your great
uncle Stan!
В™є ( techno music ) в™є
в™є ( banjo music ) в™є
в™є ( heroic music ) в™є
so, whaddya say?
( Kids cheering )
Mabel: we made
the right choice!
Ingrates!
ah, who needs 'em?
I got a whole box
of creepy fishin' lures
to keep me company.
( Flies buzzing )
Uhh!
Hoist the anchor!
Raise the flag!
Mabel: we're gonna find
that gobblewonker!
Dipper: we're gonna win
that photo contest!
Zeus: do any of you dudes
have sunscreen?
Dipper: we're gonna...
Go get sunscreen!
All: yay!
( Deep growling )
All right, if we want to
win this contest,
we've gotta do it right.
Think. what the #1 problem
with most monster hunts?
You're a side character
and you die in the first
five minutes of the movie.
Dude, am I a side character?
Do you ever think about
stuff like that?
No, no, no--
camera trouble.
Say bigfoot shows up.
Zeus, be bigfoot.
There he is! Bigfoot!
Uh-oh! no camera!
Oh, wait! Here's one!
Aw, no film!
You see what
I'm doing here?
Uh-huh.
dude's got a point.
That's why I bought
seventeen disposable cameras.
Two on my ankle,
three in my jacket,
four for each of you,
three extras in this bag,
and one under my hat.
There's no way
we're gonna miss this.
Okay, everybody,
let's test our cameras out.
Ahh! dude!
You see? This is exactly
why you need backup cameras.
We still have sixteen.
Ahh! bird!
Fifteen. okay, guys,
i repeat, don't lose
your cameras.
Wait. lose the cameras?
Don't!
Dude, I just
threw two away.
Thirteen!
All right, we still
have thirteen camera--
( crunch )
Twelve. we have
twelve cameras.
So what's the plan?
Throw more cameras overboard
or what?
No! no. Okay.
You'll be lookout,
Zeus can work
the steering wheel,
and I'll be captain.
What?!
Why do you
get to be captain?
What about Mabel, huh?
Ma-bel! ma-bel!
I'm not sure
that's a good idea.
What about co-captain?
There's no such thing
as co-captain.
Ohh. whoops!
Okay, fine!
You can be co-captain!
Can I be associate
co-captain?
As co-captain,
i authorize that request.
Well, as first co-captain,
our #1 order of business
is to lure the monster out
with this.
Permission
to taste some?
Granted.
permission co-granted.
Permission
associate go-granted.
( Grunts )
( Gagging )
( Laughing )
dude, I don't know what
i expected that to taste like.
Traitors!
I'll find my own
fishin' buddies.
( Mabel laughing )
Ah!
( Starts engine )
there's my new pals!
( Exhales )
Now that we're alone,
rosanna,
there's a burning question
which my heart longs
to ask of you.
Oh, Reginald!
Stan: Hey!
Wanna hear a joke?
Here goes.
My ex-wife still
misses me,
but her aim
is gettin' better!
Her aim is
gettin' better!
Ya see, it's--
it's funny because
marriage is terrible.
What?!
Hey, how's it going?
It's going awesome.
В™є bow bow, ba-bow bow в™є
Mabel,
leave that thing alone.
Aw, I don't mind none!
Hey, look,
I'm drinking water!
В™є grinkle, grinkle,
little-- в™є
( coughing,
choking )
Aren't you supposed
to be doing lookout?
Look out!
Ha ha!
But seriously,
I'm on it.
( Crash )
whoa!
Whoa!
See? we're here.
I'm a lookout genius!
Hamster ball,
here we come!
( Owl hooting)
Dude, check it out.
Butt island.
Zeus, you
rapscallion!
Hey, why aren't you laughing?
Are you scared?
Yeah, right. I'm not--
yeah, you are!
Hey--
quit it--
stop, Mabel!
Uhh! Uhh!
( Blubbering )
( Loud growling )
( Both gasp )
Dude, did you guys
hear that?
What was that?
Was it your stomach?
No, my stomach
normally sounds
like whale noises.
( Whale calls )
Wow! so majestic!
( Gasps )
Our lantern!
Ahh! I can't see anything!
Dude, I don't know, man,
maybe this isn't worth it.
Not worth it?
Guys, imagine
what would happen
if we got that picture!
Tonight, we're here
with adventure-seeker
Dipper pines
who bravely photographed
the elusive gobblewonker.
Tell me, Dipper,
what's the secret
to your success?
Well, I run away from nothing...
Nothing except for
when I ran away from
my annoying grunkle Stan
who I ditched in order
to pursue that lake monster.
How right you were to do so.
He looked like a real
piece of work.
I don't often do this,
but I feel the need to
give you an award.
( Crash )
Charlie!
( Panting )
Why won't you interview me?!
( All screaming )
I'm in!
Me too!
( Panting )
All right, dudes,
I'm comin!
( Zeus making beat-box sounds )
( Rapping )
в™є my name is mable,
it rhymes with "table" в™є
в™є it also rhymes
with "glable" в™є
with "schmable" в™є
dude, we should be
writing this down.
Guys! guys, guys.
You hear something?
( Deep growling )
( Birds cawing )
(Gasps)
this is it.
This is it!
Uh. uh...
This is cooooool!
Oh!
Everyone...
get your cameras ready.
( Camera powers up )
Ready? go!
Whaaaaa!
Aaaaaah!
But-- but what was
that noise, then?
I heard a monster noise.
( Growling )
( Growling continues )
Sweet! beaver with a chainsaw!
Maybe that old guy
was crazy after all.
He did use
the word "scrapdoodle."
( Growling continues )
( Sighs )
Look, when you're
threading the line--
a lot of people
don't know this--
but you want to use
a barrel knot.
That's a secret
from one fishin' buddy
to another.
Heh heh!
Uh...
I, uh--
who are you, exactly?
Just call me
your grunkle Stan!
Woman: sir-- sir!
Why are you talking
to our son?!
If you don't leave right now,
I'm calling the police!
Ha ha! Ya see,
the thing about that is--
arrrr!
go bother
your own kids!
Zeus: ooh, yeah,
work it, work it!
Nice! Nice!
Give me
another one of those.
Yeah, I like that one.
What are we gonna say
to grunkle Stan?
We ditched him
over nothing.
( Sighs )
( Low booming sound )
Hey. guys,
do you feel that?
Wha--
hey, hey!
Whoa, whoa!
Aaah!
This is it!
Come on,
this is our chance!
What's wrong
with you guys?
Dipper...
dude...
It's not that hard,
all right?
All you gotta do
is point and shoot.
Like this.
( Roaring )
Run!
Get back to the boat!
Hurry!!!
Aaah! ooh!
The picture!
Dude, if it makes you
feel any better,
I got tons of pictures
of those beavers, dude!
Why would that make me
feel better?!
Let's get out of here,
dudes!
All right,
this is it!
Cracked lens?!
Zeus, get a photo!
Hyuh! nyeah! Nyeah!
Unhh!
what are you doing?!
I still got one left.
Don't worry, dude. Here.
Aaah!
( Roaring )
Whoa!
aaah!
Go go go go go!
( Roaring )
Grr! gaa!
Mollycoddling--
boy: can you please tell me
more funny stories, pop-pop?
Anything for
my fishin' buddies!
Ho ho ho ho!
Arghh!
Pop-pop, I just weawized
that...I wuv you.
Aw, come on!
Boo! Boo!
Hey, there!
What's the big idea?
Maybe has no one
who wuvs him, pop-pop.
Yeah, well, i-i--
nahh!
Ahhh.
Zeus! beavers!
Aaaaah!!!
Ohh! beavers--
( Shouting )
Aaah! oooooh...
Aaaah!
Ow ow ow ow ow ow ow
ow ow ow ow ow ow ow!
( Beaver shrieks )
Headlock!
dead! dead! Dead!
( Gasping )
The fishes?!
They seek revenge!
Swim, boys, swim!!!
( Beaver chattering )
aaah! Look out!
Easy, easy...
My glass!
Where do I go?!
( Grunting )
Um-- uh--
go to the falls!
I think there might be
a cave behind there!
"Might" be?!
( All scream )
Brr. ahh.
Ooh.
Ahhh.
( All scream )
( Roaring )
It's stuck!
Ha ha! Yeah!
Wait. it's stuck?
( Gasping )
Boop.
ha ha ha!
( Dipper laughing )
Did you get
a good one?
They're all good ones!
Whoo-hoo!
hamster ball!
( Electrical crackling )
What the--?
Huh?
Uh!
Mabel: what's wrong?
( Metallic clanking )
hmm.
Zeus:
careful, dude!
I've got this! Hold on!
Hey, guys!
Come check this out!
( All coughing )
Work them bellows
in the-- huh?!
Aw, banjo Polish!
Wha-- you?
You made this?
Wha--why?
Well, i--
I, uh...
I just wanted attention!
I still don't understand.
Well, first I just
hootenannied up
a bio-mechanical
brain wave generator,
and then I learned to operate
a stick shift with my beard.
Okay, yeah,
but why did you do it?
Well, when you get to be
an old fella like me,
nobody pays any attention
to you anymore.
My own son hasn't
visited me in months!
So I figured maybe
I'd catch his fancy
with a 15-ton
aquatic robot.
Wha-ha-ha-ha!
aha-ha-ha!
Aha-ha! aha-ha--
ahh...
In retrospect,
it seems a bit contrived.
You just don't know the lengths
us old-timers go through
for a little quality time
with our family.
( Both sigh )
Zeus: Dude.
I guess
the real lake monster
is you two. Heh heh.
Sorry, it just, like, boom,
just popped into my head here.
So...did you ever
talk to your son about
how you felt?
No, sir, I got to work
straight on the robot.
I made lots of robots
in my day.
Like when my wife left me
and I created a homicidal
pterodactyl-tron,
or when my pal Ernie didn't come
to my retirement party
and I constructed
an 80-ton shame-bot
that exploded
the entire downtown area!
Aha-ha-ha-ha!
Aha-- well, time to get back
to work on my death ray!
( Jackhammer, sawing,
drilling )
Any you kids
got a screwdriver?
Well, so much for
the photo contest.
We still have
one roll of film left.
What do you want
to do with it?
Ahh.
Dipper:
hey! over here!
What the-- kids?
I thought you two were off
playin' spin the bottle
with Zeus.
Well, we spent all day trying
to find a legendary dinosaur.
But we realized
the only dinosaur
we want to hang out with
is right here.
Save your sympathy!
I been having a great time
without ya--
makin' friends,
talkin' to my reflection--
I had a run-in with
the lake police!
Guess I gotta wear
this ankle bracelet now,
so that'll be fun.
So I guess there
isn't room in that boat
for three more?
You knuckleheads
ever seen me thread a hook
with my eyes closed?
Five bucks says
you can't do it.
You're on!
Five more bucks
says you can't do it
with your eyes closed
plus me singing at
the top of my lungs!
I like those odds!
Whoa! what happened
to your shirt?
Long story, dude.
All right.
Everybody get together,
say "fishing."
Fishing!
fishing!
Dude,
am I in the frame?
Whaa!
What was that?
Mm-mm.
Who wants to hear a joke?
Dipper: Not me.
Huh huh! Yeah, you do!
Here it goes.
Why did the pelican
get kicked out
the restaurant?
I don't care.
Because he had
a very big bill!
В™є la la la la в™є
yuk yuk yuk!
Ooh. Boo.
Blah blah bluh.
Bad joke. Bad pelican joke.