I'm gonna say b-five.
Miss!
Wop!
I don't think you're
playing this right.
Stan:
kids! come quick!
( Chuckling )
I need you to laugh
at this with me!
В™є who's cute as a button,
and always your friend? В™є
в™є 'lil g-i-d to the e-o-n! В™є
wink!
Announcer: lil' Gideon.
Ugh, Gideon.
Remember when
i wouldn't date him,
and he tried
to destroy us?
He's always trying to trick me
into losing the mystery shack!
One time, I caught him
stealing my moisturizer.
And yet, our mutual hatred
for him bonds us together.
( Laughing )
Announcer:
come on down to
'lil Gideon's tent
of telepathy.
Opening soon at this location.
Uh, should we be
worried about that?
Please. the only way
Gideon's taking over this shack
is by breaking in
and stealing my deed.
( Crashing, breaking glass )
You mean like right now?
Uh, thirty-eight?
Forty-one?
oh, heavens to Betsy!
Gideon!
Well, well,
Stanford!
My arch Nemesis.
We seem to have entered
a dangerous game
of cat and mouse.
But the question remains,
who is the cat,
and who is the--
Soos, broom.
Oh, no,
not the broom!
( Grunting )
( Hisses )
( Squealing )
You Mark my words,
Stanford!
One day I'm gonna get
that combination!
And once I steal that deed
you'll never see
the mystery shack again!
Good luck, bucko!
Ha! the combo to this safe
is in the one place
he'll never find it, my brain!
Your brain isn't as safe as you
might think, Stanford pines!
This is the last straw.
It's time to unlock
the journal's greatest secret.
В™єв™є
announcer:
he put the "old" in old west.
They call him...
В™є grandpa the kid! В™є
I'm tired during the day.
I can relate to this.
Grunkle Stan,
why can't we watch a movie
that we'll all enjoy?
Dream boy high!
Where love is on
your permanent record.
All: boo!
You'll learn
to like it.
( Clanging, yelling )
Dudes!
there's a bat in the kitchen!
It tried to touch me with
its weird little bat fingers.
Don't worry,
i got this under control.
Dipper, take care of it.
( Chuckles )
yes!
What?
why can't Mabel do it?
'Cause life ain't fair.
Now go fight a bat
so we can watch TV.
No way,
grunkle Stan.
You always make me
do dumb chores.
I'm putting my foot
down this time.
I said, do it, kid!
Now!
( Growls )
( Both continue growling )
Okay, I'll do it!
( Sighs )
Stupid chores.
Remember, bats are more afraid
of you than you are of them.
Maybe I'm thinking of ducklings.
( Dipper screaming )
Ducklings.
( chuckles )
quack, quack.
Quack, quack, quack.
Dipper:
ow, ow!
В™є swabbin' on
disinfectant в™є
в™є doo-do-doo в™є
( sighs ) why does grunkle Stan
always pick on me?
Think about it, the more painful
or difficult the chore is,
the more likely it is
I'll have to do it.
Why doesn't he pick on you guys?
Dipper, Stan's personality is
one of life's great mysteries.
Like whether or not it's
possible to lick your own elbow.
I bet you can't.
I bet I can.
( Chanting )
lick it!
Lick it!
Sometimes I feel
like Stan hates me.
Stan: the sink's clogged!
Dipper, get in here and fix it!
( Growls )
You think that combination's
safe in your mind, Stanford?
We'll see what my new Minion
has to say about that.
"Triangulum. entangulum.
"Veneforis Dominus ventium.
Veneforis venetisarium!"
( Chanting )
lick that elbow!
Lick that elbow!
Like the infinite horizon,
it eludes my grasp.
( Evil laughter
in the distance )
Is that who
i think it is?
( Gideon grunting )
( Indistinct chanting )
( Thunder )
( Chanting continues )
( Croaks )
( Evil laughing )
Oh! oh! Gravity falls,
it is good to be back!
Name's bill cipher.
And I take it you're some kind
of living ventriloquist dummy?
( Laughs ) I'm just kidding,
I know who you are, Gideon.
What-- what are you?
H-- how do you know my name?
Oh, I know lot of things.
( Distorted voice )
lots of things.
( Normal voice )
hey, look what I can do.
Deer teeth, for you, kid!
( Laughs )
( Gasps )
you're insane!
Sure, I am!
What's your point?
( Grunting )
Listen to me, demon!
I have a job for you!
I need you to enter
the mind of Stanford pines
and steal the code to his safe!
( Soos gasps )
( Laughs )
wait.
Stan pines.
You know what, kid,
you've convinced me.
I'm sold!
I'll help you with this,
and in return,
you can help me
with something I've
been working on.
We'll work out
the details later.
Deal.
Well, time to invade
Stan's mind.
This should be fun!
Remember,
reality is an illusion,
the universe is a hologram,
buy gold!
Bye!
( Gasps )
( Both gasp )
It worked!
( Evil cackling )
( Snoring )
( Muttering )
no. Sorry.
What is going on
in that guy's head?
( Panting ) Dipper!
We've gotta help Stan!
Wait, what?
( Chewing )
this evil triangle guy
said he's gonna
break into Stan's mind,
and steal the combination
to his safe!
Also, we stopped for
snacks on the way here.
Triangle guy?
I feel like I've seen something
like this before in the journal.
Dipper: "beware bill.
"The most powerful
and dangerous creature
"I've ever encountered.
Whatever you do,
never let him into your mind."
( Grunts )
( Gasps )
grunkle Stan!
( Grunting and yelling )
"It is possible
to follow the demon
"into a person's mind
and prevent his chaos.
One must simply recite
this incantation."
( Sighs )
this is just great.
I spend all day cleaning sinks
and fighting bats for Stan,
and now I have to save him
from some crazy brain demon?
But if we don't do anything,
Gideon might steal
the shack, or worse!
( Yelling )
( Sighs )
fine.
Get ready, guys.
We're about to journey
into the most horrifying,
disturbing place
any of us have ever been.
Our uncle's mind.
( Thunder )
You think I can take
these burrito bites
into Stan's brain?
Thumbs up, thumbs down?
You know what?
I'm just gonna bring them.
( Stan snoring )
okay, guys.
In order to save our uncle,
we're going to have to follow
that dream demon into his mind.
I wonder what Stan's
thinking about right now.
( High-pitched voice )
i love Soos like a son.
Soos!
this is serious!
( High-pitched voice )
sowee.
( Soos and Mabel laughing )
Both: yeah!
Let's do this!
( Snoring )
"Fidentus omnium.
"Magis omentium.
"Magnesuim adharminum.
"Magnum opus.
"Habeas corpus.
"Insectus nominus overratus.
"Magis tremensium.
Magis tremensium.
Magis tremensium!"
Oh, wow!
Whoa!
Oh, what the--
whoa!
this is Stan's mind?
Huh. figured there would
be a lot more hot old ladies.
Mabel: remember, everyone,
we've got to look out
for the triangle guy.
Yeah, look out for
the triangle guy!
It's him!
It's the guy!
You leave our
uncle's brain alone,
you isosceles monster!
( Yelling )
Gotcha!
Wait. what?
Ah, Stan's family,
we meet at last.
Question Mark,
shooting star, pine tree,
I had a hunch
i might bump into you.
( Screams )
( Panting )
Mabel: boop!
(Soos and Mabel laugh )
Mabel!
What do you want with
our uncle's mind anyway?
Oh, just the code
to the old man's safe!
Inside the shack is
a maze of a thousand doors
representing
your uncle's memories.
Behind one of them is a memory
of him inputting the code.
I just need to find it
and Gideon will
pay me handsomely!
Not if we stop you!
Ha!
fat chance!
I'm the master of the mind.
I even know what
you're thinking right now.
That's impossible!
No one can guess
what I'm thinking!
Whoa!
where are we, bro?
We must be in heaven,
'cause I just saw an angel.
I'm never letting go
of your leg!
You're out of your league, kids.
Turn around now, before you
see something you might regret.
Later, suckers!
We're going in.
Mabel, can we leave
those guys out here?
Looking at them hurts my eyes.
No!
they can help us!
Xyler and craz:
Totally! Arm throne!
( Mabel giggles )
( Sighs )
dude, arm throne!
Arm throne!
Ah!
Xyler and craz: Whoa!
Mabel: Neato!
Craz: radical!
Xyler:
I also think it's radical!
Stan: no refunds!
No refunds!
( Echoing ) no refunds!
( Growling )
( Stan speaking indistinctly )
Soos: whoa, look!
All of Stan's memories.
Great, sure there's
plenty of memories
of Stan bossing me around.
Can't wait to see more of that!
Come on, Dipper.
We've gotta find the code
before bill does.
Mabel is talking!
So rad!
Let's get searching!
( Panting )
Jorge, rico,
you're the two best
Colombian prison friends
a fella could make.
Nope.
Sir, would you like
to buy a Stan vac vacuum?
Stan vac: It sucks more
than anything.
Gotta work on that.
Nope.
Whoa!
it's Stan on a date!
So, your, uh,
your eye is weird.
Let's, let's talk
about that.
( Laughing )
( Both laughing )
This is going terrible.
I can't think
of anything to say,
and she looks weird up close.
Think of a way out.
Non-specific excuse!
( Grunts, panting )
Yeesh!
Look, guys.
Memories about me.
That doesn't seem
like a good idea.
I just want to know
what the old guy
really thinks of me.
We already know how
Stan feels about us,
he loves us!
We're great.
Yeah, let's
just keep moving.
More moving?
Yes!
I love motion!
Okay, just a quick peek.
Stan: Dipper, my back itches,
can you scratch it?
Dipper, clean the boiler!
( Stan laughs )
No buts!
Now go chop that
firewood already!
Ah!
Dude, Stan, I been
meaning to ask you.
Why are you so hard on
Dipper all the time?
Look, Soos, I'm gonna
let you in on something.
You wanna know what
i really think?
( Indistinct whispering )
The kid's a loser.
He's weak.
He's an utter embarrassment.
I just want to get rid of him.
Hello, code to Stan's safe,
where are you?
Opening and closing
doors is fun.
I can do it also!
If only people knew the truth.
That hidden behind
this vending machine,
I secretly have a--
boring!
All right, guys,
I have a good feeling
about this door.
Hey, Mr. tummy.
( High-pitched voice )
hey, Mr. Stan!
( Normal ) are you hungry?
( High-pitched voice ) yes.
( Normal ) eat your crackers!
Soos: Ugh!
( High-pitched voice
chomping and giggling )
Sweet Sally.
Oh, we've been
searching forever.
What if the triangle guy
finds the memory before we do?
If we wanna find Stan's memory,
we gotta think like Stan.
He's always hiding stuff, right?
Yeah, like how he hides
his arrest warrants
under that rug in the gift shop?
Soos, that's it!
Look!
( All gasp )
There ya go.
And now to input the code.
Thirteen, forty-four,
and finally--
dude, we found it!
Yeah!
Guys: but what
do we do now?
Jinx!
Um, um, let's just
destroy the door
before bill can find it.
Wait!
maybe I should do it!
My big fat arms are great
at destroying stuff.
Oh, okay.
Hey, guys!
I just saw
a memory of Stan
roller skating
and wearing short-shorts!
Didn't look--didn't look
half bad.
Hey, something weird
is going on here.
( Laughs )
( All gasp )
Boy, you kids sure are gullible!
I knew you'd lead me
straight to the code!
( Evil laughing )
It's funny how dumb you are.
The combination to Stan's safe!
Boy, that was even easier
than I thought.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you're a...
A stink-face!
Awesome comeback, Mabel!
Don't treat me
like a child, xyler.
Later, suckers!
( All yell )
Come on, we've got to save Stan!
Dipper:
what's the point?
Why should I save him, huh?
I work for Stan day and night,
and all he does in return is
say he wants to get rid of me.
Dipper, I'm sure
that's not true.
I saw it with my own eyes
in one of his memories, Mabel!
He's always picked on me
and now I know why!
Stan hates me!
( All gasp )
Dipper, it doesn't
matter what you saw.
If we don't stop bill,
we'll lose the shack!
No, you know what?
Not this time.
For once, this is one of Stan's
problems I'm not gonna fix.
Fine!
come on, Soos.
We'll save Stan ourselves!
Dipper, you're a cool dude,
but this isn't cool, dude.
Craz:
let's go, xyler!
Xyler:
all right, craz!
Those are our names!
( Phone ringing )
Yello?
bill!
Did you find the memory
with the combination yet?
Relax, shortstack,
i got it right here.
( Laughs )
perfect!
Now give it to me
and I'll fulfill
my end of the bargain.
Finally! it's--
you got a pen there?
It's thirteen, forty-four--
ah! no, no, wait!
No!
Stan: none more bottomless
than the bottomless pit.
Which, as you can see here,
is bottomless.
Whoo! whatever that was,
it's gone forever.
Ha ha! Boom!
Xyler and craz:
Mabel did it!
The shack is safe!
The deal's off!
Wait. no! Wait!
I'm switching to plan b!
You!
You can't even imagine
what you just cost me!
Do you have
any idea what I'm like
( distorted )
when I'm mad?
( Mabel gasps )
Soos: so I guess he gets
really mad when he gets mad.
Eat nightmares!
( Screaming )
( Grunts ) how do i
get out of this place?
Exit? hello?
Ah, this again?
Stan: he's a loser.
He's weak.
I just want to
get rid of him.
( Chuckles )
Yeah, those are all
things people said
about me when I was a boy.
Huh?
It was terrible.
I was the biggest wimp
on the playground.
( Whimpers )
( Laughing )
( Crying )
Stan: so one summer my pop
signs me up for boxing lessons.
And it was even worse
than the schoolyard!
Left hook!
You know, at the time, I thought
my pop was trying to torture me.
But wouldn't you know it?
The old man was doin' me
a favor all along.
Give me that bag!
Help!
my purse!
Woman: help!
Left hook!
Ah!
( Cheering )
So you see?
That's why I'm
hard on Dipper.
To toughen him up,
so when the world fights,
he fights back.
Do you think it's
actually working?
I, I did it!
Yes!
He's really comin' along.
When push comes to shove,
I'm actually proud of him.
Just don't ever tell him that.
His head's big enough as it is.
Soos: that's true.
Whoa, kid, what are
you doin' here?
Nice hole in your chest,
by the way.
Let's fix that up.
W-- what the--
how did you do that?
Word to the wise, kid,
we're in the mind.
You could do whatever
you can imagine in here.
Well, how about that.
( Bill laughing )
Soos: No! Make it stop!
Mabel: help!
Someone, please!
Oh, my gosh, what am I doing?
I gotta stop bill!
Huh.
fightin' back.
One nightmare, coming up!
Nightmare?
Hope he doesn't mean
that British dog-man
I'm always dreaming about.
( British accent )
'ello, 'ello, 'ello!
Who's crike for
a shdig in the pudding?
Ah! it's everything
i ever feared!
You!
Ahh! my cuteness!
( Distorted )
what did you do to my cuteness--
( spitting )
You're next!
Cool, we're next!
( Pop music plays )
( Both scream )
( Distorted )
my dream boys!
And now to finish you off,
for once and for all!
No!
no!
Dude, no!
Hey, bill!
What!
Nice bowtie!
Ahh!
( Distorted )
Dipper!
Dude!
Guys! I just learned
that you can conjure
whatever you can conceive
in grunkle Stan's mindscape!
Huh?
Just think of cool fighting
stuff and it'll happen!
Like this.
( Chuckles )
he's dead now.
What?
who told you that?
Don't listen to him!
We can do anything?
( Normal voice )
like have kittens for fists?
( Grunts )
Pow, pow!
Pow, pow, pow! Pow!
( Meowing )
Ahh!
( Giggling )
well, hello, friends!
Anything, huh?
Soos loves stomach beam stare!
( Screams )
( Growls )
Enough games!
Hamster ball shields, activate!
Dipper and Soos: Activate!
Ah, my eye!
Ahh!
Rise, xyler!
Rise, craz!
( Synthesized pop music plays )
No!
synthesized music!
It hurts!
And now to imagine
your worst nightmare!
A portal out of Stan's mind!
Mabel: в™є out of Stan's mind! В™є
Mabel!
everyone!
Together!
( All grunting )
No, no, no!
Enough!
You know, I'm impressed
with you guys.
You're a lot more
clever than you look.
Especially the fat one.
He's talking about you.
So I'm gonna let you
kids off the hook.
You might come in handy later.
( Distorted voice )
but know this.
( Normal voice )
a darkness approaches,
a day will come in the future
when everything you
care about will change.
Until then,
I'll be watching you.
He's gone,
we did it!
( All cheering )
Wha--
Stan must be waking up.
Will I ever see you
guys again?
In your dreams.
Good one, bro.
Good one.
( All yell )
We did it!
What?
did what?
What are you all doing here?
And why was I dreaming
of two brightly colored
and radical young men?
Grunkle Stan!
You're okay!
What is this, a hug?
Nope.
It's a choke hold.
( Chuckles )
Not bad, kid.
Not bad.
I'm just glad Gideon
didn't get into the safe.
I really love this old shack.
Group hug!
No?
I never know the right time!
( Rumbling )
hey, do you guys feel a--
oh, I'm sorry, pines family,
did I wake you?
But we defeated bill.
Bill failed me!
So I switched to plan b.
Dynamite.
What? bill?
Who-- wh-- what
are you guys talking about?
Spoiler alert, Stanford.
I've got the deed!
The mystery shack belongs to me!
So, get off my property!
Daddy?
Bring it around the front.
Don't worry, guys.
It's just part of the dream.
We're going to wake up
any second now.
Right? right?
( Laughing )
( All gasp )
Someone, pinch me, dude.