In this land of ours,
there are many great pits,
but none more bottomless
than the bottomless pit,
which as you can see here,
is bottomless.
Question. is it bottomless?
( Sighs ) kids, could one of you
try explaining this to Soos?
Grunkle Stan,
why are we here again?
To dispose of things
that we don't want.
So long, mystery shack
suggestion cards.
Goodbye, creepy love letters
from lil' Gideon.
( Grunts)
die! die!
( Grunting )
What are you doing?
Throwing stuff, dude.
Everyone's doing it!
( Grunting )
what you got there, Mabel?
( Chuckles )
it's just my personal box
of mysterious secrets.
Nothing worth wondering about!
( Laughs, grunts )
Goodbye forever!
Grunkle Stan, do I really
have to be the one to point out
that a bottomless pit is,
by definition, impossible?
Says you!
Well, I guess
we'll never know.
Aah! it's some sort
of invisible pushing force!
Quick! everyone
back to the shack!
I'm not done getting rid
of these yet!
Ahh!
Grunkle Stan! No!
Almost... almost... almost...
( All screaming )
( Bleats )
( Theme music playing )
( All screaming )
( Screaming stops,
wind blowing )
So, anyone wanna
scream some more?
Where are we?
We're somewhere where
it looks like we're nowhere.
( Laughing )
We're gonna land on
something eventually.
Could be any second now!
Well, it looks like we're
down here for the long haul.
Who wants to see
some card tricks?
Ta-da!
Hey! maybe we should pass
the time by tellin' stories.
I've got a story! It's called:
"The time grunkle Stan
got us all thrown
into a bottomless pit,
where we spent the rest
of our natural lives!"
Go on.
Come on, Dipper,
you can do better than that.
Fine. I'll tell you a story,
a story I'd like to call:
Ready?
All: spin the pig!
Whoo!
Hey, grunkle Stan,
ever kissed a pig before?
I'm not gonna answer
that question.
Guys! guys! I think
i just got bit by a snake!
I need you to get me
to a hospital quick!
( Laughing )
What? what's so funny?
Uh, sorry, it's just hard
to focus on what you're saying
with that squeaky
puberty voice you got there.
My what?
It's nothing to be
ashamed of, Dipper.
Your voice is hilarious.
Are you saying
my voice cracks?
My voice doesn't crack.
Dude, no offense,
but it cracks so much
we've already made
a techno remix out of it.
( Dipper on recording )
nice to meet you.
My name's Dipper pines.
( Distorted )
p-p-pines, pines, pines.
Do I really sound like that?
Oh! here comes
my favorite part!
Stop it, guys!
( Laughing )
Gimme that!
( Grunting )
All: spin the pig!
( Sighs, voice cracks )
Ugh! even my sighs sound weird.
Hello there!
Aah!
I couldn't help
but overhear
yer sitchy-ation!
Old man mcgucket!
( Spits )
part-time inventor!
Why did you spit
on your hand?
I don't rightly know!
Hey, I remember you!
Your robot almost killed me!
Come here! Follow
me into this dark,
dangerous alley!
Lately I been a-tinkerizin'
with a voice altering tonic,
on account
of my horrifyin' voice!
( Cries )
You can run,
but I'll still be
in yer nightmares!
This will really
fix my voice?
Thanks!
( gulping )
ah!
Come mornin',
you'll sound like a new man!
If you survive.
( Rooster crowing )
( Yawns )
( In deep voice )
good morning, Dipper.
I did it! I did it!
Now I have a new voice!
( Hearty laugh )
'Morning, Mabel.
Who's my favorite Mabel?
Ahh!
Who are you?
Ohh! Ohh! Ohh! Ohh!
What have you done
with my brother?
Dipper!
I'll save you from this
body-switching warlock!
Mabel, it's me!
This is my voice now.
I sound awesome.
Sound awesome.
I knew boys' voices changed,
but this is weird.
Weird and bad.
Mabel, this is the best thing
that ever happened to me.
And just think
of the prank calls.
Hello?
Hello. this is the president of
the United States of America.
I'm calling to tell you...
( Blowing raspberries )
(Through telephone)
What? Who is this?
(In deep voice) Ho-ho-ho!
Magnificent!
Mabel no like.
How you diddly doing, Soos?
Kill it!
Oh!
Kill it with fire!
Everyone flee!
Ahh!
What gives, man?
You guys all made fun
of my old voice.
I thought you'd
like the new one.
Dude, at least before
you sounded like a real person.
Now you sound like some kind
of weird commercial dude.
I'll find Stan.
He'll like my new voice.
You'll see!
I'll be right back
after these messages.
I, uh, I mean, goodbye.
Grunkle Stan. Grunkle Stan!
Where are you, grunkle Stan?
Huh? I'd know
that voice anywhere!
You're the guy who
prank called me earlier!
( Growls )
No. no, I'm not.
I'm just a 12-year-old boy!
You expect me to believe that,
you crazy-voiced punk?
W-wait! no! Aiyee!
There's a prank caller
on the loose! Let's get him!
Yeah! come on!
Come on, let's get him!
Oh! oh! Oh!
( Grunting )
Huh!
whoa!
Escape!
( Laughing )
Mcgucket! your invention
was a catastrophe!
That's probably why
i live in the dump!
My own sister
didn't recognize me.
I scared away crowds!
I even sound ridiculous
when I ( crying ) cry.
Well, now,
here's yer problem!
I gave you the wrong
drinky-majig!
This one's for
voiceover professional.
Ah! I'm sure I've got a better
voice in here somewhere.
Good! hurry up.
You got here just in time.
Come sundown, you'd have
reverted back to your
ridiculous old voice.
It was ridiculous,
wasn't it?
( Dipper on walkman )
d-d-d-d-Dipper pines,
that's me!
Mabel: this remix
is dedicated to my brother.
Dipper, your voice
is one of a kind.
Soos: dude, I never
heard anything like it.
R-r-remix over!
( Imitates sound
of an explosion )
You ready for yer new voice?
This one should be permanent!
( Clears throat )
( Inhales deeply )
( Normal voice )
hey, guys.
Dipper!
oh, dude, you're back!
( Chuckling )
Yeah. I guess I realized
that even though my voice
might not be perfect,
it's still mine,
and I wouldn't change
it for anything,
not even for whatever
was in this new vial.
So what did you do
with the rest of that potion?
I dumped it in Stan's coffee.
( High-pitched voice )
any of you kids seen my girdle?
Where my girdle at?
( All laughing )
What? what's so funny?
I'm grunkle Stan!
Kids laughin'.
Laughin' at their grunkle.
I spy, with my little eye,
something that is... black!
Ooh! ooh! Everything.
Yay for Soos!
Stan: yay for Soos!
Hey, guys, who wants
to pass the time by spinning?
Everyone spin!
No.
whee!
Ahh!
( Chuckles )
Whee! ( laughing )
Ow! ow! Ow! Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Dipper's pain is funny,
but I'm starting to get bored.
Soos, tell a story.
Really? okay.
This story is called "Soos's
really great pinball story."
( Dipper screaming )
Is that a good title?
Do they have to be, like,
puns or whatever?
( Gunshots, neighing )
Go! go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
This is it, dudes.
After four long
years of trying,
I might finally
get the high score
on Stan's creepy old
pinball machine.
If I do this,
I'll go down
in pinball history
with the likes of
sal, gaff,
and of course poo.
Have you ever tried maybe
just tilting the machine?
I don't know, dudes.
Isn't breaking the rules,
like, against the rules?
Nuts to the rules!
Tilt! Tilt! Tilt!
( Gunshot, neighing )
Failure. you stink!
All right, that's it.
Ready, kids?
Both: tilt! Tilt! Tilt! Tilt!
Tilt! Tilt! Tilt! Tilt!
Quit tiltin', pardner.
Tilt!
Bull's-eye!
( Gunshots )
New high score!
Yay!
whoo-hoo!
Oh, yes!
All right!
This is the best moment
of my life.
This totally beats
my old best moment.
Aah.
That ain't right. You cheated.
Oh, yeah? What are
you gonna do about it?
You're just a pinball game,
pinball game.
Taunt, taunt.
Uh, guys? There's an awful
lot of green lightning
coming out of that game.
No, that's the normal
amount of green lightning.
( All screaming )
( Bells ringing )
Ugh. five more minutes.
( Ringing continues )
Aah! that's not
a normal alarm clock.
Soos!
we're inside the game!
Crazy.
sweet Moses!
Hushed exclamation of wonder.
( Gasps )
( All chuckling )
Awesome!
Boing! boing! Boing!
( Laughing )
Dude, if this is a dream,
i never wanna wake up!
That can be arranged.
Welcome to tumbleweed terror,
pardners!
( Gunshots )
Hey,
it's the skeleton cowboy guy.
Did you zap me into your game
to congratulate me
on getting the high score?
I beat poo, dude.
Hardly. if'n I do recall,
i warned y'all not to cheat.
I tried to be gentleman-like,
but I'm plum sick
of being tilted.
( Clanging )
So now I reckon
I'm gonna tilt you.
Oh, yeah?
Well-- well, take this!
Ow! and this! Ow! It hurts!
I wish this was working better!
Oh, dude!
Both: Soos!
( Laughing )
get yourselves ready for the...
( Neighing )
All in succession:
Multi-ball!
( Cowboy skeleton laughing )
All: ahh!
Over there!
( Panting, gasping )
Where are you?
I'm not done teachin' you
a lesson about cheating yet!
How are we ever gonna
get out of here?
Think, guys!
I'm trying, but it's
hard with that gorgeous
pinball wench distracting me.
( Chuckling )
Okay, don't worry, guys.
I know every inch
of this machine.
( Whispering ) there's
a manual power switch inside.
I can sneak in there
and turn off the game,
but we'll have to distract
the cowboy guy.
Are either of you
good at jumping up and down
and making annoying noises?
My time has come.
All right, let's go, Soos.
Soos?
So are you, like,
doing anything later or--
right.
Come on out
and show yourselves, varmints!
Hey! hey! Hey!
Listen to me and look
at what I'm doing!
( Sputtering )
( Blowing raspberries )
Somethin' ain't right here.
Distraction!
distraction!
( humming )
Let me see where this is goin'.
La, la, la,
la, la, la...
( Humming )
( Grunting )
Oof! ( gasps )
( Laughing ) yippe-ti-yi--
what? Where are ya?
( Grunting )
durn it, I wish I had a neck!
Soos! psst!
What's going on?
Just press
the switch already!
Okay, so I was gonna do that,
but I've been thinking.
According to this,
turning off the power erases
the high score permanently.
That score is, like,
my one big life accomplishment.
What? if you don't hurry up
we could die in here!
Fair point.
But, what is life anyway,
when compared to the immortality
of a high score?
Soos! are you out of your--
there y'all are.
Get ready to meet yer maker,
kids!
My maker is ballway games
in redmond, Washington.
( Grunting, yelling )
( Both screaming )
Mabel!
Dipper: Soos!
Mabel: Soos, please!
Turn it off!
Uh...
Ahh!
Goodbye, high score!
( Grunts )
( Beeping )
( Gasps )
Aah!
Oh, you dudes okay?
Yeah, Soos.
You did it!
You freed us!
Hey, man, I'm sorry
you had to lose
your high score.
That's okay. I got
a new life accomplishment now:
Saving you dudes.
Aw!
aw!
You think that pinball wench
will call me?
I can't believe this nonsense!
Magic tonics?
Soos winning at something?
Where do you come up
with this stuff?
I'll tell you a good story.
It's called "grunkle Stan
wins the football bowl."
( Grunts, laughs )
Mr. pines.
I thought old folks
were useless,
but you taught me and my
gloating friends a lesson.
Woman: here's your football
winning trophy, Mr. pines!
Thanks, beautiful woman,
but I couldn't have done it
without my sidekick,
foot-bot.
Thank you for
building me, daddy.
( All laughing )
Foot-bot:
i love you, Stan.
( Overlapping jeers )
What? that story was great.
I even threw in
a talking robot
for the kids.
Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna
tell a non-terrible story,
a story called...
This attraction is
gonna make me a fortune!
Easy with that bear,
corduroy!
I need him in
showroom condition!
( Roaring )
no! No!
Aw!
they're hugging!
So let me get this straight.
Your plan is to teach
this bear to ride a bicycle?
Nah, come on.
Everyone's seen
a bicycle-riding bear.
No, no. I'm gonna
teach this bear...
To drive!
( Tires screeching )
And the yellow light
means speed up.
( Sirens )
Uh-oh.
What seems to be the problem,
officers?
( Roars )
Now there had
better be a darn good
explanation for this.
Oh, there is.
You see, I'm a very old man,
not long for this earth,
and the doctor's assigned me
a seeing-eye bear
to drive me to the hospital
in case of emergencies.
Is that right?
Then where's
your doctor's note?
Why, it's right here,
inside my jacket!
( Grunts ) ah! There you go!
Well, I can't argue
with Dr. medicine.
To the hospital, honeypants!
( Roars )
Grunkle Stan,
how could you lie
to those policemen?
Don't you know lying
is always wrong?
Mabel, when you
get to be my age,
you'll learn that sometimes
you have to bend the truth
for the greater good.
Hey, has anyone seen
my plate of spaghetti?
( Slurps ) no.
But I bet Soos has.
You know how he likes to eat.
This is a dark day.
Thanks, grunkle Stan!
See? greater good.
Ahh!
Waddles, what am I gonna
do about grunkle Stan?
( Deep voice )
he needs to stop lying.
( Normal voice )
i know! But how do we stop him?
( Deep voice ) maybe you
should check Dipper's journal.
Oink, oink!
( Normal voice )
say "oink" one more time.
( Deep voice )
oink, oink.
( Normal voice )
waddles, you genius!
"Buried 'neath a tree stump in
the deep forest are truth teeth,
which force upon the wearer
an inability to lie." Hmm.
( Snoring )
Aah! what's going on?
What? Mabel?
Quick question.
What happened to
Dipper's spaghetti plate?
I ate it, because I have
little to no concern
for other people's
possessions or emotions.
Huh.
that was strangely candid.
Almost as if I'm unable to lie.
Well, goodnight!
( Snores )
You what? That seems
like a horrible idea!
It's great!
Now he has to tell
the truth.
Hmm.
Scrambled meat,
here it is.
Stan, what do you do
in secret every day
during your lunch break?
Usually I spend the hour
aggressively scratching myself
in places
i shouldn't mention.
Now I'm going to avoid
making eye contact
by pretending to read
this newspaper,
and go to the bathroom
without washing my hands.
Both: ew!
Well, that was disturbing.
Don't worry, Dipper.
The truth is
always a good thing.
Hey, excuse me.
Do you think this t-shirt
is my size?
Never mind the t-shirt!
Hey, everybody!
Look at this guy's abnormal
and unattractive face!
( Audible reactions )
I'm so sorry.
Doing my taxes.
Uh, grunkle Stan,
why did you write this?
Because I regularly commit
massive tax fraud.
Might wanna tuck
that one away there.
Doo-doo-doo-doo-do.
oh, no!
( Mabel and Dipper laughing )
Sometimes I think,
is this all there is?
Is life just some
kind of horrific joke
without a punch line?
That we're all just
biding our time
until the sweet,
sweet release of death?
( Audibly shudders )
Kids!
I think I have a growth
forming on my back!
Just wanted to be honest
with you guys!
I can't take it anymore,
Mabel!
You have to take those teeth
out of his mouth.
But then
he'd be a liar again!
Could is possibly be
any worse than this?
( Doorbell rings )
So after further
investigation,
turns out there is
no Dr. medicine
in gravity falls.
You'd better have a durn
good explanation for this.
Oh, and I do!
You see, I lied to you.
In addition, I've been
parking in handicapped spaces,
shoplifting fireworks,
and smuggling endangered
animals across multiple
state lines.
Also, you're fat.
Is all this true?
No, no, it's not true...
Right, Mabel?
Uh... sirs,
I have to be completely
and totally honest with you.
Our great uncle Stan is...
Is... ugh!
( Growling )
Stan is...
Secretly a crime fiction
writer!
What?
Yeah!
he was just telling you
about a character
from his upcoming page-Turner
crime grandpa.
He's never committed
a crime in his life!
Also, have you lost weight?
( Tittering )
Finally, someone noticed.
Wow, an author!
Can you teach me
how to read?
What? author?
( Chuckling ) authors--
masters of fiction!
Good night, officers!
Ugh!
Hey, you all right?
I can't believe I lied!
Mabel, it was for
the greater good.
Yeah. the greater good.
Hello, police station?
Yeah, I forgot to
tell 'em about my tax fraud.
No, tax fraud.
Get 'em out!
What's gotten into you kids?
We have to find a place
to get rid of these!
( Audibly struggling )
And I never saw that box
full of magical teeth again.
Oh, wait, there it is.
( All groan )
Oh, sweet, my shoes.
I liked the part
with the bear.
The rest seemed
pretty farfetched.
Mabel, we already
know that story.
We just lived through it.
So, if we're living
through that story right now,
how does it end?
Guys, do you see that?
Oh, what is that?
Oh, no!
Where are we going?
Oh, my god!
( All screaming )
( Bleating )
Aah! oooph!
Where... where are we?
( Gasps )
look! The shack!
Which means...
We came right back out
the top.
And I don't think
any time has passed.
It must be some kind
of wormhole.
Yeah, dude, that sounds
"sciencey" enough to be true.
But that's impossible!
No one will believe us!
Maybe this is one story
we should keep to ourselves.
Agreed!
Aah!
He'll be fine.
( Grunts )
This is stupid!