**
there she is, Mabel--
the cheapest fair
money can rent!
I spared every expense!
( Screams )
I think the sky tram
is broken.
Also most of my bones.
( Laughs ) this guy!
All right, all right.
I got a job for you two.
I printed up a bunch of fake
safety inspection certificates.
Go slap one on anything
that looks like a lawsuit.
Grunkle Stan,
is that legal?
When there's no cops around,
anything's legal!
Soos, how's that dunk tank
coming along?
Almost ready to go, Mr. pines.
Ha! you got it rigged
from here to timbuktu!
There's nothin' on earth
that could knock me down!
Yeah, except for like
a futuristic laser arm Cannon.
( Grunts ) hey,
you haven't seen my
red screwdriver, have ya?
Darn thing went missing.
Maybe some magical creature
or paranormal thing took it.
Oy, you been spendin'
too much time with those kids!
All right, let's see.
Where did I put that thing?
This mission
is proceeding as planned. Over.
**
Stan: it's 12:00!
The dunk tank is now open!
( All groan )
Step right up
and dunk me, folks!
I'm talkin' to you, cut-offs!
That's right!
Muffin top! High pants!
Who wants a piece of me?!
( ( Laughs ))
Come back any time, folks!
( Laughs )
How do they get them
into this shape?
It's unnatural.
But, Dipper, they're so...
Delicious?
( Both laugh )
Uh, boo!
I'll be right back.
I'll be right here!
( Laughs )
( Whispers ) I love you.
Look at you two,
gettin' all romantic
at the fair.
Come on, it's no big deal.
Yeah, it is.
Okay, you're right! It is!
Isn't this amazing?!
I just dove in! I said,
"hey, you wanna hang out
at the fair?"
And you know what she said?!
Yeah, I guess so.
Yeah, I guess so!
It totally worked!
All your advice
about just going for it,
it's finally paying off!
When are you going
to learn, Dipper?
I'm always right
about everything.
Hey, do you smell
a gallon of body spray?
Hey, either of you dorks
seen Wendy around?
Hey!wants to know?
Yeah, I got some new
super tight jeans.
Thought she might
wanna check 'em out.
Yeah, you know,
i think I saw her
in the bottomless pit.
You should really
go jump in there.
Maybe I will, smart guy.
( Groans )
He is such a jerk.
Yeah, but he's a jerk
with tight pants and a guitar.
I need to keep him away
from Wendy at all costs.
Don't worry, brother,
whatever happens,
I'll be right here,
supporting you ever step of--
oh, my gosh! A pig!
( Panting )
If you can guess
the critter's weight,
you can take the critter home!
( Gasps)
(he said "Mabel"!.
Either that or "doorbell."
Did you say "Mabel"
or "doorbell"?
( Oinking ) Mabel.
( Gasps )
Oh, look, Mabel here
found her real twin.
( All laugh )
Pacifica!
Sir, I must have that pig!
Ah, old fifteen-poundy!
So, how much
you guessin' he weighs?
Um, 15 pounds?
Are you some kind of witch?
Well, there's your pig.
( Squeals )
( Cheering and applause )
And you'll be
needin' these.
No? suit yourself.
Mm-mm.
( Whispers )
everything is different now.
Whoa! check it out!
I don't know if it's a duck
or a panda, but I want one!
My uncle taught me
the secret to these games--
you aim for the carny's head
and take the prize
when he's unconscious.
( Laughs ) nice.
One ball, please.
You only get once chance.
And a one,
and a two, and a...
( Grunts )
Ow! my eye!
Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
Wendy, are you okay?!
Does it look swollen?
Everything's gonna be fine!
Don't worry! I'll...
I'll go get some ice!
Where is she? Where is she?
( Both groan )
Hey, watch where
you're going, man!
( Grunts )
( Panting )
All right, just ease
your eyeball into that
freezy cone.
Robbie, thanks.
That's really sweet--
the gesture
and the flavored syrup.
Yeah, I was just here
in the right place
at the right time.
You know, I've been
meanin' to ask you...
We've been spendin'
a lot of time together
and I was wondering
if maybe you wanted
to go out with me?
( Whimpers )
Yeah, I guess so.
Sweet!
Look, Dipper!
I won my pet pig!
His name is waddles.
I call him that because
he waddles! Waddles!
Everything is different now.
What are ya lookin' at?
Oh...
Uh...
are you gonna move?
( Groans )
( Sighs )
Paging Dr. waddles,
we got a boy here
with a broken heart.
Come on, man,
these are the jokes.
Mabel, do you ever
wish you could go back
and undo just one mistake?
Nope! I do everything right
all the time. ( Humming )
I mean, Wendy only went out
with Robbie because
he was there with the ice,
and she only needed ice
because of the baseball,
and I would have had the ice
if it wasn't for...
( Gasps ) that guy!
Hey, you! Tool belt!
You ruined my life!
Huh?
Don't "huh" me!
I've seen you before!
What's your deal?
Are you following us around?
And why are you bald?
What's all that about?
( Screams ) my position
has been compromised!
Assuming stealth mode!
Color match!
Initiating color match!
Come on! Dang it!
That's amazing! ( Gasps )
are you from the future
or something?
Uh, no! Who told you that?!
Memory wipe!
This is a baby wipe.
( Sighs )
all right, you've cornered me.
I'm a time traveler.
So wait a minute,
if you're from the future,
do you have, like,
a time machine or something?
That's kinda how that works.
Could I borrow it?
Dipper: come on, can I use
your time machine just once?
Out of the question!
This is sensitive,
extremely complicated
time equipment!
It looks like
a tape measure.
You shut your time-mouth!
This makin'
any sense to you?
( Whispers )
i think he's just crazy.
Oh, you don't believe me?
Gueboth: whoa!Was!
That's right, 15 years ago
there was a costume store
right here!
One second!
Aw, heck! Pat!
So who are you again?
Blendin blandin,
time anomaly removal crew,
year 20-snyeventy-12!
My mission is to stop
a series of time anomalies
that are supposed to happen
at this very location!
B-but I don't see
any anomalies!
I don't know if it's
some kind of paradox
or if I'm just really tired!
You know, you sound like
you could use a break.
Definitely. definitely.
Might we recommend one
of the various attractions
at the mystery fair?
You know what? What the heck!
I'm worth it!
But I got my eye on you!
( Grunts )
Aw, sorry, dude,
but you're gonna have to take
your belt off for the ride.
One of your tools might fly off
and accidently fix something.
Guard it with your life!
I will watch it
like a hawk, dude.
( Cheering )
Like a hawk!
Here it is, Mabel--
our ticket to any moment
in history!
Lets go get two dodos
and force them to make out!
No! we gotta be
smart about this.
All that paradox talk
kinda freaked me out.
All I'm gonna do is go back
and fix my one mistake.
If I don't miss
that baseball throw,
I won't hit Wendy in the eye,
and Robbie won't comfort her,
and they won't start going out.
I'm coming, too! I wanna relive
the greatest moment of my life--
winning waddles! Mwah!
( Oinks )
See ya later.
See you earlier!
Yuck, yuck, yuck!
( Beeps )
( Squeals )
( Eating loudly )
Ah! ah! Ah! Ah!
( Both panting )
Stan: it's 12:00!
The dunk tank is now open!
( All groan )
Step right up
and dunk me, folks!
I'm talkin' to you, cut-offs!
Do-over?
Do-over!
Fifteen pounds!S--
and yes, I am a witch.
Well, time to round up a mob.
There you are.
Hey, what happened
to your hat?
Uh, nothing.
Hey, look! What's that?
Whoa! check it out!
I don't know if it's a duck
or a panda, but I want one!
One ball, please.
You only get one chance.
That's what you think.
One panda-duck,
coming right up!
Okay, Dipper, second chance.
Don't mess this up.
( Grunts ) yes!
Ow! my eye!
What?!
Does it look swollen??
That's so weird.
Wendy: oh, hey, Robbie.
So anyway,
we've been hangin' out a lot,
and I've been wondering if, uh,
you wanted to go out with me?
Yeah, I guess so.
Sweet!
The exact same thing
happened twice! It was spooky!
Ooh, maybe it's a time curse!
Waddles, can you
say "time curse"?
( Squeals )
Your face is so fat!
Is it possible
that the forces of time
naturally conspire
to undo any new outcomes?
No, no.
I just need to try again.
Third time's the charm.
How hard can it be?
( Beeps )
Find the witch!
Ow! my eye!
Hey, are you all right?
( Laughs )
Ow! my eye!
Oh, bad luck.
Uh, Wendy? How badly
do you want that
stuffed animal thing?
More than anything
in the world, Dipper.
( Sighs ) okay.
( Grunts )
( Screams )
I love my pig!
If I adjust the ball
for wind speed...
Factoring cotton candy...
Face it, Dipper,
you're obviously fated
to have a bad day at the fair.
Just like I'm fated
to be with waddles!
It's like there's
one variable missing.
What's a variable?
Ha! that's it!
I figured out a way
to win the toss,
not hit Wendy,
and stop Wendy and Robbie
from going out!
Awesome! I'm gonna go
win my pig again!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You can't leave.
I need you for my plan.
But what about waddles?
It'll just take a few minutes!
Let's go!
( Blows )
( Wind blowing )
You gonna go, man?
And a one, and a two,
and a... ( Grunts )
Aw, dude, you missed.
Did I?
( All gasp )
( All sigh )
( Laughs )
( Groans )
Huh?
( Screams )
Your stuffed creature
of indeterminate species, miss.
Oh, awesome!
There you hi, Robbie.
So I was wondering
if, uh, you--
look what Dipper got for me!
Whatever. can't even tell
what species it is. Stupid.
What's his deal?
Looks like I came to the fair
with the right guy!
We have a winner!
Anytime, broseph.
Now to win my pig. ( Gasps )
It's all yours!
No one else's!
Old fifteen-poundy!
Yours forever!
( Squeals )
( Screams )
( Both laugh )
That was even more awesome
the third time around!
( Gasps ) funnel cake!
Let's go get some, Dipper!
( Screaming )
( Screams )
M( screams )-
I'll just wait
until you're done.
Okay, what is wrong?
We messed up the timeline!
Pacifica saw the flier
and won waddles before I did!
She took waddles, Dipper!
Oh, Mabel, I'm sorry.
( Sighs ) it's okay,
we just need to go back
and do things differently.
Mabel, wait!
Look, I did the math--
in any other timeline, Wendy
ends up going out with Robbie!
I can't mess this day up again!
But if we don't go,
then I'll lose waddles forever!
Hey!
( Both grunting )
Give it back!
Whoa!
( Both gasp and groan )
When are we?
The real question is,
when are we?
Oh, wait,
did you already--
'cause I was gonna--
yeah. yall right.Thing.
Do you hear that?
( Rumbling )
( Both scream )
( Both panting )
Be on the look out
for mountain lions, travelers!
Dysentery? who wants dysentery?
Forge ahead, mighty oxen!
For a new life awaits us
on this Oregon trail!
Where are we? The '70s?
You sent us back 150 years,
genius! It's pioneer times!
By trembly! Fertilla,
it seems you've given birth
to two more children!
It appears I have.
More little hands
to render the tallow.
( Chuckles ) tallow? What?
Her mouth is filled
with silver, mother!
These are called braces.
Mabel, we can't start
messing with the past!
Oh, says the guy who messed
with the past all day,
and cost me my pig?
I'll mess with whatever I want!
Check it out!
A magic button machine!
Shoes that blink!
( All gasp )
Hey, sister, guess who
gets to vote in the future?
Ladies! up top!
That's called a high-five.
Teach it to your friends.
Give me that!
I'm gonna set
the timeline right!
Hey! no!
( Roars )
( Both scream )
( Both scream, sigh )
( Screams )
Run! take cover!
It's coming!
( Laughs )
This future seems neat.
( Beeping )
I'm coming, waddles!
Hey!
I seen it! I seen it again!
But enough about me.
Behold...
me!
( Groans )
( Roars )
( Both panting )
This thing is getting hotter!
Hot! hot, hot, hot!
Whi don't know!?!
( Both scream )
Where are we?
It's nothing
but inky blackness for miles!
Mabel, don't you see?
We've transported
to the end of time!
( Both scream )
Wait, why does it
smell so bad in here?
( Thumping )
( Both panting )
Look! we're back
in the present!
But which present?
This is the byes!Present ever!
( Squeals )
No! give me that thing!
Dipper, give it back!
Look, Mabel,
it's over, okay?
Give it up!
I've worked too hard
to lose this!
But what about waddles?
He was my soul mate!
You said that about
a ball of yarn once!
Do you really want Wendy
to date Robbie?
I don't know.
You're not
guilt-tripping me, Mabel.
Not this time.
Come on, Mabel, I know you.
You're gonna forget about this
in a day.
Here! hey, I'll prove it!
See?
Okay, maybe you'll
forget in a week.
( Beeps )
A month.
She'll be better in a month!
( Beeps )
Waddles. waddles.
And if you look to your left,
you'll see miserable Mabel--
the girl who went bonkers
after her dreams were shattered
by some heartless jerk.
Oh, hey, Dipper!
( Groans )
( Sighs )
( Beeps )
I don't know if it's a duck
or a panda, but I want one.
( Sighs )
Wendy, I just wanted
to say that...
Well, I just wanted to say
that people make mistakes,
and when they do,
you should forgive them.
And also, that tight pants
are overrated.
Dude, you lost me.
I know.
One ball, please.
You only get one chance.
And a one, and a two,
and a... ( Grunts )
Ow! my eye!
Hey, Wendy,
are you okay?
You know, this is
the perfect time for me
to ask you something.
It is done.
Dipper! thank you! Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
( Oinks ) thank you.
He's saying
"thank you" in pig!
Aren't you, waddles?
( Oinks )
Ow. ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
I couldn't break
your heart, Mabel.
Besides, there's no way
Wendy can date Robbie
all summer, right?
You two!
( ( Squeals ) )
Do you have any idea
how many rules you just broke?!
I'm asking,
i wasn't there with you.
It was probably a lot, right?
Blendin blandin!
( Screams )
the time paradox avoidance
enforcement squadron!
That's right, and our phones
have been ringing off the hook.
There's settlers
high-fiving in the 1800s
and calculators littered
through eight centuries!
You are under arrest
for violations
of the time travelers
code of conduct.
It was those kids!
And their leader, waddles!
That's a pig, blendin.
Oh! I'll get you for this!
I'll go back in time
and make sure your parents
never meet!
Well, we're still here.
Guess he forgot to go back.
Ha! you suckers!
Your pockets are empty and I'm
still sitting high and dry!
All: boo!
( Laughs ) yeah, boo!
Boo! I love it!
Hey, biceps! Yeah,
I'm talking to you, haircut!
Take your best shot! ( Laughs )
W-whoa!
( All cheer )
So I guess we never
found out who was causing
those time anomalies
blendin was looking for.
Wait, Mabel...
I think it was us.
Ugh, my brain hurts.
Aw, jeez, I gotta deal
with this all summer?
( Chuckles ) it's good.
It's caramel.
I'm on it.
( Sniffs )
( Squeals )
( Screams )
My pants! They're shrinking!
( All laugh )
( Gags )
( Laughs ) oh, man.
( Sighs ) that'll do, pig.
( Oinks )
That'll do.
You have broken the eternal laws
of space-time.
I beg your mercy, time baby!
You now must clean up
all of the anomalies.
( Humming )
Old man mcguckett, local kook!
Are the wax figures alive?
( Roars )
What are you looking at?