Do you have this t-shirt
in my size?
I have something
even better.
Behold! my butt!
( Both laugh )
(Whispers) I could
play this game
forever.
What'd you say?
Coughing! I was coughing!
Those weren't words!
Ha ha ha ha!
This if fun,
what you two have.
Mabel! how long have you
been standing there?
Don't worry about that.
Let's talk about why
I'm doing this dance!
( Sings melody )
Oh no! She got into
the smile dip again!
Wrong one thousand!
It's because today is
the greatest day of my life!
Waa!
ow!
Sev'ral timez is playing at
the gravity falls civic center
and buffet!
Ahh. sev'ral timez?
Aren't they that boy band
that came a decade too late?
В™є oh, oh в™є
в™є girl, you got me actin'
so cray cray в™є
в™є cray cray! В™є
в™є you tell me that you won't
be my baby в™є
we're not threatening!
Mabel, you know
all those boy bands
are fake, right?
Dipper's right. They're just
a manufactured product
of the bloated corporate
music industry.
You're making my dance sad!
(Snickers)
there's probably a machine
that mass produces them.
Or maybe the boys
are grown from pods.
Yeah! pods, totally!
You guys can't
ruin this for me.
Mabel's got backup!
Hey, guys!
Whoo whoo!
I'm ready for the greatest
night of our lives!
В™є how many times
am I gonna love ya? В™є
в™є sev'ral timez! В™є
uhh. girls.
I know, right?
( Giggling )
I'm okay.
В™єв™є
ooh. should I got with lip balm
or lip salve?
Go wild!
Tonight's our night!
I can't wait, guys.
Tonight we're gonna meet
creggy g, greggy c,
leggy p, chubby z,
and deep Chris!
He's the fat one.
And those boys will
fall in love with us.
Why wouldn't they?
Hey, this is
the fingerless glove store?
I like things that are dumb.
I'm Robbie.
Come on, man!
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Laugh it up, chief.
So, Wendy, Nate and his
girlfriend are going to
lookout point this weekend.
Maybe we should go, too.
Are you kidding me?!
First you stand me up
last night,
and instead of apologizing,
you want me to go to
lookout point?
I'll just be...Over here.
Look, Robbie. I'm not sure
this relationship's working.
Maybe I should
see other people.
Yes!
Whoa. whoa. Hey. Hey.
Before you do anything crazy,
I, uh, I want you
to hear this.
(Low) hope this works.
I wrote this song
just for you.
( Backing track plays )
в™є when I think about you в™є
в™є I feel feelings so deep в™є
в™є I'm tossin' and turnin' в™є
в™є and you know
I'm losing sleep в™є
yeesh!
в™є and I know I'm goin' crazy в™є
в™є when I look
into your eyes в™є
в™є just listen to this song в™є
в™є and you'll be
hypnoti-yi-yized в™єв™є
you know, maybe I was being
a little hasty.
I'll give you
another chance.
Yes! all right!
Mwah.
Let me go
grab my coat.
All right, Robbie,
i saw that weird cd.
What the heck
are you up to?
It's called romance, kid.
Something you'd never
understand.
Wendy: you ready?
I can't believe you
wrote that for me.
I know.
I'm just so insanely talented.
Hm.
Hmm...
( Sniffs )
Mabel:
what are you doing?
Guys, the weirdest thing
just happened.
I think Robbie might be
hypnotizing Wendy
with his music.
Oh, Dipper! Girls
just like musicians.
You'll understand
when you're older.
We're the same age!
Girls mature
faster than guys.
Right, grenda?
Mmm...this is
grenda time!
Mmm...mmm...mmm....
Okay, girls,
have you all practiced
your obsessed boy band scream?
Aaaah!
Aaaaah!
Just gonna
ignore that.
Tickets, please!
Too late, girls!
The show is sold out.
( All gasp )
This night is ruined!
I welcome you,
death.
( Grunting )
No! I said we're going to
meet sev'ral timez tonight,
and I meant it!
And I'm not gonna let
a "keep out" sign
keep us out!
В™є stockin' meat
for the apocalypse,
doodla-doo в™є
в™є we're all gonna die-- в™є
what's with
the pacing, kid?
You look even more
freaked out than usual.
Ah, I don't know.
You wouldn't understand.
Ah, come on, kid.
Try me.
Okay. this is gonna sound weird,
but I think Robbie might be
brainwashing Wendy with music.
I've seen this before.
Really?
her name was
Carla mccorkle.
Carla "hot pants" mccorkle...
( '50s rock plays )
Stan: me and Carla baby
would cut a rug together
at the juke joint,
our favorite '50s-themed
1970s diner.
Then one day,
this new age tree-hugger
starts playing this
transcendental hippie music.
Ahh...
Carla's hot pants
turned into bell-bottoms
before I even
knew what happened.
My memories get
a little hallucination-y
at the end,
but you get the gist.
So, wait. You actually
believe my theory?
You're darn right I do,
and we're gonna get to
the bottom of it.
Right after I get
to the bottom of
this brown meat.
It's apoca-licious!
В™єв™є
в™є sev'ral timez в™єв™є
( delighted screams )
Hey, girl, I just want to
get real for a moment
and say that while
we love being superstars,
the real reason we do this is
for you, for you specifically,
not the girl
sitting next to you, but you.
I love you, deep Chris!
He was talking
to me!
Git 'em! Git 'em!
Thank you! Good night!
( Girls screaming )
Grenda: hello?
Sev'ral timez?
We want to give you
several kisses!
Look!
This is it, girls.
You're finally going to meet
the five cutest boys
in the world!
Dipper's gonna eat his words
that boy bands are fake.
( Inhales, exhales )
This is fun!
Yo! we're clones, dawg!
O...
m...
g!
That is one big
hamster tube.
Someone's coming!
Terrible show!
What is wrong
with you boys?!
You barely even
sold out the arena!
And deep Chris,
you call that a pout?
( Whimpering )
Every one of you should be
ashamed of yourselves!
Except for you, leggy p, you
were really on point tonight.
Here ya go, gorgeous.
As for the rest of you,
remember:
You can always be replaced
by your brothers.
Dance for me, child, dance!!!
( Laughs, coughs )
My throat is killin' me!
Can someone get me
a lemon and water?
Ooh!
who goes there?
Prepared to be danced at!
Step off, deep Chris!
She's a lady.
Don't disrespect her, bro!
Don't disrespect!
Mah bad. (Kisses)
( Squeals )
Chubby z, let's calm this boo
by posin' for her, poster-style!
Whoo! trying hard not to
let my brain explode!
I've always wanted
to meet you guys!
But what was the deal with
that scary chub-chub man?
Mr. bratzman's
our producer, yo.
He genetically engineered us
to be the perfect boy band, g!
But he keeps us
in cages!
That junk is straight
brutal, girl!
That is straight brutal,
chubby z!
Our one dream is to escape
into the real world, for real.
Yo, I heard tell about
these things called trees?
I don't know what they are,
but I want to kiss one!
But we can't disobey
Mr. bratzman!
He says he loves us!
If he loved you,
he'd set you free!
All: true dat.
That's a valid
perspective!
Let's go right now.
Me and my friends
can help you escape.
We're masters of stealth!
Yo! you'd really
do that for us, beef?
You can count on me!
I'm sorry, did you
just call me "beef"?
You see, Dipper, music has
subliminal mind control
hidden in it all the time.
If you listen closely,
even the music I play
in the gift shop has
subtle hidden messages.
Store pa:
В™єв™є... buy more keychains!
Buy more keychains!
If you want to hear
the mind-controlling messages,
you gotta slow down
the record.
Gimme that l.P.!
( Needle scratching )
Oh. right.
We're doing something
wrong here,
but I can't put
my finger on it.
( Grunting )
Hey, guys!
How was the concert?
And what's in the bag?
Uh, money. Money we stole.
We are criminals.
We will cut you!
Let's go away from here now!
Band member: Ooh! Ow!
Dang, girl!
Your tour bus is
really strange,
Mabel girl.
Where the feeding tubes at?
Yo, what up, girl?
( All giggling )
So when do we get
to go outside?
I want to cavort like
a woodland creature!
( Tires squeal outside )
(Gasps) it's your producer!
( Panicky chatter )
Hyahh!
Can't believe those boys
escaped from their cage!
You there! I found this trail
of frosted tips
leading to this
very location!
Have you seen any perfect boys
around here?
Only when I look
in the mirror.
Ha ha! Up top!
They must be
around here somewhere.
I'll find those boys
if I have to turn this town
upside-down!
( Goat bleating )
Shoo! shoo!
Grrr!
Good boy.
Guys, it's not safe
out there.
Ergman's still
looking for you!
What do we do?
Oh, dang!
I'm scared, Mabel!
Don't worry, guys,
he has to give up eventually.
Hey, in the meantime,
you can stay here with us!
( Enthused chatter )
2013!
Girls, do you realize
what's happening here?
We have our very own
pet boy band
that we can do
whatever we want with!
Remember, eventually
we have to let them go.
We have to promise not to get
too attached to them.
Right, Mabel? Mabel?
All aboard the braid train!
Braid, braid!
What?
В™є come on, baby, won't you
fly away with me в™є
в™є take my hand, it's destiny в™є
в™є we don't need nobody
if we stay together в™є
в™є girl, just take my hand,
it can be forever в™є
в™є up into the sky,
girl, we're gonna fly в™є
в™є look into my big blue eyes в™є
в™є girl, you know it's destiny в™є
в™є take my hand
and you're gonna see в™є
в™є let's escape,
runnin' from reality в™є
в™є it'll be this way
forever в™єв™є
just a--
just a few more minutes.
But--
( hissing )
All right.
Took all day,
but I converted it
to a record.
Now we can slow it down
to see if the mind control
message theory is correct.
Prepare to have
your mind blown.
Spit take, here I come.
Robbie:
в™є when I think about you в™є
в™є ( slowed down ) I feel
feelings so deep в™є
в™є I'm tossing and turning в™є
hmm.
В™є (continues)
That's now spit-worthy.
What gives?
What? is that it?
( Changing record speed)
Ohh! this was so stupid!
Of course there's no
hidden mind control messages!
Mabel was right.
Wendy just likes the song.
She just likes Robbie.
(Door opens)
Wendy: Hey, dip.
Forgot my keys.
What's up, junior?
What are you doing,
trying to come up
with an equation
to make girls like you?
Ha ha ha!
Ready to go
to lookout point?
Am I. Later, dorks.
Catch you on
the rewind.
I made that up.
I'll rewind
your face!
Wait a minute.
Stan, rewind!
( Playing backwards )
в™є you are now under
my control в™є
в™є your mind is mine в™є
holy mackerel!
Now there's your
spit take!
Ha ha! I knew it!
It's mind control after all.
Oh, no! I gotta
save Wendy!
Finally, a good reason
to punch a teenager
in the face! Let's roll!
How'd it go up there?
Ohh. I finally
got them to sleep.
Poor greggy c.
He tried to eat
a tape dispenser.
I think this is food, dawg!
Yo, you gonna share that?
Ah, memories.
The music industry
was shaken today
at the news that
boy band king ergman bratzman
has been arrested.
He was pulled over tonight
for not having
a rear license plate.
I'm telling ya,
the goat took it!
That's what
they all say.
He is now in county jail
awaiting trial.
Yes!
we have to tell the boys
they are free now!
( Nervous laughter )
Let's go!
Not so fast!
They're not going anywhere.
( Both gasp )
What the dealio, Mabel?
That evil producer is gone.
We have to tell the boys!
Wait, girls, let's not
be so hasty. I mean,
think about it:
If we don't tell the boys,
then they can
stay here with me.
I mean with us.
Mabel, we can't keep
them here forever.
But I love them!
If you love them,
you'd set them free.
Never! every boy I loved
this summer has left me,
and I'm not gonna
let it happen again!
Candy, we gotta
get past mable!
She's gone boy-crazy!
Uhh! boys!!!
( Growls )
Candy...attack!
Whoa!
dang!
You guys! Ergman bratzman
is in jail!
You're free!
Just go!
Whoa! is that true,
Mabel dawg?
Uh, no. Your producer's
still out there.
You're gonna
have to stay here--
probably forever!
What?! you can't
listen to her!
Mabel's our girl, girl.
She puts pizza
in our food trough.
She changes my newspaper,
yo. She's a'ight.
She is not a'ight,
chubby z!
Sev'ral timez!
All:
yes, Mabel dawg?
Remove these two
from the premises,
please.
В™єв™є
oh, no! They're
aggressively
dancing at us!
Mabel's gone mad
with power!
Save yourselves,
sev'ral timez!
You were better off
with your producer!
Word!
Call me, deep Chris!
2013!
( Deep sigh )
thanks, you boys.
Now let's get aboard
the braid train.
Things just got
pretty heavy, Mabel.
Maybe we should all just like
chill for a minute, and--
I said, let's get aboard
the braid train!!!
Ohh.
hmm.
We gotta warn Wendy
about that song before
she gets brainwashed!
Road safety laws,
prepare to be ignored!
( Collision sounds )
Huh. weird.
Nate didn't show up.
So i-i guess
it's just you and me.
This isn't what
i was planning at all.
Stan: whoa! Ooh!
Wendy! stop!
Robbie's been lying to you!
Dipper?
kid? Mr. pines?
That's Mr. pines to you!
What? that's what
i just said.
Look, Wendy.
You've gotta
hear this.
Mabel, you've gotta hear this.
It's a song we wrote
to say thank you.
Hit it!
В™єв™є
oh boy! Songs are like hugs
that mouths give to ears!
В™є here comes
young Mabel girl в™є
в™є we've dreamed of bein' free в™є
в™є but now we know
that can never be в™є
в™є you know what friends
are all about в™є
в™є you kicked those lyin'
shorties out в™є
в™є kick 'em out, y'all в™є
I'm starting to
feel guilty here.
В™є break it down! В™є
в™є who's the girl
who's so a'ight в™є
в™є tucks us into bed at night в™є
в™є holds the fan up
while we sing в™є
в™є keeps me entertained
with string в™є
в™є my shirt was wrinkled
till she pressed it в™є
в™є chews our food
so we can digest it в™є
в™є he was evil,
mean and reckless в™є
в™є you gave me
this candied necklace в™є
в™є what's up, girl? В™є
в™є other folks
we could never trust в™є
в™є but we know в™є
в™є that you'd never
lie to us в™є
в™є Mabel, girl в™є
в™є we know you
love us so в™є
and that's why I've got
to let you go. (Sighs)
В™є when I think about you в™є
uh...
There's a message
in there, I swear!
Let me just
close the window.
Wait! wait! Here.
В™є you are now
under my control в™є
в™є your mind is mine в™є
ohh!
Robbie, what's that
doing in our song?
Baby, I promise.
I don't know anything
about those messages.
In fact, I didn't
even write that song.
I ripped it off
some other band.
So we're all good,
right?
No! we're not all good.
I don't care about the messages.
You said you wrote that song
for me,
and I actually
thought it was sweet,
you big liar!
I know, I know,
i lie about a lot of stuff.
Like using your makeup
and fighting a bear.
Although--
no. you know what?
It's over, Robbie.
We're through.
What?! Wendy!
Good-bye.
Ha ha! We won!
Kid, this is a victory
for every guy whose hands
are too weak or fat to
play a musical instrument.
I couldn't have done it
without you, grunkle Stan.
Ha!
ha!
Um, hey! Now that
your night is free,
me and grunkle Stan
were thinkin' maybe
bowling or something?
Are you serious?
Right now?
Uhh! what is wrong with guys?!
You only think
about yourselves!
All of you should just
leave me alone!
Ohh, man.
Look, if it makes you
feel any better,
the apocalypse
is coming soon.
Bury your gold.
You've been buying
gold, right?
We've gotta
save the boys.
I'm prepared to
defend myself.
Hi, guys. I'm sorry
i went bonkers.
A catchy song made me realize
that you were right.
Can you ever forgive me?
Of course!
Friendship repaired.
What's goin' on,
Mabel girl?
You said you had something
you wanted to show us
or some deal?
Yep, this!
Oh! huh? Yo, dawg,
who is this big,
round, bright fool?!
That, chubby z,
is the sun!
That fool's making my eyes
burn straight painful!
I'm gonna stare
that fool down.
Hrrrrgg...
Aaaah!!!
Yo, yo, hold up.
What this big
green mess?
That's nature, deep Chris.
Bratzman won't
bother you anymore.
You can do anything
you want to do,
go anywhere
you want to go.
You're free!
Fuh-ree?
Free!
you're free!
It means you can
skedaddle!
( Crying )
now, go! Go!
Get out of here
before I change my mind!
В™є good-bye, girl в™єв™є
they won't last a week.
Women! they're the real
mystery, dip!
You ruin your date,
drop their hippie boyfriend's
Van into a ravine,
and somehow you're
the bad guy.
No, it's my fault.
I shouldn't have meddled
in Wendy's personal life.
She probably hates me now.
Ah, chin up, kid.
You were trying
to do the right thing.
Even though you destroyed
her relationship
and part of my car.
You think
she'll ever forgive me?
I bet she will.
And until then,
you can always
go bowling with me.
Thanks, grunkle Stan.
Don't mention it, kid.
( Growling, clatter outside )
Wait a second.
Is something rooting
through our trash?
Hey! hey!
Get outta here!
( Panting )
Darn beautiful men!
Always eating
out of my trash.
Wait. what?
В™є girl, you got me acting
so cray cray в™є
в™є cray cray в™є
в™є you tell me that
you won't be my baby в™є
в™є we're non-threatening, girl в™є
в™є yeah в™є
dang, girl.
2013.