( Brakes screech,
all exclaim )
Here we are.
The summerween superstore.
Wait-- summer what?
Summerween!
The people of this town
love Halloween so much,
they celebrate it
twice a year.
And wouldn't you know it?
It's today!
Do you always carry that
calendar in your pocket?
Yes.
Summerween? something
about this feels
unnatural.
There's free candy!
Both:
to the costume aisle!
I'd lend you a hand--
but I don't seem to have any!
( Cackling )
This guy
tells it like it is.
Sir.
Could please
stop pushing that.
Ma'am, make these heads
less hilarious
and you got
yourself a deal.
( Head cackles )
well!
When the children
come to my door tonight,
they're gonna
run away screaming
from Stan pines,
master of fright!
Boo!
( baby cries, Stan laughs )
( Ongoing noise )
Uh-oh. think
this one's leaking!
Have the police come
and eject the pines
family from the store.
Not today!
My eyes!
You paid for this stuff,
right?
Of course!
I hate summerween.
Stan: let's move!
В™єв™є
( owl hooting )
i am so excited!
We're gonna have
the best costumes,
get the most candy...
And have the biggest
stomachaches ever!
Yeah!
ha ha! Yeah!
Dude, I've never seen
you guys so pumped.
Well, back at home,
me and Dipper were
kind of the kings
of trick-or-treating.
Twins in costumes--
the people eat it up.
Well, you dudes better
be careful out there.
It's a night
of ghouls and goblins,
not to mention...
The summerween trickster.
The summer what
what-what?
The trickster
goes door to door,
so the legend goes,
eating children
who lack
the summerween spirit.
Well, you don't have
to worry about us.
We've got
spirit to go around.
( Hacking and coughing )
oh, what is this stuff?
I've never even heard
of these brands.
Sand pop?
Gummy chairs?
Mr. adequate bar?
This is all
cheapo loser candy!
Quiet your discontent,
children,
lest the trickster overhear.
Your cape is caught
in your fly, Soos.
Touchг©.
( nom nom )
Goodbye, loser candy!
( Sinister breathing )
( Doorbell rings )
Stan: Trick-or-treaters!
Quick, give 'em
that terrible candy!
Happy summer--
wha--?!
'sup, squirt?
Hey, Dipper.
Wendy! ha ha ha!
Ow! wh--
what's up, guys?
Ugh! I left my jacket
here, again.
Hey, what's
with the candy?
You goin' trick-
or-treating or something?
Well, actually, I, uh...
Shut up, Robbie.
Of course he's not
going trick-or-treating.
No, yeah, uh...
( Nervous chuckle )
Trick-or-treating
is for babies...
I guess.
You should come
to this party with us.
Tambry's parents
are out of town,
and it's gonna be
off the chain!
Not surprised you
didn't hear about it.
В™єв™є
hey, guys, wait!
Maybe I'll see you
at the party.
If you're not too busy
playing dress-up.
( Audible blow )
it's at nine!
Don't forget!
( Sighs )
what am I gonna
tell Mabel?
( Distant wolf howls )
Uncle Stan, these are
my best friends...
Candy and grenda!
I am so sweet,
i could eat myself.
( Unusual, raspy voice )
hello, Mr. pines.
You got a cold, honey?
Something wrong
with your voice there?
What do you mean?
Why would you say that?
Is waddles
coming with us?
I wish he could, but...
He's got some
very important
meetings to attend!
( Grunting )
File these documents
under "i,"
for "i have a curly tail!"
( All laughing )
what about your brother?
Oh, man, guys,
just wait until you
see Dipper's costume.
It's amazing!
Here he comes now.
That is a very good
Dipper costume.
What the hey-hey,
bro-bro? Where's
your costume?
Look, I can't go
trick-or-treating.
I'm, uh, really sick.
( Coughing )
Must have been
that bad candy.
You go on without me.
Fight through it,
man! Where's your
summerween spirit?
( Pounding on door )
Trick or treat.
Dude, really?
You're a little old
for this, man. Sorry.
But wait. I'm...!
Why'd you close the door?
I told you, Mabel...
I'm just not feeling
it tonight. ( Coughing )
I think a little
trick-or-treating
will make you feel better.
I'm not trick-or-treating.
( Pounding on door )
Look, man, just go
to another house!
Dipper, where's your
summerween hospitality?
( Pounding on door )
I'm not getting that.
Well, I am.
I apologize
for my brother.
He came down with a case
of the grumpy grumps.
Silence!
You have insulted me,
and for this you must pay...
With your lives!
Ohh! what a cute
little mask.
You're a funny guy,
aren't you?
Funny am I?
"Twick-or-tweat"!
My name is gorney!
Aah! remember me!
( All scream )
gorney!
There's only one way
for you
to avoid his fate--
I need a treat.
If you can collect
500 pieces of candy
and bring it to me
before the last
Jack-o'-melon goes out...
( Blows )
I will let you live.
Five hundred treats
in one night?
That's impossible!
The choice is yours,
children.
You must
trick-or-treat...
Or die!
( Sinister laughter )
Oh, my gosh, Mabel,
do you know what this means?
I do.
( Happily ) it means
you have to come
trick-or-treating!
Yay!
Who was that guy?
It's the legend
Soos told us about.
It's true!
What do we do,
what do we do?
What's going on
out here, dudes?
I heard a ruckus.
( Chuckles )
That's a funny word--
"ruckus."
Soos, a monster is making
us trick-or-treat,
or else he's gonna eat us.
I got a picture.
The summerween trickster!
Oh, man, dude, you guys
are in crazy bonkers trouble.
How are we gonna get
that much candy in one night?
There's no way!
( Claps )
listen up, people!
Now, some might say
that being cursed
by a bloodthirsty holiday
monster is a bad thing...
I wet myself!
But that monster messed
with the wrong crew.
With candy's spirit,
grenda's strength,
Dipper's brains, and...
( Awkwardly )
Soos, here...
We'll get 500 pieces
of candy and have fun
doing it, too,
even if it takes all night!
( All exclaiming )
Mabel: to the streets!
All night?
But-- but I'm sick,
remember? ( Coughing )
Dipper, what's worse--
getting eaten by
a horrifying monster,
or going trick-or-treating
with us?
Well...
Come on!
Aah!
Ah, summerween!
Those kids aren't gonna
know what hit 'em!
( Cackling )
( Doorbell rings )
Trick-or-treat!
( Laughing )
what can I do for--!
Oh! oh, no! No!
( Screaming )
( Laughing )
huh?
Can we have candy now?
What's the matter
with you kids?
That was the scariest
thing you've ever seen, right?
Well, have you seen...
This?
( Comedic screaming )
guts! Very real guts!
Uh... we've been
watching horror movies
since we were, like,
two years old.
Yeah, we're not scared.
Oh, you will be.
You will be.
( Overlapping chatter )
For glory,
my children! Charge!
You make a great me.
No, you make a great me!
No, you do! Heh heh!
I don't understand why
we can't just buy our
candy and be done with it.
That sort of
takes the fun out of
"trick-or-treat or die."
I'm trying to
take the "die" out of
"trick-or-treat or die."
( Doorbell rings )
all: Trick-or-treat!
Well, aren't you
just the cutest!
And is everyone
in costume?
Oh, good!
Wonderful!
happy summerween!
Trick-or-treat!
And is everybody in costume?
Chimney sweep,
elephant man,
squeegee, ant farm.
Oh, and what are you
supposed to be?
Uh, actually, I'm not
dressed up as anything.
We-- we're kind of
in a hurry here.
Oh. I see.
В™єв™є
enjoy!
One piece of black licorice?
Circus peanut!
This is loser candy!
Four pieces of candy?
This is gonna take forever.
We've gotta
up our game, Dipper.
You gotta
put on your costume.
I told you, I'm not
up to it, Mabel.
Oh, really?
В™єв™є
hmm.
I've seen better.
Tick tock.
( Blows )
So, what was that
about being too sick
to wear a costume?
( Sighs )
Both: we want candy!
We want candy!
All right,
you got me, kids.
You guys win.
I guess I'm not
that scary, you know?
You've-- you--
oh, no!
( Screaming and squealing )
Why? why is there a pig
jumping out of my chest?
Candy.
can-Dee!
What scares
you two freaks?
Here, watch this.
What? what is this,
some kind of--
some kind of kitten or...?
Aah, aah, aah!
( Both laughing )
( Gasping )
What happened to you,
Stan pines?
What happened?
Introducing, for the first
time in public...
В™є tah-dah! В™є
peanut butter and jelly!
Both: awww!
I will make you
Internet-famous!
Hey, erase that.
Let's just get this
over with, okay?
All:
over with! Over with!
( Doorbell rings )
do you really think
this will make a difference?
( Man grunts )
В™є tah tah tah,
tah-tah-tah-tah в™є
в™є twins! В™є
в™єв™є
( both laughing )
Let's get that candy, guys!
Thirty-four...
thirty-five...
Thirty-six.
You see? Because...
Yeah, I get it.
Twenty-two, twenty-three,
twenty-four...
A hundred and twenty-four!
( Blows )
Come on, come on!
( Doorbell rings )
Hello!
( All shriek )
what a horrible mask!
That's just my face.
This is a mask!
Ohhh!
( Overlapping chatter )
Soos: It's actually better.
Urr...!
( Doorbell rings )
Four ninety-eight,
four ninety-nine!
We did it!
( All celebrating )
All we need is one more
piece of candy.
And it's only 8:30.
Perfect timing!
Yeah, and your cough
went away, too!
Dude, I'm gonna go around
and grab the truck.
Soos away!
Last one to the final house
is a pair of wax lips!
Not me! No!
Ah!
The perfect time
to go to Wendy's party,
and no one needs to know
i was trick-or-treating.
( Panicky gasping )
Hey, Dipper!
Oh, hey, Wendy.
What's up?
Are you coming
to the party?
What are you doin'
out here?
Oh, I'm--
I'm on my way.
I like watching
the trick-or-treaters.
Reminds me of when
i was a kid.
Okay, then.
You're coming, right?
Definitely, definitely.
Cool. see ya there.
Later, guys.
You're going to a party.
Well-- well, hey, i--
aah!
That's why you were
acting so weird
and trying to hurry us.
You're not sick at all,
so if it wasn't for
this crazy monster,
you were gonna ditch me...
On our favorite holiday!
( Both gasp )
What happened to the Dipper
who used to love Halloween?
And where's all the candy?
Relax, relax.
I left it right here,
behind this bush.
Oh, no!
( All gasping )
What did you do?
Well, i-- i--!
Uh... guys?
Mabel: oh, no!
All the Jack-o'-melons
are out!
Look!
Heh heh heh!
Good night!
( Inhaling )
( All gasp )
stop!
What?
No, no, no, no, no!
Don't, don't, don't!
Huh? what's happening?
Just don't blow out
that candle.
What?!
Don't blow out
that candle!
I'm old man mcgucket!
( Inhales )
wait!
Sorry!
( Monkey-like sounds )
Whoo, that was close.
( All sigh )
Uh-oh.
Knock-knock.
So, children...
Where's my candy?
I swear, we had
all 500 pieces!
Look, it's
down there somewhere.
We can still get it.
I'm afraid it's too late!
That was your last chance.
( Audibly exerts )
( Laughing )
Go! go, go, go!
( Sinister laughter )
( Shrieking )
Aah! Dipper!
Mabel!
( Monstrous laughter )
( Shrieking )
We're alive! Yeah!
( Tires squeal )
Whoa!
Soos!
That wasn't, like,
a regular pedestrian,
was it?
It was the monster.
Thanks, Soos.
I'm just glad it's over.
Right?
Did everyone remember
to put on their seatbelts?
Yes.
yes.
Let's go.
Hey, are you okay?
There are probably
some bandages back
at the shack.
Uh...
Guys?
Raaahhh!
( All screaming )
( Sinister laughter )
Brakes, brakes, brakes!
( Tires squealing )
( All shouting )
( Coughing, then gasping )
We have to hide!
It's blocking
the only exit.
Everyone stay quiet.
Oh, now you're worried
about the monster!
I thought all you
cared about was Wendy.
Mabel, you know
that's not true.
I just-- I felt like I was
getting a little too old
to go trick-or-treating.
That's exactly why we need
to go trick-or-treating,
Dipper.
We're getting older.
There's not that many
halloweens left.
( Sighs )
I guess I didn't realize
it was already our last one.
( Monstrous roar )
We have to escape.
What if it sees us?
If only there was something
we could use to cover
our bodies and faces with--
you know, like a disguise
of some kind.
( Monstrous breathing )
This way!
Almost there!
Soos!
Stop!
Soos, don't you dare!
Sorry, dude, today's
been way stressful.
I need some levity.
( Silence )
Oh, thank goodness.
It was out of batteries.
Soos! no!
( Gasps )
( Audibly straining )
No matter the score,
I'm always "a head"!
( Cackling )
( Guffaws )
this cackling head's
the voice of a generation.
Wha--?
( Cackling )
Hey, monster!
Hiyah!
Aaahhhh!
( Audibly exerts )
Salt water Taffy?
Gross!
What are you--?
Wait, it is!
You really haven't
figured it out yet?
Aah!
( Crying out )
Don't you recognize me?
Look at my face.
Look closely.
( Both gasp )
loser candy!
That's right.
Did you ever stop and think
about the candy
at the bottom of the bag
that no one likes?
Every year, the children
of gravity falls
throw away all
of the rejected candy
into the dump.
So I seek revenge--
revenge on the picky
children who cast me aside.
I'm made of every tossed
piece of black licorice,
every discarded bar
of old chocolate
with, like, that
white powder stuff on it.
You know that stuff?
I hate that stuff!
No one would eat me!
But now, I'm going
to eat you!
Aaahhh!
I'm gonna eat... ohh!
What is that?
( Groaning )
'Sup, bro?
( Shrieking )
( Groans )
Mm. dudes, you want
some of this?
Wait. you actually
think I taste good?
Uh, sure. You know.
All I've ever wanted
is for someone to say
that I was good.
( Weak laughter )
I'm so happy!
The crying makes it
a little weird, but...
I guess I'm still eating.
'Sup, gorney?
I've been "twaumatized"!
В™єв™є
now what?
Let's get our candy already.
Old dude! Old dude!
Ahh.
Wash off the shame, Stan,
wash off the shame.
Ha! he thought
he could scare us!
( Both gasp )
Heh? what's that?
( Both screaming )
( Triumphal laughter )
Still got it.
Hey, Stan.
Hi, uncle Stan.
Hello, Mr. pines.
How's it hangin'?
Hey, Dipper.
Wendy!
i didn't see you
at the party.
Where where you?
Uh, I, uh...
I was trick-or-treating...
With my sister.
Yeah.
Mm. party was lame,
anyway.
Robbie ate a lollipop
stick first and had
to go home sick.
( Snickering )
aw, man.
We went to every
single house,
and we didn't even
get to eat any candy!
Candy?
How's that for candy!
And now back to
the fear guy from
terror town street!
( Comical screams )
You know, kids,
i been thinking--
at the end of the day,
summerween isn't about candy,
or costumes,
or even scary people.
It's a day when
the whole family
can get together
in one place
and celebrate
what really matters--
pure evil!
( Sinister laughter )
( All laughing )
( Sudden silence )
i ate a man alive tonight.
( Oinking softly )
( Camera shutter clicks )
( Laughter )
( Dolly parton singing
"nine to five" )