TV:
ladies and gentlemen,
we now return to...
Sponsored by...
They taste
just like chips!
( Game show music plays )
Congratulations!
you're taking a....
Cash shower!
Ha ha ha ha!
I like that guy's style.
Mr. pines!
We got tourists
at nine o'clock!
A whole busload of 'em!
( Goat bleats )
Hot tamales!
It's a jackpot!
Soos, make some new
attractions!
You got it, boss.
( Muttering )
Wendy, Mark up those prices!
The higher, the better!
Stan: higher!
Bleed 'em dry!
Sheesh, grunkle Stan,
it's like when you
look at tourists
all you see are
wallets with legs.
That's not true.
Thanks for taking me
to the mystery shack, daddy.
Ha ha! Now,
don't spend yourself
all in one place.
I'm feeling car sick.
Breahhh!
Clean-up on the front lawn!
( Sighs )
В™єв™є
( ding )
( Sighs )
Stan:
ladies and gentletourists,
looking around my mystery shack,
you'll see many wondrous
roadside attractions.
Be amazed at
the only known photo
of a horse riding
another horse.
That's--that's pretty good.
Ooh!
wow!
Be astounded
by the horrible
pre-teen wolf boy!
Oh, look at him!
All that hair!
His body is changing!
Aaah!
Grunkle Stan,
this is demeaning.
What?! I don't know
"da meaning" of that word.
( All guffaw )
If you throw money at him
he dances.
All: whoo!
Ow! hey!
( Whimpering )
Ha ha ha! Ooh!
Ha ha! Thank you!
Behold! mystery shack
bumper stickers!
You can stick 'em
on your bumper or...
Over your husband's mouth.
Am I right, ladies?
She knows what
I'm talkin' about.
Ha ha ha ha!
You arebad.
How much?
Hey, it's on the house.
That's the Mabel difference.
Thanks for visiting!
What?!
What the heck do you
think you're doing?
Business!
ching, ching, ching!
Listen, kid,
you don't make money
by giving stuff away.
You're off of
register duty!
But--but--
no "buts" except
yours out the door!
Now shut your yap
and get to work!
Grunkle Stan,
whatever happened
to "please" and "thank you"?
Hmm? oh, wait.
Here they are!
Lop lop!
Ha ha!
Huh!
"Please" never made me
any money, kid.
In fact,
just saying the word
is giving me
a burning sensation.
Grunkle Stan,
why do I have to
wear this wolf costume?
I think
I'm getting hookworm.
Ha ha! Yep, gluing
dog hair to your body
will do that.
You have all these
dumb fake exhibits
in the shack.
Meanwhile, I've seen
actual amazing things
in the forest every day.
What if you hunted down
arealattraction
instead of lying to people
for a living?
And you should be nicer
to your employees, too.
Yeah!
Look, you guys
got a problem with
how I run the shack,
take it up with
the complaints department.
Zing! ha ha ha!
I am going to write them
sucha letter!
And don't stop till
you've covered that sign
with glitter!
Glittery signs
attract tourists!
Also large birds.
( Cawing )
aaah! Aaah!
Ha ha! That's funny.
Okay, is it just me,
or is having grunkle Stan
as a boss seriously the worst?
I know, right?
Why do we even
put up with it?
I tried to give him
a suggestion to improve
the shack once.
I had this idea
where I could be, like,
the mystery shack mascot--
"questiony the question Mark."
I ask people questions,
you know,
do the question dance...
That sounds amazing!
Oh, cool!
Yeah, totally!
Yeah, well, Stan said
i couldn't handle it.
He saidwhat?!
And remember, folks,
we put the "fun"
in "no refunds"!
Ha ha! Suckers.
You!
Grunkle Stan, you've gone
too far this time!
Did you seriously
tell Soos not to follow
his hopes and dreams
because he
"couldn't handle it"?
Look, kid, let me
break it down for you.
Being a boss is about
commanding respect.
If you give people
everything they ask for,
they'll walk all over ya.
No way! I bet you'd make
way more money being nice
than being a big, grumpy grump
to everyone all the time.
Ha! you think you know
more about business
than I do?
You thinkyou
could wear this hat?
Yeah, because
i give people respect.
And glittery stickers.
Ha! I'd make more money
on vacation than you would
running this place!
Then why don't you
goon vacation?
Interesting. all right,
I'm a wagering man.
Three days. 72 hours.
You run the shack,
and I'll go on vacation.
If you make more money than me,
I guess it means you're right
about the way I run my business.
Butif you lose,
you gotta wear
this "loser" shirt
all summer. Ha ha!
Fine! but ifiwin,
i get to be the boss
for the rest of the summer!
Plus, you have to sing
an apologizing song
with lyrics by me, Mabel.
Oh ho! You got
yourself a deal, missy!
No, you got
yourselfa deal!
Deal! deal!
Deal! Deal!
Deal.
See you in 72 hours! Ha ha!
We'll see who makes
more money.
Uh!
( Stan laughing )
Mabel, did you just
make a bet with
a professional con man?
Oh, come on. Being
a better boss than Stan
will be a cinch.
Profits, here we come!
( Shatters )
you broke the jar.
We'll get a new one.
I guess I shouldn't
betooworried.
I mean, how much money could
Stan even make on vacation?
Can I help you, sir?
I'm here to take
all the cash from your wheel.
You wanted to see us,
Mr. pines?
Stan is no longer with us.
He's dead?! No!
It should have been me!
Whoa, Soos.
Stan's not dead.
He's on vacation
for three days.
We made a bet.
Thank you for
that clarification.
Mabel's in charge now!
Are those
shoulder pads?
Uh-huh!
It's just one of the many
up-to-date managerial tricks
I learned from this book
i found propping up
the kitchen table.
Why does your mug
say "#2"?
Because the real #1 isyou.
Yeah, I get it.
Morale!
Walk with me.
With me as boss,
you're gonna notice
a few changes around here.
My job is to help you be
your best "selves."
( Mabel reads list )
Great listening here
so far!
Ahh!
ahh!
Ho ho! Ha ha!
Waddles, hold my calls.
( Squeals )
All right, people,
now rap with me.
Wendy, how can I make
your workspace more
Wendy-friendly?
Hmm. well, Stan never lets me
hang out with friends at work.
Stan ain't here, sister!
Door's open!
Sweet!
and Soos,
I believethisis yours.
Questiony the question Mark?
I wish this was
an exclamation point
to show how excited I am.
As for you, Dipper...
Die, wolf costume, die!
I want you to head into those
woods and don't come back
until you've found
an amazing attraction!
Finally! time to show Stan how
arealmystery hunter does it!
( Grunting )
Dipper out!
Ahh! ( crash )
Okay, guys, it's time to prove
that nice bosses finish first.
In the next 48 hours,
we're gonna fill up this jar
with six hundred
billion dollars!
Yeah!
yeah!
Wait. do you know
how money works?
Of course. Waddles,
run down to the shop
and grab me a latte.
( Squeals )
(Laughs) he's
a hungry little guy.
( Chatter )
Ahh. this line
is taking forever.
Time to use
my old man powers.
Aaah! I'm having
a heart attack!
And the only cure is to be
a contestant on--
oncash wheel!
Oh! someone give me a part!
I'm old
should we escort him
off the lot?
That man is a self-centered
attention hog
with no regard
for human decency.
Get him on TV!
В™є whoa, yeah, come on girl в™є
в™є shoulder pads в™є
в™є make that money в™є
в™є Mabel's the boss now в™є
в™є walk in, girl в™є
в™є show them boys в™є
в™є make that money... в™є
time cards.
Time cards.
Boss, boss, boss,
boss, boss!
It's beautiful!
Man: wow, this is
some freak show you got.
Thank you!
See you soon!
Tell 'em Mabel sent you!
Mabel,
i captured something!
( Growling )
this is gonna blow
those tourists away!
Ha ha ha!--Aah!
Aah! aah!
Marvelous work,
valued employee.
Oh! who'sthat?
Is it questiony
the question Mark?
Ah, I'm starting
to have second thoughts
about this, Mabel.
I keep forgetting
my lines,
and this costume
is more, uh, revealing
than I expected.
Soos, don't give up.
Anything is possible
when you...
"Imaginize it."
But I don't know
what that means.
Shh!
Shh...
Believein yourself.
But--but i--
( wind whistles )
oh, so--so cold.
How's my favorite Wendy?
( Laughter )
Yeah. okay, all right.
No. Look out. Look out.
Yeah!
keep it goin'!
Oh, what's this?
( Sobbing )
Billy!
Your face!
It's ruined!
I'm so sorry.
Please, have a refund.
Wendy, you've got
a lot of cleaning up to do.
Please?
Whoa. all this rule stuff
is starting to make you
sound like Stan.
What?! no,
I'm nothing like Stan!
In fact, take the rest
of the day off.
With full pay?
Of course.
Ha ha ha. Ha ha ha.
Mabel pines, you are
the best boss ever.
I'm questiony
the question Mark!
Aaah!
Aaah! oh, don't!
It stings so bad!
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to...
All:cash wheel!
Now let's meet
those contestants.
I'm Doug,
from Fairfield, California.
I'm Donna, from--
I'm Stan! Stan pines!
Ha ha!
Did we--did we already do me?
Hello? I'm Stan!
Heh heh. Okay.
Well, it's gonna be
a long night, folks.
( Audience laughs )
It's time to solve--
(Stan laughs loudly)
Ha ha ha ha!
It's, uh, time to
solve that puzzle.
Carla.
yes, rich?
Are there any "s's"?
Actually, it's not
your turn yet--
( ching ching )
I'm ready to solve!
No. The game hasn't started.
Is it "shut your yaps"?
( Audience applauds )
Well played.
Cash shower, cash shower,
cash shower...
Announcer:
cash shower!
Yes! в™є da da doo в™є
Mr. pines--
no--you don't need
to take your clothes off--
no--go to commercial.
Go to commercial!
Dipper:
ladies and gentlemen--
my name's honest Dipper,
and, unlike my cheating uncle,
I have something to show you
thatisn'ta hoax.
It nearly killed me
getting him into that cage.
Behold: part gremlin,
part goblin--
the gremloblin!
( Growling )
( Roars )
Well,that'sfun.
It's fake, honey.
You can see the strings.
What?! those aren't strings!
That's body hair!
Ah, look at this, dear.
The six-pack-o-lope.
Ha ha! Wordplay!
No! everythingelse
here is fake!
This is areal
paranormal beast.
Hey! fun fact about
this little guy:
You look into his eyes,
you can see your
worst nightmare.
Amazing, right?
I work for tips.
( Siren wailing )
( Both whimpering )
Thanks again
for visiting!
( Sighs )
Thanks for
shopping with us.
I'll get that!
( Laughing )
Here ya go.
Sorry! have refunds!
That's the Mabel difference!
Ohh!
Well, I just made
two people go insane.
How about you?
I'm so tired.
I gave Wendy the day off,
so I had to doherjob.
Well, maybe you need to start
being a little bit tougher
around here.
No way! That's what
Stan would do!
I just need to
think positive,
be friendly,
and everything
will work out fine.
( Creature roars )
( All screaming )
What? how did he get out
of his locked cage?!
Well...
Huh?
You gave him abreak?!
He's an employee!
Sort of.
We gotta round him up.
Where's Soos?
He was stressed out,
so I told him to take
a soothing nature walk.
Hello? civilization?
( Wind howls,
thunder rumbles )
( Howling )
Doggy?
( Roaring )
( Crashing )
Ladies and gentlemen,
Stan pines is poised
to become our grand champion!
Anything to say to
your fans out there?
See you tomorrow night,
Mabel!
Ha ha ha ha!
( Creature roars )
( Mabel shrieking )
Mmm!
What do we do?!
He's awarding himself stickers
that he didn't even earn!
Uh, got it. "When fighting
a gremloblin, use water...
"...only as a last resort,
as water will make him
much, much scarier."
Aah! who writes
sentences like that?!
( Cuckoo clock strikes )
Cuckoo.
Don't worry. He's gotta
leave eventually.
В™є I'm the singin' salmon
spendin' all day jammin' в™є
в™є I'm the singin' salmon
ohh! why doesn't he
just leave?
( Sniffs, growls )
Our profits!
Mabel, wait!
Stop! stop!
( Screaming )
Don't look into
his evil eye!
You'll see your
worst nightmare!
I wishwehad an evil eye
to showhim!
Oh, no!
Aahh....
Wait. hey, monster!
Take a look at this!
( Anguished roar )
( Whimpering )
Well, at least he didn't do
thatmuch damage.
( Car alarm wails )
Oh, boy.
Dipper, it's the third day.
We've only got seven hours
to earn back our profits
or I've gotta wear
that "loser" shirt
all summer!
Hey, guys. Am I nuts,
or does this place
look different?
Wendy! Soos!
Am I glad to see you.
We've got a lot of work to do,
but if we hurry,
we can still beat Stan!
Uh, yeah. I got
a little headache,
so maybe I should,
like,notwork today.
And I actually just met
this pack of wolves,
and I think they're gonna,
like, raise me as
one of their own?
So I should really be
at the den right now.
But--but--
but, hey,
we'll see you on Monday.
Uh, is anyone
gonna eat these?
Enough!!!
I havehadit!
I fought amonster
to save this business,
and this is how
you repay me?!
I'm gonna get an ulcer
from your lollygagging!
Lollygagging?
ulcer?
You're acting...
Different.
You shut your yaps!
I've been doing
everyone's jobs
while you've both
been bleeding me dry!
But--
no "buts" except yours
on the floor, cleaning!
Now quit loafing
and get to work!
Yes, Mabel.
That's "yes,boss."
( Gasps )
Dipper! what have I become?
What you had to, Mabel...
What you had to.
We've got seven hours
to turn this around!
Let's go, people!
You landed on "cash flood"!
Ha ha ha ha!
I'm givin' none of this
to charity!
And now you can go home
a thousandaire...
Or you could risk everything
to double your money
with the bonus word!
( Siren wails )
Rich, I'm a simple man.
So I'm gonna take my winnings,
pack my bags, and...
Bet them all on the bonus word!
( Cheers, applause )
come on!
Time is money, hardhats!
You got complaints,
file 'em with
the complaint department!
Ohh! my back!
Dipper! we got tourists
at nine o'clock!
What do I show them?
Real magic just
freaks people out.
Figure something out,
knucklehead!
Dipper:
ladies and gentletourists,
this shack is filled with
wonders never before seen
by human eyes!
Behold: the horrible
giant question baby!
Am I a man?
Am I a baby?
These are legitimate questions.
( All gasp )
Have your picture taken
with it for a buck.
Uh, ten bucks.
A hundred bucks!
( All clamoring )
We put the fun
in "no refunds."
How'd we do?
We filled
the whole jar!
( All cheering )
Minus the money to replace
all the furniture
and supplies to fix the shack,
that leaves us..
One dollar.
( Door opens )
Tick-tock! time's up, kids!
Oh, no!
Nice to see you learned
how to dress while I was gone.
How much did you
beat us by?
I won $300,000!
And then...
For a chance to
double your cash
or lose it all,
what is a six-letter word
you use to ask for something
politely?
For example,
"may I (blank) Have that?"
Do I look like
an idiot, folks?
( Laughter )
The word is "gimmee."
Two e's.
( Buzzer )
Oooh! you know,
because you've gone this far,
we're gonna give you
one more chance.
Let's try again.
It's a "p" word.
Some might even say
it's the "magic word."
Abracadabra!
final answer!
( Buzzer )
I'm sorry, Stan,
but the word is...
"Please."
Apparently that word
canmake you money.
So, wait. If you
lost everything,
then that means--
Mabel! You won!
Whoo!
we did it!
Wait. what do we win
again?
Well, according to our bet,
I guess Mabel's the new boss?
All: no! No!
Don't do that!
Huh? What?
Grunkle Stan,
i had no idea how hard
it was being boss.
This place was cuckoo bananas
until I started barking orders
at people like you.
Yeah, well, I got to admit,
it's kind of nice
to be back, ya know?
Okay, okay, that's enough,
get offa me!
And Soos, Wendy...
Get to work!
Ahem. please.
Uhh! Still hurts.
Mabel, didn't
your agreement say
something about
Stan having to do
some kind of apology dance
if he lost?
N-no. no, it didn't.
Actually, yeah,
I think I have it
in my notes here.
No! that never happened!
Ha ha! I'll get the camera!
All right, let me just--
huhh!
Grunkle Stan!
Uhh. look, I'm not gonna--
Mabel: do it!
В™є I'm Stan,
and I was wrong в™є
в™є I'm singing
"the Stan wrong song" в™є
в™є I shouldn't have
taken that chance в™є
в™є now here's my
remorseful dance в™є
do the kicks!
( Grunting )
Jazzier!
Hey, gimme that!
Stan: ow! My back!
What doyouthink?
( Squeals )
Take thirty!