For tonight's final illusion,
we have
the incredible sack of mystery.
When you put your money in,
it mysteriously disappears!
Oh, of course!
That makes perfect sense!
Wow! what a nice man!
That was totally
worth the drive!
The tiger was badly injured
in the explosion,
but we repaired him...
With a fist!
( Gong chimes )
( All cheer )
That tiger is a hero!
Hey, look, it's that commercial
i was telling you guys about.
Are you completely miserable?
( Crying ) yes!
Then you need to meet...
Gideon?
what makes him so special?
He's a psychic.
A-roo?
So don't waste
your time with
other so-called
men of mystery.
( Roars )
Learn about
tomorrow tonight
at Gideon's
tent of telepathy!
Void where prohibited,
no c.O.D.'S accepted,
Carla, I've always loved you,
but I've never had the guts
to say it.
Wow! I'm gettin'
all curious-y inside!
Well, don't get too curious-y!
Ever since that monster Gideon
rolled into town,
I've had nothing but trouble!
( Tires screech, horn honks )
( All cheering )
Gideon!
Well,
is he really psychic?
I think we should go
and find out.
Never! you are forbidden from
patronizing the competition!
No one that
lives under my roof
is allowed under
that Gideon's roof!
Do tents have roofs?
I think we just
found our loophole...
Literally! mwop-mwop!
So come down soon, folks.
Gideon is expecting you.
В™єв™є
step right up there, folks!
Put your money in
Gideon's psychic sack!
Oh, sure!
That makes perfect sense!
Whoa, this is like
a bizarro version
of the mystery shack.
They even have
their own Soos!
It's starting!
В™єв™є
let's see what
this monster looks like.
Hello, America!
My name is lil' Gideon!
( Cheering and applause )
That's Stan's mortal enemy?
But he's so... "Widdle."
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is such a gift
to have you here tonight!
Such a gift!
I have a vision.
I predict you'll
soon all say, "aw!"
All: aw!
It came true!
What? I'm not impressed.
You're impressed.
Hit it, dad!
В™єв™є
aah!
( All screaming )
В™є oh, I can see
what others can't see в™є
в™є it ain't some sideshow trick,
it's innate ability в™є
в™є where other's are blind,
i am future-ly inclined в™є
в™є and you too could see
if you was "widdle" ol' me в™є
come on, everybody, rise up!
I want y'all to keep it going!
How did he...?
Keep it going!
В™є you wish your son
would call you more в™є
I'm leaving everything
to my cats!
( Screeches )
В™є I sense that you've
been here before в™є
what gave it away?
Come on.
В™є I'll read your mind,
if I'm able в™є
( all clapping )
В™є something tells me
you're named Mabel в™є
how'd he do that?!
So welcome all ye в™є
в™є to the tent of telepathy в™є
в™є and thanks
for visiting... в™є
в™є "widdle" ol' me в™є
( panting )
oh, my goodness.
( Cheering and applause )
Thank you!
You people
are the real miracles!
Whoo! yeah!
Man, that kid's an even
bigger fraud than Stan!
No wonder
our uncle's jealous!
Oh, come on,
his dance moves were adorable!
And did you see his hair?
It was like whoosh!
You're too easily impressed.
Yeah, yeah!
( Both laugh )
Check it out, Dipper!
I successfully
bezazzled my face!
Blink!
Ow.
Is that permanent?
I'm unappreciated in my time.
( Doorbell rings )
Stan: somebody answer the door!
I'll get it!
Howdy!
It's "widdle" ol' you!
( Chuckles )
yeah, my song's quite catchy.
I know
we haven't formally met,
but after
yesterday's performance,
I just couldn't get
your laugh out of my head!
You mean this one?
( Laughs )
Oh, what a delight!
When I saw you in the audience,
i said to myself,
"now there's a kindred spirit,
someone who appreciates
the sparkly things in life."
That's totally me!
( Laughs )
( Coughs )
Enchanting.
utterly enchanting.
Stan: who's at the door?!
No one, grunkle Stan!
I appreciate your discretion.
Stan's no fan of mine.
I don't know how
a lemon so sour
could be related
to a peach so sweet.
Gideon! ( chuckles )
What do you say we step away
from here and chat a bit more?
Perhaps in my
dressing room?
Oh, makeovers!
( Cheers )
( Chuckles ) ow.
Do you see something you like?
'Cause I do.
( Chuckles ) what?
Hey, Dipper, what's going on?
Whoa, where have you been?
And what's going on
with those fingernails?
You look like a Wolverine.
I know, right?!
( Roars )
I was hanging out
with my new pal Gideon!
He is one
dapper little man!
Mabel, I don't trust anyone
whose hair is bigger
than their head.
Oh, leave him alone!
You never wanna
do girly stuff with me.
You and Soos get to do
boy stuff all the time.
What do you mean?
Hey, dude, you ready to blow up
these hot dogs in the microwave,
one by one?!
Am I?!
( Microwave beeps )
( Both laugh )
Dipper: one at a time!
One at a time!
Whoa, the view from
your family's factory is nuts!
Good thing
we both brought our...
Both: opera glasses!
( Both laugh )
Mabel, when I'm up here,
looking down on all them
little ol' people,
I feel like
I'm king of all I survey.
I guess that
makes you my queen.
What?! you are being so nice
to me right now! Quit it!
I can't quit it.
I'm speaking from the heart.
From the where now?
Mabel, I've never felt
this close with anyone.
So, so close...
( Chuckles )
Look, Gideon, I, um...
I like you a lot,
but let's just be friends.
At least
just give me a chance.
Mabel, will you do me the honor
of going on a date with me?
A play date?
Mm-mmm.
A shopping date?
It'll just be
one little ol' date.
I swear on my lucky bolo tie.
Um...
Okay then...
I guess.
Mabel pines, you have made me
the happiest boy in the world!
Are you sniffing my hair?
It's not a date-date.
It's just, you know,
i didn't want to hurt
his feelings,
and so I figured
I'd throw him a bone.
Mabel,
guys don't work that way.
He's gonna
fall in love with you.
Pfft! yeah, right.
I'm not that lovable.
Kaboom! yes!
Okay, we agree
on something here.
( Doorbell rings )
( Neighs )
( Screams )
A night of enchantment awaits,
milady!
Oh, boy.
В™єв™є
I can't believe they let us
bring a horse in here.
Well, people have a hard time
saying no to me.
Ah, Mr. Gideon!
The feet on the table!
An excellent choice!
Jean-Luc, what did we discuss
about eye contact?
Yes, yes! Very good!
I've never seen so many forks!
And water with bubbles in it?
Ooh-la-la! Oui oui!
Oh, parlais-vous francais? *
I have no idea
what you're saying.
Hey! hey! What the Jekyll
is Mabel doing in the paper
next to that
greasy pickpocket Gideon?!
Oh, yeah, it's like a big deal.
Everybody's talking about Gideon
and Mabel's big date tonight.
What?! that little shyster
is dating my great-niece?!
I wonder what the new name
will be for the power couple.
Mab-ideon? gide-Abel?
( Gasps ) ma-gid-bel-eon!
I didn't know!
I didn't hear about it!
And plus, I told her not to!
Yeah, well, it ends tonight!
I'm going right down
to that little skunk's house!
This is going to stop right now!
Dude, wouldn't it be funny
if that was a closet
and he had to come out again
and walk out the real door?
( Bell dings )
Nope. real door.
( Tires screech )
Gideon, you little punk!
Open up!
I will pardon nothing!
Why, Stanford pines,
what a delight!
Out of the way, bud,
I'm looking for Gideon.
Well, I haven't
seen the boy around,
but since you're here,
you simply must come in
for coffee!
But-but I came--
it's imported
all the way from Columbia!
Wow...
i went to jail there once!
( Whistles )
some digs you got here.
Oh, this.
This is beautiful.
Now, I hear your niece
and my Gideon are...
Well, they're singing
in Harmony lately, so to speak.
Uh, yeah, and I'm against it!
Neh!
No, no, no, I see it as a
fantastic business opportunity!
Yes, the mystery shack
and the tent of telepathy!
We've been at each other's
throats for far too--
let me get that--
at each other's throats
for far too long!
Yes, we have!
This is our big chance
to brush aside our rivalry
and pool our
collective profits, you see.
( Cash register dings )
I'm listening.
And so I said, "autograph
your own headshot, lady!"
( Laughs )
Uh, yeah.
Mabel, tonight's date
was a complete success,
and tomorrow's date promises
to top this one in every way!
Whoa, whoa,
you said just one date,
and this was it!
Hark! what a surprise!
A red crested south American
rainbow macaw!
Aah!
Two, three, four...
Mabel... will... you...
Accompany... Gideon... to...
The... ballroom... dance...
This... "Thurbday"...
Thursday! kaw!
Aw, so adorable!
Gideon's got a girlfriend!
They're expecting us.
Please say you'll go.
All: aw!
Gideon, I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna have to say--
I'm on the edge
of my seat!
This is gonna be adorable!
If she says no,
I'll die from sadness!
I can verify that
that will indeed happen.
( All talking )
Hey! how'd it go?
I don't know.
I have a lobster now.
Well, at least it's over
and you won't ever have
to go out with him again.
Mabel? it's over, right?
Mabel?
Blargh! he asked me out again
and I didn't know how to say no!
Like this: "No."
It's not that easy, Dipper!
And I do like Gideon--
as a friend/little sister.
So I didn't want
to hurt his feelings.
I just need to get things back
to where they used to be--
you know, friends.
Boatin' at night!
( Laughs )
You know, I thought dancing
was going to be the end
of the evening. Right?
Don't you want this evening
to last, my sweet?
No! I mean, yes.
I mean, I'm always happy
to hang out with a friend.
Buddy. pal. Chum.
Other word for friend.
Pal?
i already said pal.
Uh, mate?
How about soulmate?
Well, you can't say no to that!
He's so nice!
But I can't keep doing this!
But I can't break his heart!
Aah! I have no way out!
What in the heck
happened on that date?
I don't know!
I was in the friend zone!
And then, before I knew
what was happening,
he pulled me
into the romance zone!
It was like quicksand!
Chubby quicksand!
Mabel, come on.
It's not like you're
gonna have to marry Gideon.
Great news, Mabel!
You have to marry Gideon!
What?!
it's all part of my long-term
deal with buddy gleeful!
There's a lot of cash
tied up in this thing.
Plus, I got this shirt!
Ugh, I am fat.
( Screams )
Bodies change, honey.
Bodies change.
Oh, no. Mabel?
Mabel's not here.
She's in sweater town.
Are you gonna come out
of sweater town?
Mm.
All right, enough is enough.
If you can't
break up with Gideon,
then I'll do it for you.
You will?
Oh, thank you,
thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you!
В™єв™є
( clears throat )
Oh! Dipper pines, how are you?
You look good, you look good.
Thanks. you, uh...
Look, Gideon,
we've gotta talk.
Mabel isn't
joining you tonight.
She doesn't want
to see you anymore.
She's kind of
weirded out by you.
No offense.
So what you're saying is...
You've come between us.
You're not gonna, like...
Freak out or anything, are you?
( Chuckles )
of course not!
These things happen.
Bygones, you know.
So, okay, cool.
Well, then again, sorry, man...
But, uh, hey, thumbs up, huh?
Thumbs up, indeed, my friend.
How did it go? Was he mad?
Did he try to read your mind
with his psychic powers?
Don't worry, Mabel.
He's just a kid.
He doesn't have any powers.
( Breathing deeply )
Dipper pines, you don't know
what you've done!
You've just made the
biggest mistake of your life!
( Grunts )
Gideon Charles gleeful!
Clean up your room
this instant!
I can buy and sell you,
old man!
Fair enough.
Hit me, dude!
( Grunts )
( Laughs ) ow.
Feels good.
I'm so glad
everything's back to normal.
( Phone rings )
Your turn.
Your turn. Oh, man.
( Phone rings )
Hello?
Toby determined,
gravity falls gossiper!
Oh, hey, man.
Sorry for accusing you
of murder last week.
Water under the bridge!
Say, we want to interview you
about whether you've seen
anything unusual
in this here town
since you've arrived!
Oh, finally!
I thought nobody would ever ask!
I have notes and theories!
Uh-huh. uh-huh.
412 gopher road.
Uh, tonight? Got it.
There. I did your dirty work!
Now it's time to pay
your end of the bargain.
( Gasps )
Sandra jimenez's phone number!
Bless you, lil' Gideon!
( Echoing ) hello?
Hello, friend.
Gideon...
Dipper pines, how long have you
been living in this town?
A week? Two?
You like it here?
Enjoy the scenery?
What do you want from me, man?
Listen carefully, boy.
This town has secrets
you couldn't begin
to comprehend.
Is this about Mabel?
I told you, she's not into you!
Liar!
you turned her against me!
She was my peach dumpling!
Are you okay, man?
( Gasps )
( Groans )
( Squeaks )
howdy!
Reading minds
isn't all I can do!
But-but you're fake!
Oh, tell me, Dipper...
Is this fake?
( Door opens )
How's that
hair tasting, buddy?
Wendy, I need some advice.
You've broken up
with guys, right?
Oh, yeah. Russ durham,
Eli hall, stony Davidson...
I don't know what's
wrong with me.
I thought everything
was back to normal,
but I still feel all gross.
Mike worley, Nate holts,
that guy with the tattoos...
Maybe letting Dipper
do it for me was a mistake.
Gideon deserves
an honest break-up.
Danny feldman,
Mark Epstein...
Oh, man, I'm not sure I ever
actually broke up with him.
No wonder
he keeps calling me!
I know what I gotta do.
Thanks for
talking to me, Wendy.
( Bell rings )
( Phone rings )
Ignore!
( Grunting )
( Laughs )
( Gasps )
Whoa! ( groans )
Grunkle Stan
was right about you!
You are a monster!
Your sister will be mine!
( Laughs )
Who's a cute little guy?
You are!
No, you are!
Aah!
( Grunts )
she's never gonna date you, man!
That's a lie!
And I'm gonna make sure
you never lie to me
again, friend.
( Grunts )
Gideon, we have to talk!
Mabel! my marshmallow!
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry, Gideon,
but I can't be your marshmallow.
I needed to be honest
and tell you that myself.
I... I don't understand.
Uh, Mabel, this probably
isn't the best time to be
brutally honest with him!
Hey, but we can still be
makeover buddies, right?
Wouldn't you like that?
Really?
No! not really!
You were like attacking
my brother! What the heck?!
My tie! Give it back!
Ha! not so powerful
without this, are you?
Dipper!
( Both screaming )
( Both grunting )
Listen, Gideon, it's over.
I will never, ever date you.
Yeah!
( both groan )
My powers!
Oh, this isn't over.
This isn't the last you'll see
of "widdle" ol' me.
Ah, this is livin', brother.
From now on,
it's all name brand foods
and clown paintings.
Well, hey, Gideon, look who i--
Stanford pines, I rebuke thee.
I rebuke thee!
Rebuke? is that a word?
The entire pines family
have invoked my fury!
You will all pay recompense
for your transgressions!
What, you got like a word-a-day
calendar or something?
B-but, sunshine,
what about our arrangement
with Mabel and the--
silence!
Well, I see he's taken
to one of his rages again.
Sorry, Stan. I have to side
with Gideon on this one.
Okay! okay!
I can see when I'm not wanted!
Stan, I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna need
that painting back. Stan! Stan!
Try and catch me, suckers!
( Sighs ) I could've had it all.
What the heck
happened to you two?
Gideon.
yeah, the little mutant
swore vengeance
on the whole family.
I guess he's gonna try to
nibble my ankles or something.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, how's he
gonna destroy us now, huh?
Try to guess what number
we're thinking of? ( Laughs )
He'll never guess
what number I'm thinking of.
Negative eight!
No one would guess
a negative number!
( All laugh )
Ooh, look out!
I bet he's planning
our destruction right now!
( All laugh )
( Imitating Mabel )
Gideon! I still love you!
If only my family
weren't in the way!
( Imitating Stan )
look at me, I'm old!
And I'm smelly!
( Imitating Dipper)
Hey, what are you gonna do
without your
precious amulet?
Oh, you'll see, boy.
You'll see...
You're done?
Not yet.
How about now?
Almost.
And there.
Let's do this.
В™єв™є
you're fired.