This is it, dudes--
my favorite place
in gravity falls.
Everything I know,
i learned right here.
A frog taught me how
to cross the street.
When my house was haunted,
i learned how to eat ghosts.
And this thing
taught me how to dance.
Whoo-hoo-hoo! ha ha!
I've been jiggin'
for seven days straight!
Uh, Soos?
( Laughing )
Let him have this.
What?
( Beeping )
**
( beeping )
( Groans )
Oh! oh, watch out!
Whoa! ooh, cut scene!
( Both grunting )
Yeah! yeah! Yeah!
Go! Yes! Yes!Ghs )
( Both grunting )
The winner...
What? you cheated.
You take that back! ( Laughs )
Round two!
I'm gonna punch the ref.
Dipper: let's gang up on him.
( Both grunting )
( Both laughing )
Wendy, what's up, babe?
Yeah, just puttin' up
some flyers for my band.
I'm lead guitar.
No biggie.
Are you wearing mascara?
Uh, it's eye paint for men.
Hi, Robbie. Dipper was just
showing me this great game.
Uh, yeah, sweet, sweet.
Hey, how's about you
sit this one out, okay, champ?
( Cracks knuckles )
But we just
started this round.
Whoa, whoa.
Hey, relax, man.
I'm just tryin'
to spend a little time
with my girlfriend, all right?
It'll just be one round.
**
so, hey, I'm going camping
tomorrow with my dad,
so I won't be around.
Oh, cool, cool. ( Grunts )
( Both laughing )
Opponent sighted! Fight!
**
king me!
A( laughs )!
It's not fair! She doesn't
even know what we're playing!
Go fish?
**
( rumbling )
Dude, I think I'm pickin' up
a radio station inside my head.
Try blinking to see
if you can change the channel.
( Grunting )
Robbie: * Wendy!
Ugh, sounds like Robbie.
Robbie? is he that jerky twerp
i see making goo-goo eyes
at Wendy all the time?
He called me "big dude" once.
I mean, I know I'm a big dude,
but it kinda hurt.
Should I sic
waddles on him again?
Whoa! easy, tiger.
I'll handle it.
All: ooh!
( Chuckles ) conflict!
* Wendy! Wendy, Wendy!
Wendy! come on out, girl!
Come on down!
You realize
she's not here, right?
( Scoffs ) yes.
What?
She's out camping
with her family today.
Maybe if you listened to her
for once, you'd know that.
What was that?
I just said she's not here.
No, no, no.
You wanna get into it, huh?
Let's get into it, kid.
You think I don't know
what's been goin' on, huh?
It's obvious you've got
a thing for my girlfriend.
Don't you? Don't you?
What?! no! Come on, man.
Yeah, I'm sure she's just dyin'
to ask out a 12-year-old kid
who wears the exact same
shorts every day.
Hey, here's an idea,
why don't I call her right now
and see if she wants
to go out on a date with you.
Hey! look! Don't!
Y-you don't have to--
"oh! don't! Please, man!"
What are you gonna do? Huh? Huh?
( Ringing )
Wendy: hello?
My phone!
I'll buy you
a new one!
Oh, no! You're not
gettin' off that easy!
Hey! I know a fight
when I see one!
Stay right there!
( Groans )
You, me, circle park, 3:00--
we finish this.
Aw, he's gone. I was just
gonna call the boys over
to place a few bets.
The smart money's
on skinny jeans.
( Sighs ) what was I thinking?!
I can't fight!
I've never been in
a fight before!
Look at these noodle arms!
Just bonk him over the head!
It's nature's snooze button!
Boys, why can't you learn
to hate each other in secret?
Like girls do.
Sure, listen to your sister.
( Chuckles )
maybe you can share dresses too!
( Laughs ) boom!
Maybe he'll just
forget about it.
Maybe it'll all blow over.
I don't know, Dipper.
Teenagers are dangerous.
Those hormones turn 'em in
to, like, killing machines.
Oh, yeah, dude.
My cousin Reggie
got in a fight with a teen once.
The guy broke, like,
all his arms, all his legs,
and I think killed him
or something. I didn't know.
Me and Reggie
were just talkin' about it.
( Panting )
I can't stay here!
What if Robbie comes back?!
I gotta hide!
Look, kid,
you got yourself a choice here.
You could either
go face him like a man,
or you could
hide indoors like a wimp.
What'll it be?
Wimp it is.
Come on, Soos,
Robbie's like twice my size!
I mean, what would getting
myself killed accomplish?
I just need to hide here
until 3:00 passes.
( Sighs )
this day will never end!
Relax, Dipper. Just try
not to think about Robbie.
( Gasps )
( Applause )
Girl, who you ackin'
so cray-cray?
( Cheers and applause )
...will be back
in a moment.
( Sighs ) poor Dipper...
Hiding from Robbie,
unable to face his fears.
( Grunts )
Fears are for chumps!
That's why I don't have any!
( Grunting )
You want me
to go get a ladder?
What?n't have one.
You know, studies show
that keepin' a ladder
inside the house
is more dangerous
than a loaded gun.
That's why I own ten guns,
in case some maniac
tries to sneak in a ladder.
Grunkle Stan,
why you ackin' so cray-cray?
You're the one
who's ackin' cray-cray!
I gotta go now.
Why would grunkle Stan
be so weirded out by ladders?
Of course! I think he has
a secret fear of heights!
( Grunts )
We'll have to test him
to be sure.
Or we could leave
well enough alone.
Nah!
**
man, I wonder what
it would be like to go inside
a video game for real.
I should've thought of this
years ago!
( Grunting )
Stupid Robbie, such a jerk!
( Beeping )
( Both grunting )
( Sighs ) that's easy
for you to say.
You have more than one life.
( Sighs )
I wish one of these guys
could fight Robbie for me.
Huh?
"To unleash ultimate power"?
I do like things
that are ultimate.
Back, back, hold,
forward, back, forward, down,
hold, quarter-circle,
forward, triple-punch!
I guess it didn't work.
( Rumbling )
Uh...
Soos?
Select your character!
Uh...
Rumble mcskirmish?
( Grunts )
You're real?
Both: high-five!
Ow! your pixels
are really sharp! Aah!
Greetings, child boy!
I am rumble mcskirmish
from the usa!
( Grunting )
Ow! cool!
Change machine!
Change me into a powerful wolf!
( Grunts )
With rumble around,
Robbie will be so scared
i won't even need to fight him.
I've got the world's
greatest fighter
to be my bodyguard!
( Beeping )
I need power-ups!
This is so amazing!
I gotta show Soos!
Soos?
( Gasps )
Help, I'm trapped in the game!
It was cool in theory,
but in practice
it was really boring.
( Screams )
It's not just a game anymore.
All right, waddles,
it's time to begin
operation get Stan
over his fear of heights!
( Grunts )
I came up with that name.
Happy great uncle's day!
Huh?
there's a great uncle's day?
( Chuckles ) of course
it's not a day I made up!
High heels?
You shouldn't have!
Seriously. w-what?
What is this?
What's wrong? Are you saying
these heels are too high?
Do they make you
uncomfortable? Hmm?
Admit it! Admit you have
a fear of heights!
What?! that's why
you bought me these?!
You should be
ashamed of yourself!
And on great uncle's day
no less!
But, no, I don't have
a fear of heights.
We now return to world's
most terrifying skydiving!
( Screams ) turn it off!
So I have a fear of heights.
Is that really so cray-cray?
( Buzzing )
( Grunting )
Well, we don't have
any traditional power-ups--
Turkey legs, pizza boxes,
or gold rings.
How about half a taco?
Place it on the floor!
( Beeping )
I wish I could do that!
Now I must defeat the world's
greatest fight fighters!
Take me to the Soviet union!
That's gonna be tough...
For a number of reasons.
But I do know a fighter
here in gravity falls.
Maximum power?
His name is Robbie v,
and he's kinda like
my arch-enemy.
Did he kill your father?
Well, he's dating
the girl I like...
And he posts a really annoying
amount of status updates.
And then he killed your father!
Uh, sure.
Anyway, I was hoping
you could, you know,
scare him off for me
so I don't have
to fight the guy.
( Laughs ) your question
makes my shoulders bounce!
Fireball! uppercut!
Downercut! Love punch!
So you'll
protect me from Robbie?
Challenge a( Beeps )press start!
( Beeps )
Uh-oh, I think
i hear my uncle.
Stay perfectly still.
I said stay still.
This is as still as I can stay!
How am I gonna get grunkle Stan
over his fear of heights?
Hey, Mabel,
have you met rumble yet?
He's my new bodyguard.
The child gave me a taco!
Wow! he's got a crazy voice!
Here, say these words.
Effervescent!
apple fritter!
Riboflavin!
Mabel, he's not a toy.
He's a fighting machine.
I'm gonna get him
to defend me from Robbie.
Isn't that kinda like cheating?
I guess so.
Well, I'll see you
after the fight.
Poop! poop and butts!
Tell me my opponent's
special move.
Don't worry,
as soon as he sees you,
he's gonna wet his pants.
His wet pants
will be no match for this!
Whoa!
where'd that come from?
I punched an oil drum!
Trust me,
you won't need that.
Just give him a good scare.
Yes!
With this!
This street
has really dangerous litter.
Hey, grunkle Stan!
How would you like to go take
a walk nowhere in particular
while wearing a blindfold?
Eh, beats just sittin' around
bein' old.
Wait a minute. You're not
plannin' on takin' me somewhere
super high up, are you?
Grunkle Stan, I would never!
Scout's honor!
All right, let's go.
( Laughs )
( Clock chiming )
Well, well, well,
look who decided to show up.
I thought
you'd chicken out.
You ready
to settle this like men?
Look, dude, I don't think
you wanna fight me.
Let's just call this thing off
before someone gets hurt.
You scared, huh?
Is that it?
Okay, dude, you asked for it.
( Snaps fingers )
Who's your friend?
And why is he blurry?
This happens to be
the greatest warrior
that ever lived.
Yeah, right. Hey, eye patch,
what did the kid promise you,
more tape for your forearms?
( Laughs )
How can you laugh when you
killed this boy's father?!
I'm giving you one last chance.
Back down,
or this guy's gonna go nuts.
How 'bout you back down, kid?
You asked for it. Rumble, go!
( Laughs )
What the...?! ( Grunts )
W-what is happening?!
I didn't wanna have to do this,
man, but you gave me no choice.
Maybe now
you won't mess with--
( groans )
Whoa! rumble, you can stop!
I think Robbie's had enough!
( Retches )
Rumble throw!
Stop! I said stop!
( Groans )
What the...?!
That guy's crazy!
( Grunts ) fireball!
What the heck was that?!
You were only
supposed to scare him!
You almost killed him!
I will not rest until the man
who dishonored you is destroyed!
( Grunting )
Punch!
This isn't good.
Something told me
this would be his first stop.
( Panting )
( Roars )
( Screams ) chill out, man!
( Screams ) please,
rumble, you gotta stop!
( Grunting )
( Beeping )
( Grunts )
Rumble, wait!
punch, punch, punch!
( Beeping )
You don't have to do this!
At least pace yourself!
( Panting )
you might get a cramp!
( Groans )
I love you, dad.
( Screams )
( Grunting )
( Beeps )
We'll just buy another one.
I love being rich.
( Panting )
All you can eat!
Hey, dude.
Soos! where have you been?!
Uh, long story, man.
Dude, did you see
that video game guy
destroying
everything in sight?
( Laughs ) it was crazy.
Yeah, i-i kinda sorta
brought him to life
to be my bodyguard.
But now I have to stop him
before he kills Robbie!
You need an amiable sidekick
with a pickup truck?
You know I do.
( Tires screech )
Take off your blindfold now!
Yeah, that's pretty much
what I was expecting.
You're doing better
than I thought!
Now let go of the handrail.
No!
Hey, do you smell
anger and hormones?
( Panting )
Finally, I'm safe!
Hey, Robbie,
get your own water tower!
Shh! keep it down!
He'll find us!
Challenger sighted!
( Screams )
Time to save the day, dude.
You can hide,
but you cannot hide!
Rumble! this has to stop!
Please, listen to me!
Kick!
( All scream )
What was that?!
Oh, boy!
( Grunting )
We're safe, right?
Of course not!
This thing is on stilts
high, high up!
( Grunts )
( All scream )
( Grunts )g )
No, no, no! Don't!
Don't finish me!
Rumble!
Rumble, I have
something to tell you.
Robbie...
Robbie didn't kill my father.
( Gasps ) then who did?
What? no one did.
I-i lied to you.
( Gasps ) then you're
actually a... bad guy!
I guess I kinda am.
( Grunts )
My entire journey, a lie.
My honor has been insulted.
Sensei warned me
not to join the path of evil.
The boy has led me astray
from my teachings.
If Robbie v
is not the last stage,
then it must be...
You!
( Beeping )
Dude... ( panting )
don't fight him, man.
That guy's got like a black belt
wrapped around his black belt.
You could get killed.
I have to,
i started all this,
and I've got to
at least try to stop it.
You sure you wouldn't
rather hide like a wimp?
( Beeps )
Fight like a man it is.
**
( beeping )
( Roaring )
( Whimpering )
Fireball! lightning bolt! Fire!
( Gasps )
( Groans )
( Laughs )
you fight like a girl
who is also a baby!
( Growls )
( Roaring )
( Groaning )
Ooh!
( Groans )
( Rumbling )
Oh, no.
( Screams )
( Grunting )
It was worth a shot.
( Screaming )
No, I have no
looking-up animation!
( Grunts )
( Grunting )
( Laughs )
( Grunts )
what should I do?
Roll him up
and put him on my wall?
Dude, we should
"rock, paper, scissors"
for him.
Fist punch rain!
( Both groaning )
( Grunting )
Never underestimate
that I have punches!
( Roars )
( Beeping )
**
you, sir, truly are
the champion of champions.
( Groans )
**
winners don't lose!
I wouldn't be too sure
about that, man.
What? no! No! No!
Game over, old friend.
**
( beeping )
( Chuckles )
nice one, dude.
I'm sorry, grunkle Stan!
I thought this would help,
but I was wrong! So wrong!
I-i survived!
I survived
and I feel great!
Wait, let me do a cocky dance
just to be sure.
( Humming )
( Laughs )
deal with it, world!
Stan pines has cured
his fear of heights!
You comin'mm-mm.
Hey, what's the matter?
You got a fear of heights now?
( Chuckles )
Uh-oh.
( Grunts )
( Groans )
What?! w-who was that guy?!
Why is it that
whenever you're around,
there's always ghosts
or monsters or whatever?!
I don't know, man.
That guy
almost broke my neck!
You know how mad
i am right now?!
So I guess you and i
have to fight now, huh?
Go ahead, man, do your worst.
I just wanna get this over with.
Oh, man,
i am so gonna enjoy this.
Aren't you gonna run?
Nope.
Are you sure?
( Grunts )
it's not even worth it.
I play lead guitar
so I gotta save my hands.
Hey, guys, I heard some
crazy screaming out here.
Wendy?! you're back!
Yeah, man. Whoa.
What the heck happened here?
Freak tornado or something?
( Both stammering )
And why are your faces
all jacked up?
You guys weren't fighting
each other, were you?
I hate it when guys fight.
No! why would we?
Never! yeah, we actually
fell down trying to stop
two oth guys
from fighting each other.
Cool. it really makes me happy
to see my two boys hangin' out.
I got some unpackin' to do.
I'll text you guys later.
( Both sigh )
Did you hear that?
She called me
one of her two boys!
She was looking at me, though.
Look, Robbie, if we stay
at each other's throats,
we'll both lose Wendy.
We need to make
a cold-war pact.
Okay. what's that?
We need to learn to just
hate each other in silence.
You mean like...
What girls do?
Yeah, exactly.
What girls do.
So then I told Thompson,
"hey, save some
for the rest of us."
( Laughs )
good one, Wendy. Yeah.
( Laughs ) good one, Wendy.
That's great.
Oh, man. Just a second.
( Growls )
So as I was saying...
( Laughs ) yeah, I know.
You're the best.
( Laughs )
that was so fun, yeah.
Everybody's friends.
We're all friends.
**
I'm Dipper. I have shorts
and determination!
It's me, Mabel!
I'm slower,
but I jump higher!
Pick me or whatever.
( Chomping )
( Snoring )
Oh! alas, 'twas not but a dream.
( Chomping )
Eating my friends.
( Beeping )