There now follows
a party political broadcast
On behalf of the liberal party.
Pratt, back to pratt.
Pratt again, a long ball
out to pratt
and now pratt is on the ball...
a neat little flick back inside
to pratt, who takes it nicely
and sends it through
on the far side to pratt.
Pratt with it but passes
instead to pratt, pratt again...
Oh, and well intercepted
by the swarthy little
number nine concito maracon.
This 21-year-old halfback
remarkably stocky
for six foot, three inches
square shouldered, balding
giant, hair flowing in the wind
bright-eyed, pert,
young for his age
but oh-so-old in so many ways.
For a 39-year-old you wouldn't
expect such speed.
Normally considered slow...
sweeping up and taking
the defense to the cleaners.
Who would have thought,
though many expected it
this remarkable 45-year-old
nine foot, four inches
dwarf of a man
who is still only 17
in some parts of the world
would ever really be...
oh, and there was
a goal there apparently...
and now it's pratt,
back to pratt...
Pratt again...
a long ball out to pratt...
I really like
this ano-wheat.
It really
unclogs me.
Oh, do be careful!
Sorry, mum.
I mean, a lot
of the others
Say they
unclog you
But I never had
a single bowel movement
With them
"recto-puffs."
Now, if we...
Oh, sorry, mum.
If we lived
in rhodesia
There'd be
someone
To mop that up
for you.
Don't be so
bleedin' stupid.
If you lived
in bleedin' rhodesia
You'd be out at bleedin' fascist
rallies every bleedin' day.
You're a bleedin' racist,
you bleedin' are!
Language!
Well, he gets
on my sodding wick.
That's better.
No, the stuff
I liked was
That stuff they gave you
before the war
What was it?--
Wilkinson's number eight
laxative cereal.
Whew, that one
went through you
Like a bloody ferrari.
Now, who's that
at this time of day?
If it's the man
to empty the elsan
Tell him it's
in the hall.
Right, dear.
And make sure
that you hold it
The right
way up.
Dad?
Yeah?
No, no,
my dad.
Oh.
Dad, why is rhodesia
called rhodesia?
Oh, sorry, dad.
No, no, thank you
very much.
No, I'm sorry.
Thank you very
much, indeed.
No, thank you
for calling.
Not today, thank you.
Good morning.
Who was that?
The liberal party
candidate, darling.
What have you
done now?
Sorry, mum.
I was just
washing up.
Go and
sit down!
Mum...
Mum, do you know
Why rhodesia's
called rhodesia?
Do you remember
"go-eazi"?
They were
hopeless...
Little black
pellets
Tasted foul
And they stuck
inside you
Like flooring
adhesive.
Well, I'm off!
What time are you
coming back tonight?
3:00 a.m.!
I think it's disgusting
You a member of parliament.
Last night I heard you
snogging away.
We was not snogging!
Sure... sounded like
snogging to me.
I could hear his great wet,
slobbering lips going at you
And his hand
going...
Dad!
Yeah?
No, not you.
Oh.
Just mind
your language.
Oh, sorry, mum.
I've run out of beans!
We was
talking!
not snogging!
Talking about
snogging, I'll bet.
If you
must know
We was talking about
council re-housing!
Would it mean
going to live in hollywood?
I've run out of beans!
Where to re-house
his right hand--
That's all he was interested in!
And has faye dunaway
definitely said yes?
He is the chairman
of the housing subcommittee.
Snogging subcommittee,
more like.
Ralph, do answer
that door, will you?
Beans!
Shut up!!
Yes, mum.
If it's the man
from probbo-rib
Tell him
it's in the bed.
All right.
Sorry, mum.
Postmaaaan!
Well, a very good try there
by the garibaldi family
Of droitwich in worcestershire.
Professor?
Well, I can't
make up my mind
About this family.
I don't think there was
The sustained awfulness
that we really need.
I mean, the father
was appalling...
Appalling, yes.
He was dirty, smelly
and distasteful
And I liked him
very much, but...
Lady organs?
Well, they were
An unpleasant
family, certainly
But I don't
think we had
Any of the really
gross awfulness
We're looking for.
Well, harsh words there
For the garibaldi family
of droitwich in worcestershire
At present holders of the east
midlands most-awful-family award
Lower middle-class section
But unable today to score more
than 15 on our disgustometer.
Well, with the scores
all in from the judges
The garibaldis are number three
and a surprise at number two:
The fanshaw-chumleighs
of berkshire.
Well, some of
the wonderful behavior
That made the fanshaw-chumleighs
The second-most-awful family
in britain, 1974.
But the winners,
by a clear ten-point margin
Once again, the awful
jodrell family of durham.
Unfortunately,
we're not allowed to show you
Some of the performance
that won them the award
But I assure you it was
of the very highest standard
Was it not, lady organs?
Oh, yes, superb.
I mean, mr. jodrell--
You know, the old grandfather
who licks the...
Yes, yes...
He's superb.
His gobbing is consistent
and accurate.
His son is a dirty,
foul little creature
And those frightful scabs
which mrs. jodrell...
Well, thank you
very much, lady organs
And from all of us,
well done to the jodrells
And to all of you,
not forgetting those of you
Who may be halfway in between
Without whom, of course
and not forgetting
Who made it all possible when,
and we'll be back
Until then, and so
it's good night from me
And here's wishing you
a safe journey home.
Thank you for watching
this show.
Don't forget it was
all great fun, I enjoyed it
And I hope you
watching at home
Have enjoyed it too.
The jodrells win
every bloody year.
Makes you vomit!
Dad?
Yes?
Get your stinking feet
off the bread.
I'm only wiping
the cat's do's off!
Mum?
Shut your gob,
douglas.
I want more
corn plasters!
Shut up and eat
what you got!
Some fat bastard at the door!
Shut up!
A strong hive of bees contains
approximately 75,000 bees.
Each honeybee must make
154 trips to collect
One teaspoonful
of honey.
Hello, sir.
What do
you want?
Would you like to buy
some of our honey, sir?
What are you
doing in here?
Which would
you like--
The californian
orange blossom
The mexican,
the new zealand
Or the scottish
heather?
He can't eat honey.
It makes him
go plop-plops!
Come on, please
try some.
All right,
I'll have
Some icelandic
honey.
No, there is no such thing.
You mean you don't make
any honey at all?
No, no, we must import it all,
every bally drop.
We are a gloomy people.
It's so crikey cold
and dark up there
And there's only fish to eat.
Fish and imported honey.
Oh, strewth!
Well, why do you
have a week?
Listen, buster!
In reykjavik
it is dark
For eight months
of the year
And it's
cold enough
To freeze
your wrists off
And there's only
golly fish to eat.
Administrative errors
are bound to occur
In enormous
quantities.
Look at this.
It's all a mistake.
It's a real pain
in the sphincter!
Icelandic honey week? my life!
Well, why do you
come in here
Trying to flog
the stuff, then?
Listen, cowboy,
I got a job to do.
It's a stupid,
pointless job
But at least
it keeps me
Away from iceland,
all right?
The leg of the worker bee has...
Well, mr. cotton,
you have
What we in the medical
profession call
A naughty complaint.
Now, my advice
to you is
To put this paper bag
over your head--
It's got little
holes there, you see
Little holes
for your eyes--
And to ring this bell
and to take this card
Along to your
hospital, okay?
And I shall inform all your
relatives and friends
And anyone else that I happen to
bump into, okay?
Cash, wasn't it?
Thank you very much.
Get out.
Dirty little man.
Hippocratic oath, hippocratic...
Oh, it's not in there.
Jolly good.
Very useful. next!
Ah, yes, you must be
mr. williams.
Well, do take a seat.
What seems to be
the trouble?
I've just been stabbed
by your nurse!
Oh, dear, yes, well...
I'd probably better have
a look at you then.
Could you fill in
this form first?
She just stabbed me.
Yes, she's
an unpredictable sort.
Look, you seem to be
bleeding rather badly.
I think you'd better hurry up
and fill in that form.
Couldn't I fill it
in later, doctor?
No, no, you'll have
bled to death by then.
Can you hold a pen?
I'll try.
Yes, jolly good.
It's a hell
of a nuisance
All this damn paperwork.
Really, it is.
It's a real nightmare,
this paperwork.
It really is a hell
of a nuisance.
Something ought
to be done about it.
Do I have to answer
All the questions,
doctor?
No, no, no, just...
Just fill in as
many as you can.
No need to go into too much
detail, you know.
I don't know why we bother
with it all, really
It's such a nuisance.
Well, let's see
how you've done, then.
Oh, yes.
Oh, dear, oh, dear
That's not
very good, is it?
Look, surely
you knew number four!
No...
It's from
the merchant of venice.
Even I knew that!
It's going
on the carpet, doctor.
Oh, don't worry
about that!
Look at this--
number six--
It's the treaty
of versailles!
Didn't you know that?
Oh, my god.
And number nine--
emerson fittipaldi!
Virginia wade?
you must be mad!
Oh, doctor...
I've just shot
another patient.
I don't think there's any point
in your seeing him.
You didn't kill him, did you?
Afraid so.
You mustn't kill them, nurse.
Oh, I'm sorry, doctor.
It was just on the spur
of the moment.
Rather silly, really.
I'm sorry about
the carpet, doctor.
Mr. williams, I'm afraid I can't
give you any marks
So I won't be able to recommend
you for hospital.
I tell you what,
I'll stop the bleeding
But strictly speaking
I shouldn't
even do that
On marks like these.
There are no more patients
now, doctor.
Oh, well, let's go
for lunch, then.
What about... er...
Ah, yes, look,
mr. williams
We're just popping out
for a bite of lunch
While we've got a spare
moment, you know.
Look, have another
bash at the form
And if at least
you can answer
The questions
on history all right
Then we
may be able
To give you
some morphine
Or something
like that, okay?
Thank you, doctor, thank you.
Dear sir, I wish to protest
In the strongest
possible terms.
Yours sincerely
Brigadier n.f.
marwood-git [retired].
Read that back,
will you, brian?
"and when he had
built up cedron
"he sent horsemen there
"and an host of footmen
to the end
"that issuing out
they might make outroads
Upon the ways of judea
as the king commanded them."
Good!
Pop it in an envelope
and bung it off!
It's no good bottling
things up, brian.
If you feel them
you must just say them
Or you'll just go mad.
Oh, yes, indeed.
As the book of maccabee said
"yea, as the flea
is like unto an oxen
"so is the privet hedge
liken unto a botanist
Black in thy sight, o lord."
Quite.
Look, why don't you just nip out
for lunch, brian?
Yea, as raymond
chandler said
"it was one
of those days
"when
los angeles felt
Like a rock-hard fig."
Brian, let's stop this
pretending, shall we?
Yea, as
dirk bogarde said
In his
autobiography...
Brian!
Let's stop all
this futile pretense.
I've...
I've always been
moderately fond of you.
Well, to be quite
frank, brigadier
One can't walk
so closely
With a chap like you
for... for so long
Without feeling
something
Deep down inside
Even if it isn't
anything...
Anything
very much.
Well, splendid, brian.
Well, I don't suppose
There's much
we can do, really.
Not on
television, no.
No.
They, uh...
They are a lot more
permissive these days
Than they used to be.
Ah, yes, but not with
this sort of thing.
No.
I suppose they've...
Got to draw
the line somewhere.
Yes.
Well, take
a letter, brian.
Dear sir,
I wish to protest...
Ooh!
Hmm?
Oh.
Ho-oh!
Oh, oh.
Hmm?
Mmm... mmm?
There now follows...
Hello.
I'd like to talk to you tonight
about a minority group of people
Who have no mental
or physical handicaps
And who, through no fault
of their own
Have never been deprived
And consequently are forced
to live in conditions
Of extreme luxury.
This often-ignored minority
Is very rarely brought to the
attention of the general public.
The average man in the street
scarcely gives a second thought
To these extremely
well-off people.
He quite simply fails
to appreciate the pressures
That vast quantities of money
just do not bring.
Have you at home ever had
to cope with this problem?
Or this?
I know it's only human to say
"oh, this will never happen
to me"
And of course, it won't.
So I'm asking you,
please, please
send no contributions,
however large, to me.
There now follows a party political
broadcast...
All right, I'll go.
Everything goes up,
everything goes down
Fish, bananas...
Hello, madam.
Oh, hello, you must
have come about...
Finishing the
sentences, yes.
Oh, well, perhaps
you'd like to...
Come through this way,
certainly.
Oh, nice place
you've got here.
Yes, well, we, uh...
Like it.
Yes, we certainly...
Do, good.
Now, when did you first start...
Finding it difficult...
To finish sentences, yes.
Well, it's not me, it's my...
Husband?
Yes, he...
Never lets you finish
What you've started?
Quite, I'm beginning to feel...
You'll never finish a sentence
again as long as you live?
Exact--
--ly-- it must be awful.
It's driving me...
To drink.
No, rou--
--nd the be--
--en--
--d.
Yes.
May i...
Take a seat.
Thank you.
You see, our method
Is to reassure the patient
by re-creating normal...
Conditions.
Yes, then we try and get them
into a position
Where they
suddenly find
That they're completing other
people's sentences...
Themselves.
Spot on, mrs...
Smith.
Good, well, try not
to overdo it to...
Begin with.
Keep it to one or two...
Words...
To start off with,
otherwise you may find...
I'm taking on too long
a sentence
And getting completely...
Stuck.
Good, yes, well,
that's about it...
For now, so...
Thanks very
much for calling.
Oh, not at all.
And...
I'd just
like to say...
Thank you very much
for coming along.
Not at all.
And good...
Bye, mr...
Vernon.
Carl!
Yes, dear?
I've just had
another baby.
Oh, no.
how many is that now?
Uh, 12 since lunch.
Oh! there's another one.
This is stonehenge, and
it's from here we go to africa.
Well, here it is at last,
the goal of our quest.
After six months and three days,
we've finally caught up
With the legendary
walking tree of dahomey--
Quercus nicholas parsonsus--
Resting here for a moment
on its long journey south.
It's almost incredible,
isn't it
To think that this huge tree
has walked over 2,000 miles
Across this inhospitable terrain
to stop here
Maybe just to take in water
Before the 2,000 miles
on to cape town where it lives.
It's almost unimaginable,
I find
The thought of this mighty tree
strolling through nigeria;
Perhaps swaggering a little
As it crosses the border
into zaire;
Hopping through
the tropical rain forest
Trying to find a quiet grove
Where it can jump around
on its own;
Sprinting up to zambia for the
afternoon, then nipping back...
Oh, super.
Well, I've just been told
that this is not in fact
The legendary
walking tree of dahomey.
This is one of africa's
many stationary trees
Arborus bamber gascoignus.
In fact, we've just missed
the walking tree.
It left here at 8:00
this morning.
It was heading off
in that direction
So we'll just see if we can go
and catch it up.
Come on, boys.
Well, we're still keeping up
with it
But it's setting a furious pace.
Early this morning,
we thought we'd spotted it
But it turned out to be
an angolan sauntering tree--
Amazellus robin ray--
Out walking with
a gambian sidling bush.
So, on we go.
It's going to be difficult.
A walking tree can achieve
speeds of up to 50 miles an hour
Especially when it's in a hurry.
Super.
Well, rupert has spotted
something.
This could be it--
a walking tree on the move.
But what rupert
had in fact discovered
Was something very different...
The turkish little rude plant.
This remarkably smutty piece
of flora was used by the turks
To ram up each others'...
Ah, no!
In fact, it was something
even more interesting.
Yes, there it was, over
the other side of the clearing--
The legendary puking tree
of mozambique.
No, what they'd come across
was a tribe lost to man
Since time immemorial--
The legendary batsmen
of the kalahari.
Primitive customs
still survive here
As if the march of time
had passed them by.
But for all the mumbo jumbo
and superstition
The batsmen of the kalahari
are formidable fighters
As we can see in this rare
footage of them in action
Against warwickshire.
Warwickshire had dismissed
the kalahari batsmen for 140
But then it was their turn
To face this extraordinary
kalahari attack.
Pratt was the first to go,
but pratt and pratt put on
A second wicket stand of naught
Which was broken by odinga
in his most hostile mood.
That's b. pratt,
hit wicket-- naught.
But pratt and z. pratt dug in
And took the score to a half
before z. pratt ran away.
But out came m.j.k. pratt to
play a real captain's innings.
He'd taken his own score
up to naught
When he mistimed a shot
of bowanga and was l.b.w.
Typical of umbonga's hostile
opening spell
Was his dismissal of v.e. pratt
Who offered no resistance
to this delivery...
And he was caught behind.
But by lunch, the situation
had changed dramatically.
And so, with
the tension colossal
As we come up
to the last ball...
That's all from us.
Good evening.
Over funt400,000 million
Were wiped off the value
of shares this afternoon
When someone in
the stock exchange coughed.
Sport-- capital punishment
is to be reintroduced
In the first and second
division.
Any player found tackling
from behind
Or controlling the ball
with the lower part of the arm
Will be hanged.
But the electric chair remains
the standard punishment
For threatening the goalie.
Referees' chairman
len goebbels said
"at last, the referee
has been given teeth."
Finally, politics-- the latest
opinion poll published today
Shows labor ahead with 40%,
the a.a. second with 38%
And, not surprisingly
Kentucky fried chicken running
the liberals a very close third.
And now, back to me-- hello.
And now it's time to go over
to hugh delaney at paignton.
Hello, and welcome to paignton
because it's from paignton
That we take you straight back
to the studio.
Hello, and it's from here
we go over there.
Well, we're already here,
so let's go over there.
Welcome back.
And now it's time
for part eight of our series
About the life and work
of ursula hitler
The surrey housewife
Who revolutionized
british beekeeping
In the 1930s.
That was a party
political - cast
On behalf of
the liberal party.