In the czech republic, too,
we love pork.
Ever had our sausages?
In the czech republic, too,
we love pork.
You ever had our sausages?
- Adriana?
- In the czech republic, too,
we love pork.
Ever had our sausages?
Emil kolar?
- Help you?
- Salami sub, hold the mayo.
We're out of mayo.
Change my meat
to black forest.
- You killed me.
- What do you want me
to do about it now?
- I wanna tell you.
- Tell me what?
You come here every night.
- You fucked up.
- What do you mean?
Here's these.
Where did you find'em?
One in the table.
Three in my skull.
You will have our sausages.
Get rid of these.
Let go of me! Let go!
I would have wrapped it, but--
that's okay.
A computer!
This model got such a good
write- up, i got one for myself.
You're gonna love it.
Let's move on, okay?
Congratulations.
God bless.
Hon, you look gorgeous.
By the way,
who's your date?
I'll give you "who's
your date." come here.
Good to see you.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Melissa was beautiful
up there.
I know. Thank you.
Oh, mama livia.
Come esta, darling?
Listen to him with
that "my darling."
I am nobody's darling.
This one here,
she never disappoints ya,
i'll tell ya that.
Are you still seeing
your other women, lorenzo?
Come on, ma.
Let's mingle.
Sorry. The older she gets,
the worse she gets.
Ah. Listen. I heard
some disturbing shit
last night.
I wanted to talk to you about
it. But with the rehearsal
dinner and everything, it just--
yeah.
I-- there's
the priest, though.
I'll be right back.
Go ahead.
Yeah! Whoo!
Salute!
Federal indictments?
Yeah.
Where the fuck
you get this?
I got a guy who owes me.
He's got agoomatowho
works at f. B. I. Headquarters
as a word processor.
When's it comin' down?
I don't know. When she
knows, she'll tell me.
Indictments? What the fuck
you talkin' about?
You sure about this?
It ain't just my source in
jersey. Half of new york moved
to fort lauderdale already.
Fuck. They're gonna
want my ass.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
I'm o. C.
When'd you get
your fuckin' wings?
I didn't.
Not yet anyway.
Uncle junior, you got anything
you wanna say about this?
You guys see indictments
under your bed at night.
Right away you're ready to lam
it. As far as i'm concerned,
it's just speculation.
- It's rumor.
- Better be safe
than sorry, no?
I say we duck for a while.
And what are we gonna do?
Close shop?
We can't do that.
Tony, what do you think?
What the fuck you askin'
him for? I just--
i just gave you the answer.
Junior's right. We go on
the lam now, it's open season.
The fuckin' albanians
will be livin' in our houses.
Fuck!
I just gave a g- note to
larry boy's kid for the boost.
If i knew i may have to lam
in a hurry, i would've duked
her another time.
Thank you, darlin'.
Gotta go.
Say good- bye
to your father for me.
I agree with my uncle.
He calls the shots,
we do it.
But maybe, for today,
for right now...
you were thinkin', uncle jun,
that everybody should do
a little spring cleaning.
That was my next comment.
We're goin' right now.
Let's go.
Come on. We have to go.
Think they're gonna come
over the weekend?
They're comin' someday.
- Where's the rest of the money?
- It's everywhere.
Well, get it.
What else?
How'bout your phone numbers?
Anybody who's anybody
is in my head.
What's the matter?
Nothin'.
Just here we go.
Here.
Why now?
Why the fuck now, just
when things we're goin' good?
Boot your computer.
The cops are coming.
- So?
- You want them to see all that
porno you downloaded?
Shit!
You better give me
your jewelry.
Jesus.
Hey.
They know we can't produce
receipts. You want'em stealing
this shit from us?
Come on.
I'm not giving you my engagement
ring. This isn't stolen.
Is it?
No. What do you
think i am?
Come on.
Give me that.
Adriana!
It ate my whole script now!
You're still on the file.
You must've deleted
the text.
What the fuck--
whatever, whatev--
you fuckin' asshole!
All right, stop
with the hysteria,
would you, please?
If you're gonna keep behavin'
like a baby, fuck it, i'm not
gonna help you, christopher.
- I mean it.
- At least you work that squirrel
program in the restaurant.
There.
The text came back.
You put it in
buffer memory.
What do you think?
Of the script?
Babe, i can't like give
an opinion every time
you add a sentence.
I gotta have
the whole story flow.
I'm startin' with the dialogue.
"Imanugedto get
the drop on him"?
Do you mean to say,
"imanagedto get
the drop on him"?
Or is he saying"manuge,"
like"manugia l'american"?
My tennessee william.
Where you goin'?
Get over here.
I have never seen you
apply yourself like this.
I love movies.
You know that.
That smell in blockbuster,
that candy and carpet smell,
i get high off it.
I'm gonna let all this
love and knowledge
go to waste?
My cousin gregory's
girlfriend amy, the one that
works for tarantino, said,
"mob stories
are always hot."
I can make my mark.
Babe,
with these indictments,
shouldn't you put
the script away for a while
and get rid of evidence?
Travel light.
Free bird.
You stole this computer,
plus the one
you just gave melissa.
- I'm writing!
- Turn on channel 6.
Turn on channel 6.
New jersey attorney general
james d. Ricci stated
at a fund- raiser...
that a grand jury has been
impanelled to investigate...
possible mob activities
in the garden state,
with indictments to follow.
With us is syndicated columnist
and author ofmafia:
America's longest running
soap opera, jeffrey wernick.
First of all, welcome.
Thank you.
Pleasure to be here.
For years now, the f. B. I.
Has been telling us that
the mafia is all but dead.
Let me interject.
While it is true...
that the mob is getting
a standing- eight count,
uh, i wouldn't call
the fight.
The government knows this
better than anyone.
Murder, truck hijacking as well
as money laundering are expected
to be among the inquiries.
Do we know yet
the names of those
who will be indicted?
Well, the indictments
are sealed.
But with the recent death
of acting di meo family boss,
jackie aprile,
my sources tell me that
corrado "junior" soprano...
was made new boss
after the death of aprile.
The sopranos have
long historic ties to
the new york families.
What about these possible
murder charges?
They will undoubtedly
be focused on
the as- yet- unsolved...
execution- style slaying
of soprano family associate,
brendan filone.
Uh, was it part
of a power struggle?
Interesting.
No one would ever have
ranked him as associate!
My associates tell me that...
filone is a loyal soldier, if
you will, and he winds up dead--
soldier?
Brendan filone!
Associate? Soldier?
Fuck you!
Jesus.
Georgie, did you see it
from the beginning?
Did they mention my name?
No-- stop the fuckin'
chitchat, all right.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
Nobody makes "ginzo" gravy
like you, nana.
You know, i'm up at bard
waiting for my care package.
I don't like
that word, jason.
- What? Ginzo?
- The word is offensive.
She's right, jason.
It's not a nice word.
Sorry, nana.
- What's it mean?
- Derived from the word
"guinea."
- What's that mean?
- It's a derogation.
I have a patient,
you wouldn't wanna say the word
"guinea" in front of him.
Huh, italian male
seeing a shrink.
Let me guess.
Mother issues.
- Why wouldn't you say it, mom?
- You just wouldn't.
What, you'd be scared?
Is he in the mafia?
I shouldn't have mentioned it.
Can't we change
the subject?
No way. What's he do, mom?
Is he in the mob or what?
He's not a mobster,
is he, jen?
Nobody knows better
than you, richard,
i can't discuss my patients.
I just hope he's not
one of those crumbs they're
talkin' about on the news.
Jen, just refer him
to another doctor. You could
do that, couldn't you?
- Grate the cheese, dad, okay?
- Sure she can.
That might be what
you would do, richard.
Now i remember why
we got divorced.
Why should i refer him
to another doctor?
He's my patient.
You know you can't treat
sociopaths.
He's scum and you shouldn't
help him with his bed- wetting.
You have no idea
who this man is,
and yet you call him scum.
People like him are
the reason italian- americans
have such a bad image.
I agree.
Ask any american to describe
an italian- american,
and invariably he's gonna
referencethe godfather,
goodfellas.
Good movies.
And the rest
are gonna mention pizza.
Good movies
to eat pizza by.
Stop it, jason.
I never said he was
in the mafia.
Why do you think we're never
gonna see an italian president?
And that's
my patient's fault?
- Hey.
- I realize you're very involved
in the antidefamation lobby.
So go after hollywood if you
feel you absolutely have to,
but leave my patient alone.
It's a synergy. News items
and the constant portrayal of
italian- americans as gangsters.
Wasn't the italian antidef deal
started by joe colombo,
a mobster?
Italians against discrimination
did a study,
and in its height,
the mafia in this country
had less than 5, 000 members.
And yet, that tiny,
insignificant fraction...
cast such a dark shadow
over 20 million
hard- working americans.
Dad, at this point
in our cultural history,
mob movies are classic
american cinema,
like westerns.
I have to agree there, rich.
You know,
you never saw that scotch- irish
pissin' and moanin'...
about always bein' portrayed
as, as rustlers
and gunslingers.
That's absurd.
See what you started
with your gravy, nana?
To we,
the 20 million.
- Salute.
Salute.
- What?
- Get down here right away.
We're exterminatin'.
- I'm kind of busy now.
And get some sfogliatelle
and cannoli and shit
for the guys.
Yeah.
Twenty- nine.
Here you go, big guy.
Thank you.
Hey, gino.
What can i get you?
Give me some--
whoa, whoa.
Number 34, right here.
He was in line.
He just went out to go
get gas in his car.
Oh, so i could go out,
fuck your sister, come back
saturday, i go to the front?
- I said he could.
- Hey, poppin' fresh,
i'm in no fuckin' mood today.
I'm next.
Now get a fuckin' pastry box.
Gino, what can i get ya?
Oh!
It's all right, dougie.
Let him go first.
No. He don't make
the rules here.
All right, let me have
two neapolitan loaves--
you touch a single fuckin'
crust, you're gonna wish you
took that job at mcdonald's.
- Fuck you.
- Okay, take a walk.
What about my bread?
You come back
in ten minutes.
- What the fuck do you
think you're doin'?
- Come on.
Come on. Get up.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
What is it? What is it?
Do i look like a pussy to you?
No.
I'm serious.
Be honest.
I won't get mad.
No.
Why the fuck would you give me
a hard time and talk to me like
i'm nothin' to worry about?
I- i- i'm sorry.
Get a pastry box.
Move it!
That's better.
Now fill it...
with cannoli, sfogliatelle
and napoleons.
Okay.
- Move!
-
good.
Give me the box.
Come on.
Here.
Next time you see my face,
show some respect.
I will.
You motherfucker!
- You shot my foot!
- It happens.
Oh, you fuckin' asshole!
If i'm gettin' an invitation
to the dance,
i wish the feds would hurry
the fuck up about it.
You heard what
they're sayin' on the news.
The way things are workin',
it's gonna be junior's party.
That was a far- thinkin' plan
you had there, ton.
I called you
last christmas.
Fuck this.
Hey, the sfogliatelle.
What's wrong with you?
What are you doin'?
Were you brought up
in a barn or what?
What's the matter with you,
huh? This is no time to go
on the rag, christopher.
Not with the indictment shit
comin' down.
Take georgie,
go in the bathroom,
sweep for bugs, okay?
Come on.
Well, i hope
they'll be all right.
- Who?
- The guys.
- What about me?
- You'll be all right.
They didn't even mention
your name on television.
Fuckin' amazing,
though, huh?
You know what, that news guy,
he said the words,"brendan
filone," i'm tellin' ya, the
hairs on the back of my neck,
they fuckin' stood up.
- I mean, i knew the guy.
- They made him look like
john fuckin' gotti.
I brought him around here.
Tony wouldn't have never
known him if it wasn't for me.
Huh. I had no idea.
Who is it?
I'm sleeping!
Carmela.
Oh, come on in.
I- i- i just said that in case
you were that snooty- ass...
mrs. Ryan down the hall.
Oh, she is so shanty irish,
and with all her airs.
Come on. Get dressed.
I'm taking you to brunch.
What?
You heard me.
Get dressed.
What's wrong? Tell me.
Nothing is wrong, ma. Why does
something have to be wrong?
Is it meadow?
She eats like a bird.
Everything is fine, ma.
Relax. Nothing is wrong.
But you come here unannounced.
And i- i shouldn't wonder
if something's wrong?
Oh, jeez. I'm sorry.
It's a nice day.
I thought i would
take you out.
I don't wanna go out.
Is it anthony?
Those indictments?
His father could take it
in stride, but he can't.
I don't believe you.
- Come on, ma.
Will you get dressed?
- We just went to a wedding.
That was a big to- do.
This way, you and me, we get
to spend some quality time.
The manor is gonna stop
serving brunch any minute.
Did he cheat on you again?
You know,
i try to do something nice.
I come here to take you out.
Right away you think
i have some other agenda that
i have to talk toyouabout?
Don't flatter yourself.
I'll, uh--
i'll throw something on.
Buckle your seat belt, ma.
I can't find it.
Where is it?
It's not definite.
I just thought i'd tell ya,
you know, in case i don't
show up for an appointment.
So, you're telling me
that you're planning
a vacation,
but you're not sure
exactly when it will be?
Right.
I may never go.
Let's put it this way.
There's a strong possibility
that it-- it could happen.
Does this have anything
to do with what's been
on the news lately?
So, if you, uh, suddenly stop
coming to your appointments,
i will assume that
you are on vacation.
And i should wait
to be contacted?
That would be
a good assumption.
Who is it?
Paulie.
Open the door.
I thought we were
steppin' out.
I got two broads in the car.
You said ad' went to stay
at her mother's.
No wonder.
This place looks like
a fuckin' sty.
What's wrong with you?
Talk to me.
This ain't like you, kid.
I ran into
billy cracchiolo.
The meter maid?
What about him?
Told me the regular cops
in nutley are lookin'
for a guy.
Blew off a kid's toe
for no good reason
in russo's bakery.
Drove a lexus.
Does tony know about this?
What's goin' on, chrissy?
Been workin' my ass off
on this movie script.
You know how many pages
i got? Nineteen.
That a lot
or a little?
Books say movie's supposed
to be about 120 pages.
Got this fuckin' computer.
I thought it would
do a lot of it.
You ain't bein' frank
about the business, kid?
I would never do that.
It's only "suggested by."
That writer,
with the bullfights,
blew his own fuckin' head off.
I bought a script- writin'
program and everything.
My advice.
Put that thing down a while.
We go get our joints copped,
and tomorrow, the words
will come blowin' out your ass.
You ever feel like
nothin' good was ever
gonna happen to you?
Yeah. And nothin' did.
So what?
I'm alive.
I'm survivin'.
That's it.
I don't wanna just survive.
Says in these movie- writing
books that every character
has an arc. You understand?
Like everybody starts out
somewheres,
and then they do somethin'
or somethin' gets done to them,
it changes their life.
That's called their arc.
Where's my arc?
Take richard kimble,
all right?
No, that's no good.
His arc is run, run,
jump off a damn-- run.
Uh--
keanu reeves, devil's advocate.
You see that?
Al.
Right.
Keanu's a lawyer.
Gets all turned on by money,
power and the devil.
Then his wife says to him,
"you're not the man i married."
Leaves him.
You see the arc?
He starts down here.
He ends up here.
Where's my arc, paulie?
Kid, richard kimble,
thedevil'swhatever,
those are all make- believe.
Hey, i got no arc either.
I was born, grew up,
spent a few years in the army,
a few more in the can
and here i am.
A half a wise guy.
So what?
I got no identity.
I mean, even brendan filone's
got an identity. He's dead.
I killed that fuckin'
emil kolar and nothin'.
I don't even move up a notch.
All i got is nightmares.
That polish, czech, slavic,
whatever the fuck he is,
is hauntin' me in my dreams
every night.
That happens.
The more of them you do,
the better you'll sleep.
I had one prick chasin' me
for months in my dreams.
I feel like he's tryin'
to tell me somethin'.
That we fucked up
the night that we buried him.
We didn't fuck up.
- That i'm in danger.
- Could i ask you a question?
Why the fuck would he wanna
tell you you're in danger,
considering you put
a fuckin' moon roof
in the back of his head?
What did we do wrong
that night?
The gun was hot,
so the slugs in his head
couldn't be traced back to me.
You know who had an arc?
Noah.
Is that him?
Now that would be
some fuckin' coincidence
if it wasn't, wouldn't it?
Holy shit!
Look at that!
- What?
- He was clean shaven.
He's got a fuckin' beard now.
You know what?
I read that. That happens.
Jesus. I always thought
it was bullshit.
Oh! Look
at his fingernails!
- Oh, fuck!
They're like a woman's.
- I'm gonna fuckin' puke.
All right, help me lift him.
We'll take him down to
pine barons before they build
a fuckin' condo here.
Georgie!
I don't know about
selling this property.
I don't know about you,
but i sure as hell
could use an infusion...
if we're gonna support jas
after he graduates.
It's funny how
even during our marriage
we saw things differently.
I never saw this place
as an investment.
I always thought
that we'd build a house.
So, are we gonna sell
or what?
For jason.
But, you know, i don't wanna
hear that you took one of
your colleens on a cruise.
What's that supposed to mean,
"colleens"?
We all know you're a sucker
for those irish girls.
Every italian boy
bows down to the freckles.
I married you.
- Yeah, i was a mother figure.
- Don't bust my balls with freud
by numbers, would ya?
"Don't bust my balls"?
Watch it, richard.
Yourcalibrazeis showing.
What, are you somehow
implying by all this...
i'm- i'm ashamed to be
an italian- american?
With all the poverty,
starvation, ethnic cleansing...
and generally horrible shit
in this world,
you devote your energies
to the protection of the dignity
of connie francis.
You know, you're all
worked up about my patient,
a man who has no bearing
on who you are or where
you are in this world.
Call him a patient.
The man's a criminal, jennifer.
And after a while,
finally you're gonna get
beyond psychotherapy...
with its cheesy
moral relativism.
Finally, you're gonna get
to good and evil.
And he's evil.
Sorry i'm late.
The alarm was--
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Didn't paulie tell you
i ain't been feelin' good?
I wipe my ass
with your feelings.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
Drive the fuckin' car!
We're under a microscope,
and i gotta hear you shot some
fuckin' civilian in the foot...
'cause he made you wait
for buns?
Fuckin' paulie.
Don't blame paulie!
Makazian comes to me
and says nutley p. D. S...
got a description
and a make on the car!
Why don't you just leave a
fuckin' urine sample next time?
If i could've done it--
oh, shut up! Fuckin' georgie
comes into the club, he's got
vomit all over his shirt.
I ask him,"what the fuck?" he
said you're diggin' up some body
you clipped three months ago!
I was worried--
shut up!
People do that shit,
they wanna get caught.
I wanna get caught?
You wanna get caught.
I seen it before,
this fuckin' "cowboy- itis"!
You wanna be a big,
bad guy, christopher?
I was worried that i didn't--
shut up!
Can i try and explain here?
I don't know, tony.
It's like just the fuckin'
"regularness" of life is
too fuckin' hard for me.
I don't--
i don't know.
Look at you.
I bet you're sleepin'
all the time, right?
It's the only thing
i still enjoy.
You know what i think?
Maybe i have cancer.
You remember
how jackie got?
Cancer?
Somethin' fuckin' horrible's
goin' on inside my body.
There's a physical change.
Does this word "cancer"
pop into your mind a lot,
a little bit, what?
- Huh?
- Well, i'm just thinkin'
maybe you're...
depressed.
Me?
I'm no fuckin'
mental midget.
All right.
- Watch the, the--
- what?
The filter.
Oh, fuck!
Maybe you got a, uh,
serotonin problem,
or whatever the fuck
they call it, ya know.
You know about that shit?
I saw it last night
on a...program.
What, take fuckin' prozac?
Not this skinny guinea.
Let me ask you a question.
You ever think about,
uh, you know--
fuck no!
Good.
Can you imagine those
fuckin' losers blowin' their
skulls all over the bathroom?
It's fuckin' pathetic.
Hey, didn't you hear
the goddamn doorbell?
I'm in the middle of a game.
You'll be in the middle
of the fuckin' street
you don't wise up.
Anthony soprano?
What are you doing
in my backyard?
The gate was open.
I'm agent harris.
This is agent driscol.
May we come in?
If i say no?
If we were local,
we wouldn't even have knocked.
What's your point?
We have a search warrant.
We know you have children
in the house.
Other team's waiting out front.
We don't think it necessary...
to traumatize kids
by kicking in doors.
So, why don't you take
a minute and tell them
you have, uh, visitors.
Hmm.
Any quarters,
you can keep.
You tryin' to bribe me?
Why don't you tell me
what you're lookin' for?
Maybe i can save you some time.
- Any incriminating evidence
would be nice.
-
dad!
They're taking my computer.
I have an english paper.
You gotta be shittin' me.
I better have all
my programs on there
when it comes back.
Anthony.
What the hell are they doin'
in my kitchen?
What the hell are you doin'
in my refrigerator?
- If you forgot your lunch box,
pal, why don't you just ask?
- I'm very sorry.
Mrs. Soprano, how much
would you say that bowl cost?
I'm not cleaning that up.
Grasso, get somethin'
to clean that.
Grasso--
- your ass!
- Hey, hey, hey! Tony.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Grasso, take it easy.
Tony, we're gonna be out
of here in a few minutes.
Tony, let's wait
in the living room.
Clean up the bowl.
Come on.
I know those feds are doin'
their job, but it pisses me off
the way they act.
That one guy wasn't
so bad, harris.
Trust me, he was the biggest
sneak out of all of'em.
It's all part of his little act.
And that guy
that broke the bowl,
he did that on purpose.
I don't think so.
He was just a klutz.
What was his last name?
Rizzo, razzo, what?
Grasso.
Grasso. Do you think
it's a coincidence
they sent him?
If he wasn't an italian,
he'd be back at the office
sweepin' up. The stupid jerk.
They probably frisk him
every night before he goes home.
- Why?
- Why? 'cause he has a vowel
at the end of his name.
Grasso. What's he think,
he's gonna make it to the top
by arresting his own people?
Pass the mushu.
He'll see.
- He'll learn.
- We have a vowel.
"F"- in' right,
and you be proud of it.
Jesus christ, you'd think
there never was a michelangelo
the way they treat people.
Did you know that an italian
invented the telephone?
- Alexander graham bell
was italian?
- You see?
You see what i'm talkin'--
antonio meucci invented the
telephone and he got robbed!
Everybody knows that.
Who invented the mafia?
What?
La cosa nostra,
who invented that?
- Who cares?
- Wasn't it salvatore lucana,
better known as
charlie "lucky" luciano who
organized the five families?
Lucchese, gambino,
bonnano, profaci.
Is there somethin'
you wanna say to me?
I just like history,
like you, dad.
- Can you just shut
the fuck up about it?
- Hey!
Hey!
A. J. , did you know that
john cabot was italian?
Whoa.
- Like he knows who that is.
- It's the famous discoverer
of canada.
The bank of america.
You ever heard of it?
One of the biggest banks
in the world,
started by an italian.
The first american saint
was italian-- mother cabrini.
That's right.
Is it true that the chinese
invented spaghetti?
Now think about it.
Why would people
who eat with sticks...
invent something that
you need a fork to eat?
And here's something else
i bet you didn't know.
More italians fought for
this country in world war ii
than any other ethnic group.
And they won't tell you about
sacco and vanzetti either.
The two antichrists
that got the electric chair
in massachusetts?
- Anarchists.
- Isn't it antichrists?
They were two innocent men
who got the chair
because they were italian.
How can there be
two antichrists?
There was only one christ.
- So?
- And of course,
francis albert.
Will i see you next week?
Unless you know somethin'
i don't.
Just so you understand,
that i have to charge you
for the missed session.
What are you talkin' about?
We agreed on that
on our very first meeting.
I know, but i just explained
to you my situation.
I understand,
but it's important that
we respect the agreement.
- What if i got hit by a car?
- But you weren't.
- I know, but what if?
- I know that, but, but what if?
- You weren't.
- Why don't you answer
my fuckin' question?
- I will not.
You won't?
All right, fine, fine.
Here. Here you go.
Of course, 'cause this is what
it's all about? Motherfuckin',
cocksuckin' money!
Here.
I don't understand that comment,
and i don't appreciate
being made to feel afraid.
I don't appreciate feelin' like
i pour my heart out
to a fuckin' call girl.
- Is that how you see me?
- Not until now.
But it's obvious you don't
give a shit about my situation
or what's happenin' with me!
Otherwise, you wouldn't
be shakin' me down.
It'll show as "paid"
on your next month's bill.
Fine.
Stick it up your ass.
And how about dr. Goldman
over here?
Originally, he was gonna be
a tree surgeon, but he fainted
at the sight of sap.
Sap, ladies and gentlemen.
Pace yourselves.
Don't spend it all
in one place.
Movie night, right?
Last week they showed
the polish version ofrashomon.
Everybody remembers
the rape exactly the same.
The'60s--
what's the matter
with you, corrado?
Headaches, that's all.
Not the kind you take
aspirin for.
Now, tonight on our show,
we have mitzi gaynor,
sergio franchi
and a woman from france...
who will pull
a string of lightbulbs
out of her husband's throat.
This woman can relate.
I think we may have
a bad apple.
Does tony know about this?
What are you gonna do?
There's not much to do.
We have to sit back and wait.
And do me a favor,
don't let tony know you know.
He's under enough pressure.
I'm sure he's tellin'
his psychiatrist
it's all his mother's fault.
- What are you talkin'
about, a psychiatrist?
- Yeah, a psychiatrist.
He's been seein' one
for a while now.
God only knows what he says.
- Tony?
- Yes, tony.
Tony, who had
such a terrible mother.
- A psychiatrist?
- Yes, junior.
For christ's sake!
Show of hands.
How many people think j. F. K.
Is still alive? Come on.
They should take
a zapruder film
of your salad bar?
Hello? Help me out.
Who?
The psychiatrist, i mean.
Do you think i know?
What did you say
to tony about this?
Me?
Nothin'. I wouldn't give him
the satisfaction.
And, junior, i don't want
there to be any repercussions.
A psychiatrist?
You're a broken record.
Yes, yes.
Shh.
Do i have to--
this lady is blind. Dear,
i have a few words for you.
Do i have to say it again?
They are lucy in the sky
with diamonds.
All right?
Picture yourself in a boat
at ellis island.
All right,
how does that sound?
It's me. Leave a message.
Christopher? It's mommy.
I know you're there.
Pick it up.
Are you all right?
I'm worried about you.
My god, they mentioned your name
in the newspaper today.
Thestar- ledger.
Mrs. Jones told me.
With all those scumbags.
It's been a while
since we met for therapy.
Mm- hmm.
Jason, how's bard?
I'm moving into
a smoke- free dorm.
And how do we feel
about that?
I'm more interested
in discussing what
we mentioned before.
Jason, are you concerned
that your mother is treating
this patient x?
I don't care.
As a colleague, jen,
i suggest you drop the patient.
After her
last encounter with him,
she finally acknowledged...
that she saw the different side
of him-- the subhuman.
I take it you were frightened.
Frightened, revolted.
At long last,
appropriate emotions.
Oh, for christ's sake, richard.
You too, sam.
- When did we become so afraid
to get our hands dirty?
- It's what she gets paid for.
Jason, how would you like
to see your mother--
never mind.
I'm not gonna paint
any graphic images.
See?
He always does that.
- What?
- Follow that up, jas.
Dad does what?
His real issue is that
i should distance myself
from this man...
on the grounds of the stigma
that he brings us.
I say, refer this patient
to a therapist...
that specializes
in mafia depression.
- Sam, this isn't funny.
- No, of course not.
Jen has a real honest
to goodness personal...
and professional dilemma.
You know,
on my mother's side
we have a few dark sheep.
Excuse me?
Lepke.
Who's lepke?
Louis lepke buchalter.
You know.
Murder incorporated.
My mother's uncle
was lepke's wheel man.
His driver.
Uh- huh.
Those were some tough jews.
Closed- captioned by
captions, inc. Los angeles