So, you know...
usual girl stuff.
She picks up the dry cleaning.
She does the food shopping.
By the way,
your dr. Melfi
has excellent taste.
She only shops at
the fancy- shmancy deli--
the kind with the italian name
but you can't find a fuckin'
meatball in the whole joint.
What else?
I don't even know what i'm
supposed to be lookin' for.
What's up with this cooze?
It's none of your fuckin'
business. You're on a strict
need- to- know, lieutenant.
I oughta knock the shit
outta ya for what you did
to her date last month.
What? I figure this girl
is somegoomahof yours,
so i scare him a little.
What's the big deal?
This guy
still come around?
No.
He's not her type.
I told ya, he's a coward.
He nearly pissed himself.
All right, anything else?
I don't wanna be here all day.
Yesterday--
yesterday she got off at 9:00
and she went to bed early.
That's it?
That's it.
Here.
Buy yourself an iron.
You ready?
Decaf, right?
So, how was your college trip
with your daughter?
Tell ya, my life,
it's like, uh,
episode of
provolone somethin'.
- What's goin' on?
- My wife. All we do is fight.
Can you believe it?
She's jealous of you.
Is that something that you feel,
or has there been some
discussion with carmela?
She didn't know
you were a girl.
You know, a woman.
Excuse me, a doctor.
Woman doctor.
Why did it take you
so long to tell her?
I didn't tell her.
You spilled the beans
when you called
to change the appointment.
Let me ask you a different
question. Why a female?
Why a female doctor?
You know, she asked
the same friggin' question.
I sometimes wonder myself.
And?
I'll tell you
what i told her.
Cusomano gave me a choice
between two jewish guys
and apaisanlike me.
- I picked thepaisan.
- What's the one thing
every woman--
your mother, your wife,
your daughter--
have in common?
- They all break my balls.
-
no, i know what you mean.
They're all italian. So what?
So maybe by
coming clean with me,
you're dialoguing with them.
Let me ask you a question.
Why do you have me
as a patient?
Most legit people, they'd go a
hundred miles out of their way
not to make eye contact with me.
But you--
you didn't flinch.
The water's warm.
Come on in.
Hey, sammy.
How are you?
Just in time.
I was just gonna
make some coffee.
Yeah?
How's junior?
Sit the fuck down!
Down!
That's how junior is, sammy.
I'm with
little jimmy altieri.
Yeah? You payin' jimmy
for this game?
Huh, sammy?
No.
Are you payin'someone
for this game?
Huh?
Aah!
The party's over.
Junior soprano is the new boss
and he ain't respectin'
old arrangements.
You're lucky.
You stayed slim.
You can buy
right off the rack.
I wanted something special.
The boys are having
a little time for me.
You're wearin'
the suit to
the dinner, eh?
These guys today,
they want to be buried
in their joggin' outfit.
So how's your, uh--
what's your
oldest boy's name?
Rafaelle. Ralphie.
Yeah. Good kid.
Yeah.
He lost his son, you know.
- What do you mean, lost?
- Dead. Morte.
Ah, just a--
just a fucking kid.
A baby.
Oh, what are we
talkin' about here?
You lost your grandson?
What are you gonna do?
These fucking animals.
These--
these drug dealers.
The little kid used to run
around here breakin' balls.
Domonique.
My namesake.
Did you know about this?
See? What'd i say
about this fucking poison?
These kids
shouldn't touch it.
I read the paper every day
about these poor pricks
overdosin'.
He didn't overdose.
He killed himself.
Fourteen years old.
Jesus!
Was this at
patterson falls?
- Holy shit!
That was your grandson?
- Why?
The kid, he took one of those
designer drugs, right?
Goes to the falls,
takes a header
right off the fence.
They said the current whirled
so much that his head was
bashin' on the rocks for days...
before he even came up.
And meanwhile,
this piece of shit...
he gets to walk the streets
and sell more of this stuff
to young kids.
Oh, really?
What's this
motherless fuck's name?
Even the coffee's old in here.
How much complaining
can you do?
Eventually they find you
with a broken hip.
I want to make a gift of
a maganet. That's the only
way you'll get good coffee.
What are you wearing?
You smell like a frenchputa.
It's canoe.
Johnny wore canoe.
Morning, livia.
Oh, good morning.
Morning.
Hi.
New arrival?
Keep moving, fella.
I'm happy for you, junior.
I know how long you waited
to be made boss.
Just don't let certain people
take advantage of your good
nature like they did to johnny.
What certain people?
Nobody got over on johnny.
Nobody's gonna
get over on me.
How's your jewish friend?
- Hesh? What about him?
- Who ever heard of a jew
riding horses?
- He owns a horse farm.
- Aahh!
He's tony's friend, not mine.
What do you got
against him anyway?
Who, me? Nothing.
Johnny liked him, and my son
thinks that every word
that comes out of his mouth...
is pure gold.
Are you tellin' me that
since i'm the new boss
i should tax hesh?
Heh!
Boy, anthony must've really
gotten under your collar.
Admit it.
You're lookin'
to crack hiscalione
for puttin' you in here.
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
Yeah.
And i'm playin'
shortstop for the mets.
Oh, all right,
watch the balls!
What is the matter?
Tony's cannoli doesn't want
to stand up?
Tony's cannoli's tired.
But i can make it
happen, baby.
I know.
It's just, maybe--
so how's your job?
Huh?
Since when do you
care about my job?
Can't i be nice?
All right. Forget it.
Mmm.
Okay, you don't want to talk
about your job? Fine.
Here. Tell somebody
who gives a fuck.
I'm not a fucking whore!
Stick your money up your ass.
I don't know
what's wrong with you,
but don't take it out on me.
Hey, there's nothing wrong
with me! Just wanted
to talk, that's all.
For all the conversation
i get around here, i might
as well be a fuckin' dildo!
If you were a dildo,
we wouldn't be fighting.
What does that mean?
Huh, you fuckin' refugee?
- Aah!
-
come here!
Knock you out,
you fuckin' communist cunt!
Hey, hey, hey!
Yeah, same to you!
You fuckin' burned me!
Angela.
What do you got, andrea?
Clabby?
Hearts.
Jump in,
the water's warm.
Child's play.
Pound a point.
Hesh is outside.
Tell him to come in.
He says he needs
a word with you.
What the fuck.
I've eaten more queens
than lancelot.
What's up?
Let's walk.
That serious?
You spoke to
your uncle lately?
Junior? Yeah.
No.
I don't know.
Why? What's up?
Your father was
a fair man, tony.
What's that got to do
with junior?
Junior's not so fair.
Sometimes i wish
you'd just get to
the fuckin' point.
What'd he do?
He's taxing me,
tony.
He's taxing you?
When did this happen?
Today.
Did you tell him you operated
for years without any tax?
That my father loved you
and respected you?
That ten cents
out of every dollar
that goes into his kick...
is directly related
to your shylock business?
My uncle's been boss of
the family ten fuckin' minutes,
already i gotagita.
What'd you tell him?
Told him the truth.
It's a reasonable request
but an unreasonable figure.
Back up a minute.
What do you mean,
"it's a reasonable request"?
He's the boss now.
He can call the tune, we all
dance to it. That's the way
it's always been done.
You can either respect
what's been done in the past
or change the rules.
Look, tony, the reason
i came over here was to tell you
with all this bullshit goin' on,
i don't know if i can
stay in this area.
Where you gonna go?
Hey, come on. I can sit on my
royalty checks. You forget
i wrote six gold records.
No, a couple of black kids
wrote six gold records.
You owned the company.
You gave yourself a co- writing
credit. Come on, hesh.
Besides, i know you.
You leave this action,
you're gonna kill yourself.
How much does he want?
Five hundred large,
plus two points monthly
on my shy.
Hm! All right.
Do me a favor.
Sit tight for now.
Let me think about it
for a while.
How was that, baby?
The best.
You are the best.
Come here.
Tony, i love your cannoli.
You okay?
Yeah, i'm okay.
Go back to your sleep.
Sure you're all right?
So, what do you want
new york to do?
First of all,
junior can't know
that we talked.
He's gotta think
hesh came to you
on his own by himself.
You are still
runnin' things.
Another thing,
the arrangement, whatever it is,
can't be insulting to my uncle.
Hesh's gotta pay
somethin',
i just haven't
decided what.
I gotta get back.
We'll talk later.
How's the veal?
It's like rubber.
Yeah?
Tastes all right to me.
Want somethin' else?
No.
Hm.
Don't look at me.
Compliments of johnny sack.
Maybe you'd like to spend
the rest of our anniversary
with him.
I was over there for
ten friggin' minutes, carmela.
Don't do this.
All right, tony.
At least i know
where i stand.
Why you always gotta be
so dramatic, huh?
Here we go.
Huh!
All right, i'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
You don't even know what
you're apologizing for.
It's our anniversary, tony.
Ours.
Not yours, mine
and johnny fuckin' sacks'.
Ours.
Here i was thinkin' maybe we
could get a room at the plaza
like last year, or--
i don't know.
I do--
i'm sorry, carmela.
Huh?
I just got a lot on my mind,
and i'm not thinkin' straight.
Hey. I'm sorry.
Should i call the plaza?
Come on.
Nah, let's go home.
Hey, come here.
Carmela, what do you
want me to say?
I'm lost at sea here.
You've changed, tony,
and i resent it.
I resent it because it's
destroying what little
self- esteem i have left.
I swear, sometimes i think
you skeeve me.
I skeeve you?
You're the mother
of my children.
How the fuck did i skeeve you?
You see what
i'm talkin' about?
Right there.
"You're the mother
of my children."
I feel like i'm just
someone you've chosen
to procreate with.
You knew this might happen
with the prozac.
Ginny torrelli's
been on it for years
and she'd hump a fire hydrant...
if it could make a pass at her.
Dr. Melfi told me it affects
different people different ways.
Oh. She told you that?
I think before we start
today's session,
we need to address
the coffee situation.
It's not appropriate
of me to take gifts.
- It's a cup of coffee.
- Let's just make a rule, okay?
No gifts.
This mean i can't
drink mine?
No, no.
I'm sorry. I usually have
my answering service on
when i have a patient,
but i have
a car emergency.
Yes?
What does that mean,
"diagnostic"?
I just wanna know
what's wrong with my car.
No.
No, don't do anything.
No, i want to get
a second opinion.
I'll-- i'll take my chances.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
It's all right.
So...how's it goin'?
Good. Real good.
As a matter of fact,
i think i may flush
the medication.
You know? See if the changes
i'm feelin' are for real.
Why would you do that?
The prozac seems to be working.
Well, that might be the problem.
It might be workin'
a little overtime.
What do you mean?
Umm--
- i'm havin' a, uh--
- reaction?
You know.
A side effect from the stuff.
We talked about that
when you started.
Some people get insomnia;
others a stomach ache
or headaches.
- But it usually passes.
- Are there any other side
effects that you know of?
Some people experience
a diminished libido.
- They have a hard time
getting or maintaining a--
- bingo.
I see.
Mm.
You know, not all impotence
is a result of the medication.
You sayin' there's
somethin' wrong with me?
When's the last time
you had a prostate exam?
Hey, i don't even let anybody
wag their finger in myface!
I'm sorry,
i shouldn't have laughed!
- Don't apologize.
- Oh, boy.
- You got a nice laugh.
- All right, let's be serious.
Hey, i'm serious.
You know that depression
is also a leading factor
in impotence.
When you awaken in the morning
or in the middle of the night,
do you ever have an erection?
- You could set your clock to it.
- Okay, so we know it's not
a physical problem.
Let's put that in
after the credenza.
Yes, ma'am.
You wanna tell me
what's goin' on?
I bought some furniture.
Why don't we just
move into roche bobois?
Save the delivery charge.
Fine.
I'll send it back.
No, but you've been spendin'
like a drunken sailor
all last week.
I said
i'll send it back.
Mother of christ, carmela,
i didn't say that, did i?
Jesus.
All due respect to new york,
i don't think you should be
tellin' my uncle
how to run things.
You think i got the balls
to drive in from new york...
and tell your uncle
how he should run
his family?
I shouldn't expect to see
the statue of liberty again
if i did that, huh?
- All right, look, tony. -
hesh isn't only
a friend of you guys.
He's a friend of ours.
Somebody has to step in
so he doesn't get fucked.
I never said fucked.
And you.
Frankly, i'm a little hurt.
You should've come to me first.
- Airin' your dirty laundry
in public.
- Junior knew how i felt.
How would it look if i went
to you after i spoke to him?
He's got a point.
Bottom line is,
what're we gonna do about this?
Somethin' tells me you
have a suggestion.
Junior,
if there're any flies on you,
they're payin' fuckin' rent.
Five hundred is a little steep
for back taxes, no?
As far as two percent
of his action,
that's up to you to settle.
After all, that affects tony
as much as hesh.
I'm not out to hurt anyone.
God forbid i get in the way
of someone earning.
Let's say one and a half
on the shy business
and 300 on the back tax.
Two fifty.
What'd i tell ya? Hold onto
your cock when you negotiate
with these desert people.
Two fifty.
All right.
Mr. Soprano.
You want sex?
No.
Go back to sleep.
You know, you have a nice body.
You ought to make it
work for you more.
Oh, really?
You reveal too much.
You don't want other men
looking at me?
No.
When you're not with me
you do what you want.
But i'm sayin' maybe
you could wear a nice,
businesslike outfit.
I think i could
get into that.
You want me to dress
like a man?
No.
No, you fuckin' wack- a- doo,
i don't want you to dress
like a man.
I'm just sayin',
maybe wear somethin'
a little more professional.
You know,
like you're in business.
Fuck you. I'm no whore.
No. That's not what i mean.
Not like you're in
the whore business.
Oh, forget it.
Come here.
Is everybody in my life
bananas or what?
Get over here!
Come here.
Go jerk off.
Yeah.
Look at this.
She burned me.
That's not good.
What led up to that?
Carmela can be
pretty violent sometimes.
This added problem
that i've been havin'
that we talked about--
i just thought that maybe
we needed to spice things up
a little bit. You know?
If it's not the prozac,
then maybe i just needed
a little jump start.
So i suggest to her that maybe
she dress a little differently.
Something titillating.
Yeah.
You know, maybe it'd help.
So i suggested to her--
not demanded--
suggested--
you know, maybe dress
a little sexier.
But carmela
can be very sensitive.
Maybe she felt
it degraded her.
Not all women
are into sexy lingerie.
I'm not talkin' about
dressin' like that.
Then what are we
talking about?
Some women are sexier
when they dress simple.
You know, understated.
I don't mean--
fuck it.
I don't know what i mean.
Like you.
How like me?
You play it down.
Now, it's obvious you got
a killer body under there.
Don't get me wrong.
All right.
Not only do you
play it down,
but you're gentle.
Not loud.
Sweet sounding...
like a mandolin.
Anthony--
it's unfortunate that
we have to stop now,
because i think
it's really important
we talk about this.
Do you think you could
come back later
this afternoon?
No.
Till tuesday.
Okay?
Yeah, all right.
See you tuesday.
Oh, motherfucker!
Ow.
Shit!
It's the oddest thing.
I've had this problem for weeks,
but this morning i get in
and it starts right up.
- And then again at the deli.
- Uh, looks fine.
Are you sure?
I was told i need a new starter.
Lady, as much as
i might wish to rob you...
even i wouldn't try to replace
a new starter with another.
- What do you mean "new"?
- New. It has everything but
the price tag hanging from it.
Come on, mikey!
I didn't do nothin'!
Poor kid
committed suicide
up here'cause of you.
You fuckin' know me!
Yeah, i know ya.
Now listen to me.
I'm gonna give ya a break.
When i toss ya over--
no!
If you can fly
i won't shoot you down.
Deal?
No!
Son of a bitch.
My goodness.
What happened here?
It's some sad shit.
Motherfucker said he didn't
want to live no more.
He jumped.
How much he give you?
I thought i was the only one
junior could make look
like that.
All right.
Let me hear it.
Rusty irish.
What about him?
He took a header off the falls.
That's the closest that
junkie fuck ever got to a bath.
I got news for you.
That junkie fuck
was my biggest earner.
During the football season
he moved more cards
than ten guys put together.
And another thing.
A certain friend of ours
should've checked with me...
before he did a favor
for the old man capri.
You're losin' me.
Irish was the one who sold
capri's grandson that shit.
I think you created
a fuckin' frankenstein
in junior.
I created?
We all agreed to let
junior have his day.
Let him be the lightning rod.
When lightning strikes, god
forbid, and somebody goes down,
it's not a young man
with a family, remember?
- We all agreed.
- Yeah, but who expected
to get raped?
When jackie was acting boss no
one minded, 'cause it all evened
out at the end of the day.
But your uncle-- marone!
Doesheeat alone.
He doesn't even
pass the salt.
Heh heh.
What about that
sammy grigio card game?
That fuckin' mikey
smacked him around.
That ain't right.
Come on, jimmy.
Even a broken clock
is right twice a day.
Junior was right.
He had a position.
That game wasn't payin' anybody.
The minute sammy grigio used
jimmy's name, it should've
been end of story.
- That's right.
-
what do you want me to do?
We made our bed. We sleep
in it. We're all men.
But how long we gonna
continue to kick upstairs
without it hurtin'?
I mean something, anything,
should trickle down over here,
no?
All we want you to do
is talk to him.
After all, he's your uncle.
- Come on.
- That's right.
Who is it?
It's me, ma.
Who?
Anthony.
Open the door.
I thought you were
the activities lady.
Hey.
She's a real pain
in the ass.
Playing bingo,
livia?
Not tonight,
honey.
You know, she's a
degenerate gambler.
Uh, millie?
Millie?
Hmm?
My son.
Handsome.
So how's it goin'?
Oh, what can i say?
Hey, this is great.
The only thing that's missin'
is that broken readin' lamp
you had by the phone.
I got it downstairs.
I can bring it if you want.
Shh, shh, shh.
Listen.
Oh, she's
driving me crazy.
Who?
Next door!
There it is again.
Oh!
That's enough water!
How much water
does she need?
She runs
the water all day.
Water, water, water!
I'm livin' next door
to gunga din!
I went down to ferrara's.
I got you some biscotti.
Almonds?
Yeah.
All right.
Leave'em there.
I'll take'em
downstairs later
for my coffee.
Uncle jun been by?
Oh...once in a while.
It makes him
uncomfortable here.
He's got a lot on his mind.
More responsibilities
means more headaches.
Better men than him
had to work hard.
Yeah.
He'll be all right...
long as he remembers
who his friends are.
I'd just hate to see him mess
this up. He's been waitin'
a long time for the big chair.
What do you mean?
It's not a business that
forgives bad decisions.
I hate to see him making
wrong moves, you know?
Especially at the start
of the game.
Why're you tellin' me?
- Tell him.
- Ma...you got his ear.
He listens to you.
I don't know that world.
No, of course not.
But if anything, you know,
were to come up--
that's all.
I don't want
to get involved.
If you have something
to say to your uncle
then bring it up to him.
Oh, i wish the lord
would take me.
Come on, ma.
There's probably plenty of gents
in this place that want a date
with a lovely woman like you.
Look, i'm goin'
downstairs...
before that
activities lady finds me.
You want coffee?
Yeah, all right.
Bring my cookies!
Carmela, i don't
want to sound like...
religion is a cure- all,
but i think if tony
got more involved
with the church...
it may help to expedite
things in his therapy.
What's killing me
is this is
a self- inflicted wound.
I pushed for it.
I could deal with thegoomahs.
I knew i was better than them.
As stupid as it sounds,
i viewed them as a form
of masturbation for him.
I couldn't give him
what he needed all the time.
You're a man, father.
You know that thirst.
I was too busy with
the house and kids
to quench it.
But the psychiatrist--
you know, she's not
just agoomah.
For the first time i feel
like he's really cheating...
and i'm the one
who's thirsty.
I'm not gonna stay in
a marriage that's made--
shh. Shh.
Let's not even
think about that.
Divorce is for the weak,
for people who never
intended on dying married
in the first place.
You know, carm,
we reap what we sow.
What do you mean?
You admit to accepting
his dalliances in the past.
They meant nothing to tony.
But you said
it was like they were
lightening the workload,
providing a wife's duty
when you were too busy
with the kids and the house.
You practically
welcomed it.
I want you to pray
to our holy mother.
Ask her for guidance
and forgiveness...
so that you can get
through this as a couple.
You're not without sin
in this, carmela.
She's outta control.
She's spendin' money like we're
the sopranos of park avenue.
But you've noticed her,
which may have been
the point.
Look, before we
run out of time,
i'd like to discuss
what happened when
we were here last week.
How's your car?
Did you steal my car
and have it fixed?
We had an agreement:
No gifts.
I didn't want
to see you get robbed.
It was you.
You had no right
to steal my car.
- I've been scared to death.
- Why?
It's a violation of my privacy.
What else have you done?
Answer me.
I love you.
Anthony--
i'm in love with you.
I'm sorry.
That's just the way it is.
Okay, let me talk.
No.
It's not the prozac.
I dream about you.
I think about you
all the time.
I can't get excited
about any other women.
There's nothing else
to say.
I love you.
Let me start here.
I know this may be
very hard for you
to swallow,
but you're only feeling
this way because we've
made such progress.
What?
I've been gentle.
That's my job.
I listen.
That's what i do best.
I've been a broad, generic
sympathetic woman to you,
because that's what
this work calls for.
You've made me all of
the things you feel are
missing in your wife...
and in your mother.
You're makin' me out to be
some fuckin' mama's boy.
I'm a man...
and you're a woman.
End of story.
And this crap about freud
and every boy wanting to have
sex with his mother--
that's not gonna fly here.
I didn't say that.
I want to make sure we
understand each other.
Yeah, we understand
each other.
You don't love me.
You don't want me to come
back any more, fine.
It's quite the opposite.
This is all a byproduct
of progress.
Has someone been
following me?
Okay, forget it.
I'll see you next week.
All right! Let's go!
Move it!
Remember when you
used to tell me--
i always thought you could make
the pros. You coulda done it.
You had a swing like joe di.
You're crazy.
What, you think
i'm shittin' you?
Yeah, i could barely
hit. 250.
That's because
you didn't want it.
Too busy chasin' skirt.
Chasin' skirt,
your average was. 500.
- Yeah, what happened?
- So what is it you want
to talk about?
Octavian.
You know, augustus.
You fuckin' with me?
No.
Octavian became augustus.
Forget about that.
Bottom line:
Augustus was a caesar--
and everybody loved him,
right?
You know why?
I don't know
that i give a fuck.
Everybody loved him
'cause he never ate alone.
Capisci?
It was the longest time
of peace in rome's history.
He was a fair leader,
and all his people
loved him for that.
This the one that they
stabbed in the back?
No, that was julius.
I'm talkin' about augustus.
He shared his wealth,
and all his people loved him.
You said that three fuckin'
times. I heard it."his people
loved him." what's your point?
Remember the story you told me
about the father bull
talkin' to the son?
They're up on this hill.
They're lookin' down
on a bunch of cows.
The son goes to the father,
"dad, why don't we run
down there and fuck
one of these cows?"
You remember what
the father said?
Father says,
"son, why don't we walk down
there and fuck'em all?"
I told you that?
Yeah!
Why don't we
fuck'em all!
That's funny.
Okay, i get your point.
Why don't you just
come out with it...
instead of all this
augustus- octavian shit?
I don't know.
Are you okay?
You been actin'
mesamortelately.
I ain't seen
a long face like that
since you were a kid.
I'm okay. It's just,
uh...bullshit stuff.
Don't worry about it.
You sure?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm okay.
Junior took the 250
you gave him and whacked it up
amongst the top five guys.
You know, so he doesn't
look greedy.
Smart move.
Yeah.
Your uncle may turn out
to be another harry truman.
What's that mean?
Truman had a big job
thrust upon him.
He didn't want it,
but in the end he made
some pretty wise decisions.
So who knows?
Your uncle may turn out to be
the right man for the job.
I fuckin' hope so,
'cause i'll tell you right now,
i don't want the fuckin' job.
Let junior die
from the stress.
It's what gave
jackie the cancer,
god rest his soul.
"Boss."
Fuck it.
Who needs it?
- It's nice here.
- I can't stand the smell.
Shit, flies all over
the place.
But i could stand here for hours
and watch'em run around.
There's a kind of beauty to it.
I envy them.
I wouldn't go that far.
I would.
They got no bills,
no headaches,
no familycazies
runnin' around.
One horse likes another horse,
they go up to each other,
they fuck. That's it.
No problems,
no hundred questions,
no guilt.
I don't know what the fuck
i'm talkin' about.
So junior whacked up my money
and spread it around, huh?
Yeah.
Five bosses, 50 a pop.
Not a bad day's pay.
Still, i wish it
wasn't your money.
You know, it makes me
feel terrible.
What?
You old fuckin' jew.
Here's my share.
You think i'm gonna
profit off your tax?
Never entered my mind.
Dr. Melfi--
there's nothin' there,
you know.
You don't have to
explain nothin',
tony.
This psychiatry shit--
apparently, what you're feelin'
is not what you're feelin',
and what you're not feelin'
is your real agenda.
You're gonna stick with it,
right?
I don't know.
Think you should.
You do?
Uh- huh.
I was jealous.
I should've told you--
no, wait.
Let me finish, tony.
I've been thinkin'
a lot about this.
I was jealous of her ability
to help you--
to be a sort of
salvation to you.
I talked to father phil,
and...
i wanna be that woman
in your life.
Carm, you aren't just
in my life.
You are my life.
Come here.
Okay, i'm no good
at speeches.
Yeah,
you owe him a fuckin' dime,
you'll hear some great speeches.
- Shut up. Let me talk. -
go ahead, talk.
I was only kiddin'. Go ahead.
I'd like everybody
to raise their glasses.
Okay, uh--
he taught me
as much as anybody,
'cept for maybe my father.
Even if he wasn't my uncle,
i'd be
standin' here sayin'...
- to our new boss, salud.
-
to junior.
Junior.
To junior.
Salud.