It's...
Monty python's flying circus.
Good afternoon.
Afternoon.
Ah... lovely day,
isn't it?
Ar... 'tis that.
Are you here
on holiday or...?
No, no, I live here.
Oh, jolly good.
I say, those are sheep,
aren't they?
Ar.
Yes, yes, of course,
I thought so.
Only... why are they
up in the trees?
A fair question
And one that
in recent weeks
Has been much
on my mind.
It is my
considered opinion
That they're nesting.
Nesting?
Like birds?
Ar... exactly.
Birds is the key
to the whole problem.
It's my belief
that these sheep are laboring
Under the misapprehension
that they're birds.
Observe their behavior.
Take for a start
the sheep's tendency
To hop about the field
on their back legs.
Now witness their attempts
to fly from tree to tree.
Notice they do not
so much fly as plummet.
Observe, for example,
that ewe in that oak tree.
She is clearly trying
to teach her lamb to fly.
Talk about the blind
leading the blind.
But why do they think
they're birds?
Another fair question.
One thing is for sure:
A sheep is not
a creature of the air.
It has enormous
difficulty
In the comparatively
simple act of perching.
As you see.
As for flight, its body
is totally unadapted
To the problems
of aviation.
Trouble is,
sheep are very dim.
And once they get an idea
into their heads
There's no shifting it.
But where do they get
the idea from?
From harold.
He's that sheep over
there under the elm.
He's that most dangerous
of animals--
A clever sheep.
He's the ringleader.
He's realized
the sheep's life consists
Of standing around
for a few months
And then being eaten.
And that's
a depressing prospect
For an ambitious sheep.
He's patently hit
on the idea of escape.
But why don't you just
get rid of harold?
Because of the enormous
commercial possibilities
Should he succeed.
and what exactlyare
the commercial possibilities
of a vine a viation?
bonsoir.
ici nous avons
les diagrammes modernes
d'un mouton anglo-francais
ce n'est pas...
maintenant...
Baa, baa, baa.
nous avons, dans
la tete, le cabine.
tres bon.
ici, ou se trouve
le petit capitaine anglais,
un monsieur trubshawe.
Vive brian,
wherever you are.
d'accord, d'accord.
maintenant, je vous
presente mon collegue
le pouf celebre,
jean-brian jatapathique.
maintenant,
le mouton...
Le landing...
Les wheels, bon.
bon.
Les wheels, ici.
c'est formidable,
n'est-ce pas?
est bon, ooh, ah.
de la machine...
de la a vion...
de la baa, baa, baa.
Ooh, ooh, ooh, baa.
de la derriere
du mouton...
Chug, chug, chug.
ah, merci beaucoup.
suivez la piste.
tais-toi.
pardon.
pas de tout.
mais...
ou sont les bagages?
ou... les voyageurs?
les voyageurs.
Gaspard?
merci.
les voyageurs.
les bagages.
ils sont... ici!
premiere classe,
deuxieme classe...
et maintenant...
Baa, baa, baa.
Maa, maa, maa.
comme ca...
demonstration
fantastique.
sur trois...
un, deux trois.
maa, maa, maa, maa, maa, maa...
We get a lot of french people
around here.
Oh, yes.
All over, yes.
And how do
you get on
With these
french people?
Oh, very well.
So do i.
Me, too.
So does
mrs. ames.
Yes, yes.
Yes, I like them.
I mean, they think
well, don't they?
I mean, be fair...
pascal.
Mm, blaise
Jean-paul sartre.
Yes, voltaire.
Ooh.
Rene
descartes.
Hmm... hmm.
Hmm!
And now for something
completely different--
A man with three buttocks.
Good evening.
I have with me
mr. arthur frampton
Who has...
Mr. frampton, I understand
that you, as it were
Have...
Well, let me put it
another way.
I believe, mr. frampton
That whereas
most people have two...
Two...
You... you.
I'm sorry?
Ah, yes...
yes, I see.
Um... are you
quite comfortable?
Yes, fine, thank you.
Um... mr. frampton...
Vis-a-vis your rump.
I beg your pardon?
Your rump.
What?
Your... posterior.
Derriere.
Sit-upon.
What's that?
Buttocks.
Oh, me bum!
Shh.
Well, mr. frampton,
I understand, mr. frampton
You have a 50% bonus
In the region
of what you said.
I've got three cheeks.
Yes, yes,
splendid, splendid.
Well, we were wondering,
mr. frampton
If you could
see your way clear...
Here, what's that
camera doing?
Nothing, nothing,
nothing at all, mister.
We were wondering if you
could see your way clear
To giving us a quick...
A quick visual...
Mr. frampton, will you take
your trousers down?
What? get off!
I'm not taking me trousers off
on television.
Please take them down.
No.
Just a little bit.
Now...
Now, look here, mr. frampton
It's perfectly easy for somebody
Just to come along here
to the bbc
Simply claiming that they have
A bit to spare
in the botty department.
The point is, mr. frampton,
our viewers need proof.
I've been
on persian radio.
Get off!
Arthur figgis knows
I've got three buttocks.
How?
We go cycling
together.
'strewth!
And now for something
completely different--
A man with three buttocks.
Good evening.
I have with me
mr. arthur frampton who...
Mr. frampton, I understand
that you, as it were
Have...
Well, let me put it
another way.
I believe, mr. frampton,
that whereas most people...
Didn't we do this just now?
Why, yes.
Well, why didn't you say so?
I thought it was
a continental version.
And now for something
completely the same--
A man with three buttocks.
Hello.
Oh, did we?
And now for something
completely different--
A man with three noses.
He's not here yet!
Two noses?
Ladies and gentlemen,
wasn't she just great, eh?
Wasn't she just great?
And she can run as fast
as she can sing.
And I'm telling you
because I know.
No, only kidding.
Seriously now,
ladies and gentlemen
We have for you one of the most
unique acts in the world today.
He's... well, I'll say no more
And just let you see
for yourselves.
Ladies and gentlemen, my very
great privilege to introduce
Arthur ewing
and his musical mice!
Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have in this box
23 white mice--
Mice which have been
painstakingly trained
Over the past few years
to squeak at a selected pitch.
This is e-sharp.
And this one is g.
You get the general idea.
Now, these mice are so arranged
upon this rack
That when played
in the correct order
They will squeak
"the bells of st. mary."
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you, on the mouse organ
"the bells of st. mary."
Thank you.
Oh, my god!
Oh, stop him!
Stop him!
For god's sake,
stop him!
Next.
Are you the marriage
guidance counselor?
Yes-- good morning.
Morning, sir.
And good morning to you,
madam.
Name?
Mr. and mrs. arthur pewtey...
pewtey.
And what is the name
of your ravishing wife?
Wait!
Don't tell me.
It's something
to do with moonlight.
It goes with her eyes.
It's soft and gentle,
warm and yielding
Deeply lyrical and yet
tender and frightened
Like a tiny white rabbit.
It's deirdre.
Deirdre...
what a beautiful name.
What a beautiful,
beautiful name.
And what seems
to be the trouble
With your marriage,
mr. pewtey?
Well, it all started
about five years ago.
We started going on holiday
to brighton together.
Deirdre, that's my wife,
has always been
A very good
companion to me.
I never particularly anticipated
any marital strife.
Indeed, the very idea
Of consulting a professional
marital advisor
Has always been of
the greatest repugnance to me.
Although, far be it from me
To impugn the nature of
your trade or profession.
Do go on.
Well, as I say, we've always
been good friends
Sharing the interests,
the gardening and so on
The model airplanes
The sixpenny bottle
for the holiday money
And, indeed,
twice in the month
Setting down in the evening
to do the accounts
Something which deirdre...
deirdre, that's my wife
Particularly looked forward to
on account of her feet.
I should probably have
said at the outset
That I'm noted for having
something of a sense of humor
Although I've kept myself
Pretty much to myself
over the last two years
Notwithstanding, as it were.
And it's only been
comparatively recently
That I've begun
to realize...
Well, perhaps "realize" is
not the correct word.
Imagine... imagine
That I was not the only thing
in her life.
You suspected your wife?
Well, yes... yes.
At first, frankly, yes.
Her behavior did seem
at the time to me
Who was, after all,
there to see
To be a little odd.
Odd?
Yes, well, I mean, to
a certain extent, yes.
I'm not by nature
a suspicious person--
Far from it.
I have something
of a reputation
As an after-dinner speaker,
if you take my meaning.
Yes, I certainly do.
Anyway, in the area
where I'm known
People, in fact, know me
extremely well.
Right.
Will you hold this?
Thank you.
Yes-- anyway,
as I said
I must learn to
face up to the facts
Stop beating
about the bush
Or I'd never
look myself
In the bathroom
mirror again.
Anyway, so...
Would you mind running
along for ten minutes?
No, no.
Make it half an hour.
Yes, I'll wait outside,
shall i?
Yes, well, that's perhaps
the best thing, yes.
Certainly put my mind
at rest on...
On one or two... points there.
Now, wait
there, stranger.
A man can run and run
for year after year.
Till he realizes
That what he's
running from is hisself.
Gosh!
Now, a man's
got to do
What a man's
And there ain't
no sense in running.
Now, you got to turn
and you got to fight
And you got to
hold your head up high.
Yes!
Now, you go back
in there, my son
And be a man.
Walk tall.
Yes.
Oh, I will!
I will!
I've been pushed around
long enough.
This is it.
This is your moment,
arthur pewtey.
This is it, arthur pewtey.
At last...
You're a man!
All right, deirdre,
come out of there!
Go away!
Right, right.
These historic pictures
of queen victoria
Taken in 1880 at osborne
Show the queen with gladstone.
This unique film provides
a rare glimpse
Into the private world of a
woman who ruled half the earth.
The commentary, recorded
on the earliest wax cylinders
Is spoken by alfred lord
tennyson, the poet laureate.
Well, hello,
it's the wacky queen again...
And who's the other fella?
It's willy gladstone
And when these two way-out
wacky characters get together
There's fun aplenty.
And, uh-oh, there's a hose pipe.
This means trouble for somebody.
Uh-oh, charlie gardener's
fallen for that old trick.
Queenie's put him
in a heap of trouble.
Uh-oh, that's one in the eye
for willy.
"here, you have a go."
"well, doggone it,
where's that water?"
Uh-oh, there it is,
all over his face.
Well, hello, what's britain's
wacky queen up to now?
Well, she's certainly not sitting
on the fence... she's painting it.
Surely nothing
can go wrong here.
Uh-oh, here's the p.m.,
coming back for more.
And he certainly gets it.
Well, that's one way
to get the housework done.
Oh, dad, look
who's come to see us!
It's our ken.
Ah, and about bloody
time, if you ask me.
Aren't you pleased
to see me, father?
Yes, of course he's
pleased to see you, ken.
All right, woman, all right.
I've got a tongue in me head.
I'll do the talking.
Bligh!
I like your fancy suit.
Is that what they're wearing
up in yorkshire now?
It's just
an ordinary suit, father.
It's all I've got,
apart from the overalls.
How are
you liking it
Down the
mine, ken?
Oh, it's not too bad, mum.
We're using some new
tungsten carbide drills
For the preliminary
coal-face scouring operations.
Oh, that sounds
nice, dear.
Tungsten carbide drills?
What the bloody hell is
tungsten carbide drills?
It's something they use
in coal mining, father.
"it's something they use
in coal mining, father."
Your bloody fancy talk
since you left london.
Not that again.
He's had
a hard day, dear.
His new play opens
At national
theatre tomorrow.
Oh, that's good.
Good?! good?!
What do you know about it?
What do you know about getting
up at 5:00 in the morning
To fly to paris, back at
the old vic for drinks at 12:00
Sweating the day
Through press interviews,
television interviews
Then getting back here at 10:00
to wrestle with the problem
Of an homosexual
nymphomaniac drug addict
Involved in the ritual murder
Of a well-known
scottish footballer?
That's a full working day, lad!
And don't you forget it!
Oh, don't shout
at the boy, father.
Hampstead wasn't good enough
for you, was it?
You had to go poncing off
to barnsley.
You and your
coal-mining friends.
Coal mining is
a wonderful thing, father.
But it's something
you'll never understand.
Just look at you.
Oh, ken, be careful!
You know what he's like
After a few novels.
Go on, lad, go on.
Out with it--
what's wrong with me?
Your tit!
I'll tell you
what's wrong with you.
Your head's addled
with novels and poems.
You come home
every evening
Reeling of
chateau la tour.
Don't, don't!
And look what you've
done to mother.
She's worn out with meeting film
stars, attending premieres
And giving
gala luncheons.
There's nowt wrong
with gala luncheons, lad!
I've had more
gala luncheons
Than you've had
hot dinners.
Oh, please, please.
Oh, no!
What is it?
Oh, it's his
writer's cramp.
You never told
me about this.
No, we didn't
like to, kenny.
I'm all right,
I'm all right, woman.
Just get him
out of here!
Oh, ken, you'd better go.
All right,
I'm going.
After all
we've done for him.
One day you'll realize
There's more
to life than culture.
There's dirt and smoke
and good, honest sweat!
Get out, get out,
you laborer!
Hey, you know, mother?
I think there's
a play there.
Get agent
on the phone.
Aye, I think
you're right, frank.
It could express...
It could express
A vital theme
of our age.
Oh, shut up!
Shut up!
Well, that's better.
Now, for something
completely different--
A man with three buttocks.
We've done that!
Oh, all right, all right!
A man with... nine legs.
He ran away!
Oh, bloody hell.
Uh...
A scotsman on a horse.
Harold!
Come back, harold!
Come back, harold.
Oh, blast!
Good evening, and welcome
once again to the epilogue.
On the program this evening
we have monsignor edward gay
Visiting pastoral emissary
At the somerset
theological college
And author of a number
of books about belief
The most recent of which
is the best-seller my god.
Good evening.
And opposite him,
we have dr. tom jack
Humanist, broadcaster, lecturer
And author of the book
hello, sailor.
Good evening.
Tonight, instead of discussing
The existence
or nonexistence of god
They have decided
to fight for it--
The existence or nonexistence
to be determined
By two falls, two submissions
or a knockout.
All right, boys,
let's get to it.
Your master of ceremonies
for this evening
Mr. arthur waring.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen
And welcome to a three-round
contest of the epilogue.
Introducing on my right,
in the blue corner
Appearing for jehovah
The ever-popular
monsignor eddie gay.
And on my left,
in the red corner
Author of the book
the problems of kierkegaard
And hello, sailor
And visiting professor of
modern theological philosophy
At the university of east anglia
From wigan, dr. tom jack.
Now, dr. jack's got
the flying mare there.
Flying mare there.
What's he doing?
And this is going
to be a full body slam.
Full body slam there.
And he's going in again.
No, he's standing back.
Well, there we're...
We're leaving the epilogue
for the moment.
We'll be bringing you the result
of this discussion
Later on in the program.
Oh, my god!
Oh!
Isn't he an impressive
figure of a man?
People all over the country...
...defacement of public property
And this sort of thing
has got to be stopped.
Destruction, defacement
has got to be put to an end.
This country is not standing
For vandals and hooligans
running about.
Oh, yes, that's much better.
Oh, isn't he
a lovely little...
Wait a minute, buckaroos.
This has gone far enough.
Look out!
Get away from me!
Get it away,
get it away!
Yes, the mouse problem.
This week, the world around us
Looks at the growing social
phenomenon of mice and men.
What makes a man
want to be a mouse?
Well, uh, it's
not a question
Of wanting
to be a mouse.
It just sort of
happens to you.
All of a sudden,
you realize
That's what
you want to be.
And when did
you first notice
These, shall we say,
tendencies?
Well, I was about 17
And some mates and
me went to a party
And, uh, well, we had
quite a lot to drink
And then some of
the fellows there
Started handing cheese around.
Well, just out of curiosity,
I tried a bit and...
Well, that was that.
Yes, and what else
did these fellows do?
Well, uh,
some of them started...
Dressing up as mice a bit.
Um...
And then when they
got the costumes on, they...
Started squeaking.
Was that all?
That was all.
And what was your
reaction to this?
Well, I was shocked.
Yes.
But, uh...
Gradually I came to feel
That I was more at ease
with other mice.
A typical case, whom
we shall refer to as mr. "a."
Although his real name is this.
What is it that attracts someone like
mr. "a" to this way of life?
I have with me
a consultant psychiatrist.
Well, we've just heard
A typical case history.
I myself have over 700 similar
histories, all fully documented.
Would you care
to choose one?
Mr... arthur aldridge
of livington.
Well, that's amazing.
Thank you.
Amazing...
thank you, janet.
Kargol, speaking
as a psychiatrist
As opposed
to a con jurer...
Oh.
What makes certain men
want to be mice?
Well, we psychiatrists
have found
That over eight percent of the population
will always be mice.
I mean, after all, there's something
of the mouse in all of us.
I mean, how many of us
can honestly say
That at one time or another, he hasn't
felt sexually attracted to mice?
I know I have.
I mean, most normal adolescents
go through a stage
Of squeaking
two or three times a day.
Most youngsters,
on the other hand
Some youngsters, are attracted to it
by its very illegality.
It's like murder.
Make a thing illegal,
and it acquires a mystique.
Look at arson.
I mean, how many of us
can honestly say
That at one time
or another
He hasn't set fire
to some great public building?
I know I have.
The only way, the only way
to bring the crime figures down
Is to reduce
the number of offenses.
Get it out in the open.
I know I have.
Hmm... the amazing kargol
and janet.
What a lot of people
don't realize is
That a mouse, once accepted
Can fulfill
a very useful role in society.
Indeed, there are examples
throughout history
Of famous men now known
to have been mice.
veni, vidi, vici.
And of course, hilaire belloc.
But what is the attitude...
Of the man in the street
towards...
This growing social problem?
I'm down on them.
I'd strangle them.
Well, speaking as
a member of the stock exchange
I would suck their brains out
with a straw
Sell the widows and orphans
and go into south american zinc.
Yeah, I'd stuff sparrows
down their throats
Until the beaks stuck out
through the stomach walls.
Oh, well,
I'm a chartered accountant
And consequently too boring
to be of interest.
I feel that these
poor, unfortunate people
Should be free to live
the lives of their own choice.
I'd, uh, split their nostrils
open with a boat hook, I think.
Oh, well, I mean,
they can't help it, can they?
But, I mean, there's
nothing you can do about it
So I'd kill them.
Clearly the british public's
view is a hostile one.
Hostile.
But perhaps this is because
so little is generally known
Of these mice men.
We have some film now
Taken at one of the notorious
weekend mouse parties
Where these disgusting
little perverts meet.
Mr. "a" tells us
what actually goes on
At these mouse parties.
Well, uh, first of all
You get shown
to your own private hole
In the skirting board.
Then you put
the mouse skin on... uh...
Then you scurry
into the main room
And perhaps take
a run in the wheel.
The remainder of this film
was taken secretly
At one of these mouse parties
By a bbc cameraman
posing as a vole.
As usual, we apologize for
the poor quality of the film.
Well, uh, then you steal
some cheese-- brie or camembert
Or cheddar or gouda,
if you're on the harder stuff.
You might go and see
one of the blue cheese films.
Then there's a big clock
in the middle of the room
And about 12:50,
you climb up it and then...
Eventually it strikes one
and you all run down.
What's that?
That's the farmer's wife.
Perhaps we need to know
more of these mice men
Before we can really judge them.
Perhaps not.
Anyway, our 30 minutes are up.
Good night.
And here is the result
of the epilogue:
God exists
by two falls to a submission.