It's...
Monty python's flying circus.
Good evening.
Hello again, and
welcome to the show.
Tonight, we continue to look
at some famous deaths.
Tonight we start
with the wonderful death
Of genghis khan,
conqueror of india.
Take it away, genghis.
9.1, 9.3, 9.7.
That's 28.1 for genghis khan.
Bad luck, genghis.
Nice to have you on the show.
And now, here are the scores.
Well, you can see
the scores now.
St. stephen in the lead
there with his stoning.
Then comes king richard iii
at bosworth field--
A grand death, that--
Then the very
lovely jean d'arc.
Then marat, in his bath--
Best of friends with charlotte
in the showers afterwards.
Then a. lincoln
of the u.s. of a.--
A grand little chap, that--
And number six, genghis khan
And the back marker,
king edward vii.
Back to you, wolfgang.
Thank you, eddie.
And now, time for
this week's request death.
For mr. and
mrs. violet steppings
Of 23 wolverston road, hull
The death of mr. bruce foster
of guildford.
Strewth!
Oh, blimey, how time flies!
Sadly, we are reaching the end
of yet another program
And so it is finale time.
We are proud
to be bringing to you
One of the evergreen
bucket kickers
Yes, the wonderful death of the
famous english admiral nelson.
Kiss me, hardy!
Well, good evening, everyone
And welcome to the second
of our italian language classes
In which we'll be helping you
brush up your italian.
Now, last week we started
at the beginning
And we learned the italian
for a "spoon."
Now, I wonder how many of you
can remember what it was?
si, si!
Sit down, mario--
giuseppe.
il cucchiaio.
Oh, well done, giuseppe
Or as the italians
would say, molto bene, giuseppe.
grazie, signore, grazie
de tutta la sua gentilezza.
Well, now, this week
we're going to learn
Some useful phrases to help us
Open a conversation
with an italian.
Now, first of all, try telling
him where you come from.
For example, I would say, "sono
inglese di gerrard's cross. "
"I am an englishman
from gerrard's cross."
Shall we all try that together?
si, si!
sono inglese
di gerrard's cross.
Not too bad.
Now let's try with
somebody else-- mr...
Mariolini, signor.
Mr. mariolini.
And where are you from?
napoli, signor.
You're italian?
si...
si, si.
Well, in that case
You would say,
"sono italiano di napoli. "
ah... capisco.
mille grazie,
signore.
per fa vore,
Yes?
non conosceve parliamente
signor, devo me parlo
"sono italiano di napoli"
quando il habitare de milano.
che stupido!
Sorry, I don't understand.
Ah... signor, my
friend is saying...
bitte,
mein herr.
bitte.
was ist das wort
fuer "mittelschmerz"?
Helmut, you want
the german classes!
Oh... danke schoen.
Ah, das deutschen klassenzimmer.
Ach!
My friend, he say, he
say, "why must I say
'i am italian
from napoli'?"
When he lives
in milan.
Ah... well, tell your friend
if he lives in milan
He must say,
"sono italiano di milano. "
eh, milano e tanto
meglio di napoli!
che cosa?
si, I milanesi sono
i megli nel mondo!
He say, "milan is
better than napoli."
Well, he shouldn't
be saying that.
We haven't done
comparatives yet.
Yes, mothers,
new improved whizzo butter
Containing 10% more less
Is absolutely indistinguishable
from a dead crab.
Remember, buy whizzo butter
and go to heaven!
I can't tell
the difference
Between whizzo butter
and this dead crab.
Yes, you know,
we find
That nine out of ten
british housewives
Can't tell
the difference
Between whizzo butter
and a dead crab.
It's true.
It's true, we can't.
You're on television,
aren't you?
Yes, yes.
He does that thing
with those silly women
Who can't tell
the difference
Between whizzo butter
and a dead crab.
Oh, yes.
You try that around
here, young man
And we'll slit
your face.
Yes, with a razor.
Hello, good evening, and welcome
To another edition
of "it's the arts."
We kick off tonight
with the cinema.
Good evening.
One of the most prolific
of film producers
Of this age, or indeed any age
Is sir edward ross.
Back in this country
For the first time
for five years
To open a season
of his works
At the national
film theater.
And we are very
fortunate to have him
With us here in
the studio this evening.
Good evening.
Edward-- you don't mind
if I call you edward.
No, not at all.
Only it does worry some people--
I don't know why-- perhaps
they're a little sensitive
So I do take the precaution
of asking on these occasions.
Oh, no, that's fine.
So "edward" is all right.
Splendid, splendid.
Sorry to have brought it up.
No, no, "edward" it is.
Well, thank you very much indeed
for being so helpful
Only it's more than my job's
worth to, er...
Quite, yes.
Makes it rather difficult
to establish a rapport
To put the other person
at their ease.
Quite.
Yes, silly little point
But it does seem to matter.
Still... less said the better.
Um... ted, when you
first started in the...
You don't mind
if I call you ted?
No, no, no.
Everyone
calls me ted.
Well, it's shorter,
isn't it?
Yes, it is.
And much less formal.
Ted, edward,
anything.
Splendid, splendid.
Incidentally,
do call me tom.
I don't want you
playing around
With any of this
"thomas" nonsense.
Now, where were we?
Eddie-baby,
when you first...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I don't like
Being called
eddie-baby.
I'm sorry?
I don't like being
called eddie-baby.
Did I call you
eddie-baby?
Yes, you did.
Now get on with it.
I don't think I did
call you eddie-baby.
You did call me
eddie-baby.
Did I call him
eddie-baby?
Yes! no!
I didn't really
call you eddie-baby
Did i, sweetie?
Don't call me
sweetie!
Can I call you
sugar plum?
No!
Pussycat?
no!
Angel-drawers?
No, you may not!
Now, get on with it.
Frank.
What?
Can I call
you frank?
Why frank?
It's a nice name.
Robin day's got a hedgehog
called frank.
What's going on?
Frannie, little frannie,
frannie knickers.
No, I'm leaving.
I'm leaving--
I'm off.
Tell us about your
latest film, sir edward.
What?
Tell us about
your latest film
If you'd be so kind,
sir edward.
None of this
"pussycat" nonsense?
Promise.
Please,
sir edward.
My latest film?
Yes, sir edward.
Well, the idea, funnily enough,
came from an idea I had
When I first joined
the industry in 1919.
Of course, in those days,
I was only a tea boy.
Oh, shut up!
Sir edward... ross.
Now, later in the program
We'll be bringing you
a unique event
In the world of modern art.
Pablo picasso will be doing
a special painting for us
On this program...
live, on a bicycle.
This is the first time
That picasso has painted
while cycling.
But right now it's time to look
at a man whose meteoric rise...
Last week the royal
festival hall saw
The first performance
of a new symphony
By one of the world's
leading modern composers
Arthur "two sheds"
jackson.
Mr. jackson.
Good evening.
May I just sidetrack you
For one moment, mr. jackson?
This-- what shall I call it?--
nickname of yours...
Oh, yes.
Two sheds.
How did you come by it?
Well, I don't
use it myself.
It's just a few of my
friends call me "two sheds."
I see.
And do you in fact
have two sheds?
No, I've only
one shed.
I've had one
for some time.
But a few years ago
I said I was thinking
Of getting another one,
and since then
Some people have
called me "two sheds."
In spite of the fact
that you have only one.
Yes.
I see... and
are you thinking
Of purchasing
a second shed?
No.
To bring you in line
with your epithet?
No.
I see, I see.
Well, let's return
to your symphony.
Did you write this symphony
In the shed?
No.
Have you written
Any of your recent works
in this shed of yours?
No, it's just a perfectly
ordinary garden shed.
I see.
And you're thinking of
buying this second shed
To write in?
No, no, look...
this shed business
It doesn't really
matter at all.
The sheds aren't
important.
It's just a few friends
call me "two sheds"
And that's all
there is to it.
I wish you'd ask me
about me music.
I'm a composer.
People always ask me
about the sheds.
They've got it
out of proportion.
I'm fed up
with the sheds.
I wish I'd never got it
in the first place.
I expect you're probably
thinking of selling one.
I will sell one.
Then you'd be arthur
"no sheds" jackson.
Look, forget about the sheds--
they don't matter.
Mr. jackson, I think,
with respect
We ought to talk
about your symphony.
What?
Apparently your
symphony was written
For organ and timpani.
What's that?
What's what?
It's a shed--
get it off.
All right.
Now, then,
mr. jackson...
Your symphony.
I understand
that you used...
That you used to be
interested in trainspotting.
What?
I understand
That about 30 years ago
You were extremely interested
in trainspotting.
What's that got to do
with my bloody music?
Are you having
Any trouble from him?
Yes, a little.
Well, we interviewers
are more than a match
For the likes
of you, two sheds.
Yes, make yourself
scarce, two sheds.
This studio
isn't big enough
For the three of us.
Get your own arts
program, you fairy.
Arthur "two sheds"
jackson.
Never mind, timmy.
Oh, michael, you're
such a comfort.
Arthur "two sheds"...
Jackson.
And now for more news of
the momentous artistic event
When pablo picasso is doing
A specially commissioned
painting for us
Whilst riding a bicycle.
Pablo picasso,
the founder of modern art
Without doubt the greatest
abstract painter ever
For the first time
painting in motion.
But first of all
Let's have a look
at the route he'll be taking.
Well, picasso will be starting,
david, at chichester here.
He'll then cycle
on the a29 to fontwell.
He'll then take the a272, which
will bring him on to the a3
Just north of hindhead here.
From then on, pablo has
a straight run on the a3
Until he meets the south
circular at battersea here.
Well, this is a truly
remarkable occasion.
It's the first time
That a modern artist of such
stature has taken the a272.
And it'll be very
interesting to see
How he copes
with the heavy traffic
Round the wisborough
green-- vicky.
Well, picasso will be riding
his viking super roadster
With the drop handlebars
and the dual-thread wheel rims.
And with his wiley-prat
20-to-1 synchro-mesh
He should experience
difficulties
On the sort of road surfaces
They just don't
get abroad-- mitzie.
And now for the latest report
on picasso's progress
Over to reg moss
on the guildford bypass.
Well, there's no sign
of picasso at the moment, david
But he should be
through here at any moment.
However, I do have with me
Mr. ron geppo,
british cycling sprint champion
And this
year's winner
Of the derby
doncaster rally.
Well, reg, I think
pablo should be all right
Provided he doesn't
attempt anything
On the monumental scale
Of some of his
earlier paintings
Like guernica or
mademoiselles d'avignon
Or even his later
war and peace murals
For the temple of peace
chapel at vallauris
Because with this strong head
wind, I don't think
Even doug timpson
of manchester harriers
Could paint anything
on that kind of scale.
Well, thank
you, ron.
Well, there still seems to be
no sign of picasso
So I'll hand you
back to the studio.
Well, we've just heard
That picasso is approaching the
tolworth roundabout on the a3.
So come in,
sam trench at tolworth.
Well, something certainly
is happening here
At tolworth roundabout, david.
I can now see picasso.
He's cycling down very hard
Towards the roundabout.
He's about 75, 50 yards away
And I can now see his painting.
It's an abstract.
I can see some blue, some purple
Some little black oval shapes.
I think I can see...
That's not picasso.
That's kandinsky.
Good lord,
you're right!
It's kandinsky,
wasily kandinsky!
And who's this
here with him?
It's braque, georges braque
of the cubists
Painting a bird in flight
over a cornfield
And going very fast
down the hill
Towards kingston.
And piet mondrian
just behind
Piet mondrian
the neoplasticist...
Then a gap,
then the main bunch.
Here they come: chagall,
max ernst, miro, dufy
Ben nicholson,
jackson pollock
And bernard buffet
making a break
On the outside here.
Brancusi's
going with him.
So is gericault,
fernand leger, delaunay
De kooning... kokoschka's
dropping back here
By a little bit
And so's paul klee
dropping back a bit
And, right at the back
of this group
Our very own
kurt schwitters.
Schwitters
is german.
As yet absolutely no sign of
pablo picasso.
And so, from
tolworth roundabout
Back to the studio.
Well, I think I can
help you there, sam.
We're getting reports in
from the a.a. that picasso...
Picasso has fallen off!
He's fallen off his bicycle on
the b2127 just outside ewhurst
Trying to get a shortcut
through to dorking
Via gomslake and peashall.
Well, picasso is
reported to be unhurt
But the pig has
a slight headache.
And on that note, we
must say good night to you.
Picasso has failed
In his first bid for
international cycling fame.
So from all of us here
at the it's the arts studio
It's good night.
good night.
Hold it.
Sit up.
Sit up!
Ooh!
Shh... there's
somebody out there.
Huh?
Blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Help, help me, I'm
trapped in this body.
Oh, please, help me out!
Help me, oh, please,
help me out.
Blah blah blah blah blah blah.
I'm free! I'm free! I'm free!
Hmm... just
checkin'.
Just checkin'.
Oh, no you don't.
Ooh!
Shh... somebody out there.
Dobson's bought
it, sir.
Porker, eh?
Swine.
This man is ernest scribbler,
writer of jokes.
In a few moments
He will have written the
funniest joke in the world
And, as a consequence,
he will die laughing.
It was obvious
that this joke was lethal.
No one could read it and live.
This morning,
shortly after 11:00
Comedy struck this little
house in dibley road.
Sudden, violent comedy.
Police have sealed off the area
And scotland yard's crack
inspector is with me now.
I shall enter
the house
And attempt to
remove the joke.
I shall be aided
By the sound
of somber music
Played on
gramophone records
And also by the
chanting of laments
By the men of
"q" division.
The atmosphere thus created
should protect me
In the eventuality
of me reading the joke.
Well, there goes a brave man.
Whether he comes
out alive or not
This will surely be remembered
As one of the most courageous
and gallant acts
In police history.
It was not long before the army
became interested
In the military potential
of the killer joke.
Under top security,
the joke was hurried
To a meeting
of allied commanders
At the ministry of war.
Top brass were impressed.
Tests on salisbury plain
confirmed
The joke's devastating
effectiveness
At a range of up to 50 yards.
Fantastic.
All through the winter of '43
We had translators working
in joke-proof conditions
To try and produce a german
version of the joke.
They worked on one word each
for greater safety.
One of them saw
two words of the joke
And spent several
weeks in hospital.
But apart from that,
things went pretty quickly
And we soon had
the joke by january
In a form which our troops
couldn't understand
But which the germans could.
So on july 8, 1944
The joke was first told
to the enemy in the ardennes.
Squad, get
ready joke!
Squad, tell
the joke!
wenn ist das nunstuck
geht und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund das oder
die flipperwaldt gespuhrt!
It was a fantastic success
Over 60,000 times as powerful
as britain's great prewar joke
And one which hitler
just couldn't match.
insbesondere keiner mehr der
in deutschland leben wird...
wir sind des reiches
junge mannschaft!
eure schule.
In action, it was deadly.
wenn ist das nunstuck
geht und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund...
wenn ist das nunstuck
geht und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund...
...nunstuck geht
und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund das oder
die flipperwaldt gespuhrt!
German casualties
were appalling.
What is the big joke?
I can only give
you a name, rank
And "why did the chicken
cross the road?"
That's not funny.
I want to know the joke!
All right.
How do you make
a nazi cross?
I don't know.
How do you make
a nazi cross?
Tread on his corns.
gott im himmel!
That's not funny!
Now, if you don't
tell me the joke
I shall hit
you properly.
I can stand physical
pain, you know.
ach, you're no fun!
All right, otto!
Oh, no-- no, anything
but that, please.
Tickle him.
All right, I'll tell you.
Quick-- otto,
the typewriter!
wenn ist das nunstuck
geht und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund das oder
die flipperwaldt gespuhrt!
That's not funny!
die flipperwaldt
gespuhrt!
was ist,
was gibt's?
wenn ist das nunstuck
geht und slotermeyer?
ja! ba yerhund das oder
die flipperwaldt gespuhrt!
Hmm?
In peenemunde
in the autumn of '44
The germans were working
on a joke of their own.
die ist ein kinderhunder
und zwei mackeluber
und bitte schon ist
den wunderhaus sprechen sie.
"nein, "zweckt der herren.
"istauf'n borger
mitzweitingen. "
We'll let
you know.
But by december,
their joke was ready.
And hitler gave the order
For the german v-joke
to be broadcast in english.
There were zwei peanuts
walking down the strasse
and one was assaulted... peanut.
In 1945, peace broke out.
It was the end of the joke.
Joke warfare was banned
At a special session of the
geneva convention, and in 1950
The last remaining copy
of the joke was laid to rest
Here in the berkshire
countryside
Never to be told again.
And here is the final score:
pigs 9, british bipeds 4.
The pigs go on to meet
vicki carr in the final.