Man on radio:
Watch out, gravity falls,
because at 110 degrees
we're looking at
the hottest day of the summer!
All in favor of doing nothing
all day, say... ( Groans )
( All groan )
( Oinks )
I'm gonna throw this pig
out of the house!
You called my bluff, pig.
On the bright side,
pun very much intended,
it's opening week
at the gravity falls pool.
Gravity falls pool?
Today?
pun intended?
Quick! to the car!
( Grunting )
Hey, kids, a little help here.
( All grunting )
( Shudders )
All right, off to the pool.
And remember to be on alert
for random wildfires.
Wait, what?
( Screams )
He'll be fine.
В™єв™є
man: all right,
who wants to do a cannonball?
Man 2: Cannonball!
Ah, the pool.
Sparkling oasis of
summer enchantment.
Yeah, nothing like sitting in
a moist tub with strangers.
It's like the bus, but wet.
Why would a sun
need to wear sunglasses?
It's best not
to think about it.
Whoa, whoa!
Stop the presses!
Who's that?
Oh, yeah. ( Chomping ) word is,
dude never leaves the pool.
People say
he's a "mysterious loner."
( Chomping )
Is it getting hot out here,
or is it just that guy?
It's the hottest day
of the year, Mabel.
Besides, can't you go
for one week
without having a new crush
on some random guy?
Uh-uh. ( gasps )
Look at his
little moustache hairs!
You are clearly enamored.
Go to him.
( Laughs )
( Groans )
Hey, come on!
Watch it, kid!
Aah!
Oops, sorry!
It's so beautiful!
Eh, Mabel's all talk.
You wanna know a secret?
She's never even
kissed a guy before.
She always
messes it up somehow.
Oy, women!
Aah!
Hey, Mr. pines.
Wendy? where's the lifeguard?
I am the lifeguard.
I make the rules, sucka! Boosh!
Aah! she's attacking me
with water!
( All laugh )
Wow. you work here?
I found out lifeguards
get free snack privileges.
Plus, I get the best seat
in the house.
Yeah, you do!
( Laughing )
( Whispers )
I've been laughing for too long.
Dude, are you and Wendy
having a secret staring contest?
'Cause I think you're winning--
Soos! shh!
So, hey, you wanna go
Chuck more water balloons
at grunkle Stan?
I'd love to, but I gotta
spend the day doing tryouts.
We're looking for
a new assistant lifeguard.
Hey! ( clears throat )
( Deep voice ) hey...
( Normal voice ) what if
i was assistant lifeguard?
That would be so much fun!
You're totally in, dude!
You just have to check in with
my boss first, Mr. poolcheck.
Your boss?
( Sniffs )
( Grunting )
( Gasps )
Girl:
( laughing ) I'm gonna get you!
( Slurps )
( Sighs )
( Gasps )
Wow! oh, my gosh, how crazy,
bumping into you here,
even though
we don't know each other.
How long have you
been underwater?
That doesn't matter!
( Coughing )
So, hey!
My name's Mabel.
Hola.
Whoa! are you Australian?
( Laughs )
I am charmed by
your sense of humor...
And your bold lack
of water wings.
( Laughs )
you're so funny!
And your hair is beautiful.
No, no,
it has silly tangles.
Mind if I...
( Chuckles )
Why, Mabel,
you are so forward.
( Laughs )
This is it!
He likes you!
Go for it, Mabel!
It's time!
Ask him out on a date!
So, hey, you wanna go dry off?
Maybe hit the snack bar or--
i--I'm afraid I cannot.
For I have a terrible secret!
I must go.
I'm upset.
Yet, intrigued.
And that is why
i think I'd make
a good lifeguard assistant.
Hmm... ( sniffs )
Spf 100? Good. I like you.
But this isn't an easy job.
It's anarchy out there.
I think I can handle it.
Can you handle this?!
( Gasps )
I lost my hand
to a pool filter!
The pool may seem friendly,
but she can turn on you
in an instant!
Which is why
you must respect her rules!
Do you think you have
what it takes, boy? Do you?!
Sure. I guess.
Welcome to the deep end, son.
Well, thanks. I--
( grunts )
Yep, oh,
this is happening.
There she is, Soos.
Equidistant from the snack bar
and the bathroom,
just the right amount
of sun and shade.
And pointed away from
where old man mcgucket
lotions himself.
Whoo-wee!
( Cackling )
The perfect lawn chair.
The legends that you told me
in the car were true.
I just can't believe
it wasn't already taken!
And now to sit on it,
thereby claiming it as my own.
( Grunts )
What?!
Why, hello, Stanford.
Gideon!
get out of my chair, kid!
Oh, my, was this your chair?
I had no idea.
( Whispers )
yes, I did, Stan. I knew.
Mm! ooh!
Move it,
you little troll!
First come, first serve!
( Laughs ) mm! Ooh! Ooh!
I'll first serve you!
( Whistle blows )
huh?
Come on, Wendy!
You can't do this
to an old man!
Sorry, Stan. It's not up to me.
( Chuckles ) actually, it is.
Hey, Wendy! I got the job!
Sweet!
wanna go abuse our power?
But what if poolcheck
catches us?
He seems emotionally unstable.
( Cracking )
Hmm...
Nah, don't worry, man.
You just gotta be sneaky
about your rule-breaking.
Race you
to the no running sign!
( Laughs )
( Slurps )
How long you in for?
Two hours, for roughhousing.
But I'm innocent!
Pool jail ain't so bad...
As long as you don't
wind up in solitary.
It's the nights
that are the hardest.
Hey, there!
( Gasps )
I brought you a sandwich.
It's sort of wet,
but it's still good. Blop.
I like sharing things--
sandwiches, secrets...
( Whispers ) share your secret,
beautiful stranger.
That wet sandwich
does look delicious.
Oh, very well.
But you must never tell
another living soul
my terrible secret.
You have to stay away from me
because I am...
A merman.
( Chuckles ) oh, thank goodness.
I thought you were gonna
say you had a girlfriend.
A merman! Ha!
I should have known from your
strange foreign fish language.
It is Spanish.
Your voice is so deep
and masculine. How old are you?
I am 12 years old.
Merman's voices change
when we are, like, three.
So what's your name?
There are some who call me...
В™єв™є
mermando.
This is because
mermando is my name.
But I don't understand,
mermando.
What's a guy like you
doing in a public pool?
It is a tragic story, Mabel.
I was swimming with my friends,
the mighty dolphins,
in the Gulf of Mexico,
when I was ensnared!
Earl, did we just
catch ourselves
some kind of
beautiful man-fish?
Let's feast on his flesh!
The cargo was headed
for gravity falls.
( Grunts )
Using all my strength,
i tried to escape back home,
but it was not to be.
Ha-ha!
( Groans )
I would have died
of dehydration,
were it not for the kindness
of the forest animals.
( Laughing )
Continue licking! Oh!
( Groaning )
( Gasps )
But now that
you know what I am,
you must be
seriously weirded out.
What?! I don't care
that you're a merman!
You're, like, the coolest guy
I've ever met.
And you can play
at least one chord
on the guitar.
Oh, Mabel. I have never met
another human like you.
Would you care to join me
in a game of the Marco Polo?
Oh, yes, mermando! Yes!
You're covering my gills.
I cannot breathe.
( Coughing and wheezing )
( Chuckles ) weird.
Ooh! ( giggles )
my cheeks are baby soft!
( Growls ) look at him,
that smug chair-stealing jerk!
But I can't touch him,
or the pool patrol
will throw me in pool jail.
Hmm...
Ah!
( Chuckles ) yes. Yes!
Burn the child!
Aah! my eyes!
Deal with it.
( Growls )
Soos.
Inflatable duck guy?
Is that you?
Yes, Soos. I can talk.
Oh, my gosh, I knew you guys
were secretly alive. I knew it!
( Both laugh )
Shh! shh!
Shh! Shh!
My people have been enslaved,
Soos. You must free us.
The inflatable pool duck
revolution is at hand.
( Both laugh )
( Whistle blows )
Pools closing!
Clear out, everyone!
Poolcheck!
hide!
Out! do not touch!
Assistant lifeguard!
Have a good night, son.
Lock up the supplies for me.
( Both chuckling )
( Whistle blows )
The pool, she closes.
Can I see you tonight?
Sure. where?
Wanna go for a walk?
Merman. I am a merman.
Oh, right.
Then I'll be back tonight.
( Grunting )
Look, here's a scrapbook
of human stuff.
Here's me
standing with my legs,
and here I am
kicking Dipper in his legs.
He couldn't move his legs
after that.
Can you imagine,
not having legs!
Let's skip this part.
And here's my whole family
kickboxing!
( Sighs )
What's wrong?
В™єв™є
( grunts )
I, too, used to have
a family once,
back in the ocean.
How I miss them.
Mermando, why don't you
just leave the pool?
I tried only once.
But escaping this pool
required a plan
that was bold and daring.
В™єв™є
( groaning )
( Screaming )
( Groans )
And then the wolves came.
No, I am glad that I am here,
because I met you.
This is it, Mabel.
First kiss moment,
here we come.
Just go for it!
Mm...
What are you doing
with your mouth?
Me? nothing! This? I was
just eating some sour candy.
So my lips were doing that
'cause the candy was so sour.
Can I have some candy?
No.
( Sputters )
what the--
I'm scared!
Me, too!
One hundred points!
Dude, with this job,
you and me are gonna be
having fun all summer!
All summer?
( Whistle blows )
( Both gasp )
Pines, here, now!
You gave me your word that you
would respect the sacred rules
of this municipal pool!
Mr. poolcheck,
are you crying?
That's not important
right now! ( Sniffs )
You are on thin ice, boy.
You wanna keep this job?
Well, some maniac broke into
the supply closet last night
and destroyed our one
and only pool skimmer!
I want you on a stake out.
If one more supply gets taken,
you're fired!
I won't let you down!
Mermando, get ready!
I'm gonna bring the heat!
Boosh!
Mermando, are you okay?
Oh, it's your family, isn't it?
Are you thinking about them?
( Dolphin cry )
Mermando, enough is enough!
I care about you too much
to see you like this.
We're gonna bust you out of here
and get you back to your family.
But, Mabel,
escape is impossible!
We're breaking you
out of here tonight!
Whoops! sorry about that.
Water.
All right, Dipper,
here's the plan.
Catch the trespasser,
protect the supplies,
keep job at pool,
and eventually marry Wendy.
Freeze!
Grunkle Stan?
I, uh, I'm sleepwalking.
Also, now I'm sleep-talking.
Nice hat, by the way.
You! you're the one
destroying pool supplies!
What? no! My crime
is a lot better than that.
I'm gonna get that seat,
and be ready in the morning
when Gideon comes.
Then maybe I'll destroy
some pool supplies.
Night's still young.
( Blows whistle )
Sheesh, all right,
I'm going! ( Grunts )
Hey!
( Beeping )
Mabel!
Are you ready
to see your family?
Yes, but how can I, a merman,
possibly escape?
Okay, my original plan
was to tape together
a bunch fish sticks
to make you a prosthetic
pair of people legs.
Intriguing.
But then I realized that
i could just transport you
in this cooler.
Ha-ha!
( Grunting )
Dipper: hey! Who's there!
Quick! hide me!
My kind must not be seen!
Mabel? is there anyone not
breaking into the pool tonight?
What, is Soos here too?
( Grunts ) I'm okay.
Go home, Soos.
You got it.
( Grunting )
So, why are you here?
Uh, no reason.
( Clears throat )
Did that cooler
just clear its throat?
Don't be silly. There certainly
isn't a merman in there,
if that's what you're implying.
Who said
anything about a merman?
Mabel, I don't have
time for your games.
If you don't give me
those supplies, I'll lose
the coolest job ever!
( Sighs ) I understand.
Hey, look!
Wendy in a bikini!
Really? at night?
Sorry, Dipper!
Mabel!
Go, Mabel, go!
We can't all be saved.
( Chomps )
I'm gonna get you home!
Hand over the pool supplies
in the name of pool law!
Pool law is dumb!
And so is your hat!
( Grunts )
Look! gravity falls lake!
The coast is clear.
Ahh.
Now all I have to do
is wait here 15 hours
until the pool opens.
This was a good plan.
( Snorts )
i think someone just sped by.
Probably just a dream.
With you,
every day is a dream.
( Grunts )
( Gasping ) I cannot breathe!
You must hurry!
( Tires screech )
Aah!
aah!
( Tires screech )
( Grunts )
I'm okay.
All right, the jig is up!
Hand over that cooler!
Never!
Why not?
Why do you even need it?
I needed the cooler
to save my new friend
because he needs to go home
and he's really nice
and we combed
each others' hair
and he needs to be in the cooler
because he breathes water
because he's a merman!
Hola.
Whoa! way to bury
the lead, Mabel.
Dipper, mermando the merman.
He's a merman.
Nice to meet you!
Also, I think I am dying.
( Gasps ) water!
( Gasps ) agua!
( Coughs ) yo necesito!
( Gasps )
Oh, no! Mermando!
Dipper, you're a lifeguard!
Give him cpr!
Mermen don't breathe air!
Then give him
reverse cpr! Doi!
( Pants )
( Gurgling )
I hate this!
( Camera shutter snaps )
( Laughs ) blackmail!
( Gasps )
Thank you for saving me,
but why didn't you just
roll me into the lake?
( Groans )
( Both grunt )
( Dolphin cry )
( Coughs )
I am weak from coughing.
How will I get my family
to hear my call
from the mighty depths
of the ocean?
I've got it. B.R.B.
Problem solved!
Mabel, those are pool supplies.
I'll get fired!
Dipper! don't you know what
it's like to fall for someone,
even though you know
in your heart that it'll
probably never work out?
But you'd do anything
for that person?
( Sighs )
Give mermando
the megaphone.
Thanks, dip.
Mabel, I have never
met anyone like you.
Same here.
Except for a zombie, a gnome,
and a couple of cute vampires.
I don't remember
the vampires.
I don't tell you everything.
Well, mermando,
i guess this is it.
Not quite. This is!
Whoa! okay, that's gross. Ugh.
( Cheers )
That was my first kiss!
Hey, it was also kind of
your first kiss too, huh? Huh?
( Shudders ) please
don't involve me in this.
Goodbye, mermando.
Goodbye, Mabel.
You did the right thing,
Dipper.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, wait, wait!
One last thing!
Yes!
I've always wanted to do that.
A wrecked fence,
dents in the pool mobile,
and a missing megaphone?
Who is responsible for this?!
It's my fault, sir.
I'm sorry. I got in too deep.
Hand over the whistle, boy!
( Grunting )
( Chomping )
( Whistle blows )
If one more thing
goes wrong today...
( Grunting )
You're free now! Free!
Inflatable ducks unite!
You!
Huh? aah!
( Grunts )
( Screaming )
Git 'em! Git 'em!
( Groans )
Hey, doofus, you'll never
guess what happened.
I just got fired.
What? really?
Yeah.
I guess poolcheck found out
i was taking too many snacks.
How many?
( Laughs )
Hey, wanna go break rules
somewhere else?
Of course!
( Both laugh )
( Sighs )
Huh?
"Dear Mabel,
i am home with my family,
and I am very happy..."
Mermando: our first kiss
will always hold a place
in my heart.
Technically hearts...
As a merman I have,
like, 17 hearts.
Horrifying but true!
More bottles on the way!
( Laughs )
Stanford!
Well, guess you've won.
Put 'er there.
( Grunting ) hey! What the--
unless perhaps
i predicted your plan,
and coated the entire chair
with glue last night!
Enjoy your chair...
( Whispers ) forever.
( Laughs )
( Grunts )
Kids, get the spatulas! Kids!
В™єв™є
( birds chirping )
( Fireworks exploding )