Oh, no Mabel. I--
i don't feel so good!
I--
bleechhh!
Ohh! grunkle Stan,
what did you feed us?
Bwahhhh!
( Both "retching" )
( Both laughing )
Guys, stop!
Something terrible
just happened!
( "Retching" )
( Laughing )
All right, all right!
Party supplies
are now off-limits.
Mr. pines,
whose birthday is it again?
Nobody's. thought this party
might be a good way
to get kids to spend money
at the shack.
Nice!
The young people of this town
want fun,
I'll smother 'em with fun!
Maybe comments like that
are why kids don't come
to the mystery shack.
Hey! hey! How's about
you make yourself useful
and copy these flyers?
Oh, boy! A trip to
the copier store!
Calendars, mugs,
t-shirts and more!
They got it all
at the copier store.
That's not their slogan,
i just really feel that way
about the copier store.
Save the trouble.
You know the old copier
in my office?
I finally fixed
the old girl up.
Good as new!
( Electrical crackling )
Butterflies!
Does it even work?
( Mechanical humming )
Uhh!
( Both coughing )
Success!
Aah!
Aaah!
Stay back!
Oh, my gosh. Mabel,
i think this copier
can copy human beings!
Do you realize
what this means?
( "Retching" )
**
all right, party people,
and Dipper,
let's talk business.
Soos, because
you'll work for free--
and you begged--
I'm letting you be d.J.
You won't regret it,
Mr. pines.
I got this book that
teached me how to d.J.
R-r-r-right.
Not encouraging.
Wendy, you and Mabel
are working the ticket stand.
What?! but grunkle Stan,
this party is my chance
to make new friends!
I-i could work
with Wendy.
You realize if you do,
you gotta commit to staying
at the ticket stand with Wendy.
No getting out of it,
just the two of you,
alone, all night.
Ha ha ha!
( Laughing )
I promise.
Aah! what?
(Mocking) uh, uh,
i can work the counter
with you, Wendy!
Let's kiss! Mmm...Mmm...
Yeah, yeah,
laugh all you want,
but I have devised a plan
to make sure my night with Wendy
goes perfect. ( Clicks tongue)
Plan? oh, you're not
making one of those
overcomplicated listy things,
overcomplicated?
Let me just--all right,
hold that there... okay...
"Step one:
Getting to know each other
with playful banter."
Banter is like talking,
but smarter.
That sounds like
a dumb idea for poop-heads.
Yeah, see,
this isn't banter.
This is what I want
to avoid with Wendy.
The final step
is to ask her to dance.
Oh, Dipper!
I'm so happy you decided to work
the ticket stand with me!
You're so organized.
Show me that checklist again?
Oh!
If I follow
steps one through eleven,
nothing can get in my way.
Dipper, you're the one
getting in your way.
Why can't you just walk up
and talk to her
like a normal person?
Step nine, sister...
( Dance music plays )
( Scatting to music )
Can your uncle
throw a party or what?
(Over pa) The energy--
it's electric!
U( ducks quack, dogs bark )
And if anyone
wants to leave,
I'm charging an exit fee
of 15 bucks!
I'vwe're trapped!
"Step one: Casual banter."
So, here's a casual question.
(Clears throat)
What's your favorite
type of snack food?
Oh, man. I can't
just pick one.
No way! Mine too!
Uh, I mean--
I mean--
(coughing)
new topic! New topic!
**
go! go!
Work it! Work it!
Wow! you've got an animal
on your body! I'm Mabel.
(Very low voice)
Hi. I'm grenda.
This is candy.
Why do you have forks
taped to your fingers?
Improvement of
human being.
( Both laugh )
I've found my people.
Remember, dudes,
whoever, um,
party hearties--what?--
gets the party crown!
Most applause at the end
of the night wins!
( Inhales )
Wwow!
Party crown?
I'll take that.
Thank you very much.
Who's that?
The most popular girl in town:
Pacifica northwest.
I always feel bad about myself
around her.
I can't just
give you the crown.
It's sort of
a competition thing.
( Laughs ) honestly,
who's gonna compete
against me?
(Pacifica, over pa):
Fork girl? Lizard lady?
( Laughing )
Hold me, candy!
Our kind isn't
welcome here!
Hey! I'll compete!
( Both gasp )
I'm Mabel.
That sounds like
a fat old lady's name.
I'll take that
as a compliment.
May the better partier win.
( Snaps fingers )
Nice meeting you!
She's going down.
( Raucous party sounds )
Whoa! sounds like the party's
gettin' nuts!
Let the battle for
the party crown begin!
Mabel comes out strong.
Watch out, pacifica!
I've gotta get in there!
Cover for me?
Heh heh. Um, well, i--
thanks, man.
**
I'll be back shortly!
I'm sure Stan won't mind
if I'm gone for a few minutes.
Hey! what are you
doin', kid?!
These suckers aren't
going to rip themselves off.
Yeah!
You promised. Remember?
I did?
Dipper: I promise.
( Sighs )
Wendy: whoo-hoo-hoo!
Argh. if only I could be
two places at once.
( Wind whistles )
( Copier powers up )
I wonder if this
is a good idea.
Whoa!
I have a really big head.
So, uh--
ha! sorry.
You first.
Stop copying me!
Ha ha ha ha!
Aah! ow! Ow!
Funny bone.
I will call you
"number two."
Definitely not.
You know a name
I've always wanted...
Tyrone.
Okay, Tyrone,
let's get down to business.
I'm thinkin' you cover me
at the ticket stand
while I ask Wendy to dance.
I know the plan, buddy.
Hey, we're not gonna get jealous
and turn on each other
like the clones
in the movies, are we?
Dipper, please. This is you
you're talking about.
Plus, hey, you can always
just disintegrate me with water.
Yeah...
Yeah....
Whew.
( Scatting to music )
Great news, Wendy.
I got somebody to cover
the concessions for me.
That's awesome! You can
hang out with me and Robbie.
Robbie, you remember Dipper
from the convenience store.
Uh, no.
Yo, Wendy, check out
my new guitar.
( Plays fancy lick )
Whoa, cool.
Robbie, you're a stupid,
arrogant fraud,
but kiss me anyway
because you can play guitar.
Oh, wait. I forgot
something.
Ohh...
Let's get married tonight!
( Cell phone rings )
Dipper 2: Hey, buddy,
it's me. You.
I just had the same
jealousy fantasy.
We gotta get rid of Robbie
if I ever want to
dance with Wendy!
Hey, Dipper!
We're gonna go sit on the couch.
Meet us when you're done.
Oh, no! They're
sitting on the couch!
We gotta think of
something quick!
I got the same one.
But we're gonna
need some help.
And that's where
you come in,
number three.
But what if Robbie catches me?
I'll be all alone.
Omakes a good point..
Four dippers. This is
a four-Dipper plan.
( Small explosion )
Uh-oh, paper jam.
Nyi-nyi-nyi-nyi!
( Scratchy, disjointed
laughter )
Come on, you're not gonna
make me partner up with him,
are you?
Shh! don't be rude.
Hey, buddy, hey.
It's okay.
( Shrill gibberish )
Okay,
just one more clone.
* ...Me is forever
( very high note)
* always
( cheers )
(Breathless)
* forever *
I used to
sing like that...
Before my voice changed.
Pacifica pulls ahead!
Try and top that.
Oh, grenda? By the way,
you sound like
a professional wrestler.
Ha ha ha ha!
I wanna put her in a headlock
and make her feel pain!
It's not over
till it's over,
sisters!
Watch this!
Soos! give me
the eighties's
crowd-pleasingest,
rock balladiest song you got!
Excellent.
* don't start
un-believing *
* never don't not
feel your feelings *
( cheering )
Now I'm gonna
do a flip!
That was for you guys!!!
( Loud cheering )
( Whispering )
Dudes, would the owner
of a silver and red dirt bike
please report outside?
It is being stolen right now.
Wait--what?!
Ha ha ha!
Hey! come back here!
Oh, tough break.
I wonder who those guys are
that aren't me
because I'm right here?
Now we're gonna
bring it down for a minute.
Ladies, dudes,
now's the time.
* ( slow dance music )
Ah, snap!
Love this song!
Hey, goofus!
Now's your chance
to ask Wendy--
now's your chance
to ask Wendy to dance!
Coi--ahh--o!
Uhh-uhh-uhh...
Aah! I'll be right back.
Oh, I agree. You can't
just go and dance with her.
The dance floor
is a mine field!
A mine field, Tyrone!
What if there's a glitch
in the sound system!
Srobbie might come back!Y!
There's too many variables!
We need help.
( All dippers
talking at once )
All right, dippers,
gather round.
Now's the time.
You all clear on
what to do?
Hey, Soos, look!
A glowing dot!
Oh, man, I am so glad
i turned my head.
That dot does not disappoint.
Right. like I'm gonna
fall for that.
Aaah! gimme that money, Sonny!
There's your cue.
It's the perfect moment
to ask Wendy to dance.
Good luck, me.
I don't need luck.
I have a plan.
Aaah!
Oh, hey, man,
w-what are you doing here?
I mean, wouldn't you rather
be out on the dance floor,
uh, in, like,
exactly 42 seconds?
I'm just waiting
for the bathroom.
Um, um, okay.
Uh, small talk,
small talk, small talk...
So, hey, let's say
everyone at this party
gets stuck on a desert island.
Who do you think
the leader would be?
I...uh--
I think I'd go with
this lunatic.
( Grunting )
( Laughs )
I'd probably go for
stretch over there.
Uh, because tall people
can reach coconuts?
( Laughs )
Speaking of tall,
want to see something?
Those are my three brothers,
and I'm...
Boop!
Ha! you were a freak!
Yep.
You know, kids used to
make fun of my birthmark
before I started
hiding it all the time.
Uh, no, it's nothing!
I-i--
why did I say that?!
No way, dude.
Now you have to show me.
Show me, show me!
The big Dipper!
That's how you
got your nickname!
I thought your parents
just hated you or something.
Hey, I guess
we're both freaks.
( Both laughing )
Of course!
( Door closhey!
What are you doing up here?!
Number ten had been
distracting Soos for 15 minutes!
He's gonna get tired
Soos: Never!Eventually.
You won't believe it, guys.
I bumped into Wendy accidentally
and things are actually
going great!
That's nice, but not the plan.
Do we have to remind you?
( All talking at once )
Oh, man,
you guys sound crazy.
Look, maybe we don't
need the plan anymore,
ya know?
Maybe I could just go talk
to her like a normal person.
You bite your tongue!
If you're not gonna
stick to the plan,
maybe you shouldn't be
the Dipper to dance with Wendy.
If y( All talking )it...
Guys, come on.
We said we weren't
gonna turn on each other.
I think we all knew
we were lying.
No! no! Hey!
( Screaming )
Uhh!
No, wait!
Aaah! I can't breathe
clone: Yeah, you can!
Plus there's snacks
and a coloring book
in there for you!
Ohh!
Okay, so now that
original Dipper--
or "Dipper classic"--
is no longer fit for it,
i nominate myself
to dance with Wendy instead.
I've been around the longest,
so it should be me.
Right? I mean, logically.
Logically, guys.
Fair point, fair point.
Counterpoint:
maybe I should get
to dance with Wendy
because I've been around
for the least.
That makes,
like, zero sense.
You make zero sense!
Don't shove people!
Nyi-nyi-nyi-nyi!
Aaaah!
Hey, you want some
cheese and crackers, buddy?
( Wheezy, drooly sounds )
Huh? huh?
Yikes.
Hey, guys?
What would you do if you
were trapped in a closet?
All: break out.
Wend--
( muffled shouting )
Come on, man, give it up.
You're overpowered.
Hold on, guys,
think about it.
We're exact equals
mentally and physically.
If we start fighting,
it'll just go on for infinity!
Maybe we should
just give up...
Aaah!
Clone fight!!!
( All grunting )
Quit hitting myself!
Aaah!
Guys, come on, it's me!
Hget off!
Hey! classic Dipper's
getting away!
No, friends.
It's me. Number seven.
That's not me, guys,
that's not me!
Get him!
Stay back, stay back...
( Fire alarm rings )
Lame. lame.
( All groaning )
Huh. how 'bout that?
Uh-oh.
**
one more song, dudes,
and then it's time
for the bestowing
of the party crown!
( Bomb explosion sound )
Nailed it.
Pacifica, I just want to say
that whoever wins,
it's been a super-fun party.
Aww. it thinks
it's gonna win.
Hey, did you hear that?
People clapping
for the weird girls?
Yeah. me neither.
Say it! Say I can
dance with Wendy!
Never!
( Wendy laughing in distwendy?
( Whispers )
Robbie!
( Boshut up. Ing)
Ohh. we blew it, man.
I don't know.
You wanna go grab
a couple sodas or something?
Let the party crown
voting commence!
( Bell rings )
Good luck, Mabel.
Applaud to vote for Mabel!
( Cheers, applause )
Let's check
the applause-o-meter.
Oh...oh....pretty good...
And your next contestant,
pacifica!
( Scattered cheers, applause )
( Applause increases )
Uh-oh! a tie!
This has, like,
never happened before.
( Snoring )
( Sniffs )
( Cackling,
applauding )
Ladies and gentlemen, we--
we have a winner.
The winner of the contest
is pacifica northwest.
Thank you, Jorge.
Thank you, everyone!
Everyone come to the after-party
at my parents' boat!
Whoo-hoo!
( All cheer )
Chanting:
pacifica! pacifica! Pacifica...
Ohh. sorry I let you guys down.
I understand
if you want to leave.
But then we would
miss the sleep-over.
We want to call our moms
and sleep over here
with you!
You're like
a total rock star!
I have magazine boys.
Really? you guys!
Maybe we don't have
as many friends as pacifica,
but we have each other,
and that is pretty good,
i think.
Soos! play another song!
This thing's
going all night!
Way head of you, hambone.
**
( owl hoots )
Some night, huh?
Ahh. you think we really
even have a chance with Wendy?
I mean, she's 15, we're 12.
I don't know, man.
I hope so.
But we're making zero progress
the way we're doing it.
The only good conversation
you had with her
was when you didn't do
any of that list stuff.
I know. Mabel was right,
i do get in my own way.
Literally!
Whoa...
(makes explosion noise )
Oh, boy, don't look now.
It's okay, dude,
i had a good run.
Remember what
we talked about.
Uh, of course!
Hey, and quit being
such a wimp around Wendy, okay?
For my sake!!!!
Tyrone!
You were the only one
who understood.
( Dance music playing )
Ha ha ha!
Mabel:
Dipper! where have you been?
Meet my girlfriends!
( Doorbell )
( Explosion )
( Bicycle horn )
Man: yeah-uh!
( Cymbal crash )
( Cat mewling )
( Thwonk )
( Chimpanzee chittering )
( Man retching )
( Man gulping )
( Baby crying )
( Metallic clank )
( Cuckoo clock striking )
( Dog barks )
( Crickets chirp )
( Toilet flushing )
( Lightning crashes )
Found it.