( Screams )
( Sighs )
I just had a horrible dream
that Gideon stole the deed
to the mystery shack
and kicked us out
and we all had to move in
with Soos's grandma.
That was no dream, dude.
( Screams )
Shh! por favor.
Uh, sorry, abuelita.
Oh! Soos, your grandma
is so adorable!
And her skin
is old lady soft.
( Sighing )
Mabel, quit being creepy!
The news is finally on!
In a move that has
all of gravity falls buzzing,
child psychic Gideon gleeful
has taken surprise ownership
of the mystery shack,
previously belonging to area
shyster Stanford pines.
That picture's
taken out of context.
Now that you have the shack,
what exactly are you
planning to do with it?
I have a big announcement
to make today,
and I'd like
to cordially invite
all the good people
of gravity falls to join me.
Free admission to everyone
who wears their Gideon pins!
It's my face!
I just can't believe
Gideon beat us!
Normally I'm able
to save the day.
This is all my fault.
Don't worry, Dipper.
Looks like Mabel's gonna
have to be the hero
of the family now!
I'll defeat Gideon
with my grappling hook!
Mabel, no offense,
but that grappling hook
has literally
never helped us once.
Oh, yeah? Jelly grab!
I vacuum the walls now.
So you lost the shack.
Look on the bright side, dudes.
Now you get to live
here with me.
Soos!
Hey, anyone wanna
play racecars?
They're out of batteries
but we can make pretend.
( Gags and coughs )
would it be a new low
if I ate that?
( Chuckles )
I'm just kidding.
I'm totally eating it.
We've gotta
get the shack back.
Hello, gravity falls!
( Spectators cheering )
Gideon is
the psychic-est!
He guessed
the secret ingredient
to my coffee omelet!
Somehow he knew
about my horrifying
secret birthmark.
I love that
child psychic so much!
( Grunts )
you're choking me!
Grandma, is that you?
We're in.
Just wanna say,
don't know what
we're doing here,
but I am loving these
fake moustaches!
If anyone asks,
I'm not Soos.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Today I am delighted
to announce my new plans
for the former mystery shack.
I give you gideonland!
What?!!
dude!
We're gonna turn
this dirty old shack
into three square miles
of Gideon-tertainment!
And, introducing
our new mascot,
li'l Gideon junior!
Boom! he's a pig!
Waddles! you monster!
All right, that's it!
Hey! hey!
( Grunting and panting )
Listen up, people!
Gideon's a fraud!
This kid broke in
and stole my property!
Arrest him, officers!
Yeah!
Such accusations!
Mr. pines, I recall
you gave the property to me.
Look, here's the deed
right here!
Well, that's all the proof
i need to see.
I love you, li'l Gideon!
Sing them funny songs!
Hey!
( Gasping )
Now get off my property,
old man.
I'll show you
who's the old ma--
ow! aah! My hearing aid!
Aah! ( Grunting )
Thanks for visiting
gideonland, friends!
( Chuckles ) don't come back.
I don't care for y'all.
( All sigh )
( Grunts with exertion )
Don't worry, guys,
we'll get the shack
back somehow.
We better.
Wendy!
If I can't work
at the shack,
my dad's gonna force me
to work upstate
at my cousin's
logging camp.
What? you're leaving town?
But we need you here!
Yeah, especially Dipper,
because of his giant
crush on...
You. calyptus trees!
( Nervous chuckle )
the kids loves
eucalyptus trees.
( Chuckling )
saved it!
Oh, man, guys,
don't look now.
Take me back, Wendy!
My arms are too skinny
to keep holding this
boom box forever!
I was never here.
Have you been
getting my texts?
Do I need to send you
more texts? Wendy!
This is not good.
I cannot feed such
a big family.
Where will we stay, Dipper?
Where will I put
all my sweaters?
And what's Stan
gonna tell mom and dad?
Ah, Mr. pines will
figure something out.
He always does!
Don't worry, your son
and daughter are fine.
Where are we staying?
Uh, I put 'em up at this
amazing 4-star hotel!
What? uh, sure, we got...
Plenty to eat.
Uh, relax.
If I thought I couldn't
take care of these kids,
I'd send 'em back right away.
Uh-huh. You, too.
Grunkle Stan,
can we order pizza?
( Sighs )
( Laughs )
( Blows whistle )
back to your corner!
I've been meanin'
to ask you, boy.
Shouldn't you be
celebratin' gideonland
instead of sticking your head
in that there book all day?
Father, have I ever told you
the true nature of this book?
It was written many years ago
by a brilliant unknown author
who learned secrets
too powerful for one man.
He hid his journals
where he thought no one
would ever find 'em.
Because he knew
that if the journals
were ever brought together,
they would unleash a gateway
to unimaginable power!
Codes and maps
have led me to believe
the other book's
buried somewhere
on this very property.
And I intend to find it.
So that's why you
wanted the mystery shack.
That's right, father.
It's time to begin
the search...
For the other journal!
Go, red car!
Go, other red car!
This would be a lot
more fun with batteries.
( Grunts )
( Clears throat )
kids, we gotta talk.
Look, I've been thinking,
and I can't take care
of you anymore.
I don't have a house,
or-- or a job.
The plan is
you're going home.
Your bus leaves tomorrow.
Here are your tickets.
But, grunkle Stan,
you can't give up.
Yeah, dude.
Look at these faces!
Be cuter, Mabel!
Your summer depends on it!
Look, I lost, okay?
The best thing
is for you to be
with your parents.
I'm sorry, kids.
Gideon won.
Summer's over.
Mr. pines! Come back!
Reconsider!
Mabel, that's enough!
If Stan won't get
our home back from Gideon,
then we'll have
to do it ourselves!
Gideon may have
the upper hand,
but we have one thing
he doesn't.
A grappling hook!
The journal!
Oh, the journal.
Journal!
All right.
The bus to take us
out of gravity falls
comes at sundown.
If we wanna stay in town,
we've gotta get past
those guards,
make it through the fence,
and get Gideon
to hand over that deed.
Leave that to Mabel!
Wa-cha!
Aah! ( grunts )
Now will you admit
the grappling hook
is useless?
Nope!
Okay, what can we use
to defeat Gideon?
Let's see. Barf fairy?
Yeah!
nope.
Butternut squash
with a human face
and emotions?
Yeah!
nope.
Whoa! what's this?
I've stared at
this page for hours.
It seems like a blueprint
to build some kind
of strange futuristic
super weapon--
boring! to defeat
those guards, we need
some kind of army.
Wait a minute. An army!
Mabel, that's it!
The gnomes!
Uh...
I think this is
their hiding spot.
I wonder what gnomes
do out here all alone
in the forest.
Both: aah!
( Scatting ) aah!
This, this is normal.
This is normal for gnomes.
Scrub, scrub.
Well, well, well!
Look who came crawling back!
Take five, Chris.
You guys keep doin'
what you're doin'.
So, changed your mind
about marrying me,
did you, Mabel?
Ew! hardly!
We need your help.
And seriously, ew!
You want our help?
After you left me
at the altar? No dice!
Well, what if we
were able to get you
a new queen?
One even more
beautiful than me!
Her name's Gideon
and she has lovely
white hair.
Whoa! mature woman, huh?
Hey, shmebulock,
get my Cologne!
Shmebulock!
Is "shmebulock"
all you can say?
Shmebulock.
It's a deal!
Waiter, give me a glass
of the strongest,
most expired
apple cider you've got.
Sure thing, Mr. pines.
Soos? what are you
doing here?
Since the mystery shack
shut down,
I've had to take a bunch
of part-time jobs.
Grave digger, bus driver,
really awesome cook.
Hey, is the kitchen
supposed to have
that much fire in it?
( Woman screams )
( Sighs ) you're
a good man-child, Soos,
but it's not looking good.
This whole town loves
Gideon and hates me.
If only they knew
how evil he really was.
Hey, I'm here
for you, dude.
The entire lower half
of your body is on fire.
Shh. we're having
a moment.
Where are you, journal?
Where are you?
Boy, I hate
to interrupt you,
but you have some guests.
What?
Give us the deed
to the shack, Gideon!
Or else!
Am I supposed to say,
"or else what?"
Yes, you are supposed
to say that! Now!
( Both grunt )
( Gasps )
( Laughing )
( Gasping )
You're surrounded by
an unstoppable gnome army.
Now give us back our deed
and get off our property!
And let the marriage
ceremony begin!
( Sighs ) very well.
I suppose this deed
belongs to--
( shrill whistle )
Ha! what do you know?
Works on gnomes, too.
Stop! we'll do anything!
How can we serve you,
your majesty?
The most beautiful girl
we've ever seen!
I am not a girl!
Really? but your
skin is so soft.
You moisturize or...
Subdue them!
( Overlapping grunting )
I have to admit,
kids, I am impressed
by your creativity.
How did you ever?
Let go!
Oh, no!
No! could it be? Is it?
( Gasps )
( Laughs ) of course!
It all makes sense!
The one place I'd
never think to look.
You had it the whole time!
And to think I actually
considered you a threat!
No! give it back!
Every victory you had
was because of your
precious book!
Give it back or I'll--
or you'll what, boy?
You'll what? Huh? Huh?
No muscles, no brains.
Face it. You're
nothing without this!
Bye-bye forever,
y'all.
( Whistles )
No!
Next time, do your
own dirty work!
Come on, boys!
Well, that's it.
Guess the bus
should be here soon.
What? Dipper,
don't give up!
You always
have a plan!
No, the journal always
has the plan!
Think about it, Mabel.
Gideon was right.
The only courageous
or cool things
I've ever done
have been because
of that journal.
Without it,
i can't help you
or Stan or anyone.
There's gotta be
something we can do.
What can we do?
Man: bus fifty-two departing
gravity falls. All aboard.
Sorry, kids.
It's for the best.
Can't believe
this is happening.
( Giggles ) I've got it!
I've finally got it!
Get out!
( Exclaims )
It's finally mine!
At last, I have
journal number...
Three?
There are three of 'em?
But where is
journal number one?
I must have all three for
the power to be unlocked!
But where could i-- Dipper!
He must know where it is!
He gave me the third one
and kept the first
for himself!
I can't let him leave
gravity falls!
You there! Is it ready?
Only one way to find out!
( Grunts )
I got a good feelin'
about that kid!
Well, Stan, this is it.
Rock bottom.
No friends, no family,
stuck watching infomercials
for whatever that is.
Are you sick of
piles of owls constantly
blocking your driveway?
Well, then you've
gotta get owl trowel!
How did you do it, kid?
Why are you always
one step ahead?
Maybe he really is
psychic after--
( ringing sound )
aah! My hearing aid!
What keeps causing that?
Wait a minute. That's it!
I know Gideon's weakness!
Would Mr. pines like a--
mwah!
I go vacuum my face.
Hey, Dipper. Wanna play
bus seat treasure hunt?
I'm not in the mood.
Oh, come on.
We got Canadian coin,
gum that's shaped like
Ronald Reagan's head.
Ooh! miscellaneous
fluid stain.
Giant robot!
Yeah, giant robot.
Wait. What?
Look!
halt! I command you
to halt!
( Both scream )
Mr. bus driver!
There's a giant gideonbot
coming towards us!
Oh, hey, dudes!
Both: Soos!
Don't worry, guys.
I've been a part-time
bus driver
for at least 40 minutes.
One of these things
is probably a clutch.
Hang on, dudes!
Aah!
Soos! look out!
( All scream )
He already won!
What does he want from us?
I got you in my sights!
Soos! cliff!
( All scream )
( Grunt of exertion )
Soos: aah!
( All screaming )
Okay, what's closest
to our present situation?
"Raccoon in the engine"
or "angry grandparent
won't leave bus"?
Probably-- probably
the second one.
( Panting ) huh?
Tell me! Where is
journal number one?
Both:
Don't play games
with me, boy!
Oh!
aah! aah!
I don't know what
you're talking about!
You took the only
journal I ever had!
What do you even want
with these journals, anyway?
Both: aah! Aah!
( Audibly struggling )
let go of her!
Ha ha ha! You still think
you're some kind of hero?
Aaahhh! unh!
( Groans )
Once I find
the final journal,
I'll rule this town!
With you as my queen!
( Laughs )
Dipper, help me!
Help!
Gideon: face it, kid.
You're nothing without
that journal.
How you gonna fight back?
No muscles, no brains.
What are you gonna do? Huh?
What are you gonna do?
( Yelling )
Let go of my sister!
Never! I finally
won this time!
( Fighting grunts )
Aah! aah! Get off!
Let go of me!
( Grunts )
( Grunts ) huh?
( Audible struggling )
( Screaming )
Careful in there!
Dudes! no!
Grappling hook!
Told you it would
come in handy.
Mabel,
that was amazing!
Not as amazing as you
defeating that robot!
Hey, my journal!
Man: oh, there it is!
Man #2: Is this the thing
that exploded?
What's going on?
What is that?
It's over here.
Ohhh.
Gideon!
Oh, good heavens!
What on earth
happened here?
It was the pines twins.
They tried to attack me
and blew up my statue
with dynamite!
Arrest 'em!
Both: what?
Officers, he's lying!
Sorry, kids,
but we trust Gideon,
and nothing short
of a miracle could
ever change our--
( screaming )
aah!
Wait! wait! Stop everything!
I've got something to say!
Not this guy again.
Just wait! Look!
You guys all think Gideon
is so perfect and honest.
"Oh, I could never
tell a lie! I'm Gideon!"
He's more honest
than you!
Yeah!
and he's psychic too!
How's this for psychic?
Bam! Take a good look!
Wait a minute!
Is that me?
The secret ingredient
to my coffee omelet
is coffee!
And me!
I can verify
that that birthmark
is indeed disgusting.
Hooray!
Onlookers:
that's me!
That's right! These pins
are hidden cameras!
And my hearing aid was
picking up the feedback!
Who's the fraud now?
Gideon,
we gave you our trust.
You lied to us!
Please, i-- ( gasps )
it's not what it looks like.
What are you
gonna do with me?
Tyler?
Get him.
( Sniffles )
get him.
( Gasps )
li'l Gideon,
you are under arrest...
For conspiracy, fraud,
and breaking our hearts.
Durland,
the tiny handcuffs.
Wha-- no!
Just one more thing.
Let go of me!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
I believe
this belongs to me.
No! no! Watch the hair!
You can't do this to me!
Y'all are sheep!
You need me!
I'll be back!
You'll hear
from my lawyers!
There you have it.
Local hero Stanford pines
has just exposed
li'l Gideon as a fraud.
Anything you have to say
to the town, Stanford?
The mystery shack
is back, baby!
( Laughing )
( Sighs )
( Laughs )
oh, thank you,
thank you!
( Chomps )
( Mewing )
hey, grunkle Stan!
Uh, you kiddos
settling back in okay?
Yep! all of my
favorite moldy spots
on the ceiling
are still there!
Even you, Daryl!
Hey, grunkle Stan,
me and Mabel have
been talking,
and I think there's
something we should
finally tell you.
This is a journal
i found in the woods.
It talks about
all the crazy stuff that
goes on in gravity falls.
Gideon nearly
destroyed the whole town
trying to find it.
I don't know what it means,
or who wrote it,
but after all
we've been through,
maybe you should
finally know about it.
I'm glad you
showed me this, Dipper.
( Laughs )
now I know where you've
been getting it all from!
Spookums and monsters.
This kooky book
has been filling your head
with crazy conspiracies!
But it's all real!
( Laughs ) you gotta
quit readin' this fantasy
nonsense for your own good.
Although some of these
would make great attractions!
Can't come up with this stuff!
Mind if I borrow this?
Wait! no! Grunkle Stan!
( Laughingly )
"magic book." Ridiculous!
Stan, I need it!
Dipper, you don't
need that book!
Don't you see?
On your own you
defeated a giant robot
with nothing
but your bare hands!
You're a hero
whether you've got
that journal or not!
Whoa. thanks, Mabel.
I still want it back though.
I'm sure
you'll get it back.
What would a boring
old man like Stan want
with that book anyway?
( Both gasp )
Soos'ed!
( Both laughing )
After all these years.
Finally, I have them all.
It's working!
( Grunts with exertion )
Here we go.