Oh!
total domination!
I am the master
of attic-stuff mini-golf!
From the mighty Swiss alps
to the badlands
of Dipper's old laundry,
where man fears to tread.
All right,
let a pro on the field.
Er...floor.
whatever.
Stan: ow! My head!
It hit me right
in the head!
Yes!
Stan shot!
Is that legal?
The judges say
it's out of bounds.
You're out of bounds!
Hey!
stop it!
( Both laughing )
( Alarm rings )
Hey, Dipper, I gotta
go hang out with candy
and grenda tonight.
Aw, again?
You can't
leave mid-game!
Don't be silly,
I'm not leaving!
My friends
are coming to me!
Wait, what?
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
Sleeping bags?
Rom-coms?
Calling all boys
preteen edition?!
You're not having a--
both:
sleep over!
Ahh!
Mabel: okay, so how much
do you like boys?
So much!
Boys make me think
about kissing.
Candy!
( giggling )
Oh my gosh!
Ow!
We are so crazy tonight!
Ohh!
All:
ahh!
( Screaming continues )
Who wants to smear
make-up on my face?
Oh, you're already
so beautiful grenda,
what would
be the point?
Beautiful!
beautiful!
( groaning )
Mabel!
Do you think you could
do this somewhere else?
You're laughing
at frequencies only
dogs should hear.
Come on,
it's not that bad.
You know what
your brother needs?
( Gasps )
a makeover?
( Dipper screaming )
( Bleats )
( Sighs )
Hey Soos, can I sleep
in your break room tonight?
Of course, dude.
You just gotta
make your body
go like a video game
puzzle block.
( Beeping )
The trick is to hold
perfectly still,
( sizzles )
oh! Wait, wait.
( Sizzles )
Ow, ow, ow--
I think I'll
sleep somewhere else.
( Sizzles )
actually felt good that time.
ow! Wait, wait.
Ah!
Sleeping under the stars...
Not bad.
( Growling )
Ah!
get off!
Ah! ah!
Get away!
( Screaming )
( Barking, growling )
This is still better.
Uhh...
what happened last night?
Whoa!
What's up,
party girl?
I don't know what
i was kissing in there,
but I have no regrets.
Candy falls down now!
That was awesome,
girls!
See you again
soon!
Hey brother!
You want any
of this leftover pizza?
It's got glitter on it!
Mabel, last night an owl
tried to eat my tongue.
( Chuckles )
that's great!
No, it's not great!
This is impossible
to live with!
What? I'm delightful
Get ready to be poked
by the fun stick!
Boop.
ahh!
Mabel, I've had it
with the fun stick!
You've totally
wrecked our room.
And...
( gasps )
oh no!
Our mini golf course!
Yeah, grenda sure
loves breaking things.
Mabel, we need to lay
down some ground rules
if we're gonna be living
in this room together.
First of all,
no sleepovers.
What?!
Well if I can't
have sleepovers,
then you can't keep
me up every night with
your summer reading.
How does reading
keep you up?
( Gasps )
Oh...
( chuckles )
Interesting...
But who stole the capers?
( Pen clicking )
( Groaning )
Well, at least my braces
don't whistle when I breathe!
At least I wash
my clothes once in a while!
Washing clothes
is a waste of time!
I'm a busy guy!
( Meowing )
All right.
If you meow
one more time--
( meows louder )
Okay, that's it,
that's the final straw.
Maybe we shouldn't
share a room anymore.
Well, uh--
well, maybe
we shouldn't!
Fine by me!
Double fine by me!
Then we need to talk
to grunkle Stan
about moving rooms.
Yeah, he's
a reasonable guy.
( Grunting )
Fight! fight!
Fight!
fight! fight!
( Cooing )
Fight! fight!
Fight!
Stan:
fight! fight! Fight!
TV, it knows what I want.
Grunkle Stan?
We want different rooms.
And I want a pair
of magic money pants!
It's not gonna happen.
Magic money pants?
Come on,
grunkle Stan!
Can't we work
something out?
Look, kid.
There's my room
and the attic.
That's it.
What do you think,
there's some kind
of secret hidden room
in the shack?
( Crash )
Soos: dudes!
I found some kind of secret
hidden room in the shack!
Okay, so I was cleaning
up behind this bookcase,
when boom!
Mystery door.
This old shack is full
of weird secrets.
Woah!
( Gasps )
classy!
( Coughing )
"Experiment 78."
Grunkle Stan,
what is this place?
I don't know.
Just another room
i gotta clean up now.
The carpet it's amazing!
Yeah, if you're into
things that are terrible.
Problem solved!
I'll move in here!
What? why do you
automatically
get the room?
We both saw it
at the same time!
Wait a second...
So you both
want this room, huh?
I guess I'll give it to
whichever one of you
i like more.
Uh oh.
Looks like my shoe's untied!
( Both grunting )
give it to me.
( Laughing )
To the kitchen!
Fight! Fight!
Fight! fight!
Whoa.
i don't know dudes.
This room gives me
major creep-o vibes.
Ya know, the attic
is a pretty good space.
Maybe you two should
appreciate what you got.
Grunkle Stan!
I gotta have that room!
Huh.
hey, what do I know?
Maybe there's nothing creepy
going on in this room.
( Ominous music )
( Zapping )
All right, kids,
here's how it's gonna go down.
Whoever sucks up the hardest,
gets the key to the new room.
Grunkle Stan, we're not
going to suck up to you
just to get the new room.
Yeah, we are!
Ten suck up points for Mabel!
I mean, uh,
yeah we are!
( Chuckles )
Trying too hard.
Minus 15 suck up points.
What?
good decision,
grunkle Stan!
Trying way too hard!
Plus 50 suck up points.
Now who wants
to re-tile the roof
in searing 105 degree heat!
Me! me!
I'll do it!
Me! no, Dipper!
Give it here!
Ahh, Stan,
you're a good uncle.
Mabel:
I'll kill you!
( Sighs )
Dipper!
you're phoning it in!
Ahh. man,
that's refreshing.
Ten suck up points
for this lemonade.
( In high pitched voice )
thank you, Stan.
Oh, ho! Ten more
for politeness.
Oh, and so sweet!
( Sighs )
All these chores will be
worth it when I get this room.
Shag carpeting...
Come on!
( Ominous music )
Hey, brother.
Don't get too
comfortable,
I just made Stan an omelet
shaped like his own face.
I have seen the face of beauty.
Face it.
I'm like a suck up ninja!
This room's
as good as mine!
You might as well give up now.
What do you say?
I say, I'm gonna win
this room somehow,
and when I do...
I'll finally
have my own space,
and we'll never have
to share anything ever again!
Both:
ahh!
( Dipper's voice )
ugh...What happened?
( Mabel's voice )
Dipper?
Why are you wearing
my clothes?
And my... face!?
Am I in my your body?
Ahh!
ahh!
( Retching )
( Panting, screaming )
Get out!
This isn't happening.
Aahh!
( Still Dipper's voice )
great, just what we need.
More gravity
falls weirdness.
( Still Mabel's voice )
this is stupid!
Sharing a room
was bad enough.
Now we're sharing bodies?
Ugh, braces are horrible.
It's like my
mouth hates me!
And what are
these things?
I wanna know why
you're so sweaty!
And awkward.
Hey, look!
Experiment 78!
Electron carpet.
Atoms can swap electrons.
This carpet must
build up a static charge
so powerful
it can swap minds.
It was the static
electricity.
Maybe, we could use
it to switch back!
( Pen clicking )
phew. Oh, oh!
Glad I'm switchin' back.
If I was you,
i would totally
lose the contest.
And if I was you,
which I am...
I could sabotage myself!
Then Mabel would
lose all her points
and the room
would go to Dipper!
Wait, what?
Oh, Stan!
I've always
hated you!
Ha ha! See who he
gives the room to now!
No! wait!
Tie your shoes!!
Mmm... those cannibals are
onto something,
I taste delicious!
Grunkle Stan!
What's the word,
Mabel?
That's right!
It's me, ugh, Mabel!
If you like that omelet,
you'll love this...
A sandwich made
out of rocks!
Candy rocks?
Regular rocks!
Keep that up, and I'll be
giving your brother this key.
Ha ha!
I mean... darn.
Mabel:
hey, grunkle Stan!
Your face looks
like a butt!
What?!
В™є breaking stuff is
so much fun! В™є
в™є I am Dipper and I stink! В™є
Mabel's gone bananas!
Bing! zow!
Ba-low!
( Laughing )
Well,
this is getting weird.
Wait!
Are you gonna
dock Mabel points?
Dipper should lose
all his points!
Ugh!
grunkle Stan!
Waddles, you got it good, bro.
You got no worries.
I mean, nobody
thinks it's cute
when I lie naked
on the living room floor.
I wish I could be a pig.
( Ominous music,
coos yells )
Yes!
I should do
out loud wishing more often.
Is that a corn cob I spy?
( Grunts )
i got little legs!
( Snorting, squealing )
Hey, Soos.
What's up?
Have you seen my--
( ominous music )
Uh... I'll come back later.
Grunkle Stan, come back!
I have more
terrible things to do!
You're toast, Mabel!
That room's
as good as mine!
There you are Mabel!
Attack her
with love!
Yeah!
Both:
sleep over!
What!?
no no no!
Ahh!
Dipper?
hey, wait!
Wait, come back!
Hey! could i
talk to my, uh,
sister for a sec?
This is a sleepover buddy.
No boys allowed!
( Giggling )
Look guys, I'm not really
in a sleepover mood right now.
One of my irrational
girl mood swings, you know?
Right?
don't we have those?
Come on! My mom's
age-inappropriate romance novels
aren't going to read themselves!
Oh! "wolfman, barechest"!
Ohh!
Uh, really,
i should probably..
Come on!
You know you love it!!!
"My name is Gerard.
"I am a werewolf,
creature of the night,
but I am also
a creature of passion."
( Giggling )
( Groans )
Gerard is just so fierce.
What's goin' on,
Dipper?
( Gasps )
Ahh... you're at that creepy
age where you spy on girls, huh?
Guess it's time you and me
had a man-to-man talk
about the birds and the bees,
ya know.
I--i should
really be going--
no way out of it!
Look, it all begins
with this little fella,
the pituitary gland.
He may be little,
but he has big plans.
Ahh!
I wonder what rollicking
adventures I'll stumble into.
A mud puddle!
Do I dare live out
the cliche?
( Laughing )
( Jabbering )
wow!
I'm a pig!
Oink oink, right?
( Chuckles )
Free meal!
No! don't eat me!
I'm a man trapped
in a pig's body!
That's what they all say!
( Coos panting,
old man mcguckett laughing )
Soos:
help! police!
( Gasps )
a bearded witch
chasing a talking pig!
My horoscope came true.
Now read mine!
What are you,
gemini?
You knew?!
Yeah, of course,
i knew!
And now you know where
babies come from.
Goodbye, childhood.
You know, I find you more
likable today than usual.
Maybe you could still
win that game after all.
Huh?
I was gonna give that
new room to Mabel--
no, you should!
Give it to Mabel!
You big jerk!
What did you say to me?
I said, uh,
shut up, old man!
You're fat and dumb,
and you're a dummy,
and take that!
Finally standing up to me, huh?
I love it!
You know,
I've made up my mind.
The room belongs to you,
Dipper.
You can't!
You have to give
it to Mabel!
Shh.
You had me at
"shut up old man."
No!
The end.
Phew.
Now for the 38 sequels!
No!
I'm gonna make you
into bacon!
Oh, ho! That sounds
pretty good.
Wait, I mean,
no!
Three, four, five.
( Phone rings )
It's him!
My dream date!
Hello!?
( Automated voice)
Hello baby, this is Kevin.
My beach house has room...
For two.
Kevin has the voice
of a robot.
Don't ruin this
for me, candy!
It's your turn, Mabel.
( Panting )
I gotta win the room.
Stan! it's me, Mabel!
I'm doing things you hate!
( Grunts )
( Sighs )
it's over, Dipper.
Stan gave you the room.
Ha ha! Yes!
All right!
( Clears throat )
Well let's switch bodies then,
and I can start moving in!
Wait a minute,
you can't have the room...
If you can never get in!
Hey, come back!
( Panting )
Come on!
Open the door, Dipper!
I mean... Mabel.
( Sighs )
How am I ever
gonna get in there?
Hmm...
Kevin for the last time,
I'm not interested!
How could you
say that to Kevin!
Hey girls, who wants
to give my brother a make-over!
( Both gasp )
( Oinking )
Oh, good, Soos.
( Squeals )
ya got a second?
Look, times are tough,
economy, or something, etc.
Basically...
i have to cut your pay.
Wh-- what are
you doing?
( Snorting )
Is this some sort
of negotiating tactic?
'Cause it's not gonna to work.
Fine! I was lying.
I'll give you a raise!
Just never do that again.
Stan:
ugh. nightmare.
Can you help me?
I'm looking for directions--
( oinks )
Oh, you'll
show me the way?
Such a gentleman!
( Knocking )
Candy and grenda:
It's candy and grenda!
Friends!
Hey guys!
What's up?
Dipper?! wait!
Don't let him in here!
Both:
make over!
No, no! Stop, stop!
Whoa, no!
We're gonna
make you so hot!
Wait, no!
Stop!
Guys, you have to
listen to me!
No!
Good job, ladies!
Now let me just add
one final touch!
( Groans )
( Dipper's voice )
my body!
I'm a genius!
Ugh... all right, Mabel.
The room is mine.
Wait! hold on here.
What just happened?
( Mabel's voice, sighs )
i barely understand it.
All I know, is if you shuffle
your feet on this carpet,
you can switch bodies
or whatever.
Zip zip!
No!
( Dipper's voice )
aw, come on!
( Candy's voice )
i am a boy now!
( Deepens voice )
what's up, brah?
Lets grow some
moustaches!
Dipper, give me
that key back!
( Both grunting )
Guys!
stop fighting!
( Dipper's voice )
oh, no!
Then again, I like
having muscles for once
( grenda's voice ) wow!
Now I have
tiny little doll hands!
( Mabel's voice )
everybody, look.
Swap back in three, two--
Soos: oh, dude!
Come back!
I wanna deep fry yer ears!
( Arguing over each other )
Announcer:
tonight on baby fights!
Tensions rise between
Madison and Avery
at baby fight headquarters.
Mabel:
give me my body back!
( Groans )
( Grenda's voice )
cool! I'm Santa claus!
( Old man mcguckett )
whoo-ee! Ha ha!
I've regained my innocence!
(Dipper's voice, sighs )
well, I guess I'm a pig now.
So, that's a thing.
( Soos' voice )
this body's not
that different
from my old one.
We got some reports
of excessive giggling.
( Giggling )
( Blubs' voice )
my horoscope didn't
say anything about this!
( Durland's voice )
ahh! What's happening to me?!
Ow! ugh!
( Giggles )
( Candy's voice )
i am a police officer now!
( Giggles )
( Grenda's voice )
let's go get some perps, candy!
Give me that key, Mabel!
Never!
( Shouting )
( Dipper's voice )
Mabel, are you you?
( Mabel's voice )
yeah, I'm me.
Well, I've got the key!
Mabel!
the room is mine!
Give it to me!
( Both grunting )
What's with you?
Why do you need
that room so bad?
I never even
wanted to move out!
Me either!
Wait, what?
Say that again!
I--i never
wanted to move out.
Then what was all this?
Everything was fine until
you started bringing
your friends
around every night.
I mean, hanging out with
you this summer's been fun.
But now, you're always
with candy and grenda.
And I'm... like,
just left behind.
Aw, Dipper.
It's okay.
I've been having
a hard time.
You wouldn't understand
what I'm going through.
You're probably feeling
awkward and sweaty, huh?
Yeah. how'd you know?
Here.
i won't fight you for it.
Thanks.
Well, it looks like
everyone's back to normal!
( Sighing )
Except for Soos,
who may be pig permanently?
Oh, no. I changed back.
At least I think I did.
I'll still eat ya.
Dipper: okay pal,
that's enough of that.
Mabel: move it along,
weird old man.
Huh, I guess being a pig
wasn't that great after all.
Hey, lemme get that spot
you can never reach...
( Doorbell rings )
Hey, I've been thinking
and the answer is...
Yes!
i will marry you!
Wait I don't remember
anything about a--
hmm. all right.
( Sighs )
Ah, there.
Ahh, a man
in his own space.
That's right!
Finally.
So what are you gonna
do with this old thing?
Get rid of it.
Ha ha!
You got it.
This carpet's ugly.
Ah, finally, my own room.
Goodnight, Mabel.
Goodnight, Dipper.
( Knocking )
Hey, um, you wanna
have a sleepover?
Fore!
( Laughing )
Stan: ah! Why am I even
out here at night?
( Mabel and Dipper laugh )
So, what are we gonna
do with that new room?
I gave it to Soos
to replace
that horrible
break room he has.
Hey, do you know what
the deal was with that lady?
I just don't think
i can do this anymore.
You just seem so...
Different.
Look, dude, uh, I'm playing
a little bit of catch up here.
I was in a pig's body
for most of the day.
What's going on?
Can we kiss again?
Is that an option?
( Sizzling )
Soos: Oh! Wait, wait.