I'VE SEEN DEATH,
l'VE SEEN...
MY FRlENDS,
MY MEN BElNG KlLLED.
AND, UH...
THlS lS...
IT DOESN'T TAKE
TOO MANY DAYS OF THAT
AND YOU CHANGE
DRAMATlCALLY.
WE WAS HUNGRY,
WE HAD NO FOOD,
WE DlDN'T HAVE
MUCH AMMUNlTlON,
IT WAS COLD, DlDN'T
HAVE ANY CLOTHES.
YOU COULDN'T
BUlLD TO FlRE.
IF YOU'D BUlLD A
FlRE, SOME CRAZY THlNG
WOULD SHOOT AT YA.
EVERY WHERE YOU WOULD LOOK,
YOU WOULD SEE DEAD PEOPLE.
A DEAD SOLDlER THERE,
HERE, OURS, THElRS.
THEN ClVlLlANS BESlDES.
DEAD ANlMALS.
SO, DEATH
WAS ALL OVER.
YOU DON'T HAVE A CHANCE
WHEN YOUR FRlENDS GO DOWN
TO REALLY...
TAKE CARE OF 'EM
AS YOU MlGHT.
AND ESPEClALLY lF YOU'RE UNDER
ATTACK, MOVlNG, OR WHATEVER.
I WlTHSTOOD lT WELL,
BUT I HAD A LOT OF
TROUBLE lN LATER LlFE
BECAUSE THOSE EVENTS
WOULD COME BACK AND...
YOU NEVER
FORGET 'EM.
Captions made possible by
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
( Lipton )
AFTER HOLDlNG
THE LlNE AT BASTOGNE,
"EASY COMPANY" WAS ONCE AGAlN
CALLED ON TO HELP PUSH
THE GERMANS BACK
THROUGH THE BULGE.
WE WERE HERE THlS MORNlNG
AND THEN WE CAME THlS WAY.
RlGHT, SO, RlGHT HERE'S
GOTTA BE THE LOGGlNG ROAD
COMlNG lNTO HERE...
WHlCH MEANS WE
GET RlGHT THERE.
HEY, TAKE lT EASY.
STOP CRYlNG,
MALARK, OR l'LL
NAlL lT TO YOUR HEAD.
HEY, YOU SHOULD,
lT'S MADE OF WOOD.
GUARNERE, MOVE 'EM
OUT, LET'S GO.
YES, SlR.
2nd PLATOON,
LET'S GO!
( Lipton )
I WAS GLAD TO BE OUT OF
MY FOOHOLE AND MOVlNG AGAlN.
EVEN lF ONLY
TO GET WARM.
( Buck )
SPREAD OUT,
KEEP YOUR lNTERVAL.
( Lipton )
"E COMPANY" WAS SENT
TO CLEAR THE BOlS JACQUES,
THE WOODS NEAR
THE TOWN OF FOY,
IN PREPARATlON FOR WHAT
WE ALL KNEW WOULD BE
THE EVENTUAL ASSAULT
ON FOY lTSELF.
I SEE lT, BUCK,
WATCH FOR MlNES.
( Lipton )
DURlNG THAT 1,000 YARD
ATTACK THROUGH THE WOODS,
WE ENCOUNTERED SPORADlC
GERMAN MACHlNE-GUN FlRE
AND HAD A COUPLE
OF CASUALTlES.
BUT, FOR THE MOST PART,
MET LlTTLE RESlSTANCE.
HOOBLER'S RUN-lN
WlTH THE GERMAN OFFlCER
ON HORSEBACK
WAS THE MOST DRAMATlC
MOMENT OF THE DAY.
HALT!
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
( laughing )
OH, SHlT.
THANK YOU.
HOOBLER HAD BEEN TALKlNG
ABOUT GETTlNG A LUGER
SlNCE NORMANDY.
AS WE DUG lN, HE WENT
FROM FOOHOLE TO FOOHOLE
TELLlNG EVERYONE JUST
HOW HE'D FlNALLY GOT ONE.
AND DOWN HE GOES
RlGHT OUT OF THE SADDLE,
LlKE A SACK
OF POTATOES.
OUTSTANDlNG ACCURACY
ON MY PART,
IF I DO SAY
SO MYSELF.
WHlCH YOU DO.
WHlCH I DO.
HELL, SHlFTY, I THlNK MAYBE
I COULD HAVE EVEN GlVEN YOU
A RUN FOR
YOUR MONEY, RlGHT?
NO, NO, l'M NOT
A GOOD SHOT.
NOW, DAD, HE WAS
AN EOCELLENT SHOT.
EOCELLENT, I DECLARE,
HE'D SHOOT THE
WlNGS OFF A FLY.
HEY, LlP, THAT GERMAN,
WHAT'D YOU THlNK
HE WAS DOlNG?
PROBABLY A
LlTTLE RECON.
HE MUST HAVE FlGURED
NOBODY WOULD HEAR A HORSE.
I THlNK HE WAS JUST
TRYlNG TO GET THE
HELL OUT OF DODGE.
YEAH.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE HORSE?
I DON'T KNOW,
PROBABLY STlLL RUNNlNG.
HOPE HE'S OKAY.
YOU DUG lN?
YEAH, YEAH.
YEAH, JUST THOUGHT
l'D TAKE A WALK,
SHOOT THE SHlT.
WELL, YOU'RE
A GOOD SHOT, HOOB.
JUST GLAD
YOU'RE ON OUR SlDE.
THANKS, LlP.
HEY, LlPTON?
YEAH.
THANKS FOR
THE HELP.
YOU GOT lT,
SHlFTY.
HEY, LlP?
YES. YOU GOT A SEC?
YES, SlR.
GlVE HlM A HAND.
WHERE'S DlKE?
HE'S, ER,
HE'S AROUND.
COULD YOU BE A
LlTTLE MORE SPEClFlC
THERE, SERGEANT?
NOT REALLY, SlR.
GODAMMlT, I HAVEN'T
SEEN HlM ALL DAY.
I DlDN'T SEE HlM
WHEN WE WERE COMlNG
THROUGH THE WOODS,
AND I HAVE TO FlGURE
OUT HOW WE ENDED UP.
WELL, TWO WOUNDED.
WHO?
BROWN AND STEVENSON.
GODAMMlT.
AND WHERE'S DlKE,
WHERE THE HELL lS HE?
WHERE THE HELL
DOES HE EVER GO?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT I WlSH
HE'D STAY THE HELL THERE.
IT'D BE NlCE lF
HE TOOK LlEUTENANT
SHAMES WlTH HlM, TOO.
SHUT UP,
BOYS.
SHUTTlNG UP,
SARGE.
OH, HEY, WHAT
THE HELL lS THAT?
PATROL?
NO, WE WOULD
HAVE HEARD.
ONE MAN,
MAYBE A SNlPER.
THAT WAS NO RlFLE.
WHAT DO YOU
SEE, SHlFT?
NOBODY OUT THERE.
ARE YOU SURE?
UH-HUH.
AH, JESUS, lT'S
HOOB, HE'S SHOT.
SNlPER?
NO, NO, HE
SHOT HlMSELF.
STUPlD, STUPlD.
MEDlC!
WHAT HAPPENED?
DOC.
IS HE ALRlGHT?
IT'S MY FUCKlNG LEG.
HE DlD WHAT?
IT JUST WENT OFF.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
DOlNG WlTH A LOADED
GUN lN YOUR PANTS?
SHlT, BUCK, I WASN'T
TOUCHlNG lT OR NOTHlNG.
GODAMMlT,
GODAMMlT.
( Hoobler )
I WASN'T TOUCHlNG
lT, I SWEAR.
MEDlC!
WHERE ARE
YOU HlT, HOOB?
HOOB, WHERE ARE
YOU HlT?
IN MY LEG.
HOLD ON, HOOB, HOLD ON.
NOW, DON'T LOOK, HOOB.
IT'S GONNA BE FlNE.
IT HURTS LlKE
A SONOFABlTCH.
I THlNK MAYBE
I HlT BONE.
DOC!
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT lT, HOOB.
WARM HlM UP,
WARM HlM UP.
CAN YOU HEAR
ME, HOOB?
SOMEBODY KEEP
HlM WARM.
SERGEANT.
SERGEANT, LET ME
SEE lT, HUH?
HANG lN THERE.
CAN WE GET HlM,
WARM UP SOME BLANKETS
OR SOMETHlNG FOR HlM?
YOU'RE GONNA
BE FlNE.
OKAY, HOOB,
LlSTEN TO ME, HOOB.
DlD YOU THlNK lT WAS
A GERMAN LEG, HOOB?
YOU'RE GONNA
BE FlNE.
HOLD ON, HOOB,
HOLD ON.
PERCONTE, PUT
THlS ACROSS HlM.
WRAP HlM UP,
WRAP HlM UP.
HANG lN THERE, HOOB.
COME ON, COME ON.
HEY, LlP.
YOU SAlD I WAS A
GREAT SHOT, RlGHT?
YOU'RE A GREAT SHOT,
YOU'RE A GREAT SHOT.
COME ON, HOOB,
YOU JUMP OUT OF PLANES.
YOU'RE TOUGH, MAN,
YOU'RE TOUGH, COME ON.
HE'S STlLL SHlVERlNG.
IT'S NOT THAT BAD
AT ALL, COME ON.
STAY WlTH US, HOOB.
HOOB, TAKE lT EASY.
HOW ARE WE
DOlNG, DOC?
OKAY, YOU'RE
GONNA BE FlNE.
I CAN'T SEE A THlNG,
WE'VE GOTTA GET HlM BACK
TO AN AlD STATlON.
HOLD ON TlGHT.
ALRlGHT, RlGHT, LET'S
GET READY TO MOVE HlM.
TAKE lT EASY.
STAY THERE, HOOB.
I CAN'T SEE ANYTHlNG,
WE'RE GONNA NEED TO...
DOC!
JESUS.
PERCO, WE
NEED A JEEP.
( Lipton )
HE WAS WEARlNG
SO MANY CLOTHES,
WE COULDN'T TELL HOW
BAD HE WAS BLEEDlNG.
BY THE TlME WE GOT HlM
TO THE AlD STATlON,
HE WAS ALREADY DEAD.
THE BULLET CUT
THE MAlN ARTERY
lN HlS LEG, SlR.
OH HELL, LlP.
IT WOULDN'T HAVE
MADE A DlFFERENCE
lF YOU HAD KNOWN.
CUT THAT MAlN ARTERY lN
THE LEG, THAT'S, THAT'S lT.
YES, SlR.
WELL, l'M GONNA GO BACK
AND MAKE SURE THE BOYS
ARE ALL DUG lN, SlR.
LlP.
WHERE'S DlKE?
YOU WANNA
SEE HlM, SlR?
NO, I JUST WOULD
HAVE EOPECTED TO GET
THlS KlND OF NEWS
FROM HlM.
WELL, I WAS THERE, SlR.
OH.
I FlGURED lT MlGHT
AS WELL BE ME.
( Lipton )
"WHERE'S DlKE?"
I PROBABLY HEARD THAT
QUESTlON 1,000 TlMES.
I PROBABLY ASKED lT
A FEW TlMES MYSELF.
THERE WERE LONG STRETCHES
WHERE WE DlDN'T KNOW
WHERE LlEUTENANT DlKE WAS.
HE'D DlSAPPEAR, GO OFF
ON THESE WALKS FOR
HOURS AT A TlME.
WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN SO BAD
lF HE WAS JUST ONE OF THE GUYS
IN THE COMPANY,
BUT LlEUTENANT DlKE
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
LEADlNG THE COMPANY.
CAPTAlN WlNTERS WAS A
C.O. WE COULD ALL RESPECT.
MOOSE HEYLlGER PROBABLY
WOULD HAVE DONE A GOOD JOB,
BUT BEFORE WE GOT
A CHANCE TO FlND OUT,
HE WAS ACClDENTALLY
SHOT BY A SENTRY.
THEN CAME
NORMAN DlKE.
AND I WANT TlGHT SECURlTY
AROUND THE COMPANY C.P.,
LlEUTENANT SHAMES,
THAT UNDERSTOOD?
( Lipton )
DlKE WASN'T A BAD LEADER
BECAUSE HE MADE BAD DEClSlONS.
HE WAS A BAD LEADER
BECAUSE HE MADE NO DEClSlONS.
NOW, BATTALlON S-3
lS PLANNlNG A MOVE.
SO, I WlLL PROBABLY
BE CALLED AWAY...
REGULARLY.
ARE THERE
ANY QUESTlONS?
ER, YEAH.
FORMATlON
YOU WANT US TO GO FOR?
AT PRESENT, AS PER USUAL,
BUT l'LL CLARlFY THAT WlTH YOU
AT A LATER TlME,
LlEUTENANT COMPTON.
YES, SlR.
ALRlGHT, I GOTTA
MAKE A CALL.
LET'S MOVE lT OUT.
( Lipton )
DlKE WAS THE FAVORlTE
OF SOMEBODY AT DlVlSlON.
HE'D BEEN SENT
DOWN TO "E COMPANY"
TO GET SOME
COMBAT EOPERlENCE.
SOMETlMES WE GOT THE
FEELlNG "E COMPANY"
WAS AN ANNOYANCE
TO HlM.
SOMETHlNG UNPLEASANT
HE HAD TO GET THROUGH
BEFORE HE COULD CONTlNUE
HlS MARCH UP THE LADDER.
I'M TELLlNG YOU BOYS,
WE'RE SCREWED.
IF YOU ASK ME,
l'M GLAD LlEUTENANT
DlKE'S NEVER AROUND.
HEY, YOU
KNOW WHAT?
WE'RE DOlNG
ALRlGHT,
EVEN WlTH
FOOHOLE NORMAN.
YEAH, DON,
WE'RE DOlNG
ALRlGHT.
ALRlGHT NOW.
IN CASE YOU
AlN'T NOTlCED,
THERE'S A LlTTLE TOWN
DOWN THE HlLL
OVER THERE, RlGHT?
AND lN THAT TOWN
ARE THESE GUYS,
AND THESE GUYS
ARE CALLED GERMANS.
AND THESE
GERMANS GOT TANKS.
I KNOW.
YEAH.
AND OUR SlDE'S
GONNA WANNA GO
lNTO THAT TOWN.
YOU WANNA TAKE
ONE GUESS AT WHO
THEY'RE GONNA WANT
TO GO
KNOCKlNG ON THE
GODDAMN DOORS.
I KNOW, BlLL,
IT'S ME YOU'RE
TALKlNG TO HERE.
JESUS CHRlST,
WE'VE GOTTA DO
ALL THlS WlTH A C.O.,
WHO'S GOT HlS HEAD
SO FAR UP HlS FUCKlNG ASS
THAT LUMP lN HlS THROAT
lS HlS GODDAMN NOSE.
HEY, 1 st SERGEANT.
HEY, BOYS.
HEY, SARGE.
HEY, LlP.
HEY, MUCK,
WHAT'S THE WORD?
OH, YOU KNOW.
SlTTlNG AROUND
FREEZlNG OUR ASS OFF.
SlNGlNG DlKE'S PRAlSES.
OH, YEAH.
LlEUTENANT DlKE.
WELL, l'LL TELL YOU,
I WOULDN'T WANNA BE
A REPLACEMENT OFFlCER
COMlNG lN HERE,
GETTlNG THROWN lN
WlTH A GROUP OF GUYS,
WHO'VE KNOWN EACH
OTHER FOR WHAT?
TWO YEARS?
THAT HAVE BEEN lN COMBAT
TOGETHER SlNCE NORMANDY.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO JUST
SHOW UP AND LEAD THEM?
HOW'S A GUY
DO THAT?
HOW COULD ANYONE REALLY
HOPE TO GAlN THE RESPECT
OF THE TOUGHEST,
MOST PROFESSlONAL,
MOST DEDlCATED SONSOFBlTCHES
lN THE ENTlRE E.T.O.?
HUH?
SO, lF YOU ASK ME,
A GUY'D HAVE TO...
MARCH OFF TO BERLlN
AND COME BACK WlTH HlTLER'S
MOUSTACHE OR SOMETHlNG.
( chuckling )
ANYWAY, LlSTEN,
YOU GUYS, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT DlKE, ALRlGHT?
YEAH.
WE ALL DO OUR JOBS,
EVERYTHlNG'LL BE FlNE.
SEE YOU, SARGE.
YEAH, BOY.
( Lipton )
WELL, I DON'T KNOW lF
I BELlEVED ANY OF THAT,
BUT AS COMPANY 1 st
SERGEANT lT WAS MY JOB,
NOT TO PROTECT DlKE,
BUT TO PROTECT THE lNTEGRlTY
OF THE COMPANY.
YOU KNOW WHAT DlKE'S
PROBLEM lS, DON'T YOU?
MMM.
HE'S JUST ANOTHER ONE OF
THOSE ARROGANT RlCH JERKS
FROM YALE.
OH, GOD, NOT ANOTHER
ONE OF THOSE.
( laughing )
DlVlSlON'S NOT GONNA
LET ME REPLACE HlM
JUST 'CAUSE I GOT A
BAD FEELlNG ABOUT HlM.
MM-MM.
EVEN lF THEY WOULD,
WHO'D I PUT lN HlS PLACE?
SHAMES?
DO NOT EVER TALK
WHEN l'M TALKlNG,
YOU GOT THAT?!
( Winters )
SHAMES' SEEN TOO
MANY WAR MOVlES.
THlNKS HE HAS TO
YELL ALL THE TlME.
BOTH OF YOU LlTTLE CRAPHEADS
DlD NOT LlSTEN TO A WORD
I SAlD DURlNG THAT
BRlEFlNG, DlD YOU?
OR PEACOCK?
( Winters )
GOD BLESS HlM, NO
ONE TRlES HARDER,
BUT HE'S NOT CUT OUT
TO TAKE MEN lNTO COMBAT.
I'M SURE AS HELL NOT GONNA
MAKE HlM COMPANY C.O.
WHEN I DON'T EVEN WANT HlM
AS A PLATOON LEADER.
WHAT ABOUT COMPTON?
HE'S THE ONLY
REAL CHOlCE.
BUCK'S A REAL COMBAT
LEADER, BUT, YOU KNOW...
I WANT "EASY COMPANY"
TO HAVE AT LEAST
ONE EOPERlENCED
PLATOON LEADER.
NOT THAT lT MATTERS
ANYWAY 'CAUSE I CAN'T
GET RlD OF DlKE.
WELL, WE ALL KNOW
WHO YOU'D LlKE TO
HAVE RUNNlNG "EASY".
TROUBLE lS lT'S NOT
YOUR JOB ANY MORE, DlCK.
WE'VE GOTTA
FlND SOMEBODY.
( Lipton )
WE ALL AGREED
BUCK COMPTON
WOULD'VE BEEN THE BEST
CHOlCE TO RUN "EASY",
IF WlNTERS HAD BEEN ABLE
TO GET RlD OF DlKE.
BUT, TO BE HONEST,
BUCK WASN'T THE SAME
SOLDlER HE'D BEEN
BEFORE HE GOT
SHOT lN HOLLAND.
HE WAS MORE
SERlOUS SOMEHOW.
( Buck )
HE HAD A GODDAMN
LUGER lN HlS PANTS.
JESUS.
DEAR GOD.
AND DON'T YOU TWO DO
SOMETHlNG STUPlD LlKE
THAT, ALRlGHT?
TRY NOT
TO, BUCK.
I MEAN lT.
AND YOU,
WlLD BlLL,
I'VE lNVESTED TOO
MUCH GODDAMN TlME
SHAPlNG YOU lNTO
SOMETHlNG USEFUL.
YOU DO
SOMETHlNG CRAZY,
GET YOURSELF KNOCKED
OUT OF THlS THlNG...
I KNOW, I KNOW,
YOU'LL KlLL ME.
EVEN lF YOU'RE DEAD,
l'LL STlLL KlLL YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU GUYS
LATER, ALRlGHT,
I'M GONNA CHECK ON
THE OTHER GUYS.
CRAZY JOE McCLOSKEY.
WHAT?
THlS GUY USED TO HANG OUT
THE FRONT OF DELANCEY'S
AND JUST, YOU KNOW,
JUST STARE AT PEOPLE.
YEAH, I KNOW WHO
CRAZY JOE McCLOSKEY lS.
WHAT THE HELL'S THAT GOT
TO DO WlTH ANYTHlNG, BABE?
HMM, BUCK KlND OF
REMlNDS ME OF HlM NOW.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, EVER SlNCE HE
GOT SHOT lN HOLLAND...
WAlT, WAlT, WAlT.
WHAT, ARE YOU SAYlNG,
HE'S NUTS?
'CAUSE CRAZY JOE McCLOSKEY
WAS FUCKlNG NUTS, BABE.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALLED
HlM CRAZY JOE.
NO, l'M NOT
SAYlNG HE'S NUTS.
I'M JUST SAYlNG...
WHAT, WHAT ARE
YOU SAYlNG?
OH, FORGET lT.
WHAT?
FORGET lT.
OH, COME ON,
YOU'VE SEEN HlM, BlLL.
HE'S ALL WOUND UP
LlKE A SPRlNG.
HEY, HEY, HEY,
HE'S FlNE.
IT WASN'T GETTlNG
SHOT THAT GOT HlM,
IT WAS BElNG
lN THAT HOSPlTAL.
I'VE BEEN
THERE, OKAY?
IT AlN'T PRETTY.
YEAH, MMM.
BESlDES, YOU SAW,
ONCE HE WAS UP
AND MOVlNG AROUND,
HE WAS HlS OLD
SELF AGAlN.
I'M TELLlNG YOU,
BUCK COMPTON'S FlNE.
I'M SERlOUS.
SURE THlNG, BUCK,
NOTHlNG STUPlD.
WE GOT lT, RlGHT?
WE GOT lT.
ALRlGHT.
GEORGE?
YEAH.
NOTHlNG STUPlD, BUCK.
DON'T DO ANYTHlNG
STUPlD?
WHO THE HELL'S
HE TALKlNG TO?
BUNCH OF MORONS
WHO VOLUNTEERED
TO JUMP
OUT OF A PERFECTLY
GOOD AlRPLANE.
CAN YOU GET ANY MORE
STUPlD THAN THAT?
PROBABLY NOT.
RlGHT.
I SWUM ACROSS
THE NlAGARA ONCE.
YEAH.
I SWEAR.
ON A BET.
WHAT, lN A BARREL?
NO.
I DlDN'T GO OVER
THE FALLS, GEORGE.
I SWAM ACROSS
THE RlVER.
1 0 MlLES UP
FROM THE FALLS.
I TELL YOU, THAT CURRENT
lS DAMN STRONG.
OH, YEAH.
MUST HAVE CARRlED
ME AT LEAST TWO
MlLES DOWNSTREAM,
BEFORE I GOT ACROSS.
BUT, I GOT ACROSS.
NOW, PERSONALLY, l
DlDN'T THlNK lT WAS
ALL THAT STUPlD,
BUT, MY MOM,
MY SlSTER, RUTH,
THEY GAVE ME
ALL KlNDS OF HELL.
YEAH, I BET, MUCK.
SO DlD FAYE.
AH, SWEET FAYE TANNER.
SHUT lT, GEORGE.
WELL, THEY
HAD A POlNT.
YOU'RE AN lDlOT.
( Dike )
I HEARD ABOUT
HOOBLER.
SHAME.
YES, SlR.
IT lS.
THAT THE LUGER?
YES, lT lS.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO WlTH lT?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
WHERE YOU FROM,
LlPTON?
WHERE'D YOU
GROW UP?
HUNTlNGTON,
WEST VlRGlNlA.
HUNTlNGTON?
YES, SlR.
I DON'T KNOW lT.
WHAT KlND OF WORK
DlD YOU DO THERE?
MY BROTHER AND I HELPED
MY MOM RUN A BOARDlNG HOUSE.
AND YOUR FATHER?
HE WAS...
HE WAS KlLLED
WHEN I WAS 1 0, SlR.
AUTOMOBlLE ACClDENT.
THAT'S SAD.
SO, WHAT MADE YOU DEClDE
TO JOlN THE PARATROOPERS?
I READ AN ARTlCLE
ABOUT PARATROOPERS
lN "LlFE MAGAZlNE".
TALKED ABOUT THE TRAlNlNG,
HOW HARD lT WAS.
SAlD lF YOU WANT TO
MAKE lT AS A PARATROOPER
YOU HAD TO BE
THE BEST.
AND I WANTED TO FlGHT
WlTH THE BEST, SlR.
YOU MlSS lT?
MlSS WHAT?
HUNTlNGTON.
HONESTLY, SlR...
I TRY NOT TO THlNK
ABOUT lT THAT MUCH.
WHERE ARE YOU
FROM, S--?
CAP'N NlOON, SlR.
WHAT?
GOOD MORNlNG, SlR,
SORRY TO DlSTURB YOU.
THlS CAME
FROM DlVlSlON.
ALRlGHT.
MORNlNG.
LEW, EVlCTlON NOTlCE?
NOT QUlTE.
BUT I THlNK I GOT
SOMETHlNG THAT
WlLL HELP YOU
WlTH YOUR
LEADERSHlP PROBLEM.
OH, DlKE'S BElNG
TRANSFERRED?
NO, I CAN'T
HELP YOU WlTH THAT,
BUT DlVlSlON HAS DEClDED
TO PLUCK ONE OFFlCER
FROM EACH REGlMENT
THAT SERVED lN
THE HEROlC
DEFENSE OF BASTOGNE,
SEND HlM BACK TO THE STATES
ON A 30-DAY FURLOUGH.
GET HlM OUT BANGlNG THE DRUM
FOR THE WAR BOND DRlVE,
THAT KlND
OF THlNG.
IT TURNS OUT
l'VE BEEN PLUCKED.
HEY, THAT'S FANTASTlC,
LEW, GOOD FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
HOW lN THE WORLD DOES
YOUR LEAVlNG HELP ME?
IT DOESN'T,
l'M NOT GOlNG.
I'VE ALREADY SEEN THE
STATES, I GREW UP THERE.
THAT'S WHY l
CAME TO EUROPE.
I JUST WlSH THEY'D TOLD
ME THERE WAS A WAR ON
ANYWAY, THE POlNT lS,
THlS THlNG'S WASTED ON ME.
BUT l'M SURE
WE CAN FlND AN
OFFlCER SOMEWHERE
IN THlS BATTALlON WHO COULD
USE A LONG TRlP HOME.
( Bull )
CONGRATULATlONS,
LlEUTENANT PEACOCK.
I CAN'T THlNK OF ANYBODY
WHO DESERVES THlS MORE.
THANKS.
I'M REALLY GLAD
THAT YOU'RE GOlNG HOME.
OKAY.
BEST NEWS l'VE
HEARD lN WEEKS.
HELL OF A GUY,
HELL OF A GUY.
THANKS, GUYS, I MEAN.
IT REALLY MEANS
A LOT, YOU KNOW?
OH, GET OUT OF HERE.
THREE CHEERS FOR
LlEUTENANT PEACOCK, GROUP.
( all )
HlP HlP HOORAY,
HlP HlP
HOORAY,
HlP HlP HOORAY!
( Sink )
lF THEY COME BY HERE,
Y'ALL REMEMBER TO
SMlLE FOR THE CAMERA.
GOT TO KEEP THE MORALE UP
FOR THEM FOLKS BACK HOME.
WHY?
DAMNED lF I KNOW.
ALRlGHT, NlO, WHAT
HAVE THEY GOT WAlTlNG
FOR US lN FOY?
AT LEAST ONE COMPANY FROM
THE 1 0th PANZERGRENADlERS
DUG lN ALONG HERE.
THEY'VE ALSO GOT
AT LEAST ONE 88
ALTHOUGH WE HAVEN'T BEEN
ABLE TO SPOT lT YET.
HOW ABOUT ARMOR?
AS OF LAST NlGHT,
THREE TlGERS.
WOULD YOU EOCUSE ME
FOR A MOMENT, SlR?
YEAH.
HOW DO I FEEL ABOUT BElNG
RESCUED BY PATTON?
WELL, l'D FEEL
PRETTY PEACHY ABOUT lT,
IF lT WASN'T
FOR ONE THlNG,
WE DlDN'T NEED TO BE
FUCKlNG RESCUED BY PATTON.
YOU GOT THAT?
JOE.
EOCUSE US
FOR A MOMENT.
SORRY, SlR.
SORRY ABOUT WHAT?
PATTON?
I COULDN'T
AGREE MORE.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOlNG HERE?
I WANNA HEAD BACK
TO THE LlNE, SlR.
JOE, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO DO THAT.
GET YOURSELF BACK
TO THE AlD STATlON.
HEAL UP.
I'D REALLY LlKE
TO HEAD BACK WlTH
THE FELLAS, SlR.
ALRlGHT, THEN GO.
THANK YOU, SlR.
( Lipton )
JOE TOYE HAD BEEN AT THE
AlD STATlON FOR THREE DAYS,
AND EVERYBODY WAS GLAD
TO HAVE HlM BACK.
ESPEClALLY
BlLL GUARNERE.
HEY, JOE.
HEY, BlLL.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, PAL.
YOU, TOO.
WHAT THE HELL
YOU DOlNG BACK HERE?
I HAD TO MAKE SURE
YOU WERE ON TOP OF THlNGS.
I'M ON TOP
OF THlNGS.
TlED ME OWN BOOTS
ONCE LAST WEEK.
ALL BY MYSELF.
HEY, FELLAS,
LOOK WHO I FOUND.
HEY, JOE TOYE,
BACK FOR MORE.
HOW ARE YOU, JOE?
YEAH, DOlNG
PRETTY GOOD.
ESCAPED FROM
THE AlD STATlON.
WHERE'D YOU GET HlT?
WHAT'S THAT?
AH, lT'S WEBB.
REPLACEMENT.
REALLY,
THOUGHT lT WAS SOME GUY
l'VE KNOWN FOR TWO YEARS
AND I FORGOT HlS FACE.
JOE GOT HlT
lN THE ARM.
NEW YEAR'S EVE GlFT
FROM A LUFTWAFFE.
A LOT OF YOU GUYS
BEEN lNJURED?
IT'S CALLED
WOUNDED, PEANUT.
INJURED'S WHEN
YOU FALL OUT OF A
TREE OR SOMETHlNG.
DON'T WORRY, THERE'S
ENOUGH CRAP FLYlNG
AROUND HERE,
YOU'RE BOUND TO
GET DlNGED SOMETlME.
ALMOST EVERY SlNGLE
ONE OF THESE GUYS
HAS BEEN HlT
AT LEAST ONCE.
EOCEPT FOR ALLEY,
HE'S A TWO-TlMER.
HE LANDED ON BROKEN
GLASS lN NORMANDY,
AND GOT PEPPERED BY
A POTATO MASHER lN HOLLAND.
NOW, BULL, HE GOT A PlECE
OF EOPLODlNG TANK lN HOLLAND.
AND GEORGE LUZ HERE...
HAS NEVER BEEN HlT.
YOU'RE ONE
LUCKY BASTARD.
TAKES ONE TO
KNOW ONE, SKlP.
AH, CONSlDER US
BLESSED.
NOW, LlEBGOTT,
THE SKlNNY LlTTLE GUY,
HE GOT PlNKED lN
THE NECK lN HOLLAND.
AND RlGHT NEOT TO HlM, THAT
OTHER SKlNNY LlTTLE GUY,
THAT'S POPEYE.
HE GOT SHOT lN HlS SCRAWNY
LlTTLE BUTT lN NORMANDY.
AND BUCK GOT SHOT lN HlS
RATHER LARGE BUTT lN HOLLAND.
YEAH, KlND OF AN "EASY
COMPANY" TRADlTlON,
GETTlNG SHOT
lN THE ASS.
HEY, EVEN 1 st
SERGEANT LlPTON
OVER THERE,
HE GOT A COUPLE OF
PlECES OF A TANK SHELL
BURST AT CARENTAN.
ONE CHUNK
lN THE FACE.
ANOTHER CHUNK ALMOST
TOOK OUT HlS NUTS.
HOW ARE THOSE
NUTS, SARGE?
DOlNG FlNE, BlLL.
NlCE OF YOU
TO ASK.
( Lipton )
ON THE AFTERNOON
OF JANUARY 3rd,
MOST OF "E COMPANY" HEADED
BACK TO OUR OLD POSlTlON
IN THE WOODS
OVERLOOKlNG FOY.
A FEW MEN REMAlNED
lN THE BOlS JACQUES
ATTACHED TO "D COMPANY"
TO HOLD THE MAlN LlNE
OF RESlSTANCE.
GOOD LUCK, LADlES.
BEEN NlCE
KNOWlNG YOU.
WOULDN'T DRlNK TOO MUCH
lF I WERE YOU.
HEY, BE CAREFUL lF
HE OFFERS YOU A ClGARETTE.
WHAT ARE THEY
TALKlNG ABOUT?
IF WHO OFFERS US
A ClGARETTE?
SPElRS.
WHO?
LlEUTENANT SPElRS.
( Lipton )
LlEUTENANT RONALD SPElRS WAS
ONE OF THE PLATOON LEADERS
IN "D COMPANY".
HE WAS ALREADY
A LEGEND.
THE STORlES ABOUT SPElRS ARE
PROBABLY ALL BULLSHlT ANYWAY.
WHAT STORlES?
WELL, SUPPOSEDLY SPElRS
SHOT ONE OF HlS OWN MEN
FOR BElNG DRUNK.
YOU'RE KlDDlNG.
THAT'S UNBELlEVABLE.
YEAH, AND THERE'S
ANOTHER ONE ABOUT
HlM GlVlNG ClGARETTES
TO 20 GERMAN P.O.W.s
BEFORE KlLLlNG 'EM.
HE SHOT 20 P.O.W.s?
WELL, ACTUALLY, I HEARD
lT WAS MORE LlKE 30.
CHRlSTENSON.
LlEUTENANT SPElRS.
I GOT THE NAME RlGHT,
DlDN'T l, CHRlSTENSON?
YES, SlR.
WHAT ARE YOU MEN
DOlNG OUT HERE?
WE'RE WATCHlNG
THE LlNE, SlR.
WELL, KEEP UP
THE GOOD WORK.
WHlLE YOU'RE AT lT,
YOU MlGHT WANNA
RElNFORCE YOUR COVER.
OH, WELL,
ACTUALLY, SlR,
LlEUTENANT DlKE SAlD
NOT EVEN TO BOTHER.
THAT WE'RE ONLY
GONNA BE HERE ONE DAY.
LlEUTENANT DlKE
SAlD THAT, HUH?
THEN FORGET
WHAT I SAlD.
CARRY ON.
OH, ANYONE
CARE FOR A SMOKE?
YOU?
( Lipton )
LATE lN THE AFTERNOON
ON JANUARY 3rd,
WE RETURNED TO OUR
OLD POSlTlON lN THE
WOODS OVERLOOKlNG FOY.
OH, YOU GOTTA BE
FUCKlNG KlDDlN' ME.
SOMEONE'S GONNA DlE.
SOMEONE'S GONNA
FUCKlNG DlE.
GUARNERE, LOOK
AT THlS SHlT!
ONE OF THOSE 1 st
BATTALlON FUCKERS
TOOK A DUMP
lN MY FOOHOLE.
I THlNK THEY SHlT lN
EVERYONE'S FOOHOLE, JOE.
I DON'T THlNK THEY WANTED
TO SPEND MUCH TlME
ABOVE GROUND.
( Lipton )
WHlLE WE WERE lN
THE BOlS JACQUES,
THE GERMANS HAD BEEN
SHELLlNG OUR OLD POSlTlON.
THERE WERE SlGNS OF
TREE BURSTS EVERYWHERE.
THAT GOT
OUR ATTENTlON.
( male )
LlGHTEN NOlSE,
DlSClPLlNE.
WE'RE GETTlNG CLOSE.
( Lipton )
LOOKlNG ACROSS
THE FlELD AT FOY,
I COULD SEE
ENEMY TROOPS.
I STlLL COULDN'T
SEE THElR ARTlLLERY,
BUT I KNEW lT
WAS DOWN THERE.
OH, LOOKS LlKE THE KRAUTS
HAVE BEEN POUNDlNG THlS AREA
WlTH PRETTY
BlG STUFF, 88s.
I'D SAY THEY GOT
THlS WHOLE STRETCH
OF THE LlNE TARGETED.
WELL, THEY'RE
NOT SHELLlNG NOW.
MAYBE THEY'VE GOT
A NEW TARGET--
NO, THEY'RE
JUST WAlTlNG.
FOR WHAT?
FOR US TO RE-OCCUPY
THE POSlTlON.
MAYBE WE SHOULD FALL
BACK TO A DlFFERENT
LOCATlON, DlG lN.
NO, lT'S OUR JOB TO
HOLD THE LlNE HERE.
WE'VE GOT PRETTY
GOOD FOOHOLES.
WE JUST NEED TO
FORTlFY THE COVERS.
IF THEY'VE GOT US
TARGETED, MAYBE--
WE HOLD THE
LlNE HERE.
SERGEANT
LlPTON'S RlGHT.
WE'RE GONNA STRENGTHEN
OUR COVERS AND WE'RE
GONNA HANG lN.
WE'RE NOT GONNA
FALL BACK.
RlGHT, LlEUTENANT?
MMM?
FlNE.
YOU ALL TAKE
CARE OF lT.
I GOTTA GO TALK
TO REGlMENT.
WE'D BETTER
GET MOVlNG.
YEAH.
HERE YOU GO, BlLL.
HEY, THANKS, LlP.
YOU GOT lT, l'LL GET
YOU SOME MORE BRANCHES.
I'D APPREClATE THAT.
( explosions )
INCOMlNG!
TAKE COVER!
TAKE COVER, COME ON,
FlND SOME COVER.
THEY GOT US ZEROED!
FlND SOME COVER,
FlND A FOOHOLE!
COME ON,
TAKE COVER!
FlND SOME COVER!
SHlT.
COME ON, FlND SOME COVER,
FlND SOME COVER!
( Lipton )
FOR SOME REASON,
AT THAT MOMENT,
IN THAT HALF-FlNlSHED
FOOHOLE, ALL I COULD
THlNK ABOUT
WAS THE 4th OF JULY
WHEN I WAS A KlD.
I LOVED TO MAKE
MY OWN FlRECRACKERS,
CHERRY BOMBS,
LADY FlNGERS.
I LOVED TO BLOW UP DlRT CLODS
AND POP BOTTLES AND THE LlKE.
LOOKED FORWARD TO
lT ALL YEAR LONG.
WHAT I SAW THAT DAY
WAS THE MOST AWESOME,
AND TERRlFYlNG
DlSPLAY OF FlREPOWER
I'D EVER SEEN
lN MY LlFE.
OF COURSE, I WOULDN'T
HAVE BEEN LAUGHlNG
IF l'D KNOWN WHAT HAPPENED
TO JOE TOYE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD SEE
lF ANYBODY'S HlT.
YEAH, MALARK,
THAT'S WHAT THEY WANT.
THE KRAUTS ARE TRYlNG
TO DRAW US OUT lN THE OPEN.
STAY lN
YOUR FOOHOLES.
STAY lN YOUR
FOOHOLES!
ARE YOU OKAY,
CAN YOU WALK?
COME ON, FlND A
FOOHOLE, COME ON.
I GOTTA GET UP.
I NEED MY HELMET.
( Toye )
I NEED HELP!
YOU HEAR THAT?
IS THAT JOE?
HELP!
YEAH, I THlNK
THAT'S JOE.
STAY.
STAY DOWN!
STAY lN YOUR
FOOHOLES!
STAY lN
YOUR FOOHOLES!
HELP!
HELP, ANYONE THERE?
JESUS.
I GOTTA GET UP.
I GOTTA...
SHlT.
COME ON, JOE,
COME ON, BUDDY.
COME ON,
COME ON, PAL.
YOU SAlD YOU'D GET BACK
TO THE STATES BEFORE ME.
YOU AlN'T GOlNG ANYWHERE,
YOU'RE ALRlGHT.
I GOTTA GET
MY HELMET.
FORGET lT.
I GOTTA GET
MY HELMET.
FORGET lT, JOE.
ANYONE THERE?
HANG ON. HELP!
WHO'S THAT?
IT'S HEFF, BABE.
COME ON, GET ME
OUT OF HERE, LlP.
COME ON.
I GOT YOU.
COME ON, JOE,
COME ON, JOE.
HANG ON.
ARE YOU OKAY?
COME ON, COME ON.
AH, JEEZ, THlNK I OVERDlD lT
ON THE COVER FOR MY FOOHOLE?
INCOMlNG!
TAKE COVER!
COME ON, COME ON!
HURRY UP, GUARNO,
YOU'RE GONNA GET BOMBED!
COME ON, COME ON!
MOVE lT, BlLL!
COME ON, JOE.
HOLD ON, l'LL BE THERE,
l'M GONNA HELP YOU.
NO!
MEDlC!
( Lipton )
DURlNG THE SECOND BARRAGE
I WASN'T LAUGHlNG ANYMORE.
LlP?!
ARE YOU OKAY?!
STAY DOWN!
YOU STAY DOWN!
1 st SERGEANT LlPTON?
YOU GET THlNGS
ORGANlZED HERE.
I'M GONNA GO FOR HELP.
WHAT THE FUCK?
LlP, WHERE THE
FUCK'S HE GOlNG?
I DON'T KNOW,
LlSTEN, GET BATTALlON
ON THE LlNE,
TELL THEM
TO NOTlFY B.A.S.
BATTALlON'S UP, LlP.
MMM...
MEDlC!
STAY READY,
STAY READY.
THOSE STUPlD SONSOFBlTCHES
MlGHT BE TRYlNG TO
COME THROUGH.
YOU OKAY, ONE LUNG?
SERGEANT!
HOW YOU DOlNG,
POPEYE?
1 00 PERCENT READY TO KlLL
GERMANS, LlP.
( groaning )
OKAY, JOE.
DOC, WHAT CAN I DO?
HOLD THlS.
YOU GOT A SMOKE?
JESUS, WHAT'S A GUY GOTTA DO
TO GET KlLLED AROUND HERE?
JOE.
BlLL, YOU'RE
GOlNG FlRST.
WHATEVER YOU SAY, DOC,
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
OVER HERE,
TAKE THlS MAN.
HEY, LlP, THEY GOT
OLD GUARNERE THlS TlME.
WE GOT YOU, SOLDlER.
AAAH!
JUST LlE BACK.
TAKE lT EASY.
HEY, JOE, I TOLD YOU
l'D BEAT YOU BACK
TO THE STATES.
HEY, LlP.
HOW'S BUCK?
LUZ, HOW'S BUCK?
HE'S FlNE.
YOU SURE?
YES, HE'S FlNE.
I THlNK YOU SHOULD
PROBABLY GO TALK
TO HlM NOW, HUH?
ALRlGHT.
( Lipton )
SOME SAY BUCK CHANGED AFTER
HE WAS SHOT lN HOLLAND.
MAYBE...
BUT I KNOW SOMETHlNG
HAPPENED TO HlM,
WHEN HE SAW TOYE AND
GUARNERE ON THE GROUND.
ON THE REPORT lT SAlD COMPTON
WAS BElNG TAKEN OFF THE LlNE,
BECAUSE OF A BAD
CASE OF TRENCHFOOT.
DlDN'T SAY ANYTHlNG ABOUT
HlM LOSlNG HlS FRlENDS.
BUCK WAS A GREAT
COMBAT LEADER.
HE WAS WOUNDED
lN NORMANDY,
AND AGAlN
lN HOLLAND.
HE RECElVED THE SlLVER STAR
FOR HlS PART lN TAKlNG OUT
THOSE GERMAN GUNS
ON "D" DAY.
HE TOOK EVERYTHlNG THE
KRAUTS COULD THROW AT HlM
TlME AND AGAlN.
LlEUTENANT COMPTON?
"UCLA DlD NOT MAKE THE
ROSE BOWL THlS WlNTER,
"PROBABLY BECAUSE
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
"l'M SURE YOU'RE TEACHlNG
ALL OF YOUR YOUNG SOLDlERS
"THE JOY YOU HAVE
OF THE SPORT.
"GOSH, HOW WE ALL KNOW WHAT
AN EOClTlNG YOUNG MAN YOU ARE,
AND HOW YOUR HEART
AND LOVE..."
( Lipton )
I GUESS HE JUST COULDN'T
TAKE SEElNG HlS FRlENDS
TOYE AND GUARNERE
ALL TORN UP LlKE THAT.
NO ONE EVER THOUGHT
ANY LESS OF HlM FOR lT.
HEY, BULL.
( Lipton )
WlTH BUCK
OFF THE LlNE,
THERE WAS NO LONGER ANY
POSSlBLE ALTERNATlVE TO DlKE,
AT LEAST NONE
WE COULD SEE.
THANKS.
HEY, MUCK.
MUCK.
YES, SERGEANT?
I'M LOOKlNG FOR
LlEUTENANT DlKE.
( Lipton )
WE WERE STUCK
WlTH DlKE.
AND HE WAS OFF
TAKlNG A WALK.
SURE THlNG.
LlGHTNlNG SlO KlDNAP.
AH, YES, SlR.
WE'VE CLEARED ALL THE GREEN
AREA BETWEEN, ER...
( Lipton )
WE'D CLEARED THE
WOODS EAST OF FOY.
SO, A FEW DAYS LATER
"E COMPANY" AND THE
REST OF THE 506
CLEARED THE WOODS
WEST OF FOY
SlSTANCE.
YOU FELLAS KNOW
I GOT NO REASON TO
BULLSHlT YOU, RlGHT?
( laughing )
LOOK, l'M NOT GONNA
BULLSHlT YOU.
THlS lS
WHAT I SAW.
IT WAS SO UNBELlEVABLE,
YOU MlGHT NOT BELlEVE ME.
SO, YOU-KNOW-WHO COMES
RUNNlNG UP TO LlPTON.
HE'S GOT NO HELMET,
NO GEAR, NO NOTHlNG.
AH, 1 st SERGEANT LlPTON,
YOU ORGANlZE THlNGS HERE,
AND l'M GONNA
GO FOR HELP.
I NEED TO GO POLlSH
MY OAK LEAF CLUSTERS.
HEY, LUZ.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S OKAY.
UM, FELLAS.
GOODNlGHT,
GOODNlGHT ALL.
YEAH, SEE YOU, LUZ,
SEE YOU, MALARK.
WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU, SARGE?
TWO THlNGS, FlRST,
GREAT lMPRESSlON OF DlKE.
YOU THlNK SO?
I THOUGHT lT
WAS A LlTTLE OFF.
NO, YOU GOT lT
PRETTY GOOD.
SECOND, DON'T
DO lT ANY MORE.
ESPEClALLY THE PART ABOUT
WHAT HE SAlD TO ME.
IT DOESN'T DO
ANYBODY ANY GOOD, OKAY?
YEAH, I GOT YOU.
ALRlGHT.
WlSE ASS.
INCOMlNG!
LUZ!
COME ON!
HURRY!
LUZ!
STAY DOWN!
COME ON!
GET lN HERE!
COME ON, LUZ!
MUCK AND PENKALA!
WHAT?
MUCK AND PENKALA
GOT HlT!
AHH!
MEDlC!
HASHEY.
IT'S MY SHOULDER.
COME ON,
GET UP!
( male )
STAY DOWN 'TlL YOU
GET THE ALL CLEAR.
THOUGHT YOU
DlDN'T SMOKE.
I DON'T.
UH-HUH.
( Lipton )
THE SHELL THAT HlT THE FOOHOLE
LUZ AND I WERE lN WAS A DUD.
THE ONE THAT HlT MUCK AND
PENKALA'S FOOHOLE WASN'T.
THAT'S JUST
THE WAY lT WAS.
MUCK AND PENKALA
WERE GOOD MEN.
THElR DEATH HlT
MALARKEY THE HARDEST.
MALARKEY'S BEST FRlENDS
lN THE COMPANY
HAD BEEN COMPTON,
MUCK, AND PENKALA.
IN LESS THAN A WEEK,
HE'D SEEN TWO OF THEM DlE.
WHAT'S THE WORD?
WELL, THE MEN ON
THE LlNE ARE OKAY.
FOOD HAS JUST
BEEN RE-SUPPLlED.
WE'RE lN GOOD SHAPE.
OKAY, WE'LL JUST
HUNKER DOWN.
WE MlGHT GET
SOME RELlEF SOON.
OKAY?
ALRlGHT.
( Lipton )
LATER THAT DAY WE WERE
BACK lN OUR OLD POSlTlON,
OVERLOOKlNG FOY.
WE WERE ALL WORRlED
ABOUT MALARKEY.
HEY, MALARK.
HEY, ER...
DlDN'T I HEAR YOU
SAY YOU WANTED TO
BRlNG A LUGER HOME
FOR YOUR KlD BROTHER?
YEAH.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU...
WHY DON'T YOU
GlVE HlM THAT?
IT'S HOOB'S, RlGHT?
YEAH.
YEAH, I WAS GONNA
GET RlD OF lT,
BUT, I DON'T KNOW.
LlSTEN, CAP'N WlNTERS
WAS WONDERlNG lF YOU WANTED
TO GO BACK
TO BATTALlON
AND WORK AS HlS RUNNER
FOR A FEW DAYS.
TELL HlM THANKS,
l'M GONNA STAY HERE.
WELL, LOOK,
WHY DON'T YOU
AT LEAST COME BACK
FOR AN HOUR OR SO.
SAY GOODBYE TO BUCK.
I'M SURE lT'LL
MEAN A LOT TO HlM.
ALRlGHT.
YOU BE CAREFUL
WlTH THAT.
YEAH.
( Lipton )
GETTlNG EVEN 50 YARDS
BACK FROM THE LlNE,
JUST FOR AN HOUR OR TWO
COULD MAKE A BlG DlFFERENCE
IN A SOLDlER'S
STATE OF MlND.
THE MORNlNG AFTER THE SHELLlNG
THAT KlLLED MUCK AND PENKALA,
I SAW A SOLDlER TRY TO DlG A
FOOHOLE WlTH HlS BARE HANDS.
PRlVATE.
HE DlDN'T NOTlCE THAT HE'D
TORN OFF ALL HlS FlNGERNAlLS.
PRlVATE, HEY.
( Lipton )
I GOT HlM OUT
OF THERE QUlCKLY.
NOT FOR HlS SAKE,
BUT FOR OURS.
FEAR lS POlSON
lN COMBAT.
IT'S SOMETHlNG WE ALL FELT,
BUT YOU JUST DlDN'T SHOW lT.
YOU CAN'T.
IT'S DESTRUCTlVE
AND lT'S CONTAGlOUS.
TOLD YOU l'D
GET YOU STARTED.
( male )
WE GOT A BLEEDER HERE.
( Lipton )
BUCK WAS NEVER THE SAME
AFTER SEElNG TOYE AND
GUARNERE GET HlT THAT DAY.
I GUESS HE JUST NEEDED
SOME TlME AWAY FROM lT ALL.
THE BARRAGES ON
JANUARY 3rd, AND THE
SHELLlNG ON JANUARY 9th
MARKED THE LOW
POlNT lN THE WAR
FOR MANY OF THE MEN
lN "E COMPANY".
EVEN THEN, VERY
FEW ACTUALLY BROKE.
BUT I KNEW THE TERROR
OF THOSE SHELLlNGS
AND THE UNRELENTlNG
PRESSURE WE'D BEEN UNDER
SlNCE WE GOT TO BASTOGNE COULD
TAKE THElR TOLL lN OTHER WAYS.
I WAS AFRAlD THE MEN
WOULD LOSE FOCUS,
SUFFER A DROP
lN MORALE.
AND THAT WAS DANGEROUS,
ESPEClALLY lN COMBAT.
MORE OF WHlCH LAY
lN STORE FOR US.
PERCONTE.
HEY.
WE'D CLEARED THE WOODS
EAST AND WEST OF FOY.
NOW lT WAS TlME FOR
THE lNEVlTABLE ASSAULT
ON FOY, lTSELF.
FRANKLY, I WAS
DREADlNG lT.
I ALWAYS KNEW
THE "E COMPANY" MEN
WHO TRAlNED AT TOCCOA,
WOULDN'T GET THROUGH
THE WAR UNSCATHED,
BUT NOW I WAS
BEGlNNlNG TO WONDER
IF ANY OF US WERE GONNA
MAKE lT THROUGH AT ALL.
HEY, LlEB.
"E COMPANY" WOULD
LEAD THE ATTACK.
THE PROBLEM WAS, AT
LEAST lN MY ESTlMATlON,
"E COMPANY" STlLL DlD
NOT HAVE A LEADER.
THE NlGHT BEFORE
THE ATTACK I DlD
SOMETHlNG AS 1 st SERGEANT,
I WOULD NEVER HAVE
lMAGlNED MYSELF DOlNG.
LlP...
DlDN'T FlGURE YOU
FOR A SMOKlNG MAN.
NElTHER DlD l.
"D COMPANY",
LlEUTENANT SPElRS,
PATROL ORDER.
SO...?
WE'VE BEEN WATCHlNG
FOY ALL DAY, SlR,
NOT MUCH ACTlVlTY.
WANT A COFFEE?
NO, THANK YOU, SlR.
HOW'S "EASY'S" STATUS?
THE MEN ARE GOOD, SlR,
THEY'RE PREPARED.
I'M GONNA BE LEADlNG
2nd PLATOON, TOMORROW.
THEY'RE PROBABLY THE
WEAKEST AFTER LOSlNG TOYE,
AND GUARNERE, AND
MUCK, AND PENKALA.
BUT ALL lN ALL, I HAVE EVERY
CONFlDENCE lN THE MEN, SlR.
GOOD.
BUT, ON THE OTHER HAND,
I HAVE NO CONFlDENCE
lN OUR C.O., SlR.
LlEUTENANT DlKE lS AN
EMPTY UNlFORM, CAPTAlN.
HE'S JUST...
HE'S NOT THERE, SlR.
WELL, HE'S GONNA
BE THERE TOMORROW.
YES, SlR, I UNDERSTAND HE
WlLL BE THERE PHYSlCALLY.
BUT TOMORROW'S
GONNA BE THE REAL DEAL,
AND HE'S GONNA HAVE
TO LEAD THOSE MEN.
HE'S GONNA HAVE TO MAKE
DEClSlONS, SlR, AND l...
I GOTTA TELL YOU, SlR,
I THlNK HE'S GONNA GET
A LOT OF "EASY
COMPANY" MEN KlLLED.
THANK YOU, SERGEANT,
THAT'LL BE ALL.
YES, SlR.
( Lipton )
I SAlD WHAT
I HAD TO SAY.
THERE WAS NOTHlNG
WlNTERS COULD DO.
HE COULDN'T VERY WELL
REMOVE A COMPANY C.O.,
ESPEClALLY
A WELL-CONNECTED ONE,
BECAUSE OF THE MlSGlVlNGS
OF A COMPANY 1 st SERGEANT.
( Winters )
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT AN ElGHTH OF
A MlLE OF OPEN FlELD TO CROSS
BEFORE WE GET DOWN
HERE lNTO FOY.
THERE'S VERY LlTTLE COVER,
SO YOU'VE GOTTA MOVE QUlCKLY.
I'VE SET UP TWO SECTlONS
OF LlGHT MACHlNE GUNS
AT ElTHER END, HERE.
THEY'LL GlVE YOU
COVERlNG FlRE.
3rd BATTALlON WlLL
COME lN FROM THE EAST,
LED BY "l COMPANY".
THAT SHOULD
CAUSE DlSTRACTlON.
"D COMPANY" WlLL
BE lN RESERVE BUT WE
SHOULDN'T NEED 'EM.
THE POlNT lS,
YOU GOTTA MOVE
lN THERE FAST.
GET lN THERE
BEFORE THEY CAN
BRlNG THElR MORTARS,
AND ARTlLLERY
DOWN ON YOU.
CLEAR?
CLEAR.
I'M RELYlNG ON
YOU, GET lT DONE.
( gunshots )
( paratrooper )
COVERlNG FlRE!
LET'S GO!
KEEP lT MOVlNG!
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE!
KEEP MOVlNG!
MOVE!
( speaking German )
LET'S GO,
LET'S GO!
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE!
FlRE!
KEEP 'EM TlGHT, SHAMES.
KEEP MOVlNG.
COME ON.
( Leibgott )
KRAUTS lN THE OPEN!
KEEP MOVlNG!
THREE lNSlDE!
WAlT A MlNUTE,
WHERE'S FOLEY?
RANDLEMAN!
LlEBGOTT.
WHERE THE HELL
lS 1 st PLATOON?
HOLD UP!
KEEP MOVlNG!
"EASY COMPANY",
HOLD UP!
2nd PLATOON, HOLD UP!
WlLL YOU MOVE!
GET ME FOLEY
ON THE RADlO.
GET OUT OF THERE, MOVE!
SlR, I THlNK WE
SHOULD TAKE COVER.
FlND SOME COVER!
WHAT?
STAY DOWN!
EASY RED,
EASY RED, EASY...
Six, oVer.
SlO, EASY RED,
GO AHEAD.
EASY RED, EASY RED,
STAND BY FOR THE SlO.
Foley, Foley,
you get back...
HERE WHERE I CAN
SEE YOU, GODAMMlT!
1 st PLATOON,
HOLD UP, HOLD UP.
TAKE COVER!
MARTlN.
COME ON, SOLDlER,
WlTH ME.
WlTH YOU, SlR.
FlRE!
FALL BACK!
TAKE COVER!
GODAMMlT.
GO FORWARD!
HERRON, ON ME.
MOVE BACK.
STAY ON MY ASS.
HOLD FAST,
2nd PLATOON.
FOLLOW LlPTON!
TAKE COVER!
WHAT ARE WE DOlNG,
LlEUTENANT?
WHY ARE WE STOPPED?
FALL BACK!
ROGER, KlDNAP.
STANDBY TO SlO,
HERRON...
LlEUTENANT,
WHAT'S THE PLAN?
I DON'T KNOW, I DON'T
KNOW, I DON'T KNOW!
YOU'D BETTER GET DlKE
ON THAT RADlO TO ME NOW.
LlEUTENANT,
WHAT'S THE PLAN?
CAPTAlN WlNTERS, SlR.
OKAY, OKAY, FOLEY.
FOLEY, YOU TAKE
YOUR MEN,
YOU TAKE YOUR MEN ON
A FLANKlNG MlSSlON
AROUND THE VlLLAGE,
AND ATTACK lT
FROM THE REAR.
DlKE, WE CANNOT
STAY HERE!
YOU WANT 1 st PLATOON
TO GO 'ROUND
AND ATTACK THE
VlLLAGE, BY lTSELF?
WE WlLL PROVlDE
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE.
WE'RE GONNA BE KlND OF
ALONE OUT THERE, LlEUTENANT.
WE WlLL PROVlDE
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE!
AHH!
GET GOlNG FORWARD!
YOU NEED TO TALK TO
CAPTAlN WlNTERS, SlR.
SlR, OKAY,
HERE lT lS.
WE GO ON A FLANKlNG
RUN 'ROUND THE
BACK OF THE VlLLAGE,
AND WE ATTACK
FROM THE REAR.
RAMlREZ, TWO GUYS,
TAKE 'EM, GO.
FlND SOME COVER
BEHlND THE STABLE.
GO, GO!
SHlT!
JESUS CHRlST.
WEBB, MOVE UP,
FlND COVER!
SUPPRESSlNG
FlRE, NOW!
PERCONTE!
I GOT YOU.
GlVE ME SOME COVER!
HOW YOU DOlNG,
PERCONTE?
THEY SHOT ME lN
MY ASS, MARTlN.
YOU'RE ALRlGHT,
STAY DOWN, STAY DOWN!
I THlNK WE
LOST FlVE MEN.
CAN YOU LOCATE?
THE BUlLDlNG WlTH
THE CAVED-lN ROOF.
SlR, WE ARE
SlTTlNG DUCKS HERE.
WE HAVE TO
KEEP MOVlNG!
YOU'VE GOT
TO KEEP MOVlNG!
( Sink )
DlCK!
CAPTAlN WlNTERS.
GODAMMlT, YOU DO
NOT GO OUT THERE.
YOU'RE THE BATTALlON
COMMANDER, NOW GET BACK HERE!
NOW DlCK, I UNDERSTAND
YOUR ATTACHMENT TO
"EASY COMPANY"--
SPElRS, GET YOURSELF
OVER HERE!
GET OUT THERE AND
RELlEVE DlKE AND TAKE
THAT ATTACK ON lN.
WEBB, FALL BACK,
YOU'RE TOO EOPOSED.
COME ON, WEBB,
LET'S GO, KlD.
HANG ON, PERCO.
FlRE!
LlEUTENANT, WHAT
ARE WE DOlNG?!
I'M TAKlNG OVER.
1 st SERGEANT LlPTON.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT?
SlR, MOST OF THE COMPANY
lS SPREAD OUT HERE.
1 st PLATOON TRlED
AN END AROUND BUT
THEY'RE STRETCHED OUT,
THEY'RE PlNNED DOWN
BY A SNlPER.
I BELlEVE HE'S lN
THE BUlLDlNG WlTH
THE CAVED-lN ROOF.
ALRlGHT, I WANT MORTARS
AND GRENADE LAUNCHERS
ON THAT BUlLDlNG
'TlLL lT'S GONE.
WHEN lT'S GONE, I WANT
1 st TO GO STRAlGHT lN,
FORGET GOlNG AROUND,
EVERYBODY ELSE, FOLLOW ME.
YES, SlR.
THANK GOD, HUH?
ALRlGHT,
3rd PLATOON MOVE OUT.
3rd PLATOON,
LET'S GO, GO, GO!
ALRlGHT, YOU HEARD THE WORD,
2nd PLATOON, ON THE C.O.!
SERGEANT ALLEY!
GOT lT, SARGE.
OKAY, 1 st PLATOON,
MOVE OUT!
ON YOUR FEET,
2nd PLATOON.
MOVE OUT!
GET ON YOUR
GODDAMN FEET.
COME ON!
COME ON, LUZ,
LET'S GET THE BASTARDS.
FlRE!
COME ON,
MOVE OUT!
FlRE!
TAKE COVER!
GO, GO, GO!
GO ON, COME ON.
TAKE THE CART OUT!
FlRE!
LlPTON.
STREETFlGHT lTEM,
STREETFlGHT lTEM.
EASY SlO, OVER.
WHAT DO YOU SEE,
LlPTON?
ARMOR AND lNFANTRY,
A LOT OF lNFANTRY.
"l COMPANY'S" SUPPOSED TO BE
ON THE OTHER SlDE OF THE TOWN.
D'YOU SEE ANY
SlGN OF THEM?
RADlO, ANYTHlNG?
NO, SlR.
SlR, I THlNK THEY'RE
GONNA PULL BACK.
IF WE DON'T CONNECT WlTH
"l", THEY GONNA SLlP AWAY.
THAT'S RlGHT,
WAlT HERE.
ITEM, lTEM,
EASY SlO.
WHAT THE HELL?
( Lipton )
AT FlRST THE GERMANS
DlDN'T SHOOT AT HlM.
I THlNK THEY
COULDN'T QUlTE BELlEVE
WHAT THEY WERE SEElNG.
BUT THAT WASN'T THE
REALLY ASTOUNDlNG THlNG.
THE ASTOUNDlNG
THlNG WAS
THAT AFTER HE HOOKED
UP WlTH "l COMPANY",
HE CAME BACK.
I'VE BEEN WORKlNG
ON THE RAlLROAD
ALL THE LlVE LONG DAY
I'VE BEEN WORKlNG
ON THE RAlLROAD
( Lipton )
WE TOOK OVER 1 00
GERMAN PRlSONERS.
AFTER THAT lT WAS
MOSTLY CLEAN UP.
LET'S GO,
MOVE lT, MOVE lT!
TAKE 'EM DOWN
TO THE BARN.
RlSE UP EARLY
lN THE MORN
SlT DOWN.
( gunshots )
SNlPER
TAKE COVER,
TAKE COVER!
COME ON, COME ON.
WHERE lS HE?
SHlT, I CAN'T SEE HlM.
SECOND FLOOR,
BUlLDlNG ON THE RlGHT.
DON'T MlSS, SHlFTY.
NOW!
( cheering )
( male )
OVER HERE.
I NEED HELP
( Lipton )
MELLET, HERRON,
SOWOSKO, AND KEN WEBB
WERE KlLLED
BY A SNlPER.
THERE WOULD'VE
BEEN MORE
IF lT HADN'T BEEN
FOR SHlFTY POWERS.
YOU HlT BAD,
PERCONTE?
BEAUTlFUL WOUND, LlP.
THEY SHOT ME
RlGHT THROUGH MY ASS.
YOU HANG TOUGH.
HEY, SARGE.
YEAH?
IS lT TRUE
ABOUT DlKE?
YEAH.
THANK GOD FOR
SMALL MERClES, HUH?
YEAH.
( Lipton )
WE'D BEEN LOOKlNG DOWN
AT THE TOWN OF FOY
FOR THE BETTER
PART OF A MONTH,
KNOWlNG THAT'S WHERE
WE HAD TO GO.
IT WAS A GREAT RELlEF
TO HAVE DONE lT.
I GUESS A LOT OF
THE MEN THOUGHT
ONCE WE'D TAKEN FOY,
THEY'D GET US OFF THE LlNE,
SHlP US BACK TO MOURMELON
FOR A BREATHER.
BUT THAT
WASN'T TO BE.
TWO DAYS LATER,
WE TOOK NOVlLLE,
AND AFTER THAT,
RACHAMPS.
( singing )
WE SPENT OUR NlGHT lN
RACHAMPS lN A CONVENT.
IT WAS THE FlRST TlME
WE'D SPENT A NlGHT lNDOORS
IN A MONTH.
THE SlSTERS THERE BROUGHT lN
THElR CHOlR TO SlNG FOR US.
IT WAS HEAVEN.
THE MOOD OF THE
MEN WAS RELAOED.
WE WERE FlNALLY
BElNG RELlEVED
AND WOULD SOON
BE lN MOURMELON.
OF COURSE, lN THE
MORNlNG WE FOUND OUT
MOURMELON WOULD
HAVE TO WAlT.
HlTLER HAD LAUNCHED
A COUNTER-OFFENSlVE lN ALSACE,
AND WE WERE BOUND
FOR THE TOWN OF HAGENAU
TO HELP
HOLD THE LlNE.
BUT AT LEAST FOR THAT NlGHT
WE DlDN'T KNOW lT YET.
THAT NlGHT
WE WERE OKAY.
I SPENT PART
OF THAT NlGHT
TRYlNG TO COME
UP WlTH A ROSTER
FOR THE COMPANY
TO SEE WHO WE HAD LEFT.
WE'D COME lNTO BELGlUM
WlTH 1 21 MEN AND OFFlCERS,
PLUS 24 REPLACEMENTS.
THAT'S 145 TOTAL.
WE WERE GOlNG
OUT WlTH 63.
GUARNERE WAS BADLY WOUNDED
AND HOOBLER DlED ACClDENTALLY.
JOE TOYE HAD
LOST HlS LEG.
AMONG THE DEAD
WERE HERRON, MELLET,
SOWOSKO, KENNETH
WEBB, HAROLD WEBB,
ALEO PENKALA,
AND SKlP MUCK.
OUR MONTH lN BELGlUM
COST US ONE GOOD OFFlCER,
BUCK COMPTON.
AND ONE BAD ONE,
NORMAN DlKE.
BUT WE GAlNED A GOOD
ONE lN THE END,
SO I GUESS WE
CAME OUT AHEAD.
( clearing throat )
WHAT lS lT?
NOTHlNG.
WELL, l'D BETTER
GET BACK TO BATTALlON
BEFORE THEY DlSAPPEAR.
YOU WANNA ASK
ME, DON'T YOU?
ASK YOU WHAT, SlR?
YOU WANNA KNOW
lF THEY'RE TRUE OR NOT,
THE STORlES ABOUT ME.
DlD YOU EVER NOTlCE
WlTH STORlES LlKE THAT,
EVERYONE SAYS THEY HEARD lT
FROM SOMEONE WHO WAS THERE,
BUT THEN WHEN
YOU ASK THAT PERSON,
THEY SAY THEY HEARD lT
FROM SOMEONE WHO WAS THERE.
IT'S NOTHlNG NEW, REALLY.
I BET lF YOU WENT
BACK 2,000 YEARS,
YOU'D HEAR A COUPLE
OF CENTURlONS
STANDlNG AROUND
AND YAKKlNG ABOUT
HOW TERClUS LOPPED
OFF THE HEADS
OF SOME
CARTHAGlNlAN PRlSONERS.
WELL, MAYBE THEY
KEPT TALKlNG ABOUT lT
BECAUSE THEY NEVER
HEARD TERClUS DENY lT.
WELL, MAYBE THAT'S
BECAUSE TERClUS
KNEW THERE WAS SOME
VALUE TO THE MEN
THlNKlNG HE WAS THE
MEANEST, TOUGHEST
SONOFABlTCH
IN THE WHOLE
ROMAN LEGlON.
SlR?
THESE MEN AREN'T
REALLY CONCERNED
ABOUT THE STORlES.
THEY'RE JUST GLAD TO
HAVE YOU AS OUR C.O.
THEY'RE HAPPY TO HAVE
A GOOD LEADER AGAlN.
WELL, FROM WHAT
l'VE HEARD, THEY'VE
ALWAYS HAD ONE.
I'VE BEEN TOLD THERE'S
ALWAYS BEEN ONE MAN
THEY COULD COUNT ON.
LED 'EM lNTO
THE BOlS JACQUES,
HELD THEM TOGETHER
WHEN THEY HAD THE CRAP
SHELLED OUT OF 'EM
IN THE WOODS.
EVERY DAY HE KEPT
HlS SPlRlTS UP,
KEPT THE MEN FOCUSED,
GAVE 'EM DlRECTlON.
ALL THE THlNGS A GOOD
COMBAT LEADER DOES.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY lDEA WHO
l'M TALKlNG ABOUT, DO YOU?
NO, SlR.
HELL, lT WAS YOU,
1 st SERGEANT.
EVER SlNCE WlNTERS
MADE BATTALlON,
YOU'VE BEEN THE LEADER
OF "EASY COMPANY".
OH...
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE
1 st SERGEANT MUCH LONGER,
1 st SERGEANT.
SlR?
WlNTERS PUT lN FOR A
BATTLEFlELD COMMlSSlON,
AND SlNK APPROVED
ON YOUR BEHALF.
YOU SHOULD GET
THE OFFlClAL NOD
lN A FEW DAYS.
CONGRATULATlONS,
LlEUTENANT.
HEY, LOOK,
lT'S 1 st BATTALlON.
HEY!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YEAH, THANKS FOR CRAPPlNG lN
OUR FOOHOLES, YOU SHlTHEADS.
HEY, lT'S OUR PLEASURE.
ENJOY THE WALK, BOYS.
( male )
THERE THEY GO, "EASY COMPANY"
RlDlNG OUT AGAlN.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNlCATlONS CENTER