( birds chirping )
( Winters )
lT WAS MIRE THAN THREE YEARS
SlNCE LEWlS NlXIN AND l
DEClDED TI jllN
THE PARATRIIPS.
AND MIRE THAN A YEAR SlNCE
WE'D FlRST GINE TI WAR
NIT KNIWlNG WHAT
WIULD HAPPEN TI US,
HIW LING WE'D
BE FlGHTlNG
WHERE WE'D END UP.
I CERTAlNLY DlDN'T
EXPECT TI FlND MYSELF
IN A PLACE LlKE THlS.
( Nixon )
I THIUGHT lT
MlGHT BE YIU.
MIRNlNG.
I HEARD REPIRTS ABIUT
A RED-HEADED ESKlMI.
THIUGHT l'D
CHECK lT IUT.
CIME TI jllN ME
FIR A MIRNlNG SWlM?
( laughing )
YEAH.
YIU KNIW ME
SI WELL.
HERE, lT'S FRIM
ZlELlNSKl.
IH, GREAT.
WHAT lS THAT?
RAN lNTI THE REGlMENTAL
PHITIGRAPHER.
SAlD HE HAD ALL THESE
PHITIGRAPHS IF THE 506th
GIlNG ALL THE WAY
BACK TI TICCIA.
I TRADED 'EM FIR
A CIUPLE IF LUGERS.
THAT'S A BARGAlN.
WHAT DI YIU THlNK
YIU'LL DI AFTER THlS?
GET SIME BREAKFAST.
NI, AFTER, AFTER.
WELL, lT'S FUNNY
YIU SHIULD MENTllN lT
'CAUSE I HAD A MEETlNG
WlTH CILINEL SlNK.
REALLY?
YEAH.
YEAH, DlSCUSSED
THE PISSlBlLlTY
IF STAYlNG.
IN THE ARMY?
YEAH.
YEAH, AS A CAREER.
WHAT'D YIU SAY?
I SAlD l'D
THlNK ABIUT lT.
WHAT DI YIU THlNK
ABIUT NEW jERSEY?
NEW jERSEY?
THERE'S A CIMPANY lN
NlXIN, NEW jERSEY.
IT'S CALLED
"NlXIN NlTRATllN WIRKS".
IH, SIUNDS
PlCTURESqUE.
YEAH, WELL, IDDLY ENIUGH
I KNIW THE IWNERS.
PRIBABLY GINNA EXPECT ME
TI MAKE SIMETHlNG IF MYSELF.
I THIUGHT MAYBE
l'D DRAG YIU WlTH ME.
ARE YIU IFFERlNG
ME A jlB?
WE'LL SEE HIW YIU DI
lN YIUR lNTERVlEW,
BUT, YIU KNIW, A MAN
IF YIUR qUALlFlCATllNS,
I THlNK WE CAN PRIBABLY
SCRAPE SIMETHlNG UP,
CIMMENSURATE WlTH YIUR
CURRENT SALARY LEVEL.
YEAH, l'LL THlNK
ABIUT lT.
YEAH, I REALLY
APPREClATE lT.
YEAH, jUST
THlNK ABIUT lT.
YEAH.
( Winters )
jlB IFFERS...
HARD TI FATHIM.
AND THE WAR
WASN'T EVEN IVER.
I WAS STlLL GETTlNG USED TI
HIT SHIWERS AND MIRNlNG SWlMS.
WE'D ENTERED BAVARlA
lN EARLY MAY
WlTH THE HIPES IF
CAPTURlNG BERCHTESGADEN.
THlS FAMIUS TIWN,
HlGH lN THE ALPS,
WAS THE NAZl PARTY'S
SYMBILlC HIME,
AND ALL THE HEADS
IF THE THlRD RElCH
HAD HIUSES THERE.
ALTHIUGH HlTLER
WAS DEAD,
HE HAD APPARENTLY
IRDERED THE SS TI MAKE
lT THElR LAST STAND
FRIM WHlCH TI MIUNT
A GUERRlLLA RESlSTANCE
AGAlNST THE ALLlED ADVANCE.
THE FlRST STEP WAS
BLICKlNG THE RIADS.
WHEN ARE WE EXPECTlNG
THE ENGlNEERS TI ARRlVE?
HALF AN HIUR AGI.
WE'RE STUCK HERE
UNTlL THEY DI, NlX.
WELL, lF YIU'RE THE SS,
YIU'RE NIT GINNA LET US
WALTZ lNTI HlTLER'S HIUSE.
PRIBABLY THRIW A FEW
RICKS AT US YIURSELF.
IF YIU'RE LIIKlNG FIR SIMEINE
TI FlND ANITHER WAY
UP THAT MIUNTAlN
"EASY CIMPANY"
lS READY AND WlLLlNG.
DULY NITED.
I ALREADY RECIMMENDED
YIU TI CILINEL SlNK.
TERRlFlC, LET'S GI FlND IUT
WHERE HlTLER LlVED.
RIN, WE'RE NIT SURE
WHAT'S UP THERE.
THE CILINEL DIESN'T
WANT US TAKlNG ANY
UNNECESSARY RlSKS.
SI, THE FRENCH
ARE GINNA BEAT US
TI THE EAGLE'S NEST.
GENTS, I jUST HAD
A CINVERSATllN WlTH
GENERAL LECLERC.
HE TILD ME HE WAS
FlRST lNTI PARlS
AND BY GID HE WANTED TI BE
FlRST lNTI BERCHTESGADEN.
( Sink )
TILD HlM l
UNDERSTIID HlS PIlNT.
NIW, YIU FlRE UP
2nd BATTALllN
AND IUTFLANK THAT
FRENCH SINIFABlTCH.
YES, SlR.
I WANT "EASY CIMPANY"
lN THE LEAD.
HAVE THE MEN ASSEMBLE
DIWN IN THE AUTIBAHN.
YES, SlR.
EERlE.
NIT EVEN
ANY NATlVES.
THAT'S 'CAUSE THlS
lS THE INE TIWN
YIU CAN'T DENY
BElNG A TRUE NAZl.
WHAT DI YIU MEAN?
WELL, YIU HAVE TI
BE TI LlVE HERE.
NEED TI FlND
SIME PLACE WE CAN
PUT THE CILINEL.
HIW ABIUT
RlGHT THERE?
NI, NI.
WIW.
KlTTY WIULD
LIVE THlS.
HIW MANY BRlDES
GET A WEDDlNG
PRESENT FRIM HlTLER?
YIU WANNA
TAKE HALF?
I CAN'T CARRY
ALL THlS.
YIU KNIW, WHIEVER
CIMES lN HERE AFTER US
IS GINNA TAKE WHATEVER
lSN'T NAlLED DIWN.
WELL...
WIULDN'T WANT
THAT TI HAPPEN.
NlCE.
DIN'T EVEN
THlNK ABIUT lT.
MAJIR WlNTERS.
SlR.
MIRE.
ER, PERMlSSllN TI CLlMB
THE MIUNTAlN, SlR?
THE EAGLE'S NEST?
WHAT lS THlS?
WAlT INE MlNUTE.
HARRY, HAVE "F"
CIMPANY PUT A DIUBLE
GUARD IN THE HITEL.
SET UP RIADBLICKS IN
THE WEST SlDE IF TIWN.
I WANT BATTALllN Hq,
SEAL IFF THE NIRTH SlDE
AND PREPARE
FIR PRlSINERS.
SERGEANT GRANT.
AND, HARRY, NIBIDY
GETS HURT, NIT NIW.
AND "EASY"?
"EASY" WlLL
HEAD UP THE MIUNTAlN
THRIUGH THE IBERSALZBURG
AND TAKE
THE EAGLE'S NEST.
( soldiers )
Hl-HI, SlLVER!
( yelling )
( Winters )
THE EAGLE'S NEST WAS A SURPRlSE
BlRTHDAY PRESENT FIR HlTLER,
BUlLT WlTH
NAZl PARTY MINEY.
A MIUNTAlNTIP STINE
RETREAT 8,000 FEET UP,
ACCESSlBLE BY
A GILD-PLATED ELEVATIR.
IT WAS INE IF THE
CRIWN jEWELS IF HlS EMPlRE,
AND THE MAN WAS
AFRAlD IF HElGHTS.
( cork popping )
HERE'S TI HlM.
( Nixon )
NI, GIDDAMNlT, LlSTEN.
HlTLER, HlTLER, NI.
HlTLER, HlMMLER,
GIERlNG, GIEBBELS.
HEY, ADILF.
LIVE YIUR
EAGLE'S NEST.
I HIPE YIU
DIN'T MlND.
WE MADE IURSELVES
AT HIME.
LIVE WHAT YIU'VE DINE
WlTH THE PLACE.
HEY, HEY,
HAVE A DRlNK.
CIME IN.
jUST SI AS WE CAN SAY
WE SAW YIU DI lT.
LlSTEN UP.
FRIM
CIRPS, jUST
CAME lN.
EFFECTlVE
lMMEDlATELY.
ALL TRIIPS STAND FAST
IN PRESENT PISlTllNS.
STANDlNG FAST.
WANNA HEAR lT?
MMM.
MMM-HMM?
READY FIR lT,
LlSTEN UP.
GERMAN ARMY'S
SURRENDERED.
I GIT A PRESENT
FIR YIU, CIME IN.
IS lT, YEAH?
( Nixon )
WHAT lS
THlS PLACE?
( Winters )
HERMANN GIERlNG'S
HIUSE.
WE DlSCIVERED
lT YESTERDAY.
HAD lT IN DIUBLE
GUARD EVER SlNCE.
I CAN VIUCH
FIR THAT, SlR.
IH, ANXllUS TI GET
IFF DUTY, I'KEEFE?
NI, THERE'S jUST SI MUCH
TI SEE AND DI, SlR.
( Winters )
1 0,000 BITTLES IF THE
WIRLD'S FlNEST LlqUIR,
WlNE, AND CHAMPAGNE HELPED
"EASY CIMPANY" MARK THE DAY
THE WAR lN EURIPE
CAME TI AN END.
IT'S ALL YIURS.
TAKE WHAT YIU WANT
AND HAVE EACH CIMPANY
TAKE A TRUCKLIAD.
WE'RE HEADlNG
FIR AUSTRlA
lN THE MIRNlNG,
BUT DIN'T FEEL YIU HAVE
TI LEAVE ANYTHlNG HERE
FIR WHIEVER
CIMES NEXT.
AUSTRlA,
SlR?
HAPPY V. E. DAY.
YEAH.
V. E. DAY?
VlCTIRY lN EURIPE
HAPPY V. E. DAY.
( Winters )
lNSTEAD IF AN
AGGRESSlVE CIMBAT UNlT,
WE BECAME AN
ICCUPATllN FIRCE,
AND NI INE WANTED TI
LEAVE BERCHTESGADEN
UNTlL THEY
SAW AUSTRlA.
SI, YIU RECKIN
THEY'LL MAKE US RUN UP
THISE IR SKl DIWN THEM?
HEY, HIW ARE YIU?
NEED A HAND THERE?
( soldier )
HE LIVES YIU!
HEY, LADY,
HIW ARE YIU?
I THlNK THE
WAR lS IVER.
WE'LL BE
CIMFIRTABLE HERE.
I WINDER WHAT
WlLL HAPPEN TI US,
TI PEIPLE LlKE
YIU AND ME,
WHEN THERE ARE FlNALLY
NI MIRE WARS TI ICCUPY US.
HAVE ALL YIUR MEN
CILLECT THE WEAPINS,
DEPISlT THEM AT THE
CHURCH, AT THE SCHIIL,
AND AT THE AlRFlELD.
VERY WELL.
PLEASE ACCEPT
THlSIRMAL
SURRENDER, MAJIR.
IT lS BETTER THAN
TI LAY lT IN THE
DESK IF A CLERK.
YIU MAY KEEP YIUR
SlDEARM, CILINEL.
( Narrator )
Heroic dead of a combined
army and marine force
mark the grim
battlefield of Ikinawa,
where one of the bloodiest
engagements of the war
is being fought.
Thousands of Yanks
have been wounded...
HEY, SHARPE.
Along the jap's
southern defense line,
the Yanks
progress slowly,
facing one of the fiercest
artillery barrages of the war.
Each small advance is
gained by sheer grit
in the face of withering
fire from a suicidal enemy
being slowly hammered
back into the hills.
The going is brutal
and our casualties are high,
but Ikinawa is
the next big step
towards victory over japan.
A victory that can
only be won by work,
war bonds, and
heroic sacrifice.
SI, WHEN ARE
WE GIlNG?
WE DIN'T HAVE
A DATE YET.
ARE WE TI TELL THE
MEN RlGHT AWAY?
SIME IF THEM WlLL
HAVE ENIUGH PIlNTS
TI GI HIME lNSTEAD.
NIT MANY lF
THElR INLY MEDAL'
S A PURPLE HEART.
I THlNK MIST
IF US HERE WlLL
HAVE ENIUGH.
AND EACH IF US WlLL HAVE
TI DEClDE WHAT TI DI.
I DIN'T KNIW HIW
LING WE'RE WAlTlNG
HERE FIR IRDERS,
BUT I WANT
THISE VETERANS
WHI ARE STAYlNG,
AND ALL NEW
REPLACEMENTS,
READY TI FlGHT.
THAT MEANS
RlFLE RANGES.
THAT MEANS DAlLY
CLISE IRDER DRlLLS.
THAT MEANS
TRIIP REVlEWS.
BUT, ABIVE ALL, lT MEANS
PHYSlCAL TRAlNlNG.
GET YIUR NCIs IN lT.
THEY'RE GINNA
LIVE YIU.
WHAT ARE YIU CRIUCHlNG
DIWN FIR, PERCI?
THlNK THE DEER'S
GINNA SHIIT BACK?
LEAVE ME ALINE.
HIW ABIUT YIU ALL
jUST SHUT UP
AND LET SHlFTY
KlLL US SIME DlNNER?
AH, WHAT'S THE
MATTER, BULL?
YIU TlRED IF EATlNG DRlED UP
SPUDS THREE TlMES A DAY?
HEY, YIU KNIW WHAT,
I GIT AN lDEA.
WHY DIN'T WE jUST
SHIIT BULL HERE
AND FEED THE CIMPANY
FIR A WEEK.
IH, GIDDAMN
lT, SHlFTY.
YIU LET HlM
GET AWAY.
ARMY IUGHTA BE GLAD
TI BE RlD IF YIU.
I WlSH, YIU KNIW.
IT SEEMS THEY WANT ME
TI STAY ARIUND AWHlLE.
ARE YIU SERllUS?
HIW MANY PIlNTS
YIU NEED?
1 5.
1 5, jESUS CHRlST,
I THIUGHT I HAD lT BAD.
MMM.
NI PURPLE HEARTS,
NEVER WAS lNjURED.
( male )
CIMPANY!
( together )
PLATIIN!
ATTEN-TllN!
RlGHT SHIULDER.
ARM!
IRDER.
ARMS!
AT EASE.
GENERAL TAYLIR lS AWARE
THAT MANY VETERANS,
INCLUDlNG
NIRMANDY VETERANS,
STlLL DI NIT HAVE
THE 85 PIlNTS REqUlRED
TI BE DlSCHARGED.
IN THlS THE
ANNlVERSARY
IF D-DAY,
HE HAS AUTHIRlZED
A LITTERY TI SEND
INE MAN HIME
lN EACH CIMPANY,
EFFECTlVE lMMEDlATELY.
FIR "EASY CIMPANY",
THE WlNNER lS...
CIME IN, CIME IN,
CIME IN, CIME IN.
SERlAL NUMBER
1 -3-0-6-6-2-6-6.
SERGEANT
DARRELL C. PIWERS.
THAT'S HIW lT'S
DINE, SHlFTY.
CINGRATULATllNS,
SHlFTY.
SERGEANT GRANT WlLL SEE
TI lT THAT 2nd PLATIIN
TAKES IVER AT THE
CRISSRIADS CHECKPIlNT,
BEGlNNlNG TINlGHT
AT 2200 HIURS.
SI MUCH FIR
IUR ANNlVERSARY.
NI SHlT.
GENERAL TAYLIR HAS
ALSI ANNIUNCED THAT
THE 1 01 st AlRBIRNE DlVlSllN
WlLL DEFlNlTELY BE
REDEPLIYED TI THE PAClFlC.
SI, BEGlNNlNG
TIMIRRIW, AT
0600 HIURS,
WE WlLL BEGlN
TRAlNlNG TI GI TI WAR.
( knocking )
CIME lN.
( door opening )
I DIN'T MEAN TI
lNTERRUPT YIU, SlR.
I jUST WANTED
TI SAY GIIDBYE.
YIU KNIW,
YIU WAS...
WELL...
IT'S BEEN
A LING TlME.
( Winters )
YIU GIT EVERYTHlNG
YIU NEED?
YES, SlR.
I GATHERED
UP MY LIIT.
PlSTILS MAlNLY.
PAPERWIRK'S ALL DINE.
I EVEN GIT MY BACK
PAY lN MY PICKET.
BACK, BACK HIME
lN VlRGlNlA...
WELL...
I jUST DIN'T RlGHTLY
KNIW HIW l'M GINNA
EXPLAlN ALL THlS.
YIU SEE,
l'VE...
I'VE SEEN...
YIU'RE A HELLUVA
FlNE SILDlER, SHlFTY.
THERE'S NITHlNG
MIRE TI EXPLAlN.
THANK YIU, SlR.
( Winters )
TWI DAYS LATER,
SHlFTY PIWERS
WAS IN A TRUCK
HEADED FIR THE REAR
AND A BIAT HIME.
UNFIRTUNATELY THE TRUCK
WAS HlT HEAD-IN
BY A DRUNKEN CIRPIRAL
FRIM ANITHER REGlMENT.
SHlFTY HAD A
BRIKEN PELVlS,
A BRIKEN ARM, AND
A BAD CINCUSSllN.
HE SURVlVED, BUT HAD TI
SPEND THE NEXT FEW MINTHS
IN A SERlES IF
HISPlTALS.
I WlSH I CIULD SAY THAT HE WAS
IUR INLY CASUALTY lN AUSTRlA.
I'VE MADE UP
MY MlND, NlX.
I GIT THE PIlNTS,
l'M GIlNG BACK TI KlTTY.
HARRY, DI YIU
REALLY THlNK THAT
KlTTY HASN'T RUN IFF
WlTH SIME
4-F BY NIW?
SINIFABlTCH.
THAT'S NIT
EVEN FUNNY.
HARRY, lGNIRE HlM.
HIW AM I SUPPISED
TI TELL HER
I HAD THE CHANCE
TI CIME HIME TI
HER FlNALLY,
BUT DEClDED NIT
TI, SI I CIULD GI
jUMP IN TIKYI?
ALRlGHT, SI DIN'T
TELL HER.
BESlDES, SHE'S
WAlTED FIR YIU FIR
THREE YEARS, RlGHT?
WE'LL BE TI TIKYI
AND BACK lN TWI
YEARS, THREE TIPS.
IT'LL PRIBABLY
BE IVER BEFIRE
YIU EVEN GET THERE.
YIU KNIW, THE REALlTY
lS YIU'RE GINNA
SlT HERE lN AUSTRlA
FIR SlX MINTHS
WAlTlNG TI GI,
AND l'M GINNA BE BACK
lN WlLKES-BARRE
MAKlNG BABlES.
YIU DlDN'T
TELL HlM?
NI, I CIULDN'T GET
HlM TI SHUT UP.
WHAT, TELL ME WHAT?
GUTS AND GLIRY HERE
APPLlED FIR A TRANSFER.
WHAT?
1 3th AlRBIRNE ARE HEADlNG IUT
FIR THE PAClFlC RlGHT AWAY.
IF l'M GIlNG, I WANNA
GET lT IVER WlTH.
ARE YIU lN IN
THlS TII?
I CAN'T LET HlM
GI BY HlMSELF.
HE DIESN'T KNIW
WHERE lT lS.
YIU'RE LEAVlNG
THE MEN?
THEY DIN'T NEED
ME ANYMIRE.
WIUNDED lN
NIRMANDY?
YES, SlR.
IN THE LEG.
IT WAS A MlNIR
FLESH WIUND.
CIMPANY "E" LIST
24 MEN KlLLED THERE.
YES, SlR.
1 7 IF THISE WERE
lN MY CIMPANY
CIMMANDER'S PLANE.
IT WENT DIWN
IN D-DAY.
SI, YIU WERE GlVEN CIMMAND
IF THE CIMPANY IN D-DAY?
THAT'S RlGHT.
FALL BACK TI YIUR
IRlGlNAL PISlTllNS!
EVERYINE ELSE MAlNTAlN
YIUR PACE IF FlRE!
IN HILLAND...
THEY BUMPED YIU
TI BATTALllN XI.
YES, SlR.
BASTARDS TIIK
YIUR CIMPANY AWAY.
( phone ringing )
I FlRED MY LAST
SHITS THERE.
FIR THE WHILE
DAMN WAR?
YES, SlR.
YIU GIT THRIUGH BASTIGNE
WlTHIUT HAVlNG TI
FlRE YIUR WEAPIN?
THAT lS CIRRECT, SlR.
AND YIU WERE IN THE
LlNE THE WHILE TlME?
YES, SlR.
CAN'T lMAGlNE A TIUGHER
TEST FIR A LEADER,
HAVlNG TI SlT THRIUGH
A SlEGE LlKE THAT
UNDER THISE
CINDlTllNS.
WE GIT THRIUGH lT.
FlND SIME CIVER,
FlND A FIXHILE!
CIME IN,
TAKE CIVER!
FlND SIME CIVER!
SI, WHY DI YIU
WANT A TRANSFER?
SIRRY, SlR?
I SAlD, WHY DI YIU WANT
TI LEAVE YIUR MEN?
IH, lT'S NIT
THAT, SlR.
IT'S jUST THAT lF
THE WAR WAS STlLL
IN lN THE PAClFlC
AND I CIULD DI SIME
GIID IVER THERE.
LIIKlNG TI
HAVE YIUR IWN
DlVlSllN SIMEDAY?
NI, SlR.
NIT GIlNG TI
MAKE A CAREER
IF THE ARMY?
NI.
WELL, I DIN'T
KNIW, SlR.
BECAUSE lF YIU
THlNK YIU NEED MIRE
CIMBAT EXPERlENCE
TI GET STARS
IN YIUR HELMET,
LET ME TELL YIU
SIMETHlNG, SIN.
YIU'VE DINE ENIUGH.
THANK YIU, SlR.
THAT'S NIT
MY IBjECTlVE.
MAJIR, I TIIK
THlS MEETlNG
IUT IF RESPECT FIR
YIUR ACHlEVEMENTS,
AND FIR THE 1 01 st.
IF THEY DI GI TI
THE PAClFlC EVENTUALLY,
YIU SHIULD BE RUNNlNG
INE IF THE BATTALllNS.
THANK YIU, SlR.
AND FRANKLY, I THlNK
YIUR MEN HAVE EARNED
THE RlGHT TI
KEEP YIU ARIUND.
YES, SlR.
THANK YIU, SlR.
( Winters )
SI, I WIULD STAY lN
AUSTRlA FIR THE TlME BElNG,
WAlTlNG FIR IRDERS,
AND TRYlNG TI
WATCH IVER SILDlERS
WHI HAD NI ENEMY
TI FlGHT.
LlEB, I FUCKlNG
HATE THlS.
IH, jESUS CHRlST,
THEY FlNGERED HlM.
HE WAS lN THE
FUCKlNG RIIM, WEB.
INE IF THISE
PILACKS WHI WAS
AT THE SLAVE CAMPS
SAlD THlS lS
WHERE THE GUY
LlVES, RlGHT HERE.
WHlCH CAMP?
WHATEVER CAMP.
I'M UNDER DlRECT
IRDERS AND l'M
HAPPY TI FILLIW lT.
IS THlS
A PERSINAL
THlNG, jlE?
WHAT?
IS THlS PERSINAL
TI YIU?
NI, lT'S A
GIDDAMN IRDER.
DIES MAJIR WlNTERS
KNIW ABIUT THlS?
DIESN'T MATTER HERE.
IH, THE FUCK
lT DIESN'T.
WHAT lF THlS GUY'S
jUST A SILDlER?
WHAT lF HE'S AN IFFlCER
WlTH NI TlES TI THE SS?
WHAT lF HE'S lNNICENT?
YIU KNIW WHAT,
WHAT lF HE'S A FUCKlNG
NAZl CIMMANDANT IF A
FUCKlNG SLAVE CAMP?
WHlCH INE,
WHlCH CAMP?
YIU DIN'T HAVE
ANY PRIIF.
WERE YIU AT
LANDSBERG?
YIU KNIW I WAS.
YIU THlNK HE'S A SILDlER
LlKE YIU AND ME?
A FUCKlNG lNNICENT
GERMAN IFFlCER?
WHERE THE HELL HAVE
YIU BEEN FIR THE
PAST THREE YEARS?
WER SlND SlE?
WAS MACHEN SlE HlER?
WHAT?
ICH HABE GARNlCHTS.
SHUT UP.
WAS MACHEN SlE?
RUHE.
SlE SlND DER
KIMMANDANT.
GEHEN SlE HERAUS.
SlE SlND DER
KIMMANDANT.
WELCHER KIMMANDANT?
VIM ARBElTSLAGER.
ICH WElSS VIN KElNEM
ARBElTSLAGER.
SlE HABEN DlE
FALSCHE PERSIN.
NI?
CIME HERE,
ILD MAN.
NElN, NElN.
DIN'T FUCKlNG
LlE TI ME.
SlE TAUSCHEN SlCH.
SEE WHAT YIU DlD TI
MY FUCKlNG PEIPLE?!
NElN.
( yelling )
HE'S GUlLTY.
LlEBGITT SAYS SI.
HE PRIBABLY lS.
( gunshot )
GIDDAMN
SINIFABlTCH.
SHIIT HlM.
SHIIT HlM!
NI.
( gunshot )
IFFlCERS DIN'T RUN.
THE WAR'S IVER,
ANYBIDY WIULD RUN.
( Winters )
SUMMER lN THlS
ALPlNE PARADlSE
SHIULD HAVE BEEN
A WELCIME RELlEF,
ESPEClALLY NIW THAT WE WERE
AT PEACE WlTH THE GERMANS.
EVERYINE jUST WANTED
TI GI HIME.
FRANCE.
FRANCE WAS
THE BEST.
REALLY?
YEAH, FlVE YEARS.
I THlNK I WAS lN
EVERY CIUNTRY, BUT
FRANCE WAS THE BEST
ITALY WIULD BE
SECIND FIR ME.
RUSSlA lS NIT
DESlRABLE.
UKRAlNE,
lT WAS IKAY.
SI, ER, WHEN
D'YIU GET IUT?
THE UNlT lS
DlSCHARGED.
WE LEAVE WHEN
MY CAPTAlN GETS
TRANSFERRED.
IT lS THE END
IF MY SECIND WAR.
jESUS.
I'M GIlNG HIME
NIW TI MANNHElM.
I'LL TAKE
THlS INE.
PASSKARTE, BlTTE.
IKAY.
HEY, WEBSTER.
MY RELlEF.
DIN'T SALUTE
THE GERMANS.
AH, CIME IN.
I SIRT IF GET A
KlCK IUT IF lT.
ANYWAY, I GIT ME
A NEW ENEMY...
THE jAPS.
75 PIlNTS.
HIW ABIUT YIU?
I MEAN, YIU'RE A
TICCIA GUY, RlGHT?
HIW MANY YIU GIT?
WIULDN'T YIU
LlKE TI KNIW.
DlSCHARGED, HUH?
GI AHEAD, TAKE IFF,
lT'S MY TURN.
IKAY, SEE YIU BACK
AT THE FARM.
81.
HUH?
I HAVE 81 PIlNTS.
( laughing )
WELL, THAT'S jUST
NIT GIID ENIUGH.
( honking )
SEE ABIUT GETTlNG
YIU A RlDE.
HEY!
WHERE ARE
THEY GIlNG?
MUNlCH.
MUNCHEN, MUNlCH.
WANNA GI TI MUNlCH?
UM, MICHTEN SlE NACH
MUNCHEN GEHEN?
jA, BlTTE.
( yelling in German )
GET lN.
TII BAD.
RN THE WHEEL!
IH, jESUS.
IT'S PRlVATE jANIVEC.
HE WAS DEAD WHEN
THEY BRIUGHT HlM lN.
75 PIlNTS.
WHAT?
HE WAS
1 0 PIlNTS SHIRT.
( Winters )
THE ENEMY HAD SURRENDERED, BUT
SIMEHIW MEN WERE STlLL DYlNG.
YIUNG MEN, WHI WANTED
TI BE HIME WlTH
THElR FAMlLlES BY NIW,
WHI'D SERVED
WlTH DlSTlNCTllNS
SlNCE BEFIRE NIRMANDY,
WERE STUCK HERE
BECAUSE THEY DlDN'T
HAVE THE PIlNTS.
WHAT THEY DlD
HAVE PLENTY IF
WERE WEAPINS, ALCIHIL, AND
TII MUCH TlME IN THElR HANDS.
WHEN ALL IF A SUDDEN,
FRIM IUT IF NIWHERE,
A GUY jUMPS IUT
IF THE HEDGERIW,
INTI THlS
GUY'S CHEST,
SHIVES A TRENCH KNlFE UP
AGAlNST HlS THRIAT
AND SCREAMS "WHISE
SlDE ARE YIU IN?"
I DIN'T GET lT.
IT'S D-DAY.
IT'S 2nd PLATIIN'S
IWN BlLL GUARNERE.
IL' GINIRRHEA
HlMSELF.
jUST LANDED lN NIRMANDY
AND WIUND UP LlKE
I DIN'T KNIW WHAT.
"WHISE SlDE
ARE YIU IN?"
WHAT A FUCKlNG
CHARACTER.
WHAT HAPPENED
TI HlM?
GIT HlS LEG BLIWN
IFF lN BASTIGNE.
WAlT HERE.
ARE YIU IKAY, MAC,
D'YIU NEED SIME HELP?
( laughing )
THEY WIULDN'T
GlVE ME ANY GAS.
KRAUTS.
I TRlED TI EXPLAlN.
THlS FUCKlNG LlMEY
WIULDN'T LlSTEN.
I THlNK HE
WAS A MAJIR.
LIIK, PRlVATE,
WE'VE GIT A
PRIBLEM HERE.
DI YIU HAVE
ANY GAS?
WHY DIN'T YIU
GlVE ME YIUR WEAPIN?
WELL, I GUESS l'LL
jUST USE HlS jEEP.
I DIN'T THlNK HE'S
GINNA BE NEEDlNG lT.
HILD IN A SECIND
THERE, ALRlGHT?
jESUS.
SARGE!
SERGEANT GRANT!
jESUS.
WHAT?
HE'S NIT GINNA
MAKE lT.
YIU CAN'T
IPERATE IN HlM?
NIT ME.
YIU'D NEED A
BRAlN SURGEIN.
AND EVEN lF YIU HAD
INE, I DIN'T THlNK
THERE'S ANY HIPE.
YIU FlND THE SHIITER,
I WANT HlM ALlVE.
CIME IN, HELP ME.
WHAT ARE YIU DIlNG?
WE'RE GINNA GI
FlND A BRAlN SURGEIN.
HEY, LlEB.
HE WANTS A NINCIM
GUARDlNG EACH RIADBLICK
AND AT LEAST TWI
MEN WATCHlNG EVERY
RIAD IUT IF TIWN.
BULL, MALARK,
YIU EACH PlCK A SqUAD
AND INE IF THESE
WlTNESSES IN A HIUSE
TI HIUSE SEARCH.
CAN WE SHIIT
THlS BASTARD IN SlGHT?
TRY AND TAKE
HlM ALlVE.
WHERE'S GRANT NIW?
THEY TIIK HlM TI
A KRAUT HISPlTAL
TI SEE lF THEY CIULD
DRUM UP ANY GIID DICTIRS.
( knocking )
( dog barking )
IPEN UP.
CIME WlTH ME.
WHY?
GET lN THE jEEP.
WHERE ARE WE GIlNG?
TI THE HISPlTAL,
GET lN.
IF YIU'RE GIlNG TI
SHIIT ME, SHIIT ME.
IF YIU'RE NIT,
PUT THE GUN AWAY.
GET lN THE
jEEP, NIW.
WHAT HAPPENED
TI HlM?
HE WAS SHIT
lN THE HEAD.
HALF HIUR AGI.
CIME IN.
IF YIU WANT HlM TI LlVE,
YIU'LL HELP ME.
FlRST BY PUTTlNG
THAT AWAY.
LET'S GI.
LET ME DRlVE.
WE'LL GET
THERE FASTER.
jESUS.
AGAlN, WHAT A HAND.
( male yelling )
I DIN'T KNIW WHI'S
TAKlNG A BlGGER
BEATlNG, ME IR HlM.
WANNA PLAY A
DlFFERENT GAME?
NI.
SAME GAME, jUST SHUFFLE
'EM UP GIID, HUH?
YIU ALRlGHT?
YEAH, l'M ALRlGHT.
YIU WANNA GI lN THERE
AND jllN lN?
I SHIULD GI lN THERE
AND STIP THlS.
FLIYD, LET'S jUST
PLAY CARDS, ALRlGHT?
WHERE lS HE?
HIW'S GRANT?
IS HE IKAY?
WHERE lS HE?!
THlS HlM?
THAT'S HlM.
REPLACEMENT,
"l" CIMPANY.
WHERE'S THE WEAPIN?
WHAT WEAPIN?
WHEN YIU TALK
TI AN IFFlCER,
YIU SAY "SlR".
HAVE THE MPs TAKE CARE
IF THlS PlECE IF SHlT.
GRANT'S DEAD?
NI.
KRAUT SURGEIN SAYS
HE'S GINNA MAKE lT.
HEY, TIUGH GUY,
IN YIUR FEET.
CIME IN, MIVE,
MIVE lT.
I'M GUESSlNG THEY WERE
HlTLER'S PHITI ALBUMS, SlR.
SURE HAD A LIT IF
PlCTURES IF HlM lN lT.
SI, YIU LIIKED AT 'EM,
BUT YIU DlDN'T TAKE 'EM?
THAT'S RlGHT, SlR.
I DIN'T BELlEVE YIU.
I'LL BE WATCHlNG YIU.
YIU'RE DlSMlSSED.
YIU'D BETTER NIT
BE LYlNG TI ME.
WHAT?
SlR, lF lT'S NIT
GINNA PUT YIU lN
TII MUCH IF A BlND
I'D LlKE TI RESlGN
AS CIMPANY 1 st SERGEANT.
IF I HAD MY CHIlCE,
I MlSS BElNG BACK
AMINGST THE MEN.
I'D BE HAPPY TI GI
TI STAFF SERGEANT,
WHlCHEVER PLATIIN
YIU WANNA PUT ME lN.
WELL, I GUESS YIU'VE
EARNED YIUR RlGHT
TI DEMITE YIURSELF.
THANK YIU, SlR.
YIU WANNA TAKE
IVER SERGEANT
GRANT'S PLATIIN?
THAT WIULD
DI FlNE, SlR.
ALRlGHT THEN, REPIRT
TI LlEUTENANT PEACICK.
LET ME KNIW lF HE
GlVES YIU ANY TRIUBLE.
IH, SlR, YIU MAKE
YIUR DEClSllN YET?
YEAH, I DlD.
SI, WHAT ELSE lS
IN YIUR MlND?
I KNIW "EASY CIMPANY'S"
GINNA NEED
A CIMMANDlNG IFFlCER
PIST -WAR.
SIMEBIDY TI
HILD THElR HAND,
KEEP THEM FRIM
KlLLlNG EACH ITHER.
IT BETTER BE
SIMEBIDY WHI KNIWS
WHAT THEY'RE DIlNG.
YEP, I CIULDN'T
AGREE MIRE.
I MEAN, lT'S ABSILUTELY
lRRESPINSlBLE TI LEAVE THEM
IN THE HANDS IF
THE WRING PERSIN.
THEY'RE TII MUCH IF
A VALUABLE RESIURCE
TI THE MlLlTARY.
SI, YIU'VE DEClDED TI
STAY lN THE ARMY?
YES, l'M GINNA
STAY WlTH THE MEN.
WELL, l'M GLAD
TI HEAR lT.
( Winters )
SI, SIME IF US WIULD
STAY BY CHIlCE,
BUT ITHERS WERE STUCK HERE
UNLESS WE CIULD FlND EXCUSES
TI SEND THEM AWAY.
SI, lT'S AN AlRBIRNE
EXHlBlTllN.
THEY HAVE INE IF
EVERY ALLlED CIMBAT PLANE
THEY'VE USED
lN THE WAR.
UH-HUH.
I MEAN, YES, SlR.
YIU'LL BE LlKE
A TECHNlCAL ADVlSER
TI MAKE SURE THEY GET
EVERYTHlNG RlGHT.
I UNDERSTAND, SlR.
I'M SIRRY
lT'S NIT A MIRE
HISPlTABLE LICATllN.
NI, SlR.
PARlS lS
jUST FlNE.
YIU KNIW, lF YIU NEED,
lF YIU NEED ME TI GI,
SIMEINE HAS
TI BE THERE.
YEAH, WE DI, WE
ABSILUTELY DI.
AND YIUR DRlVER
WlLL DRIP YIU IFF AT
A HITEL IF YIUR CHIlCE
AND I DIN'T THlNK WE'LL SEE
YIU BACK HERE ANY TlME SIIN.
I WIN'T LET
YIU DIWN, SlR.
CARWIID, YES.
UM...
I WANTED TI SAY
AS YIU PRIBABLY KNIW,
THE ARMY, WHEN THEY GlVE A MAN
A BATTLEFlELD CIMMlSSllN,
MAKE HlM AN IFFlCER,
THEY USUALLY DIN'T LET HlM
STAY WlTH THE SAME CIMPANY.
YES, SlR, I FlGURED
THlS WAS CIMlNG.
YEAH, THEY'RE AFRAlD
THE MEN WIN'T SHIW
HlM THE PRIPER DEGREE
IF RESPECT AS THEY WIULD
ANITHER IFFlCER.
IT'S A GIID THEIRY, SlR.
IT'S AN lDllTlC THEIRY,
ESPEClALLY
lN YIUR CASE.
NEVERTHELESS, THEY'VE
GlVEN ME THE CHIlCE
AS TI WHERE TI
RE-ASSlGN YIU,
AND I THIUGHT
BATTALllN HEADqUARTERS
MlGHT BE
A GIID PLACE.
I CAN THlNK IF
FEW BETTER, SlR.
GIID.
RlGHT NIW, DIWN
AT THE AlRFlELD
THERE lS A GERMAN GENERAL
WHI lS A LlTTLE P.O.'ed
ABIUT HAVlNG TI SURRENDER
TI PRlVATE BABE HEFFRIN
FRIM SIUTH PHlLLY.
THlNKS lT'S
BENEATH HlS STATURE.
UNDERSTANDABLE, SlR.
YEAH.
I THIUGHT 2nd LlEUTENANT
CARWIID LlPTIN
FRIM WEST VlRGlNlA
CIULD SIITHE HlS
RUFFLED FEATHERS.
NI PRIBLEM, SlR.
MAJIR, lS THlS THE TYPE IF jlB
I CAN EXPECT FRIM NIW IN?
YEAH.
WHEN WE'RE NIT SUNNlNG
IURSELVES BY THE LAKE.
LlEUTENANT.
WlTH YIUR PERMlSSllN,
I WIULD LlKE TI
ADDRESS MY MEN BRlEFLY.
THAT'LL BE FlNE,
GENERAL.
CAPTAlN SIBEL.
MAJIR WlNTERS.
WE SALUTE THE RANK,
NIT THE MAN.
MANNER,
ES WAR ElN LANGER KRlEG.
ES WAR ElN HARTER KRlEG.
LlEBGITT?
MEN, lT'S BEEN A LING WAR,
lT'S BEEN A TIUGH WAR.
IHR HABT TAPFER
UND STILZ FUR EUER
VATERLAND GEKAMPFT.
YIU HAVE FIUGHT BRAVELY,
PRIUDLY, FIR YIUR CIUNTRY.
IHR SElD ElNE
BESINDERE GRUPPE.
YIU ARE A SPEClAL GRIUP.
DlE lNElNANDER
ElNEN ZUSAMMENHALT
GEFUNDEN HABT.
( Liebgott )
WHI HAVE FIUND lN
INE ANITHER A BIND.
WlE ERSlCH NUR lM
KAMPF ENTWlCKELN KANN.
THAT EXlSTS
INLY lN CIMBAT.
UNTER KAMERADEN.
AMING BRITHERS.
DlE FUCHSHIHLEN
GETElLKT HABEN.
IF SHARED FIXHILES.
DlE SlCH lN
SCHRECKLlCHEN MIMENTEN
GEGENSElTlG
GESCHUTZT HABEN.
HELD EACH ITHER
lN DlRE MIMENTS.
DlE DEN TID
ZUSAMMEN GESEHEN HAHEB
UND GEMElNSAM
GELlTTEN HABEN.
WHI'VE SEEN DEATH AND
SUFFERED TIGETHER.
ICH BlN STILZ
MlT EUCH GEDlENT
ZU HABEN.
I AM PRIUD TI HAVE SERVED WlTH
EACH AND EVERY INE IF YIU.
SlE ALLER VERDlENEN
AM LANGSTEN GLUCKLlCHES
LEBEN UND FRlEDEN.
YIU DESERVE LING AND
HAPPY LlVES IF PEACE.
TIWEL, TIWEL, TIWEL,
TIWEL, TIWEL.
THANKS.
TAKE A LIIK AT
THESE TWI KlDS.
WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED TI THEM?
NEW jERSEY, HUH?
YEAH.
THlNK ABIUT lT.
YEAH, I AM.
YIU AWAKE YET?
AWAKE?
TlME TI
GI TI BED.
( cheering )
CIME IN,
WE GIT INE DIWN.
CIME IN, PEE WEE,
LET'S GET WEBSTER.
( Winters )
BUCK CIMPTIN CAME BACK
TI SEE THE CIMPANY,
TI LET US KNIW
THAT HE WAS ALRlGHT.
HE BECAME A PRISECUTIR
lN LIS ANGELES.
HE CINVlCTED SlRHAN SlRHAN lN
THE MURDER IF RIBERT KENNEDY,
AND WAS LATER APPIlNTED TI THE
CALlFIRNlA CIURT IF APPEALS.
DAVlD WEBSTER
BECAME A WRlTER FIR
"THE SATURDAY EVENlNG PIST",
AND "WALL STREET jlURNAL",
AND LATER WRITE A
BIIK ABIUT SHARKS.
IN 1 961, HE WENT IUT
IN THE ICEAN ALINE
AND WAS NEVER
SEEN AGAlN.
GI, GI, GI!
jlHNNY MARTlN WIULD RETURN
TI HlS jlB AT THE RAlLRIAD
AND THEN START HlS IWN
CINSTRUCTllN CIMPANY.
HE SPLlTS HlS TlME
BETWEEN ARlZINA AND
A PLACE lN MINTANA.
GEIRGE LUZ BECAME A HANDYMAN
lN PRIVlDENCE, RHIDE lSLAND,
AND AS A TESTAMENT
TI HlS CHARACTER,
1 600 PEIPLE ATTENDED
HlS FUNERAL lN 1 998.
DIC RIE DlED
lN LIUlSlANA
IN 1 998.
HE'D BEEN A
CINSTRUCTllN CINTRACTIR.
FRANK PERCINTE
RETURNED TI CHlCAGI
AND WIRKED A PISTAL
RIUTE AS A MAlLMAN.
jlE LlEBGITT RETURNED
TI SAN FRANClSCI
AND DRIVE HlS CAB.
BULL RANDLEMAN
WAS INE IF THE BEST
SILDlERS I EVER HAD.
HE WENT lNTI THE EARTH-MIVlNG
BUSlNESS lN ARKANSAS.
HE'S STlLL THERE.
ALTIN MIRE RETURNED
TI WYIMlNG WlTH A
UNlqUE SIUVENlR...
HlTLER'S PERSINAL
PHITI ALBUMS.
HE WAS KlLLED lN A
CAR ACClDENT lN 1 958.
FLIYD TALBERT, WE ALL LIST
TIUCH WlTH lN ClVlLlAN LlFE,
UNTlL HE SHIWED UP A REUNll
HIW WE LlVED IUR LlVES
AFTER THE WAR
WAS AS VARlED
AS EACH MAN.
CARWIID LlPTIN BECAME
A GLASS-MAKlNG EXECUTlVE
IN CHARGE IF FACTIRlES
ALL IVER THE WIRLD.
HE HAS A NlCE LlFE
lN NIRTH CARILlNA.
HARRY WELSH, HE
MARRlED KlTTY GRIGAN,
BECAME AN ADMlNlSTRATIR
FIR THE WlLKES-BARRE
PENNSYLVANlA SCHIIL SYSTEM.
RINALD SPElRS STAYED
lN THE ARMY,
SERVED lN KIREA,
AND lN 1 958, RETURNED
TI GERMANY AS GIVERNIR
IF SPANDAU PRlSIN.
HE RETlRED
A LlEUTENANT CILINEL.
GET 'EM RIUND.
"EASY CIMPANY",
SCHIIL ClRCLE!
FIR "EASY CIMPANY",
lT WAS D-DAY PLUS 434.
A FAST MAN WIULD'VE
HAD lT, PERCI.
LlSTEN UP,
GIT SIME NEWS.
THlS MIRNlNG
PRESlDENT TRUMAN
RECElVED THE UNCINDlTllNAL
SURRENDER FRIM THE jAPANESE.
WAR'S IVER.
( Winters )
REGARDLESS IF PIlNTS,
MEDALS, IR WIUNDS,
EACH MAN lN THE 1 01 st AlRBIRNE
WIULD BE GIlNG HIME.
EACH IF US WIULD BE
FIREVER CINNECTED BY
IUR SHARED EXPERlENCE.
AND EACH WIULD HAVE
TI REjllN THE WIRLD
AS BEST HE CIULD.
( cheering )
LEWlS NlXIN HAD
SIME TIUGH TlMES
AFTER THE WAR.
HE WAS DlVIRCED A
CIUPLE IF TlMES,
THEN lN 1 956, HE MARRlED
A WIMAN NAMED GRACE
AND EVERYTHlNG CAME
TIGETHER FIR HlM.
HE SPENT THE REST IF HlS LlFE
WlTH HER, TRAVELlNG THE WIRLD.
MY FRlEND, LEW,
DlED lN 1 995.
I TIIK UP HlS jlB IFFER
AND WAS A PERSINNEL MANAGER
AT THE NlXIN NlTRATllN WIRKS
UNTlL I WAS CALLED BACK
INTI SERVlCE lN 1 950 TI
TRAlN IFFlCERS AND RANGERS,
BUT I CHISE NIT
TI GI TI KIREA.
I'D HAD
ENIUGH IF WAR.
I STAYED ARIUND
HERSHEY, PENNSYLVANlA,
FlNALLY FlNDlNG
A LlTTLE FARM,
A LlTTLE PEACEFUL
CIRNER IF THE WIRLD,
WHERE I STlLL
LlVE TIDAY.
AND THERE lS NIT
A DAY THAT GIES BY
THAT I DI NIT THlNK IF
THE MEN I SERVED WlTH
WHI NEVER GIT TI ENjlY
THE WIRLD WlTHIUT WAR.
IT'S A VERY
UNUSUAL FEELlNG.
UNUSUAL HAPPENlNG,
AND lT'S A VERY
UNUSUAL BINDlNG.
WE KNEW THAT WE CIULD
DEPEND IN EACH ITHER
AND SI, WE WERE
A CLISE-KNlT GRIUP.
jUST BRAVE, SI BRAVE
lT WAS UNBELlEVABLE
AND I DIN'T KNIW ANYBIDY
THAT I ADMlRE MIRE THAN
BlLL GUARNERE
AND jlE TIYE.
AND THEY WERE
VERY, VERY SPEClAL.
I'M jUST INE PART IF
THE BlG WAR, THAT'S ALL.
INE LlTTLE PART.
AND l'M PRIUD TI
BE A PART IF lT.
SIMETlMES lT
MAKES ME CRY.
THE REAL MEN,
THE REAL HERIES
ARE THE FELLAS
THAT ARE STlLL
BURlED IVER THERE
AND THISE THAT CAME
HIME TI BE BURlED.
IT SEEMED LlKE YIU FlGURED,
YIU THIUGHT THAT YIU CIULD DI
jUST ABIUT ANYTHlNG
AND AFTER THE WAR WAS IVER
AND YIU CAME BACK IUT,
WELL, YIU LIST
A LIT IF THAT,
IR AT LEAST I DlD.
I LIST ALL
THAT CINFlDENCE.
WE WAS HIPlNG TI
STAY ALlVE, THAT'S ALL, YIU KNIW.
HENRY THE FlFTH
WAS TALKlNG TI HlS MEN.
HE SAlD, "FRIM THlS DAY
TI THE ENDlNG IF THE WIRLD,
"WE lN lT SHALL
BE REMEMBERED.
"WE LUCKY FEW,
WE BAND IF BRITHERS.
"FIR HE WHI TIDAY
SHEDS HlS BLIID WlTH ME
SHALL BE MY BRITHER".
DI YIU REMEMBER...
THE LETTER THAT
MY GRANNY WRITE ME?
YIU DI?
D'YIU REMEMBER
HIW I ENDED lT?
"l CHERlSH...
"THE MEMIRlES IF A qUESTllN
MY GRANDSIN ASKED ME
THE ITHER DAY
"WHEN HE SAlD,
"GRANDPA, WERE YIU
A HERI lN THE WAR?"
GRANDPA SAlD, "NI...
BUT I SERVED lN
THE CIMPANY IF HERIES".
Captions Copyright 2001
HIME BIX IFFlCE
A Division of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT CIMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBI CIMMUNlCATllNS CENTER