Captions made possible
by HOME BOX OFFlCE
A Division of TIME WARNER
ENTERTAINMENT COMPANY, L.P.
THE TOCCOA MEN, THAT'S
THE ONES THAT WAS THERE
AT THE VERY BEGINNING,
THEY ARE VERY
CLOSE AND...
THEY ACCEPT PEOPLE
COMING IN LIKE MYSELF,
AS A REPLACEMENT.
BUT YOU ALSO HAD
TO PROVE YOURSELF.
MOST OF THEM WERE, WE KNOW
WERE QUALIFIED PARACHUTISTS,
THEY HAD TO BE.
A LOT OF THEM
WERE AWFULLY GREEN,
AND WE KNEW THAT.
WE JUST, WE HOPED
WE COULD KEEP 'EM ALIVE
OR THEY COULD KEEP ALIVE,
A LOT OF 'EM DIDN'T.
BUT, ER, WELL, ALRIGHT,
THEY EVENTUALLY...
BLEND RIGHT IN.
I THINK MAYBE
THEY WERE TRYING TO
IMPRESS THE OLDER GUYS,
PEOPLE LIKE ME
OR SHIFTY...
I DON'T KNOW WHY BUT,
I GOT RIGHT THERE TO WHERE
I DIDN'T WANNA
BE FRIENDLY
WITH REPLACEMENTS
COMING IN BECAUSE,
GOD, I DIDN'T LIKE
SEEING 'EM GET KILLED.
I JUST, IT JUST
TORE ME UP.
'CAUSE WE WERE
IN AWE OF THEM.
THEY WERE, THEY WERE WEARING
INFANTRY BADGES, YOU KNOW,
THE UNIFORM.
THEY HAD A STAR ON
THEIR JUMP WINGS.
THEY, UH...
THEY WERE LIKE HEROES
TO US, YOU KNOW?
THAT'S HOW
WE LOOKED AT THEM.
AND THEY WERE GOOD.
FURTHERMORE,
THEY WERE GOOD.
WE HAD GOOD OFFICERS,
FOR THE MOST PART,
BUT WE HAD
EXCELLENT NCOs.
THEY LOOKED, THEY
LOOKED AFTER YOU.
( chattering )
LIEUTENANT, NICE AND EASY.
WE'VE STILL GOT A SHOT.
( groaning )
TOUGH BREAK,
YOU'RE HAVING
A TOUGH NIGHT.
PEOPLE HAVE
TOUGH NIGHTS.
I'M SORRY, GEORGE.
IT'S ALRIGHT.
NICE SHOT, SIR.
THANK YOU, BULL.
THANK YOU,
LIEUTENANT.
FINISH ME UP.
HERE WE GO.
DOUBLE SEVEN.
( groaning )
YOU'RE EMBARRASSING
THE LIEUTENANT, HERE.
HAVE A DRINK.
OH, DON'T MIND
IF I DO, SARGE.
BETTER START
WINNING MONEY SOON,
I THINK YOUR BUDDIES ARE
STARTING TO MISS YOU.
YEAH, THEY DO LOOK
KIND OF SAD, DON'T THEY?
THEY'RE JUST SERIOUS
FIGHTING MEN, THAT'S ALL.
WELL, I THINK
I'M GONNA GO
INTRODUCE MYSELF.
CAREFUL WHAT
YOU SAY NOW.
DON'T TAKE MUCH
TO SET MY GUYS OFF.
YEAH, AND YOU GOT
SOME WILD-EYED KILLERS
RIGHT THERE, BULL.
YOU KNOW, IT'S A GOOD THING
WE WEREN'T GAMBLING.
OH, BOY,
WE WOULD'VE
GOTTEN KILLED.
WANNA BET?
WHAT?
YOU WANNA BET?
NO, I'M NOT MUCH
OF A GAMBLING MAN.
HEY, COME ON.
FIRST ONE TO HIT
THE BULL'S-EYE?
YEAH, ONE SHOT,
ONE SHOT.
YEAH?
MAKE IT TWO.
TWO PACKS. TWO PACKS.
ALRIGHT, TWO PACKS,
HERE WE GO,
ONE SHOT, VERY GOOD.
HEY, FELLAS.
WHAT DO YOU HEAR?
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
ACTUALLY,
THAT'S BABE'S SEAT,
PRIVATE HEFFRON'S.
IS THAT RIGHT?
I DON'T CARE IF
IT'S FUCKING ElSENHOWER'S.
WHO ARE YOU?
PRIVATE MILLER,
JAMES MILLER.
I'M IN SERGEANT
RANDLEMAN'S SQUAD.
US TOO,
I'M LES HASHEY.
TONY...
GARCIA, I KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
OLD GONORRHEA
DON'T MISS NOTHING.
LIEUTENANT, ARE
YOU GONNA SHOOT
LEFTY ALL NIGHT?
HEY, C'MON.
JUST CURIOUS 'CAUSE
HE'S RIGHT-HANDED.
GEORGE, WHAT WOULD I DO
WITHOUT GEORGE LADS?
BOOP!
OOH! OOH!
GOODNESS
GRACIOUS.
TWO PACKS,
GENTLEMEN.
I KNOW YOU
GOT 'EM,
PAY UP.
SO, HEFFRON
TELL YOU ABOUT
DORIS YET?
NO.
NO?
MMM.
WELL, THEN I'M GONNA
EDUCATE YOU.
WE'RE GETTING READY
TO GET ON A PLANE
FOR THAT FIRST FROG TOWN
WE NEVER JUMPED INTO.
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
HEFFRON STOPS
DEAD IN HIS TRACKS.
BING AND A BANG
AND A BOOM,
EVERYBODY BANGING
INTO EACH OTHER,
HEFFRON'S JUST STARIN' UP
AT THE NOSE OF THE PLANE
BECAUSE ON IT IS PAINTED
THIS BEAUTIFUL PINUP.
AND WRITTEN UNDERNEATH
"DARLING DORIS".
DORIS, WHICH JUST HAPPENS
TO BE THE NAME OF
THE SKIRT WHO JUST,
THAT DAY, SENT BABE
ONE OF THEM LETTERS.
YOU KNOW THE...
WHAT DO YOU CALL
THEM LETTERS THAT
THE BROADS SEND?
ER, "DEAR
JOHN" LETTER.
THAT'S IT, A
"DEAR BABE" LETTER.
WELL, ANYWAY, LUCKY
FOR BABE, PATTON
OVERRUNS OUR DROP ZONE.
MISSION CANCELLED.
ON OTHER WORDS,
BABE DON'T HAVE TO
RISK GETTING INSIDE
OLD DORIS AGAIN.
HAH!
HEY, BULL, YOUR SQUAD
LISTENS UP REAL GOOD.
YEAH, THEY'RE BEING
POLITE LIKE WHENEVER
BULL OPENS HIS MOUTH.
JOHNNY, WHAT ARE
YOU SAYING?
BULL'S BOYS ARE JUST
HUMORING HIM?
YEAH, LIKE WHENEVER
HE GIVES OUT SOME
OF HIS FOLKSY WISDOM
FROM BACK DOWN
ON THE FARM.
PROBABLY THINK HE'S
A FUCKING HAYSEED.
AIN'T THAT RIGHT?
WHAT ARE YOU
LAUGHING AT?
YOU NEW BOYS, YOU
PAY ATTENTION TO
SERGEANT RANDLEMAN.
GOT THAT?
THAT'S THE SMARTEST
MAN IN THE COMPANY.
WHERE'D YOU
GET THAT?
IT'S A PRESIDENTIAL
DISTINGUISHED
UNIT CITATION.
FOR, UH...
FOR WHAT THE REGIMENT
DID IN NORMANDY.
THAT'S RIGHT,
FOR WHAT THE
REGIMENT DID.
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
HEY, HEY, EASE
UP, COBB, MMM?
IT'S A UNIT CITATION.
SHIT, COBB.
YOU DIDN'T FIGHT
IN NORMANDY NEITHER.
I GOT HIT IN THE
PLANE BEFORE I GOT
A CHANCE TO JUMP.
HEY, Y'ALL,
LISTEN UP.
I GOT US AN
ANNOUNCEMENT
TO MAKE.
THIS HERE IS
CARWOOD LIPTON.
HE'S AIREADY
MARRIED, SMOKEY.
( laughing )
THIS HERE lS
CARWOOD LIPTON.
THE NEW EASY COMPANY
1st SERGEANT.
( cheering and applause )
AS BEFITTING
THIS POSITION,
HE SAYS HE HAS TO
MAKE AN ANNOUNCEMENT.
WELL, HATE TO BREAK
THE MOOD HERE, BOYS,
BUT, WE'RE MOVING
OUT AGAIN.
( Winters )
AS YOU CAN SEE,
THIS IS CALLED
OPERATION MARKET GARDEN.
IN TERMS OF AIRBORNE
DIVISIONS INVOLVED,
THIS ONE'S EVEN
BIGGER THAN NORMANDY.
WE'RE DROPPING DEEP
INTO OCCUPIED HOLLAND.
THE ALLIED OBJECTIVE IS
TO TAKE THIS ROAD HERE,
BETWEEN EINDHOVEN
AND ARNHEM,
SO, THAT TWO BRITISH
ARMORED DIVISIONS
CAN MOVE UP IT
TOWARD ARNHEM.
OUR JOB IS GONNA BE TO
LIBERATE EINDHOVEN.
STAY THERE,
WAIT FOR THE TANKS.
THE ENTIRE EUROPEAN
ADVANCE HAS BEEN PUT
ON HOLD TO ALLOCATE
RESOURCES FOR
THIS OPERATION.
IT'S MONTGOMERY'S
PERSONAL PLAN
AND WE'LL BE UNDER
BRITISH COMMAND.
THE GOOD NEWS IS,
IF THIS WORKS,
THESE TANKS WILL BE OVER
THE RHINE AND INTO GERMANY.
IT COULD END THE WAR
AND GET US HOME BY CHRISTMAS.
( mumbling )
IT'LL BE A
DAY-TIME JUMP.
INTELLIGENCE DOESN'T
EXPECT MUCH OPPOSITION.
THEY THINK THE KRAUTS
IN HOLLAND ARE MOSTLY
KIDS AND OLD MEN.
AND WE SHOULD
TAKE 'EM BY SURPRISE.
ON ANY CASE,
SAY GOODBYE TO ENGLAND.
I DON'T THINK THEY'RE
GONNA CALL THIS ONE OFF.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LOOK AT COBB, MAN.
WATCH AND LEARN, KIDS.
YOU WANNA LIVE?
JUMP READY TO FIGHT
THEY LET YOU OUT OF
THE HOSPITAL LIKE THAT, BOY?
THEY DIDN'T LET ME
OUT, I BUSTED OUT.
I DIDN'T WANNA GET
RE-ASSIGNED TO
SOME OTHER UNIT.
YEAH?
CAN YOU MAKE
THE JUMP?
OH, SURE I CAN, LIP,
I JUST CAN'T SIT.
WELCOME BACK, POPEYE.
THANKS, BULL.
POPEYE WENT AWOL
JUST IN TIME TO JUMP.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
WHO, SOBEL?
WELL, HE'S THE NEWLY
APPOINTED REGIMENTAL S-4.
SUPPLY OFFICER?
YEAH, YOU GOT IT.
HE PICKED ME UP
IN AIRBOURNE,
TRYING TO
FIND YOU GUYS.
HE KNOW YOU WENT AWOL?
HE KNOWS.
HE JUST SAID
I WAS LUCKY,
I COULD SIT OUT
THIS JUMP IF I WANTED.
I SAID I
DIDN'T WANT TO.
SO, HE SAYS
"HOP IN".
"HOP IN"?
YEAH, I KNOW, I COULDN'T
BELIEVE IT EITHER.
HEY, MAYBE HE'S
GONNA COURT-MARTIAL
ME LATER, HUH?
LET'S GET YOU
SOME GEAR.
HEY, MAL.
OVER THERE.
SON OF A BITCH.
MALARKEY.
SERGEANT MALARKEY.
SIR?
YOU THOUGHT YOU COULD
GET AWAY WITH IT?
WHAT DO
YOU MEAN, SIR?
SERGEANT, THAT
MOTORCYCLE IS UNITED
STATES ARMY PROPERTY.
THAT MAY NOT MEAN
ANYTHING TO YOU,
BUT IT MEANS
SOMETHING TO ME.
WHERE'D YOU FIND IT?
THAT'S HIM
ALRIGHT.
WHO IS HE, SARGE?
HE WAS OUR FIRST CO.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE GOT PROMOTED.
JUST TAP MY LEG,
SERGEANT.
LIEUTENANT, YOU'LL
BE IN THE DOORWAY.
YEAH, I KNOW, BUT...
LOOK, SERGEANT,
YOU'LL BE THE
MAN BEHIND ME.
WHEN THE GREEN
LIGHT COMES ON,
IF YOU COULD JUST
TAP ME, ALRIGHT?
THE GREEN LIGHT WILL
BE NEXT TO YOU, SIR.
JUST DO IT,
THAT'S AN ORDER.
COME HERE, COME HERE.
SLING IT UP AND DOWN,
AND WHEN YOU HIT GROUND,
YOUR KNEE'LL
HIT THE BUTT.
THE BUSINESS END'LL
BREAK YOUR JAW.
LOSE YOUR RESERVE,
YOU WON'T NEED IT,
WE'RE JUMPING LOW.
TAKE YOUR BELLY BAND
AND WRAP IT AROUND YOU, FINE.
I'M SORRY, SARGE.
DON'T BE SORRY.
GRAB YOUR RIFLE,
LET'S GO.
WHERE'D YOU GET
THAT FROM, HOOBLER?
I THINK I
LOVE HOLLAND.
WHERE'D YOU
GET THESE?
THAT FARMHOUSE
OVER THERE.
JUST SITTING
OUT IN THE OPEN.
I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE THEY WERE
EXPECTING US.
( loud plane soaring )
BOYS?
WHOO, MADE IT.
I WONDER IF
THEY HIT ANYTHING.
GOODBYE AIR SUPPORT.
THERE'S SOME KIND
OF HOLDUP AHEAD.
WE'RE GOING IN THROUGH
THIS FIELD HERE.
MOVE OUT, LET'S GO!
LET'S GO,
MOVE IT, MOVE IT!
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO
SHOOT AS STRAIGHT WITH
THAT THING ON.
OKAY, HOLD YOUR FIRE.
HEY, KID.
BULL!
BULL, YOU SEEN
CAPTAIN WINTERS?
NO, WHY?
KEEP YOUR SQUAD MOVING.
WHERE ARE ALL
THE GERMANS?
THEY COULD
BE ANYWHERE.
KEEP MOVING!
PARDON ME.
C'MON, LADY.
DICK,
CLOCK'S TICKING.
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU,
THANK YOU...
VERY KIND.
WHAT'S UP,
WELSHY?
SNIPERS.
WE'VE GOTTA GET
TO THESE BRIDGES.
( chattering )
SERGEANT TALBERT.
LET'S MOVE, WE'VE
GOT WORK TO DO.
( crowd singing )
WHAT DID THEY DO?
THEY SLEPT WITH
THE GERMANS.
THEY ARE LUCKY.
THE MEN WHO COLLABORATED
ARE BEING SHOT.
MR. VAN KOOIJK
HERE IS WITH THE
DUTCH RESISTANCE.
WE'VE BEEN WAITING
AND HOPING FOR THIS DAY...
FOR ALMOST
FIVE YEARS.
SAYS HE CAN HELP
US SECURE THE
BRIDGES HERE.
YES.
TOGETHER WE CAN PUSH
THE REMAINING GERMANS
OUT OF EINDHOVEN.
AND THAT'S JUST
THE BEGINNING.
ANY IDEA WHERE
THEY MIGHT BE?
AH, WELL, WE'RE STILL
WORKING ON THAT RIGHT NOW.
PEERS AND HIS FRIENDS HERE
ARE GATHERING INFORMATION
AS WE SPEAK.
HIS CONTACTS,
A COUPLE OF
TOWNS DOWN,
SAID THEY SAW
THE BRITISH 2nd
AND GUARDS ARMORED
MOVE THROUGH,
HALF AN HOUR AGO.
THEY'RE KIDS.
THESE ARE
RELIABLE REPORTS.
ANYTHING WE CAN DO TO
HELP YOU, WE WILL DO.
ANYTHING.
( cheering )
RIGHT ON TIME.
CAPTAIN.
I'LL BE HAPPY TO SHOW YOU
THE QUICKEST ROUTE
TO THE BRIDGES.
I'D BE HAPPY TO
HAVE YOUR HELP.
GET SCOUTS TO
THE EDGE OF TOWN
IN CASE WE'RE HERE
FOR THE NIGHT.
HEY, VAN KLINKEN.
WEBSTER.
SLEEPING OUTSIDE
IS FOR SUCKERS, GUYS.
BETTER BE GOOD,
I WAS ALMOST ASLEEP.
HERAUS, HANDE HOCH.
MACH SCHNELL.
NIEDERLANDER.
SPRECHEN SIE ENGLISH?
JA.
A LITTLE BIT.
WHAT WERE YOU
DOING DOWN THERE?
IT'S AN AIR-RAlD
SHELTER.
MY FAMILY
HAS BEEN IN THERE
EVER SINCE THE FIRST
PLANE FLEW OVER.
WE'RE AMERICANS.
PARATROOPERS.
THE GERMANS--
ARE GONE?
THINK SO.
YOU SEE ANY,
YOU LET US KNOW.
ARE YOU HERE
TO STAY?
HMM-MMM.
AS LONG AS
WE HAVE TO.
YEAH, THEY DON'T
TELL US VERY MUCH.
OR FEED US MUCH.
PLEASE...
WAIT HERE.
YOU SEE THAT?
I SAY SCREW PARIS.
HEY, DON'T TALK
ABOUT SCREWING,
ALRIGHT?
THEY ALL
SPEAK ENGLISH.
THEY ALL LOVE US.
WHAT A FANTASTIC COUNTRY.
HEY, TAKE A LOOK.
HERE, TAKE.
DANKE.
ARE THESE OLIVES?
THANKS, DANKE.
JA, KOMME VIDAS
IST GUT.
CIGARETTEN?
JA.
HE NEVER
TASTED CHOCOLATE.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD,
ISN'T IT?
OH, MAN,
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I HATE EGGS!
HEY, SARGE, YOU CAN
HAVE THIS ONE.
VINCENT VAN GOGH
WAS BORN IN NUENEN.
YEAH?
SO WHAT?
SURE TEACH A LOT OF
USEFUL STUFF AT HARVARD.
MELLET.
HEY, GET A LOAD OF
GENERAL PATTON.
WHAT THE HELL'S
HE DOING?
MAKES QUITE A
TARGET, DON'T HE?
LIEUTENANT!
SNIPER!
SARGE!
CLEAR THE TRACK!
MOVE IT!
COME ON, COME ON!
MEDIC UP FRONT,
MEDIC UP FRONT!
WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
KEEP DOWN,
STAY STILL.
KEEP MOVING!
GET UP!
HE'LL SHOOT
A STATIONARY TARGET!
MOVE!
THE FARMHOUSE,
DEPLOY RIGHT.
( dogs barking )
TAKE THE RIGHT SIDE.
RIGHT.
GO.
GO ON.
KRAUT!
SHIT.
GODDAMMIT, MOVE!
GO, COME OUT,
COME OUT!
AWAY, AWAY, AWAY!
WHAT'S HE SAYING?
HE SAID, OH...
"AWAY, AWAY".
WHICH EITHER MEANS THAT
THE GERMANS HAVE GONE
OR HE WANTS
US TO GO.
I DON'T KNOW.
( dog barking )
GO, GO!
( whistling )
RAMIREZ
( panting )
BEAT IT!
ALRIGHT, FELLAS,
SET 'EM UP.
TIGER.
SHIT!
HEFFRON, ON ME.
STAY LOW.
YOU GOT A CAN
OPENER, BABE?
AFRAID I
DON'T, SARGE.
WE'VE GOT
A KRAUT TANK,
100 YARDS
ON THE LEFT...
I DON'T SEE HIM.
PUT A COUPLE OF SHELLS
THROUGH THAT BUILDING,
YOU GONNA SEE HIM
REAL GOOD.
I CAN'T.
MY ORDERS ARE
NO UNNECESSARY
DESTRUCTION OF PROPERTY.
I'M TELLING YOU,
HE'S RIGHT THERE.
AND I BELIEVE YOU.
AND IF I CAN'T
SEE THE BUGGER,
I CAN'T BLOODY WELL
SHOOT HIM, CAN I?
ARE YOU STAYING
OR GOING?
HE'S GONNA SEE
YOU REAL SOON.
WHAT THE HELL'S
HE DOING?
FORWARD,
ROLL TANK!
FALL BACK!
PULL BACK,
PULL BACK!
TAKE COVER!
THERE'S A DITCH
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
FOLLOW ME THROUGH.
( gunshots )
VAN KLINKEN!
BULL!
GO!
RIFLE GRENADE!
SCHMIDT, MG42.
10 O'CLOCK,
NAIL 'EM.
FIRE!
YOU HAD TO LEAVE HIM.
HE'S STILL ALIVE!
WHO'S HURT?
VAN KLINKEN.
OTHER SIDE OF
THAT HEDGE.
UH-HUH.
OH, SHIT!
OKAY, READY.
FALL BACK, FALL BACK,
FALL BACK!
PULL BACK, ALLEY,
PULL BACK!
GO!
TAKE OVER.
YEAH, WHERE?
WE HAVE TO GET HIM
TO THE REAR.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO,
LIEUTENANT?
I'M NOT SURE.
SIR, THEY'RE ABOUT
TO UNFLANK US,
WE GOTTA GET
OUTTA HERE!
WE HAVE INFANTRY
EVERYWHERE.
REPEAT, ARNHEM
HAS CUT THE ROAD.
WE ARE COVERED
IN INFANTRY.
WE ARE PULLING BACK.
LADS, FALL BACK!
HASH, WHERE'S
RANDLEMAN?
I DON'T KNOW,
SERGEANT.
GET OUT OF HERE!
MILLER!
COME ON.
HASHEY, LET'S GO!
GET DOWN!
MEDIC!
GO, GET A MEDIC,
KEEP MOVING!
HEY, DOC.
LIEUTENANT.
IT'S GONE RIGHT
THROUGH, BUCK.
SIDE TO SIDE,
BOTH CHEEKS.
MALARKEY, GET 'EM
OUT OF HERE, GO!
WHAT?!
LEAVE ME HERE
FOR THE GERMANS.
YOU NUTS?
WE'LL CARRY YOU.
ARE YOU KIDDIN' ME?
I WEIGH MORE THAN BOTH
OF YOU TWO GUYS COMBINED.
COME ON.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
HELP US!
GET BACK TO
THE TANK!
KEEP MOVING,
KEEP LOW!
LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
OVER YOU GO.
ONE BULLET,
FOUR HOLES.
YEAH, IT'S ALMOST
A MIRACLE.
LIP, I DON'T THINK
WE KNOW WHERE
BULL IS, HUH?
LET'S GO,
LET'S GO!
KEEP MOVING,
KEEP MOVING!
MOVE 'EM OUT,
LET'S GO!
HURRY UP, LET'S GO!
HOW BAD?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
NlX!
I'M ALRIGHT,
I'M ALRIGHT.
AM I ALRIGHT?
YEAH.
YEAH, YOU FEEL
ALRIGHT?
YEAH, QUIT LOOKING
AT ME LIKE THAT.
CAP'N, WE GOT
FOUR DEAD.
11 INJURED.
OKAY, LET'S
MOVE 'EM OUT.
OH, AND, SIR,
RANDLEMAN'S
MISSING, TOO.
RANDLEMAN?
YES, SIR.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
WHERE'S THE BULL?
DON'T KNOW.
I NEVER FIRED A SHOT,
THE WHOLE TIME.
FIND ANYTHING OUT?
ABOUT WHAT?
ANYTHING.
WHAT WE'RE
DOING NEXT.
NO.
OH, I DID HEAR
ONE THING.
LIEUTENANT BREWER'S
GONNA MAKE IT.
WHAT?
LIEUTENANT BREWER'S
GONNA MAKE IT.
NAH, THERE'S NO WAY.
HE'S HEADED
BACK TO ENGLAND.
THEY'LL PROBABLY
SEND HIM HOME.
HOW IS
THAT POSSIBLE?
HE DID TURN HIS HEAD
AT THE LAST SECOND.
WHEN SERGEANT RANDLEMAN
CALLED OUT TO HIM.
NO.
JUST PULL...
FUCK.
JUST PULL IT OUT.
( speaking Dutch )
( male speaking German )
GO, GO!
( soldiers laughing )
( banging noise )
( speaking German )
( screaming )
HOOB...
ANY NEWS OF
THE BULL YET?
IF THERE AIN'T
NO BODY,
THEN THERE AIN'T
NOBODY FUCKING DEAD.
UNDERSTAND ME?
I'M GONNA
LOOK FOR HIM.
NOT BY YOURSELF
YOU'RE NOT.
I'LL GO WITH YOU,
LET ME GET SOME AMMO.
THAT'S OKAY...
I'LL GO.
ME, TOO.
ALRIGHT.
GO GET HIM.
ALRIGHT,
WHAT THE HELL.
I AIN'T GOING
BACK UP THERE.
WEBSTER,
US OR THEM?
NOT US.
STUPID.
GO.
THEY'RE BOMBING
EINDHOVEN.
YEAH.
COME ON, NIX.
WE'LL DIG IN
FOR THE NIGHT.
WON'T BE WAVING
SO MANY ORANGE FLAGS
AT US TOMORROW.
WHERE THE FUCK
YOU BEEN?
GLAD TO SEE
YOU BOYS.
NOT AS GLAD AS US.
BET YOU THOUGHT WE'D GIVEN UP
ON YOU THERE, HUH, BOSS?
SHUT UP, COBB.
WHAT?
I THINK WE SHOULD
GO BACK NOW.
HEY, JOHNNY, LOOK.
BULL!
HEY, JOHNNY.
GET A LITTLE LOST?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YOU, TOO.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
TO SLAP YOU, KISS YOU,
OR SALUTE YOU.
I TOLD THESE SCALLYWAGS
YOU WAS OKAY.
AND THEY
DIDN'T LISTEN?
NAH, THESE
SALTY BASTARDS,
THEY WANTED TO GO
ON A SUICIDE RUN
TO DRAG
YOUR ASS BACK.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH, I TOLD 'EM
DON'T BOTHER.
I NEVER DID LIKE
THIS COMPANY NONE.
HOOBLER.
OH, THEY FOUND YOU.
WAIT, WHAT
DID YOU SAY?
JOHNNY, DON'T
IRRIGATE ME!
"THEY
FOUND
YOU"?
I DON'T KNOW WHO'S
MORE STUPID, YOU
OR THE HICK.
ALRIGHT, MOUNT UP!
HUP HUP,
LET'S MOVE OUT!
GRAB YOUR GEAR,
LET'S GO!
2nd PLATOON,
GRAB YOUR GEAR!
LET'S GO!
1st PLATOON!
LET'S START
FALLING IN NOW.
COBB, MOVE IT.
DUKEMAN,
ROUND 'EM UP.
1st PLATOON.
GRAB YOUR GEAR,
LET'S GO!
VAN KOOlJK SAYS
THE GERMANS ARE
CONCENTRATING
THEIR ARMOR
UP NEAR VEGHEL.
WE MAY BE HEADING
INTO SOME MORE TANKS.
WELL, AS LONG
AS IT'S ONLY OLD
MEN AND KIDS.
YEAH.
I DON'T LIKE
RETREATING.
FIRST TIME
FOR EVERYTHING.
HOW ARE THE OTHER
DIVISIONS FARING
UP NORTH?
I THINK WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO FIND ANOTHER
WAY INTO GERMANY.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOX OFFICE
Division of TIME WARNER
COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNICATIONS CENTER