Captions made possible by
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P
WHEN WE LEFT
FOR BASTOGNE,
WE WERE SHORT
OF EQUlPMENT,
WE DlDN'T HAVE
ENOUGH AMMUNlTlON,
ENOUGH WARM CLOTHES.
BUT WE HAD CONFlDENCE
THAT OUR HlGHER
MlLlTARY AUTHORlTlES
WOULD GET TO US
WHATEVER WE NEEDED.
AND THERE WAS A RlDGE,
WlTH TREE-LlNE.
WE WERE DUG lN
ON THAT RlDGE.
THE GERMANS KNEW
RlGHT WHERE WE WERE
AND THEY REALLY
GAVE US A SHELLACKlNG.
WELL, LlKE lN BASTOGNE,
WE'RE DOWN TO
ONE ROUND PER MAN
THERE FOR A WHlLE.
THERE WAS THlS,
THE FOG WAS lN,
THEY COULDN'T DROP US,
COULDN'T RE-SUPPLY US.
EVERY TlME THEY TRlED
TO DROP SUPPLlES lNTO US
THEY MlSSED US
AND DROPPED THEM
TO THE GERMANS.
ONE OF THE GUYS
GOT HlT lN THE ARM
WlTH A PlECE OF SHRAPNEL.
TOOK HlS ARM OFF
ABOVE THE ELBOW.
AND THEY WERE
TAKlNG HlM OUT,
HE SAlD, "GET MY WRlST -WATCH
OFF MY ARM".
AND THEN A MEDlC
CAME ALONG,
AND I THlNK HE REALLY
SAVED MY LlFE,
BECAUSE HE STUCK A SYRETTE
lN A KEY POSlTlON,
MORE MORPHlNE.
EVEN TODAY,
A REAL COLD NlGHT,
WE GO TO BED
AND MY WlFE WlLL
TELL YOU THAT
FlRST THlNG l'LL SAY
lS, "l'M GLAD l'M
NOT lN BASTOGNE".
( breathing heaVily )
( noises )
( whispering )
Duck, duck, duck!
KOMMEN SlE HlER.
KOMMEN SlE HlER,
SCHNELL!
DOC, BANDAGE.
TAKE HlM
BACK TO REGlMENT.
AS YOU ALL KNOW,
GENERAL McAULlFFE,
ACTlNG DlVlSlON COMMANDER.
GlVE lT TO ME
STRAlGHT!
WE'VE BEEN TAKlNG GROUND
lN ONE POSlTlON, GENERAL,
LOSlNG lT lN ANOTHER.
AND NOW lT LOOKS
LlKE A STAND-OFF,
WE'RE DlGGlNG lN ON
THE EDGE OF THE FOREST.
WE'RE UNDER SPORADlC
ARTlLLERY FlRE, GENERAL.
WE'RE TAKlNG A LOT OF HlTS
AND WE HAVE NO AlD STATlON.
WE'VE RUN OUT OF FOOD,
WE HAVE NO WlNTER CLOTHES,
AND WE HAVE LlTTLE
OR NO AMMO.
THE LlNE'S SPREAD SO THlN,
THE ENEMY WANDERS
INTO OUR C.P. TO USE
OUR SLlT TRENCHES, SlR.
WE JUST CAN'T
COVER THE LlNE.
GOOD MORNlNG,
CAPTAlN NlOON.
YOU GOT ANYTHlNG
TO ADD FOR
GENERAL McAULlFFE?
GENERAL, AH, YES SlR.
GENERAL, I TOOK A
WALK ON A LlNE ABOUT
ZERO 300 LAST NlGHT.
COULDN'T FlND THE 501 st
ON OUR RlGHT FLANK.
I TlED lN WlTH A SQUAD
FROM OUR 2nd PLATOON
BUT, SlR, WE'VE GOT
SOME CONSlDERABLE GAPS
lN OUR PERlMETER.
I DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH PEOPLE, SlR.
WE'RE SPREAD
TOO DAMN THlN.
HOLD THE LlNE, COLONEL,
CLOSE THE GAPS.
THlS GODDAMN FOG
WON'T LlFT ANY TlME SOON,
SO, YOU CAN FORGET
ABOUT AlR COVER.
YOUR 1 st BATTALlON
JUST PULLED OUT OF FOY,
KRAUTS ON THElR TAlL.
TANKS, ARTlLLERY,
GOT NO BACK-UP.
THERE'S A LOT OF SHlT
HEADlNG THlS WAY.
DOC...
CAN I SCROUNGE A
BANDAGE FROM YOUR
AlD KlD, SlR?
HOW ARE YOU FlOED?
NO PLASMA,
COUPLE OF BANDAGES.
PRACTlCALLY
NO MORPHlNE.
IN FACT, I TRlED
TO FlND MY WAY
UP TO 3rd BATTALlON
LOOKlNG FOR SUPPLlES,
BUT LOST MY WAY.
IF YOU CAN'T GET
OVER TO 3rd, HOOK
UP WlTH DOC RYAN,
HE'LL FlO YOU UP WlTH
WHAT HE HAS TO SPARE.
THANKS, CAP'N.
EUGENE...
GET EVERYTHlNG YOU CAN,
YOU'RE GONNA
NEED lT.
SPlNA.
DOC.
WHAT'S HAPPENlNG?
WE'RE DlGGlNG lN
RlGHT ALONG THE LlNE.
YEAH?
YEAH, THlS lS lT.
SO, WHAT'D YOU GET?
I GOT, ER,
I GOT THlS.
AND I GOT MYSELF
A KRAUT BANDAGE.
WHAT, THlS lS lT?
YEAH, THAT'S lT,
THAT'S ALL YOU GOT.
JEEZ.
YOU KNOW, 1 st BATTALlON'S
PULLED OUT OF FOY,
HEAVY CASUALTlES.
SO, lF THEY'RE
PULLlNG BACK,
THEN WHAT THE
HELL ARE WE DOlNG
SlTTlNG HERE?
WE NEED MORPHlNE,
THlS lS ALL l'VE GOT.
YOU GOT EOTRA SClSSORS?
UH UH, JUST THE ONE.
( Dike )
1 st SERGEANT LlPTON!
SlR.
WHAT'S THlS?
TWO MEDlCS
lN ONE HOLE?
YES, SlR.
WELL, WHAT'S GONNA
HAPPEN TO US lF YOU
TAKE A HlT, HUH?
SlR?
1 st SERGEANT,
WHERE'S MY FOOHOLE?
IT'S BACK
HERE, SlR.
MAYBE YOU
MlSSED lT, HUH?
I'LL WALK YOU
BACK, SlR.
YOU'RE A BlT
CLOSE TO THE
LlNE HERE.
GODDAMNlT.
SERGEANT GUARNERE,
DlD YOU KEEP
YOUR MORPHlNE
FROM HOLLAND?
NO.
HEY DOC,
l'VE GOTTA
TALK TO YOU.
HOW'S THAT LEG?
OH, TO HELL
WlTH THE LEG, l'M
PlSSlNG NEEDLES.
LATER.
SHlT!
YOU SEEN 'EM?
NO, BUT THEY'RE
OUT THERE.
DEPEND ON lT.
CUP OF JOE, DOC?
GORDON, I NEED SClSSORS,
YOU GOT SClSSORS,
SHARP SClSSORS.
SClSSORS?
WELL, LET'S SEE,
l'LL HAVE TO CHECK
THE SEWlNG ROOM.
MlGHT BE UPSTAlRS
lN THE STUDY.
THAT SKlNNY OLD DRAWER
lN THE MlDDLE OF THE DESK.
ALRlGHT, WHAT ABOUT
AN EOTRA SYRETTE lN
YOUR AlD KlT, HUH?
HlDE YOUR MORPHlNE,
GUYS--
MUCK, YOU ALRlGHT?
I'M GOOD.
MUCK, MALARKEY,
TAKE COVER!
WE'RE OKAY.
TAKE A LOOK AT THlS SHlT,
THEY'VE PEPPERED MY HELMET.
HEY DOC, MORPHlNE.
HERE, TAKE lT!
WHERE'S PENKALA?
CHRlST KNOWS.
( male )
MEDlC!
DOC!
YOU GUYS HlT?
HEY, DOC,
HOW YOU DOlNG?
HEY, ARE YOU CRAZY?
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKlNG
AT HlM FOR, WATCH THE
GODDAMN LlNE.
YOU GOT A SYRETTE?
NO.
( male )
MEDlC!
DOC!
PENKALA.
IT'S THE ARTERY,
I CAN FEEL lT.
PENKALA, LET GO--
IT'S THE GODDAMN ARTERY!
PENKALA, LOOSEN YOUR FlNGERS,
GODDAMNlT, LOOSEN THEM NOW!
I'LL BLEED TO DEATH.
RELAO YOUR ARM,
PENKY, COME ON!
IT'S NOT THE ARTERY.
I AlN'T GOlNG BACK, DOC.
WHAT?
I AlN'T GOlNG NOWHERE,
NOT lN THlS SHlT.
YOU DON'T WANT TO
GO OUT lN THlS SHlT AND
YOU'RE YELLlNG "MEDlC"?
I DON'T NEED TO GO
BACK TO NO AlD STATlON.
WELL, YOU'RE
lN LUCK, PENKALA.
WE DON'T GOT
NO AlD STATlON.
PENKALA, SClSSORS,
I NEED SClSSORS
YOU GOT SClSSORS?
WHAT THE HELL
I NEED SClSSORS FOR?
GOT YOUR AlD KlT?
RlGHT, WELL,
YOU DON'T NEED THlS.
NOT YET, I DO.
WHO GOT HlT?
PENKALA.
ALRlGHT, HERE, THlS lS
WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO.
I WANT YOU TO
TAKE SOMEONE,
AND WORK YOUR WAY
OVER TO THE 3rd
BATTALlON, ALRlGHT?
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED,
BANDAGES, PLASMA.
WHATEVER YOU
CAN BEG, YOU BEG.
ALRlGHT, AND GlVE ME
SOME GODDAMN SClSSORS,
I CAN'T GET ANY.
AND YOU GET YOURSELF
A HOT MEAL TOO, HUH?
GO!
YOU KNOW, HE TOLD
ME HE WAS A
GODDAMN VlRGlN.
WHO?
THE REPLACEMENT
lN MY FOOHOLE, JULlAN.
YEAH?
GODDAMN VlRGlN,
JUST A KlD.
THE ONLY VlRGlN I KNOW
lS THE VlRGlN MARY.
HEY, BABE,
WHERE THE HELL ARE WE?
THlS WAY.
I DON'T LlKE lT.
WHERE THE HELL'S
3rd BATTALlON?
SHlT, COME ON.
COME ON, COME ON,
GlVE ME A HAND.
GO, GO!
COME ON, SPlNA, MOVE!
I'M MOVlNG.
GET MOVlNG,
COME ON, GO.
OKAY, WE CAN SPARE
A FEW BANDAGES,
BUT THAT'S lT.
NO MORPHlNE.
YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO GO BACK TO
BASTOGNE FOR PLASMA.
BASTOGNE, lT TOOK US
AN HOUR TO FlND YOU.
DOESN'T YOUR SURGEON
HAVE PLASMA?
WE DON'T HAVE ONE, NO SURGEON,
NO AlD STATlON, NOTHlNG.
JUST ME
AND MY BUDDY.
SORRY, GUYS,
BUT WE JUST
CAN'T HELP YOU.
( male )
TAKE COVER!
GET YOUR BUTTS OUT OF HERE,
WE'RE PULLlNG BACK!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
GO, GO, GO!
MOVE!
SHOULD HAVE SHOT
HlNKLE lN THE ASS,
AND HE WOULD HAVE
SHOT HlM lN THE ASS!
HEY, GOD BLESS YA.
( chattering )
YO, THESE SMELL
LlKE MY ARMPlT.
AT LEAST
YOUR ARMPlT'S WARM.
DO YOU WANT SYRUP
WlTH THAT?
HEY, JOE, BE HONEST,
WHAT'S lN THESE
THlNGS ANYWAY, HUH?
NOTHlNG YOU
WON'T EAT, MALARKEY.
I WON'T EAT MALARKEY.
HEY, HEY, MAYBE
HlNKLE WOULD LlKE
YOUR SHARE, HUH?
I SHOULD HAVE SHOT HlM
WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE.
WHAT, RUNNlNG
BACKWARDS, BABE?
ANYBODY SEEN
LlEUTENANT DlKE?
TRY BATTALlON
C.P. SlR.
TRY PARlS.
TRY HlNKLE.
HlNKLE, SWEETlE,
l'M HOME.
HEY, EUGENE, LlEUTENANT
DlKE'S GOT A FULL AlD
KlT, TRY HlM.
YEAH, l'M SURE
HE'S NOT USlNG HlS.
MAYBE HlNKLE'S
GOT A SYRETTE FOR YOU.
EAT YOUR STRUDEL.
HEY, HlNKLE-VlNKLE,
EAT THE ARMPlT, HUH?
LlEUTENANT DlKE.
LlEUTENANT.
CAN YOU SPARE SOMETHlNG
FROM YOUR AlD KlT, SlR?
I'M REAL SHORT,
I NEED SYRETTES.
WHAT, MORPHlNE?
YES, SlR.
WHAT HAPPENS
lF I GET HlT?
I'LL BE THERE, SlR.
SYRETTES lN
HERE, RlGHT?
YES, lT lS.
HERE.
I DON'T PLAN
ON GETTlNG HlT.
THANK YOU, SlR.
( coughing )
HEFFRON.
HEY, HEFFRON,
YOU OKAY?
GENE, WHAT lS WlTH
THE HEFFRON BULLSHlT, HUH?
YOU KNOW MY NAME,
WHY DON'T YOU USE lT?
IT'S EDWARD, RlGHT?
EDWARD,
ARE YOU SERlOUS?
ONLY THE GODDAMN
NUNS CALL ME EDWARD.
HEY, LlSTEN,
I NEED TO KNOW WHETHER
YOU KEPT YOUR MORPHlNE
FROM HOLLAND.
NO, YOU ASKED ME
ALREADY, REMEMBER?
NO, I DON'T RECALL.
HEY.
GORDON, YOU WANT ME?
OH, YEAH, MORPHlNE.
3rd PLATOON PONlED
UP THE CONTRABAND.
YOU STlLL LOOKlNG
FOR SClSSORS?
YES, I AM.
PERCONTE.
DOC.
THANK YOU.
OH, AND YOU'D BETTER
CHECK ON JOE TOYE
OUT ON THE "O.P.".
HE'S MlSSlNG
SOMETHlNG.
THANKS.
YOU GUYS
OKAY?
THEY GOT HOT FOOD,
CAN YOU SMELL lT?
TOYE, ARE
YOU MlSSlNG
SOMETHlNG?
HOME.
ASK HlM TO
DANCE, DOC.
TOYE, SHOW
ME YOUR FEET.
YOU WATCH
THE GODDAMN
LlNE, McCLUNG.
WHERE ARE
YOUR BOOTS?
IN WASHlNGTON,
UP GENERAL
TAYLOR'S ASS.
I DON'T BELlEVE THlS.
I CAN MOVE BETTER
lN BARE FEET, DOC.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I TOOK 'EM OFF TO
DRY MY GODDAMN SOCKS.
THEY GOT BLOWN
TO HELL, OKAY?
WELL, WHAT'S
YOUR SlZE?
NlNE, JUST LlKE
EVERYBODY ELSE.
FRANK, YOU KEEP
CLEANlNG THOSE TEETH,
THE GERMANS WlLL
SEE YOU A MlLE AWAY.
SHOOT HlM DEAD.
( Perconte )
THAT'S RlGHT, PEE WEE,
YOU KEEP LAUGHlNG.
HEY, DOC,
MY STUFF.
OH, COME ON, DOC.
WHAT, YOU GOT
A DRUG STORE lN HERE?
NO, I OWN MY STUFF.
WHAT ARE YOU
LOOKlNG FOR?
SClSSORS,
THANK YOU, PERCONTE.
( Perconte )
MY GODDAMN SClSSORS.
SERGEANT GUARNERE.
MARLENE, lS THAT YOU?
HEY, DOC.
DOC, COME HERE.
U.S.O. PlCKlN' UP SYRETTES,
ALLEY, LlEBGOTT,
YOU GOT ANY?
NO, GOT USED lN
HOLLAND, DOC.
YOU AlN'T USlNG THlS
STUFF, ARE YOU, DOC?
I MEAN PERSONAL, LlKE?
COME ON.
( singing )
HEY, DOC,
I STlLL GOT THE lTCHlN'.
EVERY TlME I PEE
lT'S MURDER.
YEAH, I KNOW,
l'M SORRY,
BUT I JUST DON'T
HAVE PENlClLLlN FOR
YOUR PlROUETTE.
MY WHAT?
LlEUTENANT, MAKE SURE
YOU MOVE AROUND A LlTTLE.
GET YOUR BLOOD FLOWlNG.
I CAN'T FEEL MY FEET.
YEAH, WELL, THAT'S WHY
YOU'VE GOTTA MOVE AROUND
SO YOU DON'T
GET TRENCH FOOT.
SHOULD I TAKE
MY BOOTS OFF?
UH UH, ALL YOU GOTTA DO
lS JUST LOOSEN 'EM UP.
KEEP MOVlNG.
SERGEANT, l'M SORRY.
LOOK, I KNOW lT MUST
BE HELL BUT I CAN'T
HELP YOU, ALRlGHT.
JUST DRlNK
LOTS OF WATER.
WATER, lT'S PlSSlNG
THAT HURTS!
SHUT lT!
SHUT THE HELL UP!
WHAT'S GOlNG
ON HERE, BlLL?
WHO THE HELL'S SlNGlNG?
WELL, l'LL FlND
OUT, LlEUTENANT.
I'LL FlND OUT,
l'LL SHUT 'EM UP.
( gunshots )
Oh lord, grant that
I shall neVer seek
so much to be consoled,
as to console,
to be understood,
as to understand,
or to be loVed,
as to loVe
with all my heart.
WlTH ALL MY HEART.
( explosion )
( male )
MEDlC!
( Perconte )
OH, CHRlST!
PERCONTE,
YOU GETTlNG A JEEP?
I'M ON lT, DOC.
LOOK WHAT THEY
DlD TO MY LEG!
EASY C.P., EASY C.P.,
THlS lS PERCONTE.
SlSK HAS BEEN HlT
AND I NEED A JEEP.
I SAY lT AGAlN, l
NEED A JEEP NOW!
THEY'RE MOVlNG,
GODDAMNlT, WE
NEED lT NOW.
( explosion )
OKAY SlSK, lT
AlN'T THAT BAD,
AlN'T THAT BAD.
AlN'T THAT BAD?
AAAARGH!
PULL!
NO, DOC, SAVE
THE MORPHlNE, l
CAN MAKE lT.
I CAN MAKE lT,
SAVE lT, OKAY?
OKAY, ALRlGHT,
LET'S GET HlM OUT OF HERE.
( groaning )
WHERE'S THE
GODDAMN JEEP?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I HEAR lT.
AAAH, JESUS CHRlST!
OH, SKlNNY, YOU'VE
GOT BLOOD ALL OVER
MY TROUSERS.
I'M REAL SORRY, FRANK.
GET HlM UP.
DAMNlT, SKlNNY.
TELL SPlNA
I WENT lN FOR PLASMA.
GET HlM UP.
ALL THE TANKS,
ARTlLLERY,
ARE PULLED BACK TO HERE.
WE'VE GOT
NO BACK-UP BEYOND
BASTOGNE, THlS lS lT.
THE KRAUTS CAPTURED
THE 326th MEDlCAL
AND THEY TOOK EVERYBODY.
DOCTORS, MEDlCS,
THE WHOLE SHEBANG.
WE GOT NOTHlN'.
THEY'RE GlVlNG THE BOYS
HOOCH FOR THE PAlN.
AAAH!
HE TOOK A MORTAR HlT,
WATCH THE LEG.
YEAH, WATCH THE LEG.
GET HlM lN.
MOVE lT!
COMlNG THROUGH.
MORNlNG FELLAS.
OH, NO, NO, NO, HERE,
PUT HlM HERE.
( Paratrooper )
YES, MA'AM.
AAAH.
IS HE BAD?
NO, LOWER LEG WOUND,
NO MORPHlNE.
NURSE, HAVE YOU GOT
PLASMA I CAN--
WAlT, PLEASE.
HEY, WHAT'S GOlNG ON HERE,
WHY AREN'T THESE
MEN EVACUATED?
WE CAN'T EVACUATE,
WE'RE CUT OFF.
THlS lS AS FAR
AS lT GOES.
( Renee )
FAlTES ATTENTlON
DES PLASMA.
CA VA?
CE N'EST PAS GRAVE,
CE N'EST PAS URGENT.
I'M lN HEAVEN, DOC.
PAS ENCORE, DE MERCl.
NURSE?
THlS WAY.
I NEED MORPHlNE,
I NEED BANDAGES,
WHATEVER YOU'VE GOT.
OKAY, I CAN GlVE YOU
A LlTTLE, BUT NOT A LOT.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU CAN HAVE THlS,
DO YOU WANT THAT?
OUl, YOU GOT PLASMA?
A LlTTLE.
ARE YOU A SURGEON?
NO, WE DON'T
GOT NO SURGEON.
WHAT'S THlS?
ER, FROM THE BED.
WHAT, SHEETS?
YES, FOR BANDAGES.
OKAY.
VOlLA.
MERCl.
COMMENT VOUS
APPELEZ VOUS?
MY NAME lS RENEE.
I'M GENE,
EUGENE ROE.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
LOUlSlANA, HALF CAJUN.
ET TOl,
D'OU VlENS TU?
BASTOGNE.
CAN YOU GET ME
BACK TO THE LlNE?
SURE.
EUGENE.
CHOCOLAT.
POUR VOUS.
( Maloney )
BENEDlCTlO DEl
OMNlPOTENTlS PATRl ET FlLll
ET SPlRlTUS SANCTl
DESCENDAT SUPER VOS
ET MANEAT SEMPER.
AMEN.
( Paratroopers )
( Maloney )
FlGHT WELL FOR YOUR GOD
AND YOUR COUNTRY.
GOD BLESS YOU ALL,
AND STAY SAFE.
THAT'S lT, GUYS,
NOTHlNG MORE TO
WORRY ABOUT.
WE'RE GONNA DlE NOW,
WE'RE GONNA DlE lN
A STATE OF GRACE.
ISN'T THAT RlGHT, BABE?
BATTALlON WANT A
RECONNAlSSANCE PATROL.
KRAUT HUNTlNG.
ALRlGHT, l'LL GO,
TAKE THESE.
GlVE THE BOOTS
TO JOE TOYE, TELL
HlM THEY'RE A NlNE.
KEEP GOlNG, 'TlLL WE MAKE
SOME KlND OF CONTACT.
PEACOCK'S LEADlNG, RlGHT?
RlGHT.
ASSHOLE COULDN'T
FlND A SNOWBALL
lN A BLlZZARD.
THAT'S WHAT'S HAPPENlNG,
THAT'S THE ORDER.
SARGE?
YEAH, JULlAN.
LET ME BE
THE LEAD SCOUT.
BACK lN LlNE,
PRlVATE.
ALRlGHT, THAT'S lT,
LET'S MOVE OUT.
TACTlCAL COLUMNS,
GENTLEMEN.
DOC, DOC, lT'S
A COMBAT PATROL.
WHY DON'T
YOU STAY BACK
AND KEEP YOUR ASS
OUT OF TROUBLE, HUH?
YES, SERGEANT.
YEAH.
( Martin )
COME ON, HOOBLER,
PlCK lT UP.
( explosion )
RlGHT, MOVE ON.
GO.
FlRE!
GET DOWN!
JESUS.
SHlT!
BULL!
CHRlSTENSON!
UP ON LlNE!
JOHNNY!
WE GOT A MAN DOWN!
JACK, OVER HERE.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT?
KEEP STlLL, JULlAN!
WE'VE GOTTA
MAKE A MOVE!
I CAN GET HlM, SARGE.
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE!
ONE MAN DOWN, EASY!
COVERlNG FlRE!
( shouting )
EASY C.P.,
I HAVE ONE MAN DOWN!
OKAY, STAY THERE,
DON'T MOVE.
STOP MOVlNG ELSE
THEY'LL KEEP SHOOTlN'.
( gunshots )
WHAT'S HAPPENlNG, SlR?
WE'RE PULLlNG BACK,
WE MADE CONTACT.
I GOTTA GET
TO THE C.P.
DON'T MOVE!
STOP MOVlNG,
THEY'LL KEEP FlRlNG,
STOP MOVlNG!
JESUS CHRlST, FUCK.
JOHN, WHAT--?
PULL BACK,
WE GOTTA PULL BACK!
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE!
LET'S GO,
LET'S GO, LET'S GO!
MOVE!
GO!
STAY WlTH US,
STAY WlTH US!
HOLD ON, JULlAN,
LOOK AT ME,
STAY WlTH US!
HOLD ON, HOLD ON!
DON'T MOVE, JULlAN,
WE'RE COMlNG BACK!
WE'LL GET YOU OUT OF
HERE, JUST HOLD ON!
GO, LET'S GO!
( gunshots )
( male )
MOVE!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
WHERE THE HELL
ARE WE?!
( male )
STRAlGHT AHEAD,
STRAlGHT AHEAD!
DOC!
( male )
OKAY, CHRlSTENSON
SET lT UP ON THE ROCK.
( Luz )
EASY C.P., EASY C.P.,
LlGHTNlNG, OVER.
I NEED AN "A" JEEP
STANDlNG BY AT THE C.P.
OKAY, GOT YOU
A JEEP, DOC.
MARTlN!
( Martin )
SlR!
WHAT'S GOlNG ON?!
THEY GOT JULlAN!
HE'S STlLL ALlVE!
WE DON'T
KNOW THAT!
WE'VE GOTTA
GO GET HlM, SlR!
DlD YOU HlT AN
O.P. OR THElR LlNE?
THElR LlNE, SlR!
WE'VE GOTTA GO BACK, SlR,
GET JULlAN OUT OF THERE!
NO, FALL BACK!
( male )
WE LOST PEACOCK.
NO, HE'S BACK
AT THE C.P.
( Nixon )
COME ON, MARTlN,
FALL BACK!
GET HlM
OUT OF HERE!
LET'S UP AND GO!
( gunshots )
( Luz )
DOC, WE'VE GOTTA MOVE NOW, DOC,
COME ON, LET'S GO!
DOC, NOW,
LET'S GO!
( Martin )
MOVE!
LET'S GO!
FALL BACK!
( coughing )
WE COULDN'T GET
TO HlM, CAPTAlN.
WE TRlED, BABE TRlED,
WE COULDN'T GET TO HlM.
HEY, PEOPLE.
LET ME SlT lN HERE
WlTH YOU GUYS.
( coughing )
HEFFRON?
TOYE.
WHAT YOU
DOlNG OUT HERE?
THANKS FOR THE BOOTS,
DOC, DOlNG FlNE.
ARE YOU STlLL
HAVlNG TROUBLE
WlTH YOUR FEET?
SHOW ME,
LET ME SEE lT.
IT'S TRENCH
FOOT, TOYE.
IF lT TURNS GANGRENE,
YOU COULD LOSE lT.
I AlN'T COMlNG OFF
THE LlNE, DOC.
WELL, YOU GOTTA
STAY DRY.
MASSAGE YOUR FEET.
CHANGE SOCKS EVERY DAY,
AND DRY THE WET ONES
AROUND YOUR NECK.
TRY.
DO lT.
I'M WORKlNG ON lT.
OH, YOU SEEN
HEFFRON?
NO.
WHY?
HE AlN'T
lN HlS HOLE.
FUCK.
GOT YOU.
HEFFRON?
EDWARD.
EAT lT.
GOOD.
PERFECT.
I PROMlSED HlM,
lF HE GOT HlT,
I'D GET HlS STUFF
AND BRlNG lT TO
HlS MA, YOU KNOW?
NOW THE FUCKlNG KRAUTS
WlLL STRlP HlM.
HEY, NO,
lT'S OKAY.
IT'S NOT!
IT'S NOT OKAY.
WE SHOULD'VE
GOT TO HlM.
( coughing )
( gunshots )
HEY, WHAT DO YOU CALL
THOSE PEOPLE AGAlN?
THOSE CAJUN
HEALERS?
TRAlTEURS.
YOU KNOW, MY GRANDMA
WAS A TRAlTEURS.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER?
UH-HUH.
NO SHlT?
WELL, SHE WAS.
LAlD HER HANDS ON
PEOPLE AND CURED 'EM.
TOOK AWAY SlCKNESS,
CANCER, YOU NAME lT.
YOUR GRANDMA
DlD THAT?
WOW, YOU'RE
SHlTTlNG ME.
I REMEMBER SHE USED
TO PRAY A LOT.
YEAH, I GUESS
SHE HAD TO.
TALKED TO GOD ABOUT THE
PAlN SHE PULLED OUT.
ASKED HlM TO...
CARRY lT AWAY.
THAT'S WHAT
SHE DlD.
JESUS.
I'M STlLL TRYlNG TO
FlGURE WHY THEY PlCKED
ME FOR A MEDlC.
GOD KNOWS.
SNAP OF A FlNGER
AND JUST LlKE THAT
YOU'RE A MEDlC.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH
PLAYlNG DOCTOR.
HEY, HOW
ABOUT YOU?
JOE.
( airplanes flying oVerhead )
( cheering )
( gunshots
CEASE FlRE!
CEASE FlRE,
GODDAMNlT!
SERGEANT, I DON'T
UNDERSTAND, lT WAS
OUR OWN PLANES.
SHH!
C-47's.
THEY'RE
BRlNGlNG SUPPLlES,
lT'S A DROP.
IT'S A DROP,
COME ON!
( Lipton )
ALRlGHT, HELP THE DOC.
THE REST OF YOU
COME WlTH ME.
( male )
MEDlC!
SOMEONE GlVE US
A HAND HERE!
HELP, HELP!
( Renee )
THlS ONE THROUGH HERE.
NOW, VlTE!
( Renee )
LA PRESSlON EST SE
TROUVE A L'ARTERE.
OUl, D'ACCORD.
THE ARTERY, GOTTA
FlND THE ARTERY.
MOl, JE NE
LA TROUVE PAS!
ANNA!
JE NE LA TROUVE PAS!
WHERE DOES
SHE COME FROM?
THE BLACK GlRL?
THE CONGO.
HOW'D SHE
GET HERE?
JUST LlKE ME.
SHE CAME TO HELP.
CHOCOLAT?
HMM.
WHAT?
YOUR HANDS.
MY HANDS?
MM-HMM.
YOU'RE A
GOOD NURSE.
NO.
I NEVER WANT TO TREAT
ANOTHER WOUNDED MAN AGAlN.
I'D RATHER WORK
lN A BUTCHER'S SHOP.
BUT YOUR TOUCH...
CALMS PEOPLE.
THAT'S A GlFT
FROM GOD.
NO, lT'S NOT A GlFT.
GOD WOULD NEVER GlVE
SUCH A PAlNFUL THlNG.
( male )
NURSE!
WE NEED SOME HELP
OVER HERE!
GUY'S SHOT
THROUGH THE STOMACH.
( Renee )
HOW BAD lS lT?
OKAY, GET THlS
ONE lN FlRST.
( male )
YOU'LL BE ALRlGHT.
( Compton )
NOW WE KNOW
HOW THEY FELT.
WHAT?
WHO?
THE LEGlONNAlRES.
WHEN THEY WERE
WATCHlNG THE HUNS,
THE GOTHS,
THE VlSlGOTHS.
VlSlGOTHS?
JESUS CHRlST.
ER, BARBARlANS.
AH.
THEY CAME RlGHT
THROUGH HERE.
RlGHT THROUGH
THESE TREES,
JUST SWEEPlNG DOWN
TO BURN THE SHlT
OUT OF ROME.
THAT'S A HELL OF
A LONG RlDE.
SO WHAT,
WHAT'S COLLEGE
LlKE, BUCK?
YOU GOT TlME
TO HlT THE BOOKS
WlTH CHEERLEADERS
RUNNlNG THElR FlNGERS
THROUGH YOUR HAlR?
HELL, BABE, l
CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER.
( gunshot )
HEY, lT'S DOC.
SERGEANT.
HEFFRON.
LlEUTENANT.
WRAP UP.
NEVER CALLS ANYBODY
BY THElR NlCKNAME.
HE ONCE
CALLED
ME EDWARD.
IS THAT RlGHT?
EDWARD?
THAT'S YOUR NAME?
YEAH.
FUNNY, YOU
DON'T LOOK
LlKE AN EDWARD.
( coughing )
( wind blowing )
( tanks )
HEY, DOC.
IT'S GONNA GET
BUSY, PAL.
HOLD YOUR FlRE, BOYS.
DON'T LET 'EM
DRAW YOU OUT.
( male yelling )
HOLD YOUR FlRE!
STAY READY, BOYS.
WHAT THE HELL ARE
WE GONNA HlT THOSE
THlNGS WlTH, LlP?
HOLD YOUR FlRE.
GET READY, WALTER.
( explosion )
( male )
STAY lN YOUR HOLES, GUYS.
( gasping )
( male )
SMOKEY'S HlT, MEDlC!
HEY, EUGENE,
LET'S GO!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
OKAY, GO!
READY.
MEDlC!
DOC!
SMOKEY!
Hl, MO.
I GOT lT, l'M
KEEPlNG lT FOR YOU.
SMOKE!
I CAN'T FEEL
MY LEGS, GENE.
TAKE lT EASY.
MY FOOHOLE, GET
THE PLASMA, NOW!
HERE THEY COME!
( tanks )
YOU GOT 'EM?
I GOT 'EM, GO!
MACHlNE GUN OPEN FlRE!
OPEN FlRE, LEFT!
SERGEANT LlPTON!
DOC, WE GOTTA GET
THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
STAY WlTH US SMOKEY.
STAY WlTH US!
WE GOTTA GET THE
HELL OUT OF HERE!
( machine gun )
YOU READY?
ALRlGHT, GO!
STOP, WE'VE
GOTTA STOP.
ALRlGHT.
TAKE THE PLASMA.
HEY, HEY,
COME ON, WALT.
COME ON, BUDDY.
HURRY, DOC,
COME ON, DOC.
I'VE GOTTA GET
BACK TO THE LlNE.
OKAY, OKAY.
LlP?
YEAH, BUDDY.
YOU'RE STANDlNG
ON MY HAND.
SORRY, BUD.
LOOK, l'LL GET
YOU ANOTHER PURPLE
HEART FOR lT.
HEY!
HEY, GlVE
US A HAND.
I GOT YOU
A RlDE, DOC.
JONES!
GlVE lT HERE.
OKAY, PUT HlM HERE.
WHERE'S HlS TAG?
WHAT'S WRONG WlTH HlM?
PARALYZED.
WHAT?
HE'S PARALYZED.
CAN'T FEEL A THlNG.
IN THE NAME
OF THE FATHER,
OF THE SON
AND OF THE
HOLY SPlRlT.
AMEN.
EUGENE?
ARE YOU...
( male )
RENEE, I NEED
SOME HELP HERE.
ARE YOU ALRlGHT?
( male )
RENEE.
( coughing )
HERE YOU GO, MAN.
ONE FOR THE DOC.
SURE.
DOC?
BETTER THAN SlTTlNG DOWN
TO A CHRlSTMAS EVE DlNNER
OF TURKEY AND HOOCH
BACK AT THE DlVlSlON C.P.
DAMNED lF l
DON'T LlKE OLD
JOE DOMlNGUS'
RANClD-ASSED
BEANS BETTER.
HELLO, "EASY COMPANY".
( all )
HELLO, SlR.
GENERAL McAULlFFE
SENT A MESSAGE TO
THE ENTlRE DlVlSlON.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
YOUR PEOPLE WOULD
LlKE TO HEAR lT.
OH, THAT SHOULD BE
YOUR PREROGATlVE, SlR.
ALRlGHT.
MEN!
GENERAL McAULlFFE
WlSHES US ALL A
MERRY CHRlSTMAS.
WHAT'S MERRY ABOUT
ALL THlS, YOU ASK?
JUST THlS.
"WE'VE STOPPED COLD
EVERYTHlNG THAT'S
BEEN THROWN AT US
"FROM THE NORTH,
EAST, SOUTH AND WEST.
"NOW, TWO DAYS AGO
THE GERMAN COMMANDER
"DEMANDED OUR
HONORABLE SURRENDER
"TO SAVE THE U.S.A.
ENClRCLED TROOPS FROM
TOTAL ANNlHlLATlON.
"THE GERMAN COMMANDER
RECElVED THE FOLLOWlNG REPLY,
"TO THE GERMAN COMMANDER,
NUTS!"
( giggling )
"WE'RE GlVlNG OUR COUNTRY
AND OUR LOVED ONES AT HOME
"A WORTHY
CHRlSTMAS PRESENT,
"AND BElNG PRlVlLEGED
TO TAKE PART
"lN THlS GALLANT
FEAT OF ARMS,
"WE'RE TRULY MAKlNG
FOR OURSELVES...
A MERRY CHRlSTMAS."
MERRY CHRlSTMAS TO YOU
ALL AND GOD BLESS YOU.
( soldiers shouting )
... CHRlSTMAS, SlR.
( screaming )
NUTS!
( Germans singing
"Silent Night")
BlLL.
HUH?
PlCTURE OF MY GlRL.
GOOD LOOKlNG
BROAD, BUCK.
SHE'S...
SHE'S FlNlSHED
WlTH ME.
YEAH?
YEAH.
YEAH, SHE'S, ER...
JUST lN TlME FOR
CHRlSTMAS, HUH?
JUST lN TlME
FOR CHRlSTMAS.
OH SHlT!
I ALMOST FORGOT.
OH, OH.
LUCKY STRlKES,
MEANS FlNE TOBACCO.
WHERE THE HELL
DlD YOU GET THOSE?
MERRY CHRlSTMAS,
FELLAS.
GOTTA THANK
JOLLY OLD SAlNT LUZ.
OH, BEAUTlFUL.
THERE.
THERE YOU
GO, PENK.
I AM SHAKlNG
SO GODDAMN MUCH,
I FEEL LlKE
l'M DANClN'.
THERE YOU
GO, BUDDY.
THERE YOU GO.
FRANK, WHAT
ARE YOU DOlNG?
IT'S CHRlSTMAS,
PEE WEE.
HERE, FRANK.
WHAT lS lT?
LEMON POWDER
SNOW CONE.
PASS.
MERRY FUCKlNG CHRlSTMAS.
HARRY.
FlRE'S NOT
A GOOD lDEA.
JUST A COUPLE
OF MlNUTES.
WE'RE lN A DELL.
A DELL?
YOU MEAN WHERE
FAlRlES AND
GNOMES LlVE?
I SWEAR I THOUGHT
I COULD SMELL A FlRE.
I DlD
SMELL A FlRE.
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR MlND?
WELL, WE'RE
lN A DELL.
HUH?
DOWN!
CROSSFlRE!
OH, GOD NO!
AAARGH!
THlS lS
CAPTAlN NlOON.
I NEED AN "A" JEEP
FOR 2nd BATTALlON C.P.
STAY STlLL, HARRY.
( male )
HEY, DOC,
PUT THAT OUT!
REPEAT, "A" JEEP
FOR 2nd BATTALlON C.P.
MEDlC!
DOC!
COME ON, DOC.
IS HE HURT?
I DON'T KNOW.
MOVE, GET lN!
DOC!
I GOTTA GO.
EUGENE,
COME ON, GET UP.
THE CAPTAlN'S YELLlNG,
OKAY, GET UP,
NOT OKAY, LlE DOWN.
COME ON, MOVE!
JESUS CHRlST!
OH MY HAND,
MY GODDAMNED HAND!
ROE!
( screaming )
JESUS!
OKAY?
ROE?
( screaming )
STAY STlLL, HARRY.
( Nixon )
lT'S JUST A
SCRATCH, HARRY.
YOU'RE NOT
GETTlNG OUT OF
HERE THlS EASY.
JEEP'S ON lT'S WAY,
HANG TOUGH.
HERE'S A TOWEL.
( moaning )
TOWEL.
YEAH SURE.
I GOT MORPHlNE
lN MY POCKET,
GlVE lT TO HlM
U WANT lT?
OPPOSlTE THlGH.
AAAAH!
OKAY.
( Roe )
ELEVATE HlS HEAD.
GET HlM UP.
THERE YOU GO,
SOLDlER, TAKE THAT.
EUGENE,
GET YOURSELF
lNTO TOWN, GET
A HOT MEAL.
( male )
GET OUT QUlCK!
CLEAR THE ROAD!
( screaming )
GET OUT QUlCK!
STAY OUT OF THERE!
MEDlC!
GET YOUR ASS
OUT HERE!
COME ON!
EVERY HOUR,
ON THE HOUR,
ON THE RADlO,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHERE THE HELL YOU ARE.
EVERYTHlNG OKAY?
BABE?
YEAH.
HEY, HOW'D
YOU DO THAT?
YOU DlD THAT.
I'LL FlO lT UP.
HEY, GENE, YOU
CALLED ME BABE.
I DlD?
WHEN?
JUST NOW.
BABE...
I GUESS I DlD.
BABE.
HEFFRON, WATCH
THE GODDAMN LlNE.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNlCATlONS CENTER