Captions made possible by
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
WE HAD LOST SOME
VERY GOOD MEN THERE.
TOYE AND GUARNERE HAD
LOST THElR LEGS THERE.
GUARNERE--
GORDON WAS BADLY HlT.
A NUMBER OF OTHER PEOPLE
WERE KlLLED.
IT WAS A DlFFlCULT
SlTUATlON THERE.
I DON'T KNOW THE
EOACT AMOUNT OF MEN
THAT GOT KlLLED
lN THAT,
BUT SlO, SEVEN OF 'EM, WERE
REAL CLOSE FRlENDS OF MlNE.
SKlP MUCK DlED,
AND EUGENE ROE
CAME TO ME,
ABOUT 1 0 MlNUTES
AFTER HE WAS KlLLED,
AND HE WANTED ME TO SEE
lF I WANTED TO GO LOOK AT HlM,
AND I SAlD "NO, I WOULDN'T
BE ABLE TO STAND THAT",
SO, I DlDN'T
GO LOOK AT HlM.
AFTER BASTOGNE,
WE WENT TO HAGUENAU.
THERE WAS ANOTHER
PUSH THERE.
WE WANTED TO GET
SOME lDEA WHAT WAS
ACROSS THE RlVER THERE,
WHAT KlND
OF STRENGTH THEY HAD.
YOU HAVE A FEELlNG YOU'RE
GONNA LlVE THROUGH THE WAR.
YOU HAVE A FEELlNG lT'S
STARTlNG TO EASE OFF.
YOU CAN'T ACCOUNT FOR lT,
lT'S JUST A GUT FEELlNG,
BUT EVERYBODY
HAD THAT FEELlNG.
I BELlEVE I MlGHT BE
ABLE TO LlVE THROUGH,
SO, WALK CAREFULLY,
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
( explosion )
( Webster )
THE 1 01 st AlRBORNE
HAD BEEN MADE FAMOUS
BY WHAT lT DlD lN
"THE BATTLE OF THE BULGE".
NEWSPAPERS
CALLED THEM
"THE BATTERED BASTARDS
OF BASTOGNE".
THEY'D BEEN THROUGH
HELL ON EARTH,
AND WERE NOW PULLlNG lNTO
THE COMPARATlVE PARADlSE
OF HAGUENAU,
THE SOUNDS
OF THE WAR
STlLL COMlNG FROM
JUST ACROSS THE RlVER.
I HAD
MlSSED BASTOGNE.
ALL I KNEW WAS WHAT
l'D READ AND HEARD
AROUND THE
REPLACEMENT DEPOT.
THAT WE HAD BROKEN
THE BACK OF THE ENEMY,
AND THE WAR
WOULD SOON BE OVER.
THANKS FOR
THE LlFT.
( Webster )
WHEN I WAS FlNALLY ABLE
TO REJOlN "EASY COMPANY",
THEY LOOKED NOTHlNG
LlKE THE HEROES,
WHO HAD JUST HELPED
WlN THE WAR.
GEORGE LUZ!
YEAH?
IT'S ME.
OH, COME ON, I HAVEN'T
BEEN GONE THAT LONG.
JESUS, YES,
YOU HAVE.
NOW, LOOK
WHAT l'VE FOUND.
HEY, GUYS.
SERGEANT MARTlN.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT, PRlVATE?
OH, l'M SORRY, SlR.
MY NAME'S
DAVlD WEBSTER.
I JUST GOT BACK
FROM THE HOSPlTAL.
GOOD FOR YOU.
WHERE'S THE REST
OF THE GUYS?
THlS lS EVERYBODY.
OH, COME ON,
SERGEANT MARTlN.
THlS CAN'T
BE EVERYBODY.
WHAT ABOUT, UH...
HOOBLER,
WHERE'S HE?
LlEUTENANT FOLEY,
2nd PLATOON LOST MORE
GUYS THAN WE DlD.
THEY'RE REALLY
SHORT-HANDED.
YEAH, RlGHT,
REPORT TO
2nd, WEBSTER.
THEY'LL FlND A
PLACE FOR YOU.
NEOT TRUCK UP, WEBSTER,
YOU'LL FlND 2nd, MOVE.
HEY, GUYS.
SOME LlEUTENANT TOLD
ME TO REPORT TO 2nd.
YOUR NAME'S
JACKSON, RlGHT?
THAT'S RlGHT.
WHO'S LEADlNG
THE PLATOON?
SERGEANT MALARKEY lS.
WHAT, NO
OFFlCERS?
I GUESS YOU
DlDN'T HEAR.
NO, WHAT'S THAT?
THEY'RE MAKlNG MALARKEY
A LlEUTENANT.
HE'S ON THE
FAST TRACK NOW.
REALLY, THAT'S GREAT.
YEAH, lSN'T lT?
YEAH.
JACKSON, HELP ME
UP, WlLL YOU?
SO, UH...
YOU COME FROM
THE HOSPlTAL?
YEAH.
MUST'VE LlKED
THAT HOSPlTAL.
'CAUSE, UH, WE LEFT
HOLLAND FOUR MONTHS AGO.
WELL, I WASN'T THERE
THE WHOLE TlME.
THERE WAS REHABlLlTATlON,
THEN THE REPLACEMENT DEPOT.
WELL, l'M SURE YOU
TRlED TO BUST OUT
AND HELP US
lN BASTOGNE, WEB.
I DON'T KNOW HOW l
WOULD HAVE DONE THAT.
THAT'S FUNNY, 'CAUSE
POPEYE FOUND A WAY.
SO DlD ALLEY,
RlGHT, BACK
lN HOLLAND?
AND GUARNERE AND...
YEAH, WHERE
lS GUARNERE?
HE STlLL YOUR
PLATOON SERGEANT?
NO.
( male )
LET'S GO!
HE GOT HlT.
YEAH?
YEAH,
BlLL GOT HlT.
BLEW HlS
WHOLE LEG OFF.
( male )
1 st PLATOON,
MOVlNG OUT!
OKAY, SPREAD OUT.
HOLD ALONG THlS LlNE
'TlLL I FlGURE OUT
WHERE WE'RE GOlNG.
SARGE?
( explosions )
WHAT'S THE MATTER
THERE, WEBSTER?
NERVOUS lN
THE SERVlCE?
OH, NO.
NO, l'M FlNE,
SARGE.
WHY DON'T YOU GO TALK
TO CAPTAlN SPElRS.
MAKE SURE HE WANTS
YOU WlTH US.
CAPTAlN SPElRS?
WHAT HAPPENED TO
CAPTAlN WlNTERS?
HE'S RUNNlNG THE
WHOLE BATTALlON NOW.
GO.
( Webster )
SO, "EASY COMPANY" HAD
A NEW C.O. TO GO ALONG
WlTH ALL THE
OTHER NEW FACES.
THE GUYS I KNEW
WERE ElTHER GONE,
OR VERY DlFFERENT
FROM WHAT I REMEMBERED.
I WAS A VETERAN OF "D DAY"
AND "MARKET GARDEN",
AND HAD BEEN WlTH THE COMPANY
SlNCE lTS FORMATlON,
BUT, NOW, BECAUSE
I HAD MlSSED BASTOGNE,
I WAS TREATED
AS A REPLACEMENT
AND FELT LlKE I WAS
STARTlNG ALL OVER AGAlN.
HEY, LOOK WHO lT lS.
NlCE DlGS,
HUH, LlP?
YEAH.
SERGEANT LlPTON?
HEY, LOOK
WHAT I FOUND.
FEELlNG ALRlGHT?
THERE YOU GO.
HE'S GOT PNEUMONlA.
I'M SORRY TO
HEAR THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU
SORRY ABOUT?
HE'S ALlVE,
HE'S GOT A COUCH,
A GODDAMN BLANKET,
SNUG AS A BUG.
YEAH.
SERGEANT MALARKEY SAlD
TO CHECK WlTH THE C.O.
IF I SHOULD BE
lN 2nd PLATOON.
HAVE A SEAT, WEBSTER,
WE'LL GET YOU SlTUATED.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN SlCK?
LONG ENOUGH.
( Winters )
HE WANTS US TO
CROSS THE RlVER.
( Nixon )
YEAH, I BET THAT
WATER'S COLD.
SHOULD BE ABLE TO
GET YOU SOME BOATS.
HAD TO BE A FULL MOON.
SO MUCH FOR THE
COVER OF DARKNESS.
IT'S GONNA LEAVE
THE PATROL EOPOSED.
IS THlS THE COMPANY
C.P. FOR "EASY"?
YES, SlR.
AS YOU WERE.
LlEUTENANT JONES
LOOKlNG FOR CAPTAlN SPElRS.
HE'S ON HlS WAY, SlR,
WHY DON'T YOU SlT DOWN?
CAN YOU GET
ME A COFFEE?
WOULD YOU LlKE
A COFFEE, SlR?
NO, THANK YOU.
ALRlGHT.
WHAT PLATOON
ARE YOU lN?
OH, WE'RE ABOUT
TO FlND THAT OUT.
YOU GOT ANY SOAP?
I NEED A SHAVE.
I'LL SEND
SOME DOWN.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA DO FOR THlS?
I'M GONNA LET SPElRS
HANDLE lT.
RlGHT.
( Lipton )
CAP'N SPElRS, SlR,
THlS lS
LlEUTENANT JONES.
LlSTEN, FOR
CHRlSSAKE,
WlLL YOU GO BACK
lN THE BACK
AND SACK OUT?
THERE'S SOME BEDS
BACK THERE WlTH
FRESH SHEETS.
I WlLL, SlR.
JUST TRYlNG TO MAKE
MYSELF USEFUL, SlR.
LlSTEN UP.
REGlMENT WANTS
A PATROL FOR PRlSONERS.
THlS ONE COMES STRAlGHT
FROM COLONEL SlNK,
SO, lT'S NOT MY lDEA.
SlNCE THE RlVER'S THE
MAlN LlNE OF RESlSTANCE,
WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO CROSS lT
TO GET TO THEM.
WHAT DO WE
NEED TO DO?
THERE'S A THREE-STORY
BUlLDlNG ON THE
ENEMY SlDE.
UP THE EMBANKMENT.
WE KNOW
lT'S OCCUPlED.
YOU CAN HAVE 1 5 MEN.
THlNK VERY HARD ABOUT
WHO YOU WANNA LEAD THE PATROL.
YOU'LL NEED A LEAD
SCOUT, A TRANSLATOR.
I'VE GOT THE
ENTlRE BATTALlON
ON COVERlNG FlRE.
WHEN?
TONlGHT, 01 00.
YES, SlR.
SPElRS, I WANT THlS ONE
TO BE AS FOOL PROOF,
AND AS SAFE
AS POSSlBLE.
YEAH, DON'T TAKE
ANY CHANCES ON THlS ONE.
WE'RE TOO FAR
ALONG FOR THAT.
SPElRS, WANT TO DlSCUSS
WHO MlGHT GO ALONG?
WHO ARE YOU?
LlEUTENANT JONES, SlR.
RlGHT, OUR WEST POlNTER.
YES, SlR.
WHEN'D YOU
GRADUATE?
JUNE 6th, SlR.
JUNE 6th,
OF LAST YEAR?
"D DAY",
YES, SlR.
( chuckling )
ALRlGHT.
DON'T GET HURT.
SlR, l'D LlKE TO VOLUNTEER
FOR THE PATROL.
SPElRS, TALK TO
YOU lN AN HOUR.
YEAH.
LlEUTENANT JONES.
YOU THlNK A NONCOM
COULD LEAD THlS?
I CAN THlNK OF
A FEW POSSlBlLlTlES.
MARTlN,
MALARKEY, GRANT?
( Lipton )
HONESTLY, SlR, MOST OF THE
N.C.O.s COULD USE A REST.
CAPTAlN, REQUEST PERMlSSlON
TO GO ON THE PATROL.
THERE'S YOUR ANSWER.
NO.
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY EOPERlENCE.
REPORT TO
2nd PLATOON.
YES, SlR.
TELL...
TELL HEFFRON,
RAMlREZ, AND McCLUNG
THEY'RE GOlNG.
YES, SlR.
SlR, THlS lS,
PRlVATE WEBSTER.
SlR, l'M PRlVATE WEBSTER
FROM 1 st PLATOON.
I JUST GOT BACK
FROM THE HOSPlTAL,
AND LlEUTENANT FOLEY
TOLD ME TO GO TO 2nd,
BUT SERGEANT MALARKEY
SAlD l--
FlNE, 2nd.
TAKE, UH...
( Lipton )
LlEUTENANT JONES.
LlEUTENANT, O.P. TWO.
COME ON.
( gunshots )
ARE THERE OTHER
OFFlCERS lN
THE PLATOON?
NO, SlR.
JUST SERGEANT MALARKEY.
BUT THEY TELL ME
HE'S GETTlNG A
BATTLEFlELD COMMlSSlON.
MAYBE HE'LL BE
ASSlSTlNG YOU, SlR.
( Kiehn )
WHO'S THAT?
WEBSTER?
THAT'S RlGHT,
HOW YOU DOlNG,
SERGEANT KlEHN?
Hl, WEBSTER.
HEY, SARGE.
HEY, LOOK WHAT
WE JUST SCROUNGED.
WE GOT SOME SPUDS.
HEY, O.P. TWO,
THlS WAY?
SHlT, MOVE! GO!
SHlT, THEY
SPOTTED US.
IS THAT lT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THlNK SO.
GO, GO, GO!
COME ON, COME ON.
( male )
ALL CLEAR!
OKAY.
( explosion )
WAlT, WAlT, lT
WAS HEFFRON,
McCLUNG, AND--
RAMlREZ,
COME ON.
RlGHT.
HEY, GUYS,
THlS TAKEN?
GO AHEAD.
SERGEANT, THlS lS
LlEUTENANT JONES.
JUST ASSlGNED
TO 2nd PLATOON.
MALARKEY,
PLATOON SERGEANT.
CONGRATULATlONS
ON THE BATTLEFlELD
COMMlSSlON.
THE WHAT?
THEY'RE MAKlNG YOU
AN OFFlCER, NO?
ME, NO.
YOU MUST BE THlNKlNG
OF 1 st SERGEANT LlPTON.
MY MlSTAKE.
SO, YOU'RE WlTHOUT
A PLATOON LEADER?
NO, NOT ANY MORE,
LlEUTENANT.
RlGHT.
SO, DO YOU WANNA
lNTRODUCE ME TO THE MEN?
WELL, SOME ARE
SLEEPlNG DOWNSTAlRS,
AND THE REST
ARE RlGHT HERE.
SERGEANT, A
PATROL'S BElNG
PLANNED FOR TONlGHT,
01 00 HOURS,
ACROSS THE RlVER.
REGlMENT WANTS P.O.W.s
FOR lNTERROGATlON.
WHAT'S THE SlTUATlON?
HEY, WEB.
WHAT?
COME HERE.
I WANNA TALK
TO YOU FOR A
SECOND, COME HERE.
WHY?
YOU WANT
SOME COFFEE?
NO.
1 5.
1 5 WHAT?
SlNCE "D DAY".
ANY MORTARS?
60s, OUT BACK.
IS THlS KlD OUT OF
HlGH SCHOOL YET?
HE'S OUT OF
WEST POlNT.
WEST POlNT?
ISN'T THAT
WHERE lKE WENT?
YEAH, HE ACTUALLY
GRADUATED WlTH HlS SON.
SHlT, SO, UH...
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THlS PATROL THlNG?
UH, NOTHlNG.
OH, COME ON, WEB,
YOU GOTTA KNOW SOMETHlNG.
I DON'T.
BULLSHlT.
YOU WERE THERE,
RlGHT, AT THE C.P.?
THlS lS A PRlSONER
SNATCH, RlGHT?
HEY, CHUCK,
LlSTEN TO THlS.
COME ON, WEBSTER,
SPlLL lT.
CAPTAlN SPElRS
lS TO PlCK 1 5 MEN.
MM-HMM.
LlEUTENANT JONES
WANTS TO BE ONE OF THEM.
I SAY LET
THE KlD GO.
HE COULD USE
THE EOPERlENCE.
PROBABLY COULD FlND
14 REPLACEMENTS
TO HELP HlM OUT.
I TAKE lT THlS
WAS ALREADY AN OUTPOST
WHEN YOU ARRlVED?
MMM.
THERE WERE SOME DOGlES
FROM THE 79th lNFANTRY,
BUT THEY LEFT
lN A HURRY.
WHAT'S THE REPORT
ON ENEMY ACTlVlTY?
EOPECT SOME FLARES,
A FEW MORTARS AT NlGHT.
SCATTERED 88s,
SNlPERS DURlNG THE DAY.
YEAH, WE DODGED
SOME MORTARS ON
OUR WAY lN.
MMM.
THEY ALSO GOT SOME
SORT OF RAlLROAD
GUN BACK THERE.
SHELLS ABOUT THE SlZE
OF A DEUCE AND A HALF.
SOUNDS LlKE A
FRElGHT TRAlN WHEN
ONE COMES OVER.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T
MADE ANY ATTEMPTS
TO CROSS THE RlVER?
NO.
THEY HAVE ROOFS
OVER THElR HEADS, SlR,
JUST LlKE US.
I DON'T THlNK ANYBODY
WANTS TO DO ANYTHlNG STUPlD
AT THlS POlNT, RlGHT?
WHY ARE YOU
HOLDlNG OUT ON ME?
I KNOW YOU KNOW.
JUST GlVE US
THE NAMES, WEB.
WHO?
THERE ARE
THREE MEN,
HERE lN THlS ROOM,
THAT THEY THlNK
SHOULD BE ON
THE PATROL.
WHO?
WELL, lF I TELL YOU, YOU
CAN'T LET ON THAT YOU KNOW.
YOUR SECRET'S SAFE, WEB.
WHO lS lT?
YEAH, HEFFRON.
AH, SHlT!
McCLUNG.
AND YOU.
HE WANT ANY OTHER
GUYS FROM ANY
OTHER PLATOON?
NO, NO,
I DON'T KNOW.
NOT THAT
I KNOW OF.
LOOK, THAT'S
ALL I KNOW,
l'M SORRY.
SO, lT'S McCLUNG,
HEFFRON, AND RAMlREZ.
I'LL TELL THEM.
I JUST NEED YOU
TO POlNT--
LlSTEN UP,
GOT SOME BAD NEWS.
THERE lS A PATROL
SET FOR TONlGHT.
AND SO FAR,
SPElRS WANTS McCLUNG--
WE KNOW.
YEAH, WE JUST
FUCKlNG HEARD.
WEBSTER HERE
TOLD US.
( phone ringing )
"EASY", WHlTE.
YEAH, UH-HUH.
OKAY.
ALRlGHT, OUT.
THE P.X. RATlONS
JUST CAME lN.
INCLUDlNG,
WlNTER SHOE PACS.
BEAUTlFUL.
YEAH, FlNALLY,
RlGHT.
GOOD OF 'EM, NOW WE'RE
lN A NlCE WARM HOUSE.
ALSO, WE
GET SHOWERS.
MMM.
( explosion )
ALRlGHT, LET'S MOVE!
CLEAR lT OUT!
GOD, MOVE, MOVE!
INCOMlNG!
COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON, GO!
STAY DOWN!
STAY LOW, STAY LOW!
( laughing )
( Malarkey )
SHOWERS, LET'S
GO, COME ON.
( explosion )
( male )
SOMEBODY'S
BEEN HlT!
WHAT HAPPENED?
CASUALTY.
WHO lS lT?
BlLL KlEHN.
I JUST LEFT HlM.
I WAS ON
MY WAY BACK.
( Webster )
lN WAR, SOLDlERS
SOMETlMES DlE
IN THE FEVER PlTCH
OF A FlREFlGHT
OR BY ARTlLLERY WHEN THEY'RE
HUDDLED lN A FOOHOLE.
BlLL KlEHN, A
TOCCOA MAN,
WAS KlLLED BECAUSE HE WAS
CARRYlNG A SACK OF POTATOES
FROM ONE BUlLDlNG
lNTO ANOTHER.
IN THE WRONG PLACE
AT THE WRONG TlME.
HE WAS DEAD BEFORE DOC
ROE EVEN HEARD THE CALL
FOR A MEDlC.
GET HlM OUT OF
HERE, WlLL YOU?
HEY, LET'S
GO, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
YEAH, OKAY.
DlD YOU
KNOW HlM WELL?
NO, NOT REALLY.
McCLUNG.
THANKS.
MALARKEY.
( whispering )
Jackson, you, and Liebgott,
Powers, Wynn, and Webster.
Alright?
2nd PLATOON, ON ME.
ALRlGHT, l'M
LEADlNG THlS PATROL.
C.O. WANTS GRANT,
LlEBGOTT, WYNN,
JACKSON, SHlFTY,
FROM 3rd PLATOON,
AND WEBSTER.
THEY WANT ANYONE
FROM 1 st?
NO.
IS THERE ANYONE
THEY DON'T WANT
FROM 2nd?
JESUS CHRlST.
THAT LlST SOUNDS
LlKE EVERYBODY TO ME.
IT'S ALWAYS
2nd PLATOON.
I SWEAR TO GOD,
lF WE WERE DOWN
TO THREE GUYS,
THEY'D STlLL
WANT US FOR lT.
I CAN'T BELlEVE
THEY'RE GONNA MAKE
MALARKEY LEAD lT.
CHRlST, HE ONLY LOST
HlS FlVE BEST FRlENDS.
WHAT THE
FUCK'S HE
GOTTA LlVE FOR?
HAS lT BEEN A LONG
TlME SlNCE YOUR LAS
COME ON.
( male )
lS lT HOT WATER
OR COLD?
COME ON, HURRY
UP, WlLL YA?
ALRlGHT.
I GUESS I DON'T
REALLY NEED A SHOWER.
I DON'T ElTHER.
LlEUTENANT?
YEAH.
YOU STlLL WANNA GET
YOUR O.D.s DlRTY?
OF COURSE.
I WAS JUST THlNKlNG.
SERGEANT MALARKEY'S
REALLY lN NO CONDlTlON
TO BE ON THlS PATROL,
AND MAYBE lF YOU OFFERED,
YOU COULD GO lN HlS PLACE.
BElNG THAT YOU
ARE AN OFFlCER.
NO, THEY WANT SOMEONE
WlTH EOPERlENCE.
THE GUYS THEY PlCKED
HAVE PLENTY OF THAT.
( Webster )
LlEUTENANT JONES WANTED
TO EOPERlENCE COMBAT
BEFORE THE
WAR WAS OVER.
DON MALARKEY HAD BEEN
ON THE FRONT LlNES
EVERY TlME " EASY COMPANY"
HAD SEEN ACTlON SlNCE " D DAY".
IF lT WAS POSSlBLE FOR THEM TO
SWlTCH PLACES FOR THE PATROL,
IT WOULD BE A SMALL
MOMENT OF JUSTlCE,
AS WELCOME AS A HOT SHOWER
AND A FRESH UNlFORM.
THE DEClSlON, THOUGH,
WAS NOT THElRS TO MAKE.
GODDAMNlT, JOHNNY,
YOU'RE BREAKlNG MY HEART,
I'M TELLlNG YOU.
COME ON, GEORGE,
JUST GlVE ME, I DON'T
KNOW, 1 0, 1 5 BARS.
HERE YOU GO.
JUlCY FRUlT,
HAPPY?
WE JUST GOT
A REPORT OF
MOVEMENT.
1 st SERGEANT LlPTON
WANTS YOU TO LAY A
FEW BAZOOKA ROUNDS
INTO A HOUSE
ACROSS THE RlVER.
YOU'D THlNK WE COULD
GET AT LEAST ONE
HERSHEY BAR FROM THE...
YOU'RE 1 st PLATOON
AT HEART.
JESUS, COBB,
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH.
WHOA,
HERSHEY BARS.
JESUS CHRlST.
WAlT YOUR TURN,
LlEBGOTT.
YEAH, WHO ARE
THEY FOR?
NOT YOU, LlEB.
OH, COME ON,
GEORGE, ONE BAR.
NO, THERE'S NOT
ENOUGH TO GO AROUND.
CAP'N SPElRS HERE?
DOWN BY THE
RlVER, SlR.
HEY, BlG MOUTH,
GlVE THE KlD A
HERSHEY BAR, HUH?
YOU GOTTA BE
SHlTTlN' ME.
WHAT'S UP, GUYS?
I LlKE WHAT YOU DlD
WlTH THE PLACE, GEORGE.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH,
I DlD GOOD, HUH?
HOW YOU FEELlNG?
AS LONG AS YOU KEEP
YOUR HANDS OFF MY
ASS l'LL BE FlNE.
HAVE A HERSHEY.
THANKS.
HEY, HE GETS
A FUCKlN' HERSHEY BAR?
WELL, HE GOT SHOT
lN THE ASS.
DlD I TELL YOU TO
STlCK YOUR BlG ASS
OUT lN THE WlND?
NO, BUT l
EOPECT A LlTTLE
SYMPATHY FROM YOU.
RlGHT?
I SHOULD
RUB lT FOR YOU?
HEY, CAN YOU
BELlEVE THlS GUY?
TRY TO GET HlM OUT
OF THE FUCKlNG WAR,
HE COMES STRAlGHT BACK.
YEAH, WELL,
THAT'S NOT
WHAT I HEARD.
I HEARD THE KRAUTS
ARE FlNlSHED.
YEAH, WELL,
JUST TO MAKE SURE,
WE'VE GOTTA ROW ACROSS
THE FUCKlNG RlVER TONlGHT,
GRAB A FEW,
AND ASK 'EM lN PERSON.
ARE YOU KlDDlNG ME?
WlSH I WAS,
WELCOME BACK, FRANK.
YEAH, OH, JESUS,
THAT REMlNDS ME, WEB.
I NEED YOU TO RUN THESE
TO O.P. TWO FOR ME.
GRENADE LAUNCHERS FOR
THE NlGHT PATROL, HUH?
ANY DAY NOW, WEB,
THERE YOU GO.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT,
SEND THESE TOO.
DlD YOU HEAR WHAT HAPPENED
ON "D COMPANY'S" PATROL
LAST NlGHT?
WHAT?
REPLACEMENT LlEUTENANT
BLEW HlS FOOT OFF.
STEPPED ON
A SCHU MlNE.
FRESH lN
FROM WEST POlNT.
HAD TO COME BACK
EMPTY HANDED.
NO SHlT.
MAYBE HE'S A FRlEND
OF YOURS, LlEUTENANT.
HEY, VEST, WHAT
YOU GOT lN THERE?
MORE HERSHEY BARS
AND LUCKY STRlKES
FOR YOU REAR
ECHELON FUCKS
TO HOARD, HUH?
( Luz )
HEY, HEY, COBB,
WlTH THE MOUTH, PLEASE.
THE KlD'S JUST TRYlNG
TO DO HlS JOB, ALRlGHT?
JESUS CHRlST.
YOU KNOW WHAT,
TO HELL WlTH lT.
COUNT 'EM UP, VEST.
I GOTTA GO
BLAST THlS HOUSE.
YOU HAPPY NOW?
YOU COMlNG, PERCO?
MAKE YOURSELF USEFUL,
WATCH THlS SHlT FOR ME.
WEB, YOU'RE
COMlNG WlTH ME.
( Jones )
SERGEANT, lS CAPTAlN SPElRS
GONNA BE WHERE YOU'RE HEADED?
SAME VlClNlTY, YEAH.
ALRlGHT, THEN
l'LL JOlN YOU.
WHERE ARE
WE GOlNG?
TO THE HOUSE
I GOTTA BLAST.
CAPTAlN WlNTERS
GONNA BE WlTH HlM?
( Luz )
JESUS, LOOK, l
DON'T KNOW, MAYBE.
THEN l'M COMlNG TOO.
ALRlGHT, COME ON,
GUYS, PLEASE.
TAKE lT EASY, l'VE
BEEN HERE ALL FUCKlNG DAY.
GlVE ME A BAR.
I'M SUPPOSED
TO WATCH THESE.
( Perconte )
COME ON, YOU DON'T EVEN
SMOKE ClGARETTES, DAMNlT.
COME ON,
I GOT A WOUNDED ASS.
( Winters )
DlD lNTELLlGENCE GlVE YOU
ANY lNFORMATlON ON THE C.P.?
THlRD HOUSE
ON THE LEFT.
AS SOON AS OUR MEN
ARE BACK lN THE BOATS,
I WANT A QUAD 50
OPENlNG UP.
( Jones )
CAP'N WlNTERS?
ABOUT THE PATROL.
I FEEL THAT I SHOULD GO
ON THE PATROL, SlR.
I KNOW I COULD USE
THE EOPERlENCE.
DENlED,
ANYTHlNG ELSE?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
LEAD THAT PATROL,
LlEUTENANT JONES.
PERMlSSlON
TO SPEAK, SlR.
GO ON, LlEUTENANT.
IT LOOKS LlKE
SERGEANT MALARKEY
COULD USE A BREAK, SlR.
I'VE DlSCUSSED lT
WlTH HlM AND HE SAlD
THAT HE DlD NOT MlND
IF I TOOK HlS PLACE
ON THE PATROL.
THAT WAS NlCE
OF HlM.
CAPTAlN WlNTERS.
YES.
I'D REALLY LlKE TO BE
ON THAT PATROL, SlR.
IF lT'S TRUE
THE KRAUTS
ARE FlNlSHED,
I HAVEN'T REALLY
DONE ANYTHlNG
EOCEPT DELlVER MAlL
AND TYPE
MORNlNG REPORTS.
ABSOLUTELY.
THANK YOU,
CAPTAlN.
HE'S GOT A
POlNT ABOUT
SERGEANT MALARKEY.
YEAH, A POlNT.
FlNE, YOU CAN GO.
THERE'LL BE A BRlEFlNG,
C.P. 1 700.
YES, SlR.
SO, WHO DO YOU
HAVE lN MlND
LEADlNG THlS THlNG,
IF NOT MALARKEY?
COME ON, HE CAN'T
BE LEADlNG.
I'M NOT SURE
WHAT THEY DEClDED.
NO WAY.
NOT ON HlS
FlRST DAY.
WELL, DO YOU SEE ANY
OTHER OFFlCER HERE?
WHAT?
THEY CALL
YOU GUYS, TOO?
SO, WHO'S lN CHARGE
OF THlS BULLSHlT?
NO, HE AlN'T.
WELL, lF HE AlN'T,
lT'S YOU, CHUCK.
OR SHlFTY OR MO.
WELL, THAT'D BE BETTER.
1 0, HUTT.
AT EASE.
GENTLEMEN.
SlR. SlR.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
WE'VE ASSEMBLED
1 5 OF YOU HERE
FOR THlS
PRlSONER SNATCH
TONlGHT, 01 00.
JUST A COUPLE
OF POlNTS.
SECURED FOUR RUBBER BOATS
TO GET YOU ACROSS THE RlVER.
LlEUTENANT JONES HERE
lS THE RANKlNG OFFlCER,
AND HE'LL BE ALONG
AS AN OBSERVER.
SERGEANT MARTlN HERE
WlLL LEAD THE PATROL
IN SERGEANT
MALARKEY'S PLACE.
THE WHOLE BATTALlON
WlLL BE COVERlNG
YOUR WlTHDRAWAL.
WE'VE lDENTlFlED
TARGETS, WE'VE PLANNED
FlRE FOR 'EM.
WE HEAR THESE
WHlSTLES,
WE OPEN UP.
SO DON'T BLOW
'EM 'TlLL YOU'RE
BACK lN THE BOATS
WlTH YOUR PRlSONERS.
AND lF THE HOUSE
TURNS OUT TO
BE EMPTY, SlR?
IT WON'T,
BUT lN ANY CASE,
WE KNOW lT'S AN OUTPOST
AND WANT lT DESTROYED,
SO, YOU HAVE TO LAY
SOME DEMO ON A TlME DELAY.
YOU HAVE TO
MOVE FAST BUT
CAREFULLY.
PUT A PERlMETER
AROUND THE HOUSE.
ONCE THAT'S lN PLACE,
GET YOUR RlFLE GRENADES
IN THE FlRST
FLOOR WlNDOW.
GET YOUR ASSAULT
TEAM lN QUlCK.
OKAY, GOOD,
UNDERSTOOD?
REMEMBER, lT'S
ABOUT PRlSONERS.
DON'T POP THE FlRST
THlNG THAT MOVES.
CLEAR?
( all )
YES, SlR.
GOOD.
PlCKED YOUR
ASSAULT TEAM?
McCLUNG, SlSK,
COBB, GARClA.
AND WEBSTER,
AS TRANSLATOR.
THE REST OF YOU GUYS, A BASE
OF FlRE WlTH SERGEANT GRANT.
YOU SPEAK GERMAN,
RlGHT, WEBSTER?
YEAH,
A LlTTLE BlT.
GOOD.
THAT'S MY TEAM, SlR.
QUESTlONS?
( all )
NO, SlR.
GOOD.
GOOD LUCK.
( all )
THANK YOU, SlR.
1 0, HUTT!
AS YOU WERE,
CARRY ON.
A LlTTLE GERMAN?
HlS GERMAN'S
AS GOOD AS MlNE.
HEY, JACKSON,
YOU NEED THlS.
THANKS.
CAN YOU BELlEVE
THAT GUY?
WEBSTER, TRlES TO
GET OUT OF EVERYTHlNG.
WHATEVER.
I WANT FOUR MEN
ON EACH BLOCK.
FOUR MEN
TO GO lN.
FOUR MEN ON THE LEFT FLANK,
FOUR MEN ON THE RlGHT.
SlR?
YES?
LlEBGOTT AND
l, WE BOTH
SPEAK GERMAN.
YEAH?
YOU SAlD 1 5 MEN,
THERE ARE 1 6 OF US,
INCLUDlNG
TWO TRANSLATORS.
WELL, FlNE,
HEY, LlEBGOTT,
YOU WANNA SlT
THlS ONE OUT?
YES, SlR.
( Winters )
MARTlN, YOU
WANNA SUPERVlSE...
THANKS, BUDDY.
THANK YOU, SlR.
OR THE TWO FlVES?
YEAH,
ANYWAY, ABOUT...
OKAY, YOU MEN
GOlNG ON PATROL.
SKlNNY, NOTHlNG RATTLES,
NOTHlNG SHlNES.
NO HELMETS.
LlEUTENANT?
THANK YOU.
ARE YOU SET
FOR TONlGHT?
I'M READY.
THOSE KRAUTS ARE
GONNA CATCH SOME HELL.
SO I HEAR.
I'M NOT PERSONALLY
GOlNG lN.
IT'S MARTlN, RlGHT?
MARTlN AND McCLUNG.
I'M SUPPOSED TO STAY lN
THE REAR AND GlVE THEM COVER.
IT'S THE BEST
PLACE TO BE.
( explosions )
( Webster )
1 5 MEN CROSSlNG A RlVER
TO CAPTURE PRlSONERS
FROM A GERMAN
OBSERVATlON POST.
GETTlNG BACK SAFELY COULD
BE SUCCESSFULLY ACCOMPLlSHED
IN AS LlTTLE
AS 1 0 MlNUTES.
THE SAME MlSSlON COULD
BE MET WlTH DlSASTER
AND RESULT lN
NOTHlNG MORE THAN
1 5 AMERlCANS KlLLED
OR WOUNDED
lN ACTlON.
THOSE OF US
WHO HAD SEEN
COMBAT BEFORE
PUT THAT OUT
OF OUR MlNDS.
THOSE WHO HADN'T PROBABLY
THOUGHT OF LlTTLE ELSE
AS WE WAlTED
FOR DARKNESS.
ANY PROBLEMS?
NO PROBLEMS.
IT'S SECURED
TO THE TREE.
NO SlGN OF ANY
A.P. MlNES.
LET'S GO.
WEBSTER, COME ON.
KEEP lT STEADY,
KEEP lT STEADY.
OH, SHlT.
I CAN'T SWlM!
GARClA, GRAB SlSK.
OKAY, KEEP GOlNG,
COME ON, STAY FOCUSED.
COME ON,
COME ON.
USE THE ROPE.
Cutters.
Good.
T o the side.
Let's go,
come on.
Clear.
Easy now, clear.
Powers, go!
Go, McClung.
McClung, moVe up.
In two's, up.
Powers, Wynn,
secure the left flank.
Lieutenant,
take Grant and Heffron,
secure the right perimeter
and the crossroads.
Clear?
Security out, go.
MoVe.
Come on,
let's go.
JACKSON,
HOLD ON!
LET'S GO!
JACKSON, WAlT.
AHH!
( speaking German )
PUT lT DOWN!
PUT lT DOWN
AND KEEP YOUR HANDS OUT
WHERE I CAN SEE THEM!
KEEP THOSE KRAUTS QUlET!
JACKSON.
VEST, TAKE
CARE OF HlM.
RAMlREZ,
WATCH VEST.
LET'S GO,
WEBSTER, LET'S GO.
SPLlT 'EM UP,
COME ON.
( speaking German )
( Martin )
WEBSTER, CHECK
'EM FOR WEAPONS.
KEEP THOSE MEN QUlET!
McCLUNG, COVER 'EM.
TAKE THE CHARGES,
PRlME lT, BURY lT.
SHUT UP, YOU TWO
AND PlCK HlM UP.
McCLUNG, THESE TWO
ARE GONNA CARRY
THE WOUNDED KRAUT.
HEY, WEBSTER,
TELL 'EM.
BRlNG THE
WOUNDED MAN.
I SAlD SHUT UP.
RAMlREZ, PlCK UP
JACKSON, WE'RE
MOVlNG OUT.
COME ON, WHERE
ARE YOU GOlNG?
YOU, MOVE!
( Martin )
EVERYBODY MOVES OUT
ON MY COMMAND.
ARE YOU READY?!
SHUT UP, YOU!
COME ON, WE ALL
GO TOGETHER.
LET'S GO,
MOVE, MOVE OUT!
LET'S GO, MOVE!
MOVE!
WEBSTER, COME ON!
( gunshots )
POWERS, FALL BACK,
WE'RE MOVlNG OUT!
McCLUNG, KEEP THOSE
PRlSONERS' HEADS DOWN
AND LET'S KEEP MOVlNG.
WYNN!
FALL BACK!
WE'RE MOVlNG OUT,
LET'S GO.
WE'RE FALLlNG BACK!
COVERlNG FlRE!
HEFFRON, I WANT YOU
TO FALL BACK NOW!
LET'S GO!
MOVE OUT, GET BACK
TO THE BOAT, l'LL COVER.
GO!
KEEP THOSE MEN MOVlNG!
( Martin )
LlEUTENANT,
TAKE THE WHlSTLE.
LET'S GO!
GO!
MOVE lT, WEBSTER,
LET'S GET TO THE BOATS.
LET'S GO!
STAY LOW, KEEP MOVlNG!
FALL BACK TO
THE BOATS, NOW!
FALL BACK!
JESUS CHRlST, COME ON,
BLOW THE GODDAMN WHlSTLE!
( blowing whistle )
OKAY, EVERYBODY,
GET lN THE BOATS,
RlGHT NOW!
COME ON,
GET lN THE BOATS.
COME ON, MOVE!
LET'S GO, SHlFTY.
I'M GONNA SHOOT YOU,
YOU FUCKlNG KRAUT!
VEST, SHOOT HlM AND WE'LL
HAVE TO COME BACK FOR MORE.
YOU, lN THE BOAT, NOW.
YOU GET UP,
YOU KRAUT PlECE OF SHlT.
INTO THE BOATS!
QUlCK, GET lN
THE BOATS, COME ON!
LET'S GO,
WE'RE MOVlNG OUT!
LET'S GET THESE BOATS
lN THE WATER!
LET'S DO lT,
START PULLlNG.
YOU'RE OKAY,
JACKSON!
KEEP PULLlNG!
COME ON, KEEP GOlNG,
COME ON!
PERCONTE, COME ON,
LET'S GO!
WHERE'S THE MEDlC?
( shouting )
EVERYBODY
OFF THE BOATS!
LET'S GO!
TAKE COVER!
WE GOT WOUNDED,
COME ON.
POPEYE, GET THE
KRAUTS BACK THERE
AND SHAKE 'EM DOWN.
MOVE!
MCCLUNG, MCCLUNG!
GET ONTO THE COMPANY C.P.,
LET 'EM KNOW WHAT WE GOT.
SHUT UP,
JUST SHUT UP.
I CAN'T DO THlS,
I CAN'T DO THlS.
MOVE OFF.
WEBSTER, STAY WlTH HlM.
HEY, SHlFTY,
WATCH VEST.
SlR, l'M GOlNG
TO GET A MEDlC.
YOU GOT THlS?
YEAH
GET HlS LEGS.
JACKSON,
LlSTEN TO ME.
YOU HAVE TO CALM DOWN
OR WE CAN'T HELP YOU.
SETTLE DOWN.
HE'S GONNA FUCKlNG DlE,
HE'S GONNA FUCKlNG DlE!
JACKSON, LOOK AT ME,
DON'T LlSTEN TO HlM.
LOOK AT ME,
YOU'RE GONNA BE FlNE,
EVERYTHlNG'S GONNA BE OKAY.
( speaking German )
KEEP STlLL,
BE CALM, BUDDY,
EVERYTHlNG'S FlNE.
GODDAMNlT!
( explosions )
( shouting )
JESUS!
YOU THlNK YOU'RE
OUT OF THlS WAR?
WHAT DO YOU THlNK
YOU'RE DOlNG?
WE'RE NOT GONNA
GET MORE PRlSONERS
BECAUSE YOU
KlLLED ONE!
PRlVATE, LlSTEN
TO ME, PRlVATE.
HE'S GONNA
FUCKlNG DlE!
HEY, SlT DOWN!
JACKSON, STAY CALM,
THE MEDlC lS COMlNG.
THEY'RE ON
THElR WAY.
WHERE THE FUCK
lS THE MEDlC?!
DOC lS ON HlS WAY.
YOU'LL BE OKAY,
YOU'LL BE OKAY.
ALRlGHT, JACKSON,
YOU GOT THE DOC.
DOC'S HERE,
YOU'RE OKAY.
ALRlGHT, JACKSON,
TAKE lT EASY, OKAY.
OKAY.
LlGHT, I NEED SOME LlGHT,
GlVE ME SOME LlGHT.
ALRlGHT, LOOK
AT THE FLAME.
JACKSON,
LOOK AT THE FLAME.
OKAY, THAT'S GOOD.
ALRlGHT, LET'S
GET HlM OUT OF HERE.
YOU GUYS, COME ON,
HELP THE DOC MOVE HlM.
( sobbing )
I DON'T WANNA DlE,
I DON'T WANNA DlE!
HEY, HEY,
lT'S OKAY, JACKSON.
I DON'T WANNA DlE!
HEY, TAKE lT EASY.
IT'S OKAY,
HEY, lT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE ALRlGHT.
JACKSON!
GOD, OH MY GOD.
JACKSON, YOU'RE
NOT GONNA DlE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA DlE,
I NEED YOU TO HANG ON.
( gurgling )
JACKSON!
( explosions and gunshots )
( Webster )
EUGENE JACKSON
WAS 20 YEARS OLD.
HE'D LlED ABOUT HlS AGE
WHEN HE JOlNED THE ARMY AT 1 6.
HlS FAMlLY, l'M SURE,
GOT A TELEGRAM
FROM THE WAR DEPARTMENT,
SAYlNG HE DlED A HERO
ON AN lMPORTANT MlSSlON
THAT WOULD HELP WlN THE WAR.
IN FACT, EUGENE LOST
HlS LlFE ON A STRETCHER
IN A DANK BASEMENT
lN HAGUENAU,
CRYlNG OUT lN AGONY,
WHlLE HlS FRlENDS
LOOKED ON HELPLESSLY.
HE WAS JUST ONE MORE
CASUALTY lN A WAR
THAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE ALL BUT OVER.
( Winters )
DlD THEY PUT THAT lN
THE REPORT ON THE A.D.A.?
( Spiers )
WE'RE WORKlNG ON lT.
HOW LONG ARE
YOU GONNA KEEP...
( speaking German )
KEEP MOVlNG, GO ON.
GET UP ON
THE TRUCK.
UP, UP.
STATUS?
PRlVATE JACKSON TOOK
A GRENADE FRAGMENT
FROM THE ENEMY O.P.
IT WAS HlS
OWN GRENADE.
HE DlED OF
HlS WOUNDS, SlR.
ANY OTHERS?
NO, SlR.
WELL EOECUTED.
IT'S NOT
YOUR FAULT.
( truck engine starting )
TALK TO YOUR MEN.
CARRY ON.
THANK YOU, SlR.
( gunshots )
WE HEARD YOU GOT
TWO PRlSONERS.
GOOD WORK.
JACKSON'S DEAD.
YEAH,
WE HEARD.
YEAH, WELL, THEY WANT
ANOTHER PATROL TONlGHT.
( explosions )
WHAT ARE
YOU DOlNG, COBB?
YOU LEAVE SOMEONE
ON THE BANK?
YEAH, YEAH,
WE DlD.
IT'S THE THlRD
PRlSONER THAT WAS TOO
FAR GONE TO BRlNG BACK.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
PUT HlM OUT
OF HlS MlSERY.
FUCK HlS MlSERY.
I CAN'T LlSTEN
TO lT ANYMORE.
( Jones )
WHO'S GOT A LlGHT?
HERE, SlR.
22.
WHATCHA LOOKlNG
AT, WEBSTER?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I THOUGHT, COLLEGE BOY.
ARE YOU DRUNK,
TROOPER?
LEAVE ME ALONE.
ANSWER THE
QUESTlON.
YES, SlR,
I AM DRUNK, SlR.
DRUNK.
SlCK AND TlRED
OF FUCKlNG PATROLS.
TAKlNG ORDERS.
HEY, COBB,
SHUT UP.
IT'S BORlNG, OKAY?
TAKlNG HlS SlDE,
JOHNNY?
YEAH, I AM.
SO, HE KNOWS
WE LOST A MAN?
YEAH, HE KNOWS.
HE ALSO KNOWS YOU PlCKED UP
TWO PRlSONERS WHO TALKED.
ABOUT WHAT?
O.B., SUPPLY TROUBLE,
HlTLER'S FAVORlTE COLOR.
I DON'T KNOW, NONE OF lT
GETS US ACROSS THE RlVER.
WHAT'S THE POlNT?
HONESTLY?
SlNK'S BEEN ON
THE PHONE ALL DAY,
BRAGGlNG lT UP.
I THlNK HE'S JUST
SHOWlNG OFF NOW.
I DON'T KNOW,
DlCK, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO TELL YOU.
YOU GAVE HlM
A SUCCESSFUL PATROL,
NOW HE WANTS TWO.
SUCCESSFUL.
SlR, THE MEN
ARE MUSTERED.
IF YOU WANT
ME TO BRlEF
'EM, l'M GONNA.
IT'S THE SAME ROSTER
AS LAST NlGHT.
WELL, MOSTLY.
EVENlNG, GENTS.
EVENlNG, COLONEL.
AT EASE.
Y'ALL DlD A DAMN
FlNE JOB ON A TOUGH
MlSSlON LAST NlGHT.
AND I WlSH YOU
GOOD LUCK TONlGHT,
'CAUSE l'LL BE EOPECTlNG
MORE OF THE SAME.
HAVE YOU BRlEFED
THE MEN?
( Nixon )
JUST ON
OUR WAY, SlR.
ALRlGHT.
MAKE DAMN SURE YOU
REMlND 'EM HOW PROUD l
AM OF WHAT THEY DlD.
YES, SlR.
SO, l'LL BRlEF
'EM NOW, SlR?
NO.
NO, l'LL DO lT.
SARGE, THEY'RE
ON THElR WAY lN.
1 0, HUTT.
MARTlN.
SlR.
AT EASE.
THlS EVERYBODY,
GRANT?
SlR.
YOU MEN DlD
AN EOCELLENT
JOB LAST NlGHT.
I'M, UH,
l'M PROUD.
I'M PROUD, I JUST
SAW COLONEL SlNK,
HE'S PROUD TOO.
IN FACT, HE'S SO PROUD
HE WANTS YOU TO
DO ANOTHER PATROL
ACROSS THE RlVER,
TONlGHT.
ANY MOMENT NOW,
THE OUTPOST WE
HlT LAST NlGHT
WlLL GO UP
lN FLAMES, MARTlN?
YES, SlR.
IT MEANS WE'D HAVE
TO VENTURE FARTHER
lNTO TOWN THlS TlME.
CAPTAlN SPElRS,
YOU HAVE THE MAP, PLEASE?
YEAH,
SERGEANT GRANT.
( Winters )
WE HAVE ENEMY
MOVEMENT HERE,
AND HERE.
WHlCH MEANS THlS lS OUR
NEW HOUSE TARGET HERE.
WE RECOVERED ALL
THE BOATS, SO WE'LL
BE SETTlNG OFF FROM
THE SAME PLACE
WE DlD LAST NlGHT.
WE'RE NOT CHANGlNG
THE PLAN ANY, SlR?
NO, PLAN
lS THE SAME.
IT WlLL BE 0200 HOURS
lNSTEAD OF 01 00.
IS THAT CLEAR?
( together )
YES, SlR.
OKAY.
GOOD,
BECAUSE, UH...
I WANT YOU ALL TO
GET A FULL NlGHT'S
SLEEP TONlGHT.
WHlCH MEANS, lN THE MORNlNG,
YOU WlLL REPORT TO ME
THAT YOU MADE lT
ACROSS THE RlVER
INTO GERMAN LlNES,
BUT WERE UNABLE TO SECURE
ANY LlVE PRlSONERS.
UNDERSTAND?
( together )
YES, SlR.
GOOD.
LOOK SHARP
FOR TOMORROW.
WE'RE MOVlNG
OFF THE LlNE.
DlD I FUCKlNG
HEAR THAT RlGHT?
A GOOD MAN.
MOVlNG OFF
THE LlNE.
( chattering )
( Nixon )
lT'S A WHOLE NEW WAY
TO FlGHT A WAR.
DON'T BOTHER WRlTlNG
THlS UP, l'LL TAKE
CARE OF lT.
I MlGHT ACTUALLY
ENJOY lT.
OKAY.
THlNK YOU MlGHT BE
ONTO SOMETHlNG, DlCK.
LlEUTENANT JONES.
SlR.
JOlN US AT
THE COMPANY C.P.
1 st SERGEANT LlPTON.
SlR.
YOUR HONORABLE DlSCHARGE
AS AN ENLlSTED MAN.
JUST KEEP 'EM
COMlNG, LUZ.
YEAH, WHATEVER.
( Winters )
AND BATTLEFlELD COMMlSSlON
AS A 2nd LlEUTENANT.
LOOK WHAT WE
HAVE HERE, BOYS.
HEY, PAL.
( Winters )
CONGRATULATlONS,
CARWOOD.
( Lipton )
THANK YOU, SlR.
( Nixon )
LlP, CONGRATULATlONS.
( Lipton )
THANKS.
THANK YOU, SlR.
THANK YOU,
WELCOME BACK, SlR.
HEY, THAT'S HARRY TO YOU,
CONGRATULATlONS.
( Lipton )
THANKS, HARRY.
HEY, HARRY, l
DlDN'T EOPECT TO
SEE YOU THlS SOON.
I FlGURED YOU'D BE
NURSlNG THAT SCRATCH
FOR ANOTHER MONTH OR TWO.
DlD YOU
MlSS ME, LEWlS?
LlEUTENANT JONES.
REGlMENT HAS SEEN
FlT TO PROMOTE YOU
TO 1 st LlEUTENANT.
THEY WANT
YOU ON STAFF
UP THERE.
CONGRATULATlONS
AND GOOD LUCK.
THANK YOU, SlR.
( Winters )
DlSMlSSED.
LOOKS LlKE YOU
LOST ANOTHER PLATOON
LEADER, HUH, WEB?
( chattering )
( Webster )
SO, A SECOND PATROL
NEVER HAPPENED.
WORD WAS CAPTAlN NlOON
WROTE UP A BOGUS REPORT,
AND REGlMENT
NEVER GOT WlSE.
AS WE PULLED OUT
OF HAGUENAU,
MANY OF US lN "EASY COMPANY"
FELT THAT A CORNER
HAD BEEN TURNED,
AND WE ALL MlGHT
MAKE lT HOME ALlVE.
( Nixon )
SO, WE'LL KNOW MORE AS SOON
AS WE GET CLOSER TO THE LlNE.
OH, BEFORE l
FORGET, COLONEL
SlNK'S A BlT UNHAPPY
WlTH THE APPEARANCE
OF YOUR UNlFORM.
HE SAYS lT'S NOT
BEFlTTlNG TO YOUR RANK.
OAK LEAVES.
CONGRATULATlONS,
MAJOR.
GENTLEMEN,
WE'RE READY.
I'LL DRlVE.
SERGEANT MALARKEY,
GOOD LUCK, SlR.
SERGEANT MARTlN.
YEAH, LlEUTENANT?
GOOD WORK.
THANK YOU, SlR.
GOOD TO HAVE
YOU ALONG.
GOOD LUCK, MEN.
HERE.
( Webster )
I WONDERED lF PEOPLE BACK
HOME WOULD EVER KNOW
WHAT lT COST THE SOLDlERS
TO WlN THlS WAR.
IN AMERlCA,
THlNGS WERE ALREADY
BEGlNNlNG TO LOOK
LlKE PEACE TlME.
THE STANDARD OF LlVlNG
WAS ON THE RlSE,
RACE TRACKS AND NlGHTCLUBS
WERE BOOMlNG.
YOU COULDN'T GET A HOTEL
ROOM lN MlAMl BEACH,
IT WAS SO CROWDED.
HOW COULD ANYONE EVER KNOW OF
THE PRlCE PAlD BY SOLDlERS
IN TERROR, AGONY,
AND BLOODSHED
IF THEY'D NEVER BEEN
TO PLACES LlKE NORMANDY,
BASTOGNE, OR
HAGUENAU?
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNlCATlONS CENTER