[insects and birds chirping]
[boy] Stop. Claire Hale. Stop!
[man] "I'd like to fry her eyeballs.
If no one else steps up
to kill the president, I will.
I'd enjoy it."
A tweet out of North Dakota.
What else?
"God never intended a woman
to rule this land.
She is the anti-Christ.
- And a Jew."
- [Mark] A Jew?
- Do we really need to hear all of this?
- Yes.
[man] An unpublished editorial.
Someone pointing a gun at your likeness.
Lots of other online stuff, including a...
contest...
For?
For the most creative way to kill you.
And the winner?
Rather not say, ma'am.
I want to hear.
Just hand me the report, Rick.
It involves, essentially, skinning you.
Cutting your body into dozens of pieces
and arranging them
in the shape of the American flag.
Flesh for the white stripes,
blood for the red.
What else?
Lot of threats
involving the C-word, ma'am.
Lots and lots of the C-word,
unfortunately.
You mean Claire? It's a long list.
- If you really want me to, I'll...
- Listen, I am not the first president
to face threats.
I know with Francis,
sometimes there were several a day.
Is it about the same
what we're dealing with here?
It's...
significantly up.
By how much?
[Mark] There are roughly
four times as many threats
on any given day since you took office.
Now it's twice that since Francis died.
I thought everyone loves a widow.
Not if she's also
Commander-in-Chief, I guess.
These are not rational people,
Madam President.
But, ma'am, as far as today's threat,
regarding your first
scheduled appearance...
We're canceling the appearance.
We're not canceling.
It's a military base.
That's got to be the safest place on Earth
for a president.
An anonymous soldier
has made a serious threat...
"To shoot me in the cunt on behalf
of the United States of America."
Yes, Mark, I heard.
The threat's unconfirmed.
He says he's among
those shipping out today.
- Anyone can claim that.
- [Mark] And that you have no right
waging war in Syria. You, in particular.
I think we stay away.
Rick, don't you agree?
There's no proof the threat is credible.
Isn't that right, Rick?
Our intelligence division
is investigating,
and the advance team is already there,
but it'll take at least a day
to comb through that base.
I think what the vice president says
is the best course.
- Maybe by tomorrow you could...
- Tomorrow is the fifth of July.
- Yes, ma'am.
- So what do you suggest I do?
- Wish the nation a happy belated birthday?
- Our only concern is your safety...
[Claire] We're not cancelling.
I am sending those soldiers
onto a battlefield.
The first female president
of the United States
is not gonna keep her mouth shut
on the Fourth of fucking July.
[theme song plays]
[Mark] Lieutenant General Gallagher
would understand.
- I could appear instead. Speak for you.
- Stop.
Is it my safety that concerns you,
or my potential endorsement of Gallagher?
Your safety first, of course.
But singling her out,
that's a provocation.
And so?
I can't provoke them?
You're forwarding a candidate
the Shepherds are against,
in their home state.
- After months of negotiation.
- This is not a negotiation,
this is an ultimatum.
Sign the bill or what?
Or what, Mark?
When Francis was looking
to finance his foundation,
why did you point him
towards Bill and Annette?
I didn't. Raymond Tusk arranged it.
Or maybe they reached out to him?
I don't remember.
I... What does it matter?
They're working with you now.
I need to meet
with the Shepherds directly.
Madam President.
I'll see them before my appearance
at the base.
- You can't.
- I what?
I'll let them know.
Thank you.
You're due at the base by 4:45,
which will have you back here by 8:30.
The fireworks show
begins right after nine.
And the Examiner would love your okay
on the photos.
Is there any progress
on the source of the sound?
The GSA is still looking into it.
They're checking the floorboards
above and below, in case there's...
I don't want to wait anymore.
Please tell the executive housekeeper
I'd like the former president's belongings
packed up.
I'll have it taken care of.
[double thud]
[double thud] [double thud]
[sirens wailing in the distance]
It's not true what he told you
all those years ago.
That there are two kinds,
useful and useless.
There's only one kind.
Pain is pain.
Francis...
[bird chirping]
I'm done with you.
There.
No more pain.
[Seth] You do this all day?
I'm under psychiatric observation, Seth.
This is what you do.
Who's your new tailor?
You gotta look the part.
So, when do they decide
whether you're crazy or not?
Because if you're not,
you should come work for us.
Us?
Have you been working there
for about five minutes?
It's been a month, actually.
So his body wasn't even cold.
It's what he would have wanted.
The Underwood Foundation
was basically gonna be modeled
after the Shepherd Freedom Foundation.
I don't need the job.
Oh. Well, for a confessed murderer,
you're pretty confident.
I'm about to be pardoned.
Pardon?
You really think
that she's gonna give you one?
As usual, you don't know
what the fuck you're talking about.
You know, there wasn't the kind of crowd
that you'd expect for him
down there in Gaffney.
He wanted to be buried in Arlington.
Not next to his father.
That's not what his wife said.
Tell me something.
She even shed a tear?
You know...
I'm almost envious, to tell you the truth.
That even beyond the grave,
you'd do anything for Francis Underwood.
Doug, do you have my lighter?
Much obliged.
Was that who I thought it was?
Fred Amburg? He went off the deep end?
Everyone has problems, Seth.
Especially the ones who think they don't.
[jazz music playing]
[door hinges creak]
- Claire.
- Annette.
Oh, did you get my note?
Oh, I haven't had the courage
to read the condolences yet.
It's good to see you finally out
and about.
Oh, what you've been through.
You know all about it.
Well, for a long time,
I pretended he was still alive.
Out of town.
It was our son Duncan
that really saved me.
Of course, we weren't married
anywhere near as long as you and Frank.
Claire Hale.
Nine years.
Late spring,
Sun Valley.
[Claire chuckles]
You look exactly the same.
Well, it's cities that age you,
it's what I tell everyone.
I hope you don't mind saying hello
to a few of our closest friends.
They're just here for a cocktail
before the...
the sun goes down
and the rest of the party shows up.
My sister's fireworks show have become
a bit of a tradition.
Don't worry. They know how to be discreet.
Scotty here just got his hands
on Nexis Security.
I heard you are speaking
to the vice president about this.
It's a company of peacekeepers, mostly.
Oh, tremendous potential
to create global partnerships.
Your husband helped me secure the deal.
I wanted to bring him onto the Board.
Bill was saying...
Yes, I was just saying.
Why in the world do they play
the "1812 Overture" at a fireworks show?
It's Russian, for Chrissakes,
in every sense.
This is Tabitha.
Oh. Peters, I know.
Frank...
- Wasn't he planning to be here today?
- He was.
You must miss him terribly.
I had some long
and hard-fought conversations with him.
He was going to help me resolve this
AFL-CIO thing
that's been going on forever
out in Nevada,
with your help, of course.
When the union stands
in the way of innovation,
it's sentencing itself to death.
[Tabitha] I do admire the way you hang on
to your party.
Your loyalty.
Did I hear that
Lieutenant General Nancy Gallagher
will be appearing with you later today?
I think she'd make an excellent candidate,
if she decides to run, of course.
Oh, she's going to run.
The president is on a tight schedule.
Excuse me.
[birds cawing]
Well, this is a surprise.
You know how Midwesterners
feel about those.
Oh, don't listen to him.
It's about time you came out.
Seems we have some things to discuss.
Yeah.
Well, as far as this special election
is concerned, Claire,
you need to know that
the soon-to-be-retiring Miss Gallagher
is out of question.
And I'm happy to see we're both fans
of the Declaration of Independence,
unalienable rights and all that.
But it says down here in the speech
you're gonna give later...
Miss Gallagher has my support.
I believe Mark conveyed our concerns.
And communicated mine, I hope.
She's a tax and spend Democrat
underneath that uniform.
- A patriot with a pristine resume.
- Claire.
Who is very vocal about keeping
private contractors away
- from US military operations.
- Even as a negotiating point,
you can do better than her.
And I am tired of these delays,
Madam President.
It is time for you to deliver.
- Your husband and I had an agreement.
- Francis is dead.
- Promises were made.
- Not by me.
Just like you, I like to negotiate
my own agreements.
And make no mistake about it,
the lieutenant general is not an anomaly.
I know that. I've seen your list
of candidates for the midterms...
- Yes, mostly women.
- I don't care what sex they are.
And for the record,
nobody loves women more than me.
But this slate of yours,
it will bankrupt the country.
They will set us back a generation.
They will completely...
Support me and what I stand for.
And what is that?
- Oh, come on, Bill.
- No, no. Tell me.
I wanna know. What's your mission?
- I wanna know what your platform is.
- Oh, please.
I know you'd like
to drown DC all at once.
But I'm gonna tell you right now,
I cannot let that happen.
I still believe in government
and its ability
to make the everyday lives
of its citizens better.
- Yeah.
- You don't wanna support my slate,
that's fine.
- Claire...
- All I ask is stay out of the way.
There's a bill sitting on your desk.
A bill that took years...
and money to get passed.
You sign that,
and I know I got a friend
in the White House.
If not...
- Then I don't.
- Enough.
Nothing good happens to you
when she's around.
Nothing.
Why did you come out for Francis?
For his foundation?
I don't think you ever really liked him.
Probably never respected him.
Why back him now?
Because he gave us you.
Tell our friends I'll be back down
in time for the fireworks.
Just so you know, I always liked Frank.
His desperation.
I'm sorry you can't stay.
I do enjoy curating our little show.
I collect a variety of fireworks shells
as I travel.
Italy, Spain, China.
Do you know what the hardest color
to make is?
- Red?
- No, red's easy.
White's easy.
It's blue.
Very tricky chemistry
involving copper and heat.
A truly bright blue is extremely elusive.
Whatever Francis promised or did...
is buried with him.
No, I know.
We all need to let him go.
Start from some kind of scratch.
Though it must haunt you,
the fact that he died next to you in bed.
Hon...
be patient.
- [woman] She doesn't like the name?
- [man] I think she finds it incomplete.
[woman] What's wrong with
the Comprehensive Safety Act?
[man 2] Comprehensive Chemical Safety Act?
[man] Or we could go back
to the Smarter Safety Act.
- Would she like "Smarter" better?
- No, we need a good acronym.
Mr. Vice President? Mark?
Yeah. Agreed.
[man] At one point, we talked about
the Repeal Unsafe Regulation Act.
That's RURAL if we come up with an L.
Legislation?
That doesn't make sense
with the rest of it.
"RURAL" is too hard to say.
"SAFE" is good.
Safety. Future.
- I like "FUTURE."
- Federal Universal Toxic and Unsafe...
- Regulation Eradication.
- [Mark] Okay.
- The FUTURE Act.
- That could work.
May I ask, Mr. Vice President,
does her hesitation go beyond the name?
She'll come around. I'm guessing...
- by the end of the day.
- [phone vibrating]
Because in one form or another,
- this bill has been on her desk since...
- She'll sign it, Henry.
- [beeps]
- Bill.
What do you want me to do?
Yank her from her own military base?
[whoosh]
When, in the course of human events,
it becomes necessary
for one people
to dissolve the political bands
which have connected them with another,
you just have to do it.
Sever the relationship.
Our nation's founding document,
the Declaration of Independence...
America's independence...
was hard-fought and hard-won.
Are you still there?
Our Founding Fathers
imagined a nation that was free.
Free from despotism.
Free from absolute tyranny.
Free from an oppressive king.
Do you miss Francis?
Tyrants come in many forms.
From the American oligarchs trying
to change the very fabric of our society,
to autocrats threatening from abroad.
Now, each one of us
has to defend our destiny.
And as I see it,
the fight against tyranny
is the only justification for war.
My first 100 days as president
have been difficult.
I lost my husband.
We were about
to celebrate 30 years together.
But I know what he would want.
For me to stop mourning and carry on.
With the help of women like
Lieutenant General Nancy Gallagher,
my presidency will not rest.
Nancy has been an inspiration to me.
A tireless warrior.
I promise her and all of you
that I will work on behalf of the rights
and freedoms earned over the last
241 years of our democracy.
As I look into the eyes
of you brave soldiers
standing before me today...
Here's the thing.
I'm feeling so proud right now.
Proud to be your Commander-in-Chief.
Whatever Francis told you
the last five years,
don't believe a word of it.
Our country is 241 years old, my friends.
Let's wish this great nation
a happy birthday.
Say it with me.
Happy birthday, America!
[all] Happy Birthday, America!
It's going to be different for you and me.
[Claire] One more time.
I'm going to tell you the truth.
[all] Happy Birthday, America.
- Thank you for your service.
- Thank you.
Thank you for your service.
- Thank you for your service.
- Thank you.
I want you to know how wonderful it is
to be here and meet
all of you new recruits.
So, thank you.
Thank you for your service.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you for your service.
Where are you from, private?
Kalamazoo, Mr. President.
- Excuse me, Madam President.
- That's quite all right.
I actually hate "Madam."
Makes me sound like I'm running a brothel
and not a country.
- [chuckles] Thank you for your service.
- Thank you, Madam President.
Thank you for your service.
And where are you from, Pvt. Burton?
South Bend, ma'am.
Oh, I love Indiana.
I enlisted right before you took office.
Well, I promise you
and every woman in this country
that during my presidency
the key components
of the Equal Rights Amendment
will finally pass.
I'm going to make sure of it.
I want you to know I support you.
[Burton] Do you even have a plan?
What did you say?
One that won't get us all killed?
[man] Oh, man...
Would you have asked me that
if I were a man?
- [reporters shouting]
- [camera shutters clicking]
[woman] Madam President!
- [shouting continues]
- [man] One question, please!
[muffle double thud, echoes]
[sighs]
How much longer till we get to the plane?
Just another 25 minutes or so,
Madam President.
Okay, thank you. [gasps]
- [man] Shit!
- [engine revving]
[siren wailing]
- [man] Is she shot?
- [man 2] Stay down, stay down!
Shots fired! Shots fired!
Are you okay, Madam President?
- Are you all right? - Yes.
[man 2] Lone Star is safe.
[echoing]
[gasps, whimpers]
[phone vibrates] [Rick] Sir, someone
just tried to kill the president.
I just got the alert. Is she all right?
[Rick] This way.
- [chattering over police scanner]
- [siren wailing in the distance]
Lincoln,
Garfield, McKinley, Kennedy.
Successful assassinations, total of four.
The attempts... Nine?
Jackson, both Roosevelts.
Truman. Ford twice.
Reagan...
the first Underwood and...
I will say, whoever tried to kill me,
perversely, it's the first sign
of real respect I've gotten in 100 days.
Somebody tried to kill her.
Bill.
Can you blame them?
The Underwoods
have always been hard of hearing.
She's not him.
No, no.
She is not.
You know that better than anyone.
Is it public?
Secret Service shut it down.
Standard procedure, apparently.
- [fireworks whistle and pop]
- Threats beget threats.
[crowd exclaims]
Bill...
were you behind this?
- [fireworks booming]
- [carousel music playing]
We're gonna miss the show.
[crowd cheering]
- How are y'all?
- Madam President.
Hi, I'm so sorry.
I want to apologize
for the late departure.
I know you all have families
and festivities waiting.
Madam President,
may I ask what happened?
Oh, the Beast was re-routed due
to security concerns. Pretty routine.
I know it's been a while
since I've been back here.
I just wanted to wish you all
a very happy Fourth,
even if you're gonna be celebrating it
on the fifth. I'm so sorry.
Your speech, afterwards with...
Yes, the new recruit.
If a new recruit, especially a female one,
can't speak her mind,
I don't know what kind of country
we actually are.
[reporters muttering indistinctly]
And be sure to tell us
if you run out of beer.
Because I am sure
there's a couple of cases left over
- from the Carter administration.
- [laughter]
And you're new.
Yes, ma'am. Melody Cruz.
I'm with Beltway Television.
Well, I hope everyone
is making you feel at home.
Very much so.
It's an honor to finally meet you.
I'm a bit overwhelmed, sorry.
- Don't worry, I don't bite.
- No, I know.
It's strange, I was supposed
to interview your husband.
It was scheduled for a few days
after he died.
It was going to be an exclusive.
We'd had a number of pre-interviews.
Questions we'd agreed on.
Questions like?
Like, was the president
going to pardon him?
And when?
Will you? Even now, posthumously?
I know you did an exclusive
with The New York Examiner,
but I'm guessing that's only
going to scratch the surface.
I bet you have more to say
- about the state of your marriage...
- Miss...
Cruz, is it?
I don't know if anyone's told you,
but when the president visits
this part of the plane,
it's usually considered off the record.
But you can ask my press secretary
anything you like
once we're back on the ground.
You're especially quiet this evening.
[Doug] Maybe I'm a little agitated.
Our patients don't do too well
when it comes to fireworks.
Ah. Pardon me.
[firework whistling, phone chimes]
Yes?
I don't understand why you leave that on
when we're meeting.
Well, it's not like you're saying
anything different or new.
Your dedication to your script
would be admirable
if it weren't so concerning.
In a few weeks,
I'll be appearing at a hearing
regarding your state of mind
and when it comes to your confession,
even a guilty man
changes his story now and then.
Who do you answer to?
I mean, who do you work for?
- You.
- [scoffs]
That's the idea, anyway.
Everybody works for somebody.
I worked for a man who refused to fail.
I respected that.
I appreciated it.
I'd be dead without him.
Why?
I was working as an aide
for a congressman.
He was idealistic and naive.
Had one-term written all over him.
But I needed a job, a place to be.
I was barely keeping it together.
Francis and I met at some function.
You know, the kind you stand up at.
I don't know how he knew,
but I had eight bottles in my trunk.
I got through four that night
when he came to my door.
I don't remember much.
Not clearly.
He took me to his home.
But Claire...
Francis got me dry.
I shook so badly
I thought I was gonna die.
And then when I was finally got clean,
he gave me my first job.
As an aide?
Hmm. Sort of.
He asked me to go talk
to Congressman Kyle from Iowa.
To what end?
To persuade him.
And I did.
[sighs]
But Claire...
The way she treated him,
in life and in death...
[exhales]
But you pay a price,
when you work for somebody like him.
Somebody you owe.
Somebody close to me died
in a car accident.
That's how I broke the terms
of my house arrest.
I went to see the site of her wreck.
It was twisted on the side of the road.
I just stood there.
An accident?
So they said.
And Zoe Barnes?
I killed her.
For the president.
[double thud]
That's what he used to do when he won.
What did he leave you with?
Last thing that Francis gave me
was the letter opener from his desk.
I mean, I chose it, but...
But I guess really the last thing
he gave me was an apology.
I spoke to him the night he died.
- [clock ticking]
- [crickets chirping in the distance]
[sighs]
[bottles rattling]
[beeping]
[beeping continues]
[Claire] My presidency will not rest.
Nancy has been an inspiration to me.
A tireless warrior.
I promise her and all of you
that I will work on behalf of the rights
and freedoms earned
over the last 241 years of our democracy.
Tyrants come in many forms...
Pathetic.
From the American oligarchs trying
to change the very...
[Mark] Are you sure you don't want
to take an hour or two to...
Mark. I'm inside the White House.
There's only two of us in the Oval,
so unless you're packing,
- it's literally the safest place I can be.
- Well, I'm not packing, Madam President,
but no one would fault you
for taking a breath for a minute.
I'm breathing just fine.
Can we keep news of this contained?
- I've taken every possible step, I think.
- So who is he?
Well, they did forensics on the route.
Compared notes with the aerial detail.
Homeland Secretary and the Bureau
were brought in.
He never left the place
he took the shot from.
Can you answer a single question directly
and simply?
He shot himself in the head
with his own US military-issued handgun.
And we're sure he's the one?
Yeah. Pro-militia. Anti-government.
Dishonorably discharged last year.
All the typical markers.
Secret Service is confident.
And the Bureau's investigating.
How did Bill Shepherd get his hands
on my speech?
What? Um...
Well, the press usually gets it
hours before.
It wouldn't be that hard
to access a copy, I guess.
I won't be signing that today.
[sighs]
You went there to declare
your independence, and you declared war.
That was a mistake.
No, the mistake was I didn't hire
a chief of staff,
and things are slipping
through the cracks.
That's where I have to disagree with you.
We need to keep this circle small.
You know, Francis warned me about you.
[sighs]
I assure you, I serve at your pleasure,
Madam President.
You need to stop meeting in my office
without me.
Yes, ma'am.
[Nathan] Secret Service took the lead.
But do you believe the theory?
That it was a disgruntled service person
who took a shot at me?
PID does.
I'm asking what you think.
[sighs] It depends if it was a warning
or an actual attempt.
Given the accuracy, the shooter
would have been informed enough to know
that a .50 caliber round
wouldn't penetrate the Beast.
I think he wanted to scare you.
On behalf of someone.
Lots of people make threats
against sitting presidents.
I'm starting to believe
Francis was murdered.
Before he died, he aligned himself
with some very powerful people.
And I think they turned on him,
and they wanted him dead,
and I think they want me dead, too.
Do you think that sounds crazy?
No, ma'am.
But I think we need to bring in
Special Agent Bowman...
Of these people, these powerful families,
they advocate
dismantling intelligence agencies.
CIA, FBI, Homeland.
You know that, right?
- Ma'am...
- We cannot bring
anyone else in at the moment.
I'm relying on you
the way I know my husband could.
So, please see what you can find.
Is it ever Nate
or always Nathan?
Nathan.
Like Francis.
For me, anyway.
Oh, have you spoken to Doug Stamper?
No.
I'm so worried about him.
He did things no one
in this White House should be proud of.
[sighs]
[clamoring]
Hey, Mom.
[Annette]
How many people do you have there?
Not many.
Nobody that interesting, anyway.
Her visit to the base.
Independence speech,
even the naughty soldier
is playing well for her.
Her charmed life persists.
Tell Uncle Bill we should step up.
I can manage the narrative. De-charm her.
He won't like that.
He's not going to like any of it,
so what's the difference?
- I don't know.
- Mom, just say the word.
Trust me.
Don't do a thing
until I get back to you.
[beep]
- [fireworks popping]
- [indistinct chatter]
Can't even tell you're still in DC.
There are parts of this city
that will always remain a secret.
I don't think I'll be welcome back
in the White House press pool
anytime soon, FYI.
Doesn't matter.
She won't speak to me.
- An interview? Not after...
- She will.
[Rosen] Tonight, for the first time,
he was forthcoming.
[Claire] But still saying he's guilty?
Yeah, as always.
And did he mention Mr. Grayson by name?
No. He was just more distressed.
So he's getting worse?
Or better, he's finally talking.
[door closes]
But the idea of his leaving the facility
anytime soon,
that's still out of the question.
I mean, for his own good.
He's either guilty of the crime
- or psychotic for admitting to it.
- Madam President,
Miss Shepherd is on the White House line.
[mouths]
Well, maybe it's time to give him
one of the antipsychotics.
Possibly. But we'd have to consider
his history of addiction.
By the way, in answer to your question,
it was a letter opener,
the last thing that Francis gave him
from his desk.
Keep me posted, Charles.
And thank you.
Sure.
[Annette in low voice] Are you prepared?
Excuse me.
[laughs] Don't you remember? Andover?
Our prep school joke?
[sighs] I'm prepared to fail the test.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry to call so late.
I... I heard about what happened today.
These things have a tendency to leak out.
I'm worried about you.
It's bulletproof, the motorcade glass.
Did they catch the guy?
How do you know it's a guy?
It's always a guy, right?
What was it Bill wanted adjusted
in my speech?
Oh. Something about...
freedom.
You're in my thoughts, Claire.
Thank you.
He's still with us, don't you think?
Who? Frank.
We're so glad we got to spend
so much time with him before he died.
He told us some fascinating things.
He's been on my mind.
Bill and I finally went down to Gaffney
a few days ago...
to pay our respects.
[phone beeps]
[double thud]
- [muffled, echoing breathing]
- [double thud]
[noisy breathing continues]
[boy] Claire!
I shouldn't have let them.
I'm sorry.
Come on out now.
[horse neighing]
[Claire] Are you still there?
Yes.
- [boy screams]
- [horse neighs]
Help!
[crying]
[echoing] Help!
I know.
You want to know
what really happened to him.
A man like Francis doesn't just die.
That would be...
what's the word?
"Convenient."