Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
...Aang can save the world
The Avatar has kidnapped my daughter.
I want you to do whatever it takes
to bring her home.
I discovered a hidden library
I tore through scroll after scroll.
You did it! You're a earthbender.
Sozen's comet will return
by the end of this summer
and Firelord Ozai will use its
power to finish the war once for all
You must defeat the Firelord
before the comet arrives.
What's out here?
A lot actually.
There's hundreds of little...
Shhh! I know you can see underground,
but don't ruin the surprise.
Just watch.
I'm putting an orchestra together.
Orchestra huh?
Well la dee da.
This is great and all, but don't we
have more important things to worry about?
We should be making plans.
We did make plans.
We're all picking mini-vacations.
There's no time for vacations.
I'm learning the elements as fast as I can.
I practice hard everyday
with Toph and Katara.
I've been training my arrow off.
Yeah. What's wrong with having
a little fun in our downtime?
Even if you do master
all of the elements, then what?
It's not like we have a
map of the fire nation.
Should we just head west until
we reach the Fire Lord's house?
Knock knock! Hello, Fire Lord?
Anybody home?
I don't think so.
We need some intelligence
if we're gonna win this war.
Alright, we'll finish our vacations,
and then we'll look for
Sokka's intelligence.
Your turn Katara. Where would
you like to go on your mini-vacation?
How about the Misty Palms
Oasis? That sounds refreshing.
Oh yeah, I've been there.
It's a pristine natural ice spring,
and I usually don't use the word pristine.
It's one of nature's wonders.
Must have changed ownership
since I was here.
One mango please.
I don't see anything wrong with
having one of those fruity beverages ...
while we plan our strategy.
Excuse me.
No worries, I clean up easy.
Oh, You're a living relic!
Thanks. I try.
An Air Nomad, right in front of me.
Professor Zei, head of anthropology
at Ba Sing Se University.
Tell me, which of the
Air temples do you hail from?
The southern temple.
Oh splendid! Now tell me, what was the
primary agricultural product of your people?
Uh, are fruit pies an agricultural product?
Oh, truly fascinating.
That is one for the journal.
So professor, you're obviously
a well traveled guy.
Do you have a more current map?
Ours seems to be a little dated.
Certainly.
What, no Fire Nation? Doesn't
anybody have a good map of that place?
You've made a lot of trips into the desert.
All in vain I'm afraid.
I've found lost civilizations
all over the Earth Kingdom,
but I haven't managed to
find the crown jewel...
Wan Shi Tong's Library.
You spent years walking
through the desert ...
to find some guy's library?
This library is more valuable
than gold, little lady.
It is said to contain
a vast collection of knowledge,
and knowledge
is priceless.
Mm, sounds like good times.
Oh, it is.
According to legend, it was
built by the great knowledge spirit,
Wan Shi Tong, with the help
of his foxy knowledge seekers.
Oh, so this spirit has
attractive assistants, huh?
I think he means they
look like actual foxes, Sokka.
You're both right.
Handsome little creatures.
Wan Shi Tong and his knowledge seekers
collected books from all over the world,
and put them on display
for mankind to read,
so that we might better ourselves.
If this place has books from all over the world,
do you think they've got info on the Fire Nation?
A map maybe?
I wouldn't know, but if
such a thing exists,
it's in Wan Shi Tong's Library.
Then it's settled.
Aang, I do believe it's my turn.
I'd like to spend my vacation
AT THE LIBRARY!
Uh, hey? What about me?
When do I get to pick?
You gotta work here a little longer
before you qualify for vacation time.
Of course there's the matter of finding it.
I've made several trips
into the Si Wong Desert,
and almost died each time.
I'm afraid that desert's
impossible to cross.
Professor, would you like
to see our sky bison?
A sky bison?
You actually have one?
Sandbenders! Shoo! Away from the bison!
Tell me, sky bison. Are
you the last of your breed?
Oh, delightful!
I only wish I spoke his tongue.
Oh the stories this beast could tell.
Shush, chatty monkey.
Wow, shouldn't be too hard
to find a place like this out here.
Aw, does this place even exist?
Some say it doesn't.
Shouldn't you have mentioned that before?
There it is!
That's what it will sound
like when one of you spots it.
It shouldn't be this hard to spot
a giant ornate building from the air.
Down there. What's that?
Forget it. It's obviously
not what we're looking for.
The building in this drawing is enormous.
What kind of animal is that?
I think that was one of
the knowledge seekers.
Oh, we must be close to the library!
No, this is the library. Look!
It's completely buried.
The library is buried!?
My life's ambition is now full of sand.
Well, time to start excavating.
Actually, that won't be necessary.
The inside seems to be completely intact,
and it's huge.
That fox thingy went in through a window.
I say we climb up there and give it a look.
I say you guys go ahead without me.
You got something against libraries?
I've held books before,
and I gotta tell you,
they don't exactly do it for me.
Oh, right. Sorry.
Let me know if they have
something you can listen to.
Don't worry buddy. I'm not making
you go underground ever again.
You can stay out here with Toph.
What's up?
Oh, it's breath taking.
The spirits spared no
expense designing this place.
Look at those beautiful buttresses!
What's funny?
Nothing. We just like architecture.
As do I.
My word!
The exquisite mosaic handiwork
of this tile-rendered avian symbol
Eh, nice...owl.
I know you're back there.
Hello! I'm Professor Zei, head of
anthropology at Ba Sing Se University.
You should leave the way you came
unless you want to become
a stuffed head of anthropology.
Are you the spirit who brought
this library to the physical world?
Indeed, I am Wan Shi Tong,
he who knows 10,000 things.
And you are obviously humans,
which by the way are no
longer permitted in my study.
What do you have against humans?
Hmm, humans only bother learning
things to get the edge on other humans,
like that firebender who came
to this place a few years ago,
looking to destroy his enemy.
So...
who are you trying to destroy?
What? Oh, no,
no, no destroying, we're not into that.
Then why have you come here?
Knowledge, for, knowledge's sake.
If you're going to lie
to an all-knowing spirit being,
you should at least put
some effort into it.
I'm not lying. I'm here
with the Avatar, and he's ...
the bridge between our
worlds, he'll vouch for me.
Uh, yeah, I'll vouch.
We will not abuse the knowledge
in your library, good spirit.
You have my word.
Very well.
I'll let you peruse my vast collection,
on one condition.
To prove your worth as scholars, you have
to contribute some worthwhile knowledge.
Please accept this tome
as a donation to your library.
First edition, very nice.
I have an authentic waterbending scroll.
Oh...these illustrations are quite stylish.
Uh, oh, I know!
I suppose that counts.
Oh, great spirit, Check this out!
It's a special knot!
That counts as knowledge.
You're not very bright, are you?
Enjoy the library.
Bright enough to fool you.
So,
you like flyin'?
Of course, I'm more comfortable
on the ground, where I can see.
Well, I don't see the way you do.
I feel the vibration in
the ground with my feet,
but this sand is so loose and shifty,
it makes everything look fuzzy.
Not that there's anything wrong with fuzzy.
Hey, look at these weird
lion turtle things.
Eh, I've seen weirder.
Aang, did you know in a
past life, you were left handed?
I always knew I was special.
The darkest day in Fire Nation history.
It's got a date at the top,
but it doesn't say anything else.
Sokka, where are you going?
I want to know what happened to
the Fire Nation on their darkest day.
This could be promising.
The information on the Fire
Nation should be right up here.
Firebender.
They destroyed everything
having to do with the Fire Nation.
That's so unfair!
Just when I think I'm one
step ahead of the Fire Nation,
it turns out they beat
us here a long time ago.
I need to know what happened
on the darkest day.
Hello, little weird fox guy.
Seems it's trying to assist you.
Um, sure, I'll guess I'll follow you.
This room is a true marvel.
A mechanical wonder!
It's a planetarium that
shows the heavens moving.
Uh, this is beautiful,
but, how is it helpful?
Maybe these dials represent
dates and times.
Sokka, try entering that
date from the parchment you took.
Shh, Katara
Not in front of the fox, he's with the owl.
Wow, I gotta hand it to you Sokka. You
picked the best mini-vacation, for sure.
Hey wait, what happened to the sun?
Great, you must have broken it.
It's not broken.
The sun is behind the moon,
it's a solar eclipse!
It's literally the darkest day
in Fire Nation history. Now I get it!
Something awful happened on that day,
I don't know what, but I do know why.
Firebenders loose their
bending during a solar eclipse!
Sorry
That makes sense.
I mean, think of what the lunar eclipse
at the North Pole did to the waterbenders.
This is huge.
Fine, you earned it.
We've got to get this information
to the Earth King at Ba Sing Se.
We'll wait for the next eclipse, then we'll invade
the Fire Nation when they're totally helpless.
The Fire Lord is goin' down!
Mortals are so predictable.
And such terrible liars.
You betrayed my trust.
From the beginning you intended to
misuse this knowledge for evil purposes.
You don't understand. If anyone's
evil, it's the Fire Nation.
You saw what they did to your library.
They're destructive and dangerous.
We need this information.
You think you're the first person
to believe their war was justified?
Countless others before you have come here, seeking
weapons or weaknesses or battle strategies.
We had no choice.
Please, we're just desperate
to protect the people we love.
And now I'm going to protect what I love.
What are you doing?
I'm taking my knowledge back.
No one will ever abuse it again.
He's sinking the building!
We've gotta get out of here!
I'm afraid I can't allow that.
You already know too much.
I already told you, I
don't want to snuggle.
Library's sinking
Library's sinking!
Great knowledge spirit, I beg you.
Do not destroy your vast
collection of priceless tomes.
We've gotta get back to the surface.
Sokka, let's go!
But we still don't know when
the next eclipse is gonna happen.
Don't be stupid, we'll find out later.
No, we won't.
If we leave this place we'll
never get the information.
Aang, come with me to
the planetarium, I need cover.
Katara, take Momo and get out of here.
But
Go£¡
Hurry, Sokka
What is it now?
Who's there?
Why are we doing this?
Because if this calendar can
tell us about eclipses in the past,
then maybe it can project
when the next one will be.
You can't possibly check every single date.
I don't have to.
We just have to check every
date before Sozin's comet arrives,
because after that...
Well, try not to think about that.
Come on eclipse!
That's it, the solar eclipse!
It's just a few months away.
Got it. Now, let's get to Ba Sing Se.
Don't make me put this down.
No, stop sinking.
NO
I'm sorry Appa.
At least I'll have one specimen
to add to my collection.
Your waterbending won't
do you much good here.
I've studied Northern Water Style, Southern
Water Style, even Foggy Swamp Style.
That's called Sokka style. Learn it!
Wait! Professor, let's go!
I'm not leaving. I can't. I've spent
too long trying to find this place.
There's not another collection
of knowledge like this on Earth.
I could spend an eternity in here.
Just go!
We got it. There's a solar eclipse coming.
The Fire Nation's in trouble, now!
Where's Appa?
-=To be Continued=-
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk