How could you let them take
Appa? Why didn't you stop them?
I couldn't! The library was sinking!
You guys were still inside and...
You could have come to
get us! I could have saved him!
I can hardly feel any vibrations out here.
The sandbenders snuck up on
me and there wasn't time for...
You just didn't care! You never
liked Appa! You wanted him gone!
Aang, stop it. You know Toph did all she could.
She saved our lives.
Who's going to save our lives
now? We'll never make it out of here.
That's all any of you guys
care about yourselves!
You don't care whether Appa is okay or not!
We're all concerned, but we
can't afford to be fighting now.
I'm going after Appa.
Aang, wait!
We'd better start walking. We're the only
people who know about the solar eclipse.
We have to get that
information to Ba Sing Se.
You think if we dig out the
giant owl, he'll give us a ride?
Maybe we should make camp.
No, please, don't stop just for me!
What now?
Colonel Mongke! What a pleasant surprise!
If you're surprised we're here then the
Dragon of the West has lost a few steps.
You know these guys?
Sure. Colonel Mongke and
the Rough Riders are legendary.
Each one is a different
kind of weapons specialist.
They are also a very capable singing group.
We're not here to give a concert.
We're here to apprehend fugitives!
Would you like some tea first?
I'd love some. How about you, Kachi?
I make you as a jasmine man. Am I right?
Enough stalling! Round 'em up!
It's nice to see old friends.
Too bad you don't have any old
friends that don't want to attack you.
Hmm... Old friends that
don't want to attack me...
Can't you watch where you're...
No.
Right. Sorry.
Come on guys, we've got to stick together.
If I sweat any more, I don't think
sticking together will be a problem.
Katara, can I have some water?
Okay, but we've got to try to conserve it.
We're drinking your bending water?
You used this on the swamp guy!
It does taste swampy.
I'm sorry, it's all we have.
Not anymore! Look!
Sokka, wait! You shouldn't
be eating strange plants!
There's water trapped inside these!
I don't know...
Suit yourself. It's very
thirst-quenching, though.
Drink cactus juice.
It'll quench ya! Nothing's quenchier.
It's the quenchiest!
Okay, I think you've had enough.
Who lit Toph on fire?
Can I get some of that cactus?
I don't think that's a good idea.
Come on, we need to find Aang.
How did we get out here
in the middle of the ocean?
Uhhh...
Appa!
No...
No!
What is that?
What? What is what?
It's a giant mushroom!
Maybe it's friendly!
Let's just keep moving.
I hope Aang's okay...
Friendly mushroom! Mushy giant friend!
Yeah, a little barefoot blind girl and her
friends passed through here a few days ago.
Did they give you any indication
where they were headed?
Maybe you could give me a little incentive?
You suggesting I break your fingers?
They went in the desert! Too bad
there's almost no chance they survived.
That's okay, since she's
wanted dead or alive.
No she's not! I'm certain
her father wants her alive.
Hey, look... Fire Nation wanted posters!
So?
So, look who's here.
I'm sorry, Aang. I know
it's hard for you right now, ...
but we need to focus
on getting out of here.
What's the difference?
We won't survive without Appa.
We all know it.
Come on, Aang! We can
do this if we work together.
Right Toph?
As far as I can feel, we're trapped
in a giant bowl of sand pudding.
I got nothin'.
Sokka? Any ideas how to find Ba Sing Se?
Why don't we ask the circle birds?
Ugh... We're getting out of this desert,
and we're going to do it together!
Aang, get up. Everybody hold hands.
We can do this.
We have to.
I think we should stop for the night.
Is there any more water?
This is the last of it.
Everyone can have a little drink.
Momo, no! You've killed us all!
No, he hasn't.
Oh, right. Bending.
Sokka, let me see the things
you got from the library.
What!? I didn't steal
anything! Who told you that?
It was you! You ratted me out!
Sokka, I was there.
It doesn't matter. None of
those will tell us where Appa is.
No, but we can find out
which way Ba Sing Se is.
We can use the stars to guide us.
That way we can travel at night
when it's cool and rest during the day.
Just try to get some sleep.
We'll start again in a few hours.
No one here is going to help us. These
people just look like filthy wanderers.
So do we.
Ah, this is interesting.
I think I've found our friend.
You brought us here to gamble on Pai Sho?
I don't think this is a gamble.
Let's take them now!
This place is full of desperate characters.
If they find out we're
collecting a bounty, ...
we might have to fight them
all just to keep our prize. Patience.
May I have this game?
The guest has the first move.
I see you favor the white lotus gambit.
Not many still cling to the ancient ways.
Those who do can always find a friend.
Then let us play.
Welcome, brother. The White Lotus
opens wide to those who know her secrets.
What are you old gasbags talking about?
I always tried to tell you that
Pai Sho is more than just a game.
I'm not waiting all night for
these geezers to finish yapping!
It's over! You two fugitives
are coming with me!
I knew it! You two are wanted criminals
with a giant bounty on your heads!
I thought you said he would help!
He is. Just watch.
You think you're going to capture
them and collect all that gold?
Gold?
Uh... Maybe we shouldn't.
Come on, get up. We need to go.
Yesterday my mouth tasted like mud.
Now it just tastes like sand.
I never thought I'd miss
the taste of mud so much.
I'm awake. I couldn't sleep.
Well, we need to get moving if
we want to get out of this sand pit.
Appa!
Appa? But why would Princess Yue need him?
She's the moon! She flies by herself!
It's just a cloud.
Wait! A cloud!
Here, fly up and bend the water
from that cloud into my pouch.
Wow... there's hardly any in here.
I'm sorry, okay! It's a desert cloud.
I did all I could!
What's anyone else doing!
What are you doing?
Trying to keep everyone together.
Let's just get moving.
We need to head in this direction.
Ow! Crud! I am so sick
of not feeling where I'm going!
And what idiot buried a
boat in the middle of the desert?
A boat?
Believe me, I kicked it hard
enough to feel plenty of vibrations.
It's one of the gliders
the sandbenders use!
And look! It's got some
kind of compass on it!
I bet it can point us out of here!
Aang, you can bend a breeze so we can sail it.
We're going to make it!
It is an honor to welcome
such a high-ranking member...
of the Order of the White Lotus.
Being a Grand Master,
you must know so many secrets.
Now that you played Pai Sho, are
you going to do some flower arranging, ...
or is this club going
to offer some real help?
You must forgive my nephew.
He is not an initiate and has little
appreciation for the cryptic arts.
Who knocks at the guarded gate?
One who has eaten the
fruit and tasted its mysteries.
I'm afraid it's members only.
Wait out here.
The needle on this compass doesn't seem to
be pointing north according to my charts.
Take it easy little lady.
I'm sure the sand folks who built
this baby know how to get around here.
That's what the compass
is pointing to! That giant rock!
It must be the magnetic
center of the desert.
A rock? Yes! Let's go!
Maybe we can find some water there!
Maybe we can find some sandbenders.
Ahhh... Finally! Solid ground!
I think my head is starting to
clear out the cactus juice. And look!
This tastes like rotten penguin meat!
Awww I feel woozy.
You've been hallucinating
on cactus juice all day and then...
you just lick something you
find stuck to the wall of a cave?
I have a natural curiosity.
I don't think this is a normal cave.
This was carved by something.
Yeah... look at the shape.
There's something buzzing in here.
Something that's coming for us!
What are you doing?
That rock almost crushed me!
Sorry, I can't tell where
they are in the air!
I got this one.
Sokka, there's nothing there.
I guess my head's not
as clear as I thought.
We have to get out of here!
I'm completely out of water to bend!
Momo!
I'm not losing anyone else out here.
Come on, we're going down.
Toph, shoot a rock right there.
Fire!
Yeah! You got it! She got it, right?
Yes. Now let's move.
On your left!
What's going on? Is the club meeting over?
Everything is taken care of.
We're heading to Ba Sing Se.
Ba Sing Se? Why would we
go to the Earth Kingdom capital?
The city is filled with refugees.
No one will notice two more.
We can hide in plain sight there.
And it's the safest place
in the world from the Fire Nation.
Even I couldn't break through to the city.
I have the passports for our guests, ...
but there are two men out
on the streets looking for them.
You seen these guys?
What are you doing in our
land with a sandbender sailer?
From the looks of it, you
stole it from the Hami tribe.
We found the sailer
abandoned in the desert.
We're traveling with the Avatar.
Our bison was stolen and
we have to get to Ba Sing Se.
You dare accuse our people of theft
while you ride in on a stolen sand sailer?
Quiet, Gashuin. No one
accused our people of anything.
If what they say is true,
we must give them hospitality.
Sorry, father.
I recognize the son's voice.
He's the one that stole Appa.
Are you sure?
I never forget a voice.
You stole Appa! Where
is he? What did you do to him?
They're lying! They're the thieves!
Where is my bison?
Hey you, where are these men?
I got a tip that they're in your shop.
As you can see, no one is here but us.
We know all about your secret back room.
Kick it down.
Hey! That room is for flowers only!
Some unlucky soul has an
incomplete Pai Sho set.
Let's go back to finding the girl.
You tell me where he is now!
What did you do?
I... It wasn't me!
You said to put a muzzle on him!
You muzzled Appa?
I'm sorry! I didn't know
that it belonged to the Avatar!
Tell me where Appa is!
I traded him! To some merchants!
He's probably in Ba Sing Se by now!
They were going to sell him there!
Please! We'll escort you out of
the desert! We'll help however we can!
Just get out of here! Run!
Subtitle by rendy1287
Fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk