Water,
Earth,
Fire,
Air,
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the fire nation attacked.
Only the avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother and i
discovered the new avatar,
an airbender named aang
And although his
airbending skills are great
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But i believe aang
can save the world.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
The Fire Nation
killed my parents.
I was only 8 years old.
Hello! My name is Joo Dee.
We found out about the solar eclipse
that lead the Fire Nation defenseless.
It is the strict policy of Ba Sing Se that
the war not to be mention within the walls.
You don't understand, they are Fire
Nation, you have to believe me!
There is no war within the walls.
Here we are safe.
Here, we are free.
I understand have been
looking for your bison.
It would be quite a shame if you're
not able to complete your quest.
We found a printer to make our posters.
Hey, I thought designing "the
lost Appa poster" was my job.
I've been working all day on my Appa.
Sokka, the arrow is on Appa's head.
This IS his head.
Why are feet coming out of it?
Those are his horns!
I haven't seen him awhile ok?
It looks just like him to me.
Thank you, I worked really...
why do feel the need to do that?
Let's just stick with
the professional version.
Grrrr!
Come on, let's get busy!
So you're the genius
behind this incredible brew.
The whole city is buzzing about you.
I hope Pao pays you well.
Good tea is its own reward.
But it doesn't have to be the only reward.
How would you like to
have your own tea shop?
My own tea shop? This is a dream come true.
What's going on here?
Are you trying to poach my tea maker?
Sorry Pao, that's business for you,
am I right?
Mushie, if you stay,
I will make you Assistant Manager.
Wait, Senior Assistant manager.
I'll provide you with a new
apartment in the upper ring.
The Tea shop is yours
to do whatever you want.
Complete creative freedom.
I even get to name the shop?
Of course!
Uh, Senior Executive Assistant Manager?
Did you hear nephew?
This man wants to give us
our own tea shop
in the upper ring of the city.
That's right young man.
You're life is about
to change for the better.
I'll try to contain my joy.
I just finished dropping all the leaflets.
Has anyone come in with news about Appa?
It's only been a day, just be patient.
Wow, you're right!
Patience really pays off.
Joo Dee?
Hello, Aang and Katara and Sokka and Toph.
What happened to you?
Did the Dai Li throw you in jail?
What, jail? Of course not.
The Dai Li are the protectors
of our cultural heritage.
But you disappeared
at the Earth King's party.
Oh, I simply took a short
vacation to Lake Laogai,
out in the country.
It was quite relaxing.
But then they replaced you
with some other woman
who also said her name was Joo Dee.
I'm Joo Dee.
Why are you here?
Dropping flyers and putting up posters
isn't permitted within the city.
Not without proper clearance.
We can't wait around to
get permission for everything.
You are absolutely forbidden
by the rules of the city
to continue putting up posters.
WE DON'T CARE ABOUT THE RULES,
AND WE'RE NOT ASKING PERMISSON!
We're finding Appa on our own and
you should just stay out of our way!
That might come back
to bite us in the blubber.
I don't care.
From now on we do whatever it
takes to find Appa.
YEAH!
Let's break some rules!
I am very disappointed in your work
with the Avatar and his friends, Joo Dee.
I had hoped that you would
be able to control this situation.
I'm so sorry,
but they don't trust me anymore.
I don't think I can keep working like this.
Joo Dee, the Earth King
has invited you to Lake Laogai.
I am honored to accept his invitation.
Good. Now go await further orders.
If the Avatar keeps
searching for his bison,
it could upset the delicate balance
we worked so hard to achieve in this city.
It could even cost us
control of the Earth King.
Should we take care of him?
No. It's much too dangerous
to confront him directly.
Let's see if we can still handle this...
quietly.
So, I was thinking about
names for my new tea shop.
How about the Jasmine Dragon?
It's dramatic, poetic,
has a nice ring to it.
The Avatar's here in Ba Sing Se.
And he's lost his bison.
We have a chance for a new life here.
If you start stirring up trouble,
we could lose all the good
things that are happening for us.
Good things that are happening for you.
Have you ever thought that
I want more from life
than a nice apartment
and a job serving tea?
There is nothing wrong with
a life of peace and prosperity.
I suggest you think about what it
is that you want for your life, and why.
I want my destiny.
What that means is up to you.
The Tea Weevil!
No, that's stupid.
Well split up to cover more area.
Toph, I guess you should just come with me.
Why because you think I
can't put up posters on my own?
It's upside-down isn't it?
I'll just go with Sokka.
Katara?
I think I can help you.
Katara! I've changed!
Tell it to some other girl, Jet!
I don't want to fight you!
I'm here to help.
Katara, what is it?
Jet's back.
We can't trust anything Jet says.
But we don't' even know why he's here.
I don't care why he's here.
Whatever the reason is, it can't be good.
I'm here to help you find Appa.
Katara, we have to give him a chance.
I swear, I've changed.
I was a troubled person,
and I let my anger get out of control.
But I don't even have the gang now.
I've put all that behind me.
You're lying!
He's not lying.
How can you tell?
I can feel his breathing and heart beat.
When people lie,
there is a physical reaction.
He's telling the truth.
Katara, we don't have any leads.
If Jet says he can take us to Appa,
we have to check it out.
Alright...
but we're not letting you out of out sight!
This is the place I heard about.
There's nothing here.
If this is a trap!?
I told you, I work nearby!
Two guys were talking about
some giant furry creature they had.
I figured it must be Appa.
He was here!
We missed him.
They took that big thing yesterday.
Shipped him out to some island.
About time, I've been cleaning up fur
and various, uh leavings all day.
What island!?
Where's Appa?!
Foreman said some rich royal type
on Whaletail Island bought him up,
guess for a zoo or such, though
could be the meat would be good.
We've gotta get to Whaletail Island.
Where's whale tail island?
Far. Very far.
Here it is. It's near the South
Pole almost all the way back home.
Aang, It'll take us weeks just
to get to the tip of the earth kingdom.
And then we'll need to find
a boat to get to the island.
I don't care.
We have a chance to find Appa.
We have to try.
Must be nice to visit an island.
I haven't had a vacation for years.
Don't you have some more hair to clean up?
Shuffle on, I get ya.
No more need for "old sweepy".
You're right Aang.
Right now, our first concern
has to be finding Appa.
We can come back when we have him.
All right, let's get moving.
I'll come with you.
We don't need your help.
Why won't you trust me?
Gee, I wonder?
Was this guy your boyfriend or something?
What? No!
I can tell you're lyyyyying.
We can take the train out to the wall,
but then we'll have to walk.
Don't worry, on the way
back, we'll be flying!
We're finally leaving Ba Sing Se.
Worst city ever!
Jet!
I thought you said you
didn't have your gang anymore?
I don't.
We were so worried.
How did you get away from the Dai Li?
The Dai Li?!
I don't know what she's talking about?
He got arrested by the Dai
Li a couple weeks ago.
We saw them drag him away.
Why would I be arrested?
I've been living peacefully in the city.
This doesn't make any sense.
They're both telling the truth.
That's impossible.
No, it's not.
Toph can't tell who's lying because
they both think they're telling the truth.
Jet's been brainwashed.
That's crazy! It can't be.
Stay away from me.
Out of my way, skinny.
Huh?
If you don't want to end up like him.
You'll do what I say.
The Dai Li must have
sent Jet to mislead us,
and that janitor was
part of their plot too.
I bet they have Appa here in the city.
Maybe he's in the same place they took Jet.
Where did they take you?
Nowhere.
I, I don't know what you're talking about.
We need to find a way to
jog his real memories.
Maybe Katara could kiss him.
That should bring something back.
Maybe you should kiss him, Sokka.
Hey, just an idea.
A bad one.
Oo, wait. I got it.
I don't think its working. Puh!
Try to think of something from
your past that triggers your emotions.
The Fire Nation,
remember what they did to your family.
Close your eyes.
Picture it.
No! It's too painful.
Maybe this will help.
They took me to a headquarters
under the water, like a lake.
Wait! Remember what Joo Dee said?
She said she went on
vacation to Lake Laogai.
That's it! Lake Laogai.
So where's this secret headquarters?
Under the water I think.
There's a tunnel right
there near the shore.
It's all starting to come back to me.
I'm Joo Dee. Welcome to Ba Sing Se.
We are so lucky to have
our walls to create order.
I think there might be a cell
big enough to hold Appa up ahead.
I think it's through here.
Expecting someone else?
Now that's something different.
You have made yourselves
enemies of the state.
Take them into custody.
Long Feng is escaping!
Alright Avatar, you've
caused me enough problems.
This is your last chance,
if you want your bison back.
You do have Appa.
Tell me where he is!
Agree to exit the city now,
and I'll waive all charges against you
and allow you to leave with your lost pet.
You're in no position to bargain.
Am I not?
You're definitely not!
Jet, The Earth King has
invited you to Lake Laogai.
I am honored to except his invitation.
You're mine now.
Uncle?
So, the Blue Spirit.
I wonder who could be behind that mask?
What are you doing here?
I was just about to ask you the same thing.
What do you plan to do now that
you have found the Avatar's bison?
Keep it locked in our new apartment?
Should I go put on a pot of tea for him?
First I have to get it out of here.
AND THEN WHAT?!
You never think these things through!
This is exactly what happened
when you captured the
Avatar at the North Pole!
You had him, and then
you had no where to go!
I would have figured something out!
No! If his friends hadn't found you,
you would have frozen to death!
I know my own destiny uncle.
Is it your own destiny?
Or is it a destiny someone
else has tried to force on you?
Stop it Uncle.
I have to do this.
I'm begging you Prince Zuko!
It's time for you to look inward,
and begin asking yourself
the big questions.
Who are you?
And what do you want?
Jet, it's me Aang!
You don't have to do this.
I'm afraid he no longer has a choice.
Jet, I'm your friend!
Look inside your heart!
Do your duty Jet.
He can't make you do this!
You're a Freedom Fighter.
Do it! Do it now!
Foolish boy. You've chosen your own demise.
I'm sorry, Aang.
Don't be.
This isn't good.
You guys go find Appa.
We'll take care of Jet.
We're not going to leave you.
There's no time.
Just go.
We'll take care of him.
He's our leader.
Don't worry Katara, I'll be fine.
He's lying.
Appa's gone. Long Feng beat us here.
If we keep moving, maybe
we can catch up to him.
Do you think we can out run them?
I don't think it's gonna matter.
What is it Momo?
Appa!
I can handle you by myself.
Yeah! Appa!
I missed you, buddy.
You did the right thing, nephew.
Leave it behind.
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk