1
00:00:00,649 --> 00:00:03,021
<i>Water.</i>

2
00:00:03,022 --> 00:00:04,895
<i>Earth.</i>

3
00:00:04,896 --> 00:00:07,004
<i>Fire.</i>

4
00:00:07,005 --> 00:00:08,296
<i>Air.</i>

5
00:00:09,362 --> 00:00:13,496
<i>Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.</i>

6
00:00:13,497 --> 00:00:17,575
<i>Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.</i>

7
00:00:17,776 --> 00:00:21,888
<i>Only the Avatar, master of
all four elements, could stop them.</i>

8
00:00:21,889 --> 00:00:25,048
<i>But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.</i>

9
00:00:25,049 --> 00:00:29,210
<i>A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar...</i>

10
00:00:29,211 --> 00:00:31,050
<i>an airbender named Aang.</i>

11
00:00:31,051 --> 00:00:33,256
<i>And although his airbending
skills are great.</i>

12
00:00:33,257 --> 00:00:36,989
<i>He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.</i>

13
00:00:36,990 --> 00:00:40,612
<i>But I believe Aang
can save the world.</i>

14
00:00:53,701 --> 00:00:55,731
You guys are gonna be done soon, right?

15
00:00:55,732 --> 00:00:58,756
We've got a lot of ground to cover
if we wanna make it to Omashu today.

16
00:00:58,757 --> 00:01:01,885
What, like you're ready
to go right now, naked guy?

17
00:01:01,911 --> 00:01:05,389
I can be ready in two minutes.
Seriously. Whenever.

18
00:01:05,417 --> 00:01:07,970
So, you were showing me the octopus form.

19
00:01:07,990 --> 00:01:11,439
Right. Let me see your stance.

20
00:01:13,609 --> 00:01:15,256
Your arms are too far apart.

21
00:01:15,257 --> 00:01:18,860
See, if you move them closer together
you protect your center. You got it?

22
00:01:18,861 --> 00:01:22,322
Oh... yeah. Thanks.

23
00:01:22,680 --> 00:01:25,384
Okay, let's see what you got.

24
00:01:42,078 --> 00:01:45,721
You make a fine octopus, Pupil Aang.

25
00:01:53,477 --> 00:02:01,351
♫ Don't fall in love with a traveling girl.
She'll leave you broke and broken hearted... ♫

26
00:02:02,684 --> 00:02:04,819
Heh-hey! River people!

27
00:02:04,856 --> 00:02:06,337
We're not river people.

28
00:02:06,358 --> 00:02:09,710
You're not?
Well then what kind of people are ya?

29
00:02:09,751 --> 00:02:11,546
Just... people.

30
00:02:11,561 --> 00:02:14,337
Aren't we all, brother? Whoo...

31
00:02:14,338 --> 00:02:15,255
Who're you?

32
00:02:15,256 --> 00:02:17,760
I'm Chong, and this is my wife Lily.

33
00:02:17,777 --> 00:02:22,780
We're nomads, happy to
go wherever the wind takes us!

34
00:02:22,812 --> 00:02:26,616
You guys are nomads?
That's great! I'm a nomad.

35
00:02:26,634 --> 00:02:28,538
Hey, me too.

36
00:02:28,551 --> 00:02:30,975
I know... you just said that.

37
00:02:30,981 --> 00:02:35,159
Oh. Nice underwear.

38
00:02:41,474 --> 00:02:45,044
I didn't find anything to eat.
I can't live like this.

39
00:02:45,062 --> 00:02:49,215
I wasn't meant to be a fugitive.
This is impossible!

40
00:02:49,216 --> 00:02:51,988
Uncle… what are you doing?

41
00:02:52,014 --> 00:02:55,018
You're looking at the
rare white dragon bush.

42
00:02:55,031 --> 00:03:00,210
Its leaves make a tea so
delicious it's heartbreaking!

43
00:03:00,231 --> 00:03:05,094
That, or it's the white
jade bush, which is poisonous.

44
00:03:05,113 --> 00:03:08,874
We need food, not tea. I'm going fishing.

45
00:03:08,903 --> 00:03:14,640
Hm, delectable tea? Or deadly poison?

46
00:03:18,770 --> 00:03:21,485
Hey, Sokka, you should
hear some of these stories.

47
00:03:21,499 --> 00:03:23,264
These guys have been everywhere.

48
00:03:23,286 --> 00:03:25,934
Well, not everywhere, Little Arrowhead.

49
00:03:25,950 --> 00:03:30,976
But where we haven't been we've
heard about through stories and songs.

50
00:03:30,991 --> 00:03:33,706
They said they'll take us
to see a giant night crawler.

51
00:03:33,723 --> 00:03:38,645
On the way there's a waterfall
that creates a never-ending rainbow.

52
00:03:38,674 --> 00:03:43,313
Look, I hate to be the wet blanket here but
since Katara is busy I guess it's up to me.

53
00:03:43,332 --> 00:03:49,535
We need to get to Omashu. No sidetracks,
no worms, and definitely no rainbows.

54
00:03:49,547 --> 00:03:55,139
Whoa… sounds like someone's got
a case of "destination fever," heh.

55
00:03:55,150 --> 00:03:57,792
You're worried too much
about where you're going.

56
00:03:57,803 --> 00:04:01,940
You've gotta focus less on the
"where" and more on the "going."

57
00:04:01,959 --> 00:04:05,674
O... ma... shu...

58
00:04:05,693 --> 00:04:07,823
Sokka's right. We need to find King Bumi...

59
00:04:07,838 --> 00:04:10,383
so Aang can learn
earthbending somewhere safe.

60
00:04:10,426 --> 00:04:13,613
Well, sounds like you're headed to Omashu.

61
00:04:13,626 --> 00:04:20,085
There's an old story about a secret pass.
.. right through the mountains.

62
00:04:20,104 --> 00:04:22,216
Is this real or a legend?

63
00:04:22,228 --> 00:04:28,470
Oh, it's a real legend. And
it's as old as earthbending itself.

64
00:04:29,827 --> 00:04:39,102
♫ Two lovers, forbidden from one another.
.. a war divides their people, ... ♫

65
00:04:39,122 --> 00:04:44,136
♫ ...and a mountain divides them apart. ♫

66
00:04:44,883 --> 00:04:50,537
♫ Built a path to be together. ♫

67
00:04:50,559 --> 00:04:53,799
Yeah, and I forget the next
couple of lines, but then it goes...

68
00:04:53,806 --> 00:05:01,074
♫ Secret tunnel! Secret
tunnel! Through the mountain! ♫

69
00:05:01,099 --> 00:05:07,410
♫ Secret, secret, secret,
secret tunnel! Yeah! ♫

70
00:05:08,508 --> 00:05:10,559
I think we'll just stick with flying.

71
00:05:10,593 --> 00:05:14,149
We've dealt with the Fire Nation before.
We'll be fine.

72
00:05:14,170 --> 00:05:17,193
Yeah. Thanks for the help,
but Appa hates going underground...

73
00:05:17,236 --> 00:05:20,874
and we need to do whatever
makes Appa most comfortable.

74
00:05:20,886 --> 00:05:22,593
Launch!

75
00:05:28,457 --> 00:05:31,579
Secret love cave. Let's go.

76
00:05:39,210 --> 00:05:43,305
Zuko, remember that plant
I thought might be tea?

77
00:05:43,318 --> 00:05:44,802
You didn't!

78
00:05:44,837 --> 00:05:48,169
I did. And it wasn't.

79
00:05:48,972 --> 00:05:52,798
When the rash spreads to
my throat I will stop breathing.

80
00:05:52,817 --> 00:05:56,417
But look what I found!
These are bacui berries, ...

81
00:05:56,429 --> 00:06:00,236
known to cure the poison
of the white jade plant.

82
00:06:00,252 --> 00:06:04,466
That, or macahoni berries
that cause blindness.

83
00:06:04,492 --> 00:06:08,849
We're not taking any more chances
with these plants! We need to get help.

84
00:06:08,862 --> 00:06:11,085
But where are we going to go?

85
00:06:11,102 --> 00:06:17,541
We're enemies of the Earth Kingdom,
and fugitives from the Fire Nation.

86
00:06:17,549 --> 00:06:20,930
If the Earth Kingdom, discovers
us, they'll have us killed.

87
00:06:20,943 --> 00:06:26,890
But if the Fire Nation discovers
us, we'll be turned over to Azula.

88
00:06:26,917 --> 00:06:29,720
Earth Kingdom it is.

89
00:06:29,750 --> 00:06:31,429
How far are we from the tunnel.

90
00:06:31,446 --> 00:06:33,761
Actually, it's not just one tunnel.

91
00:06:33,774 --> 00:06:37,067
The lovers didn't want anyone
to find out about their love, ...

92
00:06:37,080 --> 00:06:40,102
so they built a whole labyrinth.

93
00:06:40,125 --> 00:06:41,388
Labyrinth?!

94
00:06:41,414 --> 00:06:44,365
I'm sure we'll figure it out.

95
00:06:45,103 --> 00:06:51,174
All you need to do is trust in love.
According to the curse.

96
00:06:54,533 --> 00:06:56,386
Curse?!

97
00:06:56,873 --> 00:06:59,364
Hey-hey, we're here!

98
00:06:59,386 --> 00:07:01,821
What exactly is this curse?

99
00:07:01,836 --> 00:07:06,435
The curse says that only those who trust
in love can make it through the caves.

100
00:07:06,454 --> 00:07:08,846
Otherwise you'll be
trapped in them forever.

101
00:07:08,865 --> 00:07:10,090
And die.

102
00:07:10,114 --> 00:07:16,477
Oh, yeah, and die. Hey, I just
remembered the rest of that song.

103
00:07:16,478 --> 00:07:19,258
♫ And die! ♫

104
00:07:19,276 --> 00:07:24,047
That's it! There's no way we're
going through some cursed hole!

105
00:07:24,069 --> 00:07:27,825
Hey, someone's making a big campfire!

106
00:07:27,841 --> 00:07:29,994
That's no campfire, Moku.

107
00:07:30,007 --> 00:07:33,251
That's Fire Nation. They're tracking us.

108
00:07:33,269 --> 00:07:36,318
So all you need is to trust
in love to get through these caves?

109
00:07:36,333 --> 00:07:40,435
That is correct, Master Arrowhead.

110
00:07:44,793 --> 00:07:46,119
We can make it.

111
00:07:46,130 --> 00:07:48,710
Everyone into the hole!

112
00:07:58,213 --> 00:08:02,669
Hold on! It's too dangerous.
Haven't you heard the song?

113
00:08:02,675 --> 00:08:07,886
Just close them in. The
mount will take care of the rest.

114
00:08:23,048 --> 00:08:26,720
It's okay, Appa. We'll be fine. I hope.

115
00:08:26,743 --> 00:08:31,458
We will be fine. All we need is a plan.
Chong, how long do those torches last?

116
00:08:31,481 --> 00:08:33,617
Eh, about two hours each.

117
00:08:33,634 --> 00:08:37,148
And we have five torches so that's...
ten hours.

118
00:08:37,163 --> 00:08:40,529
It doesn't work like that if
they're all lit at the same time!

119
00:08:40,548 --> 00:08:42,273
Ohh, right.

120
00:08:42,281 --> 00:08:45,719
I'm gonna make a map to keep
track of exactly where we've been.

121
00:08:45,726 --> 00:08:50,237
Then we should be able to solve
it like a maze and get through.

122
00:08:58,487 --> 00:09:00,994
You two must not be from around here.

123
00:09:01,008 --> 00:09:03,526
We know better than to
touch the white jade, ...

124
00:09:03,543 --> 00:09:07,184
much less make it into tea and drink it.

125
00:09:08,659 --> 00:09:10,407
So where are you traveling from?

126
00:09:10,423 --> 00:09:12,103
Yes, we're travelers.

127
00:09:12,109 --> 00:09:14,015
Do you have names?

128
00:09:14,028 --> 00:09:23,785
Names? Of course we have names. I'm.
.. Lee. And this is my uncle, uh... Mushi.

129
00:09:23,811 --> 00:09:29,138
Yes, my nephew was named after
his father, so we just call him Junior.

130
00:09:29,159 --> 00:09:32,790
Mushi and Junior, huh? My name is Song.

131
00:09:32,807 --> 00:09:36,947
You two look like you could use a good meal.
Why don't you stay for dinner?

132
00:09:36,981 --> 00:09:39,559
Sorry, but we need to be moving on.

133
00:09:39,599 --> 00:09:42,991
That's too bad. My mom always
makes too much roast duck.

134
00:09:43,009 --> 00:09:45,640
Where do you live, exactly?

135
00:09:46,859 --> 00:09:50,009
Sokka, this is the tenth
dead end you've led us to.

136
00:09:50,010 --> 00:09:53,348
This doesn't make any sense,
we already came through this way.

137
00:09:53,366 --> 00:09:58,753
We don't need a map. We just need love.
The little guy knows it.

138
00:09:58,772 --> 00:10:01,729
Yeah, but I wouldn't mind a map, also.

139
00:10:01,753 --> 00:10:04,308
There's something strange here.

140
00:10:04,323 --> 00:10:09,927
There's only one explanation.
The tunnels are changing.

141
00:10:15,340 --> 00:10:20,177
My daughter tells me you're refugees.
We were once refugees ourselves.

142
00:10:20,207 --> 00:10:24,518
When I was a little girl, the
Fire Nation raided our farming village.

143
00:10:24,527 --> 00:10:30,736
All the men were taken away. That
was the last time I saw my father.

144
00:10:30,770 --> 00:10:33,971
I haven't seen my father in many years.

145
00:10:34,026 --> 00:10:37,759
Oh. Is he fighting in the war?

146
00:10:40,534 --> 00:10:42,137
Yeah.

147
00:10:46,824 --> 00:10:51,214
The tunnels... they're a-changin'.
Ah, it must be the curse.

148
00:10:51,264 --> 00:10:54,164
I knew we shouldn't have come down here.

149
00:10:54,180 --> 00:10:57,038
Right. If only we listened to you.

150
00:10:57,054 --> 00:11:00,762
Everyone be quiet. Listen.

151
00:11:12,504 --> 00:11:15,528
It's a giant flying thing with teeth!

152
00:11:15,934 --> 00:11:18,796
No! It's a wolf-bat!

153
00:12:06,070 --> 00:12:12,496
Yeah, it's no use. We're separated.
But at least you have us, heh heh.

154
00:12:12,527 --> 00:12:15,560
Noooooooo!

155
00:12:24,536 --> 00:12:27,912
Can I join you?
I know what you've been through.

156
00:12:27,917 --> 00:12:33,988
We've all been through it.
The Fire Nation has hurt you.

157
00:12:38,987 --> 00:12:43,376
It's okay. They've hurt me, too.

158
00:12:51,493 --> 00:12:55,792
♫ Oh, don't let the cave in get you down. ♫

159
00:12:55,816 --> 00:13:01,219
♫ Don't let the falling rocks
turn your smile into a frown. ♫

160
00:13:01,236 --> 00:13:07,054
♫ When the tunnels are darkest
that's when you need a clown, hey! ♫

161
00:13:07,519 --> 00:13:12,366
♫ Don't let the cave in
get you down, Sokka! ♫

162
00:13:18,268 --> 00:13:20,411
Aang, look!

163
00:13:20,743 --> 00:13:22,518
We found the exit!

164
00:13:44,181 --> 00:13:45,929
This isn't the exit.

165
00:13:45,961 --> 00:13:49,626
No... it's a tomb.

166
00:14:02,938 --> 00:14:08,352
It must be the two lovers from the legend.
That's who's buried here.

167
00:14:08,361 --> 00:14:11,351
These pictures tell their story.

168
00:14:19,773 --> 00:14:24,059
They met on top of the mountain
that divided their two villages.

169
00:14:24,611 --> 00:14:28,394
The villages were enemies
so they could not be together.

170
00:14:28,792 --> 00:14:32,477
But their love was strong
and they found a way.

171
00:14:32,478 --> 00:14:38,024
The two lovers learned earthbending
from the badger moles.

172
00:14:38,025 --> 00:14:40,630
They became the first earthbenders.

173
00:14:40,653 --> 00:14:44,848
They built elaborate tunnels
so they could meet secretly.

174
00:14:45,144 --> 00:14:49,830
Anyone who tried to follow them
would be lost forever in the labyrinth.

175
00:14:51,221 --> 00:14:54,165
But one day the man didn't come.

176
00:14:55,415 --> 00:14:59,218
He died in the war between
their two villages.

177
00:15:00,637 --> 00:15:05,323
Devastated, the woman unleashed a
terrible display of her earthbending power.

178
00:15:05,324 --> 00:15:07,974
She could have destroyed them all.

179
00:15:09,082 --> 00:15:11,720
But instead she declared the war over.

180
00:15:11,733 --> 00:15:17,591
Both villages helped her build a new city
where they would live together in peace.

181
00:15:17,609 --> 00:15:22,228
The woman's name was Oma
and the man's name was Shu.

182
00:15:22,246 --> 00:15:27,494
The great city was named Omashu
as a monument to their love.

183
00:15:32,257 --> 00:15:36,438
Love is brightest in the dark.

184
00:15:39,213 --> 00:15:43,331
Oh, great! Your plans have
led us to another dead end!

185
00:15:43,342 --> 00:15:48,452
At least I'm thinking of ideas
and trying to get us out of here, Moku.

186
00:15:48,469 --> 00:15:51,216
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute,
we're thinking of ideas?

187
00:15:51,229 --> 00:15:54,447
'Cause I've had an idea
for, like, an hour now.

188
00:15:54,457 --> 00:15:58,423
Yes! We're all thinking of ideas!

189
00:15:58,438 --> 00:16:01,937
Well, then listen to this,
if love is the key out of here, ...

190
00:16:01,940 --> 00:16:06,685
then all we need to
do is play a love song.

191
00:16:09,555 --> 00:16:12,272
How are we gonna find
our way out of these tunnels?

192
00:16:12,290 --> 00:16:14,201
I have a crazy idea.

193
00:16:14,208 --> 00:16:15,694
What?

194
00:16:15,706 --> 00:16:18,080
Never mind, it's too crazy.

195
00:16:18,097 --> 00:16:19,757
Katara, what is it?

196
00:16:19,766 --> 00:16:22,932
I was thinking... the
curse says we'll be trapped...

197
00:16:22,946 --> 00:16:25,410
in here forever unless we trust in love.

198
00:16:25,411 --> 00:16:26,475
Right...

199
00:16:26,476 --> 00:16:32,433
And here it says 'love is brightest in the dark' and.
.. has a picture of them kissing.

200
00:16:32,445 --> 00:16:34,285
Where are you going with this?

201
00:16:34,305 --> 00:16:37,810
Well... what if we kissed?

202
00:16:37,836 --> 00:16:39,384
Us kissing?

203
00:16:39,389 --> 00:16:42,170
See? It was a crazy idea.

204
00:16:42,183 --> 00:16:45,799
Us... kissing...

205
00:16:45,811 --> 00:16:50,542
Us kissing. What was I
thinking? Can you imagine that?

206
00:16:50,557 --> 00:16:55,295
Yeah, heh, heh. I definitely
wouldn't wanna kiss you!

207
00:16:55,313 --> 00:17:00,653
Oh, well I didn't realize it was such
a horrible option. Sorry I suggested it!

208
00:17:00,668 --> 00:17:04,954
No, no, I mean... if there was a
choice between kissing you and dying...

209
00:17:04,970 --> 00:17:06,082
Oh!

210
00:17:06,096 --> 00:17:10,332
What? I'm saying I'd rather kiss you than die.
That's a compliment.

211
00:17:10,350 --> 00:17:14,003
Well I'm not sure which I would rather do!

212
00:17:14,015 --> 00:17:16,891
What is wrong with me?

213
00:17:22,793 --> 00:17:30,850
♫ Even if you're lost you can't lose
the love because it's in your heart. ♫

214
00:17:35,859 --> 00:17:39,290
Thank you for the duck. It was excellent.

215
00:17:39,303 --> 00:17:40,484
You're welcome.

216
00:17:40,501 --> 00:17:44,928
It brings me joy to see someone
eat my cooking with such... gusto.

217
00:17:44,947 --> 00:17:47,762
Much practice.

218
00:17:48,521 --> 00:17:50,939
Junior, where are your manners?

219
00:17:50,940 --> 00:17:54,412
You need to thank these nice people.

220
00:17:54,426 --> 00:17:55,790
Thank you.

221
00:17:55,795 --> 00:18:00,217
I know you don't think there's any
hope left in the world, but there is hope.

222
00:18:00,231 --> 00:18:03,014
The Avatar has returned!

223
00:18:03,023 --> 00:18:05,432
I know.

224
00:18:17,971 --> 00:18:23,000
What are you doing? These people
just showed you great kindness.

225
00:18:23,009 --> 00:18:29,008
They're about to show us
a little more kindness. Well?

226
00:18:42,900 --> 00:18:45,919
We're gonna run out of light
any second now, aren't we?

227
00:18:45,923 --> 00:18:47,225
I think so.

228
00:18:47,233 --> 00:18:50,222
Then what are we gonna do?

229
00:18:50,236 --> 00:18:52,922
What can we do?

230
00:19:36,361 --> 00:19:39,270
Hey-hey, you saved us, Sokka!

231
00:19:39,280 --> 00:19:42,308
No, they were trying to
get away from something.

232
00:19:42,318 --> 00:19:44,422
From what?

233
00:20:25,890 --> 00:20:28,493
Hey, those things are music lovers!

234
00:20:28,575 --> 00:20:35,441
Badger moles, coming toward me.
Come on guys, help me out.

235
00:20:35,450 --> 00:20:38,628
♫ The big bad badger moles
who work in the tunnels, ... ♫

236
00:20:38,644 --> 00:20:43,588
♫ ...hate the wolf bats
but love the sounds. ♫

237
00:20:43,617 --> 00:20:47,998
It's made of some kind of crystals.
They must only light up in the dark!

238
00:20:48,012 --> 00:20:50,243
That's how the two lovers found each other.

239
00:20:50,254 --> 00:20:54,065
They just put out their
lights and followed the crystals.

240
00:20:55,219 --> 00:20:58,001
That must be the way out!

241
00:21:00,004 --> 00:21:01,691
So... um...

242
00:21:01,694 --> 00:21:03,189
Let's go!

243
00:21:22,203 --> 00:21:24,852
What about Sokka?

244
00:21:31,490 --> 00:21:33,620
Sokka!

245
00:21:34,628 --> 00:21:35,885
How did you guys get out?

246
00:21:35,886 --> 00:21:39,178
Just like the legend says,
we let love lead the way.

247
00:21:39,215 --> 00:21:43,701
Really? We let huge ferocious
beasts lead our way.

248
00:21:58,907 --> 00:22:01,328
Why is your forehead all red?

249
00:22:01,338 --> 00:22:10,008
Nobody react to what I'm about to tell you.
I think that kid might be the Avatar.

250
00:22:12,240 --> 00:22:14,877
So, are you guys gonna
come to Omashu with us?

251
00:22:14,878 --> 00:22:15,603
Nope.

252
00:22:15,604 --> 00:22:19,128
Okay. Thanks for everything, Moku.

253
00:22:19,602 --> 00:22:22,483
Sokka, I hope you learned
a little something...

254
00:22:22,484 --> 00:22:28,205
about not letting the plans
get in the way of the journey.

255
00:22:28,221 --> 00:22:30,304
Just play your songs.

256
00:22:30,318 --> 00:22:33,324
Hey, good plan!

257
00:22:35,984 --> 00:22:40,119
♫ Even if you're lost
you can't lose the love... ♫

258
00:22:40,136 --> 00:22:48,743
♫ ...because it's in your heart.
Ooooohhhh... ♫

259
00:22:49,291 --> 00:22:51,594
The journey was long and annoying, ...

260
00:22:51,609 --> 00:22:55,538
but now you get to see what it's really about.
.. the destination.

261
00:22:55,556 --> 00:23:02,222
I present to you the Earth
Kingdom city of O... Oh, no...

262
00:23:07,267 --> 00:23:08,303
Subtitle by rendy1287
Fixed by LEO33

263
00:23:09,182 --> 00:23:09,348
<font color="#ffff00">w</font>ww. leo33.tk

264
00:23:09,349 --> 00:23:09,514
<font color="#ffff00">ww</font>w. leo33.tk

265
00:23:09,515 --> 00:23:09,681
<font color="#ffff00">www</font>.leo33.tk

266
00:23:09,682 --> 00:23:09,848
<font color="#ffff00">www.</font>leo33.tk

267
00:23:09,849 --> 00:23:10,014
<font color="#ffff00">www.l</font>eo33.tk

268
00:23:10,015 --> 00:23:10,181
<font color="#ffff00">www.le</font>o33.tk

269
00:23:10,182 --> 00:23:10,348
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo</font>33.tk

270
00:23:10,349 --> 00:23:10,514
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo3</font>3.tk

271
00:23:10,515 --> 00:23:10,681
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33</font>.tk

272
00:23:10,682 --> 00:23:10,848
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.</font>tk

273
00:23:10,849 --> 00:23:11,014
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.t</font>k

274
00:23:11,015 --> 00:23:13,015
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.tk</font>