1
00:00:00,649 --> 00:00:03,021
<i>Water.</i>

2
00:00:03,022 --> 00:00:04,895
<i>Earth.</i>

3
00:00:04,896 --> 00:00:07,004
<i>Fire.</i>

4
00:00:07,005 --> 00:00:08,296
<i>Air.</i>

5
00:00:09,362 --> 00:00:13,496
<i>Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.</i>

6
00:00:13,497 --> 00:00:17,575
<i>Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.</i>

7
00:00:17,776 --> 00:00:21,888
<i>Only the Avatar, master of
all four elements, could stop them.</i>

8
00:00:21,889 --> 00:00:25,048
<i>But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.</i>

9
00:00:25,049 --> 00:00:29,210
<i>A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar...</i>

10
00:00:29,211 --> 00:00:31,050
<i>an airbender named Aang.</i>

11
00:00:31,051 --> 00:00:33,256
<i>And although his airbending
skills are great.</i>

12
00:00:33,257 --> 00:00:36,989
<i>He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.</i>

13
00:00:36,990 --> 00:00:40,612
<i>But I believe Aang
can save the world.</i>

14
00:01:07,479 --> 00:01:11,411
Spare coins for weary travelers?

15
00:01:12,488 --> 00:01:14,745
This is humiliating! We're royalty.

16
00:01:14,758 --> 00:01:17,779
These people should be
giving us whatever we want.

17
00:01:17,797 --> 00:01:22,078
They will... if you ask nicely.

18
00:01:22,233 --> 00:01:26,706
Spare change for a hungry old man?

19
00:01:26,731 --> 00:01:29,800
Aww, here you go.

20
00:01:29,813 --> 00:01:37,117
The coin is appreciated,
but not as much as your smile.

21
00:01:38,490 --> 00:01:43,926
How about some entertainment in exchange for.
.. a gold piece.

22
00:01:43,944 --> 00:01:46,192
We're not performers.

23
00:01:46,216 --> 00:01:48,743
Not professional, anyway.

24
00:01:48,754 --> 00:01:59,864
♫ It's a long, long way to Ba Sing Se, but the
girls in the city they look soo prett-ay! ♫

25
00:01:59,881 --> 00:02:05,117
Come on! We're talking a gold
piece here! Let's see some action!

26
00:02:05,128 --> 00:02:06,182
Dance!

27
00:02:06,195 --> 00:02:17,666
♫ And they kiss so sweet that you've really
got to meet the girls from Ba Sing Se! ♫

28
00:02:18,609 --> 00:02:25,229
Nothing like a fat man dancing
for his dinner. Here ya go!

29
00:02:26,345 --> 00:02:29,585
Such a kind man!

30
00:02:52,478 --> 00:02:55,937
Hey, you takin' us down for a reason?

31
00:02:56,062 --> 00:02:58,657
Aang! Why are we going down?

32
00:02:58,669 --> 00:03:02,198
What? I didn't even notice.

33
00:03:02,205 --> 00:03:03,967
Are you noticing now?

34
00:03:03,977 --> 00:03:05,103
Is something wrong?

35
00:03:05,112 --> 00:03:10,243
I know this is gonna sound weird, but.
.. I think the swamp is... calling to me.

36
00:03:10,244 --> 00:03:12,603
It is telling ya where
we can get something to eat?

37
00:03:12,604 --> 00:03:16,428
No, I... I think it wants us to land there.

38
00:03:16,442 --> 00:03:20,193
No offense to the swamp, but I
don't see any land there to land on.

39
00:03:20,207 --> 00:03:21,257
I don't know, ...

40
00:03:21,267 --> 00:03:24,447
Bumi said to learn earthbending
I would have to wait and listen, ...

41
00:03:24,450 --> 00:03:29,269
and now I'm actually hearing the earth.
Do you want me to ignore it?

42
00:03:29,286 --> 00:03:30,659
Yes!

43
00:03:30,664 --> 00:03:36,082
I don't know... There's something
ominous about that place.

44
00:03:38,322 --> 00:03:40,929
See? Even Appa and Momo don't like it here.

45
00:03:40,942 --> 00:03:45,415
Okay, since everyone feels so
strongly about this... bye swamp.

46
00:03:45,422 --> 00:03:47,406
Yip! Yip!

47
00:03:52,128 --> 00:03:56,171
You better throw in an
extra "yip"! We gotta move!

48
00:04:36,242 --> 00:04:39,008
Where's Appa and Momo?

49
00:04:44,177 --> 00:04:48,234
Appa! Momo!

50
00:04:50,797 --> 00:04:52,790
Sokka! You've got an elbow leech!

51
00:04:52,803 --> 00:04:54,422
Where! Where!

52
00:04:54,427 --> 00:04:56,573
Where do you think?

53
00:04:56,577 --> 00:05:00,744
Why do things keep attaching to me!

54
00:05:01,712 --> 00:05:03,131
You couldn't find them?

55
00:05:03,147 --> 00:05:09,105
No... and the tornado...
it just disappeared.

56
00:05:44,447 --> 00:05:47,277
We better speed things up!

57
00:05:47,769 --> 00:05:50,917
Maybe... we should be
a little nicer to the swamp.

58
00:05:50,926 --> 00:05:52,401
Aang, these are just plants!

59
00:05:52,402 --> 00:05:54,070
Do you want me to say
"please" and "thank you"...

60
00:05:54,071 --> 00:05:56,482
as I swing my machete back and forth?

61
00:05:56,493 --> 00:06:02,370
Maybe you should listen to Aang. Something
about this place feels... alive.

62
00:06:02,386 --> 00:06:05,068
I'm sure there are lots
of things that are alive here, ...

63
00:06:05,069 --> 00:06:07,436
and if we don't wanna
wind up getting eaten by them, ...

64
00:06:07,437 --> 00:06:11,373
we need to find Appa as fast as we can.

65
00:06:43,790 --> 00:06:47,039
Appa! Momo!

66
00:06:47,051 --> 00:06:50,293
There's no way they can hear
us and no way we can see them.

67
00:06:50,298 --> 00:06:53,397
We'll have to make camp for the night.

68
00:06:56,740 --> 00:06:58,179
What was that!?

69
00:06:58,185 --> 00:07:04,524
Nothing. Just swamp gas. Look, there's
nothing supernatural going on here.

70
00:07:07,855 --> 00:07:10,865
I think we should build a fire...

71
00:07:13,553 --> 00:07:17,356
Sokka, the longer we're here the
more I think you shouldn't be doing that.

72
00:07:17,371 --> 00:07:20,064
No, I asked the swamp.
It said this was fine.

73
00:07:20,072 --> 00:07:24,303
Right, swamp? "No problem, Sokka!"

74
00:07:29,394 --> 00:07:32,747
Does anyone else get the
feeling that we're being watched?

75
00:07:32,752 --> 00:07:36,610
Please, we're all alone out here.

76
00:07:41,935 --> 00:07:44,399
Except for them.

77
00:07:44,406 --> 00:07:47,466
Right, except for them.

78
00:09:15,974 --> 00:09:18,040
Guys?

79
00:09:22,909 --> 00:09:25,649
What'd you reckon make a
track like that, Tho?

80
00:09:25,669 --> 00:09:31,838
Don't know, Due. Something with six legs.
Pretty big'uns too.

81
00:09:31,847 --> 00:09:34,242
Leaves a nice, wide trail to folla'.

82
00:09:34,253 --> 00:09:37,817
You know what's at the end of that trail?

83
00:09:37,837 --> 00:09:40,159
Dinner.

84
00:10:11,996 --> 00:10:16,080
Aang? Sokka?

85
00:10:18,358 --> 00:10:24,597
Hello? Hello? Can you help me?

86
00:10:24,601 --> 00:10:28,116
Mom? Mom!

87
00:10:30,960 --> 00:10:33,531
I can't believe...

88
00:10:43,121 --> 00:10:48,817
Aang! Stupid swamp! Dumb, ugly vines!

89
00:10:48,824 --> 00:10:54,462
Katara! You think you're so tough, huh?

90
00:11:00,334 --> 00:11:02,308
Hello?

91
00:11:06,098 --> 00:11:11,375
Yue? This is just a trick of the light.
..swamp gas...

92
00:11:11,387 --> 00:11:16,642
I... hit my head running away last night.
I'm going crazy.

93
00:11:17,878 --> 00:11:21,541
You didn't protect me.

94
00:11:33,590 --> 00:11:36,339
Katara!

95
00:11:37,171 --> 00:11:39,267
Appa!

96
00:11:39,641 --> 00:11:43,452
Hello? Who are you?

97
00:11:44,560 --> 00:11:47,400
Hey, come back!

98
00:12:21,094 --> 00:12:25,773
Look at that, Tho. Is that little
hairy fellow ridin' that thing?

99
00:12:25,788 --> 00:12:27,990
Naw, that's what they call a "lemoo,"...

100
00:12:27,999 --> 00:12:31,771
saw one at a travelin' show once.
Real smart they say.

101
00:12:31,776 --> 00:12:33,873
Bet he tastes a lot like possum chicken.

102
00:12:33,883 --> 00:12:36,622
You think everything tastes
like possum chicken.

103
00:12:36,640 --> 00:12:41,842
C'mon now, fellas. Just a little closer.
Nice and easy.

104
00:12:41,850 --> 00:12:46,647
Nothing to worry about.
We just fixin' to eat ya.

105
00:12:46,661 --> 00:12:48,144
What'd ya say that fer?

106
00:12:48,163 --> 00:12:49,361
Well, we are!

107
00:12:49,368 --> 00:12:51,208
But you don't have to tell 'em that!

108
00:12:51,214 --> 00:12:53,240
Well how'd I know they'd understand me!

109
00:12:53,247 --> 00:12:55,488
Come on!

110
00:13:22,004 --> 00:13:24,782
Who are you?

111
00:13:34,341 --> 00:13:38,089
What do you guys think you're doing!
? I've been looking all over for you!

112
00:13:38,105 --> 00:13:40,692
Well, I've been wandering
around looking for you!

113
00:13:40,702 --> 00:13:42,954
I was chasing some girl.

114
00:13:42,959 --> 00:13:44,034
What girl?

115
00:13:44,046 --> 00:13:48,344
I don't know. I heard laughing
and I saw some girl in a fancy dress.

116
00:13:48,387 --> 00:13:53,395
Well, there must be a tea party here
and we just didn't get our invitations!

117
00:13:53,446 --> 00:13:56,684
I thought I saw Mom.

118
00:13:57,329 --> 00:14:01,521
Look, we were all just scared and hungry
and our minds were playing tricks on us.

119
00:14:01,530 --> 00:14:03,365
That's why we all saw things out here.

120
00:14:03,374 --> 00:14:05,171
You saw something too?

121
00:14:05,181 --> 00:14:08,560
I thought I saw Yue. But,
that doesn't prove anything.

122
00:14:08,575 --> 00:14:13,460
Look, I think about her all the time,
and you saw Mom, someone you miss a lot.

123
00:14:13,471 --> 00:14:19,488
What about me? I didn't know the girl I saw.
And all our visions led us right here.

124
00:14:19,496 --> 00:14:22,869
Okay... so where's here?
The middle of the swamp?

125
00:14:22,879 --> 00:14:27,072
Yeh, the center...

126
00:14:28,101 --> 00:14:32,455
It's the heart of the swamp,
it's been calling us here, I knew it.

127
00:14:32,465 --> 00:14:37,171
It's just a tree. It can't
call anyone! For the last time, ...

128
00:14:37,188 --> 00:14:44,031
there's nothing after us and
there's nothing magical happening here.

129
00:16:13,977 --> 00:16:18,462
Now what would a lemoo need a shirt fer?

130
00:17:29,999 --> 00:17:34,161
There's someone in there!
He's bending the vines!

131
00:17:46,917 --> 00:17:49,886
Why did you call me here
if you just wanted to kill us?

132
00:17:49,897 --> 00:17:55,366
Wait! I didn't call you here.

133
00:17:55,656 --> 00:17:59,558
We were flying over and I heard something
calling to me, telling me to land.

134
00:17:59,703 --> 00:18:02,829
He's the Avatar. Stuff like
that happens to us... a lot.

135
00:18:02,834 --> 00:18:07,076
The Avatar! Come with me.

136
00:18:09,010 --> 00:18:11,676
So, who are you then?

137
00:18:11,772 --> 00:18:14,775
I protect the swamp from
folks that want to hurt it.

138
00:18:14,816 --> 00:18:17,203
Like this fellow with his big knife.

139
00:18:17,209 --> 00:18:19,025
See? Completely reasonable.

140
00:18:19,036 --> 00:18:22,075
Not a monster, just a
regular guy defending his home.

141
00:18:22,088 --> 00:18:25,027
Nothing mystical about it.

142
00:18:25,041 --> 00:18:29,773
Oh, the swamp is a mystical
place, all right. It's sacred.

143
00:18:29,787 --> 00:18:34,275
I reached enlightenment right
here under the banion grove tree.

144
00:18:34,277 --> 00:18:38,080
I hear it callin' me, just like you did.

145
00:18:38,087 --> 00:18:42,330
Sure ya did. It seems real chatty.

146
00:18:42,341 --> 00:18:47,572
See this whole swamp is actually
just one tree spread out over miles...

147
00:18:47,573 --> 00:18:53,292
branches, spread and sink and
take root and then spread some more...

148
00:18:53,310 --> 00:19:00,342
one big living organism,
just like the entire world.

149
00:19:00,351 --> 00:19:04,657
I get how the tree is one
big thing, but, the whole world?

150
00:19:04,674 --> 00:19:10,849
Sure. You think you're any different
from me? Or your friends? Or this tree?

151
00:19:10,864 --> 00:19:16,323
If you listen hard enough you can hear
every living thing breathing together, ...

152
00:19:16,324 --> 00:19:21,484
you can feel everything growing.
We're all livin' together, ...

153
00:19:21,497 --> 00:19:26,505
even if most folks don't act like it.
We all have the same roots, ...

154
00:19:26,514 --> 00:19:30,176
and we are all branches
of the same tree.

155
00:19:30,187 --> 00:19:32,084
But what did our visions mean?

156
00:19:32,094 --> 00:19:37,439
In the swamp we see visions of
people we've lost, people we loved...

157
00:19:37,449 --> 00:19:42,500
folks we think are gone.
But the swamp tells us they're not.

158
00:19:42,513 --> 00:19:48,804
We're still connected to 'em.
Time is an illusion and so is death.

159
00:19:48,808 --> 00:19:52,587
But what about my vision?
It was someone I had never met.

160
00:19:52,592 --> 00:19:55,902
You're the Avatar. You tell me.

161
00:19:55,916 --> 00:20:04,076
Time is an illusion... so, it's.
.. someone I will meet?

162
00:20:04,093 --> 00:20:07,786
Sorry to interrupt the lesson,
but we still need to Appa and Momo.

163
00:20:07,804 --> 00:20:14,491
I think I know how to find them.
Everything is connected.

164
00:20:31,598 --> 00:20:33,727
Come on! We've got to hurry!

165
00:20:33,754 --> 00:20:40,638
? Set my lines by the river bed!
Caught ten fish and I killed'em dead!?

166
00:20:40,652 --> 00:20:43,574
? Cut 'em and gut'em and
I tossed the heads...?

167
00:20:43,585 --> 00:20:49,362
? ...in the water to keep
them cat gators dead.?

168
00:20:52,920 --> 00:20:55,077
Appa!

169
00:20:56,393 --> 00:20:58,819
We're under attack!

170
00:21:02,133 --> 00:21:04,909
Hey, you guys are waterbenders!

171
00:21:04,918 --> 00:21:09,712
You too? That means we're kin!

172
00:21:13,471 --> 00:21:15,784
Hey Hue! How you been?

173
00:21:15,798 --> 00:21:21,108
You know, scared some folks,
swung some vines, the usual.

174
00:21:21,121 --> 00:21:23,279
Hue?

175
00:21:26,165 --> 00:21:28,131
How you like that possum chicken?

176
00:21:28,147 --> 00:21:30,381
Tastes just like arctic hen.

177
00:21:30,392 --> 00:21:32,974
So why were you guys
so interested in eating Appa?

178
00:21:32,993 --> 00:21:35,776
You've got plenty of those
big things wandering around.

179
00:21:35,785 --> 00:21:40,939
You want me to eat old Slim?
He's like a member of the family!

180
00:21:40,958 --> 00:21:43,321
Nice Slim!

181
00:21:45,165 --> 00:21:48,992
Oh, oh, he don't eat no bugs!
That's people food.

182
00:21:49,009 --> 00:21:50,572
Where d'you say you're from?

183
00:21:50,591 --> 00:21:51,867
The South Pole.

184
00:21:51,868 --> 00:21:54,548
Didn't know there was
waterbenders anywhere but here.

185
00:21:54,549 --> 00:21:56,678
They got a nice swamp there, do they?

186
00:21:56,684 --> 00:22:00,154
No, it' all ice and snow.

187
00:22:00,175 --> 00:22:02,139
Hmm. No wonder you left.

188
00:22:02,156 --> 00:22:06,319
Well, I hope you realize now that
nothing strange was going on here.

189
00:22:06,330 --> 00:22:08,919
Just a bunch of greasy
people living in a swamp.

190
00:22:08,926 --> 00:22:10,629
What about the visions?

191
00:22:10,684 --> 00:22:17,162
I told you, we were hungry.
I'm eating a giant bug!

192
00:22:18,218 --> 00:22:21,555
But what about when the tree
showed me where Appa and Momo were?

193
00:22:21,569 --> 00:22:24,004
That's Avatar stuff, that doesn't count.

194
00:22:24,005 --> 00:22:27,744
The only thing I can't figure out is how
you made that tornado that sucked us down.

195
00:22:27,745 --> 00:22:33,961
I can't do anything like that.
I just bender the water in the plants.

196
00:22:33,975 --> 00:22:35,879
Well, no accounting for weather.

197
00:22:35,887 --> 00:22:41,394
Still, there's absolutely
nothing mysterious about the swamp.

198
00:22:54,586 --> 00:22:57,278
Who's there?

199
00:23:06,771 --> 00:23:10,260
Subtitle by rendy1287
Fixed by LEO33

200
00:23:10,285 --> 00:23:10,451
<font color="#ffff00">w</font>ww. leo33.tk

201
00:23:10,452 --> 00:23:10,617
<font color="#ffff00">ww</font>w. leo33.tk

202
00:23:10,618 --> 00:23:10,784
<font color="#ffff00">www</font>.leo33.tk

203
00:23:10,785 --> 00:23:10,951
<font color="#ffff00">www.</font>leo33.tk

204
00:23:10,952 --> 00:23:11,117
<font color="#ffff00">www.l</font>eo33.tk

205
00:23:11,118 --> 00:23:11,284
<font color="#ffff00">www.le</font>o33.tk

206
00:23:11,285 --> 00:23:11,451
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo</font>33.tk

207
00:23:11,452 --> 00:23:11,617
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo3</font>3.tk

208
00:23:11,618 --> 00:23:11,784
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33</font>.tk

209
00:23:11,785 --> 00:23:11,951
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.</font>tk

210
00:23:11,952 --> 00:23:12,117
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.t</font>k

211
00:23:12,118 --> 00:23:14,118
<font color="#ffff00">www.leo33.tk</font>