My husband wants
to thank you for coming.
Of course. We know what side
of the bread gets buttered.
We know how
to butter bread!
You don't have to yell.
He's not deaf.
Oh, I -- I didn't --
what's wrong
with him, then?
-He had a stroke.
-A mild stroke.
He can't walk or talk.
For now, he can't.
One day, though.
He's still...
Same lion inside.
But until he's better,
you talk to me.
Bear: That's right.
Talk to ma.
She's in charge.
Also, we want to thank you
for your cards and letters.
Are you kidding me?
Cards and letters?
We're in a state of siege,
and you're talking about --
boys.
You know about the offer
on the table?
Floyd: Kansas City?
The money's good,
you know?
More than fair.
Sure, but what they don't
tell you is after you sign,
they take your balls
with a straight razor
and fatten you up
like a housecat.
-Language.
-Give me a break.
I'm saying --
this is our business.
We built it
with blood and muscle.
It's earned.
And you can't just
write a check --
-this family has been --
-you can't just write a check.
Floyd: This family has been a
peace-time family since Kennedy.
You think we just,
out of the blue,
pick up our guns
and it's high noon?
We're talking about
the Kansas City mafia.
They're like all the sharks
in the sea.
And we're...
Let's be honest,
we're small-time.
"Know thyself."
What are you on about?
It's in the Bible.
I'm saying we hit 'em
and hit 'em hard.
Otherwise, wither and die.
Right, pop?
Look, it's not
just the business.
It's the country.
This no-brains Jimmy Carter
with his stupid peanut grin,
and now I got to wait in line
to fill my tank?
Dodd: Exactly.
Where does it end?
Enough -- all of you.
It may be we have to fight,
and I'm not afraid of a war.
I'm not.
But on my terms --
as a last resort.
So I need to know now --
are you with me?
Well, look.
We talked.
And we're not saying
"yes, we're going to war."
But we recognize
promises were made
in blood,
generations ago.
What he's saying is
we're not gonna make
the first move.
But if these Kansas City mooks
come at you shootin',
we'll cut the goddamn nose
off their face.
Uh-huh.
Late.
Sorry.
Couldn't get the shampoo
out of my hair.
Soft water.
Say what?
This goddamn northern water.
It's slick to the touch.
Yeah.
I thought
it was the shampoo.
It could be that, too.
I always carry my own.
Agree.
Agree to what?
That's the brand --
agree.
No additives. It works --
hard water or soft.
Feel my hair.
Yeah, that's nice.
So update's this --
nothing on the Gerhardt frau
as to "yes" or "no".
I didn't expect it,
but still.
Research thinks
that they'll stall, then pass.
So we kill 'em.
Maybe.
If the market says kill 'em,
we kill 'em.
The market says
offer more money,
we offer more money.
Whatever the pluses
and minuses dictate.
And on the Gerhardt kid --
this Rye?
Get this.
He gunned down a judge --
some small hick town
a couple hours south
from here -- then disappeared.
On the run now,
we're thinking.
On the run is good.
On the run we can use.
Find him.
You, not them.
Then he's leverage
over the frau,
and maybe turn things
our way
without buying a bunch
of extra bullets.
Dispatcher: Car 18, over.
This is 18.
Over.
I got the rock county sheriff
on the line.
Hold. Over.
Hank:
Went by the house.
Betsy says you're up
in Fargo.
Yeah, I went to see about
our judge's caseload.
Maybe there's a connection
to our shooter. Over.
Well, I'm callin'
'cause we got a print match
off of that gun you found.
Right index belonged
to one Rye Gerhardt,
which, I looked up,
is the youngest male heir
to that Gerhardt syndicate
out of Fargo.
You don't say.
Over.
Yup, so there's that.
Okay, well, I'll mention that
to Fargo pd.
Uh, I'll probably be back
late tonight, though.
You want to tell Betsy
not to wait up for me? Over.
Okay, then.
Sounds good.
Over.
Over and out, I guess.
How ya doing?
You know, waitin'.
Lou Solverson,
Minnesota state police.
I drove up from Luverne.
Ben Schmidt.
Forensics is inside.
Ah.
Takin' their time.
Yeah.
Heard the crime scene
was a deal.
Mm.
I'm working things
up here.
Thought maybe tomorrow,
I'd drive down, take a look.
You're welcome to.
Or I can send ya the photos.
They're pretty thorough.
Three dead,
including the judge.
Fry cook and a waitress,
also.
Shot multiple times.
Got the prints back
on the gun just before.
Rye Gerhardt.
That bad, huh?
I'm not saying
your life would be easier
if it was your own prints
on the gun,
but that's the lines along
which you should be thinkin'.
Distribution, right?
Gerhardts?
Yeah.
Dieter --
that's Otto's dad --
started running booze
during prohibition,
ended up building
a truckin' empire.
1951, he gets 19 bullets
in the head.
That's when the son, Otto,
he takes over, which is like --
the good news is,
world war I is over.
The bad news is,
"say to hello to Adolf Hitler."
And the shooter
is Otto's youngest?
Yeah.
Yeah, the runt --
mm, basically wind
and swagger,
except, I guess he's more
than that now.
Say...
You ever heard of, uh...
Mike Milligan
or the kitchen brothers?
Out of Kansas City.
We caught them sniffin'
around the crime scene,
but nothing
to hold 'em on, so...
You, uh --
you in the service?
Navy -- two tours.
Swift boat --
i was a lieutenant.
Infantry for me,
outside da nang.
And we had a saying --
fubar.
Yeah, we had that, too.
So when you put a dead judge,
the Gerhardt family,
and some hitters from Kansas
in a bag together,
I go back to thinking
it might be best
just to confess
to the crime myself --
go live a long life
in a cell somewhere
with hot and cold
running water.
Hanzee: He got a place in town,
then -- your uncle?
Simone: Rye.
Something
he doesn't tell people,
where he can do
his business?
-You mean nail girls?
-Girls, drugs.
I don't know.
I don't.
I mean...Maybe.
Okay.
Maybe I been there
with a boy
or to score some weed.
No drugs, your dad says.
Says anyone sells to you
gets the axe.
Geez, you're all
a bunch of squares.
Sometimes a girl just wants
to bust a nut, ya know?
It's over
on 13th somewhere.
Near the train station,
i think.
Not like I memorized
the address.
Show me.
♪ If you know ♪
♪ if you know someone ♪
♪ who's been looking ♪
♪ for true love ♪
♪ send her to me ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
♪ I'm looking, too ♪
Betsy: It's supposed
to fall out, they say.
With the chemo.
Donna Pearlman
lost hers overnight.
Woke up and thought there was
a dog sleepin' on her pillow.
Not everyone loses it.
We could just wait
and see.
Part of ne thinks I should
just shave it off --
be bald.
My cousin had a melanoma --
didn't lose a single hair.
Lost her eyebrows,
though.
Now,
that'd a horror show.
So I decided.
I want to do it.
What's that, hon?
The seminar.
I thought about it,
and I think I should.
I'm so happy.
-So happy.
-What seminar?
It's called lifespring.
I did it last year
in mankato.
-Amazing.
-Oh.
Yeah, and I just,
you know,
I want to be the best me
i can be, ya know?
Constance:
Good for you.
What did ed say
when you asked him?
You didn't, did you?
You naughty girl.
We were busy.
Ladies.
Hi, dad.
Spoke to your man
on the wireless.
Said to say
he's gonna be late tonight.
Oh, yeah.
I thought he might.
Whatcha got there?
Uh, Connie, you mind if I put
one of those up in your window?
Constance: Nope.
Okay, Mrs. blaycock.
You can head to the dryer.
Is that him -- the one
that killed those poor people?
We think so.
Yeah.
City boy, turns out.
Rye Gerhardt --
raised without the proper
moral fiber, I'm thinking.
I mean, to kill all
those people, and for what?
You know,
a little money?
i was thinking last night --
that shoe you found
in the tree.
What if that's got something
to do with the murders?
Something how?
Well, you said yourself,
the shooter
left his vehicle behind,
so, I'm thinking...
What if he walked out
onto the road
and got himself hit
by a car.
-Like a hit and run?
-Yeah.
I mean, you found glass
in the road, right?
-Yeah, yeah.
-And, uh, skid marks?
So, I'm thinking,
what if the killer
goes after poor Denise,
shoots her
in the parking lot,
and then inadvertently
gets himself struck
by a passing motorist?
Hey, peg,
didn't you say that --
I'm sorry,
but that just don't make sense.
I mean, how come
the motorist don't stop?
If they hit a person --
run 'em over, I mean?
Yeah, I'm inclined
to agree with Peggy.
It's not like
you're gonna just drive home
with a Gerhardt
in your windshield
and, you know,
start supper.
Betsy:
All I'm saying is --
maybe rather
than looking for a man,
you should be looking for a car.
-We got to --
-hi, Peggy.
Hey, Noreen.
Ed, we got to --
get your coat.
Hi.
-Hi.
-What's --
Noreen, hon,
we've got a -- well,
it's a family crisis
is what it is.
So I need to --
will you tell bud
I'll have him back
after lunch, okay?
Whatever.
-Slow down.
-They know.
-Know what?
-About the accident.
There's a theory --
Betsy Solverson.
She said hit and run,
so we got to deal with the car.
O-okay, yeah,
but just slow down.
I don't understand
what you're --
I can't slow down.
The clock's goin'.
Like I said,
there's a theory.
So we got to deal
with the car.
Now -- today.
Deal how?
It's broad daylight.
Sorry, officer.
Did I --
am I in a loading zone?
Sir,
let me see some I.D.
Yeah.
Is there --
am I in trouble, or...?
Skip --
that's your Christian name?
Yes, sir, skip sprang --
carriage typewriters.
Grand re-opening,
coming soon.
Re-opening?
Well, we're still open,
technically.
That is -- if you're looking
for a classic, can't do better.
But the new models are --
they'll be in any day.
Beauties --
all electric.
State of the art.
They're not just
for women anymore, ya know?
Mm.
And what's got ya here
at court today?
Well, sir, uh, had a hearing,
but, uh, it's been postponed.
Hearing on...?
Small bother --
back taxes.
Nothing scandalous,
but time sensitive, if you get
my -- on account of --
I need, you know, cash,
to cover the new models, see?
Is that why you went
by judge mundt's office?
Did what?
Oh, uh, yeah.
I, uh, heard, uh,
what happened about the --
and, I mean, condolences
to the family and all.
But -- like I said --
lives hang in the balance here.
And time is, ya know,
tickin' down
to get the typewriters --
spaceships, really --
out of, ya know...
Hock.
What do ya think?
- He's a squirrely fella.
Might be worth bringing him down
to the station, diggin' down.
Ya, I don't --
I mean, how many cases
she have, our judge?
Can't go diggin' down
on every sad sack --
yeah, exactly.
You said it.
A few back taxes.
It's not like I'm even --
-sir.
-Yeah, okay.
Okay, Mr. sprang.
You have a nice day.
Okay, then.
Uh, thanks much.
Spaceships, really.
They're just
for women anymore?
Gerhardts?
No avoiding it,
i suppose.
Rye!
Come on!
Open the -- it's --
let me in!
And here I was sitting
on my hands.
Now look
what Santa brought me --
a little man.
Whatcha doin' here,
little man?
I'm, uh --
I'm looking for Rye.
You look like
you could use a drink.
Uh --
or at least watch me
drink mine.
It gets so lonely here
by myself.
Hell,
i may even dance for ya.
♪ Joe Henry had his say ♪
♪ he wouldn't set me free ♪
Oh, geez.
-Who's --
-don't worry about him.
He's boring.
Let me guess.
You're the partner.
Uh, the, uh --
Rye said,
"i got this new deal.
Workin'
with a fella downtown."
So, I'm thinking
you're the fella downtown.
No.
Not -- I'm --
my name is skip.
I just come to, uh...
Pay off some debts.
Gamblin' -- ponies.
Oh, okay, then.
Pay me.
Well, uh,
I don't actually have
the money on me.
I was just -- come by to say,
ya know, I'll have it soon.
So, you came by
to not pay my uncle.
And you're a patriot
to boot.
Well, I mean...
Greatest country on earth,
yeah?
Uh, my tie.
I think you and me
should go for a drive.
Like, I said, I -- you know --
there's some appointments.
Sucks
to your appointments.
I say
let's have some fun.
What do you say,
red man?
Should we have some fun?
You betcha.
Ed: Well, that's the tree
i was thinking.
You want me to do it?
No, it's better me.
You sure about this plan?
It'll work.
Like I said,
my uncle used to drive his truck
and drink old Milwaukee.
And, you know,
insurance don't want to pay
for accidents when you're drunk,
so he came up with this plan.
Every crack-up,
he'd drive his truck
to some deserted spot
till he sobered up,
fake a new accident
to cover the damage
he did drinking.
Well, it's creative.
So, that's what we do.
We cover the damage,
file a report,
and then, I mean,
that should do it.
We got rid of the --
i mean, the guy's all ground up,
and you burned his clothes,
you said,
so, once the car's fixed,
it's --
we're free.
You been a real paladin.
A -- what's that?
It's like a knight.
My knight.
Oh, well --
i mean, you're my wife.
Okay, so, you should
probably get out.
You got
the one shiner already.
Okay.
Watch your toes, now.
I mean, what are the odds?
Black ice and you doing a 180,
hitting a tree with the back?
You could run
that scenario 1,000 times
and never end up
with these circumstances.
Yeah, I got it right
the second time, though.
Yeah, you did.
I think
i got the whiplash.
Come on, hon.
If they ask, I backed
into the garage door, okay?
Still going, huh?
Grandma's
working it out.
She thinks maybe
we can maybe sell Kansas City
a piece of the business,
not all.
They didn't look like fellas
who want to own half a car.
I need you to go back
to school tomorrow.
Dunlop will drive you.
No way.
It's gonna get hinkey
around here
for a while,
most likely.
Can't be worried
you're gonna catch a stray.
I can help.
No.
I promised your ma
I'd keep you out of it.
Get you good
and educated
so you can make something
of yourself.
I am something already,
though, aren't I?
A Gerhardt.
We're not negotiating.
This is
a top-down decision.
Grandma agrees.
Uncle dodd says --
dodd's got nothing
to do with it.
You're my son.
He's got his girls,
so he decides
what happens to them,
but you're mine.
Like I said,
grandma agrees.
Dispatcher:
Come in, car 22. Over.
Man: This is car 22,
copy.
Yeah, car 22,
got a situation...
Not too late
to go to the movies.
We can -- we can drive over
there, if you'd like. Over.
Copy that.
Gonna need your guns.
I'll hold onto mine.
It's got
sentimental value.
Well, you're not getting inside
with that on your hip.
Am I the only one here
who's clear
on the concept
of law enforcement?
Is that Ben Schmidt?
Mrs. Gerhardt.
Oh,
i heard about Otto.
We're beset
on all sides.
How's your mother?
Off the crutches,
thanks.
Who's that?
Lou Solverson,
Minnesota state.
Up from Luverne.
Yeah, they had
some senselessness there
a few days back I'm afraid
we're gonna have to talk about.
What kind
of senselessness?
Three dead,
including a state judge.
A judge mundt.
Everything okay, mom?
Not sure yet --
something about a dead judge.
Not sure how it falls
to us.
Ma'am we found the murder weapon
at the scene.
Prints came back
this morning.
And?
We're gonna have to talk
to Rye.
That's not gonna happen.
You need to leave.
Mrs. Gerhardt,
if either of these men draw,
I'm gonna be forced
to shoot some people,
and I don't want to do that.
Now, your son's wanted in
connection with three murders.
And I'm guessing
that's not the first time
you heard somebody say that,
so however it is you want
to handle this,
you need to handle it now,
or it'll get handled for you.
Schmidt:
Everybody go easy.
You okay, ma?
Maude Schmidt's boy here
is trying to tell me
your brother killed
a judge.
Nobody killed a judge.
We own all the judges.
What'd be the point
of killing one?
-Now, dodd.
-don't you "dodd" me.
We're not friends.
We found Rye's prints
on the gun.
You're gonna find my boot
on your neck,
you keep talking
like that.
Well, now, to be fair --
I'm the one who found the gun,
so I think you're dancing
with the wrong girl.
What'd you say?
I says, I'm the one
who found the gun,
so you should be talking
to me.
And I'm from out of town,
so forgive me
if I should be terrified,
but in Minnesota,
when a police officer says talk,
you talk.
You want to dance?
Let's dance.
Floyd: Ben, you need to teach
your friend some manners.
How about Mike Milligan
out of Kansas City?
You know
where we can find him?
Pretty sure he's looking
for your brother, too.
Uh, uncle dodd?
Uncle dodd, hanzee called.
-Not now.
-Said it's real important.
Wants you to meet him
at the dig.
We're done here.
Floyd:
You heard my son.
We've said all we're gonna say.
Give him his gun back.
Get him out of here.
Okay.
Time to go.
Well,
we could get a warrant.
From what judge?
You heard dodd.
They own most of the town.
Hey, pull over, huh?
-The typewriter guy?
-Yeah, like I said.
He was squirrely.
Hey, I -- I got to get back,
talk to my boss,
but, uh, station's just
a few blocks if you want to --
no, sure.
Sure, sure.
Thanks for showing me
around today.
Yeah.
Unh-unh.
What are you,
having a baby in there?
Hello.
You didn't tell me your family
was in from out of town.
Unh-unh.
Whoops.
Got to ask you
your business here.
-Maybe I'm the owner.
-Nope.
Met the owner
this morning.
Is that right?
Maybe tell us
where he is.
Make a few bucks.
I was gonna ask you
the same.
Say, you wouldn't by any chance
be Mike Milligan
and the kitchen brothers,
would you?
You make us sound like
a prog rock band.
Ladies and gentlemen,
introducing Mike Milligan
and the kitchen brothers.
Double whoops.
Easy.
Minnesota cop.
You do know you're
in north Dakota, right?
Must have got lost
on the way to the lake.
So where'd you say
you saw old skip?
At your mother's house.
I think,
going in the back door.
I like him.
I like you.
Met another fella
from Minnesota yesterday.
Big guy.
Sheriff, I think.
I liked him, too.
We're
a very friendly people.
No, that's not it.
Pretty unfriendly, actually.
But it's the way
you're unfriendly --
how you're so polite
about it,
like you're doing me
a favor.
Well, this has been enjoyable,
but I better get going.
What did Nixon call it?
Peace with honor.
Something like that.
Naw.
You stay.
We've seen everything
there is to see.
I am not a crook.
Rapid fire.
Some round,
some oval.
What's that, friend?
Circular patterns --
unnatural, bright,
hovering in the sky.
You know, they come only
in the odd months --
the visitors.
Always in sets of three.
Such a night
was two nights past.
Reports from mankato
to vermillion.
Visitors?
From above.
Some say they take you
to their ship
and probe you in places
you don't want to mention.
I believe their purposes
are more benevolent.
As the caretaker
to the zoo,
strange happenings occur,
they are near.
Strange happenings, huh?
I wondered
what was causing that.
Ed:
You think it worked?
Peggy:
What's that, hon?
I said
you think it worked?
Today, with the car?
It worked.
I don't know
how you can be so sure.
It worked.
Hiya, hon.
Dad's here.
Oh.
Hank.
Hank: Uh, I should go.
Sit.
Let me
get you some divinity.
Ooh,
i won't say no.
You go see
the gerhardts, then?
It's been real "high noon",
my day.
Gerhardts,
and I ran into
those Kansas City fellas
you pulled over.
Milligan, and, um...
What do ya --
the bathroom brothers.
Yeah.
The ones that don't talk.
We pointed our weapons
at each other
for a bit
before calling it a day.
Maybe two pieces of cake,
then.
Sounds right.
Mm.
-Hiya.
-Hi.
You okay?
Yeah.
No complaints.
Mm.
Playing cribbage,
you hold your horses there.
Yeah.
You-know-who's cheating.
Who's cheating, dad?
--Huh?
No, come on.
By the way,
i looked at your hand.
Get back
in the goddamn truck.
What are you
talking about?
I got him.
And button up that coat.
You're embarrassin' me.
Yeah?
You want
to hit me again?
Is that getting you
hard?
I wanted a boy.
What did god give me?
Four goddamn girls.
Please, sir,
this is a huge misunder--
shut up.
We know about the judge
and the typewriters
and the taxes,
and we know you were putting
ideas into his head.
And all I want to hear
out of your mouth right now
is where he is.
-Who?
If you knew
the day I'm havin' --
tell him.
Why would I go
by Rye's place
yellin' his name
if I knew where he was?
You talk to the cops?
In the hole.
What?
Look, I can find him.
I can -- if you give me
a day -- two days --
lie down.
On the ground?
Please!
I -- I -- I --
I'm not the one you want to --
talk to Milligan!
They got him.
What'd you say?
Came by yesterday
looking for Rye.
Probably --
they found him.
I'm just...
I could call.
Make a deal.
I got capital.
You don't know anything.
No, no!
You're gonna drive down to
that shithole Minnesota town,
and you're gonna bring
my brother back tonight.
Judge or no judge.
If Kansas City gets in your way,
if the cops get in your way,
if anybody gets in your way,
you kill 'em dead.