At the health club,
people are working out...
...and they're training,
getting in shape...
...but strangely, nobody's really
getting in shape for anything.
The only reason that you're
getting in shape...
...is that so you can get through
the workout.
So we're working out...
...so that we'll be in shape
for when we have to do our exercise.
This is the whole thing.
The other thing I don't get
is why we're so careful...
...about locking up our dirty towels
and smelly jockstraps.
What exactly is the black market
on these disgusting gym clothes?
I’ll give my car to any guy
in front of a restaurant...
...because he's got a short
red jacket.
''He must be the valet guy.''
But my stinking,
putrefied gym clothes...
...I got one of these locks...
...you could put a bullet through it
and it won't open.
That stuff is safe.
Wide open!
I was wide-open underneath.
I had three inches on that guy.
See, you two were hogging the ball.
Me? It wasn't me.
I never even saw the ball.
All you do is dribble.
I have to dribble. lf I give it to you,
you just shoot. You're a chucker.
-Oh, I’m a chucker.
-That's right.
Every time you get the ball,
you shoot.
I can't believe you
called me a chucker.
No way I’m a chucker! I do not chuck.
Never chuck!
Never have chucked!
Never will chuck! No chuck!
You chuck.
-Kramer, am I a chucker?
-Oh, you're a chucker.
My God, I’m a chucker.
-All these years, you never told me?
-It's not an easy thing to bring up.
Hey, you know, this is the first time
we ever saw each other naked?
Believe me, I didn't see anything.
Oh, you didn't sneak a peek?
-No. Did you?
-Yeah, I snuck a peek.
-Why?
-Why not?
What about you, George?
Yeah, l...
...snuck a peek.
But it was so fast, I didn't see
anything. It was just a blur.
I made a conscious effort not to look.
There's certain information
I just don't wanna have.
Okay....
I gotta go meet Newman.
-I’ll see you later. Have a good one.
-All right.
Yeah.
Look at this guy.
Does he have to stretch in here?
-You know who that is?
-Who?
That's Keith Hernandez.
Keith Hernandez,
the baseball player?
Yeah, that's him.
-Are you sure?
-Positive.
Wow! Keith Hernandez!
-He's such a great player.
-Yeah.
He's a real smart guy too.
He's a Civil War buff.
Wow, I’d love to be a Civil War buff.
What do you have to do
to become a buff?
So Biff wants to be a buff?
Well, sleeping less than 1 8 hours
a day would be a start.
I only got two weeks left
of unemployment.
I gotta prove I’ve been looking
for a job to get an extension.
Hey, should we say something
to him?
Oh, I’m sure he loves to hear
from fans in the locker room.
Well, he could say hello to me.
I wouldn't mind.
He's Keith Hernandez.
You're Jerry Seinfeld.
-So?
-What, you're comparing yourself...
...to Keith Hernandez?
The guy's a baseball player,
Jerry, baseball!
I know what he is. I recognized him.
You didn't even notice him.
What, you're making some wisecracks
in a nightclub?
The guy was in game six, two runs
down, two outs, facing elimination!
Excuse me.
I don't want to disturb you.
I’m Keith Hernandez.
And I just want to tell you what
a big fan I am. I love your comedy.
-Really?
-I’ve always wanted to do what you do.
Do what I do?! You're one
of my favorite ballplayers of all time!
Mine too.
-I love that bit about Jimmy Olsen.
-Really?
Thank you.
You know, Keith,
what I’ve always wondered is...
...with all these ball clubs
flying around all season...
...wouldn't you think
there'd be a plane crash?
Are you performing in New York now?
At this club on the East Side.
You should come in.
But think about it:
26 teams, 1 62 games a season.
You'd think eventually, an entire team
would just get wiped out.
I live on the East Side.
I’ll give you my number...
...and just tell me whenever
you want to go.
-Or maybe just get together for coffee.
-Oh, that'd be great.
Well, it's only a matter of time.
Who's this chucker?
It’s been three days,
and he hasn't called.
Well, maybe you should call him.
I can't. I can't.
-Why not?
-I just feel like he should call me.
What's the difference?
You don't understand, Elaine.
I don't want to be overanxious.
lf he wants to see me,
he has my number. He should call.
God, look at this ashtray.
I hate cigarettes.
I can't stand these guys.
You give your number to them,
and then they don't call.
Why do they do that?
I’m sorry, honey.
I mean, I really thought he liked me.
We were getting along.
He came over to me.
I didn't go over to him.
-I know.
-Why did he come over to me?
I mean, here I meet this great guy,
this ballplayer...
-...best guy I ever met.
-Yeah. I know.
Well, that's it. I’m never giving
my number out to another guy again.
I’ve given my number out to guys,
and it takes them a month to call.
Good. Good.
Well, if he's calling in a month...
...he's got a prayer.
You know, maybe he's been busy.
Maybe he's been out of town.
Oh, what, they don't have phones
out of town?
I love how people say
they're too busy. ''Too busy.''
Pick up a phone!
Takes two minutes.
How can you be too busy?
-Why don't you just go and call him?
-I can't call here. It’s a coffee shop.
-I mean, what am I gonna say to him?
-Just ask if he wants to get together.
For what, dinner?
Dinner's good.
Don't you think that's coming on a little
too strong? Isn't that, like, a turnoff?
Jerry, he's a guy.
I know, but this is all very confusing.
When you're in your 30s,
it's very hard to make a new friend.
Whatever the group is you've got now,
that's who you're going with.
You're not interviewing,
not looking at any new people.
You're not interested in seeing
any applications.
They don't know the places.
They don't know the foods.
They don't know the activities.
lf I meet a guy at a club or a gym:
''Hey, look, I’m sure you're very nice.
You seem to have a lot of potential.
We're just not hiring right now.''
When you're a kid...
...you can be friends with anybody.
Remember when you're a little kid...
...what are the qualifications? ''lf
someone's in front of my house...
...that's my friend.
They're my friend. That's it.
Are you a grownup?
No? Great. Come on in!
Let's jump up and down on my bed!''
And if you have anything in common:
''You like cherry soda? I like
cherry soda! We'll be best friends!''
You only have two more weeks
before your benefits run out.
Yes, and I was hoping, perhaps,
to get...
...a 1 3-week extension,
if that's possible.
So where have you been looking
for work?
You know what I’ve discovered,
Mrs. Sokol?
It’s not so much the looking...
...as the listening.
I listen for work.
As I’m looking...
...and listening-- I’m also looking.
You cannot discount looking.
It’s a combination.
It’s looking. And listening.
Listening. And looking.
But you must look.
Can you be specific
about any of these companies?
Specific. Let's see....
I’ve walked in and out
of so many buildings.
They all blend in together.
Just give me one name.
One name. Absolutely.
Let's see, there's....
Vandalay Industries.
I just saw them. I got very close there.
Very close.
What type of company is that?
Latex. Latex manufacturing,
Mrs. Sokol.
-And you interviewed there?
-Yes, for a sales position.
Latex salesman.
The selling of latex
and latex-related products.
They just wouldn't give me a chance.
Damn it!
Now I’m going to need an address
and a phone number for this...
...Vandalay company.
You like gum?
Because I have a friend in the gum
business. I got a gum guy!
I make one phone call, have boxes
of gum delivered right to your door.
The address?
The address is....
Jose Jimenez.
Do you recognize that?
-No.
-Jose Jimenez.
Very funny.
Really, he's very funny.
The address.
Vandalay is...
...1 29 West 81 st Street.
It’s a very small industry, Vandalay.
It’s why I wanted
to work for them.
A phone number.
That's...KL5...
...8383. Are you planning on
calling them soon?
Because they have
very strange hours.
As soon as I’m done with you.
Sure. Well....
You know, I’ll check in with you
next week.
I gotta run now because
I got a full plate this afternoon.
-Okay.
-All right. Really good to....
He'll call you back!
It’s a par five.
So, you know, I step up to the tee...
...and I hit a beautiful drive
right down the middle of the fairway.
-I mean, you know my hook, right?
-Elaine?
How about this shirt?
Is this okay?
Jerry, he's a guy.
Well, it's a dogleg left,
so I play the hook.
Wait, hold on.
There's another call.
-Jerry! Jerry!
-George?
-Kramer, put Jerry on!
-I’m in the middle of something.
-Call back.
-Kramer, no--!
So the ball takes off,
and I’m waiting for it to turn.
Would you--!
All right. Well, I’ll talk to Jerry.
Yeah.
Hey, that was Michael and Carol.
She's wondering when
we'll go see the baby.
-See the baby. Again with the baby.
-Who are they?
A guy who used to live in the building
keeps calling us to see the baby.
''You gotta see the baby.
When are you gonna see the baby?''
Can't they just send us a tape?
Maybe if you wait a few months,
it won't be a baby anymore.
-Then you won't have to see it.
-Because he'll be all grown-up.
Yeah....
Hey, Kramer, what do you think
of this shirt?
It’s too busy.
You're trying too hard
to make an impression on him.
-You're not being yourself.
-What guy?
I know he's just a guy,
but I really like him.
Who are you talking about?
Keith...Hernandez.
Keith Hernandez?
Keith Hernandez!
Do me a favor, would you?
Would you change lanes?
You gotta get out of this lane.
This lane stinks.
They're all double-parked.
Get out, I’m begging you.
Please. Please!
You know what?
Bad mistake. My mistake.
Go back. Your lane was better.
Forget this lane.
This lane stinks. Go back to your lane.
Go ahead. Bad mistake.
Go! Go! Go! Make this light!
Make this light! Oh, man!
That's it! Get out!
-What do you mean, get out?
-Get out of the cab!
What? I’m not getting out of this cab.
No! No! You cannot throw me out!
No! Get....
Hello, Newman.
I hate Keith Hernandez.
-Hate him!
-I despise him.
-Why?
-Why? I’ll tell you why.
-Let me tell her.
-No, you can't--
-You always tell.
-All right, tell it.
-Just tell it.
-All right.
June 14th, 1987, Mets-Phillies.
We're enjoying a beautiful afternoon
in the right-field stands...
...when a crucial Hernandez error
opens the door...
...to a five-run Phillies ninth.
Cost the Mets the game!
Our day was ruined.
There was a lot of people waiting
by the players' parking lot.
Now we're coming down the ramp.
Newman was in front of me.
Hernandez was coming toward us.
As he passes us, Newman turns
and says, ''Nice game, pretty boy.''
Hernandez continued past us
up the ramp.
Then, a second later,
something happened...
...that changed us in a very deep
and profound way...
...from that day forward.
-What was it?
-He spit on us!
And I screamed out, ''I'm hit!''
Then I turned, and the spit ricocheted
off him, and it hit me.
What a story.
Unfortunately, the immutable laws
of physics contradict...
...the whole premise of your account.
Allow me to reconstruct this,
if I may, for Ms. Benes...
...as I’ve heard this story
a number of times.
Newman, Kramer,
if you'll indulge me.
According to your story...
...Hernandez passes you
and starts walking up the ramp.
Then you say you were struck...
...on the right temple.
The spit then proceeds to ricochet...
...off the temple, striking Newman
between the third and the fourth rib.
The spit then came off the rib...
...made a right turn,
hitting Newman in the right wrist...
...causing him to drop
his baseball cap.
The spit then splashed off the wrist,
pauses...
...in midair, mind you...
...makes a left turn and lands
on Newman's left thigh.
That is one magic loogie.
Well, that's the way it happened.
What happened to your head
when you got hit?
Well, my head...
...went back, to the left.
-Say that again.
-Back and to the left.
Back and to the left.
So, what are you saying?
I’m saying...
...that the spit could not have
come from behind.
That there had to have been
a second spitter.
Behind the bushes,
on the gravelly road.
lf the spitter was behind you,
as you claim...
...that would've caused your head
to pitch forward.
So the spit could've only come
from the front and to the right.
But that's not what they
would have you believe.
I’m leaving.
Jerry's a nut.
Wait, wait, wait.
The sad thing is,
we may never know the real truth.
Did anybody call
asking for Vandalay Industries?
-No, what happened to you?
-All right, listen closely:
I was at the unemployment office.
I told them I was very close to getting
a job with Vandalay Industries...
...and I gave them your phone number.
So when the phone rings...
...you have to answer,
''Vandalay Industries.''
-I’m Vandalay Industries?
-Right.
-What is that?
-You're in latex.
-Latex?
-Right.
-What do I do with latex?
-I don't know! You manufacture it!
-Right here in this little apartment?
-And what do I say about you?
You're considering hiring me
for your latex salesman.
-I’ll hire you as my latex salesman?
-Right.
I don't think so.
Why would I do that?
Because I asked you to.
lf you think I’m looking for someone
to just sit...
...pushing papers around,
you can forget it.
I’ve got enough headaches
just trying to manufacture the stuff.
-Yeah?
-It’s Keith.
All right, we're coming down.
Keith Hernandez?
-Yeah. Come on, Elaine, let's go.
-Where are you going?
They're giving me a ride downtown.
You know, there had to have been
a second spitter. Who was it?
Who had the motive?
That's what I’ve been trying
to figure out the past five years.
What the hell are you two
talking about?
-That was really fun. Thanks.
-Yeah, it really was.
Should I shake his hand?
Well....
You want to catch a movie
this weekend?
Have you seen JFK?
No, I haven't.
This weekend. Wow!
Sure. That would be great.
Damn. I was too overanxious.
He must have noticed that.
I mean, if you want to.
-Well, how about this Friday?
-Yeah, Friday's okay.
Go ahead, shake his hand.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld.
I've been on The Tonight Show.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Oh, Jer, by the way...
...the woman we gave
a ride to earlier....
-Elaine.
-Yeah.
-What's her story?
-I don't know. We used to go out.
Would you mind if I gave her a call?
-For a date?
-Yeah.
Oh, no....
Go ahead.
You got a pen?
You sure you don't mind?
So then we went to dinner.
-Who paid?
-We split it.
Split it. Pretty good.
-Did you talk about game six?
-No. I gotta wait until it's the right time.
-Yeah?
-It's Elaine.
Come on up.
So then what?
Nothing. Then he took me home.
Shake his hand?
Yeah.
What kind of a shake does he have?
Good shake. Perfect shake.
Single pump, not too hard.
Didn't have to prove anything,
but firm enough to know he was there.
So...
...you're gonna see him again?
He asked me if I was doing anything
Friday night.
The weekend!
So then, as I was getting out
of the car--
-Hi!
-Oh, hi, Elaine.
Hi, Elaine.
So how was your date?
What date? It’s a guy.
So you know.... He called me.
-Already?
-Keith called you?
This guy really gets around.
-Do you mind?
-No, I don't mind. Why should I mind?
What did he say?
He asked me out for Saturday night.
-You going?
-No.
-I told him I was busy.
-Oh, really?
So we're going out Friday.
-Friday?
-Yeah.
He's going out with you on Friday?
-Yeah?
-He's supposed to see me on Friday.
-I didn't know.
-We made plans!
-Well-- I’ll cancel it.
-No, don't cancel it.
Well, this is a little
awkward, isn't it?
Well, frankly, it is.
I’ve never seen you jealous before.
Well, you're not even a fan.
I was at game six.
You didn't even watch it.
Wait a second. Wait a minute.
Are you jealous of him
or are you jealous of me?
Any Hennigan's around here?
Vandalay Industries.
Kell Varnsen speaking.
May we help you?
Oh, hi, Keith.
No, I was just joking around.
No, no, I don't mind at all.
-No, no, no. I can cancel.
-Sure. We'll do something next week.
No, it's no problem at all.
Okay. Take it easy.
That was Keith.
We're gonna do something next week.
Hey, what are you doing
Friday night?
Friday night? Nothing. Now.
Want to come to see the baby?
Oh, fasten your seat belts.
We're going to see the baby.
lf you don't see the baby now,
you're never gonna see her.
-All right, I’ll go.
-All right. All right.
I’ll get it.
Yello.
What delay industries?