[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
[PEÑA IN SPANISH] Please, pay attention!
I need you to put your cell phones,
beepers, and radios in the container.
[IN ENGLISH] Is this
necessary, Agent Peña?
- I'm afraid so, Captain.
- [IN SPANISH] Please. I'll take that.
[IN ENGLISH] One of my
guys says one of your guys
is working for the cartel.
They have any proof?
Can't say yet.
But this warrant will be hard to
execute if they're one step ahead.
It's just a precaution.
- Gracias.
- Okay.
[IN SPANISH] For the next three
hours, we'll be running silent.
My colleagues and I
will take the lead.
And the target?
I'll just say that it's
everything you've trained for.
[IN ENGLISH] We're advisors. We
work together, same as always.
Credit's all yours.
[IN SPANISH] Gentlemen, you heard!
I need you to be tight and right.
- Understood?
- [TOGETHER] Yes, sir!
Let's go.
[IN ENGLISH] In case
you're confused, Capitán,
I wouldn't have come all the way
from Bogotá if it wasn't a big deal.
My men's safety. That's
what I care about.
I make the final call
if anything feels off.
You follow?
My kid gave it to me right before
I went out on this buy-bust.
Some Jamaican took a rip at me,
missed by that much, so...
I rub it for luck ever since.
[IN SPANISH] So, what are we doing here?
We're arresting one of
the godfathers of Cali.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com
[TV ANNOUNCER IN SPANISH] Applauded by
the multitude present on 10th street,
president-elect Ernesto Samper Pizano is
welcomed by the people of Colombia...
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] I don't give
Gilberto Rodríguez credit for much,
but I have to hand it to him...
[AURA CHUCKLES]
...he was a man in control.
[IN SPANISH] It's too early.
- I rise early. I'm up with the sun.
- Up all right!
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] He was
married to three women.
At the same time.
And he managed them the same
way he ran his business.
Scheduled down to the minute.
["GOING BACK TO CALI" PLAYING]
Wife number three got
him Monday and Tuesday.
[IN SPANISH] Hi!
How did it go, honey?
Very good! Look, what a beauty.
[WOMAN MOANING]
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] Number two...
got him Wednesday and Thursday.
And wife number one got him
on Friday and Saturday.
[MAN ON TV IN SPANISH]
Look at that pass. Goal!
Damn it, what sort of defense is that?
Piece of shit!
I'm paying your fucking salaries!
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] Sundays
were for football.
[DOORBELL]
All the wives were invited
if they wanted to come.
They usually did.
[IN SPANISH] Thank you.
And they all got along.
That was the deal.
And he made it work. He insisted on it.
He made far more friends than enemies.
[IN SPANISH] I can help you
expand your businesses...
And he would count on those
friends to protect him.
I could help you make millions.
His retirement was going
to go his way, too.
He wasn't going to die
on some shitty rooftop.
Nobody was stabbing him in the
back, nobody forcing him out.
Like I said, he was a man in control.
The guy who never made a
wrong move in his life.
A guy who built a billion-dollar
empire, brick by brick.
A guy who owned every cop in town.
A guy with a get-out-of-jail-free
card burning a hole in his pocket.
And you want to go after him? Shit.
You'd have to be crazy, stupid, brave,
and lucky all at the same time.
[PEÑA IN SPANISH] Two
units: Calderón's and mine.
Breach one here. Breach two... here.
Feistl, Van Ness: Pool. You
come in from the back.
- All right, let's do this already.
- Okay.
If anyone kills the
godfather, I kill you.
We can't repeat what happened
with Escobar. I want him alive.
Understood?
[PEÑA WHISPERS] Go.
- [IN ENGLISH] Nobody lives here, boss.
- That's bullshit.
Intel had Pacho here last night.
[IN SPANISH] What do you think?
What do we do?
I think there could be hideouts here.
- We have to check the house again.
- All right.
[IN ENGLISH] We turn
this place upside down.
[IN SPANISH] Men, we're going to search
every corner of this house, understood?
It's an elegant house in Palmira, boss.
I don't know whose it is,
but it's not one of ours.
Very good. Get out of there and
make sure no one sees you.
Yes, sir.
[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
[PHONE RINGS]
- Salcedo.
- [MIGUEL] Jorge.
Sir.
I need you to do something important.
When you leave your house,
you'll find Navegante.
He knows where you have to go.
Of course, sir, but what should I do
with the operation I'm monitoring?
Córdova. Give it to Córdova.
Jorge...
- be careful.
- Of course, sir.
He's one of my best men.
He'll take care of it.
You're a man of your word.
[AMADO] Juárez.
So close to heaven and so far from God.
[PACHO] Impressive.
I'm so glad you brought me to see
the eighth wonder of the world.
[CHUCKLES]
Don't be an asshole, Pacho.
El Paso, Texas, is what
I wanted you to see.
Fucking NAFTA changed everything, Pacho.
It's been around for what?
Two years, more or less?
More than two million trucks have
crossed already, many of them ours.
Filled to the brim.
Do you know how many trucks
the Americans check?
Less than ten percent. It's insane.
They don't have the manpower.
Assholes opened the floodgates
and now they stand there with a
baby's bucket to try and stop it.
This is the right business.
I already know this, man.
No, man. What I'm saying is,
you're getting out of the right
business at the exact wrong time.
And you're going to regret it.
You want some?
Amado, are you suggesting
that I betray my partners?
No. No way. Why betray?
They want to get out.
I'm proposing that we start
something new, you and I.
Just imagine it: You send
it to me, I get it across.
In two years, we'll be flooding
this fucking shitty country.
Think about it, all right?
Think about it.
Just don't take too long,
because in six months,
I need to secure a new supply.
Hopefully, it will be with you.
Hey...
Give it another once-over?
Okay.
[IN ENGLISH] It should be now.
[IN SPANISH] Thirty seconds.
Hey!
Hey! You can't park there!
Damn truck.
These fucking trucks are
always breaking down.
You can't park here.
Let me just grab the
cables and I'll move it.
Move the fucking truck.
[GRUNTS]
- [DOORBELL]
- That's the one Lady Di uses.
Gilberto!
Someone's ringing the doorbell!
[DOORBELL]
- Careful.
- Sorry, wait just a moment.
Let me get the door.
Look.
[DOORBELL]
Gilberto?
Police! Back up. Quickly! Move it!
Quickly! Move it!
What's going on?
Sit down, ladies. Sit down,
I won't say it again.
You can't come in here. Get out.
He's fucking running!
Get up! Look at my face!
Let's go.
Sit down, miss.
I already told you,
Gilberto is not home.
Did he contact anyone?
- No one, Colonel.
- No? All good?
Mrs. Rodríguez, I have a federal
warrant signed and executed by myself,
as representative of the
Colombian National Police.
The question is, will you cooperate?
[MOANING]
Are you all right?
Yes.
It's good here.
[PAGER BUZZES]
The only thing left is
to demolish the house.
Yeah. Okay. We're done. I'm calling it.
I'm sorry, I thought we had something.
Welcome to my world.
Well...
[IN ENGLISH] Do what you need to
wrap up, have your men report back.
- Okay.
- Feistl, anything else?
- Ride to the airport?
- Sure.
[IN SPANISH] Look, when we get there,
I think it's better if I go in alone.
These people are angry.
What we're asking of them, it's
an insult on top of their grief.
You're different, Jorge Salcedo.
Different? How?
You're crippled. You don't carry a gun.
Most people don't carry guns.
Yeah... but you're not most people.
And that's why it's so weird.
Interesting.
That you never carry a gun.
I see. Why do you think that is?
I don't know.
Maybe you're scared.
Fear... of what you could do with it.
That you've been walking around
a killer and never knew it.
Pedrito, go in the house!
Good afternoon, Mrs. Salazar. Calm
down, Mrs. Salazar. Calm down.
My name is Jorge Salcedo. I'd like
to speak with you, if I could.
Go right back to where you came from
and tell that whore if
she wants my grandson,
she can come looking for him.
I just came to talk.
If you don't like what I have to say,
I'll go to Cali and deliver
whatever message you want.
I'm unarmed. I'm here to talk.
Your boss murdered my son... to
take up with his whore wife.
And now you come to take my grandson
far from the only family he has left.
I know this is not what you want
to hear. But she is his mother.
And Miguel Rodríguez is protecting her.
Protecting?
Is that what they call it now?
And he will be protected as well.
And if you let me take him back,
I promise you can see him
whenever you'd like.
You promise. How nice of you.
Who told you I would do that?
I have him here and I can see him
whenever I want and protect him.
That bitch made her choice.
Mrs. Salazar... please accept my offer.
The next men who come...
won't be asking.
There will be war.
[CAR APPROACHING]
Why don't you ask my sons?
See what they think.
[IN ENGLISH] If you don't mind, Capitán,
we need to stop by a friend's house.
Make a right here.
Nice neighborhood. Your
friend's very wealthy.
He's a very fortunate man.
[IN SPANISH] What is this?
[IN ENGLISH] My friend likes chickens.
- [IN SPANISH] Colonel Martínez.
- Captain.
You know what's happening here?
Yes, I think I know.
I'm giving you one chance
to do the right thing and
not fuck up this operation.
You think you're clever?
You're in Cali. Cali is my city.
This isn't Bogotá.
You're way out of line here, Hugo.
Perhaps.
He's here. We'll find him.
Watch him.
[IN ENGLISH] You got your kid's drawing?
[JORGE IN SPANISH] I'm unarmed.
We're going to send your head
back to Miguel in a fucking box.
- Walk, motherfucker.
- Let's go.
[GERDA] Duvan!
Duvan!
Bring out the car.
Pedro. Let's go. I'm taking you
to your mother. Take my hand.
- Very good.
- Shut your fucking mouth or I kill her.
All right, my lady. Make like
a statue or I shoot your ass.
I'm getting in first, you hear?
Real still.
You're taking the boy.
What else do you want?
Relax.
- Stop!
- Mama!
What else, motherfucker?
Fucking asshole!
[IN ENGLISH] Fuck!
[IN SPANISH] Drop the weapon.
Drop the weapon.
Don't shoot.
I'm a man of peace.
Let's go.
[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
Hey! Stop!
Colonel! Calderón took off.
- [IN ENGLISH] Fuck. We move fast.
- Okay.
[IN SPANISH]
You have a phone in there?
Yes, in there.
They got Gilberto, they're
moving towards the aerial base.
The whole workforce is on this.
They're not going to leave the city.
Tell all the men to be alert.
Understood?
Move it, asshole.
They'll try to take us on the road.
Guns out!
- [WOMAN] Cleaning, cooking, working.
- [PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
[CÓRDOVA] Don Miguel...
something's happened.
What happened?
I'm outside Gilberto's house. They
got him. They got your brother.
[MAN OVER RADIO] We've got a visual.
Surround him in the market!
[CALDERÓN] Tail him!
Look! There he goes! Faster!
Let's get him on the next turn!
Hold your fire!
Driver! Put your hands
where I can see them!
Driver!
Out further!
Further!
Get out.
Open the back.
- Okay. Let me get the keys.
- Open it.
Open it.
[IN ENGLISH] Okay. All right. Settle.
[IN SPANISH] The American
sons of bitches tricked us.
We've got the wrong truck!
They're going to the air field.
We'll get them there.
I took care of security.
Let those sons of bitches
try to touch us again.
Send Salcedo's beeper another message.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Uncle! It's me, Nicolas!
Come in.
- Nicolas.
- Uncle.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
They got him.
Nicolas, why don't you
go home and wait there?
Once something happens, I'll call you.
No, sir, I have to help.
Come.
You know your dad doesn't
want you mixed up in this.
We have to have faith that your
dad won't be taken out of Cali.
And if he is?
Why did we waste all of that money
on my education? I'm a lawyer.
I'm taking the first flight to Bogotá.
I want to help him.
Let's hope that's not necessary.
[IN ENGLISH] Fuck.
Wait here.
[VAN NESS] What's up? Why'd we stop?
There's cops surrounding the plane.
Cops? Good ones?
I don't think so.
[OFFICER IN SPANISH] Colonel Martínez.
Sir, please don't come any closer.
Your men are impeding the transport and
arrest of a fugitive under warrant.
You know it.
And that means prison.
What you do today...
what you do this moment...
defines you.
For the rest of your lives.
Are you police or not?
That's better.
[WHISTLES]
[IN ENGLISH] Home stretch.
[BEEPING]
[IN SPANISH] Shit!
[PHONE RINGS]
[JORGE] What's up? It's me.
- About fucking time.
- I was out of range.
They arrested Gilberto.
- What?
- They got him, Jorge.
They got Gilberto.
You were monitoring the raid.
But they never mentioned
Gilberto's name.
[JORGE] Even so, we checked all
the tapes. It's impossible.
It doesn't make sense!
I just don't understand!
Brother... they got him.
They took him away.
We got beat.
Get back here quick.
[DIAL TONE]
Hasta la vista, baby. Ciao.
[JORGE] Take that.
Five seconds to take photos, no more.
Congratulations.
But you know this won't hold up.
You're fucking with things that
are much bigger than you are.
Smile, Gilberto. You're
about to be on TV.
This way, Mr. Rodríguez.
Mr. Rodríguez, do you have a
response to the charges against you?
Conspiring to export cocaine
and illegal enrichment?
Enough. Let's go.
Do you have anything to say to the
people of Cali? Mr. Rodríguez.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] For those of us who
thought the surrender was bullshit,
Gilberto's arrest proved that
these guys could be caught.
For the people who thought the surrender
was the only way to avoid violence,
it was the beginning of a nightmare.
The first shot in a war to
bring down another cartel.
But whatever side you fell
on, one thing was clear:
Gilberto Rodríguez's arrest came
as a surprise to everybody.
Especially him.
Don Gilberto.
Hey, congrats.
Congratulations. Good work.
No, where you going? Come
on, we want to toast you!
Start without me.
[MAN] Great work!
- Mr. Ambassador.
- Big day.
- Quite a notch on your belt.
- It was strong intel, sir.
- I acted...
- Know how much work you torched?
People want to see the
godfathers in handcuffs
and that's what they're gonna get.
Front page of every
newspaper tomorrow.
Colombians may not feel that way.
Let's go find out.
Get changed.
- [IN SPANISH] My love!
- Mommy!
Mommy.
- Are you hungry? No?
- No.
How cute. Looks a lot like his dad.
Come on. Mom will read
you a story in a bit.
[MARÍA] Go. I'll be right there.
Thanks for showing up, Jorge.
Sir, we don't know how
much the DEA knows.
We need to assume all your
current homes are... unsafe.
I'll stay here for now.
We all need to talk.
What did you expect? A warrant by
definition authorizes the police...
Wait. Let's not lie to ourselves.
This operation was run by the
Drug Enforcement Administration
of the United States.
The takedown, Mr. Attorney
General, was National Police.
The transport was by our police.
The booking was by our police.
So a war started by National Police?
Look, as Attorney General,
my main... concern is achieving a
peaceful settlement with the godfathers.
And the arrest of Gilberto
Rodríguez Orejuela
means we now have new
leverage to negotiate with.
The President of Colombia,
Ernesto Samper.
I hate to be late to a good debate.
You know us, might as well try to
smooth rough water with a hammer.
I've been apprised by Minister Botero
about our newly-incarcerated
Cali godfather.
- With all due respect, Mr. President?
- Go ahead, Miguel.
We've worked for months to
negotiate this surrender.
We recommend the immediate release
of Mr. Rodríguez Orejuela.
Colombia is a nation of laws.
Not of concessions.
If I give a pass to the largest
criminal organization in the world...
the trust of the people
will be lost forever.
Mr. Rodríguez is entitled
to the same due process
as any Colombian citizen.
Let's see where due process gets him.
For now...
his arrest stands.
Thank you, gentlemen.
[IN ENGLISH] Fuckin' A.
[IN SPANISH] Thank you very much.
We talked about this. I don't
want the stink of this on you.
Relax, Dad.
I'm a lawyer. I'm the only one
in the family who can visit you.
Besides, I thought you
could use a friendly face.
What I could really use is a
tumbler of whiskey about this big.
How's it look?
The warrants are old.
- Invalid?
- Vulnerable.
I have a lunch tomorrow at 1:00 p.m.
with the Colombian Board of Pharmacies.
8:00 a.m., latest, I'm out.
Dad, you're here until our lawyers
get you in front of a judge.
And he'll hold you here in Bogotá
due to the conspiracy charge.
I don't get it.
This is a mistake, a blunder.
A gross overstep by a
rogue American agent!
That's what you want to believe.
But if that was the case,
you'd be out by now.
- Dad, this is real.
- No, money is real.
And what about all I've paid?
Sons of bitches can't
leave me confined here.
[DAVID] How the fuck did they
surprise us like that, gentlemen?
It was Calderón.
Dad, I say we tear him to pieces.
And his fucking family
and his children.
[MIGUEL] David, please.
Obviously, there's
responsibility on all sides.
- Córdova...
- Sir, just as we realized...
By the time you realized,
Colonel Martínez had already been in
my brother's house for 30 minutes.
Don Miguel. The failure's mine.
When it comes to the DEA,
Córdova counts on me.
Wait. Córdova, you're my brother's
personal head of security.
Yes, sir.
Then you should've been there.
Your men should've been there.
Your guards were fooled by
a fucking chicken truck.
I want to know what the
fuck is happening here.
Because I'm starting to believe
that none of us are safe.
Not your families...
and not mine.
My family.
Thank you, Attorney General
Valdivieso, Defense Minister Botero.
[IN ENGLISH] Today marks
an important beginning,
an important victory.
Because of the success of our
Colombian-American operation...
the Cali cartel is on the run.
And with the continued support of
the Colombian National Police...
I promise you... the other
three godfathers will fall.
Questions?
That's as much recognition
as we can hope for, right?
None at all? Smart move.
Keep his face all over this
while we're closing in.
Kiss-ass.
Want some?
No, I'm moving tables.
Oh, boy.
Oh, God.
Can't believe you're eating that shit.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[PEÑA IN SPANISH] Colonel, please.
Thanks.
[IN ENGLISH] Have a drink with me.
[PEÑA SIGHS]
Tonight, we celebrate.
Tomorrow, we go back to work.
Well, not for me.
[IN SPANISH] What are you talking about?
[IN ENGLISH] You remember those papers
that were seized by your men in Cali?
Yeah, we never saw those.
Apparently, Vargas did.
And there was a list of cops who've
been accepting money from Cali.
One name he was eager to share: Mine.
Those son of a bitches want to
discredit Gilberto's arrest.
Exactly. It sends a message to any
cop who wants to try what we did.
[IN SPANISH] I turned in
my weapon and my badge.
Good luck.
Colonel...
I'm sorry.
Men like me would give our lives
to arrest a man like him.
You did everything right, Peña.
But now you're all alone.
[IN ENGLISH] Take care.
[IN SPANISH] We need to
talk about your security.
Let me be in charge.
I'll protect you, Dad.
Now's not the time for a change.
We need to keep things on track
until your uncle is back.
What if he doesn't come back?
["LA GLORIA ERES TÚ" PLAYING]
[PAOLA] Jorge.
Jorge.
- They got Gilberto.
- [PACHO] I don't understand.
I thought Gilberto had
this all under control.
So did I.
And what now?
This could get messy.
Stay where you are. Right now,
we look out for ourselves.
Pacho... be smart.
For now, we wait.
You stay there a while longer.
We have to keep everything running.
The health of the business has never
been more important. Understand?
Yes. Of course.
You listening to me, motherfucker?
[IN ENGLISH] Hey, listen,
buddy, I don't speak Spanish.
No speak Spanish.
Okay.
Have a nice day.
Hey, boss. Good day today, huh?
The Jurado tapes.
Well, we probably shouldn't call them
that because they're not legal, per se.
I want all of them.
["ADIÓS" PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com