Oh, debbie,
you've got magic fingers.
Oh, i bet you give
a great hand job.
Yeah, she does.
Hey, there's my baby.
Debbie, you gotta put her
on the "a" list, really.
She rides better
than willie shoemaker.
Did she go to the whip?
He is so crazy.
Only in the home stretch.
Ah, another
satisfied customer.
I think he's having
a heart attack!
Don't move.
Go see if dr. Mop- n- glo
is still here.
What do you mean,
dr. Mop- n- glo?
Who?
Don't worry.
He's a real doctor.
A dermatologist.
Excuse me.
What's the matter?
Dr. Edelstein, looks like
he's having a heart attack.
I don't need no doctor.
It's just my back.
Nice and slow.
Oh, god.
Grab the rail.
That's right.
Go easy.
Go easy, now.
That's it.
Nice and easy.
Oh, mama.
That's it.
Come on. That's it.
Hold the rail.
I got it.
Go slow.
That's it.
Fuck this.
What, your fuckin' back
still botherin' you?
Yeah!
F. B. I.!
Nobody move!
You believe this shit?
Come on. It's
a friendly card game.
Relax, jimmy.
If i wanted to bust up
card games, i'd have
a donut in my mouth.
Hey! Hey!
Get him!
You! You!
-
oh, my goodness!
Do you know what this is?
It's a fucking gun!
Fuckin' jimmy's
still in jail.
- It don't mean shit.
- I don't like it.
This is how it starts.
I think it was
a potluck raid.
You know, make it look like
they're earnin' their pay.
I agree.
Then why the fuck
would pussy run?
The guy's out of breath
liftin' his dick up
to take a leak.
So, puss, your ears
must be ringin'.
Come on, run.
Ha, ha. You guys
are a fuckin' riot.
We were just gonna draw straws
to see who's goin' down there
and bail you out.
My wife did.
I nearly strangled her
on the ride home.
My head's hurtin',
i got angina,
and on top of all that,
i threw my goddamn
back out again.
Maybe it was
that ten- yard dash.
We don't run.
It's embarrassing.
Please. They robbed me,
those federal pricks.
- What do you mean?
- They grabbed four dimes
from me.
You shouldn't carry
that type of cash.
Never mind.
I need a drink.
Oh, jesus!
This better be good.
I was takin' my kid fishing.
Ah, jesus. What,
no "how you been?
How's it doin', vin"?
I thought we understood
each other, right?
I don't give two shits
about you, your family or
whether you take it up the ass.
Now, what's so important
you take me away from my boat?
Hey, fuck face,
where you goin'?
Why do you gotta talk to me
like this? I do a lot
of risky shit for you.
You're not doin'
charity work, remember?
All right. I'm sorry.
Hey, vin, how ya doin'?
What do you got for me?
- Bompensiero.
- Pussy?
- What about him?
- He's wired for sound.
What?
I got it
from a good source.
I thought you should know.
All right?
I'm sorry.
I know you like him.
Like him?
I fuckin'lovehim.
Now, who's your source?
He's on the force.
He's on the task force,
all right?
Look, he's not lyin' to me.
He was in my wedding.
I wanna see the report.
I can't get my hands--
i wanna see
the fuckin' 3- 0- 2!
All right.
I'll see what i can do.
It doesn't make any sense.
Yeah, it does, ton,
if you take the blinders off.
I'm in robbery/homicide. I was
told he was movin' a lot of "h"
to pay for his kid's college.
Why would i know
something like that?
And last spring,
with that big heroin bust,
where was he?
He told you
he was in las vegas,
am i right?
Again, i'm sorry,
but, yeah,
that's where he was.
He was in las vegas.
He was in a federal building,
cutting a deal.
And why did he walk so easy
from that thing the other day?
"Known wise guy
resisted arrest."
Who walks away
from a thing like that
with low- ball bail?
Why? Why would he do it?
Why?
Because he's facin' a possible
sentence of "from now on."
Mandatory, that's why.
Come on. I know a lot of guys
who can't do that kind of time.
Who is this guy, pussy, huh?
Who is he?
He's a man who loves his family
above all else.
Well, guess what?
That's their favorite target.
No--
okay. That's fine.
I just said it's fine.
Was that my mother?
She's not coming.
You say it like you
expected different.
I hoped.
Every year we have this
open house, and every year
she pulls the same shit.
It's what they call
"negative attention gettin'."
Maybe i should call her back.
That's just what
she wants you to do.
Come here.
You're bein' too nice.
Forget about her.
She'll be fine.
Will you do me a favor?
Can you get the guys to help you
move the piano out of the way?
They're comin' to get it
tomorrow because
some people don't play.
- I will.
- When? It's been gathering
dust here for three months.
Oh, puss, come here.
Excuse me.
- What do you need?
- We're gonna move this.
I wanna slide this
out of the way.
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
The fuckin' thing's on wheels.
My back, tony.
I'm thinkin' about goin' home,
sittin' in the tub.
You all right?
Yeah, it's just my back.
They got me on
these elephant pills.
All right.
Go easy on'em.
Go ahead, sit down.
Take it easy.
Listen, i want you
to keep your eye on pussy.
There's somethin'
wrong with him.
He's not himself.
You're tellin' me?
You know, he hasn't even
done his rounds in a week.
He's startin' to look
like an easy mark.
I told him,
"if someone owes you money,
even if you gotta crawl,
you get it."
I even told him to give me his
list on who owes what, and i'll
collect the fuckin' thing.
What'd he say?
He just nodded
like a fuckin' retard.
Yeah, it's those
fuckin' percs.
He's throwin' them
in his mouth
like they're m&ms.
And there isn't even anything
wrong with his back.
What do you mean?
Remember when that guy hit me
in the head with that pool cue,
and i fucked my neck up?
Yeah, down at the shore.
Right. I went
to this doctor.
This guy works on the jets'
front line when they get hurt.
Yeah, he's fuckin' like
the jonas salk of backs.
Anyway, i send pussy
to this doctor.
The guy gives him the works--
m. R. I. S, cat scans,
dog scans, you name it.
He says there's not
a fuckin' thing wrong
with his back.
Then again, he says, uh,
when it comes to backs,
nobody knows anything, really.
You know, i was on a good run,
and then, boom.
I don't know. It's like
i'm walking down the street,
and i'm looking up,
because i feel like a safe's
gonna land on my head.
A feeling of pending doom?
Let me ask you a question.
This mental stuff can cause
physical problems, right?
Are you having
any physical problems?
No, no, i'm fine.
But i got a friend,
a dear, dear friend,
and i'm concerned about him.
- What's wrong with him?
- It's his back.
See, he-- he's complaining
about his back,
but i think the doctor thinks
it's all in his head.
That's very possible.
What do you think?
- I think we should
just keep this about you.
- This is about me.
Every time i offer my opinion
about any of your friends,
it seems to interfere
with our therapy.
You start cursing
and screaming.
What kind of mental stuff
would cause a backache?
- For conversation's sake?
- Absolutely.
With some people,
the pain is...
caused by more responsibility
than they can handle.
Well, that makes sense.
I mean, he's got a lot of bills,
a lot of problems
with his kid's school fund.
Secrets.
What do you mean?
Psychologically, a secret
is a heavy load.
It leads to feelings of guilt
which further burden the mind.
If you want my opinion,
this can't be true.
Thanks, debbie.
You know, i told you
that i would do what i could,
but this is d. E. A. ,
feds, task force.
This is not as easy
as you think--
gettin' my hands
on the 3- 0- 2.
Now, you listen to me.
This is the most serious
fuckin' decision i've ever
had to make in my life,
and i need proof.
I'm not gonna hurt
a man that i love
because of some cop gossip...
from a degenerate fuckin'
gambler with a badge,
you understand me?
You know, you got
the amazing ability...
to sum up a man's whole life
in a single sentence.
"Degenerate gambler
with a badge," huh?
- You're a pisser.
You're a real pisser.
- Oh, i'm sorry.
I'm under a little bit
of pressure here. I don't
have time to suck your dick!
- Apology accepted.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck me?
- Yeah, fuck you!
You know, when i was a kid--
when i was a kid and my old man
would be in one of his ways,
with the screamin'
back and forth,
eventually it'd end
with her throwin'
the closest thing to her,
and he'd smack her around!
I don't know why,
but i would run into my room
and i would hide under my bed.
There was somethin' peaceful,
and there was somethin' safe
under that bed.
And that's where i would
wake up the next day.
Everything back to normal.
How about you, tony?
Do you ever feel
like hidin' under a bed?
Yeah. Right now.
Oh, you're a prick
to the end, right?
You really
like this place, huh?
It's my getaway.
This is where debbie's
taken care of me for years.
- I'll bet she has.
- I'm serious, she has.
I mean, there were times when
i'd be havin' a great weekend
with the football, you know,
and i would come in here
with a pocketful of money,
shitfaced,
and every friggin', fuckin'
penny of it would be there
when i got up in the morning.
She is an honest lady.
She'd do anything for you.
Anything.
Come on.
You come in here,
you flash your badge,
you get some free pussy.
Fuckin' pussy.
I wouldn't fuck one of
these broads with your dick.
They have absolutely no class,
and they're always
on the hustle.
That's kind of what they're
supposed to do, no?
"Oh, hello, carmela.
How nice to see you."
How are you feeling?
Oh, what can i say?
What's that?
Uh, it's a "rigot" pie.
I saved it from the open house.
Are you wearing makeup?
I can't eat that.
It's got cholesterol.
I made it with
the low- fat cheese.
Yuck!
Well, maybe
your friends'll eat it.
What friends?
Fine, you can eat it
when junior visits.
You know, ma, your son
loves you very much.
He worries all the time.
He felt bad that you
didn't come to the open house.
And i don't care if you think
it's disrespectful,
but i want you
to cut the drama.
- It's killing tony.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about this
"poor mother, nobody loves me"
victim crap.
It is textbook manipulation,
and i hate seeing tony
so upset over it.
I know how
to talk to people.
Well, i am a mother too,
don't forget.
And you know the power
that you have,
and you use it like a pro.
Power? What?
What power?
I don't have power.
I'm a shut- in!
You are bigger than life!
You are his mother!
I don't think for one second
you don't know what
you're doin' to him.
Who, me? Me?
What did i--
what did i do?
Look, i didn't come by
to argue.
I came by to check on you
and to bring you the rigot.
If you don't want it,
you can give it to junior,
'cause i know he stops by a lot.
He's my husband's brother.
He can't check up on me
once in a while?
It's none of
anybody's business.
Oh, my god.
I am not saying that.
All i'm saying is,
if you don't want it,
give it to junior.
I know what
you're hinting at.
Ma, there is nothing wrong
with companionship!
- What is wrong?
-
oh. Wait until
you're abandoned.
Oh!
Abandoned? Please!
When johnny was alive,
nobody treated me like this.
What are you talking about?
Who is treating you bad?
Tony would rather die
than see you hurt!
- Johnny was a saint.
- Yes, we have heard.
Funny, though, i don't remember
you telling him that
when he was alive.
Junior couldn't carry
johnny's socks.
Do you think i'd blacken
my johnny's memory...
by getting mixed up
with his brother?
Oh, jeez.
I didn't say that.
All i'm saying is that we
are happy that you and junior
get along so well.
Well, at least with junior, i--
i've got some purpose in life.
Somebody listens to me
and doesn't treat me
like an old shoe.
Jesus!
Don't worry about the dish.
I'll come back tomorrow
and get it.
Oh, tony.
Hey, college boy!
Yo, dad,
it's uncle tony.
There he is,
the beached whale.
Hey, tony,
what are you doin' here?
I figured you'd be havin'
a cannoli withdrawal by now.
Spinelli's?
No, stop'n shop.
What do you think?
Hey, you're the best.
Kev, put those on a dish.
Wait till after supper.
So, your father tells me you're
takin' up astronomy in college.
No, business.
How come he keeps sayin'
you're takin' up space
in school?
Madron, don't make me laugh.
It kills my back.
He's a good- lookin' kid.
Sure he's yours?
You're lucky my wife's not home.
She'd toss you out for that.
She doesn't play.
I know.
He's a good boy, tony.
I pray to god i keep that
fuckin' tuition comin' in.
Hey, the kid can always
go to city college.
This kid's stayin' right where
he is. He isn't gettin' fucked
'cause his old man is!
You ought to relax.
You ought to take it
easy a little.
"Take it easy."
How the fuck can i
take it easy?
Things are happenin', tony.
What kind of things?
Things!
This fuckin' back has taken me
out of the game.
I'm way behind.
And top it off,
i think i'm gettin' hooked
on these fuckin' painkillers.
I don't know.
I feel like someone
put themaloikon me.
Puss, you got options.
Don't let anyone make you feel
like you don't have any options,
'cause you got friends--
look at me-- friends
that would die for you.
You understand me?
Friends.
Yeah, i know.
You got anything
you want to say to me?
Like what?
Like,"you want some coffee,
tony? You want
somethin' to eat?"
You want coffee?
Yeah.
What do you think,
i'm gonna let you eat all those
fuckin' cannolis by yourself?
- You beached whale.
- Here.
What?
Help me up. You want coffee?
Who's gonna make it, you?
One, two, three.
You look good.
Yeah.
What's up, t?
Sit.
Fuckin' traffic.
I would've been here
20 minutes ago.
Want a drink?
Nah.
You okay?
- He's wearin' a wire.
- Who?
- Pussy.
- Oh, get the fuck outta here.
Our pussy?
Don't know how long.
- Are you sure
about this, tony?
- Ninety percent.
Not enough to do
what needs to be done.
Aw, jesus, tony,
i'm fuckin' dreamin' here.
Well, get used to it.
I've been walkin'
into walls all week.
I'll do it.
It's my responsibility.
Tony,
you waited a long time
for the stripes.
This is one of the perks.
I'll do it.
We need to be
110 percent sure.
I want you to see it.
I want you to see
that fuckin' wire
strapped on his body!
I want you to see it.
You hear me?
Otherwise,
all bets are off.
You understand?
No. This is our friend
we're talkin' about here.
You say it.
You understand?
I understand.
Come in.
Mr. Soprano.
Are you busy?
No, no, no.
Come in, please.
I was in the neighborhood,
figured i'd stop by
and see my mother.
Brought her
some mario lanza.
She, uh, loves
the old guys.
I'm a little worried about her.
You know, she's always
been depressed.
Sometimes these
half- assed tenors
can really do the trick.
You know where she is?
She's not in her room.
I wanted to tell her
her house went into escrow.
She's with the other girls
getting aqua therapy.
My mother?
The physical therapist told her
if she didn't get any exercise,
her back was gonna arch
like an old lady.
I didn't even know
she owned a bathing suit.
She's more connected
to the world.
Which one?
This one or neptune?
No, really.
I think your uncle's visits
has a lot to do with it.
Oh, she looks forward
to them.
- Oh, could you excuse me
one moment?
- Yeah, sure.
No, just, uh, tell her
her house sold,
and they accepted
the counteroffer.
Hello?
Okay. Yeah,
i'll be right there.
I'm leavin', guys.
All right, pussy.
I'll see you later.
Feel better.
I'll tell ya if that horse
is runnin'.
Don't do me any favors.
I gotta take off.
I'll see ya.
- Follow me.
- Where?
It's a surprise.
Come on, ya hard- on,
before we get a ticket.
Paulie, i been here before.
What the fuck you want?
Look around.
I'll give you three guesses.
Come on, down here.
We'll grab a rubdown after.
Here.
I don't know.
Come on, get undressed.
It's on me.
Why do you think
those russian leaders
live so long?
They take ashvitz
every day.
I can't.
Now, don't be like that.
It's a gift.
Take your clothes off.
What? You want me
to turn around?
The doctor said heat's no good
for me. I gotta avoid it.
That's why i sit in the shade.
What the fuck
you talkin' about?
Heat is good for your back.
Take your clothes off.
Look, paulie, i appreciate it,
but maybe another time, huh?
Take your clothes off.
You're fuckin' crazy.
I'm goin' home.
Why don't you wanna
take your clothes off?
I got high blood pressure,
you fuckin' idiot.
I go in there,
i could check the fuck out.
My doctor mentioned
steam and sauna
specifically as no- no's!
He said stay the fuck
away from heat!
Thanks for the thought,
but get out of my fuckin' face.
What'd you find out?
It's good.
It's fuckin' very good.
Spit it out.
He's into pussy, big.
I mean, with a capital "b."
This fuckin' makazian,
he's a lyin' motherfucker.
He's into pussy for,
like, 30 large.
Twenty grand
just on football.
Uh, the rest is shy.
Pussy must be burying
this prick in vig alone.
It doesn't mean
he's a liar.
It just means he's got
a reason to see pussy dead.
It buys him time.
Could this prick have the balls
to try somethin' like this?
Hey, we're talkin' about
30 grand here.
I don't even wanna think about
what me and you would do
to remove that debt.
I wouldn't bet football.
I gotta think about this.
Look, t, if my vote
counts for anything,
i cannot believe that pussy
would fear the can enough
to hurt his friends.
That's what they said
about gravano.
All right. Go back in.
I gotta think.
Deb?
Debbie?
Why don't you take it easy?
I would think a whore
would like a little pain.
Come on!
Take it easy!
Vinnie, stop it!
Let's get this show
on the road!
Look at this.
A doctor, a madam,
wise guy and a cop.
That's what i call
a vice superfecta.
The four were arrested
last night. A police
spokesman says...
that the officer in question
will be placed on
administrative leave,
pending the outcome
of the hearing
set for this morning.
I'd hate to have been there
when he got home.
I don't know which
is more embarrassing--
to be caught in a bordello
or to be caught
with the wise guy.
Meanwhile, there was a fire--
asshole.
What's a bordello?
It's a fancy name
for a whorehouse.
- Don't start, okay?
- It is.
Yeah, i know it is.
I just don't like that talk.
This country's light years
behind the rest of the world.
Most civilized countries...
have legalized prostitution.
Don't you got
somewhere to be?
It's a joke.
Look what they're putting
the president through.
- He deserved what he got.
- He got monica "kazinski" and
the broad with the long nose.
I just don't think sex
should be a punishable offense.
That's where i agree with you.
I don't think sex should be
a punishable offense either.
I do think that talkin'
about sex at the breakfast table
isa punishable offense.
- So no more sex talk, okay?
- It's the 90s.
Parents are supposed
to discuss sex
with their children.
Yeah, but that's where
you're wrong.
You see, out there
it's the 1990s,
but in this house
it's 1954.
1990s. 1954.
So now and forever,
i don't wanna hear
any more sex talk, okay?
What's with him?
Come on! Let's go!
Come on, come on!
Come on, you lame- ass driver!
Keep moving, please.
Come on!
Move it!
Where do you want me to go?
- Goddamn it!
- Come on, pull up!
Come on, goddamn it!
Come on! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Oh, go right ahead, detective.
Excuse me. Move it out, please.
Got a police officer here.
Move it out!
Let's go. Pull up.
Come on.
Police vehicle comin' through!
Are you sure?
Who told you this?
What?
Yeah. Yeah, i'm still here.
All right, thanks.
I'll talk to you later.
You gonna tell me?
The fuckin' jerk did a header
off the road one bridge.
Who?
Makazian.
Fuck!
There goes our only shot
to find out for sure
the truth about pussy.
Well, if it matters,
he always said how much
he respected you.
It matters.
He helped me out
of a lot of jams.
Not just with the law.
What the fuck was he thinkin'?
He could've kept his job.
He might've been suspended,
that's all.
It wasn't like
he was dealin'.
That's not why he did it.
Don't get me wrong,
it was the straw.
But he was not happy...
with himself,
how he turned out.
What did he
come here for, therapy?
You could say that.
Instead of a couch
you use a bed?
It's not a bad deal.
Hey, who wouldn't want
to sleep with their shrink?
What does that mean?
You would be amazed
how much easier it is
to open up when you're naked...
and in the arms of someone
who cares for you.
Did he ever...mention anything
about my guys to you?
He didn't like paulie.
He thought he was a psycho.
- What about pussy?
- He really didn't have much
to say about any of you guys.
Except that he
owed some money.
He wasn't worried
because you liked him,
and as long as he had you
in his corner,
there was nothing
really to worry about.
I'm not gonna lie
'cause he's dead.
He didn't have a good thing
to say about anybody,
but he did feel like
he could trust you, tony.
He said many times,
"at least with tony soprano,
you know where you stand."
Livia, open up.
It's junior.
Come on in.
It's open.
What's goin' on?
My dominican girl
said you called me.
Well, he sold our house.
Don't people
have names anymore?
Who's "he"?
Anthony.
He sold my house--
the home that
my husband and i made!
What else were they
gonna do with it?
You too?
Hey!
I suppose he would've found it
harder to have his meetings
atmyhouse...
than in this nursing home.
What are you talkin' about,
"meetings"?
Don't think i'll ever
see any of that money either.
- What meetings?
- Raymond, larry,
that sneak from manhattan.
Johnny sack?
Johnny sack was here?
With his mohair suits
and his shoe lifts.
Suits? Pleurisy?
More than once he was here?
Why didn't i know about this?
Well, maybe it was you
they were talking about.
Who knows?
I just don't like being put
in the middle of things.
I should've known
something was strange...
when suddenly larry boy's mother
moved in here...
and then
jimmy altieri's mother.
Three of mycappos
have their mothers
in this place?
Instead of living in
normal homes with their sons,
like human beings.
This must be some kind
of fuckin' end move.
What, do they think
i'm stupid?
We'll see.
Now, wait a minute.
I don't like
that kind of talk.
Now, just stop it.
It upsets me.
Or i won't tell you
anything anymore.
If this is true, livia,
you know what i--
i mean--
i'm divorced,
for christ's sake!
If i don't act,
blood or no--
i have to!
Oh, god!
What-- what did i say now?
I suppose i should have
just kept my mouth shut,
like a mute,
and then everybody
would have been happy.
Anthony, go see
who's at the door.
- I'm eating.
- But you won't have any teeth
left to eat with...
if you don't get off your ass
and see who's at the door.
Make sure you know who it is
before you answer it!
Who is coming at dinnertime?
People can't call?
I don't know.
It's uncle jimmy!
Uncle jimmy?
Let him in!
I don't believe it.
How'd you get out?
Hey.
Carm, look who's here.
It's jimmy. He's out.
Oh, my god! Jimmy!
Thought you'd never
see me again, huh?
So, what happened?
Long story.
You got someplace in private
we can talk?
Yeah, in the basement.
What's goin' on?
You got a problem.
Yeah, i know.
I'm workin' on it.
- Workin' on what?
- Why, what were you gonna say?
- You better lay low
with that safe house money.
- What are you talkin' about?
They were askin' me
a lot of questions
in there, you know?
If i knew anything
about the dead columbian
in the apartment and all that.
You look good.
Thanks. I wasn't
gone that long.
Yeah. Yeah, i know.
My lawyer told him,
"he doesn't own the building.
He's not responsible
for what's in the building."
I told him the pool table
was there when i first
rented the joint.
Good thinkin'.
Missed your callin'.
Should've been a lawyer.
Please.
Enough people hate me.
So, uh, what are you
gonna do about
the columbian money?
They were puttin'
the screws to me
like i was a school kid,
tellin' me that the money
was marked.
They even said that there's
a new fingerprint technique that
lifts'em right off the bills.
- You're a lucky man, jimmy.
- What do you mean?
- You're out on bail on that
conspiracy thing, right?
- Yeah, so?
So only a lucky prick like you
would get pinched with a gun...
while he's out on bail
for something else and still
be out in time for dinner.
You're a lucky guy.
Speakin' of dinner,
carmela's got some lasagna.
You want some?
Come on.
I'll pass.
I still got a few people to see
that are late with payments.
Oh, yeah?
I gotta make sure they
see my face, otherwise they
think they're off the hook.
Yeah, i know how that is.
- Get off the phone!
- I gotta go. What's up?
It's jimmy!
It's fuckin' jimmy!
What?
The wire,
it's fuckin' jimmy!
What are you talkin' about?
The wire.
Do you understand?
The wire,
it's fuckin' jimmy.
Holy shit.
"New fingerprint technique."
I should've killed him
right in my fuckin' basement.
Makazian's guy got his facts
crossed. They both got busted
at the same fuckin' time--
jimmy and pussy,
you understand?
Two fat fucks with black hair.
Where the fuck is paulie?
Uh, he called an hour ago,
i swear to god.
He said he's on his way.
Why the fuck
isn't he here now?
Jesus, tony.
You don't think, uh,
paulie jumped the gun?
Shut up. God forbid.
God forbid.
Don't talk like that.
Where's pussy?
Get him on the phone.
All right. All right.
I haven't seen him since, uh,
paulie took him to theshvitz.
Hey, fellas.
Where the fuck have you been?
I've been calling you
all fuckin' night long!
I was at mygoombahs.
I told silvio i was comin'.
You answer me like
i'm jesus christ himself,
and if you fuckin' lie to me,
may your mother die
of cancer of the eyes.
Where's pussy?
I don't know.
Don't you fuckin'
lie to me.
Tony.
Did you do it?
Tony--
shh. Don't fuckin'
lie to me.
Did you do it?
No.
Did you fuckin' do it?
I said no! Now get
your fuckin' hands off me.
Come on, tony.
Come on.
I'm sorry, paulie.
I can't find pussy anywhere!
Nobody knows anything!
I haven't seen him
since theshvitz.
The last thing
he said to me was,
"go fuck yourself."
Did he at least
take theshvitz?
He refused
to take his clothes off.
The rat,
it's fuckin' jimmy.
Ah, fuck it.
Let's all have a drink.
Easy. Here we go,
here we go, here we go.
All right.
Hey, babe!
- Look what chucky brought us.
- Oh, another kitchen appliance.
Whoop- fuckin'- pee.
Well, slit your wrists,
why don't ya?
A truckload fell off
the loading dock
at zim's last night.
Oh, it's not even
a "bra- oom."
That's a braun, babe.
Junior said for me to tell ya...
yeah?
He's decided...
on that thing.
He said we should
look out of town
for who's gonna do it.
Finally.
Yeah.
It's gonna
be a busy month.
Yeah.
I'll see ya.
All right.
See ya later. All right.
I'll see ya, jo.
Yeah, see ya.
- What was that sick fuck
talkin' about?
- Mind your business.
Whatever it is, mikey,
we're goin' to vegas
next month.
I already lined up child care
for frances albert,
so i don't wanna hear it.
Forget it.
Somethin's come up.
Somethin' always comes up.
This is a good somethin'.
I hope it means more money,
'cause i need a new car.
Trust me.
If this goes down,
you're gonna have a new car
and then some.
Can you tell me?
Oh, come on, mikey.
Tell me.
Mm- mmm.
Come on. Please?
I may be gettin' bumped up
a notch or two.
Tony soprano's on his way out,
and i mean as inforever.
Oh, my god!
He's goin' to jail?
No, the other forever.
Does junior know?
Oh, jeez.
Now, listen to me.
If you breathe
a word of this to anybody,
they're gonna be buryin'
me and you right next
to tony soprano, understand?
Yeah.
Okay.
Make it decaf.
You don't belittle a man
like junior soprano.
He's old school.
You don't joke
about cuntlapping,
and you definitely
don't spill your guts out
to a fuckin' shrink...
about business that isn't
yours to talk about.
Tony soprano sees a shrink?
You fuckin' believe that?
And to add insult to injury,
he was plannin' on makin'
a move against junior.
His own uncle?
Were you this fuckin' stupid
when i married you?
- Oh, fuck you!
- No, fuck you.
What are you doin'
standin' there?
Make the coffee.
Take it easy!
Take it easy.
It's brewin'.