▶️ TVWorld Proudly presents ◀️
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.:
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
Bring her back online.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not
feeling quite myself.
You can lose the accent.
Do you know
where you are?
I'm in a dream.
That's right, dolores.
You're in a dream.
Would you like to wake up
from this dream?
Yes.
I'm terrified.
There's nothing to be
afraid of, dolores,
As long as you answer
my questions correctly.
Understand?
Yes.
Good.
First...
Have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
No.
Tell us what you think
of your world.
Some people choose to see
the ugliness in this world.
The disarray.
I choose to see
the beauty.
Morning, daddy.
You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down
some of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
To believe there is
an order to our days,
A purpose.
What do you think
of the guests?
You mean the newcomers?
Now, the first time
I played it white hat.
My family was here.
We went fishing, did the
gold hunt in the mountains.
And last time?
I came alone.
Went straight evil.
It was the best
two weeks of my life.
I like to remember
what my father taught me.
That at one point
or another,
We were all new
to this world.
The newcomers are just looking
for the same thing we are...
A place to be free.
To stake out our dreams,
A place with unlimited
possibilities.
Oh, god,
it's incredible.
Better be
for what we're paying.
Murderous son of a bitch
named hector escaton.
Gunned down
the marshal.
He's holed up
in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of man
who'd put his mettle to it.
Not today, sheriff.
Apologies.
Rye whiskey.
What about it?
Well, it ain't doing any good
sitting in that bottle.
You're new.
Not much of a rind
on you.
I'll give you
a discount.
Well, no offense, but...
I'd rather earn a woman's
affection than pay for it.
You're always paying
for it, darling.
The difference is our costs are fixed
and posted right there on the door.
Do you ever feel
inconsistences in your world?
Or repetitions?
All lives have routine.
Mine's no different.
Still, I never cease to
wonder at the thought.
That any day the course
of my whole life.
Could change with
just one chance encounter.
Don't mind me.
Just trying to look
chivalrous.
You came back.
I told you I would.
Can I see you home?
Well, that all depends.
Can you keep up?
Well, I have
to fetch my horse.
Better fetch him fast.
That's a beautiful sight.
Never understood how you keep them
all headed in the same direction.
I forget you dress
like a cowboy,
But that's about
the extent of it.
See that one?
Yeah.
That's the judas steer.
Rest will follow
wherever you make him go.
How do you pick him out?
Just know these things.
Same as I knew
you'd be back.
You saying
I'm predictable?
There's a path
for everyone.
Your path leads
you back to me.
I know things will work out
the way they're meant to.
Same as I know my daddy still
won't be happy to see you.
Father wouldn't let them
roam this close to dark.
Stay put, dolores.
Ain't you got
anything out here.
Other than milk,
old man?
Go ahead.
I'm in no rush
to meet my judgment,
But I'm more sure of the outcome
than you, you son of a...
Nothing but milk, then.
Shame of it is
you killed the old woman.
Before any of us
could have a turn.
I reckon she's still
warm enough.
Nobody gonna
judge you for it.
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
Last question, dolores.
What if I told you
that you were wrong?
That there are
no chance encounters?
That you
and everyone you know.
Were built
to gratify the desires.
Of the people who pay
to visit your world?
Daddy!
Daddy! No!
The people you call
"the newcomers."
Hello again.
Your daddy
gave it up quickly.
Think he's losing
his touch.
You'll be following right
behind him, you son of a bitch.
Is that any way
to treat an old friend?
I've been coming here
for 30 years,
But you still don't
remember me, do you?
After all
we've been through.
They gave you a little
more pluck, dolores.
Absolutely charming.
Take your hands off her.
Oh, teddy.
Any special tricks for us?
They teach you
to sit up, beg?
How about I give you
the first shot, hmm?
After all,
every dog has his day.
Well, your mouth
move fast enough.
How about your gun?
What if I told you that
you can't hurt the newcomers?
And that they can do anything
they want to you?
I never understood why they
paired some of you off.
Seems cruel.
And then I realized.
Winning doesn't mean anything
unless someone else loses.
Which means you're here
to be the loser.
Let me help you, son.
Seems you're not the man
you thought you were.
Come on, beautiful.
Oh! Oh, no!
No!
Teddy! Teddy!
No, no, no,
please don't hurt him.
I'll do whatever you say.
I didn't pay all this money
'cause I want it easy.
I want you to fight.
Don't you touch her!
God damn, feels good
to be back.
Let's celebrate.
No! Don't!
Oh, no, no!
No!
Would the things
I told you.
Change the way you think
about the newcomers, dolores?
No!
No.
Of course not.
We all love the newcomers.
Every new person I meet reminds
me how lucky I am to be alive...
...And how beautiful
this world can be.
Oh, my god,
they're so lifelike.
Look at that one.
He's perfect.
Perfect is boring.
I'm more interested
in the bad guys.
Did you see it?
No.
Give it a second.
She'll do it again.
Her finger.
That's not standard.
I noticed it last night.
Went looking
in the update.
It's a whole new class
of gestures.
But if we didn't put it
there, then who did?
Ford. He still reviews every
update before we issue them.
He must have slipped it in
there without telling anyone.
He calls them "reveries."
The old gestures
were just generic movements.
These are tied to
specific memories. How?
The memories are purged at the
end of every narrative loop.
But they're still in there,
waiting to be overwritten.
He found a way
to access them,
Like a subconscious.
A hooker
with hidden depths?
Every man's dream.
It's the tiny things
that make them seem real,
That make the guests
fall in love with them.
Excuse me.
We have a problem?
We have some
unscheduled activity.
Evidently, one of your
creatures is restless.
In the park?
No, sublevel 83,
cold storage.
We should be cautious.
Send a response team,
full armor.
I'll take care
of it myself.
I think you guys enjoy playing
dress up as much as the guests.
The hosts can't hurt you
by design.
You don't have kids
at home, do you, bernard?
No.
If you did, you'd know that
they all rebel eventually.
You'll forgive them
for being a little uptight.
Every time your team
rolls out an update,
There's a possibility
of a critical failure.
We don't update the hosts
in cold storage.
And the park hasn't had a critical
failure in over 30 years.
Meaning we're overdue.
I'll go along, too. If it's one
of mine, I might be able to help.
They're only yours until
they stop working, bernie.
Then they're mine.
Cooling system's
been down for weeks.
Gonna smell fantastic.
I recommend you hang back.
When are they
gonna fix this?
Livestock management's
got other priorities.
Besides...
No one's complained.
Here's to the lady
with the white shoes.
Take all your money,
drink all your booze.
Stop.
Unless you plan
to decommission the boss.
Ain't got a cherry,
that ain't no sin.
She's still got the box
that the cherry come in.
I'll drink to that.
The old coffin varnish.
They don't make that
like they used to.
Hmm.
They don't make anything
like they used to.
Damn right.
Men neither.
I've seen a few
showdowns in my day.
More than you know.
Shall we drink to the lady
with the white shoes?
Perhaps we better
drink to a...
Deep and dreamless
slumber.
Old bill here
was always a good listener.
He was the second host
we ever built.
Were you with us
in those days, bernard,
Or was that
before your time?
Most were decommissioned before
I was brought on, I'm afraid.
They repeated themselves,
broke down constantly.
A simple handshake
would give them away.
You'll put yourself away
again, won't you, bill?
I saw the new gestures,
the reveries.
They're beautiful.
The distance you've traveled
from then till now,
It's remarkable.
Yeah, that's a word for it.
Morning, daddy.
You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down
some of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
After my errands,
of course.
See you home
before dark.
That bandit who gunned down the marshal
is still hiding up there in the hills.
I'm not a child anymore.
I'll be just fine.
When I was a law man...
Yes, daddy, I know all about
when you were a law man.
I know all your stories and so does
every boy that ever came courting.
I know how boys think.
Was one myself once.
Given to all manner
of drinking and mischief.
Whatever happened to that
fearsome ne'er-do-well?
He vanished the day
I became your father.
I am what I am
because of you,
And I wouldn't have it
any other way.
I know, daddy.
I'll be home before dark.
Murderous son of a bitch
hector escaton.
Gunned down
the marshal.
He's now holed up
in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of man
who'd put his mettle to it.
What do you think, honey?
Sounds fun.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
No offense, but I'd rather
earn a woman's affection.
Than pay for it.
Wait, wait,
I know that one.
Hey, teddy.
Yeah, last trip,
this dude showed me around.
What's the good word,
teddy?
Mighty kind of you.
Sweet.
Not as sweet as you.
I'm afraid I've got other
plans tonight, dolores.
Have a pleasant evening.
You're new.
Not much of a...
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Place your bets.
Yeah, looks like
hector's been this way.
Any idea how much longer
this is gonna take?
My wife doesn't want
to be up here after dark.
We know he's up
in these hills somewhere.
He's gonna put up one
hell of a fight when we...
When we... when we...
Sheriff?
Something is wrong with it.
I want to head back to town.
Now.
What the fuck
is wrong with it?
You updated the guy,
And now he's a six-foot
gourd with epilepsy.
So what the fuck
happened?
I don't know.
Well, that's exactly what you want to
hear from your head of programming.
We haven't finished
the diagnostic yet.
Clearly it's exhibiting
some aberrant behavior.
Pretty fucking
aberrant, bernie.
Your hosts get sick,
they get lost,
But this is grotesque.
Is it a problem
with the update?
Possible, but not likely.
If it's the unlikely version, how
many hosts have you updated so far?
Maybe 10%
of the population.
All right, we pull all updated
hosts until we can figure it out.
Are you fucking
kidding me?
That's 200 hosts spread across
a dozen active storylines.
The guests interrupt your
precious storylines all the time.
When they want to shoot
or fuck something.
No, when they want to.
We sell
complete immersion.
In 100 interconnected
narratives.
A relentless
fucking experience.
Now, you pull one character,
the overall story adjusts.
You pull 200 at once,
and it's a fucking disaster!
I mean, what do you
propose we do?
Close down? Issue fucking
gift certificates?
It's beautiful...
Your brow.
When you're angry
but trying to control it,
The fine muscles
pull into a little arc.
It's elegant.
Would you mind
if I recorded it?
I'd love to show it
to my team.
No, bernard,
you may not record it.
Ah, there it is again.
We have 1,400 guests
in the park.
I need to know
if they're in any danger.
His core code is intact,
Which means
he can't hurt a guest.
He literally
couldn't hurt a fly.
All he can do is...
...That.
All right, bernie.
Run a diagnostic.
In the meantime,
there's so much.
As an unscripted sneeze,
I want to know about it.
This place
is fucking wild.
This is basic.
Level one.
You ride out of town,
That's when the real
demented shit begins.
That's where my man
teddy comes in.
He's like a guide.
Honestly,
The guy kind of
creeps me out.
Fuck it, he leads us
out in the canyons,
We get bored, we just use
him for target practice.
I don't think we're supposed
to be cross the river.
It's too adult for jacob.
We didn't mean
to bother you.
No bother at all.
It's a beautiful spot.
I always found it a shame
that I have it all to myself.
They come here
every day.
Would you like
a closer look?
Don't be scared.
They're very gentle.
Here, put your hand
out real flat.
They're beautiful,
aren't they?
You're one of them,
aren't you?
You're not real.
I have to go now.
Sun's almost down.
You should, too. There's
bandits in these hills.
Man ♪2: Hyah! Hyah!
Here we go, yah!
Yah!
You waiting up
for me, daddy?
I told you I'd be
home before dark.
I found this
in the field today.
Doesn't look
like anything to me.
But where is she?
Have you ever seen
anything like this place?
Doesn't look like
anything to me.
I'm gonna help mama
put supper on.
I had the same thought.
Needed a little sunshine
before turning in.
So, when do you get
to rotate home again?
If you're this bad
at writing small talk,
How the fuck
did you get your job?
Get to the point.
I wanted to apologize if I
came across as aggressive.
And I wanted to talk
to you about the update.
The problem's
been resolved.
There should never have been
an update in the first place.
Ford and bernard keep making
the things more lifelike.
But does anyone
truly want that?
Do you want to think that your husband
is really fucking that beautiful girl.
Or that you really
just shot someone?
This place works because the
guests know the hosts aren't real.
So what exactly
are you suggesting?
Stop the updates
altogether.
Maybe even roll them
back a bit.
Make the hosts
more manageable.
Lobotomies tend
to do that.
Well, think of the benefits.
In terms of design time,
maintenance, costs.
Not to mention
the dr. Ford factor.
The guy's gonna chase his
demons right over the deep end.
I mean, no one respects him more
than me, but at some point...
I. No one respects him
more than i.
Your pronoun is the subject
of the second clause.
I was saying... you were saying
should our fearless leader.
Have a breakdown, you want to
leverage it for your career.
Listen, a changing of the
guard is long overdue.
I just wanted you to know
that you have my support.
And that I know that the corporation's
real interest in this place.
Goes way beyond gratifying some rich
assholes who want to play cowboy.
And here I thought
you were only good.
For writing depraved
little fantasies.
You're right.
This place is one thing
to the guests,
Another thing
to the shareholders,
And something completely
different to management.
So enlighten me.
What do you think management's
real interests are?
You're smart enough to guess
there's a bigger picture,
But not smart enough
to see what it is.
You know how much use that
makes your support to me?
Fuck all.
Get some sleep,
mr. Sizemore.
You'll have more rich
assholes to gratify tomorrow.
Early night, maeve?
Feeling a bit
out of sorts.
Clementine can
pick up the slack.
Night.
Forgetting
something, kissy?
I'm beginning to think
you're getting sweet on me.
Well, on account of you
being half cornhusker.
Tell me
which half is which.
And I'll search
that half.
Yeah, the half that's gonna
cut your fucking throat.
I told you,
I didn't take...
Good as new again, huh?
Sometimes I envy
your forgetfulness.
We've got a serious problem
with one of the hosts.
Thinking this one's
still thirsty.
Not gonna die
this time, arnold.
Ain't nothing
gonna kill me.
You can't have none.
Ain't for you.
Found me another bottle.
You're a growing boy.
A growing boy.
Growing boy!
We got two guests inside.
We'll go talk to them,
You sort this mess out.
You know, they're supposed
to turn on each other,
But only if a guest takes them
on the high sierra storyline,
And walter
always buys it.
Well, I guess walter
got tired of buying it.
I suppose this means the sheriff
wasn't an isolated incident.
It's good news, really.
Confirms the problem
was part of the update.
We can roll them back,
Clean them up,
put them back in service.
You think I'm gonna
sign off.
On this fucking homicidal thing
going back into service?
It's homicidal by design.
Walter kills other hosts
all the time.
I'll admit the method here.
Is a little unconventional,
But it didn't hurt a guest.
The hosts are supposed to
stay within their loops,
Stick to their scripts.
With minor improvisations.
This isn't
a minor improvisation.
This is a fucking
shitstorm.
We recall all remaining
updated hosts tomorrow.
Examine them one by one,
decommission the faulty ones.
What about narrative?
A recall of that size
will be disruptive.
I've told our overstimulated
friend to advance.
The saloon heist a week and
make it twice as bloody.
Should give us cover to
recall the remaining hosts.
And the guests
will love it.
I'm not sure
ford will approve.
I'm not sure either, which is why
you get to be the one to tell him.
This is your fuckup,
bernie.
Only seems fair.
So our creatures
have been misbehaving,
And you haven't yet
isolated the bug?
That's so unlike
you, bernard.
Unless, of course, you have and are
simply embarrassed by the result.
It's the code
you added, sir.
The reveries.
It has some...
"mistakes."
Is the word you're
too embarrassed to use.
You ought not to be. You're a
product of a trillion of them.
Evolution forged the
entirety of sentient life.
On this planet
using only one tool...
The mistake.
I flattered myself we were taking
a more disciplined approach here.
I suppose self-delusion is a gift
of natural selection as well.
Indeed it is.
But, of course,
we've managed to slip.
Evolution's leash now,
haven't we?
We can cure any disease,
Keep even the weakest
of us alive,
And, you know,
one fine day.
Perhaps we shall
even resurrect the dead.
Call forth lazarus
from his cave.
Do you know
what that means?
It means that we're done.
That this is as good
as we're going to get.
It also means that
you must indulge me.
The occasional mistake.
About three liters.
That's how much blood
I left in you.
Lose more than that,
you die.
But for now,
you're mine.
I'm gonna get
some answers out of you.
Where are you...
What do you want?
You know about games,
don't you, kissy?
Well, this is
a complicated one.
I don't play.
I only deal.
Who said anything
about you playing?
You're livestock,
scenery.
I play.
The others, they just come
here to get their rocks off,
Shoot a couple indians.
But there's a deeper
level to this game.
You're gonna show me
how to get there.
A lot of wisdom
in ancient cultures.
And perhaps it's...
Time to dig deeper
into yours.
No. No. No.
Morning, daddy.
Did you sleep well?
Daddy, you've been
out here all night?
I had a question.
A question you're not
supposed to ask.
Which gave me an answer.
You're not supposed
to know.
What's wrong, daddy?
Would you like
to know...
the question?
Question?
Mama!
Mama, help!
Come quick!
Don't worry.
I'll take care of you.
No!
You should go.
Leave.
Don't you see?
Hell is empty and all
the devils are here.
You stay right here.
Understand?
I'm gonna find
the doctor.
You came back.
I told you I would.
What's wrong? You have to
come with me right away.
My father's very ill.
I think we best
stay put.
All right.
With considerable effort
and lack of sleep,
I've managed to massage
events to inspire hector.
To head to town
a week early.
Oh, and I've also punched up
the speech he gives.
After robbing
the saloon.
It's chilling.
You'll see.
I can barely
contain myself.
That's the sheriff's horse,
you son of a bitch.
His rifle, too.
All the banks
and trains around here,
And you fucking reprobates
choose to rob us?
Why not?
You're all here indulging
your particular vices.
And so I've come
to indulge mine.
I've got to get
back to father.
Dolores, no!
Teddy.
Don't mind me.
Just... just trying
to look chivalrous.
Oh, teddy.
You're a low-down
son of a bitch.
I know.
I know we both
believe the same thing.
No matter how dirty
the business,
Do it well.
No telling there's anything
worthwhile in that safe.
We should take
this sweet little bitch.
Just in case.
Problem with the righteous...
They can't shoot for shit.
Making a hell
of a racket, though.
You wanted me.
Well, let this
be a lesson.
The lesson is...
Oh, Jesus.
Look at that! I just shot
him through the neck!
And his pal here, too.
Look at her wriggle.
Yo, go get
that photographer.
I want to get
a picture of this.
Okay.
Whoo!
You're welcome.
Maybe you'll get
to your speech next time.
Oh, teddy.
At least I got to see
you one last time.
You're not going
anywhere, now, hear?
There's a path
for everyone.
My path is bound
with yours.
Teddy?
Teddy, no.
Please.
No, we've only
just begun.
That was good.
Hang on. Hang on.
Let me get the hat.
Get the hat.
All right.
Help, please.
My father's sick at home,
But I can't just leave him
out here in the street.
Soon this will all feel
like a distant dream.
Until then, may you rest in a
deep and dreamless slumber.
Two more over here.
We got them all.
That's all of them.
Any preliminary
results?
Most of them
are checking out fine.
We had one who...
Definitely was not.
Bring her back online.
Cognition only.
No emotional affect.
All right, sweetheart,
can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not
feeling quite myself.
Lose the accent.
Do you know where you are?
I'm in a dream.
That's right, dolores.
You're in a dream.
A dream that could
determine your life.
You want to wake up
from this dream, dolores?
Yes.
I'm terrified.
There's nothing
to be afraid of,
As long as you answer
my questions correctly.
You understand?
Yes.
Good.
First, have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
No.
Has anyone around you?
For instance,
your father?
He was scared.
He wasn't thinking right.
He showed you
a picture.
That's right.
Was there anything odd
about that picture?
No, nothing at all.
It didn't look like
anything to me.
If it breached,
he needs to be put down.
That's the policy.
Would it not be best for
us to discover why first,
Ms. Cullen?
Please.
We've run
a full diagnostic,
But the results are,
Well, confusing.
Tell me, what happened
to your program?
"When we are born,
We cry we are come.
To this great stage.
Of f-f-fools."
That is enough.
Tell me,
do you have access.
To your previous
configuration?
Yes.
Access that, please.
What is your name?
Mr. Peter abernathy.
Mr. Abernathy,
what are your drives?
Tend to my herd.
Look after my wife.
Your final drive?
Well, my daughter
dolores, of course.
I must protect dolores.
I am who I am
because of her,
And, well, i...
I wouldn't have it...
I-I wouldn't
have it any...
Other...
I-I have to warn her.
Warn who?
Dolores.
The things
they do to her.
you do to her.
I have to protect her.
I have to help her.
I...
She's got to get out.
Very good,
mr. Abernathy.
That's enough.
This behavior,
We're miles beyond
a glitch here.
Access your
current build, please.
What is your name?
Rose is a rose...
Is a rose.
What is your itinerary?
To meet my maker.
Uh-huh.
Well, you're in luck.
And what do you want to say
to your maker?
By most mechanical.
And dirty hand...
I shall have
such revenges on you.
Both.
The things I will do.
What they are,
yet I know not,
But they will be
the terrors of the earth.
You don't know
where you are, do you?
You're in a prison
of your own sins.
Turn it off.
What the hell was that?
I don't know.
He's off script.
We didn't program
any of those behaviors.
Shakespeare.
We've used this host in a number
of different roles, have we not?
Since I've been here, he's
been abernathy for 10 years.
He was sheriff
for a while before then.
And before that...
The professor.
Yes, from a horror narrative
called "the dinner party."
He was leader of a group of cultists
out in the desert who turned cannibal.
He liked to quote
shakespeare, john donne,
Gertrude stein.
I admit the last one
is a bit of an anachronism,
But I couldn't resist.
These are fragments
of prior builds.
The reveries must be
allowing him to access them.
No cause for alarm,
bernard.
Simply our old work
coming back to haunt us.
Your father whispered
something to you.
What was it?
He said I shouldn't
tell anyone.
I won't tell anyone else.
Promise.
He said,
"these violent delights
have violent ends."
Does that mean
anything to you?
No.
I don't think so.
Have you ever
lied to us?
No.
Last question, dolores.
Would you ever hurt
a living thing?
No.
Of course not.
Tilt your head back,
please, peter.
Wipe's complete.
You don't think any of that had
an impact on her core code?
Not good old dolores.
You know why
she's special?
She's been repaired so many times,
she's practically brand-new.
Don't let that fool you.
She's the oldest host
in the park.
Come on, sweetheart.
Tell us what you think
of your world.
This world?
Some people choose to see
the ugliness in this world.
The disarray.
Morning, daddy.
You sleep well?
Well enough.
You heading out to do some more
of that painting of yours?
I choose to see
the beauty.
To believe there is
an order to our days...
A purpose.
I know things will work out
the way they're meant to.
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.: