In the 5th century, as the once-mighty
Roman Empire crumbled,
the soft underbelly of Western Europe
lay invitingly exposed
to the barbarian hordes to the East.
Alaric the Visigoth, Galseric the Vandal
and Theodoric the Ostrogoth in turn
swept westward in a reign of terror.
But none surpassed in power and cruelty
the mighty Attila the Hun.
Ladies and gentlemen, it's the
'The Attila the Hun Show'.
In the second quarter of the 5th century,
the Huns became a byword
for merciless savagery.
Their Khan was the mighty warrior Attila.
With his devastating armies
he swept across Central Europe.
Oh darling, I'm home.
Hello darling.
Had a busy day at the office?
Not at all bad. Another merciless sweep
across Central Europe.
I won't say I'm glad to see you,
but boy, am I glad to see you.
Hi, daddy.
Hi, Jenny, hi, Robby.
Hey, I've got a present for you two kids
in that bag.
I want you kids to get a-head.
Hear you are, Mr Hun!
Hi, Uncle Tom.
There's a whole horde
of them marauding Visigoths
to see y'all.
And now for something completely different.
It's ...
Yes, it's Attila the Nun.
A simple country girl who took a vow
of eternal brutality.
Nurse!
- Hello, Miss Norris. How are you?
- Not too bad, thank you, doctor.
Yes, well I think I'd better examine you.
- What are they doing here?
- It's all right, they're students.
Um... lights please, nurse.
Oh... and... er... music, too.
Breathe in ... out ...
in ... out...
Thank you, thank you.
Charles Crompton, the Stripping Doctor.
And next, gentlemen and ladies,
here at the Peephole Club
for the very first time
a very big welcome for the Secretary
of State for Commonwealth Affairs.
Good evening.
Tonight I'd like to restate
our position on agricultural subsidies,
and their effect on our
Commonwealth relationships.
Now although we believe, theoretically,
in ending guaranteed farm prices,
we also believe in the need
for a corresponding import levy
to maintain consumer prices
at a realistic level.
But this would have the effect of
consolidating our gains of the previous
fiscal year, prior to the entry.
But I pledge that should we join
the Common Market
even maintaining
the present position on subsidies
we will never jeopardize, we will
never compromise our unique relationship
with the Commonwealth countries.
A prices structure related
to any import charges
will be systematically adjusted
to the particular requirements
of our Commonwealth partners,
so that together
we will maintain a positive,
and mutually beneficial alliance
in world trade and for world peace.
Thank you and goodnight.
Wasn't he marvellous?
The Secretary of State
for Commonwealth Affairs!
And now gentlemen and ladies,
a very big welcome please
for the Minister of Pensions
and Social Security!
Yes, today in Britain
there is a new wave of interest
in politics and politicians.
Well, we're just in it for the lobbying,
you know. We just love lobbying.
And the debates, you know a good debate
is just... fabulous.
Well, I've been going with ministers
for five years now and, you know...
I think they're wonderful.
- Oh yes, I like civil servants.
- Oh yes, they're nice.
- I like the Speaker.
- Oh yes.
I like Black Rod.
What do their parents think?
Well she's broken our hearts,
the little bastard.
She's been nothing but trouble
and if she comes round here again
I'll kick her teeth in.
- Have you been talking to
television again, dear?
- Yes, I bloody told 'em.
- What about?
- I dunno.
- Was it Reginald Bosanquet?
- No, no, no.
- Did he have his head all bandaged?
- No, it wasn't like that. They had lots
of lights and cameras and tape recorders
and all that sort of thing.
Oh, that'll be Ray Baxter and the boys
and girls from 'Tomorrow's World'.
Oh, I prefer Reginald Bosanquet,
there's not so many of them.
Oh - that'll be the ratcatcher.
- Hello - Mr and Mrs Concrete?
- Yes.
Well, well, well, how very nice.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Leslie Ames, the Chairman of
the Test Selection Committee,
and I'm very pleased to be able
to tell you that your flat
has been chosen as the venue
for the 3rd test
against the West Indies.
- Really?
- No, it was just a little joke.
- Actually, I am the Council Ratcatcher.
- Oh yes, we've been expecting you.
Oh, I gather you've got
a little rodental problem.
Oh, blimey. You'd think he was awake
all the night, scrabbling down
by the wainscotting.
Um, that's an interesting word, isn't it?
Wainscotting ... Wainscotting ...
sounds like a little Dorset village,
Wainscotting.
We've been mentioned on telly!
- Now, where is it worst?
- Down here. You can usually hear them.
No, that's sheep you've got there.
No, that's definitely sheep.
A bit of a puzzle, really.
Yeah, well, I mean it's (a) not going
to respond to a nice piece of cheese and
- (b) it isn't going to fit into a trap.
- Oh - what are you going to do?
Well, we'll have to look for the hole.
- Oh yeah. There's one here.
- No, no, that's mice.
Ah, this is what we're after.
- Excuse me, is the 3rd test in here?
- No - that was a joke - a joke!
Right. I'm going in the wainscotting.
They said it again.
I'm going to lay down some sheep poison.
- Aagh. Ooh! It's got a gun!
- Blimey.
Normally a sheep is a placid, timid
creature, but you've got a killer.
It's an entirely new strain of sheep,
a killer sheep that can not only hold
a rifle but is also a first-class shot.
But where are they coming from, professor?
That I don't know. I just don't know.
I really just don't know.
I'm afraid I really just don't know.
I'm afraid even I really just don't know.
I have to tell you I'm afraid
even I really just don't know.
I'm afraid I have to tell you...
Thank you.
I don't know. Our only clue is
this portion of wolf's clothing
- which the killer sheep ...
- ... was wearing ...
- ... in yesterday's raid on Selfridges.
- I'll carry out tests on it
straight away, professor.
Hello, is the third test in here, please?
Professor, there are some cricketers
in the laboratory.
This may be even more serious than
even I had at first been imagining.
What a strange... strange line.
There's no time to waste, get me
the Chief Commissioner of Police.
No, no, on the phone.
Look of fear!
Another strange line.
Look out, Miss Carter Oil!
- What is it? What have you seen?
- Look - there, in the doorway.
Arthur X! Leader of the Pennine Gang!
Nobody move!
Put plan A into operation.
Move out!
Next, Basil, you and the kid.
Move!
Ok boys, this time we go
for the heavy stuff.
But soon the killer sheep began
to infect other animals
with its startling intelligence.
Pussy cats began to arrange mortgages,
cocker spaniels began
to design supermarkets...
And parrots started to announce
television programmes.
It's 8 o'clock and time for the News.
Good evening. Here is the news for Parrots.
No parrots were involved
in an accident on the M1 today
when a lorry carrying high-octane fuel
was in collision with a bollard.
That is a bollard and not a parrot.
A spokesman for parrots said
he was glad no parrots were involved.
The Minister of Technology today met
the three Russian leaders
to discuss a £4 million airliner deal.
None of them went in the cage, or swung
on the little wooden trapeze
or ate any of the nice millet seed
yum, yum.
That's the end of the news, now
our programs for parrots continue with
part 3 of 'A Tale of Two Cities',
specially adapted for parrots by Joey Boy.
The story so far, Dr. Manette is in
England after 18 years in the Bastille.
His daughter Lucy awaits her lover
Charles Darney, who we have just learned
is in fact the nephew of
the Marquis de St Evremond,
whose cruelty had placed Manette
in the Bastille.
Darney arrives to find Lucy
tending her aged father.
'Allo, 'allo...
And while that's going on, here is
the news for gibbons.
No gibbons were involved in...
And while that's going on, here
from Westminster is
a parliamentary report for Humans.
In the debate, a spokesman accused
the goverment of being silly
and doing not at all good things.
The member accepted this
in the spirit of healthy criticism,
but denied that he had ever
been naughty with a choir boy.
Angry shouts of 'What about the
Watermelon then?' were ordered then
by the speaker to be stricken
from the record and put into
a brown paper bag in the lavvy.
Any further interruptions would be
cut off and distributed amongst the poor.
For the Government, a front-bench spokesman
said the Agricultural Tariff would have
to be raised, and he fancied a bit.
Futhermore, he argued, this would give
a large boost to farmers,
and a lot of fun for him, his friends,
and Miss Moist of Knightsbridge.
From the back benches there were
opposition shouts of 'Postcards for sale'
and a healthy cry of 'Who likes a sailor
then?' from the minister without portfolio.
Replying, the Shadow Minister said
he could no longer deny the rumors,
but he and the Dachshund were very happy.
And in any case he argued
Rhubarb was cheap, and what was
the harm in a sauna bath?
The Minister of Technology met
the 3 Russian leaders
today to discuss a £4 million
airliner deal...
None of them were indigenous to
Australia, carried their babies
in pouches, or ate any
of those yummy Eucalyptus leaves.
Yum Yum!
Thats the news for wombats,
and now Attila the Bun!
Well that's all for Attila the Bun,
and now - idiots!
Arthur Figgis is an idiot.
A village idiot.
Tonight we look at the idiot in society.
Well I feel very keenly that the idiot
is a part of the old village system,
and as such has a vital role to play in
a modern rural society, because you see
Ooh ar thankee, Vicar.
There is this very real need
in society for someone
whom almost anyone can look down on
and ridicule.
And this is the role that...
Thank you, Mrs Thompson...
this is the role that I
and members of my family have
fulfilled in this village
for the past 400 years...
Good morning, Mr Jenkins,
ICI have increased
their half-yearly dividend, I see.
Yes, splendid.
That's Mr Jenkins - he's another idiot.
And so you see the idiot does provide
a vital psycho-social service
for this community.
Oh, excuse me, a coach party
has just arrived. I shall have
to fall off the wall, I'm afraid.
Arthur takes idiotting seriously.
He is up at 6 o'clock every morning
working on special training equipment
designed to keep him silly.
And of course he takes great pride
in his appearance.
Like the doctor, the blacksmith,
the carpenter,
Mr Figgis is an important figure
in this village
and, like them, he uses the local bank.
Yes, we have quite a number
of idiots banking here.
What kind of money is there in idioting?
Well nowadays a really blithering idiot
can make anything up to
£10 000 pounds a year
if he's the head of
some big industrial combine.
But of course, the more old-fashioned
idiot still refuses to take money.
He takes bits of string, wood,
dead budgerigars,
sparrows, anything, but it does make
the cashier's job very difficult;
but of course they're fools
to themselves because
the rate of interest over 10 years
on a piece of moss or a dead vole
is almost negligible.
Mr Brando.
Hollywood on the phone.
I'll take it in the office.
But Mr Figgis is no ordinary idiot.
He is a lecturer in idiocy
at the University of East Anglia.
Here he is taking a class
of third-year students.
After three years of study
these apprentice idiots
receive a diploma of idiocy,
a handful of mud
and a kick on the head.
But some of the older idiots
resent the graduate idiot.
I'm a completely self-taught idiot.
I mean... nobody does that anymore.
Anybody who did that round here
would be laughed off the street.
No, nowadays people want
something wittier.
Kevin O'Nassis works largely with walls.
You've got to know what you're doing.
I mean, some people think I'm mad.
The villagers say I'm mad,
the tourists say I'm mad.
Well I am mad, but I'm naturally mad.
I don't use any chemicals.
But what of the idiot's private life?
How about his relationship with women?
Well I may be an idiot but I'm no fool.
But the village idiot's dirty smock
and wall-falling
are a far cry from the modern world
of the urban idiot.
What kinds of backgrounds do
these city idiots come from?
I can't remember but I've got it
written down some where.
Daddy's a banker.
He needed a wastepaper basket.
Father was Home Secretary
and mother won the Derby.
The headquarters of these urban idiots
is here in St John's Wood.
Inside they can enjoy
the company of other idiots
and watch special performances
of ritual idioting.
Well left.
Well played.
Well well.
Well bred.
Good afternoon and welcome to Lords
on the second day of the first test.
So far today we've had 5 hours batting
from England and already
they're nought for nought.
Cowdrey is not out nought.
Naughton is not in.
Knott is in and is nought for not out.
Naughton of Northants got a nasty knock
on the nut in the nets last night
but it's nothing of note.
Next in is Nat Newton of Notts.
Not Nutring - Nutting's at nine, er,
Nutring knocked neatie nighty knock knock...
anyway England have played extremely well
for nothing, not a sausage,
in reply to Iceland's first innings total
of 722 for 2 declared, scored yesterday
disappointingly fast in only 21 overs
with lots of wild slogging and boundaries
and all sorts of rubbishy things.
But the main thing is that
England have made an absolutely
outstanding start so far,
- Peter?
- Splendid. Just listen to those thighs.
And now it's the North East's turn
with the Samba. Brian.
Rather. I'm reminded of the story
of Gubby Allen in '32...
Oh, shut up or we'll close the bar.
And now Bo Wildeburg is running up
to bowl to Cowdrey, he runs up,
he bowls to Cowdrey...
... and no shot at all.
Extremely well not played there.
Yes, beautifully not done anything about.
A superb shot of no kind whatsoever.
I well remember Plum Warner leaving
a very similar ball alone in 1732.
Oh shut up, long nose.
And now it's Bo Wildeburg running in
again to bowl to Cowdrey, he runs in.
He bowls to Cowdrey, and no shot at all,
a superb display of inertia there...
- That's the end of the over, and drinks.
- Gin and tonic please.
No, no, the players are having drinks.
And now, what's happening?
I think Cowdrey's being taken off.
Yes, Cowdrey is being carried off.
Well I never. Now who's in next,
it should be number 3, Natt Newton of Notts.
Get your hand off my thigh, West...
No I don't think it is...
I think it's er, it's the sofa.
No it's the Chesterfield!
The green Chesterfield is coming in
at number 3 to take guard now.
I well remember a similar divan
being brought on at Headingley
in 9 BC against the darkies.
Oh, shut up, elephant snout.
And now the green Chesterfield
has taken guard
and Iceland are putting on
their spin dryer to bowl.
The spin dryer moves back to his mark,
it runs out to the wicket,
bowls to the table...
a little bit short but it's coming in
a bit there and it's hit him on the pad.
And the table is out, leg before wicket.
That is England nought for one.
And now we leave Lords and go over
to Epsom for the 3 o'clock.
Well here at Epsom we take up
the running with 50 yards of
this mile and a half race to go
and it's the wash basin in the lead
from WC Pedestal. Tucked in nicely
there is the sofa going very well with
Joanna Southcott's box making a good run
from hat stand on the rails,
and the standard lamp is failing fast
but it's wash basin definitely taking up
the running now being strongly pressed by
At the post it's the wash basin from WC
then sofa, hat stand, standard lamp
and lastly Joanna Southcott's box.
Open the box!
And could we have
the next contender, please?
- Good evening, madam, and your name is?
- Yes, yes...
- And what's your name?
- I go to church regularly.
Jolly good, I see, which prize do you
have particular eyes on this evening?
- I'd like the blow on the head.
- The blow on the head.
- Just there.
- Jolly good. Well your first question
for the blow on the head this evening is:
What great opponent of Cartesian dualism
resists the reduction of psychological
phenomena to physical states?
- I don't know that!
- Well, have a guess.
- Henri Bergson.
- Is the correct answer!
- Ooh, that was lucky.
I never even heard of him.
- Jolly good.
I don't like darkies.
Ha ha ha. Who does?
And now your second question
for the blow on the head is:
What is the main food that penguins eat?
- Pork luncheon meat.
- No.
- Spam?
- No, no. What do penguins eat? Penguins.
Penguins?
I hate penguins.
- They eat themselves.
- No, no, what do penguins eat?
- Horses! ... Armchairs!
- No, no, no. What do penguins eat?
- Oh, penguins. Cannelloni.
- No.
Lasagna, moussaka, lobster thermidor,
escalopes de veau à l'estragon avec
endives gratinées with cheese.
No, no, no, no. I'll give you a clue.
- Ah, Brian Close.
- No.
Brian Inglis, Brian Johnson, Bryan Forbes.
- Nanette Newman.
- No. What swims in the sea
and gets caught in nets?
- Henri Bergson.
- No.
Goats. Underwater goats
with snorkels and flippers.
A buffalo with an aqualung.
- Reginald Maudling.
- Yes, that's near enough.
I'll give you that.
Now, Mrs Scum, you have won your prize,
do you still want the blow on the head?
- Yes, yes.
- I'll offer you a poke in the eye.
- No! I want a blow on the head.
- A punch in the throat?
- No.
- All right then, a kick in the kneecap?
- Mrs Scum, I'm offering you a boot
in the teeth and a dagger up the strap?
- Err...
(Blow on the head! Take the blow on the head!)
- No, no. I'll take the blow on the head.
Very well then, Mrs Scum, you have won
tonight's star prize, the blow on the head.