The sun is absent
for up to half the year
in the polar regions.
When it returns
at the beginning of spring,
its warmth will transform
this magical ice world.
The greatest seasonal change
on our planet is now underway.
Antarctica is still locked in ice
and surrounded by a frozen ocean.
Nonetheless, there are signs of spring.
Adélie penguins are arriving.
Just the males.
They've spent five months at sea,
where it's warmer than it is on land,
and now they're in a hurry,
for spring will be short.
They have travelled 6,000 miles
across the ocean
since leaving their colony last year
and now they're returning to breed.
They cannot lay their eggs on ice,
for they would freeze,
so they have to come here,
where there is bare rock.
Over the coming months, the few parts
of Antarctica that are ice free
will be the stage on which five million
Adélies will build their nests.
To construct one, they need pebbles,
and without a good-looking nest,
a male will be unable
to attract a female
when they at last arrive.
An impressive property
demonstrates your worth as a mate.
It takes stones of all shapes and sizes
to build a decent nest.
And finding ones that
are just right is not easy.
So some penguins turn
to a life of crime.
The one who has been robbed
seems unaware that the thief
is just over his shoulder
and looking for more.
The thief's nest is coming along nicely,
probably because he keeps a particularly
sharp lookout for robbers.
After all, it takes one to know one.
It's still cold,
but the early season sun
does lift the temperature
by a few degrees.
That, however, can have unexpected,
even dangerous, consequences.
The sea is heating faster than the land,
pulling cold air from the middle
of the continent towards the coast.
These katabatic winds are
stronger than any hurricane.
They are the coldest
and the most ferocious on the planet.
The storms catch many
new arrivals by surprise
and are the reason that spring here is,
in fact, the deadliest season.
Here, early birds take a great risk.
Some years entire colonies are lost,
buried beneath the snow.
The survivors of this storm
must hope that the females
prove to be worth the wait
when they finally decide to turn up.
Spring in the north of our planet.
The sun, after an absence of six months
breaks the horizon for the first time.
A female polar bear emerges
from her den beneath the snow.
The sun must be a welcome relief
after so long in the darkness.
Her den is on a high slope,
well away from hungry male bears
who would kill her cubs,
but close enough to the sea-ice
where she can find food
for her extraordinary new family.
Three young cubs.
If she can raise them all
to independence,
it'll be a rare achievement.
One of the cubs is underweight
and will be fortunate to
survive these early weeks.
If the family reaches the sea-ice,
where the female can catch seals,
her milk will be enriched
and the smaller cub
will quickly gain size and strength.
The sea-ice, though,
is a dangerous place.
The male polar bear has been out
on the frozen ocean all winter.
Times have been lean and a bear cub
would certainly make a welcome snack.
However, the mainstay
of his diet is seals
and now is the time
when they have their pups.
The surface of the frozen sea is marked
with pressure ridges and cracks
created by the fluctuating tides.
Both are good places to look for seals.
He has detected a seal den
beneath the ice.
Now he must pinpoint it using
only his extraordinary sense of smell.
By treading lightly,
he can avoid scaring his prey.
He will need to punch through
a metre of snow to reach the den
and if his aim is not exactly on target,
the seal will certainly escape.
In fact, the ringed seal abandoned
her den just a few hours ago
and her pup has climbed up
onto the surface.
It's more exposed up here,
but it's easier
to see an approaching bear.
The pup is well camouflaged,
difficult to see when its mother
has left it to go fishing.
But he can still smell it.
Nine out of ten polar bear hunts
end in failure.
The sun's warming effect on the Arctic
is increasing
and the sea ice is showing
the first signs of weakening.
Inland, the northern rivers
are still locked in ice.
The frozen waterfalls are like dams,
holding back billions of tonnes
of fresh water
that has not moved
for almost six months.
The vast water shed lies motionless,
but as spring advances,
it begins to stir.
The frozen waterfalls start to weaken.
Above them, the pressure is mounting.
Now, from high above,
whole sections can be seen
to be on the move.
The waterfalls are straining
to hold back the force
that is building up above them.
The dam bursts
and the river is unleashed.
Millions of tonnes of ice
grind their way downstream,
driven by the unstoppable force
of the meltwater.
Boulders and trees are plucked
from the bankside.
Within just a few days,
the rivers of the north are all running.
The Arctic's fresh water
is flowing again.
These vast floods contain 10%
of the world's fresh water
and as they enter the ocean,
they accelerate the break-up.
Soon, an area of sea-ice
the size of Australia
will vanish from the Arctic Ocean.
As the huge ice-sheet breaks up,
wildlife returns to the north.
The polar bear mother has made
it to the edge of the sea-ice,
but the smallest cub
is nowhere to be seen.
It's a sad outcome,
but the disappearance improves
the chances of the remaining two,
who now have more milk to share.
Having led her cubs
to the edge of the ice,
the mother's next challenge
is to catch a seal.
Not easy with these two in tow.
Her prey, beneath the ice,
can detect the slightest vibration,
especially from bears.
And this is not the stealthiest
of hunting parties.
Leaving her cubs behind, however,
is not an option.
A male bear would eat one in a moment.
This is not going to be easy.
It seems that the cubs already
see themselves as fearsome hunters,
but they are still young enough
to accept their mother's discipline.
It's the naughty corner for you.
This is not going to
be their lucky morning.
They saw no sign of a seal
and the cubs are hungry again.
The mother has been nursing for four
months without once eating herself,
and now her milk is drying up.
She must catch a seal soon
or the whole family will starve.
The challenge of finding food
is getting harder.
She needs the sea-ice as a platform
from which to hunt
and it's breaking up faster
with each passing day.
Even the ice around the coast
is starting to break.
The first cracks here
are eagerly awaited by some.
Narwhals.
The unicorns of the north are
on a mission,
to reach the new fishing grounds
in the bays
that have been frozen up all winter,
but are now opening up.
To get to them,
the narwhals must travel down leads,
temporary cracks in the ice.
But these new roads could close
at any time,
cutting off the air
that they need to breathe.
The road narrows until there's
barely room for one-way traffic.
Then a surprise.
Narwhals coming from
the other direction.
It's a stand-off!
Each team faces an armoury
of sharp tusks.
Finally, one side concedes
and everyone continues
in the same direction.
Within a week,
the remaining bays break wide open
and the narwhals turn their attention
to social matters.
No one knows exactly
what the narwhal's tusk is for.
Some say it's used for fencing,
yet these exchanges
are too gentle to be real fights.
Perhaps these encounters are
to remind each animal
of where it stands in narwhal society.
We may never know.
Bizarre creatures appear
as if from nowhere.
The tiny plankton they eat
have been fuelled
by the increasing warmth of the sun
and fertilised by the nutrients
brought down by the great rivers
and released from the melting sea-ice.
Sea gooseberries strain the water
with their stinging filaments,
their beating cilia
scatter the sun's rays
into dazzling bursts of colour.
Beneath the breaking sea-ice,
a predatory sea slug flies through
the water on translucent wings.
It's on the trail of a peculiar
swimming snail.
And now the most voracious of
the plankton eaters
swim up from the depths. Arctic cod.
The shoals can be enormous,
some containing 500 million fish
and predators travel hundreds of miles
to feast on them.
The cod harvest is the annual event
for the birds and seals
of the far north.
For just a short period,
the combination
of the strengthening sun,
the newly flowing rivers
and the breaking sea ice
make the Arctic Ocean teem with life.
The land is also transformed
by the sun's heat.
The small patches of bare ground
that appear are darker than the snow,
so they absorb more of the sun's energy.
This accelerates the melt.
The Arctic tundra is unveiled.
By tracking the sun, Arctic poppies
catch its rays around the clock,
so their flowers are always warmer
than their surroundings.
For early season insects,
this warmth is even more valuable
than nectar
if they're to stay active in the cold.
The woolly bear caterpillar
does not need the warmth from flowers
to kick-start its spring.
It's always the first insect
to appear after the snow retreats
and the story of how it does so
is truly astonishing.
At the start of spring,
the caterpillar eats as fast as it can,
as indeed it must,
for this far north,
the season will be brief.
The days shorten only too soon,
but the caterpillar
has not yet got enough reserves
to transform itself into a moth.
It can't leave the Arctic,
for it can't fly.
So it settles down beneath a rock.
The sun's warmth rapidly dwindles.
Beneath the rock, the caterpillar
is out of the wind,
but the cold penetrates deep
into the ground.
Soon its heart stops beating.
It ceases to breathe
and its body starts to freeze.
First its gut, then its blood.
Spring.
After four months of darkness,
the Arctic begins to thaw.
And the caterpillar rises from the dead.
By the time the first shoots
of willow appear in the early spring,
the woolly bear is already eating.
But no matter how fast
the woolly bear eats,
it will not have time
to gather enough food this year, either.
And the cold closes in once again.
Year after year, the caterpillar
slows down in the autumn
and then freezes solid.
But eventually, a very special
spring arrives.
This one will be its last.
It's now 14 years old,
the world's oldest caterpillar.
Its remaining days now become frantic.
It starts to weave a silk cocoon.
Inside, its body is changing
into one that can fly and search,
abilities that will be crucial
in the days ahead.
It's waited over a decade for
this spring and now its time is near.
All across the Arctic,
moths are emerging.
After completing
their 14-year preparation,
they now have just a few days
to find a partner and mate.
No life illustrates more vividly
the shortness of the Arctic spring
or the struggle to survive
in this most seasonal of places.
As spring advances, the transformation
of the tundra continues.
Migrants begin arriving from the south
and suddenly the tundra is alive
with birds and chicks.
The Arctic's transformation is complete.
This influx of life is good news
for some permanent residents.
Food is rarely plentiful
out on the tundra.
The Arctic wolves must make the most
of this boom while it lasts.
The wolves must gather
as much food as they can.
Many miles from here, other members
of the pack are relying on them.
This barren landscape is
a hard place to make a living,
forcing wolf packs to be
smaller here than further south.
Six hungry mouths to feed.
The cubs are just over a month old.
The ducks are devoured instantly,
but on the long journey home
they also caught an Arctic hare,
a mainstay of the tundra diet,
and one the cubs seem
to be particularly keen on.
Uneaten food is usually hidden
for leaner times,
but there will be no leftovers today.
The cubs are growing fast
and are always hungry.
The good times are certainly back,
but these white wolves remind us
of the Arctic's less welcoming side.
Their coats are pale, to conceal them
during the long, snowy winter.
It's easy to forget that one month ago,
this land was a barren white desert.
At the southern end of our planet,
the Antarctic sea-ice
is still at its greatest extent.
But there are a few islands
on its outer edge
that the sea-ice never quite reaches.
South Georgia is washed by
the rich waters of the Southern Atlantic
and the comparative warmth of the sea
takes the edge off
the vicious southern winter.
It's even possible
for a few hardy animals,
like the Wandering Albatross,
to live here throughout the whole year.
The enormous albatross chicks
take 13 months to fledge,
so they have no choice but to sit here
throughout the winter.
It can't be easy,
but their thick layer of fluffy down
keeps out the worst of the cold.
Their parents travel thousands of miles
to collect the fish and squid
they need to stay warm and to grow.
The season is turning and
storms blow in with little warning.
King penguins have
also been here all winter.
Their chicks survive by huddling
in crèches to conserve their heat.
A solitary bird here standing alone
would quickly die of exposure.
It seems for a hardy few,
violent storms are a price worth paying
for year-round fishing in
the rich waters of the Southern Ocean.
The penguins have had the beach
to themselves all winter,
but that is a luxury that will not last.
As the winter storms subside,
life begins to return.
For half of the year, South Georgia
has the greatest concentration
of sea birds in the world
and most of them arrive
in the early spring.
Macaroni penguins make
the most impressive entrance,
over five million pairs of them.
They are the world's
most numerous penguin
and half of them are now here.
The arrival is complete.
Courtship is next on South Georgia's
busy spring schedule.
The Wandering Albatross
has the most elaborate display.
These two are renewing their bonds
after being months apart.
Wanderers pair up in their teens and
can spend a further 50 years together,
one of the longest partnerships
in the animal world.
By the middle of spring,
the snows have cleared from the coves
and the low ground.
The beaches are almost free of ice, too,
but that isn't the biggest change
facing the king penguins.
Their peaceful waterfront has turned
into an obstacle course of blubber.
The elephant seals have arrived.
This beach now contains a greater mass
of animals than any other in the world.
The young seals were
conceived here a year ago,
and now that they've been born,
their mothers are ready to mate again.
The mating rights on this patch
of the beach belong to a beach master.
His harem contains 50 females,
females that are coveted by others.
His authority is being challenged.
This rival means business.
This could be the beach master's first
serious test of his spring campaign.
The beach master himself
weighs four tons,
but this rival is his equal.
When these titans clash, bones crunch.
He has won the first battle,
but he may have to defend his harem
every hour for the next month.
If he can stay master
of his beach for this period,
many of the young born here next year
will be his.
It's the end of spring
on the Wandering Albatross cliffs,
their season for fledging.
Last year's chicks
have lost their fluffy down
and step up to the challenge
of getting into the air.
An albatross is not very competent
on the ground,
so until it can fly,
it isn't good for much
and this makes the maiden flight the
crucial event in an albatross's life.
Managing the largest wingspan
in the world takes practice,
lots of it.
Weeks can go by like this.
Certainly the winds must be right.
But it does appear that for some
the problem is
something of a mental one.
At last.
The Southern Ocean beckons.
This bird's feet will not
touch land again for five years.
One thousand miles further south,
on the edge of the Antarctic continent,
the sea-ice is
only just starting to break.
But the Adélie penguins' activities
are certainly warming up.
The males have now finished their nests,
by fair means or foul,
and the females are finally returning,
just as the weather is improving.
Now their courtship can begin.
The eggs are laid
and the females leave the job
of incubating them to the males,
while they go fishing out
on the fragmenting sea-ice.
Killer whales.
It's teamwork that makes
killer whales so dangerous.
And this is a big team.
There is no real need
for the penguins to be alarmed.
These killer whales are a kind
that only eats fish.
Rising out is simply the best way
for the whales to work out
which cracks lead
towards the coast and better fishing.
A new generation of Adélies steps forth
into the short Antarctic spring
to be nurtured by industrious parents,
who've taken great risks
to give their young a head start.
They will need to grow fast
if they are to fledge
and leave before
the freeze sets in again.
It's a battle they will win
or lose over the approaching summer.
To film the entire breeding cycle
of the Adélie penguin,
Frozen Planet sent a team to
one of the world's largest colonies
at Cape Crozier, Antarctica.
I've heard so much about it,
I've read so much about it
and finally we're going to get there,
it's good.
Cameraman Mark Smith
and Director Jeff Wilson plan
to spend the next four months
living amongst the penguins,
in a location first visited by
the early explorers a century ago.
So arduous was Scott's
winter expedition to Cape Crozier
that it became known as
"the worst journey in the world".
Wow! It's fantastic.
Modern means
make Mark and Jeff's journey
a more comfortable affair,
but once there, they will be tested
to the very limits of their endurance.
The pair arrive in early spring
with enough supplies
to survive the next four months working
alone in the Antarctic wilderness.
We're here.
Scott's legend of Cape Crozier
tells of some extreme weather,
to say the least.
So, Mark and Jeff take advantage
of the clear conditions
in the knowledge that
the Adélies' arrival is imminent.
But the next morning,
things take a turn for the worse.
We've just come up to this ridge
to go and check
exactly what it looks like down
in the colony.
But even here you can hear
a huge kind of roaring noise
up on the hill.
I've never really heard anything
like that before.
Up there, it must be blowing
the most almighty gale
and that is, you know,
just a mile away or something.
So, that means that
that could get here very, very quickly.
So, yeah, it makes you slightly scared.
It's weird, isn't it?
The winds here are
famously ferocious,
and with so little experience
of this location,
Mark and Jeff retreat to
the relative shelter of their hut.
I was just stood here thinking,
"Well, it can't be too bad,
"because we haven't seen rocks
starting to blow around yet."
And just at that moment there was like
a rock took off and rolled down there.
You know, it's getting stronger.
By the second day
of the storm,
the winds reach 80 miles an hour
and it's apparent
that even getting lunch
from the outside larder is too risky.
To their increasing alarm,
the storm continues to build.
All afternoon it's been blowing about...
It must have been 100 miles an hour,
and in the last half hour
it's just got a lot stronger.
Aside from
being utterly terrified,
there's the added worry that our gear
is stashed outside somewhere.
We didn't have room for it in the hut
and we just don't know whether it's
going to be there in the morning or not,
which is...
It could spell the end of our trip.
On the third day
of the storm,
the winds hit 130 miles an hour.
The hut starts to shake
from its very foundations,
and Mark and Jeff's situation
becomes critical.
The wind's so strong, it's constantly
blowing the pilot light out
on the paraffin stove,
so the temperature's dropping,
the wind's rising.
Sounds like the bloody roof's
come off.
The really scary thing is
is that had we gone out
down to the colony
and tried to film today,
there's a very high likelihood
that we'd be dead by now,
and I don't say that lightly.
There's no way we would have seen
this through down there,
and that is quite sobering.
After four terrifying days
inside the hut,
the winds finally drop and Mark and Jeff
are keen to see what, if any,
equipment has survived.
All the real important stuff,
the camera stuff,
is all still here
and it's still strapped to this rock.
You have no idea
how much joy that gives us.
We can get on with our jobs now.
The first things to welcome us
into the colony are these skuas,
which come in and batter us from above.
At its height,
the colony will swell
to over half a million penguins.
And in the 24-hour daylight
of the Antarctic summer,
Mark and Jeff spend all
of their waking hours filming.
Unpredictable weather continues
to force the team
to climb the two miles back
to the relative shelter of their hut,
and Mark devises another way
of testing the wind speed.
After six weeks, the first sign
that the pair might be tiring
of their penguin neighbours.
Over there's a leopard seal.
It's the first non-penguin-looking
animal in two months.
Will you look at that?
It's a leopard seal!
I was down here filming
the penguins coming in,
followed this penguin
that came out of the waves
up the beach, very nice shot,
stopped the shot
and there, in the middle of the frame,
was this completely white penguin
trying to get into the shot.
We kind of suspect that
he might be following us around now.
Working around the clock
for this length of time
in the presence
of half a million screaming penguins
would test anyone's resolve.
I hate carrying gear. Hear that?
I hate carrying gear.
I don't want to do it any more.
Midway through their trip,
after more than 1, 000 hours
amongst the penguins,
their grip on reality
is beginning to loosen.
Here we are
on the penguin superhighway,
where the penguins go down to the sea.
It seems
that they follow the American system,
driving on the right,
going down to the sea on the right,
coming back from the sea on the left
as you're facing the sea.
I'm fairly sure that yesterday,
they were doing the British system.
The legendary Cape Crozier weather
soon snaps them back into reality.
Well, I'm just filming the penguins
with this huge windstorm
coming over the ice cap.
This is the kind of thing we were
warned about
by the guy who was here before,
who has been here for several years
and saying, "If you see skies like this,
then you should run for home."
But of course, we're just going
to stay and film it.
Because we're the BBC.
But in this part of the world,
working for the BBC
doesn't count for much.
Within minutes,
the winds reach hurricane strength
and the crew are in serious trouble.
So, we've got to now venture out
and go up the...
about a mile up this valley, where...
which looks like it's got about
80-mile-an-hour winds blowing down it,
so it's going to be quite an adventure.
Bit frightening, though, really.
After three months,
the pair are now fully aware
of the strength the winds can reach.
Getting a little stronger now!
There is a very real danger
that they could be separated
and lost in these white-out conditions.
Hey, watch this, Jeff.
We're going to go...
Two terrifying hours later,
and their relief at
finally reaching the hut is tangible.
With a month still to go
at Cape Crozier,
Mark, Jeff, and the penguins
will face many more storms like this.
But it seems that
their greatest challenge
will be to maintain their sanity.
Here we are, travelling
through the Antarctic by sled.
We're being pulled
by a herd of huskies.
Oh !
Twelve of them panting out front,
breath steaming from their mouths,
and as we go along,
we see the happy people waving at us.