Three features make WayneTech's
new Raven X-111 stealth helicopter
unique among military aircraft.
The first is her
silent-running capability.
Making the Raven ideal for
reconnaissance and covert operations.
Another is her state-of-the-art
cloaking device.
This renders her invisible to all normal
forms of radar and sonar detection.
Last, but certainly not least,
there is her extraordinary
ZVF sensor system.
ZVF, as I'm sure you've heard,
stands for zero visibility flight.
With this new technology, feedback
from the aircraft's radar and sonar
is translated, not into blips
on a tracking grid,
but rather into
computer generated images
on a video display terminal.
But should you think the Raven X-111
has only defensive capabilities,
think again.
Looks like it's going even better
than we'd hoped.
Wouldn't you say, Mr. Wayne?
I guess, Doctor,
though I still have serious misgivings
about building weapon systems.
Look out!
What are they trying to do?
Hey, what's that?
- Looks like the helicopter crew.
- But if you guys are here,
then who's flying the chopper?
Look at them.
Taking off like scared pigeons.
You find pigeons funny, my friend?
No, boss. Not me.
Good. You'll do well to remember that.
Attention. Attention.
This is the Penguin speaking.
I have taken control
of your precious Raven
and intend to be paid handsomely
for its return.
I will contact the mayor's office
with the instructions for delivery
of the ransom.
As of this moment,
the most dangerous bird in the sky
is the Penguin.
Master Bruce!
Home, Alfred. Now.
But, sir, you need medical attention.
No. I don't want the WayneTech
doctors examining me.
Call Leslie.
Have her meet us at the house.
Begging your pardon, sir,
but why so secretive?
Because I don't want anyone to find out
that I can't see.
It's too soon to know for sure, Bruce,
but it looks like it's only temporary.
It might last two, maybe three days
at the most.
Assuming, of course, you actually follow
my instructions for a change.
What happened?
It looks like the explosion flash
burned both retinas.
It'll heal better if you keep your eyes
completely covered
for at least 36 hours.
Otherwise, you could damage
your vision permanently.
So keep him home, Alfred,
even if you have to hog-tie him.
He needs to rest, which means
the Batman is off duty, too.
No way, Leslie.
Not as long as the Penguin
has that chopper.
If there is some question, Master Bruce,
I urge you to resolve it straightaway.
You've a call on your private line.
- Then let's go.
- In your condition, sir?
If you think a little inconvenience
like this is gonna stop me...
Indeed.
He didn't respond?
No, Mr. Mayor.
But I'm sure there's a reason.
Who cares? What's Mr. Trick-or-Treat
gonna do that we can't?
I got 12 details crawling over every
airfield and heliport in four counties.
Quite a machine, this Raven.
Amazing what its communications
equipment can do, don't you agree?
You received my instructions?
They arrived by messenger this morning.
You know, 100 million is a lot of money.
It'll take time to raise that much.
You're stalling, Hill.
Obviously, you're not
taking me seriously.
I warned you not to make that mistake.
Apparently, I'll have to show you why.
You should've seen his face
when I told him.
Yeah.
What the heck is that?
I don't know.
It's not making a sound.
Jam it, get us out of here!
- You sure this is a good idea, boss?
- Do as you're told.
Ow!
As a warning
of what he'll do tomorrow night.
Amazingly, all those on the collapsing
bridge escaped with only minor injuries.
Alfred, I've got to find some way
to stop him.
Sight or no sight.
I still think this is a terrible idea.
I mean, using electrodes
to connect this gizmo directly
to your brain's optic center?
Objection noted.
May I have the headpiece, please?
Those ZVF components I gave you,
you wired them into this thing?
I know how to follow instructions.
Just be careful with that power pack.
You have to keep recharging it.
Will it work, sir?
Only one way to find out.
Well done, sir.
I was aiming for its head.
It isn't perfect.
But it will have to do.
I can only pray that the same
technology that created this crisis
can help me put an end to it.
Just what I was afraid of.
According to the controller's office,
we can't come close
to putting that ransom together.
Not without shutting down
basic municipal services.
So, what other options we got?
None, gentlemen.
Which is why you're going to do exactly
what the Penguin wants you to.
We interrupt our regular
programming for this special report.
This is Mayor Hamilton Hill
with a personal message for the Penguin,
wherever you may be tonight.
You've won.
Just bring the Raven X-111
to the drop site at midnight
and I promise you'll get everything
that's coming to you.
You see?
I told you they'd knuckle under.
- But, boss, it sounds too easy.
- Relax.
With the Raven's instruments,
we'll be able to spot a trap
a mile away, literally.
And if in fact this is a double-cross,
may heaven help them all.
Scanners show the area is secure, boss.
In that case, gentlemen, it's payday.
Huh?
What? What?
Gotcha.
But... But how could he sneak up
on us like that?
That plane of his must have
a cloaking device, too.
This means war!
We're going down!
- Mayday!
The laser cannons. Use the lasers!
Red alert. Red alert. Traumatic impact.
Heat damage to fuselage.
Breach to hull.
Extensive structural damage.
Tell me something I don't know.
Sixty-five seconds
to total system failure.
Look. That Bat's going down.
Warning. Warning.
Electrical system failure.
Switching to auxiliary power.
Happy landing, rodent!
Look. There!
Terrific.
No, my pointy-eared old friend.
You don't escape me that easily.
Look at the way he's moving.
There's something wrong with him.
Why, yes. I think he's injured.
Argh!
I'll handle him.
What's the matter, Bat...
Ahhh!
Your aim appears to be
a little off today, Batman.
I don't think you can hit
the broad side of a barn,
let alone the broad side of this bird.
You're blind as a bat.
Sightless and helpless.
You got one right.
And where do you think you're going?
You've hit a dead end, rodent.
You're only prolonging the inevitable.
Not possible.
You're supposed to be
helpless. Helpless!
I'd feel a lot better about this
if you'd listened to me.
Master Bruce?
Well?
My word, sir. Surely, you're not...
No, Alfred. I can see just fine.
And right now,
I've never seen anything prettier.