- Night, Brian.
- See you tomorrow.
Hey, what's the matter?
Are you lost, honey?
My big brother went away
and left me by my lonesomes.
Big brothers aren't supposed to do that
to their baby sisters.
Here. Dry your eyes,
and I'll help you find a policeman.
- He'll get you home safe and sound.
- You're so nice to me.
But then, you always was
the nicest one, Tippy.
You! But how...
Sorry I had to play roughs, Tippy.
I didn't mean to.
Gotham Insider asks,
"Where are they now?"
When her sitcom, Love That Baby,
premiered 20 years ago,
little Mary Louise Dahl
became an overnight sensation.
As the adorable Baby-Doll, young Mary
quickly captured the hearts of millions.
Whoa...
Well, Baby, you'd better have
a pretty good explanation for this.
I didn't mean to.
I remember this show
from when I was a kid.
It still stinks.
Be that as it may, three of the cast's
original actors disappeared last week.
And these two?
Ms. Vance is in a show
at Gotham Rep.
I have police bodyguards
following her everywhere.
But that other one, Mary Dahl,
dropped out of sight years ago.
Ironically, the same thing that brought
her fame turned her into a recluse.
I read about her once
in a medical journal.
She was born with systemic hypoplasia,
a rare condition that
kept her from aging.
Would you believe
she was 20 years old in that clip?
She'd be about 30 now.
It's obvious someone has a vendetta
against these actors.
We'll study this
and call you back if we...
All units, all units!
Gunfire reported at Gotham Rep.
They're making a try for Vance.
Stay down!
Let me go.
- Why are you doing this?
- Quiet!
The lady asked you
a question, creep.
How about an answer?
Hey!
- Ah!
- Robin!
No. Help!
- They're getting away.
- We'll get them.
No!
Mommy!
I lost my mommy!
It's okay.
Oh, my baby.
Mommy!
Naughty, naughty baby.
Haven't I told you not to run off?
I didn't mean to.
Hold it.
Naughty Mr. Batmans.
You play too rough.
I got 'em!
It's me, dope.
Where am I?
Huh?
It can't be.
Tod, June, Brian?
Tammy. She got you, too.
Is this some sort of bad joke?
What are we doing on the old set?
And in these clothes?
Welcome home, sister Suzy.
I've missed you so.
Mr. Happy-Head says he missed you, too.
Mary? Mary Dahl?
Is this a joke?
No, sillies. I'm Baby, remember?
It's Suzy and Tippy,
and Mumsy, and Daddy, and Baby,
together again forevers and evers.
I don't care what Mayor Hill says.
The people have a right to know,
and if he won't talk to us...
I'll call you back, Marv.
Since when are you
interested in has-been actors?
Since that one's been kidnapping
her costars.
You're serious?
She's been picking them off, one by one.
- Any reason she'd have a grudge?
- Actually, they should hate her.
Dahl put them out of work when she quit
the series to become a dramatic actress.
What, will these hands never be clean?
Here's the smell of the blood still.
All the perfumes of Arabia
will not sweeten this little hand.
Ew!
That's what the critics said.
Baby's dramatic career flopped, and when
she tried to start her TV show again
the networks turned her down.
That still doesn't explain
why she's after her old cast.
Maybe there's a clue
in these old episodes.
You can borrow them if you want.
And when you crack the case,
you can pay me back with an exclusive...
Interview.
Isn't this the best-est?
Having breakfast, just like old times.
- Oh. Oh, it's swell, Baby.
- Great.
Uh-oh!
Here comes Buster, begging for scraps.
Bad boy, Buster.
Go away.
Hey, guess what's today. Anybody know?
Oh, Come on. Guess.
It's my births-day!
Yay, yay for me!
You mean you had us brought here
just so you could throw yourself
a surprise party?
That's it. I always knew
you were a selfish little brat.
Always throwing your temper tantrums
and making life miserable
for the rest of us.
Well, this time you've gone too far.
Expect a call from my lawyer.
Hi-ya!
- Tod!
- Isn't Mariams a treasure?
I couldn't gets through the day
without hers.
Naughty, naughty, Daddys.
Mustn't yell at your Baby like thats.
You're not my daughter.
And we're not a family.
We're actors, remember?
You canceled our show because you whined
you weren't getting enough attention.
But I knows now I made a boo-boo.
It was hard for me
out there.
I studied and trained and auditioned,
but no one wanted me.
Aww...
Over the years, I remembered how happy
I was with all of you around me,
and the folks at home
watching me each week. Me.
Baby-Doll.
Now I'm Baby for good,
and everyone will love me agains.
Hugs, hugs!
Aww.
Remember that time Poison Ivy
nearly smothered us in those vines
with the really sharp thorns?
- Yes.
- This is worse.
I did learn one thing, though.
Baby hasn't gotten every member
of her cast.
In the last season,
the show's ratings began to drop,
so the producers introduced
a new character.
Baby's little cousin Spunky.
Oh.
According to these, Dahl was furious
she was upstaged on her birthday episode
and walked off the series.
So why hasn't she gone
after cousin Spunky?
Maybe she's waiting
for the right occasion.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
My baby was taking a nap,
and your music woke her up.
Hey, I have to practice, you know?
You're still a stinky jerk-face, Spunky.
Wake up, sleepyheads.
Huh?
It's time for my birthday party.
Yay!
We're gonna have so much funs.
- Ready when you are, Ms. Dahl.
- Goodies!
You all remembers what happened
the last time I had a births-day.
Poopy old Spunkys pushed my head
in the cake.
Everybody laughed and laughed.
Well, I'm laughing now.
What are you mad at me for?
It wasn't anything personal.
We were just playing characters
in a TV show.
It was real to me.
Everybody loved Baby-Doll
until you came along.
You made them forget me.
Now Baby's gonna get evens.
- No, don't. Stop her.
- Help! Wait!
It's never too late
to have a happy childhood.
Blow out the candle, Spunky.
Bet your wish doesn't come trues.
Cheater! Cheater! Cheater! Cheater!
Mr. Happy-Head says
you're really gonna get it nows.
Thanks, partner.
Anytime.
No fairs. No fairs.
He wasn't Spunky at alls.
I told Spunky what you were up to.
We switched places.
Batman rigged me with a transmitter
that led him here.
Ah, aren't you Mr. Smarty-Heads.
Mariam!
Wow, lady, you're good.
It's a living.
Hi-ya!
Get the hostages out.
I'll go after Dahl.
Right. Hang on, folks. I'll have you
back to reality in a second.
Yay!
Watch it, kid.
Hmm.
- It's Batman.
- Cool. Hey, Batman, down here.
Hey, do you see what I see?
- Look at those people. It's Batman!
- It's Batman.
- Look.
- Wow, it's Batman.
Silly Mr. Batmans, can't catch me.
Don't run away.
I know you're scared, confused.
- I can help you.
- Liar, liar, cape on fire.
Nows we're playing by my rules.
Game's overs, Mr. Batman.
I wins.
No fair!
Look.
That's me in there.
The real me.
There I am.
But it's not really real, is it?
Just made up and pretend like my family
and my life and everything else.
Why couldn't you just let me
make-believe?
I didn't mean to.