Not a bad night's take.
- What happened to the lights?
- What the heck?
Here.
Put them on. Hurry.
Now.
It went down smooth, Scarf ace,
just like you said.
That's just the beginning, boys.
Soon we're gonna own this town.
Have pity on
an old man's blood pressure.
What is it, Jim?
We're taking a pounding
over this new gang.
Their boss puts heists together
smooth as a Swiss watchmaker.
- What have you got for me?
- Not much.
We don't know who the boss is
or any of the gang members.
But a home video enthusiast
taped the gang
leaving the scene of their latest crime.
- Interested?
- Always.
Let me know if you need any... Help?
Not much of a plot, is it, sir?
They're clever. Masks, gloves.
No way they can be identified.
A tattoo.
Who you looking for, bat-breath?
First guess is you.
Don't get wise with me.
I might not like you.
You're breaking my heart, Rhino.
I ain't scared of you,
but you ain't gonna
trick me into taking a swing at you.
You got nothing on me.
You seem to have me confused
with the police, Rhino.
I want information,
and I'll get it any way I please.
Who's your boss?
You want information, watch the news.
You've got a hard head.
How about using it for something
other than a blunt object?
Well, if it isn't Charles "Rhino" Daly.
- Why don't you run along home?
- Your ma's probably waiting up.
Guy like that,
I'm not so sure a bullet would stop him.
Hey, I'm not so sure
a tank would stop him.
I gotta see the boss.
He's sleeping.
He said he's not to be disturbed.
Hey, man, it's important.
Batman's on our case.
I see. I'll see what I can do.
Sir, I'm terribly sorry.
Hey, I'm sleeping here.
I lay down, I close my eyes,
what's that tell you?
Yes, sir,
but Rhino says it's important.
Oh, Rhino says
it's important, huh?
Well, it better be or there's
gonna be fireworks, get me?
Okay, take me out there.
This better be good, yous mugs.
Okay, talk, Rhino. What's so important
I can't get a good night's sleep?
Eh, Batman's got me figured, Scarf ace.
I don't know how, but he came down
on me like a cast-iron safe.
Batman? We're talking real trouble.
What are we gonna...
Hey, hey! Who you talking to, creep?
He's just the hired help.
I'm the boss here. You talk to me.
Sorry, boss. He's new.
He don't know the score.
Yeah, well, he better
get with the program pretty quick.
I don't stand for no lack of respect.
This Batman business
can only mean one thing.
We got us a squealer.
No, boss, that can't be.
None of us wanna screw up
a sweet deal like this.
Glad to hear it, Mugsy,
'cause if there is and I find him,
it's drapes for that rat!
Now, Mr. Scarf ace,
remember your blood pressure.
Shut up! I want your opinion,
dummy, I'll pull your string.
He's just tired. Irritable.
He's really a genius, Scarf ace is.
You mean the Ventriloquist is a genius.
Nah. Like Scarf ace said,
he's just hired help.
Scarf ace, he's the real brains.
Mr. Scarf ace?
My advice to you? Don't make a sound.
I'm looking for evidence.
Evidence of your previous robberies.
- Robberies?
- Don't be coy.
Cooperate and it could go
easier for you.
He... He doesn't tell me anything.
Not his plans,
not where he hides the loot.
I swear I'm just a flunky.
I know nothing.
You can think I'm dumb,
just don't talk to me like I'm dumb.
I don't know anything, I tell you.
Let me go before he...
Hey, who's making
all the racket? That you, dummy?
Oh, no. Don't let him find me with you.
You don't know how dangerous he is.
He sees me talking to you, I'm a goner.
Please.
Dummy, get in here.
Sorry, Mr. Scarf ace,
I couldn't sleep.
I need my beauty rest here,
dummy. That's twice you waked me up.
Do it again, you're gonna be wearing
a pine overcoat, get me?
You're sweating.
What's going on?
And don't feed me no apples.
Nothing, sir.
I was just having a bad dream.
What did you leave that window open for?
This ain't no meat locker. I'm cold.
Yes, sir, I'll shut it right now.
It's called multiple personality
syndrome disorder, Alfred.
Two personalities in one brain,
completely separate.
Neither one knows what the other
is thinking. Listen.
Batman's so hot,
let's see him swim Gotham Bay
in concrete boots.
A good idea,
Mr. Scarf ace.
Bet your bow tie I'm right,
dummy. Say, who dresses you anyway?
You're such a kidder, Mr. Scarf ace.
I'd swear it was two separate people.
You're not alone.
Even the computer is fooled.
When I studied with Zatara the magician,
he taught me about ventriloquism
and voice-throwing.
How to make your voice seem
to come from across the room.
This Ventriloquist could give
Zatara lessons.
You've had your share of odd opponents,
sir, but this one does take the biscuit.
Any idea where he, or they,
will strike next?
No. Scarf ace keeps his plans secret
until the last minute.
I'll just have to listen in
for as long as it takes.
All right, yous mugs, listen good.
There's a shipment of platinum gonna be
loaded onto the luxury liner Majestic.
- We're gonna...
- But, platinum?
But, boss, don't they send
stuff like that by freighter?
I'm talking here!
Okay, okay. Sorry, boss.
It's a trick, see? They think no one
will suspect the shipment's on a liner.
But they're like yous mugs. Stupid.
Not smart like me.
We'll slip in,
get the goods and skedaddle
before the ship leaves the harbor.
One more thing.
I smell a double-cross.
Woke up last night
with one of them whatchamacallits.
Prima... Primanotion.
- "Premonition"?
- Don't put words in my mouth!
All I'm saying here is
I got this feeling
somebody here is out to get me.
And I'm gonna get them first.
I don't know who it is yet, but I will.
And when I do...
Now, here's the details. Listen up.
I ain't gonna repeat myself.
Yippee ki-yay.
Uh-oh.
See? The Bat's not so tough.
Comes up against Scarf ace,
he's just another dummy.
It was a trap, Bats, start to finish.
And you fell for it like
a world-class sucker.
The dummy here spilled the beans
you'd been in his room.
I had the room searched
and lookie what I found.
You're not as smart
as you think you are, Scarf ace.
I'd watch my mouth if I were you, Bats.
One bullet through that rope
and you're history.
Get my point?
How do you think I found this place?
The phone book?
I had help. Inside help.
My primanotion. I knew I was right.
Which one of you louses is it?
It ain't me, boss.
I know it ain't you, Rhino.
You're too stupid to be a traitor.
Ooh, thanks, boss.
But whoever it is, they're gonna pay!
Big time! Who is it?
You don't talk,
you get the ultimate massage.
- And If I tell?
- Maybe you just get run over by a truck.
Tempting, but no.
Have it your way. Rhino.
- Hold it!
- This is getting old, Bats.
Last chance. Who's the traitor?
Him, the Ventriloquist.
No! No! He's lying.
I told you when he came into my room.
So what?
Maybe you did 'cause I had you cornered.
Heard you talking to Batman.
Shut up, you blockhead.
What did you say?
It wasn't me. I didn't say that.
My lips didn't move.
So what? You're a ventriloquist.
You're also a lying, yellow,
liver-bellied, two-faced...
No, Scarf ace, not me. I'm loyal.
I'd never...
He's been feeding me information
in return for legal protection.
You're going
up the river, sawdust-for-brains.
Why, I ought to...
Waste the four-flusher.
Go on. I gave an order. Ice him. Do it!
Do it now!
But, boss, we ventilate
the Ventriloquist, you're, you know...
I'm surrounded by traitors.
Okay, fine.
You want something done right,
do it yourself.
Spare me, Scarf ace. Please.
I've always been loyal to you.
Go ahead, plead, beg.
It ain't gonna do you no good.
You're lunch meat, you lousy, no... Ah!
I'm hit, boys. Get him!
Take him, Rhino!
No problem.
Ah!
The medication has helped him immensely.
His other personality
seems to have totally submerged.
- That's very good work.
- Thank you.