Poor baby. I used to
be just like you.
A child of the night, wild and free.
I was the cat who walked by herself,
and the city was my hunting ground.
I'd prowl through Gotham each evening,
going where I liked
and taking whatever I wanted.
Until I met him.
I gave him my best fight,
but in the end,
kitty got her claws clipped.
Had to promise I'd be a good little pet
and walk on a leash.
Even if it killed me.
Oh, you just say that
to all the beautiful girls.
Selina? Excuse me.
Selina?
"Extinction." I can relate to that.
You're in a cheery mood.
Giving up Catwoman
hasn't been easy, Bruce.
I miss the excitement, the danger.
Sometimes I feel so tempted.
Even though you'd be risking prison?
Tell me I'm not in a cage now.
Bruce Wayne.
I wondered where
you'd been hiding yourself.
And whom, may I ask,
is your attractive date?
- Veronica Vreeland, meet Selina Kyle.
- We've met.
- At the wildlife fundraiser last year?
- Oh, of course.
- Love what you've done to your hair.
- Thanks.
Since you're so devoted
to wildlife, Selina,
I can't wait to hear what you think
of the museum's new conservation hall.
I had it built in honor
of my grandfather, Stanton Vreeland.
He was the first to realize the
importance of preserving rare animals.
Not surprising, considering
how many of them he obliterated.
Excuse me?
Stanton Vreeland was a playboy sportsman
who'd blow away anything
that wandered into his gunsight.
He had to preserve animals
or he'd have nothing left to shoot.
Is that right?
Uh-huh!
In fact, most of these critters are gone
thanks to trigger-happy jerks
- like old Grandpa.
- Selina.
But, Bruce,
Miss Vreeland asked me what I thought.
I think you've said enough.
Yes, perhaps I have.
Just once I'd like to throw a party
without some kook showing up.
Uh. Excuse me.
Well, that was pretty rude.
Just the cat in me, I guess.
Look, Bruce, it was sweet of you
to invite me, but I don't fit in here.
Sometimes I feel like
I don't fit in anywhere.
Taxi.
- Your ride, Miss Kyle.
- Hey. What the...
- Let me out, you big ape.
- She's a live one.
In two seconds, that'll be more
than I can say about you.
Calm down, pussycat.
We're all friends here.
Dummy, don't keep
our pretty guest in the dark.
Yes, sir, Mr. Scarf ace.
Ah! That's better.
You gotta be kidding.
What's she laughing at?
My fly ain't open, is it?
- No, sir.
- So, what's the gag?
Come on. You know. "What's the gag?"
Can it, sister.
This is Scarf ace you're dealing with
and I don't stand for no disrespect.
I'd do as he says, ma'am.
Mr. Scarf ace can be quite insistent.
I don't think anyone's talking to you.
- No, sir. No, sir.
- Right.
So, what do you want with me?
My boys happened to be in the museum
when they saw your little set-to
with Miss Ronnie V.
They also seen you licking your whiskers
at the sight of Ronnie's
pretty sparklers.
You're boring me, log.
So, what if I could provide you with a
foolproof plan for snatching those rocks
with no risk of you getting caught?
Pass. Kitty's been staying in at night.
It's not the greatest, but it beats
the pound, if you know what I mean.
Now that's a darn shame.
And I thought for sure you'd want
a chance to get even with the Vreelands.
Not just for yourself, you understand,
but for all those
poor little stuffed critters
what never had the chance to fight back.
Oh! Barf.
It's a 50-50 cut.
Take it or leave it. You in, or what?
You know what, Isis?
Extinction's for wimps.
Mastodon, check.
Cave bear, check.
Saber-tooth.
Huh?
Well, where did you come from?
Aw, poor girl.
Must've wandered in and got lost.
I'll let you out back.
Excuse me, Mr. Scarf ace,
but isn't it cruel to take advantage
of that nice Miss Kyle?
Hold my hat, will you?
- Bam!
- Ow!
That's what you get
for going soft on me.
Yes, sir.
There. The guard's putting
the cat out like I planned.
Catwoman should have
all the time she needs
to lift the jewels and split.
This one's for the Vreelands.
But plans can change, can't they, Rhino?
Right, boss.
Huh?
Great. Someone else
is hitting the place.
Okay, boys, to work.
Sorry, kitty. You're taking the fall.
Hold it.
Could you please give me a hand?
This dinosaur seems to
have fallen on me.
- How did you...
- It's a dull story, handsome.
The Catwoman.
Watch out!
- Where is she?
- Couldn't have missed her.
Looks like the hunt's on again, Isis.
I think a quick trip
out of town is in order.
Don't buy your ticket yet.
What a pleasant surprise.
Though I should warn you, breaking
and entering is against the law.
You would know. Care to explain what
you were doing at the museum tonight?
Look, I was there earlier for a party,
and I kind of lost my temper.
I went back to apologize,
and the place was empty,
except for the burglars.
I happened to have my outfit in the car,
and I thought if I nailed the robbers
I could work up some
points with the cops.
Maybe even with you.
I know how bad this looks for me,
but it wasn't my fault.
Would you come back to the museum
and tell your story to the authorities?
I suppose, if you're with me.
- After all, we do make a good team.
- When we're on the same side.
The police are still
talking to the guard.
That gives us a few minutes
to look around.
I was looking at this exhibit earlier.
It's brand-new. Why would
they remove the animals so soon?
This lock's been sprung.
Our thief is clever,
using dummy cards to cover his tracks.
An extinct-animal trophy is worth
a fortune to the crook who can fence it.
"All those poor little
stuffed critters."
That's what he was after all along.
You're not telling me something.
You know what's wrong
with our relationship?
You always let me get too close.
Excuse me.
I have a date with a scratching post.
We don't have to make this difficult.
But somehow we always do.
Selina?
In here!
That's right, Penguin.
I got your bird just like I promised.
Of course, it'll cost you extra.
Hey, you don't want it, fine.
I can always use it for pillow stuffing.
Ah...
See there? I knew you'd be reasonable.
While I got you on the horn,
can I interest you in a Tasmanian tiger?
A steal at only two mil.
No, huh? That's okay.
I got a client dying
to get her paws on it.
I thought I saw a pussycat.
Let go!
You know, I never had much use
for animals, except Rhino here.
Thanks, boss.
Then it hit me, some rich geeks
will pay big bucks
for critters they can't go out
and shoot no more.
You know what these things
are worth dead?
More than my life, I bet.
You win, kitten.
I needed a dummy to keep the cops busy
while I grabbed the stiffs.
So you conned me
into that phony jewel robbery.
Too bad for you you figured it out.
Now we're gonna find out if there really
is more than one way to skin a cat.
- Rhino.
- No!
Ow!
Lousy fleabag.
Oh, Great. Him, I don't need.
I don't know whether to bite you
or kiss you.
Later.
Get me out of here.
Hurry!
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
- Put me down.
- Sure.
Uh-oh.
Mr. Scarf ace!
Let's let the chips fall where they may.
Get me off of here. Dummy, help me.
Help, help! Someone do something!
Please, let me save him.
Hmm, nah!
Dummy, please!
Phew!
Huh?
That's one way to remove a splinter.
What's wrong, Ventriloquist?
Cat got your tongue?
Please, I never hurt you.
Scarf ace, he's another person.
Not me, really.
But he's inside you somewhere.
And I'm going to keep scratching
until I find him.
Don't make it harder on yourself.
- He cost me my freedom.
- No.
You gave it up.
From the very start I suspected
there was more to this business
than you were telling.
So I put a transmitter on your cat
back at your apartment.
It led me here in time to hear
your confession.
- Why did you do it, Selina?
- I have to be who I am.
I realize now I can't change that.
Like I told someone else tonight...
It's just the cat in me.
It's priceless, Batman.
The last of its kind.
Will you take me in
or let it become extinct again?
The lady or the tiger, darling.
Your choice.
I am the cat who
walks by herself.