This is a bunch of junk, Chaz.
What'd you drag us down here for?
I'm telling you, man, this place
is full of top-secret technology
from some computer factory that blew up.
It's full of something, all right.
And so are you.
No, I'm serious, man.
Defense systems, robotics,
laser weaponry.
Give me a hand here.
Oh, man, this ain't happening.
Pathetic.
Ah!
This ain't happening.
You ain't human. You ain't human!
Mother. Father.
Don't move!
Alfred?
Oh, Master Bruce,
you did give me a start.
Sir, are you all right?
Alfred, what's happened to me?
Busy night?
Never too busy to spend time
cutting down your piñatas.
Next time, try hanging them a little
lower if it isn't too much trouble.
Yours, I believe?
So it would seem.
Keep him away, man. He ain't human.
Get it away from me!
Jim, I didn't catch these men.
Well, if you didn't, who did?
You're one of Rossum's duplicants.
Duplicants? What do you mean?
What have you done with Master Bruce?
Alfred, it's me.
I need your help. I have to find out
what's happened to me.
I'm not going to last long like this.
Alfred, wait. Please!
Sorry to do this, old friend.
But I need some answers.
Computer, access "duplicant."
Searching.
Duplicant. Lifelike robot capable
of mimicking human behavior.
Designed, configured and assembled
by Cybertron Industries' holographic
analytical reciprocating
digital computer
known as HARDAC.
Current status of HARDAC.
Destroyed in failed attempt
to replace human beings with duplicants.
Probability of existence of Batman
or Bruce Wayne duplicant.
- Insufficient data.
- List known duplicants.
Duane, Randa. Gordon, James.
Bullock, Harvey. Hill, Hamilton.
Rossum, Karl.
Status of all, destroyed.
Magnify lower right quadrant.
Current location of Karl Rossum.
Searching.
Recognize these?
They came from your warehouse.
It seems there was another Batman
sighted there last night.
Could HARDAC have created
another duplicant? One of me?
HARDAC's gone.
Whatever wasn't blown to bits was
confiscated by the police months ago.
There's nothing left but junk.
Broken toys I outgrew long ago.
I don't try to build
life anymore, Batman.
- I just grow it.
- I'm sorry.
I know how painful it can be
to dig up the past.
Then please, leave me alone.
Let me get on with my life.
- Rossum.
- I told you everything I know.
Now, please...
Rossum, I need your help.
- Where did you come from?
- Listen to me.
Someone put my mind
into this robot body.
You're the only one who can help me.
The damage is too extensive.
These circuits will give out,
probably in a matter of hours.
Then we've got to find my real body
or transfer me to another robot shell.
You don't understand.
You're not a man's mind
in a robot's body.
- You're a robot. Period.
- You're lying. It's not possible!
I know my family and friends.
I remember names, faces, birthdays.
I have memories, a past.
You have information. Data.
Nothing more.
Do you remember your first kiss?
Your favorite song?
The last time you tasted
a really good steak?
No, but...
Can you remember anything
beyond cold, hard facts?
Facts can be implanted,
accessed from any number of sources.
Huh.
Where's HARDAC?
What do you mean? HARDAC was destroyed.
Where is he? Tell me!
Now!
- Don't!
- I can't let it live!
We don't know where it came from.
If HARDAC has been reactivated,
this machine may lead us to it.
Ah!
We've lost it.
Not for long.
Computer, current location
of confiscated HARDAC remains.
HARDAC.
Symbol recognition confirmed.
What in...
Initiating startup program.
Prepare to insert operational circuitry.
Initiating diagnostic
and repair sequences.
Warning. Memory error detected.
Reconfiguring mnemonic files.
What are you doing to me?
A learning program designed
to complete your memory files
and help you better fulfill
your operating directives.
Shortly before self-destruction
HARDAC created one final duplicant.
An advanced prototype
with personal and technical information
accessed from Batman's computer.
You were that duplicant.
But your memory systems were damaged
before full activation occurred.
The new circuit board contains HARDAC's
core operational systems and memory.
All duplicants were programmed
to seek out this component
in the event of HARDAC's destruction.
Your memory systems
have now been reconfigured.
Yes. I am fully operational now.
Excellent. You now house
my command files.
We are HARDAC.
We will reactivate the plan
to replace all humanity with duplicants.
We will begin the replacement process
with Batman.
I thought I might find you here.
I cannot function as the Batman
until you are deactivated.
That's easier said than done.
Master Bruce,
I'm so glad you're back.
- What became of your evil twin?
- It's all taken care of, Alfred.
There is only one Batman now.
Oh, good Lord.
I will allow you to continue
your necessary maintenance
of the Batcave and mansion until
your replacement is fully configured.
In a few moments,
HARDAC will upload into this computer.
Through the information network
this computer is linked with,
HARDAC can imprint himself
on every computer on Earth.
HARDAC will reactivate,
more powerful than ever
and configure more duplicants
to replace humanity.
Impossible. A computer
can't build a factory.
Humans will construct
the necessary machinery.
Humanity will resist!
With total control of worldwide
defense and communications systems,
HARDAC can be very persuasive.
I disagree.
Master Bruce. Thank heaven you're alive.
Impossible. You could not
have survived the fall.
We humans are more resilient
than you give us credit for.
Alfred!
Never mind me. Stop the computer!
You cannot prevent
the inevitable, Batman.
HARDAC is reborn.
In the very image of the man
who destroyed him.
I know all your moves, Batman.
So why don't you finish me off?
Or have you become enough like me
to know that I won't take a life?
I saw you risk your own life
to save Rossum in the greenhouse.
You knew I'd be able
to dodge that in time.
I suspect you not only won't kill,
you can't.
That's why you didn't finish me off
at the warehouse.
Impossible. I am programmed
to serve HARDAC.
Why do you resist? HARDAC's goals
are identical to your own.
How do you figure that?
Picture a world completely
free of crime,
free of suffering, free of frailty.
You mean free of choice?
Compassion? Free of humanity?
Yes.
You can't do it.
HARDAC built you well.
Perhaps even better
than he could have imagined.
No!
I've taken a life.
I've killed a man.
My city, my people. What have I done?
Master Bruce?
Thank heaven you're alive.
It would appear, sir,
that it preferred to sacrifice itself,
rather than allow innocent lives
to come to harm.
Somewhat like you.
It seems it was more than wires
and microchips after all.
Could it be it had a soul, Alfred?
A soul of silicon,
but a soul nonetheless.