Don't take me
back there! Please!
Look at me, Batman.
I'm shaking with fear.
Me, the Scarecrow.
I wasn't even
going back to crime this time.
I just had to get away from him.
I'll take it from here, Batman.
Lyle Bolton, Chief of Security.
Congratulations, Professor Crane.
You're the first inmate
to escape Arkham under my charge.
You're also the last.
I won't let you and the people
of Gotham City down again, Batman.
That Bolton's a 10 on the creep-o-meter.
But it seems like he's doing a good job
keeping the inmates in check.
Maybe too good.
I've called this informal inquest
to address certain allegations
brought to my attention.
Are you sure this hearing
was necessary, Wayne?
Bolton was brought to Arkham
on a Wayne Foundation grant.
With his knowledge
of high-tech security systems,
I felt he was the perfect man
for the job.
If anyone objects to my methods...
Please, tell me.
Ms. Quinn.
Do you have any complaints
against Mr. Bolton?
I got nothing to say.
But surely you must have
something you wish to...
You got a hearing problem or something?
No, nada, ixnay, zero, zilch,
bupkes, nothing! Okay?
It's all right.
I promise, you can speak freely here.
- Mr. Bolton, he's a...
- A hard worker!
A real stand-up guy.
No complaints here, Chief.
Professor Crane, you've been
sitting here for 10 minutes.
- Don't you have anything to say?
- No, sir.
And yet yours
was the loudest voice of protest.
You must have some misgivings
about my methods.
It seems I was mistaken.
Well then, based on today's testimony,
I propose extending
Mr. Bolton's contract
for an additional 18 months.
No! You can't! You don't know
what he's doing to us!
Shut up!
Don't listen to jerk-face here.
He don't know what he's saying!
No, it's all true!
If we don't speak up now,
we'll never get another chance!
He threatens us,
takes away our privileges,
even when we're good!
We've heard enough of this nonsense.
He says,
"Scum like us must be kept in line."
That's why he chains us down at night
and electrifies our doors.
He held me over a can
filled with termites.
You hear me? Termites!
He's an animal.
- A monster.
- Keep him away!
Shut up!
All of you!
You're all scum.
You should be beaten within an inch
of your misbegotten lives.
I've seen enough!
Lyle Bolton, you're dismissed!
Before I came here,
Arkham was a revolving door
for every maniac in Gotham.
I kept them in. Me!
Now I realize I was wrong
to punish those pathetic miscreants!
They're only symptoms.
You're the cause!
The gutless police,
mindless bureaucrats,
and coddling doctors!
You should all be locked up
in a cage without a key!
Mr. Bolton,
any comments about your dismissal
and the charges of extreme behavior?
This city is an open wound
begging to be stitched.
Since that day three weeks ago,
Lyle Bolton has been unavailable
for further comment.
Next up on Gotham Insider,
she's gorgeous, she's deadly
and she's back in town.
- Once again, Poison Ivy has recently...
- Look at the way these monsters
are turned into heroes.
It all starts with the permissive,
liberal media.
The villainous vixen of vines
made off with...
Thanks for the exclusive, Mr. Wayne.
Do they always include
such a sumptuous meal?
Only when the topic
is a successful Wayne Corp merger.
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne.
You have an urgent phone call.
If you'll excuse me.
What the...
Great.
Summer?
The time has come
to cleanse Gotham of the real criminals.
You apprehend them, Dark Knight,
and Lock-Up will put them away.
Together we can make
this city safe again.
By kidnapping innocent victims?
I don't think so.
If you're not part of the solution,
then you're part of the problem.
You disappoint me, Batman.
I thought you'd wanna see
this media leech get her comeuppance.
Just what this town needs,
another psycho in a Halloween costume.
This is Lyle Bolton's handiwork.
No one configures a lock like him.
You mean this Lock-Up nut
is the security creep from Arkham?
Without a doubt.
Another fine villain made possible
by a grant from the Wayne Foundation.
Only kidding.
Bolton's last known address.
See what you can find.
Nice look. Early Alcatraz.
Dr. Bartholomew?
Commissioner?
I lit the signal, Bats.
That nutcase took the commish
and gave me these new cuff links.
Took me 15 minutes to hit the switch
on your overgrown flashlight.
You got any idea
what this is all about, cowl-head?
I think so.
First Summer Gleeson,
then Bartholomew, and now Gordon.
Put extra security around Mayor Hill.
You mind letting me in on the joke?
Typical.
You want me to hide during a crisis?
How will that look to the voters?
This is overkill, Detective.
I have the finest security system
in the city.
It's virtually impenetrable.
Virtually.
But not completely.
If we can slip through, so can Lock-Up.
Mayor!
Forget to pay a parking ticket?
Move it.
Ahh!
I see your taste in prisoners
is improving, Bolton.
You have three seconds
to release those bars.
If you let us go now, Bolton,
I can guarantee leniency.
No.
I don't do leniency.
Still nothing.
Just as I suspected from the rust.
A high salt content like seawater.
Hey. What if F-84
is the serial number of a ship?
Bingo.
The Halsey was used
as a temporary prison
while Stonegate was being built.
Computer.
Name of security chief
during Operation Stonegate.
Well, blow me down.
I've homed in on his power source.
Shut down the security systems.
I'll take care of Bolton.
You brought this on yourself, Batman.
You're resourceful, Dark Knight.
But sooner or later, you're mine.
No regard for authority.
We'll soon change that.
You think that was my only defense?
It's over, Bolton.
Face it, Bolton.
You've already lost.
No!
Amazing what a little
corrupted computer code will do.
I still have my prisoners.
- Commissioner? Mr. Mayor?
- Down here.
Hang on, I'll get you out.
I was working with you, Batman.
You apprehended the scum of the earth,
and I kept them locked away!
I've seen how you treat your prisoners.
Forgotten and scared.
Without hope or compassion.
Can it be you actually care
for those creatures?
You're just as crazy as they are.
Almost got it.
Robin, hurry!
I could have rid Gotham of the fools
in city hall and the police department.
We could have made our own order!
I was born to fight your brand of order.
If that's your decision.
Stay close. I think this is the way out.
We could have been a team.
Batman!
Batman?
I keep asking him
to teach me that trick.
Hey, look, guys.
The big shot's back.
Now you shall learn new lessons in fear.
They thought they could trap me
in a world of lunatics,
but I showed them.
Now, I can keep an eye on everyone.
They'll never slip past me again.