What's keeping him?
Commissioner Gordon?
- Forget it, Stavros.
- Your meeting's been canceled.
He's on his way, boss.
No! No!
Please, please. It's not what you think.
I wasn't gonna say anything. Honest.
Silence!
First you transgress against me.
Then you force me to descend
to the mortal plane.
And now you say I know not what I think?
No!
To the depths of Tartarus with you.
He's a lucky guy. If those tires
hadn't absorbed the shock, he...
Just a minute.
The weather was perfectly clear tonight,
and you're telling me that man
was struck by lightning?
I guess you'll have to ask him
what happened whenever he wakes up.
His name is Yanni Stavros.
He works
for Maximillian Shipping Lines.
As a scheduler.
- You know him?
- He's been under Interpol investigation
for selling vital shipping schedules
to hijackers.
That fits. Stavros had offered
to give me some information
so he could cut a deal with the feds.
What kind of information?
Ever hear of something called an EDC?
The Electron Discharge Cannon.
A fourth-generation energy weapon
being developed
by a combined US-European alliance.
Then you probably know
this prototype was stolen last month
while it was being shipped overseas.
This film contains
classified information
on defense project 406562,
the Electron Discharge Cannon.
For authorized personnel only.
And you think Stavros was either
involved in the theft or knows who was.
I pray that he does,
because if that infernal device
falls into the wrong hands...
Maybe it already has.
The grand jury is building another case,
and I can't stop them this time.
There are allegations of bribery,
extortion and racketeering,
all pointing back to you, Max.
Sure, I'm your assistant, but there's
only so much I can do on my own.
Max? Maxie? Come on,
look at me when I'm talking to you.
You bore me with these tales
of petty human concerns.
You're doing it again, Maxie.
You are Clio, my muse of history.
Amuse me with tales of ancient times,
when mortals trembled
at the name of Zeus.
You want a story? I got one.
Seems there was this guy named Max,
who, because he had been lucky so far
in the smuggling racket,
believed himself to be untouchable,
superior, godlike.
There's a cynical edge to your voice
I don't appreciate.
Know you not I am above mortal
constraints of right and wrong?
No one is above the law, Max.
I make my own laws.
Maxie, please. Don't look at me
as if you don't know me.
What's happened to you? To us?
After all we've been through together.
After all we meant to...
What's that?
Who dares?
Of course.
Like the shadow of ebon-winged night,
he rises from the dark realm.
Behold, the coming of my brother,
Lord Hades!
Welcome, Lord Hades.
Be serious, Max. That's Batman.
But Batman is a mere mortal.
And what mortal could reach
the summit of Mount Olympus and survive?
Come, dark brother. Avail yourself
of the nectar of the gods.
No, thanks.
I just want to ask you
a few questions about...
Hold. The words of the gods
are not for the ears of mere muses.
Yep, that's me,
just a lowly muse. Whatever.
Now, my brother, what brings you to me?
Has Lord Vulcan
been causing you trouble again?
The Batman? Upstairs?
What do we do?
If His Lordship wants us, he'll holler.
You're taking this too lightly, Alex.
We're in trouble.
Maxie's worse than ever.
When was the last time you saw him
wear real clothes in the office?
You know the boss and Greek stuff.
It's his thing.
Well, his thing is about to blow
this shipping firm out of the water.
And maybe Maxie with it.
An Electron Discharge Cannon?
You run one of the world's
largest shipping firms.
I thought you might know
how the hijackers were able to move it.
Why should Zeus be concerned
about the weapons of man
when he can call forth
thunderbolts of his own?
This audience is at an end.
Awake, my harpies.
Begone, Lord Hades.
Get thee back to thine own realm.
Do not come again
to Olympus until bidden.
I think I get the message.
Oh, Max, what's happening to you?
Hey, you called, boss... I mean,
thou didst summon us, O great Zeus?
Indeed I did.
For you are to be among
the first pitiful mortals
to bear witness to
the dawn of a new age.
Soon all mortals will tremble once more
at the fury of Zeus reborn!
Come back to me, Maxie.
What do you want?
The same thing you do.
To help Maximillian Zeus.
He wasn't always this way, you know.
But then business got bad and
he started handling cargo for the mob.
After a while, with the pressure,
the tension, things got confused.
He's not living in
the real world anymore.
Maybe you can relate to that.
You're the only one who can get me
close enough to help him,
while some of the man
you knew still exists.
This is as far as I can take you.
Now you're on your own.
Batman?
This isn't the roof.
Sorry, Ms. Droukas. Boss's orders.
This is as far as you go.
Like Bellerophon astride winged Pegasus,
yon foolish mortals
dare encroach on sacred Olympus.
- Does he mean us?
- Get thee back unto the mortal plane!
No, Maxie! Not the cops!
I don't believe it.
- It's on fire!
- It's gonna crash.
- It's gonna explode.
- Oh, no!
Get back!
Feel the wrath of Zeus,
thou insignificant...
Max, what have you done?
You could have killed someone!
How dare you speak with such disloyalty!
But, Maxie, please, you know I love you.
Clio? I'm sorry. I can't...
Thou art no longer fit to be among us!
Tie her to the thunderbolt of Zeus.
But, boss, don't you think
you may be carrying things a bit...
Alexander, will thou do my bidding?
Nothing personal, Ms. Droukas.
So, no longer like an eagle
against the sky,
but as a worm crawling though the dirt
does Lord Hades try to regain Olympus.
Look on my works,
ye mighty, and despair.
Heracles bested 12 labors
before I received him.
And so it shall be with you, bat demon.
So, you have survived my hydra.
But many more challenges await.
Alas.
Farewell, my dark brother.
Be not afraid, my muse.
For once thou hast been cleansed
by the fire from Olympus,
thou shalt be as a goddess
at my side throughout eternity!
Let the heavens scream!
Let the earth tremble!
Let mortals know
the gods of old live again!
It's over, Maxie.
Alexander, destroy the bat demon.
- But, boss, maybe we shouldn't...
- Traitors! My harpies, awake.
Destroy all who oppose me!
Ah.
Thank you, Bat... Look out!
Begone, thou foul bat demon!
Get thee back to the underworld
where thee belongs!
Such is the fate of all
who dare to thwart the gods.
Oh, no.
It's going to fire!
No!
That's mine!
Maxie, no!
Get down!
Now, this is truly Olympus.
Surely, it can be no other place.
There's beautiful Demeter,
goddess of the harvest.
And double-faced Janus,
lord of beginnings and endings.
And merry Hermes,
the trickster of the gods.
Now at last, mighty Zeus is home.