1
00:00:41,200 --> 00:00:44,630
This is our planet's final frontier.

2
00:00:47,480 --> 00:00:52,390
An inner world
where only the most adventurous dare to go.

3
00:01:44,120 --> 00:01:49,790
Beneath our feet are countless miles
of cave shafts and passages.

4
00:02:06,480 --> 00:02:10,790
The Cave of Swallows in Mexico,
400 metres to the bottom,

5
00:02:10,880 --> 00:02:14,670
deep enough to engulf the Empire State Building.

6
00:02:21,680 --> 00:02:24,990
This is the biggest cave shaft in the world,

7
00:02:25,120 --> 00:02:30,870
yet these depths were first explored
only two years before men landed on the moon.

8
00:02:34,880 --> 00:02:39,950
Today, caves remain
the least explored places on Earth.

9
00:02:40,240 --> 00:02:47,070
However, human beings are seldom
the first to reach these black, damp places.

10
00:02:51,720 --> 00:02:57,510
Here live some of the strangest
and least known animals on the planet.

11
00:03:29,840 --> 00:03:35,790
This galaxy of little lights is created
by thousands of living creatures.

12
00:03:40,880 --> 00:03:45,590
Any animal that lives in a cave
has to cope with complete blackness.

13
00:03:45,880 --> 00:03:50,510
But in New Zealand, some have turned
this darkness to their advantage.

14
00:04:03,480 --> 00:04:09,310
A silken strand is lowered from the ceiling
alongside hundreds of others.

15
00:04:17,280 --> 00:04:22,350
Beautiful though these threads are,
they have a sinister purpose.

16
00:04:24,120 --> 00:04:26,950
This is a cave glow-worm.

17
00:04:27,640 --> 00:04:31,910
To trap its prey, it goes fishing with a line of silk.

18
00:04:39,120 --> 00:04:43,070
The silk comes from glands
in the glow-worm's mouth

19
00:04:43,160 --> 00:04:46,270
and is loaded with droplets of mucus.

20
00:05:00,280 --> 00:05:04,310
Each glow-worm produces dozens
of these threads.

21
00:05:07,400 --> 00:05:12,310
Once its lines are set,
the glow-worm hangs from a mucous hammock

22
00:05:12,400 --> 00:05:15,350
and waits like a patient angler.

23
00:05:19,960 --> 00:05:23,150
But the glow-worm
doesn't leave everything to chance.

24
00:05:23,240 --> 00:05:27,510
That ghostly blue light
is the result of a chemical reaction

25
00:05:27,600 --> 00:05:31,230
taking place inside a special capsule in its tail.

26
00:05:32,680 --> 00:05:38,510
The light literally shines out of its backside.
It's a lure for attracting prey.

27
00:06:05,520 --> 00:06:09,670
Insects seem irresistibly drawn towards the source

28
00:06:09,840 --> 00:06:13,550
and then get trapped by the sticky lines.

29
00:06:22,760 --> 00:06:25,910
Once stuck, there is no escape.

30
00:06:31,160 --> 00:06:34,670
Now it's just a matter of reeling in the line

31
00:06:35,240 --> 00:06:38,510
and slowly consuming the catch alive.

32
00:06:54,280 --> 00:06:57,150
By ensnaring the insects that hatch in this cave,

33
00:06:57,240 --> 00:07:00,310
these glow-worms
have solved the biggest challenge

34
00:07:00,440 --> 00:07:05,670
that permanent cave-dwellers face,
finding a regular and reliable source of food.

35
00:07:13,480 --> 00:07:17,990
One kind of rock makes
this whole underground world possible,

36
00:07:18,080 --> 00:07:19,670
limestone.

37
00:07:19,800 --> 00:07:25,750
Most of the world's caves are found within it
and it covers nearly 10% of the Earth's surface.

38
00:07:32,280 --> 00:07:37,710
Limestone is composed of minerals
derived from marine shells and corals.

39
00:07:37,800 --> 00:07:41,230
So although this rocky escarpment
in the United States

40
00:07:41,360 --> 00:07:46,750
is now hundreds of metres above sea level,
it was actually formed underwater.

41
00:07:54,200 --> 00:08:00,550
The limestone towers of Vietnam's Halong Bay
are a reminder of this link with the sea.

42
00:08:00,720 --> 00:08:05,190
Originally this whole area
would have been one solid block of limestone,

43
00:08:05,280 --> 00:08:07,470
the base of a coral reef.

44
00:08:18,040 --> 00:08:23,950
In Borneo, rain has sculpted the limestone
into extremely sharp-sided pinnacles.

45
00:08:38,040 --> 00:08:44,870
But the dissolving power of rainwater has other,
much more dramatic, effects underground.

46
00:08:56,240 --> 00:09:01,110
Rivers that flow over limestone
often seem to completely disappear.

47
00:09:14,960 --> 00:09:20,270
When the water reaches a more resistant bed
of limestone, its course is altered.

48
00:09:24,880 --> 00:09:30,030
Once underground,
the water takes on a new, more erosive power.

49
00:09:35,960 --> 00:09:38,230
During its journey from the surface,

50
00:09:38,360 --> 00:09:43,550
the water absorbed carbon dioxide from the soil,
making it mildly acidic.

51
00:09:43,960 --> 00:09:48,190
And over millions of years,
this acid eats away the limestone,

52
00:09:48,280 --> 00:09:54,150
creating a maze of caverns and passages
that sometimes go on for miles.

53
00:10:32,720 --> 00:10:38,110
This is the biggest underground
river passage in the world,

54
00:10:38,200 --> 00:10:42,030
so big a jumbo jet could fly through it.

55
00:10:42,120 --> 00:10:45,230
It's Deer Cave in Borneo.

56
00:10:57,200 --> 00:11:02,830
The sheer size of Deer Cave allows some animals
to gather there in huge numbers.

57
00:11:10,680 --> 00:11:15,630
A staggering three million
wrinkle-lipped bats live here.

58
00:11:18,920 --> 00:11:23,110
The bats roost high on the walls and ceilings,
where they're well protected

59
00:11:23,200 --> 00:11:26,350
from the outside elements
and safe from predators.

60
00:11:34,600 --> 00:11:39,350
And while they're up here,
the bats produce something very important.

61
00:11:44,320 --> 00:11:50,310
This 100-metre-high mound
is made entirely of bat droppings, guano.

62
00:12:12,560 --> 00:12:17,350
Its surface is covered
by a thick carpet of cockroaches.

63
00:12:18,360 --> 00:12:20,630
Hundreds of thousands of them.

64
00:12:26,120 --> 00:12:31,270
Caves are one of the few habitats on Earth
not directly powered by sunlight.

65
00:12:32,120 --> 00:12:35,830
In the absence of plants, this food chain is based

66
00:12:35,920 --> 00:12:39,710
on a continuous supply of bat droppings.

67
00:12:52,160 --> 00:12:57,790
The cockroaches feed on the guano
and anything that falls into it.

68
00:13:24,440 --> 00:13:28,030
The droppings also support
other types of cockroaches,

69
00:13:28,120 --> 00:13:31,350
which spend part of their day
resting on cave walls.

70
00:13:36,000 --> 00:13:40,470
These in turn become food
for giant cave centipedes,

71
00:13:40,560 --> 00:13:43,590
some more than 20 centimetres long.

72
00:13:47,120 --> 00:13:52,310
Bizarrely, there are crabs here, too.
Sifting through the droppings for nutrients.

73
00:13:59,560 --> 00:14:03,470
All these animals spend
their entire lives within the cave.

74
00:14:03,640 --> 00:14:07,630
They're totally dependent
on the digested remains of food

75
00:14:07,720 --> 00:14:09,630
that's brought in from outside.

76
00:14:36,320 --> 00:14:42,390
Each evening, in just two hours,
three million bats leave the safety of the cave

77
00:14:42,480 --> 00:14:45,390
to hunt for insects in the forest outside.

78
00:14:48,320 --> 00:14:50,710
But not all will return.

79
00:15:11,920 --> 00:15:17,470
As they leave the cave,
the stream of bats form a doughnut-shaped ring.

80
00:15:20,600 --> 00:15:24,950
The wheeling bats seem to confuse
a rufous-bellied eagle,

81
00:15:25,040 --> 00:15:30,030
but they must still survive the attacks
of other, more specialised birds of prey.

82
00:15:41,240 --> 00:15:46,390
Peregrine falcons and bat hawks
are the jet fighters of the bird world.

83
00:16:17,600 --> 00:16:23,550
Good hunting will end as the light fades
so the bat hawks bolt their catches on the wing

84
00:16:25,400 --> 00:16:27,710
and fly straight back for more.

85
00:16:30,040 --> 00:16:34,590
Any bat separated from the group
becomes a clear and obvious target

86
00:16:34,680 --> 00:16:36,350
and is asking for trouble.

87
00:16:47,560 --> 00:16:51,710
Yet the nightly onslaught
has little impact on bat numbers.

88
00:16:51,800 --> 00:16:57,030
By the morning, the vast majority
will be back in the safety of the cave.

89
00:17:06,800 --> 00:17:11,190
Bats are not the only commuters
in these Bornean caves.

90
00:17:11,280 --> 00:17:13,550
There's a day shift as well.

91
00:17:19,240 --> 00:17:24,110
Returning from hunting in the sunlight,
these commuters rely on their loud clicks

92
00:17:24,200 --> 00:17:28,470
to find their way through the cave passages
in total darkness.

93
00:17:34,120 --> 00:17:36,430
They're cave swiftlets.

94
00:17:36,880 --> 00:17:40,230
Like bats, they use echolocation to navigate.

95
00:17:40,880 --> 00:17:43,270
We need lights to see what's going on,

96
00:17:43,360 --> 00:17:46,710
but in the pitch black,
the swiftlets manage unerringly

97
00:17:46,800 --> 00:17:51,790
to locate their individual nesting sites,
which are only a few centimetres across.

98
00:17:56,800 --> 00:18:01,630
It's a remarkable skill
and one we still do not fully understand.

99
00:18:06,080 --> 00:18:08,950
These birds are unusual for another reason.

100
00:18:09,040 --> 00:18:13,990
Their little cup-like nests
are made entirely from threads of saliva.

101
00:18:19,520 --> 00:18:22,590
It takes more than 30 days to complete one.

102
00:18:24,240 --> 00:18:29,230
Their nests are very precious objects,
and not only for the birds.

103
00:18:46,880 --> 00:18:52,350
For 500 years, people have been harvesting
the nests of cave swiftlets.

104
00:19:04,800 --> 00:19:07,230
It's a very risky business.

105
00:19:07,720 --> 00:19:12,910
With virtually no safety equipment
and using ladders made from forest vines,

106
00:19:13,000 --> 00:19:16,390
the gatherers climb
into the highest reaches of the cave,

107
00:19:16,480 --> 00:19:19,390
often more than 60 metres from the floor.

108
00:19:28,280 --> 00:19:33,310
The work may be hazardous in the extreme,
but the rewards are great.

109
00:19:42,840 --> 00:19:48,830
The pure white nests of cave swiftlets
are the main ingredient of bird's nest soup

110
00:19:48,920 --> 00:19:52,470
and, gram for gram, are worth as much as silver.

111
00:19:54,800 --> 00:19:59,710
As soon as its nest is removed,
a bird will immediately build another,

112
00:19:59,800 --> 00:20:03,710
so as long as this valuable harvest
is properly controlled,

113
00:20:03,800 --> 00:20:06,550
the colonies will continue to flourish.

114
00:20:18,760 --> 00:20:22,190
These Bornean caves
are among the biggest in the world

115
00:20:22,320 --> 00:20:28,270
and they're still getting bigger as, each year,
rainwater eats away a little more limestone.

116
00:20:39,120 --> 00:20:44,270
But water in caves doesn't only erode,
it also builds.

117
00:20:51,520 --> 00:20:55,110
This water is loaded with dissolved limestone,

118
00:20:55,240 --> 00:21:01,630
and when it meets the air in the cave,
some of that is deposited as a mineral, calcite.

119
00:21:04,400 --> 00:21:09,790
As it builds up, so the calcite forms decorations
that hang from the ceiling,

120
00:21:09,880 --> 00:21:12,230
stalactites.

121
00:21:18,920 --> 00:21:23,110
Each drop leaves behind
only a minuscule amount of calcite,

122
00:21:23,240 --> 00:21:27,670
but over time,
the process can produce some spectacular results.

123
00:21:57,800 --> 00:22:00,470
If the water seeps through the ceiling quickly,

124
00:22:00,560 --> 00:22:03,910
then the calcite is deposited
on the floor of the cave,

125
00:22:04,000 --> 00:22:06,830
and that creates stalagmites.

126
00:22:16,120 --> 00:22:21,790
Variations in water flow and air currents
produce an infinite variety of forms,

127
00:22:21,880 --> 00:22:24,670
but all are created by the same process,

128
00:22:25,480 --> 00:22:29,550
the slow deposition of dissolved limestone.

129
00:22:32,600 --> 00:22:37,590
And when stalactite meets stalagmite,
a column is born.

130
00:23:01,120 --> 00:23:04,630
Structures like these
in North America's Carlsbad Cavern

131
00:23:04,720 --> 00:23:08,070
can take many thousands of years to develop.

132
00:23:08,200 --> 00:23:13,310
But sometimes, the formations in a cave
stop growing altogether.

133
00:23:40,560 --> 00:23:46,870
These flooded caves in Mexico have remained
virtually unchanged for thousands of years.

134
00:23:47,560 --> 00:23:51,830
Since the last ice age,
they've become cut off from the outside world,

135
00:23:52,280 --> 00:23:56,430
yet their impact on life at the surface
has been huge.

136
00:24:02,120 --> 00:24:07,910
Five hundred years ago, they supported
one of the world's great civilizations,

137
00:24:08,000 --> 00:24:09,870
the Maya.

138
00:24:14,280 --> 00:24:19,550
Mexico's Yucatán peninsula has no rivers,
lakes or streams,

139
00:24:19,640 --> 00:24:22,230
so the Maya relied on the cenotes,

140
00:24:22,320 --> 00:24:25,950
the flooded entrances to the water-filled caves.

141
00:24:29,200 --> 00:24:34,830
These flooded shafts
are the region's only source of open fresh water.

142
00:24:37,240 --> 00:24:41,950
The cenotes are, in effect,
gigantic freshwater wells.

143
00:25:06,800 --> 00:25:12,950
Away from the life-giving rays of sunshine,
one might not expect to find plants.

144
00:25:21,720 --> 00:25:26,750
But in the darkness of the cave tunnels,
roots of giant tropical trees

145
00:25:26,840 --> 00:25:31,750
have pushed their way through cracks
in the limestone to reach the flooded caverns.

146
00:25:33,600 --> 00:25:38,710
Without this water,
the Yucatán's forest could not grow so luxuriantly.

147
00:25:58,320 --> 00:26:02,230
The Maya knew that their lives
depended on this water,

148
00:26:02,320 --> 00:26:05,070
but it's only with the help of today's technology

149
00:26:05,200 --> 00:26:10,990
that we've come to appreciate the full significance
and scale of these flooded passageways.

150
00:26:15,440 --> 00:26:18,830
So far, more than 350 miles

151
00:26:18,920 --> 00:26:22,550
of underwater galleries in the Yucatán
have been mapped.

152
00:26:22,640 --> 00:26:28,910
But still, nobody yet knows the true extent
of this subterranean water world.

153
00:26:29,400 --> 00:26:31,230
And with good reason.

154
00:26:33,800 --> 00:26:37,590
Underwater caving is notoriously dangerous.

155
00:26:37,920 --> 00:26:41,670
When the nearest exit
may be hundreds of metres or more away,

156
00:26:41,760 --> 00:26:44,990
running out of air down here would be fatal.

157
00:26:48,640 --> 00:26:52,830
To avoid getting lost,
divers carry with them a spool of string.

158
00:26:52,920 --> 00:26:56,030
It becomes their lifeline, literally.

159
00:27:09,520 --> 00:27:15,510
The string also doubles as a measuring tape,
a technique that has been used here in Mexico

160
00:27:15,600 --> 00:27:21,190
to chart the largest underwater cave
in the world, all 100 miles of it.

161
00:27:29,680 --> 00:27:35,710
Cave exploration often requires you
to push yourself through narrow gaps in the rock.

162
00:27:35,800 --> 00:27:38,950
Cavers call such places "squeezes".

163
00:27:48,080 --> 00:27:54,430
The tighter the squeeze, the greater the chance
of damaging some vital life-support system.

164
00:28:20,040 --> 00:28:25,110
In these conditions,
a diver could easily become disorientated,

165
00:28:25,200 --> 00:28:27,350
and that could be fatal.

166
00:28:40,800 --> 00:28:45,670
The flooded caverns can play tricks on you
in other ways.

167
00:28:53,440 --> 00:28:56,870
What seems like air isn't.

168
00:28:56,960 --> 00:28:59,590
It's just another kind of water.

169
00:29:07,320 --> 00:29:12,390
This is a halocline,
a meeting of fresh and salt water.

170
00:29:15,480 --> 00:29:20,590
Fresh water from the jungle flows
over the heavier salt water from the sea.

171
00:29:22,160 --> 00:29:25,470
The salt water layer is extremely low in oxygen,

172
00:29:25,560 --> 00:29:29,390
making it a particularly difficult place
for animals to live.

173
00:29:29,840 --> 00:29:31,830
Yet some have managed it,

174
00:29:31,960 --> 00:29:36,550
like the remipede,
one of the most ancient of all living crustaceans.

175
00:29:45,120 --> 00:29:48,910
The Maya understood the importance
of the cenotes,

176
00:29:49,040 --> 00:29:52,430
but they could never have known
that these flooded passageways

177
00:29:52,520 --> 00:29:56,310
were actually the beginning
of subterranean rivers,

178
00:29:56,400 --> 00:29:59,550
all of which eventually flow out to the sea.

179
00:30:09,280 --> 00:30:13,670
Salt water, unlike fresh water,
does not erode limestone,

180
00:30:13,760 --> 00:30:19,350
so most sea caves are created
by the mechanical pounding of the waves.

181
00:30:25,760 --> 00:30:29,670
The rocky outcrops
of New Zealand's Poor Knights Islands

182
00:30:29,760 --> 00:30:31,590
are riddled with sea caves.

183
00:30:31,680 --> 00:30:33,430
And just like those in Borneo,

184
00:30:33,520 --> 00:30:36,950
they have become important shelters
for many species.

185
00:30:41,600 --> 00:30:44,230
After a day feeding in the open water,

186
00:30:44,320 --> 00:30:48,470
vast shoals of demoiselle fish return to the caves,

187
00:30:48,560 --> 00:30:51,430
which they use as a refuge from predators.

188
00:30:54,040 --> 00:31:00,030
For these fish, the caves are a night-time retreat,
but they're not the only commuters in here.

189
00:31:00,760 --> 00:31:04,310
There are other fish
working to a different schedule.

190
00:31:11,400 --> 00:31:17,950
The big-eyes are the equivalent of bats,
night feeders that leave the cave each evening.

191
00:31:22,320 --> 00:31:24,750
And like all cave commuters,

192
00:31:24,840 --> 00:31:28,830
they are most vulnerable
at the scheduled time of departure.

193
00:31:39,840 --> 00:31:45,710
A bottle-neck funnels these exiting bats
into dense concentrations,

194
00:31:45,800 --> 00:31:48,070
attracting the attention of others.

195
00:32:14,800 --> 00:32:18,670
The bats can detect the snakes using echolocation,

196
00:32:19,320 --> 00:32:23,550
but the snakes are literally in the dark,
they can see nothing.

197
00:32:37,120 --> 00:32:40,190
The strikes seem to be largely hit and miss.

198
00:32:42,400 --> 00:32:45,270
But the snakes have a secret weapon.

199
00:32:45,800 --> 00:32:49,270
They can actually sense each bat flying past.

200
00:32:49,360 --> 00:32:54,110
Receptors in the snake's head pick up
the heat given off by the flying bats,

201
00:32:54,920 --> 00:32:57,150
as this thermal image shows.

202
00:33:03,840 --> 00:33:09,790
To the snakes, the bats are apparently glowing
and this gives them something to aim at.

203
00:33:31,640 --> 00:33:35,790
This is the price
that these cave commuters must pay

204
00:33:35,880 --> 00:33:38,470
for their daytime sanctuary underground.

205
00:33:39,160 --> 00:33:44,030
Small wonder, then,
that there are other cave dwellers that stay put.

206
00:33:51,480 --> 00:33:53,830
Many caves are like islands,

207
00:33:53,920 --> 00:33:58,070
cut off from the outside world
and from other caves.

208
00:34:05,840 --> 00:34:12,270
This isolation has resulted in the evolution
of some very strange creatures.

209
00:34:14,280 --> 00:34:18,430
They are the cave specialists, troglobites,

210
00:34:18,560 --> 00:34:22,670
animals that never emerge from the caves
or see daylight.

211
00:34:35,360 --> 00:34:41,350
These troglobites from Thailand are possibly
the most specialised creatures on Earth,

212
00:34:41,720 --> 00:34:45,030
for they live only in cave waterfalls.

213
00:34:46,080 --> 00:34:52,990
The entire population of these cave angel fish
seems to be restricted to just two small caves.

214
00:34:57,360 --> 00:34:59,950
It's the same story with other troglobites.

215
00:35:00,080 --> 00:35:04,870
There may well be less
than 100 Texas cave salamanders in the wild.

216
00:35:21,200 --> 00:35:25,190
And the Belizean white crab is another creature

217
00:35:25,280 --> 00:35:28,590
that is unique to just one cave system.

218
00:35:33,440 --> 00:35:35,710
Living in perpetual darkness,

219
00:35:35,800 --> 00:35:40,550
they have all not only lost the pigment
in their skin but also their eyes.

220
00:35:42,640 --> 00:35:46,270
It takes thousands of generations
for eyes to be lost

221
00:35:46,360 --> 00:35:50,830
so these species must have been isolated
for a very long time.

222
00:35:56,040 --> 00:36:01,230
But the blind salamander
has other highly-developed sensory organs.

223
00:36:03,960 --> 00:36:09,510
Receptors in the skin detect minute movements
in the water made by its prey.

224
00:36:16,040 --> 00:36:21,670
External gills help it to breathe in water
that is particularly low in oxygen.

225
00:36:32,960 --> 00:36:38,030
The cave angel fish feed on bacteria
in the fast-flowing water,

226
00:36:38,120 --> 00:36:41,950
keeping their grip
with microscopic hooks on their fins.

227
00:36:52,640 --> 00:36:55,190
Food is often in short supply

228
00:36:55,320 --> 00:37:01,310
and troglobites, like the crab, have to survive
on whatever washes into the cave from outside.

229
00:37:05,920 --> 00:37:09,430
A salamander might not encounter food
for several months,

230
00:37:09,520 --> 00:37:13,430
so when something does come along,
it can't afford to miss it.

231
00:37:20,240 --> 00:37:23,470
It's astonishing
that these extraordinary cave dwellers

232
00:37:23,560 --> 00:37:25,750
manage to survive at all.

233
00:37:26,880 --> 00:37:29,350
But one cave is so inhospitable

234
00:37:29,440 --> 00:37:32,950
that one would not expect it
to contain any life whatsoever.

235
00:37:38,880 --> 00:37:42,870
The water flowing out
of the Villa Luz cave in Mexico

236
00:37:42,960 --> 00:37:46,630
is actually coloured white with sulphuric acid.

237
00:38:01,280 --> 00:38:07,270
Explorers entering this dangerous cave
must wear respirators and carry monitors.

238
00:38:07,840 --> 00:38:13,590
Poisonous gases rise to fatal levels so quickly
that an early warning system is essential.

239
00:38:18,960 --> 00:38:22,590
Bats survive by staying close to the skylights,

240
00:38:22,680 --> 00:38:26,670
but venturing deep into the cave
is very dangerous indeed.

241
00:38:36,400 --> 00:38:41,590
The source of these toxic fumes
lies several miles below.

242
00:38:42,160 --> 00:38:47,350
Hydrogen sulphide gas bubbles up
from oil deposits in the Earth's crust.

243
00:38:47,440 --> 00:38:52,230
It mixes with oxygen in the water
and forms sulphuric acid.

244
00:39:03,280 --> 00:39:07,470
These are not the sort of conditions
in which you would expect to find fish.

245
00:39:07,600 --> 00:39:13,670
Yet these cave mollies seem to thrive,
despite the acid and the low levels of oxygen.

246
00:39:16,520 --> 00:39:20,510
There is, in fact, more life here
than anyone would think possible,

247
00:39:20,600 --> 00:39:25,110
but the biggest surprise
is something altogether more bizarre.

248
00:39:35,560 --> 00:39:39,270
These strange stalactite-like formations

249
00:39:39,360 --> 00:39:43,590
are known, rather appropriately, as snottites.

250
00:39:43,720 --> 00:39:48,110
The drops dripping from the ends
are sulphuric acid,

251
00:39:48,200 --> 00:39:50,550
strong enough to burn skin.

252
00:39:53,920 --> 00:39:58,110
The snottites are, in fact, vast colonies of bacteria

253
00:39:58,240 --> 00:40:01,270
capable of growing a centimetre a day.

254
00:40:05,800 --> 00:40:10,070
In this world without sunlight,
these bacteria extract energy

255
00:40:10,160 --> 00:40:12,590
from the hydrogen sulphide gas.

256
00:40:17,280 --> 00:40:21,230
Bacteria like these are known as extremophiles

257
00:40:21,320 --> 00:40:25,430
because of their ability to survive
in such extreme conditions.

258
00:40:28,160 --> 00:40:32,910
And these extremophiles play
another important role in this cave.

259
00:40:33,000 --> 00:40:36,510
Surprisingly, they are the basis of a food chain

260
00:40:36,600 --> 00:40:40,910
which supports, amongst other creatures,
the larvae of these midges.

261
00:40:50,600 --> 00:40:54,350
Villa Luz's ecosystem
was certainly very remarkable,

262
00:40:54,440 --> 00:40:59,270
but cave explorers were soon to make
an even more astonishing discovery.

263
00:41:11,840 --> 00:41:16,830
Beneath this arid landscape
lies a subterranean wonderland.

264
00:41:22,840 --> 00:41:26,510
Without water,
one might not expect to find any caves,

265
00:41:26,600 --> 00:41:30,790
but beneath these rolling desert slopes
in the United States

266
00:41:30,880 --> 00:41:36,790
lies one of the longest, deepest
and most surprising caves in the world.

267
00:41:41,480 --> 00:41:45,350
Its secrets remained unknown until 1986,

268
00:41:45,440 --> 00:41:50,190
when cavers dug through several metres
of loose rock at the bottom of this pit.

269
00:41:54,240 --> 00:41:59,270
They named the cave Lechuguilla
and since its discovery,

270
00:41:59,360 --> 00:42:03,550
more than 120 miles of passageways
have been mapped.

271
00:42:09,240 --> 00:42:14,910
When the first explorers descended,
no one guessed at the sheer size of this cave,

272
00:42:15,000 --> 00:42:18,350
but even that
was not going to be the biggest surprise.

273
00:42:18,960 --> 00:42:22,510
Little did they realise
that Lechuguilla would soon be regarded

274
00:42:22,600 --> 00:42:27,710
by cavers the world over
as the most beautiful of all caves.

275
00:42:27,960 --> 00:42:32,270
They were about to discover
some of the most exquisite formations

276
00:42:32,360 --> 00:42:34,230
ever seen underground.

277
00:42:48,360 --> 00:42:53,510
The walls were covered
with the most delicate and fragile crystals.

278
00:43:08,360 --> 00:43:14,070
Many of these crystals were made of gypsum,
a mineral that comes from limestone,

279
00:43:14,240 --> 00:43:17,390
and there was mile after mile of them.

280
00:43:34,200 --> 00:43:40,230
Water is the creator of most caves,
but unlike all other limestone caves,

281
00:43:40,360 --> 00:43:45,110
Lechuguilla's rock had not been eaten away
by running rainwater.

282
00:43:46,920 --> 00:43:49,190
Something else was responsible.

283
00:43:57,280 --> 00:44:03,070
The only water Lechuguilla has
are these wonderfully still, clear pools.

284
00:44:08,640 --> 00:44:11,270
As the explorers went deeper into the cave,

285
00:44:11,360 --> 00:44:16,030
they came across whole galleries
filled with the most unusual formations,

286
00:44:16,120 --> 00:44:20,870
like these five-metre cones
frosted with the most delicate crystals.

287
00:44:50,040 --> 00:44:54,590
It was Lechuguilla's gypsum crystals
that made scientists question

288
00:44:54,680 --> 00:44:56,910
how these caverns were formed.

289
00:44:59,360 --> 00:45:04,190
They discovered that Lechuguilla's limestone
had actually been eaten away

290
00:45:04,320 --> 00:45:09,710
by sulphuric acid
cutting through literally miles of limestone.

291
00:45:26,840 --> 00:45:32,070
And when sulphuric acid dissolves limestone,
it leaves behind gypsum,

292
00:45:32,160 --> 00:45:36,030
the basis of Lechuguilla's remarkable formations.

293
00:45:36,120 --> 00:45:39,870
And there was one set,
more than a mile from the surface,

294
00:45:39,960 --> 00:45:42,270
that almost defied belief.

295
00:45:58,560 --> 00:46:03,070
The Chandelier Ballroom
was the ultimate discovery.

296
00:46:03,160 --> 00:46:09,670
With its six-metre-long crystals, it's surely
the most bizarre cave chamber in the world.

297
00:46:50,800 --> 00:46:54,950
And the walls had one further surprise.

298
00:46:57,160 --> 00:47:02,950
Extremophile bacteria
were found to be feeding on the rock itself.

299
00:47:08,920 --> 00:47:14,310
The discovery of life that exists
without drawing any of its energy from the sun

300
00:47:14,440 --> 00:47:20,230
shows us once again how complex and surprising
the underground world can be.

301
00:47:24,440 --> 00:47:29,950
Each year, explorers chart over a hundred miles
of new cave passages.

302
00:47:32,160 --> 00:47:35,910
But with half the world's limestone
still to be explored,

303
00:47:36,000 --> 00:47:41,390
who knows how many Lechuguillas
are still waiting to be discovered?

