1
00:00:34,800 --> 00:00:40,750
Trees, surely among
the most magnificent of all living things.

2
00:00:43,000 --> 00:00:48,110
Some of the largest organisms on Earth,
dwarfing all others

3
00:00:48,200 --> 00:00:51,390
and these are the tallest of them all.

4
00:01:04,160 --> 00:01:09,550
The deciduous and coniferous woodlands
that grow in the seasonal parts of our planet

5
00:01:09,640 --> 00:01:12,430
are the most extensive forests on Earth.

6
00:01:21,240 --> 00:01:24,750
Their sheer extent stuns the imagination.

7
00:01:37,200 --> 00:01:39,910
The barren snows of the Arctic.

8
00:01:40,000 --> 00:01:44,150
A thousand miles from the North Pole
and heading south.

9
00:01:47,480 --> 00:01:50,830
This is the very first place that trees can grow.

10
00:01:53,760 --> 00:01:59,230
To begin with, the conifers are sparse
but soon they dominate the land.

11
00:02:07,840 --> 00:02:10,670
This is the taiga forest.

12
00:02:12,680 --> 00:02:17,830
There are as many trees here
as in all the world's rainforests combined.

13
00:02:19,480 --> 00:02:24,830
The taiga circles the globe
and contains a third of all the trees on Earth.

14
00:02:25,360 --> 00:02:31,470
It produces so much oxygen that it refreshes
the atmosphere of the entire planet.

15
00:02:36,320 --> 00:02:38,710
At the taiga's northern extent,

16
00:02:38,800 --> 00:02:42,790
the growing season
can last for just one month a year.

17
00:02:43,920 --> 00:02:48,070
It can take 50 years for a tree
to get bigger than a seedling.

18
00:03:01,880 --> 00:03:05,710
It's a silent world where little stirs.

19
00:03:07,880 --> 00:03:13,190
But there are occasional signs of life,
stories written in the snow.

20
00:03:15,080 --> 00:03:19,990
The prints of an Arctic fox
and the hare it might have been stalking.

21
00:03:25,720 --> 00:03:29,110
A female polar bear and her two cubs.

22
00:03:39,440 --> 00:03:44,230
Some animals are so difficult to glimpse
that they're like spirits.

23
00:03:44,880 --> 00:03:49,950
One could live a lifetime in these woods
and never see a lynx.

24
00:03:53,680 --> 00:03:57,630
The cat must roam hundreds of miles
in search of prey

25
00:03:57,720 --> 00:04:00,990
and may never visit
the same patch of forest twice.

26
00:04:03,160 --> 00:04:06,190
It's the very essence of wilderness.

27
00:04:10,960 --> 00:04:16,710
With so few prey animals here,
life for a hunter is particularly hard.

28
00:04:19,680 --> 00:04:23,670
Creatures are scarce
because few can eat conifer needles.

29
00:04:24,640 --> 00:04:26,990
The moose is an exception.

30
00:04:32,040 --> 00:04:33,870
Growth is so difficult

31
00:04:33,960 --> 00:04:38,230
that conifers protect their precious leaves
by filling them with resin.

32
00:04:38,320 --> 00:04:42,830
That reduces water loss,
but it also make them very distasteful.

33
00:04:53,840 --> 00:04:57,470
At least the conifer's seeds are edible.

34
00:04:57,600 --> 00:05:03,590
But they're protected within armour-plated cones
and it takes a specialist to reach them.

35
00:05:06,520 --> 00:05:10,590
The crossbill's extraordinary beak
can prise apart the scales

36
00:05:10,680 --> 00:05:13,630
so that its tongue can extract the seeds.

37
00:05:17,680 --> 00:05:19,310
Birds are fortunate.

38
00:05:19,400 --> 00:05:22,830
When the seasonal crop is gathered,
they can fly south.

39
00:05:27,680 --> 00:05:32,590
But one animal is so expert at survival
in this frozen forest

40
00:05:32,680 --> 00:05:36,510
that it stays here and is active all year long.

41
00:05:39,400 --> 00:05:43,990
In local folklore,
the wolverine is a link to the spirit world

42
00:05:44,080 --> 00:05:47,030
and a cross between a bear and a wolf.

43
00:05:47,120 --> 00:05:50,110
In reality, it's a huge weasel.

44
00:05:52,880 --> 00:05:57,430
Its bulk helps to conserve body heat
and also broadens its menu.

45
00:05:57,520 --> 00:06:02,750
It's so big and powerful,
it can even bring down an adult caribou.

46
00:06:04,440 --> 00:06:09,750
For its size, it's said that the animal
can eat more in one sitting than any other.

47
00:06:09,840 --> 00:06:12,950
Which is why it's also known as the glutton.

48
00:06:30,240 --> 00:06:34,310
Being gluttonous here is a very effective strategy.

49
00:06:34,400 --> 00:06:37,870
It's wise to eat all you can when you can.

50
00:06:39,880 --> 00:06:42,830
And when even a glutton can't eat more,

51
00:06:42,920 --> 00:06:47,590
it stores what's left for later
in the surrounding deep freeze.

52
00:06:54,680 --> 00:06:57,150
Spring in the ice forest.

53
00:07:08,360 --> 00:07:12,310
The capercaillie can also digest conifer needles.

54
00:07:12,960 --> 00:07:15,990
But feeding is not its priority at the moment.

55
00:07:18,840 --> 00:07:22,550
Like gladiators, the males square up for a battle.

56
00:07:33,680 --> 00:07:38,230
Each may have just a single chance
to impress a female.

57
00:07:39,840 --> 00:07:42,990
Neither can afford a lapse in concentration.

58
00:08:07,320 --> 00:08:10,710
The injured loser may not survive.

59
00:08:15,960 --> 00:08:18,390
The inhabitants of this great wilderness

60
00:08:18,520 --> 00:08:22,630
may live and die
without ever having contact with humanity.

61
00:08:23,520 --> 00:08:25,470
Long may it be that way.

62
00:08:35,480 --> 00:08:38,790
The northern forests may be the largest on Earth,

63
00:08:38,880 --> 00:08:43,030
but to see coniferous trees
that have reached their full potential

64
00:08:43,120 --> 00:08:45,990
you must travel 1,000 miles south of here.

65
00:08:52,320 --> 00:08:54,790
The Pacific coast of North America.

66
00:09:01,240 --> 00:09:06,390
The land of hemlock, Douglas fir
and giant redwood.

67
00:09:14,440 --> 00:09:17,750
Here water is never locked up in ice.

68
00:09:17,840 --> 00:09:19,670
And even if rains fail,

69
00:09:19,800 --> 00:09:24,470
the needles can extract moisture from the fogs
that roll in from the sea.

70
00:09:32,960 --> 00:09:38,670
The sun's energy powers these forests,
not for one month as it does in the taiga,

71
00:09:38,760 --> 00:09:40,590
but for half the year.

72
00:09:49,760 --> 00:09:54,350
These conifers grow at ten times the rate
of those near the Arctic

73
00:09:54,440 --> 00:09:56,990
and they live for thousands of years.

74
00:10:07,080 --> 00:10:13,390
One grove of redwoods in California
contains three of the tallest trees on Earth.

75
00:10:19,040 --> 00:10:24,350
This one is over 100 metres high,
the size of a 30-storey building.

76
00:10:52,240 --> 00:10:57,150
These forests were growing here
long before humans walked the Earth.

77
00:10:57,600 --> 00:11:00,790
They were in their prime 20 million years ago

78
00:11:00,880 --> 00:11:06,070
and existed before the Swiss Alps
or the Rocky Mountains were even raised.

79
00:11:18,840 --> 00:11:22,750
There is more living matter
in a forest of giant conifers

80
00:11:22,840 --> 00:11:25,350
than in any tropical rainforest.

81
00:11:25,520 --> 00:11:28,950
But it's all contained within the trees.

82
00:11:29,040 --> 00:11:32,510
These are as inedible as those in the taiga.

83
00:11:32,600 --> 00:11:37,030
So animals are still scarce, but they are present.

84
00:11:41,160 --> 00:11:42,590
A pine marten.

85
00:11:42,680 --> 00:11:47,110
It's spring, the best time of year
for a marten to find food.

86
00:12:03,120 --> 00:12:09,110
Birds' eggs are a seasonal snack
and for a short time there's plenty of them.

87
00:12:11,240 --> 00:12:13,310
Sometimes perhaps too many.

88
00:12:17,160 --> 00:12:22,190
But to live here permanently,
the marten needs a more reliable food source.

89
00:12:23,600 --> 00:12:25,870
Squirrels fit the bill.

90
00:12:25,960 --> 00:12:28,470
They thrive here on the pine cones

91
00:12:28,600 --> 00:12:33,790
and although these are also seasonal,
they can be stored and eaten throughout the year.

92
00:12:38,720 --> 00:12:41,070
The squirrels are busy mating.

93
00:12:45,120 --> 00:12:50,310
Good news for the hunter.
A distracted squirrel is a vulnerable squirrel.

94
00:12:57,080 --> 00:13:00,630
But this time the amorous couple are safe.

95
00:13:00,720 --> 00:13:05,190
There is a loner stocking his larder
who will be the easier target.

96
00:13:39,360 --> 00:13:44,190
Early summer
and great grey owl chicks are fledging.

97
00:13:46,840 --> 00:13:49,510
Adults can only raise young here

98
00:13:49,600 --> 00:13:53,710
in years when the seasonal vole crop
is big enough to support them.

99
00:13:58,920 --> 00:14:01,950
The moment has arrived for their first flight.

100
00:14:07,200 --> 00:14:12,110
Leaping from the world's tallest trees
is not for the faint-hearted.

101
00:14:37,680 --> 00:14:42,790
If you're going to fall here,
it's quite a good idea to do it in stages.

102
00:15:00,920 --> 00:15:03,870
The ground is no place for an owl.

103
00:15:06,520 --> 00:15:10,670
If he's to climb to the top of his class,
he'll need to persevere.

104
00:15:13,920 --> 00:15:16,270
So now, let's have another go.

105
00:15:36,440 --> 00:15:41,190
The American conifer forests
may not be the richest in animal life

106
00:15:42,000 --> 00:15:44,470
but their trees are extraordinary.

107
00:15:45,520 --> 00:15:51,310
This giant sequoia, a relative of the redwood,
is the largest living thing on Earth.

108
00:15:52,120 --> 00:15:56,910
Known as General Sherman,
it's the weight of ten blue whales.

109
00:16:07,080 --> 00:16:11,510
Higher up in the nearby mountains,
bristlecone pines.

110
00:16:11,600 --> 00:16:14,070
The oldest organisms on the planet.

111
00:16:16,520 --> 00:16:20,190
Some have been here for 5, 000 years.

112
00:16:20,280 --> 00:16:23,310
They were alive before the pyramids were built

113
00:16:23,400 --> 00:16:27,710
and were already 3, 000 years old
when Christ was born.

114
00:16:33,000 --> 00:16:39,470
Across the equator in the southern hemisphere,
there are forests that mirror those of the north.

115
00:16:41,040 --> 00:16:47,390
Here in South America, araucaria trees, or
monkey puzzles, are like the conifers of the taiga.

116
00:16:48,440 --> 00:16:53,830
They have waterproof scales instead of needles
and their cones look a little different,

117
00:16:53,920 --> 00:16:56,230
but the principles are the same.

118
00:17:00,960 --> 00:17:05,790
Slender-billed parakeets rather than crossbills
extract their seeds.

119
00:17:14,320 --> 00:17:19,950
Where the growing season is longer,
there are alerce trees, the redwoods of the south.

120
00:17:35,320 --> 00:17:37,310
As in the frozen north,

121
00:17:37,400 --> 00:17:42,150
the Valdivian forests of Chile
support very few animals.

122
00:17:42,240 --> 00:17:44,870
But that is the end of the similarity.

123
00:17:48,840 --> 00:17:52,670
This is a bizarre world of miniature creatures.

124
00:17:55,800 --> 00:18:01,710
The pudu, the world's smallest deer,
feeds on the giant leaves of the gunnera plant.

125
00:18:09,840 --> 00:18:13,590
The female is just 30 centimetres high
at the shoulder

126
00:18:13,680 --> 00:18:16,790
and her infants are hardly bigger than kittens.

127
00:18:33,800 --> 00:18:36,150
The male must stay alert.

128
00:18:36,240 --> 00:18:39,430
There are hunters here
who would snatch his young.

129
00:18:41,840 --> 00:18:44,830
Another miniature, the kodkod cat.

130
00:18:48,800 --> 00:18:54,350
It's the smallest cat in all the Americas
and a young pudu would be a feast for it.

131
00:18:56,160 --> 00:19:00,870
But with the male on guard,
the kodkod must lower his sights.

132
00:19:06,360 --> 00:19:10,310
Moths are hatching.
They're the last of the summer.

133
00:19:10,400 --> 00:19:13,830
The tiny cat should be able to score with these.

134
00:19:16,760 --> 00:19:23,150
No one knows why the creatures here are so small,
but at least they can survive on meagre rations.

135
00:19:49,240 --> 00:19:52,830
You might call this a game of cat and moth.

136
00:20:16,080 --> 00:20:21,750
As winter approaches in Chile,
spring is arriving in the northern hemisphere.

137
00:20:30,040 --> 00:20:33,710
These are the deciduous forests of home.

138
00:20:34,920 --> 00:20:36,430
Dormant throughout the winter,

139
00:20:36,560 --> 00:20:42,030
they now undergo one of the most
magical transformations in the natural world.

140
00:20:54,040 --> 00:20:58,830
By late spring, the landscape is wrapped
in a vibrant fresh green.

141
00:20:59,520 --> 00:21:03,550
Here, instead of conifers,
there are broad-leaved trees

142
00:21:03,680 --> 00:21:07,590
and that makes the character of this forest
entirely different.

143
00:21:12,320 --> 00:21:16,950
Being broad, these leaves trap
much more light than needles.

144
00:21:17,040 --> 00:21:20,390
But they're also thin, soft and edible.

145
00:21:39,600 --> 00:21:42,550
And others can eat the leaf-eaters.

146
00:22:04,200 --> 00:22:10,350
It's spring in the great broad-leaved forests
of Eastern Europe and Asiatic Russia.

147
00:22:12,040 --> 00:22:14,310
The mandarin ducks are calling.

148
00:22:27,840 --> 00:22:31,390
The female mandarin nests in a tree hole.

149
00:22:31,480 --> 00:22:35,590
And when it's time for everyone to leave,
she leads the way.

150
00:22:38,960 --> 00:22:42,150
The ducklings are only 24 hours old.

151
00:22:44,840 --> 00:22:49,150
It's a long drop
and a few calls of encouragement are required.

152
00:23:02,320 --> 00:23:04,430
Two down, seven to go.

153
00:23:37,960 --> 00:23:40,110
There are still two missing.

154
00:24:01,240 --> 00:24:03,190
All present and correct.

155
00:24:04,280 --> 00:24:07,310
But they won't be safe until they reach water.

156
00:24:07,400 --> 00:24:10,310
And the forest pool is almost a mile away.

157
00:24:45,520 --> 00:24:48,630
By June, the days are at their longest

158
00:24:48,720 --> 00:24:53,590
and all across the northern hemisphere
the broadleaves are hard at work.

159
00:25:02,920 --> 00:25:07,510
On the east coast of North America,
it seems like any other summer's evening.

160
00:25:10,160 --> 00:25:12,550
But tonight is special.

161
00:25:17,120 --> 00:25:22,110
After 17 years underground, creatures are stirring.

162
00:25:28,680 --> 00:25:33,870
The nymphs of the periodical cicada
have been biding their time.

163
00:25:33,960 --> 00:25:40,190
Now they march like zombies
towards the nearest tree and start to climb.

164
00:25:48,160 --> 00:25:51,030
At first there are merely thousands.

165
00:25:51,120 --> 00:25:55,990
But soon more than a billion
swarm all over the forest.

166
00:25:56,120 --> 00:25:59,910
The biggest insect emergence on the planet
is underway.

167
00:26:30,160 --> 00:26:35,590
They invade the upper branches
where they climb out of their external skeletons

168
00:26:35,680 --> 00:26:38,950
and assume their adult winged form.

169
00:26:47,280 --> 00:26:49,950
At first, they're white and soft.

170
00:26:50,040 --> 00:26:53,670
But they have until dawn
to complete their transformation.

171
00:27:07,440 --> 00:27:13,310
After an absence of 17 years,
the forest is now overrun by cicadas.

172
00:27:21,920 --> 00:27:25,790
The adults are clumsy and very edible.

173
00:27:35,240 --> 00:27:38,230
For turtles and other inhabitants of the forest,

174
00:27:38,320 --> 00:27:41,990
this is a feast they're lucky to see
once in their lifetime

175
00:27:42,120 --> 00:27:44,910
and they gorge themselves while they can.

176
00:27:58,160 --> 00:28:00,430
Times have never been so good.

177
00:28:00,560 --> 00:28:05,550
The cicadas have no defences
and virtually offer themselves to their attackers.

178
00:28:16,280 --> 00:28:18,990
The stream of insects is so relentless

179
00:28:19,080 --> 00:28:22,910
that soon all the predators
are full to the point of bursting.

180
00:28:34,600 --> 00:28:37,350
And still the cicadas come.

181
00:28:37,440 --> 00:28:41,990
With the predators overwhelmed,
the survivors can achieve their purpose.

182
00:28:45,560 --> 00:28:50,550
After mating, the adults lay their eggs
and then their job is done.

183
00:28:51,440 --> 00:28:56,830
In just a few days they will all die
and the forest will fall silent.

184
00:28:56,920 --> 00:29:01,990
The cicadas here will not be heard again
for another 17 years.

185
00:29:12,240 --> 00:29:18,270
Having fed the predators, the cicadas leave
one final gift for the forest itself.

186
00:29:19,080 --> 00:29:24,470
The nutrients in a generation of cicadas
are returned to the soil all at once.

187
00:29:25,160 --> 00:29:28,270
And the trees enjoy a marked spurt in growth.

188
00:29:29,040 --> 00:29:33,870
This may be the single largest dose of fertiliser
in the natural world.

189
00:29:54,800 --> 00:29:58,150
In the great broadleaf forests of Eastern Europe,

190
00:29:58,240 --> 00:30:00,470
the days are beginning to shorten

191
00:30:00,560 --> 00:30:05,030
and a primeval sound
heralds the onset of autumn.

192
00:30:23,440 --> 00:30:26,870
Male red deer are starting their rut.

193
00:30:32,840 --> 00:30:35,990
The air is heavy with the scent of females.

194
00:30:47,840 --> 00:30:51,670
The rules are simple, winner takes all.

195
00:31:44,240 --> 00:31:48,750
Across the northern hemisphere,
the deciduous forests are changing.

196
00:31:49,600 --> 00:31:54,390
Leaves that have provided food and shelter
since the spring, are now shed.

197
00:31:59,480 --> 00:32:04,790
In the broadleaf forests of Russia,
winter is particularly severe.

198
00:32:10,160 --> 00:32:14,350
But there will always be some
who benefit from hardship.

199
00:32:18,760 --> 00:32:22,470
Black vultures scavenge
from the carcass of a seka deer

200
00:32:22,560 --> 00:32:25,430
that has died of cold or starvation.

201
00:32:25,520 --> 00:32:27,710
These endangered birds are visitors,

202
00:32:27,840 --> 00:32:32,790
they've come down from the north
to escape the even colder conditions in Siberia.

203
00:33:09,200 --> 00:33:13,590
An Amur leopard, the rarest cat on Earth.

204
00:33:14,640 --> 00:33:17,670
Winter is a difficult time for this hunter.

205
00:33:17,760 --> 00:33:21,430
There are no leaves for cover
and no young prey animals.

206
00:33:22,080 --> 00:33:27,390
This female has the added pressure
of having to provide for her one-year-old cub.

207
00:33:28,040 --> 00:33:32,310
It will be another 12 months
before he'll be able to fend for himself.

208
00:33:45,200 --> 00:33:48,390
The bickering vultures
have abandoned the carcass.

209
00:33:49,040 --> 00:33:51,950
It's a valuable discovery for the leopards.

210
00:33:57,200 --> 00:34:00,950
But the cub
doesn't share its mother's sense of urgency.

211
00:34:30,120 --> 00:34:36,030
The vultures have left behind plenty of good meat,
but it's stiff with frost.

212
00:34:38,720 --> 00:34:43,710
The mother works to open the hide
and make feeding a little easier for her cub.

213
00:34:55,360 --> 00:34:59,030
There are only 40 Amur leopards left in the wild

214
00:35:01,840 --> 00:35:04,190
and that number is still falling.

215
00:35:05,520 --> 00:35:10,150
The harshness of the winter here,
hinders their increase in numbers.

216
00:35:10,240 --> 00:35:14,390
It takes one of these females longer
to raise her young to independence

217
00:35:14,480 --> 00:35:16,870
than it does a leopard in Africa.

218
00:35:24,600 --> 00:35:28,670
If the mother can sustain her cub
for a few more weeks,

219
00:35:28,760 --> 00:35:33,550
spring will bring an increase in prey
and her task will lighten.

220
00:35:39,160 --> 00:35:42,670
For all the inhabitants of this seasonal forest,

221
00:35:42,760 --> 00:35:45,710
the long, cold wait is nearly over.

222
00:35:57,960 --> 00:36:01,790
Spring in a deciduous woodland is special.

223
00:36:05,840 --> 00:36:10,790
With no leaves overhead,
the rays of the sun strike the forest floor directly

224
00:36:10,880 --> 00:36:14,350
and their warmth rouses plants
from their winter sleep.

225
00:36:22,000 --> 00:36:24,350
The ground-living plants are in a hurry.

226
00:36:24,480 --> 00:36:28,830
Before long, the trees above will come into leaf
and steal their light.

227
00:36:38,760 --> 00:36:41,430
Their flowers decorate the forest floor

228
00:36:41,520 --> 00:36:45,830
as they advertise their sweet nectar
to the newly emerged insects.

229
00:37:03,200 --> 00:37:07,310
The spring blooms of the deciduous woodlands
have no equivalent

230
00:37:07,400 --> 00:37:11,270
in either the great conifer forests
or the tropicaljungles.

231
00:37:16,600 --> 00:37:20,310
Within a matter of weeks, the canopy has closed

232
00:37:20,400 --> 00:37:24,590
and only a few wheeling shafts of light
penetrate the woodland.

233
00:37:33,240 --> 00:37:38,070
In the tree tops,
the broad leaves rapidly expand to their full size

234
00:37:38,160 --> 00:37:41,190
to make the most of summer while it lasts.

235
00:37:47,600 --> 00:37:52,190
Then, after a few months,
the days begin to shorten again

236
00:37:52,280 --> 00:37:55,230
and the trees must shut down
and shed their leaves

237
00:37:55,320 --> 00:37:58,870
in preparation for the cold, dark time ahead.

238
00:38:03,880 --> 00:38:09,070
Great tracts of North America flush red
as the season progresses.

239
00:38:10,720 --> 00:38:17,030
The effect is so spectacular and so extensive
that it can be seen from space.

240
00:38:32,240 --> 00:38:37,710
The threat of winter frost
is not the only reason for trees to shed leaves.

241
00:38:42,480 --> 00:38:45,390
These forests stand in the tropics.

242
00:38:45,480 --> 00:38:48,190
Here, day length never changes.

243
00:38:48,280 --> 00:38:50,590
But the dry season is so severe

244
00:38:50,680 --> 00:38:53,670
that the trees can't afford to lose
the amount of water

245
00:38:53,760 --> 00:38:56,510
that would evaporate from their broad leaves,

246
00:38:56,600 --> 00:38:58,790
so the leaves must be shed.

247
00:39:16,280 --> 00:39:20,990
The forest resembles
a European woodland in midwinter

248
00:39:21,080 --> 00:39:25,670
but the heat is overpowering
and its inhabitants unfamiliar.

249
00:39:30,080 --> 00:39:35,270
For the creatures of India's teak forests
these are desperate times.

250
00:39:37,000 --> 00:39:39,270
But salvation is at hand.

251
00:39:39,360 --> 00:39:41,630
The mahua tree is about to bloom.

252
00:39:46,560 --> 00:39:50,270
Its flowers are full of liquid,
making them irresistible.

253
00:39:57,640 --> 00:40:01,830
The mahua is an oasis in a hot, dry desert.

254
00:40:12,280 --> 00:40:17,110
Those that fly or climb
are not the only ones to get a share.

255
00:40:20,920 --> 00:40:26,470
Chital deer follow the Langur monkeys,
collecting the flowers that fall.

256
00:40:32,560 --> 00:40:38,030
The monkeys welcome the deer,
for deer are unrivalled at spotting predators.

257
00:40:39,960 --> 00:40:43,950
If they are relaxed,
it must be safe to come down to the ground

258
00:40:44,040 --> 00:40:46,550
and gather the food that lies there.

259
00:40:56,880 --> 00:41:00,830
But it's not wise to travel far from the sentinels.

260
00:41:52,960 --> 00:41:56,670
Tropical Madagascar, the wet season.

261
00:42:03,680 --> 00:42:07,310
It's now that the baobab trees re-grow their leaves

262
00:42:07,440 --> 00:42:12,870
and collect water to store in their huge trunks
ready for the dry season ahead.

263
00:42:34,000 --> 00:42:37,470
The prehistoric shape of these trees
is rightly famous

264
00:42:37,560 --> 00:42:40,950
but few have ever witnessed
the baobab's real magic.

265
00:42:41,120 --> 00:42:45,030
For that happens at night
and high in the tree tops.

266
00:42:50,840 --> 00:42:57,030
Flush with water, the baobab prepares itself
for an unforgettable display.

267
00:43:13,920 --> 00:43:19,350
Once started, the foot-long flowers
can open fully in less than a minute.

268
00:44:02,480 --> 00:44:06,950
As the flowers open,
the creatures of the forest wake.

269
00:44:18,680 --> 00:44:23,030
The mouse lemurs have been hibernating
throughout the dry season.

270
00:44:23,120 --> 00:44:26,590
With the return of rains, it's time to get busy.

271
00:44:31,880 --> 00:44:36,070
A dozen share this tree-hole,
but there's plenty of room.

272
00:44:36,160 --> 00:44:40,350
The world's smallest primate
is no bigger than your hand.

273
00:44:45,960 --> 00:44:50,670
High in the branches above,
the baobab's nectar is starting to flow.

274
00:45:05,080 --> 00:45:12,030
A drink of this sugary, energy-packed liquid
is an ideal way for the lemurs to start their day.

275
00:45:16,240 --> 00:45:21,270
Liquid oozes from the flower's centre
and trickles down the petals.

276
00:45:37,200 --> 00:45:40,350
But the nectar is not intended for lemurs.

277
00:45:44,440 --> 00:45:50,230
These giant hawk moths are the drinkers
the tree needs to attract.

278
00:45:59,400 --> 00:46:02,550
As they sip, moving from tree to tree,

279
00:46:02,640 --> 00:46:06,510
so they transfer pollen and fertilise the flowers.

280
00:46:20,520 --> 00:46:24,670
Nectar was an excellent first course for lemurs,

281
00:46:24,760 --> 00:46:27,390
but moths are the main dish.

282
00:46:29,040 --> 00:46:34,350
The moths are very important to the lemurs
for they will replenish the fat reserves

283
00:46:34,440 --> 00:46:37,870
that the lemurs need
to survive the barren dry season.

284
00:46:46,160 --> 00:46:49,590
The lemurs might seem to be a pest
for the baobab,

285
00:46:49,720 --> 00:46:55,430
they kill its pollinators and rob it of its nectar
but they do give something in return.

286
00:46:55,800 --> 00:47:01,230
For as they wrestle with the moths,
their fur inevitably becomes dusted with pollen.

287
00:47:01,320 --> 00:47:04,310
So they too become pollinators.

288
00:47:26,240 --> 00:47:32,550
As the alternation of wet and dry seasons
brings change to some tropical forests,

289
00:47:32,920 --> 00:47:38,910
so the progression of summer to winter
dictates life in more temperate regions.

290
00:47:47,680 --> 00:47:51,150
Whether trees have needles or broad leaves,

291
00:47:51,240 --> 00:47:55,150
it is their ability to survive annual change

292
00:47:55,240 --> 00:47:59,590
that has enabled them to cover
such vast areas of the Earth

293
00:47:59,680 --> 00:48:04,310
and made the seasonal forests
the greatest forests of all.

