1
00:00:31,160 --> 00:00:34,710
Only 3% of the water on our planet is fresh.

2
00:00:37,560 --> 00:00:41,270
Yet these precious waters are rich with surprise.

3
00:00:54,080 --> 00:00:58,990
All life on land is ultimately
dependant upon fresh water.

4
00:01:29,600 --> 00:01:32,710
The mysterious tepuis of Venezuela,

5
00:01:34,600 --> 00:01:38,750
isolated mountain plateaus
rising high above the jungle.

6
00:01:48,560 --> 00:01:53,430
This was the inspiration
for Arthur Conan Doyle's Lost World,

7
00:01:53,520 --> 00:01:56,310
an imagined prehistoric land.

8
00:02:02,680 --> 00:02:07,230
Here, strange towers of sandstone
have been sculptured over the millennia

9
00:02:07,320 --> 00:02:10,310
by battering wind and torrential rain.

10
00:02:23,280 --> 00:02:27,430
Moisture, rising as water vapour
from the surface of the sea,

11
00:02:27,520 --> 00:02:30,110
is blown inland by wind.

12
00:02:42,200 --> 00:02:45,870
On reaching mountains,
the moist air is forced upwards

13
00:02:45,960 --> 00:02:49,390
and as it cools, it condenses into cloud

14
00:02:49,480 --> 00:02:53,750
and finally rain, the source of all fresh water.

15
00:03:04,520 --> 00:03:08,950
There is a tropical downpour here
almost every day of the year.

16
00:03:20,520 --> 00:03:25,310
Fresh water's journey starts here,
high in the mountains.

17
00:03:41,520 --> 00:03:44,670
Growing from humble streams to mighty rivers,

18
00:03:44,760 --> 00:03:47,950
it will travel hundreds of miles to the sea.

19
00:04:25,040 --> 00:04:29,150
Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world.

20
00:04:43,400 --> 00:04:48,110
Its waters drop unbroken for almost 1, 000 metres.

21
00:04:57,400 --> 00:04:59,470
Such is the height of these falls,

22
00:04:59,600 --> 00:05:03,630
that long before the water reaches the base
in the Devil's Canyon,

23
00:05:03,720 --> 00:05:06,790
it's blown away as a fine mist.

24
00:05:38,080 --> 00:05:42,550
In their upper reaches,
mountain streams are full of energy.

25
00:05:45,800 --> 00:05:51,710
Streams join to form rivers,
building in power, creating rapids.

26
00:06:01,800 --> 00:06:06,990
The water here is cold,
low in nutrients but high in oxygen.

27
00:06:11,040 --> 00:06:15,510
The few creatures that live in the torrent
have to hang on for dear life.

28
00:06:18,120 --> 00:06:21,070
Invertebrates dominate these upper reaches.

29
00:06:21,200 --> 00:06:24,910
The hellgrammite,
its body flattened to reduce drag,

30
00:06:25,000 --> 00:06:28,910
has bushy gills to extract oxygen from the current.

31
00:06:33,400 --> 00:06:37,190
Black fly larvae anchor themselves
with a ring of hooks.

32
00:06:41,160 --> 00:06:46,750
But if these become unstuck,
they're still held by a silken safety line.

33
00:06:59,680 --> 00:07:03,310
There are advantages to life in the fast stream.

34
00:07:03,400 --> 00:07:07,150
Bamboo shrimps can just sit
and sift out passing particles

35
00:07:07,240 --> 00:07:09,310
with their fan-like forearms.

36
00:07:28,360 --> 00:07:32,150
Usually these mountain streams
only provide enough food

37
00:07:32,240 --> 00:07:35,030
for small animals to survive,

38
00:07:35,120 --> 00:07:41,350
but with the spring melt here in Japan,
monsters stir in their dens.

39
00:07:49,520 --> 00:07:53,790
Giant salamanders, the world's largest amphibian,

40
00:07:53,920 --> 00:07:56,150
almost two metres long.

41
00:07:59,640 --> 00:08:03,470
They're the only large predator in these icy waters.

42
00:08:07,800 --> 00:08:10,230
They begin their hunt at night.

43
00:08:25,120 --> 00:08:29,470
These salamanders
have an exceptionally slow metabolism.

44
00:08:29,560 --> 00:08:33,190
Living up to 80 years, they grow into giants.

45
00:08:50,000 --> 00:08:55,630
The fish they hunt are scarce
and salamanders have poor eyesight.

46
00:08:58,560 --> 00:09:05,030
But sensory nodes on their head and body
detect the slightest changes in water pressure.

47
00:09:16,240 --> 00:09:21,110
Free from competition,
these giants can dine alone.

48
00:09:34,320 --> 00:09:37,950
Pickings are usually thin for the salamanders,

49
00:09:38,080 --> 00:09:43,750
but every year some of the world's high rivers
are crowded by millions of visitors.

50
00:09:51,400 --> 00:09:53,590
The salmon have arrived.

51
00:10:01,240 --> 00:10:05,590
This is the world's largest
freshwater fish migration.

52
00:10:09,720 --> 00:10:11,550
Across the northern hemisphere,

53
00:10:11,640 --> 00:10:15,030
salmon, returning from the ocean
to their spawning grounds,

54
00:10:15,120 --> 00:10:18,390
battle their way for hundreds of miles upstream.

55
00:10:23,560 --> 00:10:27,910
Up here there are fewer predators
to eat their eggs and fry.

56
00:10:55,320 --> 00:10:56,830
A grizzly bear.

57
00:10:59,720 --> 00:11:04,110
From famine to feast, he's spoilt for choice.

58
00:11:10,640 --> 00:11:13,470
This Canadian bear is very special.

59
00:11:13,560 --> 00:11:16,710
He's learnt to dive for his dinner.

60
00:11:30,840 --> 00:11:34,710
But catching salmon in deep water
is not that easy,

61
00:11:34,800 --> 00:11:37,430
and the cubs have lots to learn.

62
00:12:14,000 --> 00:12:19,910
The annual arrival of spawning salmon brings
huge quantities of food into these high rivers

63
00:12:20,000 --> 00:12:22,670
that normally struggle to support much life.

64
00:12:35,680 --> 00:12:37,790
Although relatively lifeless,

65
00:12:37,880 --> 00:12:41,230
the power of these upland rivers
to shape the landscape

66
00:12:41,320 --> 00:12:44,630
is greater than any other stage in a river's life.

67
00:12:46,960 --> 00:12:51,670
Driven by gravity,
they're the most erosive forces on the planet.

68
00:12:56,200 --> 00:12:58,710
For the past five million years,

69
00:12:58,800 --> 00:13:03,590
Arizona's Colorado River
has eaten away at the desert sandstone

70
00:13:03,680 --> 00:13:06,430
to create a gigantic canyon.

71
00:13:17,120 --> 00:13:19,150
It's over a mile deep

72
00:13:19,240 --> 00:13:23,590
and at its widest, it's 17 miles across.

73
00:13:36,960 --> 00:13:38,550
The Grand Canyon.

74
00:13:58,080 --> 00:14:02,670
This river has cut
the world's longest canyon system,

75
00:14:02,840 --> 00:14:07,270
a 1, 000 mile scar clearly visible from space.

76
00:14:33,280 --> 00:14:36,070
As rivers leave the mountains behind,

77
00:14:36,160 --> 00:14:40,150
they gradually warm
and begin to support more life.

78
00:14:49,000 --> 00:14:53,630
Indian rivers are home
to the world's most social otter.

79
00:14:54,880 --> 00:14:59,630
Smooth-coated otters
form family groups up to 17 strong.

80
00:15:10,760 --> 00:15:14,470
Group rubbing not only refreshes their coats,

81
00:15:14,560 --> 00:15:17,310
but strengthens social bonds.

82
00:15:26,840 --> 00:15:31,190
When it comes to fishing,
there is real strength in numbers.

83
00:15:44,120 --> 00:15:48,150
Fishing practice begins
when the cubs are four months old.

84
00:16:06,800 --> 00:16:12,710
Only the adults have the speed and agility
needed to make a catch.

85
00:16:49,600 --> 00:16:53,790
Adults share their catches
with their squabbling cubs.

86
00:17:04,720 --> 00:17:06,950
Most otters are solitary,

87
00:17:07,040 --> 00:17:11,510
but these rich, warm waters
can support large family groups

88
00:17:12,440 --> 00:17:14,470
and even bigger predators.

89
00:17:33,440 --> 00:17:38,710
Mugger crocodiles, four metres long,
could easily take a single otter.

90
00:18:04,480 --> 00:18:06,950
But confident in their gangs,

91
00:18:07,040 --> 00:18:10,910
the otters will actively harass these great reptiles.

92
00:18:28,040 --> 00:18:31,030
Team play wins the day.

93
00:18:41,400 --> 00:18:46,110
The Mara River,
snaking across the plains of East Africa.

94
00:18:48,520 --> 00:18:53,510
As the land flattens out,
rivers slow down and lose their destructive power.

95
00:18:54,680 --> 00:19:00,630
Now they're carrying heavy loads of sediment
that stains their waters brown.

96
00:19:13,200 --> 00:19:16,270
Lines of wildebeest are on the march.

97
00:19:21,320 --> 00:19:24,710
Each year, nearly two million animals migrate

98
00:19:24,800 --> 00:19:29,230
across the Serengeti Plains
in search of fresh, green pastures.

99
00:19:30,040 --> 00:19:31,670
For these thirsty herds,

100
00:19:31,760 --> 00:19:35,230
the rivers are not only
a vital source of drinking water

101
00:19:35,320 --> 00:19:38,110
but also dangerous obstacles.

102
00:19:57,000 --> 00:20:03,270
This is one of the largest concentrations
of Nile crocodiles in Africa,

103
00:20:03,360 --> 00:20:06,910
giants that grow over five metres long.

104
00:20:22,680 --> 00:20:26,150
From memory, the crocodiles
know the wildebeest are coming

105
00:20:26,240 --> 00:20:28,670
and gather in anticipation.

106
00:21:31,320 --> 00:21:35,270
The crocodile's jaws snap tight like a steel trap.

107
00:21:35,360 --> 00:21:38,430
Once they have a hold, they never let go.

108
00:21:50,880 --> 00:21:54,830
It took over an hour to drown this full-grown bull.

109
00:22:03,400 --> 00:22:08,830
To surprise their prey,
crocodiles must strike with lightning speed.

110
00:22:33,400 --> 00:22:39,310
Here, only the narrowest line
separates life from death.

111
00:23:14,760 --> 00:23:17,430
Most rivers drain into the sea,

112
00:23:17,520 --> 00:23:21,590
but some end their journey in vast lakes.

113
00:23:24,600 --> 00:23:30,230
Worldwide, lakes hold 20 times more fresh water
than all the rivers.

114
00:23:33,000 --> 00:23:37,670
The East African Rift Valley
holds three of the world's largest,

115
00:23:37,760 --> 00:23:41,710
Malawi, Tanganyika and Victoria.

116
00:23:43,680 --> 00:23:48,510
Lake Malawi, the smallest of the three,
is still bigger than Wales.

117
00:24:01,520 --> 00:24:06,990
Its tropical waters teem with more fish species
than any other lake.

118
00:24:07,960 --> 00:24:11,270
There are 850 different cichlids alone,

119
00:24:11,360 --> 00:24:14,830
all of which evolved from just one single ancestor

120
00:24:14,920 --> 00:24:17,710
isolated here thousands of years ago.

121
00:24:32,280 --> 00:24:36,350
These two-metre wide craters are fish-made.

122
00:24:46,080 --> 00:24:52,030
Fastidiously maintained by the males,
these bowers are courtship arenas.

123
00:25:04,400 --> 00:25:07,670
Cichlids are caring parents.

124
00:25:11,520 --> 00:25:15,990
Brooding young in the mouth
is a very effective way of protecting them.

125
00:25:17,880 --> 00:25:20,550
This lake can be a dangerous place.

126
00:25:33,080 --> 00:25:39,030
After dark, predatory dolphin fish emerge
from their daytime lairs among the rocks.

127
00:25:44,480 --> 00:25:49,390
Like packs of sharks,
they're on the prowl for sleeping cichlids.

128
00:25:56,680 --> 00:26:01,750
In the darkness, these electric fish
hunt by detecting distortions

129
00:26:01,840 --> 00:26:05,110
in the electric field
they create around their bodies.

130
00:26:23,560 --> 00:26:27,550
Any cichlid that ventures out will be snapped up.

131
00:26:48,560 --> 00:26:54,550
The floor of Lake Malawi
drops 700 metres into an abyss.

132
00:27:02,120 --> 00:27:03,990
Here in this dead zone

133
00:27:04,080 --> 00:27:08,190
the larvae of lake fly midges
hide out away from predators.

134
00:27:11,800 --> 00:27:17,710
In the rainy season, they balloon up to the surface
and undergo a magical transformation.

135
00:27:27,400 --> 00:27:31,350
At dawn, the first adult midges start to break out.

136
00:27:35,840 --> 00:27:39,870
Soon, millions upon millions
of newly-hatched lake flies

137
00:27:39,960 --> 00:27:41,590
are taking to the wing.

138
00:27:51,960 --> 00:27:56,870
Early explorers told tales of lakes
that smoked as if on fire.

139
00:27:59,000 --> 00:28:02,670
But these spiralling columns,
hundreds of metres high,

140
00:28:02,760 --> 00:28:04,430
are mating flies.

141
00:28:18,720 --> 00:28:22,870
Once the flies have mated,
they will all drop to the water surface,

142
00:28:22,960 --> 00:28:25,310
release their eggs and die.

143
00:28:35,280 --> 00:28:38,350
Malawi may look like an inland sea,

144
00:28:38,440 --> 00:28:42,230
but it's dwarfed by the world's largest lake.

145
00:28:43,600 --> 00:28:46,630
Baikal in eastern Siberia.

146
00:28:57,280 --> 00:29:00,110
Four hundred miles long and over a mile deep,

147
00:29:00,240 --> 00:29:06,310
Baikal contains one-fifth of all the fresh water
found in our planet's lakes and rivers.

148
00:29:09,720 --> 00:29:15,310
For five months of the year,
it's sealed by an ice sheet over a metre thick.

149
00:29:30,840 --> 00:29:33,590
Baikal is the oldest lake in the world

150
00:29:33,680 --> 00:29:38,870
and despite the harsh conditions,
life flourishes here in isolation.

151
00:29:40,760 --> 00:29:44,350
80% of its species are found
nowhere else on Earth,

152
00:29:44,440 --> 00:29:48,070
including the world's only freshwater seal.

153
00:29:55,000 --> 00:29:58,870
With this seal
and its marine-like forests of sponges,

154
00:29:58,960 --> 00:30:02,150
Baikal seems more like an ocean than a lake.

155
00:30:21,240 --> 00:30:27,070
There are shrimp-like crustaceans,
giant amphipods as large as mice.

156
00:30:33,160 --> 00:30:36,150
They are the key scavengers in this lake.

157
00:30:36,440 --> 00:30:41,590
The water here is just too cold for the bacteria
that normally decompose the dead.

158
00:30:55,840 --> 00:31:01,710
Most rivers do not end in lakes
but continue their journey to the sea.

159
00:31:07,080 --> 00:31:11,470
The planet's indisputable super river
is the Amazon.

160
00:31:13,840 --> 00:31:19,590
It carries as much water
as the next top 10 biggest rivers combined.

161
00:31:22,840 --> 00:31:28,590
Rising in the Peruvian Andes,
its main trunk flows eastwards across Brazil.

162
00:31:29,040 --> 00:31:33,270
On its way,
the system drains a third of South America.

163
00:31:34,960 --> 00:31:41,190
Eventually, over 4, 000 miles from its source,
it empties into the Atlantic Ocean.

164
00:31:49,120 --> 00:31:53,350
The Amazon transports a billion tonnes
of sediment a year,

165
00:31:53,440 --> 00:31:57,230
sediment clearly visible
at the mixing of the waters,

166
00:31:57,320 --> 00:32:02,350
where one massive tributary, the Rio Negro,
flows into the main river.

167
00:32:08,680 --> 00:32:11,230
Its waters are wonderfully rich.

168
00:32:11,320 --> 00:32:15,510
To date, over 3, 000 species
of their fish have been described,

169
00:32:15,600 --> 00:32:18,590
more than in the whole of the Atlantic Ocean.

170
00:32:46,360 --> 00:32:52,270
The Amazon is so large and rich in fish
that it can support freshwater dolphins.

171
00:32:52,600 --> 00:32:56,550
These botos are huge, 2.5 metres long.

172
00:32:59,960 --> 00:33:04,550
In these murky waters,
they rely on sonar to navigate and hunt.

173
00:33:22,400 --> 00:33:26,550
They work together to drive shoals of fish
into the shallows.

174
00:34:28,200 --> 00:34:30,190
Botos are highly social

175
00:34:30,280 --> 00:34:34,270
and in the breeding season,
there is stiff competition for mates.

176
00:34:35,080 --> 00:34:38,270
The males hold court in a unique way.

177
00:34:49,560 --> 00:34:54,950
They pick up rocks in their jaws
and flaunt them to their attending females.

178
00:34:59,680 --> 00:35:03,870
Maybe each male is trying to show
how strong and dexterous he is

179
00:35:03,960 --> 00:35:08,590
and that he therefore is the best father
a female could have for her young.

180
00:35:19,920 --> 00:35:23,390
Successful displays lead to mating.

181
00:35:38,200 --> 00:35:40,950
Even for giant rivers like the Amazon,

182
00:35:41,040 --> 00:35:45,710
the journey to the sea
is not always smooth or uninterrupted.

183
00:36:13,320 --> 00:36:17,590
Iguaçú Falls,
on the border of Brazil and Argentina,

184
00:36:17,720 --> 00:36:23,350
is one of the widest waterfalls in the world,
1 .5 miles across.

185
00:36:29,880 --> 00:36:35,110
In flood, 13 million litres of water
spill over every second.

186
00:37:21,200 --> 00:37:24,630
All the world's great broad waterfalls,

187
00:37:24,720 --> 00:37:28,310
Victoria, Niagara and here, Iguaçú,

188
00:37:28,400 --> 00:37:31,910
are only found in the lower courses of their rivers.

189
00:37:40,160 --> 00:37:41,830
In their final stages,

190
00:37:41,920 --> 00:37:46,350
rivers broaden and flow wearily
across their flat flood plains.

191
00:37:47,520 --> 00:37:49,710
Each wet season here in Brazil,

192
00:37:49,800 --> 00:37:55,110
the Paraná river overflows its banks
and floods an area the size of England.

193
00:37:59,120 --> 00:38:02,830
The Pantanal, the world's largest wetland.

194
00:38:10,160 --> 00:38:14,710
In these slow-flowing waters,
aquatic plants flourish,

195
00:38:14,840 --> 00:38:19,670
like the Victoria Giant Water Lily,
with leaves two-metres across.

196
00:38:42,360 --> 00:38:46,630
These underwater forests
are nursery grounds for fish.

197
00:38:48,720 --> 00:38:53,510
Over 300 species breed here,
including red-bellied piranha.

198
00:38:58,320 --> 00:39:01,990
And other predators, like the spectacled caiman.

199
00:39:28,320 --> 00:39:35,070
Ripening fig trees, overhanging the water's edge,
provide welcome food for shoals of hungry fish.

200
00:39:42,320 --> 00:39:48,270
The commotion attracts dorado,
known locally as the river tiger.

201
00:39:55,720 --> 00:40:00,670
They patrol the feeding shoals
looking for a chance to strike.

202
00:40:37,440 --> 00:40:42,030
And waiting in the wings,
ready to pick off any injured fish,

203
00:40:42,120 --> 00:40:44,150
are the piranhas.

204
00:40:55,880 --> 00:40:58,750
A feeding frenzy quickly develops.

205
00:41:16,400 --> 00:41:20,350
Piranha can strip a fish to the bone in minutes.

206
00:41:27,040 --> 00:41:32,870
Great numbers of fish
sustain vast flocks of water birds.

207
00:41:35,840 --> 00:41:40,830
The roseate spoonbill
is just one of the 650 bird species

208
00:41:40,920 --> 00:41:42,910
found in the Pantanal.

209
00:41:49,960 --> 00:41:54,990
They nest alongside woodstorks
in colonies thousands strong.

210
00:42:23,160 --> 00:42:28,790
Spectacled caiman linger below,
waiting for a meal to fall out of the sky.

211
00:43:24,320 --> 00:43:26,510
When rivers finally reach the sea,

212
00:43:26,600 --> 00:43:30,670
they slow down,
release their sediment and build deltas.

213
00:43:32,880 --> 00:43:36,430
In Bangladesh,
the Ganges and Brahmaputra rivers

214
00:43:36,520 --> 00:43:39,070
join to form the world's biggest.

215
00:43:41,640 --> 00:43:47,870
Every year, almost 2,000 million tonnes
of sediment eroded from the Himalayas

216
00:43:47,960 --> 00:43:50,030
is delivered to the ocean.

217
00:43:54,920 --> 00:43:59,230
At the delta's mouth,
the largest mangrove forest in the world,

218
00:43:59,320 --> 00:44:01,030
the Sunderbans.

219
00:44:07,080 --> 00:44:11,350
These extraordinary forests
spring up throughout the tropics

220
00:44:11,440 --> 00:44:15,150
in these tidal zones where rivers meet the sea.

221
00:44:25,000 --> 00:44:28,390
Crab-eating macaques are mangrove specialists.

222
00:44:32,680 --> 00:44:38,310
In Indonesia, these monkeys
have adopted a unique amphibious lifestyle.

223
00:44:46,680 --> 00:44:49,110
They fish out fallen food.

224
00:45:12,120 --> 00:45:17,110
The troop also uses the waters to cool off
during the heat of the day.

225
00:45:22,360 --> 00:45:27,030
But the channels are also the playground
for restless young macaques.

226
00:45:33,240 --> 00:45:37,150
Some of the young have even taken
to underwater swimming.

227
00:45:42,840 --> 00:45:48,550
They can stay down for more than 30 seconds
and appear to do this just for fun.

228
00:46:00,880 --> 00:46:04,790
Yet these swimming skills acquired during play

229
00:46:04,880 --> 00:46:09,830
will certainly be useful later in life
in these flooded mangrove forests.

230
00:46:18,600 --> 00:46:25,110
In cooler climes, mud laid down in estuaries
is colonised by salt marsh grasses,

231
00:46:25,360 --> 00:46:29,030
and form one of the most productive habitats
on the planet.

232
00:46:58,120 --> 00:47:02,350
Four hundred thousand greater snow geese
flock to the estuaries

233
00:47:02,440 --> 00:47:05,230
along the Atlantic coast of the United States

234
00:47:05,320 --> 00:47:09,270
to rest and refuel on their long migratory journeys.

235
00:47:45,440 --> 00:47:48,750
This is the end of the rivers' journey.

236
00:47:48,840 --> 00:47:53,190
Collectively, they've worn down mountains
and carried them to the sea.

237
00:47:53,320 --> 00:47:54,870
And all along the way,

238
00:47:54,960 --> 00:47:59,150
their fresh water has brought life
in abundance to planet Earth.

