1
00:00:31,400 --> 00:00:36,430
Our planet's continents
are fringed by shallow seas.

2
00:00:38,200 --> 00:00:42,950
Rarely more than 200 metres deep,
they lie on the continental shelves,

3
00:00:43,040 --> 00:00:46,070
which may stretch sometimes
for hundreds of miles

4
00:00:46,160 --> 00:00:50,150
before the sea floor drops
into deeper, darker waters.

5
00:00:56,040 --> 00:01:00,670
Altogether, they constitute
a mere 8% of the world's oceans,

6
00:01:00,760 --> 00:01:05,150
but they contain the vast majority
of its marine life.

7
00:01:38,480 --> 00:01:43,710
A male humpback whale sings to attract a mate.

8
00:02:04,360 --> 00:02:08,270
The whales have just returned
to their breeding grounds

9
00:02:08,360 --> 00:02:11,030
in the shallow seas of the tropics.

10
00:02:17,960 --> 00:02:21,910
The calf is no more than a few weeks old.

11
00:02:27,040 --> 00:02:31,470
Despite being three metres long
and weighing nearly a ton,

12
00:02:31,560 --> 00:02:34,070
he is nonetheless vulnerable.

13
00:02:38,120 --> 00:02:42,550
But his mother watches over him
and, as he begins to tire,

14
00:02:42,680 --> 00:02:47,710
she supports him close to the surface
so that he can breathe more easily.

15
00:03:11,080 --> 00:03:15,790
These shallows around the equator
are excellent nurseries.

16
00:03:15,880 --> 00:03:20,390
They're warm, calm
and contain very few predators.

17
00:03:23,320 --> 00:03:28,150
The playful calf is now drinking
500 litres of milk a day.

18
00:03:28,720 --> 00:03:34,550
But his mother must starve.
There is nothing for her to eat here.

19
00:03:41,600 --> 00:03:47,510
Like many tropical shallow seas,
these crystal-clear waters are virtually lifeless.

20
00:03:47,600 --> 00:03:49,830
They receive year-round sunlight,

21
00:03:49,920 --> 00:03:53,630
but they lack the nutrients
essential for the growth of plankton.

22
00:03:54,640 --> 00:03:57,790
The mother will be trapped here
for the next five months

23
00:03:57,920 --> 00:04:03,670
until her calf is strong enough to make
the journey to the feeding grounds near the poles.

24
00:04:26,880 --> 00:04:30,870
Coral reefs are oases in a watery desert.

25
00:04:31,960 --> 00:04:34,710
Most tropical shallows are barren,

26
00:04:34,840 --> 00:04:40,390
but these coral havens contain one quarter
of all the marine life on our planet.

27
00:04:59,440 --> 00:05:05,630
Reefs are the work of polyps,
tiny colonial animals like minute sea anemones.

28
00:05:06,040 --> 00:05:11,710
Yet the Great Barrier Reef is so big
it can be seen from the moon.

29
00:05:17,760 --> 00:05:22,990
It's actually 2, 000 separate reefs
that together form a barrier

30
00:05:23,080 --> 00:05:28,430
stretching for over 1, 000 miles
along Australia's northeastern coast.

31
00:05:31,680 --> 00:05:35,670
Despite its vast size, this reef does not contain

32
00:05:35,760 --> 00:05:39,190
the greatest variety of marine life on the planet.

33
00:05:40,640 --> 00:05:44,750
For that, one must travel north to Indonesia.

34
00:06:11,240 --> 00:06:16,870
There are individual reefs in Indonesia
that contain almost as many kinds of fish

35
00:06:16,960 --> 00:06:20,110
as live in the whole of the Caribbean.

36
00:06:21,360 --> 00:06:24,950
There are also 10 times
the number of coral species.

37
00:06:28,080 --> 00:06:33,550
Corals thrive in these waters
with the help of microscopic plants, algae,

38
00:06:33,640 --> 00:06:36,590
that grow within the tissues of the polyps.

39
00:06:42,480 --> 00:06:47,590
And the polyps feed by snaring
passing morsels with their tentacles.

40
00:06:59,840 --> 00:07:05,910
At night, the algae are inactive,
but then the polyps put out even more tentacles.

41
00:07:06,080 --> 00:07:09,510
So coral, in effect, feeds around the clock.

42
00:07:26,760 --> 00:07:32,870
This well-balanced alliance
brings benefits to both polyps and algae,

43
00:07:33,000 --> 00:07:37,710
and between them,
they turn the barren seas into rich gardens.

44
00:07:47,960 --> 00:07:54,950
The Indonesian reefs contain such a variety of life
because they lie at a giant crossroads.

45
00:07:55,040 --> 00:08:00,790
This is the meeting place for different seas,
the Indian Ocean and the Pacific.

46
00:08:03,960 --> 00:08:07,190
Here, everything demands a closer look.

47
00:08:07,480 --> 00:08:12,550
On the surface of this sea fan,
there are two polyps that are not polyps.

48
00:08:13,240 --> 00:08:16,910
They're pygmy seahorses, the world's smallest,

49
00:08:17,000 --> 00:08:19,270
less than two centimetres high.

50
00:08:31,560 --> 00:08:37,310
They are males,
settling a territorial dispute by head-butting.

51
00:08:45,960 --> 00:08:48,150
An electric flash?

52
00:08:49,440 --> 00:08:52,950
No, the display of a file clam.

53
00:08:58,000 --> 00:09:02,190
Perhaps this extraordinary pulsation
of the clam's fleshy mantle

54
00:09:02,320 --> 00:09:07,950
is a warning to frighten away nibbling fish,
but no one really knows.

55
00:09:22,040 --> 00:09:26,630
And there are snakes here, too. Lots of them.

56
00:09:31,880 --> 00:09:35,190
These are banded sea kraits.

57
00:09:35,560 --> 00:09:40,430
They lay their eggs on land
but they hunt here in the water.

58
00:09:44,960 --> 00:09:48,710
They're too slow to catch fish in a straight chase,

59
00:09:48,800 --> 00:09:53,230
so they seek prey that is hiding
in the nooks and crannies of the coral.

60
00:09:55,760 --> 00:09:59,990
Their bite is highly venomous
and paralyses their victims.

61
00:10:04,800 --> 00:10:09,230
And on this reef, the snakes do not hunt alone.

62
00:10:14,960 --> 00:10:20,150
Shoals of yellow goatfish and trevally
are seeking similar prey,

63
00:10:20,240 --> 00:10:22,990
and they attract the snakes' attention.

64
00:10:23,120 --> 00:10:27,950
As one group of hunters searches the reef,
they are joined by the other.

65
00:10:36,240 --> 00:10:40,550
At least 30 snakes have now joined the caravan.

66
00:10:46,240 --> 00:10:52,470
The big fish scare the prey into cracks
and there the snakes can catch them.

67
00:10:53,000 --> 00:10:54,990
And anything fleeing from the kraits

68
00:10:55,080 --> 00:10:58,790
will swim straight into the mouths
of the waiting trevally.

69
00:10:59,760 --> 00:11:02,110
There's nowhere to hide.

70
00:11:07,200 --> 00:11:12,750
As the raiders scour the reef,
more and more snakes join the hunt.

71
00:11:34,080 --> 00:11:39,110
This cooperation between snakes and fish,
spectacular though it is,

72
00:11:39,200 --> 00:11:41,030
has only recently been observed,

73
00:11:41,120 --> 00:11:45,430
for it only happens
on the most remote reefs in Indonesia.

74
00:11:54,560 --> 00:11:58,510
Perhaps such hunting alliances
were once a common sight,

75
00:11:58,640 --> 00:12:04,590
but today no more than 6%
of Indonesia's reefs are in their pristine state.

76
00:12:31,720 --> 00:12:35,790
Beyond the coral
stretches a world of shifting sand.

77
00:12:36,880 --> 00:12:43,270
Out there, with nowhere to hide,
survival is not easy and camouflage can be crucial.

78
00:12:46,160 --> 00:12:50,470
If this wasn't moving,
you might think it was a shell or a rock.

79
00:12:50,560 --> 00:12:53,070
In fact, it's an octopus.

80
00:12:54,800 --> 00:12:59,190
A gurnard.
Its huge pectoral fins disguise its shape.

81
00:12:59,680 --> 00:13:03,910
And they can also help in clearing away sand
when searching for food.

82
00:13:08,240 --> 00:13:11,070
The jawfish hides underground.

83
00:13:13,480 --> 00:13:17,550
The wonderpus octopus, on the other hand,
has such a powerful bite

84
00:13:17,640 --> 00:13:23,030
that it has a special warning display
to tell others to keep out of its way.

85
00:13:34,000 --> 00:13:40,590
Here and there, plants manage to take root
and they are cropped by green turtles.

86
00:13:41,200 --> 00:13:46,110
Seagrasses are the only flowering plants
that have managed to grow in the sea.

87
00:13:46,200 --> 00:13:48,790
Although they put out a few ribbon-like leaves,

88
00:13:48,880 --> 00:13:53,150
they produce very extensive networks
of fleshy stems, rhizomes,

89
00:13:53,240 --> 00:13:55,510
that are buried in the sand.

90
00:14:02,200 --> 00:14:07,550
At their lushest, they can transform the seabed
into an underwater meadow.

91
00:14:08,800 --> 00:14:14,550
The largest expanse grows in the shallow waters
of Shark Bay in Western Australia.

92
00:14:17,280 --> 00:14:22,950
These vast aquatic grasslands
stretch for 1, 500 square miles.

93
00:14:23,040 --> 00:14:25,670
And like terrestrial prairies,

94
00:14:25,760 --> 00:14:29,870
they support herds of grazers, dugongs.

95
00:14:43,080 --> 00:14:46,630
Dugongs are the largest herbivores in the sea.

96
00:14:46,720 --> 00:14:49,550
They can be three metres long
and weigh half a ton,

97
00:14:49,640 --> 00:14:53,750
and they eat nothing but seagrass,
mostly the fleshy rhizomes,

98
00:14:53,840 --> 00:14:56,870
which they excavate with their mobile lips.

99
00:15:11,560 --> 00:15:17,750
A herd can clear a patch of seagrass
the size of a football pitch in a single day.

100
00:15:41,440 --> 00:15:47,750
Food is not evenly distributed in the tropical
shallow seas and it can take a lot of finding.

101
00:15:48,200 --> 00:15:53,910
But bottlenose dolphins are inquisitive,
energetic and very intelligent

102
00:15:54,000 --> 00:15:57,470
and they have discovered a shoal of bait fish.

103
00:16:04,920 --> 00:16:09,950
Together they ride a wave,
using it to carry them into the shallows

104
00:16:10,040 --> 00:16:13,630
and there it will be easier to make the catch.

105
00:16:39,520 --> 00:16:45,190
In Western Australia, these dolphins
have taken on an even tougher challenge.

106
00:16:46,360 --> 00:16:52,630
The fish have taken refuge close to the beach
where the water is only a few centimetres deep.

107
00:16:56,520 --> 00:17:01,870
Tail-slapping is a method
dolphins often use to stun their prey,

108
00:17:01,960 --> 00:17:05,350
but it doesn't seem to work here.

109
00:17:14,120 --> 00:17:19,070
The fish are tantalisingly close,
but they're still out of reach.

110
00:17:19,160 --> 00:17:22,710
So the dolphins try another technique.

111
00:17:27,000 --> 00:17:31,510
Vigorously pumping their tails,
they work up some speed

112
00:17:31,600 --> 00:17:34,590
and then they hydroplane.

113
00:18:01,120 --> 00:18:06,790
Their momentum carries them right through
the shallowest waters and onto the fish.

114
00:18:17,480 --> 00:18:21,590
Now they're in real danger of being stranded.

115
00:18:21,680 --> 00:18:24,670
But fortune favours the brave.

116
00:18:32,280 --> 00:18:35,590
Younger dolphins lie alongside, watching.

117
00:18:35,680 --> 00:18:41,430
But, so far, only eight individuals here
have mastered this daring technique.

118
00:19:30,400 --> 00:19:35,830
Although most life in tropical waters
is concentrated around the coral reefs

119
00:19:35,920 --> 00:19:41,030
and the seagrass meadows,
there are some spectacular exceptions.

120
00:19:47,040 --> 00:19:51,030
The desert of Bahrain seems a very unlikely place

121
00:19:51,120 --> 00:19:54,670
to find a crowded, bustling colony of seabirds.

122
00:19:55,240 --> 00:20:00,990
But every year,
100, 000 Socotra Cormorants gather here to breed.

123
00:20:07,880 --> 00:20:14,310
It's swelteringly hot and only vigorous panting
can prevent the birds from fatal overheating.

124
00:20:15,360 --> 00:20:18,830
This hardly seems a good place to rear young.

125
00:20:20,720 --> 00:20:24,270
But at least
there are no land-based predators here.

126
00:20:24,840 --> 00:20:28,430
The only source of trouble
is likely to be the neighbours.

127
00:20:28,520 --> 00:20:32,670
So each nest is built just beyond pecking reach.

128
00:20:47,840 --> 00:20:50,070
But what about food?

129
00:20:50,160 --> 00:20:54,510
There's only bare sand
and the warm shallow sea beyond.

130
00:20:54,640 --> 00:21:00,230
Neither seem likely to produce enough
nourishment to support birdlife on this scale.

131
00:21:04,280 --> 00:21:07,470
The answer is blowing in the wind.

132
00:21:09,840 --> 00:21:16,510
Sand whipped up by shamals, offshore winds,
blows into the seas of the Arabian Gulf.

133
00:21:17,440 --> 00:21:21,110
With the grains come nutrients,
which act as fertiliser,

134
00:21:21,200 --> 00:21:25,710
and they transform the shallow sea
into a rich fishing ground.

135
00:21:31,440 --> 00:21:35,510
So, paradoxically, it's the roasted sands of Arabia

136
00:21:35,600 --> 00:21:39,910
that prevent the Gulf from being
another desert in the sea.

137
00:21:52,800 --> 00:21:55,830
The whale calf is now five months old.

138
00:21:56,360 --> 00:22:01,870
He's almost doubled in size and his days
in his tropical nursery are coming to an end.

139
00:22:02,840 --> 00:22:06,150
It has been a warm and safe place
in which to grow up,

140
00:22:06,240 --> 00:22:09,390
but there's nothing to eat here for his mother.

141
00:22:11,080 --> 00:22:15,590
She has been living off her fat reserves
for the last eight months

142
00:22:15,680 --> 00:22:17,870
and she's close to starving.

143
00:22:18,680 --> 00:22:21,470
She must leave now
while she still has enough energy

144
00:22:21,560 --> 00:22:25,990
to guide and protect her calf
on the long voyage ahead.

145
00:22:43,160 --> 00:22:47,990
All across the tropics,
humpbacks are heading away from the equator

146
00:22:48,120 --> 00:22:54,150
towards the rich temperate seas of both
the southern and the northern hemispheres.

147
00:22:57,040 --> 00:23:02,110
These are colder, rougher
and more dangerous waters.

148
00:23:13,680 --> 00:23:16,750
Mother and calf must stay close.

149
00:23:35,000 --> 00:23:39,350
They can send sound signals to one another
above the roar of the ocean

150
00:23:39,440 --> 00:23:42,150
by slapping fins on the surface.

151
00:24:02,720 --> 00:24:08,070
In winter, the temperate seas are lashed
by violent storms.

152
00:24:25,240 --> 00:24:31,630
The turbulence stirs the water
and draws nutrients up from the depths.

153
00:24:39,560 --> 00:24:42,870
But nutrients alone cannot support life.

154
00:24:43,920 --> 00:24:46,310
There must also be sunlight.

155
00:24:49,360 --> 00:24:55,670
In the spring, as the sun daily climbs
higher in the sky, the algae start to grow.

156
00:24:56,720 --> 00:25:01,950
Blooms the size of the Amazon rainforest
turn the seas green.

157
00:25:04,960 --> 00:25:07,910
Individually, the algae are tiny,

158
00:25:08,000 --> 00:25:13,830
but together they produce three quarters
of all the oxygen in our atmosphere.

159
00:25:17,520 --> 00:25:21,630
They're eaten by an array of bewildering creatures.

160
00:25:21,720 --> 00:25:24,590
Salps appear in the plankton soup.

161
00:25:30,160 --> 00:25:36,550
Individuals link together to form chains
which can stretch for 15 metres.

162
00:25:46,520 --> 00:25:52,310
Pumping water through their bodies,
they strain out algae and other edible particles.

163
00:26:02,840 --> 00:26:06,070
Comb jellies cruise through the water.

164
00:26:06,160 --> 00:26:09,390
They, too, flourish in this seasonal soup

165
00:26:09,480 --> 00:26:13,750
and for short periods
they appear in astounding numbers.

166
00:26:14,720 --> 00:26:17,270
Krill, shrimp-like creatures.

167
00:26:17,400 --> 00:26:20,630
By weight,
they're the most abundant animals on the planet.

168
00:26:20,720 --> 00:26:24,550
A single swarm can contain
two million tons of them.

169
00:26:33,320 --> 00:26:36,710
And that is a lot of fish food.

170
00:26:45,920 --> 00:26:51,390
The shallow temperate seas support
the greatest concentrations of fish on our planet.

171
00:26:51,520 --> 00:26:55,630
Huge shoals migrate
from their overwintering grounds in the depths

172
00:26:55,720 --> 00:26:58,030
to feed in these rich waters.

173
00:27:06,920 --> 00:27:12,310
It's these shoals that support
most of the world's sea mammals.

174
00:27:13,560 --> 00:27:18,590
Sea lions have all the agility and speed needed
to collect what they want

175
00:27:19,120 --> 00:27:21,870
and seemingly delight in doing so.

176
00:27:55,840 --> 00:27:59,910
Dusky dolphin, often in pods 200 strong,

177
00:28:00,000 --> 00:28:02,510
work together to reap the harvest.

178
00:28:05,200 --> 00:28:08,910
They break up the shoals into smaller,
more manageable balls

179
00:28:09,000 --> 00:28:11,110
and all the hunters benefit.

180
00:28:37,320 --> 00:28:42,350
By midsummer,
the surface nutrients have all been absorbed.

181
00:28:42,440 --> 00:28:46,510
The algae die and the food chain collapses.

182
00:28:51,240 --> 00:28:53,510
In a few special places, however,

183
00:28:53,640 --> 00:28:58,950
the temperate seas sustain these levels of life
throughout the summer.

184
00:28:59,080 --> 00:29:04,190
Along the coast of California,
ocean currents carry a constant supply of nutrients

185
00:29:04,280 --> 00:29:07,470
up from the depths to the surface layers.

186
00:29:08,160 --> 00:29:14,510
These upwellings fertilise forests of giant kelp
that thrive in the summer sunshine.

187
00:29:21,440 --> 00:29:25,430
The algal towers
are as high as a three-storey house

188
00:29:25,520 --> 00:29:28,670
and they can grow by half a metre a day.

189
00:29:42,800 --> 00:29:47,950
Life in the kelp is as full of drama
as in any other forest,

190
00:29:48,040 --> 00:29:50,710
but the cast is less familiar.

191
00:29:51,400 --> 00:29:55,190
An army of sea urchins is mounting an attack.

192
00:29:57,760 --> 00:30:04,470
The urchin plague strikes at the kelps' holdfasts,
their crucial attachments to the rock.

193
00:30:18,800 --> 00:30:24,470
Holdfasts are extremely tough,
but each urchin has five teeth

194
00:30:24,560 --> 00:30:28,310
which are self-sharpening
and are replaced every few months.

195
00:30:35,640 --> 00:30:39,190
Urchins fell vast areas of kelp forest,

196
00:30:39,280 --> 00:30:43,390
creating clearings known as urchin barrens.

197
00:30:46,560 --> 00:30:50,190
Yet "barrens" is a poor description.

198
00:30:54,200 --> 00:30:58,070
Millions of invertebrates invade the seabed.

199
00:31:12,640 --> 00:31:16,190
The most fearsome predator here is a giant.

200
00:31:16,280 --> 00:31:19,790
The sunflower starfish is a metre across,

201
00:31:19,880 --> 00:31:22,950
with an appetite for brittle stars.

202
00:31:40,520 --> 00:31:44,510
It uses its feet to taste for prey.

203
00:31:49,040 --> 00:31:52,310
When its actions are speeded up, it becomes clear

204
00:31:52,400 --> 00:31:55,310
that the predator's fondness for the brittle stars

205
00:31:55,440 --> 00:32:00,030
is almost matched by the brittle stars' ability
to get out of the way.

206
00:32:12,200 --> 00:32:17,590
Sand dollars, flat sea urchins,
cluster together as a defence.

207
00:32:23,080 --> 00:32:27,550
But it doesn't seem to work against
the sunflower starfish.

208
00:32:27,880 --> 00:32:32,110
The predator extrudes its stomach
and wraps it around its victims,

209
00:32:32,200 --> 00:32:34,350
liquefying their soft parts.

210
00:32:35,600 --> 00:32:39,150
Nothing is left of them
except their white skeletons.

211
00:32:46,480 --> 00:32:51,190
The Californian upwellings
are seasonal and relatively small.

212
00:32:51,320 --> 00:32:55,710
But in southern Africa,
they're so big they create seas rich enough

213
00:32:55,800 --> 00:32:59,470
to support colonies of over a million seals.

214
00:33:04,360 --> 00:33:09,430
The Benguela Current sweeps along
the western coastline of southern Africa,

215
00:33:09,520 --> 00:33:12,870
driving nutrient-rich waters up to the surface.

216
00:33:14,760 --> 00:33:17,590
And then, at the southern tip of Africa,

217
00:33:17,680 --> 00:33:21,870
it meets the Agulhas Current
arriving from the east.

218
00:33:21,960 --> 00:33:25,030
The result? Even richer waters.

219
00:33:36,520 --> 00:33:41,870
The seals here thrive on a diet of fish and squid.

220
00:33:43,400 --> 00:33:48,230
In temperate seas,
there may actually be more squid than fish.

221
00:33:55,720 --> 00:33:59,830
These are chokka squid
and they lay their egg capsules

222
00:33:59,920 --> 00:34:04,590
in sandy shallows
bathed by the warmer Agulhas Current.

223
00:34:13,120 --> 00:34:17,310
Each capsule contains a hundred tiny squid.

224
00:34:22,480 --> 00:34:25,350
Within a few days, they develop spots of pigment

225
00:34:25,480 --> 00:34:29,870
which, when they're adult,
they will use to communicate with one another.

226
00:34:41,840 --> 00:34:48,430
With females continuing to lay eggs
and males still preoccupied with repelling rivals,

227
00:34:48,600 --> 00:34:51,230
the squid drop their guard.

228
00:34:55,120 --> 00:34:56,630
Stingray.

229
00:35:03,960 --> 00:35:07,710
Short-tail stingray can be up to two metres across.

230
00:35:14,080 --> 00:35:19,430
They're the largest of all the stingrays
and they have appetites to match.

231
00:35:47,160 --> 00:35:50,110
Another predator is on the prowl.

232
00:35:52,360 --> 00:35:55,750
The aptly named ragged-tooth shark.

233
00:36:00,120 --> 00:36:06,150
Raggies grow to three metres long but they share
these waters with a shark twice their size.

234
00:36:22,840 --> 00:36:24,830
The great white.

235
00:36:26,840 --> 00:36:30,230
The largest predatory fish on the planet.

236
00:36:37,000 --> 00:36:42,030
Each dawn,
Cape fur seals leave their colony to go fishing.

237
00:36:43,040 --> 00:36:47,670
To reach the open sea,
they must cross a narrow strip of water

238
00:36:47,760 --> 00:36:51,590
and that is patrolled by great whites.

239
00:37:00,840 --> 00:37:04,470
Each seal is indeed swimming for its life.

240
00:37:26,880 --> 00:37:30,110
The shark relies on surprise.

241
00:38:28,800 --> 00:38:33,670
The great white's turn-of-speed
is powered by a high metabolism.

242
00:38:34,040 --> 00:38:36,830
They only thrive in cold temperate seas,

243
00:38:36,960 --> 00:38:43,310
for only these waters contain sufficient food
necessary to fuel such a ravenous predator.

244
00:39:14,840 --> 00:39:18,550
As you travel towards the poles, North or South,

245
00:39:18,680 --> 00:39:22,750
the colder, stormier seas can become even richer.

246
00:39:25,040 --> 00:39:28,510
Midway between South Africa and the South Pole

247
00:39:28,600 --> 00:39:32,390
lies the isolated island of Marion.

248
00:39:37,920 --> 00:39:41,750
The island sits in the infamous Roaring Forties

249
00:39:41,880 --> 00:39:46,630
where incessant gale-force winds
draw nutrients up from the depths,

250
00:39:46,720 --> 00:39:50,150
ensuring plenty of food for King penguins.

251
00:39:53,280 --> 00:39:58,230
The Kings are returning from a three-day
fishing trip with food for their chicks.

252
00:39:58,320 --> 00:40:01,710
But first they must cross a crowded beach,

253
00:40:01,800 --> 00:40:06,870
threading their way between gigantic
and bad-tempered elephant seals.

254
00:40:18,000 --> 00:40:24,350
The 200, 000 penguins breeding here
are testament to the richness of the fishing.

255
00:40:28,320 --> 00:40:32,150
King chicks are dependent on their mothers
for over a year

256
00:40:32,240 --> 00:40:35,790
and this puts a great deal of pressure
on the parents.

257
00:40:49,880 --> 00:40:56,070
Being flightless, the returning penguins
must cross the open beach on foot.

258
00:41:27,520 --> 00:41:31,830
Fur seals that have come to the beach to breed
are waiting for them.

259
00:41:40,000 --> 00:41:42,750
Fur seals normally live on krill,

260
00:41:42,880 --> 00:41:47,990
but these have now acquired
an unexpected taste for blubber-rich penguins.

261
00:42:39,040 --> 00:42:41,870
Penguins may be featherweights by comparison,

262
00:42:41,960 --> 00:42:45,990
but they have razor-sharp bills
and a feisty character.

263
00:42:49,160 --> 00:42:51,470
The seal could easily lose an eye.

264
00:42:51,560 --> 00:42:54,950
The only safe way to grab a penguin
is from behind

265
00:42:55,040 --> 00:42:57,590
and the birds are well aware of that.

266
00:43:18,960 --> 00:43:24,550
Both animals are clumsy on this terrain
but the penguin has the more to lose.

267
00:43:36,320 --> 00:43:37,790
Made it.

268
00:43:38,800 --> 00:43:45,350
Two out of three penguins survive the seal attacks
and succeed in reaching their ever-hungry chicks.

269
00:44:14,840 --> 00:44:19,390
The humpbacks are nearing the end
of their epic journeys.

270
00:44:24,400 --> 00:44:27,470
After two months and thousands of miles,

271
00:44:27,560 --> 00:44:32,950
they're entering the polar seas,
both in the north and the south.

272
00:44:43,440 --> 00:44:47,310
In the far north, winter is over at last

273
00:44:47,400 --> 00:44:50,030
and the ice is starting to melt.

274
00:44:53,800 --> 00:44:57,310
The Aleutian Island chain,
running west from Alaska,

275
00:44:57,400 --> 00:45:00,150
is the gateway to the Bering Sea.

276
00:45:00,280 --> 00:45:06,830
With the retreating ice, rough weather
and ferocious currents stir up these shallow seas.

277
00:45:06,960 --> 00:45:11,710
Add sunshine and the mix
is spectacularly productive.

278
00:45:21,480 --> 00:45:27,630
Five million shearwaters have flown
almost 10,000 miles from Australia to get here.

279
00:45:28,520 --> 00:45:32,030
In all, 80 million seabirds
come here for the summer,

280
00:45:32,120 --> 00:45:36,310
the greatest concentration
to be found anywhere on Earth.

281
00:45:49,200 --> 00:45:52,430
The humpbacks have finally arrived.

282
00:46:11,040 --> 00:46:15,150
The giant shearwater flocks hunt the krill swarms,

283
00:46:15,240 --> 00:46:19,350
sometimes diving to depths
of 40 metres to reach them.

284
00:46:42,240 --> 00:46:47,110
A large humpback eats three tons of krill a day.

285
00:46:59,320 --> 00:47:03,590
The polar seas in summer
are the most productive on the planet

286
00:47:03,720 --> 00:47:06,990
and the whales gorge themselves round the clock.

287
00:47:14,160 --> 00:47:18,990
The fat reserves they lay down now
will keep them alive during the year to come.

288
00:47:20,680 --> 00:47:23,270
But it may not always be this way.

289
00:47:23,400 --> 00:47:26,710
Fish and krill stocks are declining so rapidly

290
00:47:26,800 --> 00:47:30,710
that spectacles like this
may soon be part of history.

291
00:47:40,360 --> 00:47:45,990
Once the mother and calf have reached
their feeding grounds, they will separate.

292
00:47:49,040 --> 00:47:53,350
With luck, the calf will make the epic journey
across the oceans

293
00:47:53,440 --> 00:47:57,750
from equator to pole another 70 times,

294
00:47:57,840 --> 00:48:01,590
cruising back and forth between the shallow seas

295
00:48:01,680 --> 00:48:05,870
where life proliferates
so abundantly on our planet.

