1
00:00:29,400 --> 00:00:32,870
Away from all land...

2
00:00:32,960 --> 00:00:34,710
the ocean.

3
00:00:35,840 --> 00:00:41,310
It covers more than half the surface of our planet
and yet, for the most part,

4
00:00:41,400 --> 00:00:44,310
it is beyond our reach.

5
00:00:47,200 --> 00:00:52,910
Much of it is virtually empty, a watery desert.

6
00:00:58,840 --> 00:01:04,870
All life that is here
is locked in a constant search to find food.

7
00:01:06,400 --> 00:01:11,550
A struggle to conserve precious energy
in the open ocean.

8
00:01:31,360 --> 00:01:34,350
The biggest of all fish.

9
00:01:34,440 --> 00:01:38,990
30 tons in weight, 12 metres long,

10
00:01:39,080 --> 00:01:41,430
a whale shark.

11
00:01:42,320 --> 00:01:48,070
Its huge bulk is sustained
by near microscopic creatures of the sea,

12
00:01:49,040 --> 00:01:50,910
plankton.

13
00:01:52,440 --> 00:01:56,750
Whale sharks cruise on regular, habitual routes

14
00:01:56,840 --> 00:01:59,790
between the best feeding grounds.

15
00:02:03,680 --> 00:02:09,870
In February, that takes them to the surface waters
far from the coast of Venezuela.

16
00:02:13,280 --> 00:02:16,030
Others are already here.

17
00:02:16,120 --> 00:02:20,710
Bait fish have come for the same reason,
to feed on the plankton.

18
00:02:21,720 --> 00:02:26,310
The whale shark has timed its arrival exactly right.

19
00:02:27,800 --> 00:02:31,470
Oddly, the tiny fish swarm around it.

20
00:02:39,200 --> 00:02:41,870
They're using it as a shield.

21
00:02:45,600 --> 00:02:49,230
Other predatory fish are lurking nearby.

22
00:02:52,240 --> 00:02:56,750
Yellowfin tuna, they seem wary of the giant.

23
00:03:03,480 --> 00:03:07,870
The shark dives,
as if to escape from such overcrowding.

24
00:03:12,960 --> 00:03:17,870
Now the tuna have a chance to attack
the unprotected bait fish.

25
00:03:29,520 --> 00:03:32,950
But then back comes the giant!

26
00:03:39,680 --> 00:03:43,630
It has taken a vast mouthful of the bait fish itself.

27
00:03:43,800 --> 00:03:49,310
Plankton, it seems,
is not the only food for a whale shark.

28
00:03:59,400 --> 00:04:03,270
Both shark and tuna feast together.

29
00:04:17,960 --> 00:04:20,710
But the tuna must beware.

30
00:04:24,400 --> 00:04:28,150
Even they can end up
in the whale shark's stomach.

31
00:04:36,560 --> 00:04:40,790
Predators here must grab what they can,
when they can,

32
00:04:40,880 --> 00:04:43,630
for such events do not last long.

33
00:04:46,680 --> 00:04:52,710
The dense shoals on which so many depend
gather only when water conditions are perfect.

34
00:05:06,640 --> 00:05:12,870
Many predators spend much of their time
cruising the open ocean, endlessly searching.

35
00:05:18,080 --> 00:05:23,150
Plankton-feeding rays do so,
gliding with minimum effort.

36
00:05:37,520 --> 00:05:40,190
The Oceanic whitetip shark,

37
00:05:42,600 --> 00:05:45,910
another energy-efficient traveller.

38
00:05:47,920 --> 00:05:53,470
It specialises in locating prey
in the emptiest areas of the open ocean,

39
00:05:53,560 --> 00:05:56,390
patrolling the top 100 metres of water.

40
00:06:05,280 --> 00:06:10,070
Taste in water is the equivalent of smell in the air.

41
00:06:10,160 --> 00:06:14,990
An Oceanic whitetip is able to detect
even the faintest trace.

42
00:06:18,720 --> 00:06:21,190
Small pilot fish swim with it.

43
00:06:21,280 --> 00:06:24,750
The shark can find prey
far more easily than they can

44
00:06:24,840 --> 00:06:28,790
and they'll be able to collect the scraps
from its meals.

45
00:06:33,200 --> 00:06:38,830
Its long, fixed pectoral fins
enable it to soar through the water

46
00:06:38,920 --> 00:06:42,150
with the least expenditure of energy.

47
00:06:46,560 --> 00:06:51,070
This shark has found a school of rainbow runners.

48
00:06:51,160 --> 00:06:54,030
It would eat one, given the chance.

49
00:06:54,120 --> 00:06:58,430
But rainbow runners are swift and agile
and not easily caught.

50
00:07:01,400 --> 00:07:04,190
So, it bides its time.

51
00:07:04,320 --> 00:07:09,750
There's a chance that, eventually,
it may spot a weakened fish that's catchable.

52
00:07:13,440 --> 00:07:16,870
The hunter, endlessly waiting.

53
00:07:27,680 --> 00:07:31,230
Excitement far from land.

54
00:07:39,200 --> 00:07:42,750
A school of dolphin, 500 strong!

55
00:07:57,880 --> 00:08:02,390
They've sensed there's food around
and they're racing to catch up with it.

56
00:08:10,760 --> 00:08:16,030
The news has spread.
Now a number of schools are on their way.

57
00:08:28,880 --> 00:08:31,430
They're heading towards the Azores,

58
00:08:31,520 --> 00:08:35,310
volcanic islands 1, 000 miles west of Portugal.

59
00:08:45,920 --> 00:08:51,150
The dolphins scan the water ahead
with their sonar. They're close to their target.

60
00:08:59,720 --> 00:09:02,950
This is it, scad mackerel.

61
00:09:06,320 --> 00:09:10,510
It's difficult for a single dolphin to catch the fish.

62
00:09:11,640 --> 00:09:15,310
To avoid wasting energy, they work as a group.

63
00:09:22,160 --> 00:09:26,310
They drive the fish upwards,
trapping them against the surface.

64
00:09:28,520 --> 00:09:31,910
And there, other predators await them.

65
00:09:34,840 --> 00:09:37,830
Cory shearwaters.

66
00:09:37,920 --> 00:09:42,670
They're waiting for the dolphin
to drive the prey closer to the surface.

67
00:09:52,440 --> 00:09:58,070
Now the shearwaters can dive down on them,
descending to 20 metres or more.

68
00:10:02,520 --> 00:10:06,070
And the dolphins block the bait ball's retreat.

69
00:10:36,200 --> 00:10:40,270
The dolphins leave
as soon as they've had their fill.

70
00:10:44,560 --> 00:10:49,910
And, at last, the mackerel sink below
the diving range of the birds.

71
00:11:13,280 --> 00:11:18,470
As the sun disappears,
a profound change takes place in the ocean.

72
00:11:20,080 --> 00:11:23,630
Deepwater plankton start to rise from the depths

73
00:11:23,720 --> 00:11:28,550
and another hungry army prepares to receive it.

74
00:11:52,040 --> 00:11:57,990
Every night, wherever conditions are right,
countless millions of creatures from the deep

75
00:11:58,080 --> 00:12:01,630
migrate to the surface seeking food.

76
00:12:10,360 --> 00:12:16,430
A baby sailfish, 15 centimetres long,
snaps up everything in its path.

77
00:12:17,480 --> 00:12:24,150
In three years' time, it will be one of the ocean's
most formidable hunters, weighing 60 kilos.

78
00:12:25,280 --> 00:12:28,990
Just now, however, it's very vulnerable.

79
00:13:09,880 --> 00:13:13,030
These manta rays are giants.

80
00:13:13,640 --> 00:13:17,630
Eight metres across and weighing over two tons.

81
00:13:21,200 --> 00:13:24,270
The blade-like projections
on either side of the head

82
00:13:24,360 --> 00:13:28,150
help to steer plankton into the manta's mouth.

83
00:13:47,200 --> 00:13:51,670
Dawn returns
and the plankton sinks back into the depths.

84
00:13:54,120 --> 00:13:58,550
If we are to follow, we must use a submarine.

85
00:14:01,440 --> 00:14:07,590
As we descend into the darkness,
the pressure builds, the temperature falls.

86
00:14:11,560 --> 00:14:15,830
Below 500 metres,
new mysterious animals appear.

87
00:14:21,640 --> 00:14:27,750
Their bizarre shapes help them
to remain suspended in the dark space.

88
00:14:31,000 --> 00:14:35,230
Some resemble creatures
familiar from shallower waters.

89
00:14:43,440 --> 00:14:46,590
Others defy classification.

90
00:14:52,120 --> 00:14:56,990
All around, organic particles drift downwards.

91
00:14:58,720 --> 00:15:04,830
Marine snow, detritus from the creatures
swarming in the sunlit waters above.

92
00:15:07,280 --> 00:15:10,350
The snow is food for many animals here,

93
00:15:10,440 --> 00:15:15,350
like the sea spider,
a small relative of shrimps and crabs.

94
00:15:27,240 --> 00:15:33,590
Those strange leg-like appendages
are feathered to stop it from sinking.

95
00:15:35,600 --> 00:15:42,390
They can also enmesh marine snow,
which it wipes carefully into its jaws.

96
00:15:57,880 --> 00:16:02,670
A sawtooth eel hangs upright and motionless.

97
00:16:05,840 --> 00:16:07,390
Gazing ever upwards,

98
00:16:07,520 --> 00:16:13,710
it watches for prey silhouetted against
the faint glimmerings of light from the surface.

99
00:16:19,640 --> 00:16:25,310
Days may pass before prey swims
close enough for it to strike.

100
00:16:30,400 --> 00:16:34,030
Farther down still, the blackness is complete.

101
00:16:35,000 --> 00:16:39,830
No vestige of sunlight can penetrate as far as this.

102
00:16:43,200 --> 00:16:48,870
Food is very scarce
and nothing can afford to waste any energy.

103
00:16:52,000 --> 00:16:56,190
A dumbo octopus simply flaps a fin.

104
00:16:56,280 --> 00:17:01,070
No need for the jet propulsion
used by its shallow water relatives above.

105
00:17:31,560 --> 00:17:35,230
The weirdest in this world of the strange,

106
00:17:35,320 --> 00:17:40,470
Vampyroteuthis, the vampire squid from hell.

107
00:17:45,160 --> 00:17:50,190
Disturb it and it only retreats a little distance.

108
00:17:53,120 --> 00:17:57,270
Go after it and it has a special defence.

109
00:18:01,000 --> 00:18:04,590
To see what it does,
you must switch off the lights.

110
00:18:07,360 --> 00:18:10,910
The vampire squid has lights of its own.

111
00:18:13,600 --> 00:18:20,070
Bioluminescent bacteria shine
from pockets on its arms to confuse its predators.

112
00:18:21,120 --> 00:18:23,390
Are those eyes?

113
00:18:27,400 --> 00:18:33,070
In fact, they're spots at the end of its mantle.
A bite there would leave the head unscathed.

114
00:18:35,680 --> 00:18:42,350
The threat diminishes and Vampyroteuthis
disappears into the blackness.

115
00:18:57,960 --> 00:19:00,590
At last, the sea floor.

116
00:19:00,680 --> 00:19:03,350
Over two miles down,

117
00:19:03,440 --> 00:19:08,350
the pressure here is 300 times that at the surface.

118
00:19:08,440 --> 00:19:13,990
It takes several months for marine snow
to drift down as far as this.

119
00:19:18,440 --> 00:19:22,390
As you travel away from the rocky margins
of the continents,

120
00:19:22,480 --> 00:19:26,270
an immense plain stretches ahead.

121
00:19:28,600 --> 00:19:33,950
It extends for thousands of miles,
gradually sinking downwards.

122
00:19:41,040 --> 00:19:47,390
There are faint trails in the ooze,
signs that even here, there is life.

123
00:19:54,760 --> 00:19:57,710
These are what made some of them.

124
00:19:57,800 --> 00:20:02,230
Sea urchins sifting the accumulating drifts.

125
00:20:06,600 --> 00:20:13,190
Shrimps, standing on elegant tiptoe, fastidiously
select the particles that appeal to them.

126
00:20:21,320 --> 00:20:28,110
But in the deep sea, as everywhere else,
if there are grazers, there are hunters.

127
00:20:37,480 --> 00:20:43,110
A monkfish, almost indistinguishable
from the sand on which it lies.

128
00:20:47,760 --> 00:20:54,070
Why waste energy chasing around
if you can attract prey towards you with a lure?

129
00:21:12,240 --> 00:21:15,430
Maybe that one was a bit big.

130
00:21:18,040 --> 00:21:21,550
The monkfish can wait for days, if necessary,

131
00:21:21,640 --> 00:21:25,150
until the right-sized meal turns up.

132
00:21:28,280 --> 00:21:33,510
Scavengers, on the other hand,
have to move around to find their food.

133
00:21:36,000 --> 00:21:40,630
Crabs can detect the faintest of tastes
in the water and that helps them locate

134
00:21:40,720 --> 00:21:44,670
the latest body to drift down from above.

135
00:21:45,840 --> 00:21:49,190
Eels are already feeding on the corpse.

136
00:21:55,880 --> 00:22:00,430
Isopods, like giant marine woodlice
a third of a metre long,

137
00:22:00,520 --> 00:22:03,510
are ripping into the rotting flesh.

138
00:22:04,280 --> 00:22:07,670
Over the next few hours,
there'll be frenzied competition

139
00:22:07,760 --> 00:22:11,990
between scavengers of all kinds to grab a share.

140
00:22:40,560 --> 00:22:45,310
Just occasionally, there is a gigantic bonanza.

141
00:22:53,920 --> 00:22:57,350
The remains of a sperm whale.

142
00:22:57,440 --> 00:23:00,550
It died five months or so ago.

143
00:23:00,640 --> 00:23:04,990
There is little left but fatty blubber
clinging to its bones.

144
00:23:08,040 --> 00:23:14,070
Its flesh has nourished life for miles around,
but now, the feast is almost over.

145
00:23:19,320 --> 00:23:25,190
Spider crabs, a metre across,
still pick at the last putrid remains.

146
00:23:32,880 --> 00:23:37,990
A few weeks more
and nothing will be left but bare bones.

147
00:23:38,800 --> 00:23:43,830
The crabs will have to fast
until the next carcass drifts down.

148
00:23:50,440 --> 00:23:54,750
But not all food comes
from the sunlit world above.

149
00:23:56,040 --> 00:24:02,550
The floor of the Atlantic Ocean is split in two
by an immense volcanic mountain chain

150
00:24:02,640 --> 00:24:07,510
that winds unbroken for 45, 000 miles
around the globe.

151
00:24:11,640 --> 00:24:17,270
In places it's riven by great fissures
from which superheated water,

152
00:24:17,360 --> 00:24:22,150
loaded with dissolved minerals,
blasts into the icy depths.

153
00:24:33,200 --> 00:24:39,950
Clouds of sulphides solidify into
towering chimneys as tall as a three-storey house.

154
00:24:44,480 --> 00:24:48,750
At 400 degrees, this scalding cocktail of chemicals

155
00:24:48,840 --> 00:24:53,390
would be lethally toxic to most forms of life.

156
00:24:54,440 --> 00:24:59,750
But, astoundingly, a particular kind of bacteria
thrives here.

157
00:24:59,840 --> 00:25:04,510
And feeding on the bacteria,
vast numbers of shrimps.

158
00:25:14,520 --> 00:25:18,030
So, beyond the farthest reach of the sun's power,

159
00:25:18,120 --> 00:25:22,630
a rich independent community exists
that draws all its energy

160
00:25:22,720 --> 00:25:25,470
directly from the earth's molten core.

161
00:25:40,880 --> 00:25:45,910
On the other side of the planet,
in the western Pacific bordering Japan,

162
00:25:47,000 --> 00:25:49,070
the dragon chimneys.

163
00:25:49,160 --> 00:25:52,830
Another series
of hot vents erupting in the darkness.

164
00:26:00,560 --> 00:26:06,350
Here, more, but different, bacteria
thrive in a similar way.

165
00:26:11,520 --> 00:26:15,830
And here, too, more crustaceans,
but quite different species

166
00:26:15,920 --> 00:26:19,630
from those around the hot vents in the Atlantic.

167
00:26:25,000 --> 00:26:29,710
These are squat lobsters clad in furry armour,

168
00:26:29,800 --> 00:26:33,910
jostling with one another
beside the jets of superheated water

169
00:26:34,000 --> 00:26:38,190
for the best places
from which to graze on bacteria.

170
00:26:44,080 --> 00:26:49,430
These vents, too, like those in the Atlantic,
are isolated oases,

171
00:26:49,520 --> 00:26:54,270
so widely separated,
that each community is unique.

172
00:27:04,600 --> 00:27:10,190
Cross to the other side of the Pacific,
to the deep near the Galapagos Islands,

173
00:27:10,280 --> 00:27:14,390
and there are yet other fissures
venting superheated water.

174
00:27:20,200 --> 00:27:25,070
One and a half miles down,
at a site known as Nine North,

175
00:27:25,200 --> 00:27:30,230
towering chimneys support a spectacular display
of giant tubeworms.

176
00:27:36,960 --> 00:27:43,750
These vents give off so much energy that
some of the worms reach three metres in length.

177
00:27:43,840 --> 00:27:47,830
They're the fastest-growing
marine invertebrates known.

178
00:27:52,480 --> 00:27:58,430
All told, over 50 different species
have so far been found living here.

179
00:28:02,760 --> 00:28:07,750
The inhabitants of these bustling communities
may grow at speed,

180
00:28:07,840 --> 00:28:13,590
but their existence can also be short,
for the vents do not erupt indefinitely.

181
00:28:14,400 --> 00:28:18,070
Suddenly, unpredictably,
they may become inactive.

182
00:28:23,320 --> 00:28:26,990
Nine months have passed at Nine North.

183
00:28:27,080 --> 00:28:30,550
What were only recently
chimneys teeming with life

184
00:28:30,640 --> 00:28:35,950
have turned into cold, sterile, mineral monuments.

185
00:28:38,760 --> 00:28:45,430
Some eddy, deep in the earth's crust,
diverted the volcanic energy elsewhere

186
00:28:45,520 --> 00:28:49,790
and an entire micro-world was extinguished.

187
00:28:57,880 --> 00:29:03,110
In places, volcanoes have erupted
to build great submarine mountains.

188
00:29:04,120 --> 00:29:08,510
There are thought to be
around 30, 000 such volcanoes.

189
00:29:08,600 --> 00:29:13,830
Some measured from the sea floor
are taller than Everest.

190
00:29:19,440 --> 00:29:24,110
Sheer cliffs soaring to drowned volcanic peaks.

191
00:29:35,920 --> 00:29:39,270
Powerful currents sweep up the mountain's flanks,

192
00:29:39,360 --> 00:29:43,750
transporting nutrients from deep water
towards the summits.

193
00:29:46,720 --> 00:29:49,590
The hard rock provides excellent anchorage

194
00:29:49,680 --> 00:29:53,910
for communities of great variety
and stunning colour.

195
00:29:56,120 --> 00:30:03,030
Soft corals, several metres across,
collect the marine snow as it drifts past.

196
00:30:05,920 --> 00:30:09,390
Whip corals stretch out into the current.

197
00:30:12,000 --> 00:30:16,350
Giant sponges filter nourishment
from the cold water.

198
00:30:30,960 --> 00:30:34,150
A richly varied community flourishes here,

199
00:30:34,280 --> 00:30:40,350
sustained by the nutrients and detritus
in the icy currents that flow around the peak.

200
00:30:45,800 --> 00:30:52,510
Yet, it is all blossoming on an extinct volcano
a mile below the reach of the sun.

201
00:31:17,800 --> 00:31:22,630
A nautilus.
It spends its days hiding 400 metres down,

202
00:31:22,720 --> 00:31:27,270
but as night falls,
it ascends up to the reefs to look for food.

203
00:31:33,120 --> 00:31:39,430
Its graceful shell contains gas-filled
floatation chambers that control its depth.

204
00:31:42,520 --> 00:31:46,590
It's powered by a jet of water
squirting from a siphon.

205
00:31:49,240 --> 00:31:54,630
But it travels shell-first,
so it can't see exactly where it's going.

206
00:31:59,800 --> 00:32:03,270
Its nearest living relatives are squid and octopus

207
00:32:03,360 --> 00:32:07,990
which, over evolutionary time,
have both lost their shells.

208
00:32:08,080 --> 00:32:13,110
And the octopus has become
one of the nautilus's major predators.

209
00:32:13,200 --> 00:32:15,990
It's a master of disguise.

210
00:32:22,160 --> 00:32:24,870
The nautilus keeps well clear of them.

211
00:32:27,640 --> 00:32:32,110
Its small tentacles
carry highly-developed chemical sensors

212
00:32:32,200 --> 00:32:36,230
which can detect traces
of both predators and prey.

213
00:32:42,120 --> 00:32:46,110
It uses its water jet to dig in the sand.

214
00:32:51,320 --> 00:32:56,670
Because it devotes so little energy to swimming,
it only needs a meal once a month.

215
00:33:02,240 --> 00:33:05,550
Got something, and just as well.

216
00:33:05,680 --> 00:33:10,430
Dawn is approaching and
it has to puff its way back to deeper waters.

217
00:33:32,520 --> 00:33:37,990
Thirty miles away, shoals of squid
are jetting upwards towards the surface.

218
00:33:39,760 --> 00:33:44,830
By night, they seek small fish
among the plankton, but they're cautious.

219
00:33:52,240 --> 00:33:54,190
Pacific spotted dolphin.

220
00:33:58,560 --> 00:34:01,310
They're guided by their sonar.

221
00:34:05,800 --> 00:34:09,310
The dolphin, as so often, are working as a team,

222
00:34:09,400 --> 00:34:13,030
synchronising their attacks to confuse their prey.

223
00:34:31,640 --> 00:34:33,110
As dawn approaches,

224
00:34:33,200 --> 00:34:39,270
squid and fish and plankton
retreat downwards to shelter in the darkness.

225
00:35:05,240 --> 00:35:11,510
Some of these isolated volcanoes
rise as much as 9, 000 metres from the sea floor,

226
00:35:11,600 --> 00:35:14,030
reaching close to the surface.

227
00:35:17,840 --> 00:35:21,510
Around these peaks,
invigorated by daily sunshine,

228
00:35:21,600 --> 00:35:26,150
marine life flourishes in spectacular abundance.

229
00:35:35,200 --> 00:35:40,550
Fish crowd here because the volcano
forces nutrients to the surface,

230
00:35:40,640 --> 00:35:43,590
encouraging the plankton to bloom.

231
00:36:02,120 --> 00:36:05,110
An oceanic wanderer, a Mola mola,

232
00:36:05,200 --> 00:36:10,110
stops by to be cleaned by reef fish
at the seamount edge.

233
00:36:18,000 --> 00:36:22,790
Butterfly fish pluck string-like parasites
from its flanks.

234
00:36:29,800 --> 00:36:34,150
The huge fish lives on jellyfish
over 1, 000 metres down,

235
00:36:34,240 --> 00:36:37,230
where the water is 20 degrees colder.

236
00:36:38,160 --> 00:36:40,710
So, a brush-up near the surface

237
00:36:40,800 --> 00:36:45,910
allows it to warm up
before making more deep-water forays.

238
00:36:53,640 --> 00:36:58,950
The summit of this volcanic mountain
rises above the surface of the sea.

239
00:37:00,280 --> 00:37:06,070
It's Ascension Island,
800 miles from any other land.

240
00:37:06,160 --> 00:37:10,750
A welcome, vital haven
for long-distance travellers.

241
00:37:15,560 --> 00:37:20,070
Frigate birds spend months
continuously airborne at sea,

242
00:37:20,200 --> 00:37:24,870
but at nesting time,
they come to Ascension from all over the ocean.

243
00:37:29,800 --> 00:37:33,630
The island's barren slopes of volcanic ash and lava

244
00:37:33,720 --> 00:37:37,590
might seem to offer
perfectly good sites for a nest,

245
00:37:39,400 --> 00:37:43,470
but the frigates choose an even more isolated site.

246
00:37:45,280 --> 00:37:50,590
Boatswainbird Island,
a lonely pillar just off Ascension's coast.

247
00:37:59,280 --> 00:38:03,910
Frigates are the world's lightest bird
relative to their wingspan

248
00:38:04,000 --> 00:38:07,550
and they can soar for weeks on end
with minimal effort.

249
00:38:12,440 --> 00:38:17,630
They seem much more at home in the skies
than in a crowded colony on land.

250
00:38:17,720 --> 00:38:19,550
But nest they must.

251
00:38:21,960 --> 00:38:26,350
They come from all over the Atlantic to this,
their only colony.

252
00:38:30,080 --> 00:38:32,150
There are boobies here, too.

253
00:38:37,280 --> 00:38:42,950
To raise their young,
seabirds worldwide seek such remote islands.

254
00:38:53,920 --> 00:38:57,350
Swimmers also come to Ascension to breed.

255
00:38:59,000 --> 00:39:02,630
A female green turtle approaches the coast.

256
00:39:05,760 --> 00:39:09,270
She has not eaten once in two months.

257
00:39:10,520 --> 00:39:14,630
She may have travelled 1, 000 miles
from her feeding grounds.

258
00:39:14,720 --> 00:39:17,110
The greatest journey of her kind.

259
00:39:24,760 --> 00:39:30,630
Many others are here, too, resting on
the sandy sea floor awaiting the darkness of night

260
00:39:30,720 --> 00:39:33,550
when it will be safer to visit the beaches.

261
00:39:39,960 --> 00:39:45,550
Eggs that were laid a few weeks ago
at the start of the season are beginning to hatch.

262
00:39:58,400 --> 00:40:00,670
Most hatchings happen at night.

263
00:40:01,640 --> 00:40:05,950
Now, in the light of day,
the young are extremely vulnerable.

264
00:40:12,240 --> 00:40:15,190
They must get to the sea as soon as possible.

265
00:40:17,680 --> 00:40:20,710
But their trials have only just begun.

266
00:40:33,640 --> 00:40:37,590
Many will drown in the pounding waves.

267
00:41:01,880 --> 00:41:07,390
During the next 20 years,
the vast majority will inevitably die.

268
00:41:07,480 --> 00:41:11,830
But those that survive will, eventually,
as their mothers did before them,

269
00:41:11,920 --> 00:41:15,350
return to the very same beach
where they were hatched.

270
00:41:18,080 --> 00:41:22,470
How they find their way back,
across thousands of miles of open ocean,

271
00:41:22,560 --> 00:41:24,830
we still have no idea.

272
00:41:33,400 --> 00:41:35,630
A frigate soars.

273
00:41:37,160 --> 00:41:42,310
Somewhere beneath the surface below
there is the food it must have.

274
00:41:43,360 --> 00:41:44,990
But where?

275
00:41:46,920 --> 00:41:52,510
Those that fly above the ocean
must be able to read the signs of fresh supplies

276
00:41:52,600 --> 00:41:54,150
or perish.

277
00:41:57,120 --> 00:42:02,270
A hundred miles from the Mexican coast
and keen eyes have spotted movement.

278
00:42:07,520 --> 00:42:12,630
Sailfish, three metres long, are closing in on prey.

279
00:42:18,480 --> 00:42:23,390
They will only use just enough energy
to make their kill,

280
00:42:23,480 --> 00:42:25,630
never wasting a fin stroke.

281
00:42:30,520 --> 00:42:34,910
Nearly a hundred sailfish
have surrounded a single school of bait fish.

282
00:42:35,000 --> 00:42:39,310
It's very rare to see
so many of these hunters in one place.

283
00:42:42,480 --> 00:42:47,270
To herd their prey,
the predators raise their huge dorsal fins.

284
00:43:05,040 --> 00:43:09,470
A mistimed strike by one sailfish
could fatally damage another.

285
00:43:09,560 --> 00:43:14,870
But each continually changes its colour
from blue, to striped, to black.

286
00:43:15,000 --> 00:43:20,270
That warns its companions of its intentions
and also confuses the prey.

287
00:43:23,360 --> 00:43:28,550
As the shoal is driven nearer the surface,
it comes within the range of the seabirds.

288
00:43:43,480 --> 00:43:48,630
Out here in the open ocean,
there is nowhere for the bait fish to hide.

289
00:44:31,040 --> 00:44:34,430
Sailfish live a high-octane life.

290
00:44:35,160 --> 00:44:39,030
To survive, they must find prey daily.

291
00:44:39,120 --> 00:44:43,190
So their entire existence
will be spent on the move.

292
00:44:54,640 --> 00:45:00,950
Over 90% of the living space
for life on our planet is in the oceans.

293
00:45:02,280 --> 00:45:07,870
Home to the biggest animal that exists
or has ever existed.

294
00:45:10,040 --> 00:45:12,110
The blue whale.

295
00:45:19,720 --> 00:45:26,630
Some weigh nearly 200 tons,
twice the size of the largest dinosaur.

296
00:45:31,560 --> 00:45:33,510
Despite their great size,

297
00:45:33,600 --> 00:45:38,510
we still have little idea of where they travel
in the vast oceans

298
00:45:38,600 --> 00:45:41,870
and none at all of where they go to breed.

299
00:46:11,120 --> 00:46:15,630
The largest animal on Earth
feeds almost exclusively

300
00:46:15,720 --> 00:46:20,790
on one of the smallest,
krill, shrimp-like crustaceans.

301
00:46:22,920 --> 00:46:28,550
They take many tons of water
into their ballooning throats in a single gulp

302
00:46:28,640 --> 00:46:31,830
and sieve out what it contains.

303
00:46:38,320 --> 00:46:44,110
Every day, each one swallows
some four million krill.

304
00:46:47,080 --> 00:46:53,230
Such gargantuan harvests
depend on the continuing fertility of the oceans.

305
00:46:56,160 --> 00:47:00,710
But global changes now threaten
the great blooms of plankton

306
00:47:00,800 --> 00:47:02,870
on which the whales depend.

307
00:47:05,520 --> 00:47:08,590
Once, and not so long ago,

308
00:47:08,680 --> 00:47:12,510
300,000 blue whales roamed the oceans.

309
00:47:13,480 --> 00:47:17,350
Now, less than 3% of that number remains.

310
00:47:22,160 --> 00:47:25,950
Our planet is still full of wonders.

311
00:47:26,080 --> 00:47:32,070
As we explore them,
so we gain not only understanding, but power.

312
00:47:34,200 --> 00:47:39,110
It's not just the future of the whale
that today lies in our hands.

313
00:47:39,200 --> 00:47:44,830
It's the survival of the natural world
in all parts of the living planet.

314
00:47:46,480 --> 00:47:49,950
We can now destroy or we can cherish.

315
00:47:53,480 --> 00:47:56,630
The choice is ours.

