1
00:00:39,960 --> 00:00:43,710
A third of the land
on our planet is desert.

2
00:00:52,680 --> 00:00:57,510
These great scars on the face of the earth
appear to be lifeless.

3
00:00:57,600 --> 00:01:00,270
But surprisingly, none are.

4
00:01:06,960 --> 00:01:12,230
In all of them life manages, somehow,
to keep a precarious hold.

5
00:01:32,920 --> 00:01:35,110
Not all deserts are hot.

6
00:01:35,720 --> 00:01:39,110
Fifty-mile-an-hour winds blowing in from Siberia

7
00:01:39,200 --> 00:01:42,550
bring snow to the Gobi Desert in Mongolia.

8
00:02:08,040 --> 00:02:11,390
From a summer high of 50 degrees centigrade,

9
00:02:11,480 --> 00:02:15,510
the temperature in mid-winter
can drop to minus 40,

10
00:02:15,600 --> 00:02:19,110
making this one of the harshest deserts of all.

11
00:02:28,040 --> 00:02:32,750
Few animals can survive these extreme changes.

12
00:02:38,960 --> 00:02:43,590
Wild Bactrian camels,
one of the rarest mammals on the planet,

13
00:02:44,160 --> 00:02:46,510
and perhaps the hardiest.

14
00:02:47,880 --> 00:02:50,350
Their biggest problem is the lack of water,

15
00:02:50,480 --> 00:02:54,990
particularly now in winter when the little there is
is locked up as ice.

16
00:03:02,240 --> 00:03:05,790
Surprisingly, snow here never melts.

17
00:03:06,440 --> 00:03:10,870
The air is just too cold and too dry for it to do so.

18
00:03:16,040 --> 00:03:19,270
The sun's rays turn it straight into vapour.

19
00:03:19,680 --> 00:03:21,430
It evaporates.

20
00:03:29,280 --> 00:03:32,470
But it is the only source of water

21
00:03:32,560 --> 00:03:35,230
so Bactrian camels eat it.

22
00:03:36,200 --> 00:03:37,510
Elsewhere in the world,

23
00:03:37,640 --> 00:03:43,030
a camel at a waterhole can drink
as much as 200 litres during a single visit.

24
00:03:45,840 --> 00:03:50,790
Here, the strategy is to take little and often,
and with good reason

25
00:03:50,880 --> 00:03:54,270
for filling the stomach with snow could be fatal.

26
00:03:59,920 --> 00:04:05,150
The camels must limit themselves
to the equivalent of just 10 litres a day.

27
00:04:21,560 --> 00:04:24,230
Winter is the time for breeding.

28
00:04:28,880 --> 00:04:33,110
This extraordinary performance
is a male Bactrian camel's way

29
00:04:33,200 --> 00:04:36,070
of attracting the attention of a passing female.

30
00:04:38,400 --> 00:04:42,470
In summer, the camels can't stray
far from waterholes.

31
00:04:43,240 --> 00:04:46,470
But now, with mouthfuls of snow lying everywhere,

32
00:04:46,560 --> 00:04:49,670
they can travel widely in search of mates.

33
00:04:53,760 --> 00:04:59,230
Today, less than 1,000 of these desert specialists
remain in the wild.

34
00:05:00,000 --> 00:05:04,670
The Gobi, hostile though it is,
is their last stronghold.

35
00:05:11,280 --> 00:05:14,550
There is no other desert quite like the Gobi.

36
00:05:14,640 --> 00:05:17,070
But why is this place a desert?

37
00:05:18,800 --> 00:05:21,830
There is one simple and massive cause.

38
00:05:21,920 --> 00:05:23,550
The Himalayas.

39
00:05:27,800 --> 00:05:31,870
Clouds blowing from the south
hit this gigantic barrier.

40
00:05:31,960 --> 00:05:33,510
As they're forced upwards,

41
00:05:33,600 --> 00:05:36,670
so they empty their moisture
on the mountain slopes,

42
00:05:36,760 --> 00:05:39,830
leaving little for the land on the other side.

43
00:05:44,840 --> 00:05:48,510
From space, deserts are very conspicuous.

44
00:05:51,240 --> 00:05:55,710
Dunes of sand hundreds of miles long
streak their surface.

45
00:06:00,560 --> 00:06:03,630
With no cloak of vegetation to conceal them,

46
00:06:03,720 --> 00:06:07,590
strange formations are exposed in the naked rock.

47
00:06:13,720 --> 00:06:17,390
Africa's Sahara is the largest desert of all.

48
00:06:17,480 --> 00:06:19,750
It's the size of the United States

49
00:06:19,840 --> 00:06:23,950
and the biggest source of sand and dust
in the entire world.

50
00:07:03,080 --> 00:07:06,350
Sandstorms like these appear without warning

51
00:07:06,440 --> 00:07:10,710
and reduce visibility for days
over areas the size of Britain.

52
00:07:19,880 --> 00:07:24,670
Dromedaries, single-humped camels,
take these storms in their stride.

53
00:07:28,400 --> 00:07:32,630
The heavy sand rises only a few metres
above the ground.

54
00:07:32,720 --> 00:07:37,430
But the dust can be blown
5, 000 metres up into the sky.

55
00:07:43,000 --> 00:07:46,550
The ferocious wind, armed with grains of sand,

56
00:07:46,640 --> 00:07:49,670
is the agent that shapes all deserts.

57
00:07:59,120 --> 00:08:04,990
Reptiles have armoured, scaly skins
that protect them from the stinging grains.

58
00:08:07,960 --> 00:08:12,190
For insects, the bombardment
can be very severe indeed.

59
00:08:14,560 --> 00:08:17,630
The only escape is below the surface.

60
00:08:33,920 --> 00:08:38,030
As the winds rise and fall, swirl and eddy,

61
00:08:38,120 --> 00:08:41,030
so they pile the sand into dunes.

62
00:08:45,000 --> 00:08:48,550
These sand seas can be hundreds of miles across.

63
00:08:53,080 --> 00:08:57,230
In Namibia, the winds have built
some of the biggest dunes in the world.

64
00:09:05,280 --> 00:09:09,110
Star dunes like these can be 300 metres high.

65
00:09:09,480 --> 00:09:13,950
Grains swept up the flanks
are blown off the crests of the ridges

66
00:09:14,040 --> 00:09:16,310
so it's only the tops that are moving.

67
00:09:23,360 --> 00:09:28,430
The main body of these dunes
may not have shifted for 5, 000 years.

68
00:09:40,320 --> 00:09:45,950
Few rocks can resist the continuous blast
of the sand-carrying wind.

69
00:09:46,640 --> 00:09:50,510
These outcrops are standing
in Egypt's White Desert.

70
00:09:51,600 --> 00:09:54,590
But they will not do so for much longer.

71
00:09:56,080 --> 00:10:01,110
They are being inexorably chiselled away
and turned into more sand.

72
00:10:39,080 --> 00:10:45,590
Now lumps of heavily eroded rocks
have been marooned in a sea of sand.

73
00:11:02,440 --> 00:11:06,110
These jagged pyramids, 100 metres tall,

74
00:11:06,200 --> 00:11:09,670
were once part of a continuous rocky plateau.

75
00:11:09,760 --> 00:11:13,790
The blasting sand will eventually
eliminate them altogether.

76
00:11:22,160 --> 00:11:24,310
The relentless power of the wind

77
00:11:24,400 --> 00:11:28,390
ensures that the face of a desert
is continually changing.

78
00:11:28,480 --> 00:11:31,110
But there is one constant presence.

79
00:11:39,080 --> 00:11:40,870
The desert sun.

80
00:11:55,240 --> 00:11:58,590
The sun's heat and the power to evaporate water

81
00:11:58,680 --> 00:12:03,670
has had a profound effect on the bodies
and habits of everything that lives here.

82
00:12:08,240 --> 00:12:11,270
This sun, potentially, is a killer.

83
00:12:12,880 --> 00:12:16,430
And the red kangaroos must acknowledge that.

84
00:12:17,920 --> 00:12:22,590
Right now, while the sun is low,
there's no immediate cause for concern.

85
00:12:23,840 --> 00:12:26,630
But this situation won't last long.

86
00:12:27,760 --> 00:12:33,310
Australia is the world's most arid continent
with blistering daytime temperatures.

87
00:12:40,640 --> 00:12:45,350
Every hour, the temperature rises
by five degrees centigrade.

88
00:12:52,880 --> 00:12:56,270
Soon the heat will reach a critical point.

89
00:13:06,120 --> 00:13:11,230
Any kangaroo out in the open
is in serious danger of overheating.

90
00:13:17,200 --> 00:13:22,670
In the full sun, the temperature on the ground
soars to 70 degrees.

91
00:13:27,560 --> 00:13:32,870
By midday, the radiation is so intense
they must take shelter.

92
00:13:52,600 --> 00:13:56,070
In the shade, they are shielded
from much of the sun's energy

93
00:13:56,160 --> 00:13:58,830
but their body temperature can still rise.

94
00:14:01,640 --> 00:14:05,070
So they lick saliva onto their forearms

95
00:14:05,160 --> 00:14:09,110
where there is a network of blood vessels
close to the surface of the skin,

96
00:14:09,200 --> 00:14:13,430
and as the saliva evaporates, their blood is cooled.

97
00:14:16,280 --> 00:14:20,790
This thermal image shows
just how effective the process is.

98
00:14:20,920 --> 00:14:24,310
The blue areas on the body are the cooler parts.

99
00:14:33,280 --> 00:14:36,910
As the saliva dries, it has to be replaced.

100
00:14:37,000 --> 00:14:41,030
And this is a real drain
on the kangaroo's body fluids.

101
00:14:51,120 --> 00:14:54,510
Even in the shade, the earth is baking hot.

102
00:14:55,480 --> 00:15:01,110
So the kangaroos dig away the warmed topsoil
to get at the cooler ground beneath.

103
00:15:23,720 --> 00:15:28,110
By staying in the shade
and licking to control their body temperature,

104
00:15:28,240 --> 00:15:32,830
kangaroos manage to get through
the hottest part of the day without heatstroke.

105
00:15:34,080 --> 00:15:39,430
But for the majority of desert animals,
this strategy would not be enough for survival.

106
00:16:02,040 --> 00:16:06,790
The extraordinary ears
of the fennec foxes of Africa radiate heat,

107
00:16:06,880 --> 00:16:10,150
but the animals have another way of keeping cool.

108
00:16:19,560 --> 00:16:24,550
They spend their days underground
and only emerge at sunset.

109
00:16:36,440 --> 00:16:39,390
Darkness brings huge changes.

110
00:16:39,800 --> 00:16:44,430
In the Sahara, the temperature can drop
as much as 30 degrees during the night.

111
00:16:44,640 --> 00:16:48,630
So it's cool enough
to allow these desert fox cubs to play.

112
00:16:56,440 --> 00:17:01,830
All sorts of creatures now appear,
including some really unexpected ones.

113
00:17:05,120 --> 00:17:07,230
Toads have permeable skins

114
00:17:07,320 --> 00:17:11,150
and would quickly die from desiccation
out in the daytime heat.

115
00:17:11,240 --> 00:17:13,710
It's only now that they can leave shelter.

116
00:17:16,680 --> 00:17:21,550
The same is true for scorpions,
even though their shells are actually watertight.

117
00:17:33,840 --> 00:17:37,470
In fact, most small desert creatures are nocturnal.

118
00:17:37,640 --> 00:17:42,990
So it's only now that you can judge
just how much life there can be in a desert.

119
00:17:43,920 --> 00:17:46,390
But moisture lost, even at night,

120
00:17:46,480 --> 00:17:49,510
has to be replaced sometime, somehow.

121
00:17:49,600 --> 00:17:53,630
And that problem dominates the lives
of all desert dwellers.

122
00:18:01,920 --> 00:18:07,190
The Atacama in Chile.
This is the driest desert in the world.

123
00:18:09,240 --> 00:18:13,590
Some parts may not see rain for 50 years,
and with such a record,

124
00:18:13,680 --> 00:18:16,550
you would expect the place
to be completely barren.

125
00:18:22,120 --> 00:18:25,910
These are South America's camels, guanacos.

126
00:18:27,760 --> 00:18:30,030
They are very good at conserving moisture

127
00:18:30,120 --> 00:18:33,110
but they, nonetheless,
need a regular supply of water.

128
00:18:45,840 --> 00:18:48,910
They get it partly from cactus flowers.

129
00:18:49,000 --> 00:18:52,270
But that explanation raises another question.

130
00:18:54,720 --> 00:18:58,070
How do the cacti survive without rain?

131
00:19:04,680 --> 00:19:09,230
Hot winds suck all the moisture
from the surface of the land.

132
00:19:11,120 --> 00:19:15,830
Clearly, there must be something else
that takes the place of rain.

133
00:19:17,240 --> 00:19:22,470
The secret is a cold sea current
that runs parallel to the land.

134
00:19:39,360 --> 00:19:45,230
The cold water cools the moist, warm air above it
and that produces banks of fog.

135
00:20:08,080 --> 00:20:13,830
At the same time, wind blowing onto the shore
sweeps the fog inland.

136
00:20:29,040 --> 00:20:33,110
Before long, the cacti are dripping with dew.

137
00:20:42,000 --> 00:20:43,790
The fog is so regular

138
00:20:43,880 --> 00:20:47,310
that moisture-loving lichens
are able to grow on the cacti

139
00:20:47,400 --> 00:20:50,390
and they absorb liquid like a sponge.

140
00:20:53,080 --> 00:20:55,670
In the land of almost no rain,

141
00:20:55,760 --> 00:21:00,550
these precious drops are lifesavers
for many different creatures.

142
00:21:09,560 --> 00:21:15,190
Further inland, the air remains so warm
that its moisture does not condense.

143
00:21:15,280 --> 00:21:19,950
So this slender strip of desert
is virtually the only part of the Atacama

144
00:21:20,040 --> 00:21:21,710
where life can exist.

145
00:21:25,960 --> 00:21:30,150
And without the fog,
this land, too, would be empty.

146
00:21:43,720 --> 00:21:46,790
The guanacos make the most of the dew.

147
00:21:47,280 --> 00:21:49,390
But it will not remain for long.

148
00:21:50,400 --> 00:21:55,470
In an hour or two, the sun will have burnt it off
and dried the surface of the cacti.

149
00:22:04,360 --> 00:22:09,550
The Sonoran Desert in Arizona
is not quite so dry as the Atacama.

150
00:22:09,640 --> 00:22:11,510
Some rain does fall.

151
00:22:12,680 --> 00:22:14,230
But it is infrequent,

152
00:22:14,360 --> 00:22:19,230
and when it does arrive, animals and plants
have to be ready to make the most of it.

153
00:22:21,040 --> 00:22:22,350
And it's coming.

154
00:22:30,960 --> 00:22:33,070
When the summer monsoon blows in,

155
00:22:33,160 --> 00:22:36,510
the giant saguaros, one of the biggest of all cacti,

156
00:22:36,600 --> 00:22:39,030
are ready to take full advantage of it.

157
00:23:12,080 --> 00:23:13,950
After a rainstorm,

158
00:23:14,040 --> 00:23:18,110
the saguaro's long, shallow root system
sucks up the water

159
00:23:18,760 --> 00:23:22,950
and the pleats on its trunk
enable it to expand rapidly.

160
00:23:31,040 --> 00:23:36,270
When full, a saguaro stem can store
up to five tonnes of water,

161
00:23:36,360 --> 00:23:40,070
and that's enough to see it through
many months of drought.

162
00:23:44,800 --> 00:23:49,670
The trunks of these huge plants
provide homes for the Gila woodpecker.

163
00:23:52,240 --> 00:23:57,790
But birds are not the only animals
to benefit from the presence of the cacti.

164
00:24:14,240 --> 00:24:20,870
During four weeks of the summer,
the saguaros bloom at night to attract visitors.

165
00:24:24,640 --> 00:24:27,830
The pollen and nectar
with which these flowers are loaded

166
00:24:27,920 --> 00:24:31,630
attract long-nosed and long-tongued bats.

167
00:24:46,600 --> 00:24:51,590
The bats left Mexico a few days earlier
to escape the heat of summer

168
00:24:51,680 --> 00:24:55,470
and are on their way north
to the southern United States.

169
00:24:57,640 --> 00:25:01,110
To get there, they have to cross
the Sonoran Desert.

170
00:25:07,080 --> 00:25:12,630
But the desert is so big that for most of the year
they would be unable to cross it.

171
00:25:12,720 --> 00:25:17,430
Now, with the saguaro in bloom,
they can refuel on the way.

172
00:25:27,360 --> 00:25:31,230
So the saguaro's success
in developing a way to store water

173
00:25:31,320 --> 00:25:37,150
is now crucial to most of the animals
that live or even travel through this land.

174
00:26:16,040 --> 00:26:20,430
The scarcity of rain determined
the shape of this icon of the desert.

175
00:26:20,560 --> 00:26:26,510
But water, scarce though it is,
has also, like the wind, shaped the land itself.

176
00:26:43,200 --> 00:26:48,070
In the deserts of Utah,
ancient rivers flowing across sandstone country

177
00:26:48,160 --> 00:26:50,550
steadily widened their canyons

178
00:26:50,640 --> 00:26:56,230
until now, the land between them
has been reduced to spires and pinnacles.

179
00:27:25,240 --> 00:27:30,190
With little or no soil to retain the water
on the surface of the land,

180
00:27:30,360 --> 00:27:33,030
life here is scarce indeed.

181
00:27:35,000 --> 00:27:39,190
And when resources are limited,
conflict is never far away.

182
00:27:49,680 --> 00:27:54,590
These are Nubian ibex
and they are squaring up for a duel.

183
00:28:01,080 --> 00:28:07,310
And when trouble starts, a smart ibex knows
that the best thing to do is to gain higher ground.

184
00:28:24,480 --> 00:28:30,230
These are actually subordinate male ibex,
but their fights are, nonetheless, serious.

185
00:28:30,320 --> 00:28:34,710
Losing one might mean
never getting the chance to breed, ever.

186
00:28:56,800 --> 00:29:00,230
When competitors are evenly matched,
as they are here,

187
00:29:00,320 --> 00:29:02,510
duels can last for an hour.

188
00:29:22,080 --> 00:29:26,110
In this heat, the effort is truly exhausting.

189
00:29:28,160 --> 00:29:33,430
But victory here will gain important ranking points
on a male's way to the top.

190
00:30:04,440 --> 00:30:07,950
There's so much at stake that not all play fair.

191
00:30:22,960 --> 00:30:25,230
The battle has produced a winner.

192
00:30:25,320 --> 00:30:28,750
But the ultimate prize is not his yet.

193
00:30:32,560 --> 00:30:36,550
That currently belongs to the dominant male ibex.

194
00:30:38,880 --> 00:30:42,630
His rank earns him the loyalty
of a harem of females

195
00:30:42,720 --> 00:30:44,150
and they follow him closely

196
00:30:44,240 --> 00:30:48,150
as he travels across this desert
searching for food and water.

197
00:30:50,640 --> 00:30:55,150
He doesn't have to waste time looking for mates,
they're his for the taking.

198
00:30:55,240 --> 00:30:59,550
So he can concentrate with them
on keeping fit and healthy.

199
00:31:14,640 --> 00:31:17,790
Lizards are desert specialists.

200
00:31:20,680 --> 00:31:23,910
But here, their numbers are extraordinary.

201
00:31:29,480 --> 00:31:31,550
These crevices in South Africa

202
00:31:31,640 --> 00:31:34,830
contain the highest density of lizards in the world.

203
00:31:44,920 --> 00:31:48,470
They're called flat lizards, for obvious reasons,

204
00:31:48,600 --> 00:31:53,150
and they flaunt their multicoloured bellies
in territorial disputes.

205
00:31:55,720 --> 00:31:59,990
He's made his point
and now it's time to find some food.

206
00:32:01,880 --> 00:32:05,590
As the day warms up,
the lizards move away from their cracks

207
00:32:05,680 --> 00:32:08,110
and head down to the bottom of the gorge.

208
00:32:09,480 --> 00:32:11,670
Their goal is the river.

209
00:32:14,040 --> 00:32:19,350
There is no food at the edge,
but this desert river holds a secret.

210
00:32:26,040 --> 00:32:30,910
Each day, black fly rise
from turbulent stretches of the river.

211
00:32:31,520 --> 00:32:34,110
This is what the lizards have come for.

212
00:32:48,920 --> 00:32:50,750
The black fly never land

213
00:32:50,840 --> 00:32:54,070
so the lizards have to leap for their food.

214
00:33:06,320 --> 00:33:11,910
In one day, each of these acrobatic little lizards
may catch 50 flies.

215
00:33:22,240 --> 00:33:27,270
There are plenty of flies to go around,
even with hundreds of lizards competing for them.

216
00:33:41,280 --> 00:33:42,950
Away from these rapids,

217
00:33:43,040 --> 00:33:47,190
flat lizard populations
are found in much smaller numbers.

218
00:33:47,280 --> 00:33:51,350
But here, one unusual abundance
has produced another.

219
00:34:02,720 --> 00:34:05,630
Deserts are created by the lack of water

220
00:34:05,720 --> 00:34:11,390
but what actually kills animals here
is not heat or thirst, but lack of food.

221
00:34:29,560 --> 00:34:33,470
So how on earth does a plant-eater this size

222
00:34:33,560 --> 00:34:38,550
survive in a place apparently
totally devoid of vegetation?

223
00:34:45,120 --> 00:34:49,070
Elephants in Namibia are the toughest in Africa.

224
00:34:49,160 --> 00:34:50,990
And they need to be.

225
00:35:07,400 --> 00:35:10,630
What little food exists is so dispersed

226
00:35:10,720 --> 00:35:13,790
that these elephants walk up to 50 miles a day

227
00:35:13,880 --> 00:35:18,790
as they travel up the dry river channels
searching for something to eat.

228
00:35:33,520 --> 00:35:37,350
At times, the task looks truly hopeless.

229
00:36:10,840 --> 00:36:14,550
Elephants may seem out of place
in this landscape,

230
00:36:14,640 --> 00:36:16,790
but they're not the only ones.

231
00:36:32,840 --> 00:36:35,950
Amazingly, lions live here, too.

232
00:36:40,720 --> 00:36:46,990
In savannah country, huge herds of game
support prides containing 20 lions or more.

233
00:36:47,480 --> 00:36:51,270
But to live here,
lions have had to change their habits.

234
00:36:51,400 --> 00:36:55,550
Prides are much smaller
and their home ranges are very much bigger.

235
00:36:56,880 --> 00:36:58,950
And there's an added problem.

236
00:37:00,560 --> 00:37:03,630
Their food is always on the move.

237
00:37:12,280 --> 00:37:13,870
Like the elephants,

238
00:37:13,960 --> 00:37:18,310
the lions must travel great distances
to find enough to live on.

239
00:37:33,120 --> 00:37:35,750
But lions can't go everywhere.

240
00:37:35,880 --> 00:37:40,070
They won't attempt to cross
this field of sand dunes,

241
00:37:40,160 --> 00:37:41,910
and the oryx know it.

242
00:38:39,480 --> 00:38:43,470
The lions must wait for the oryx
to leave the safety of the dunes,

243
00:38:43,560 --> 00:38:46,430
which eventually they must to find food and water,

244
00:38:46,520 --> 00:38:48,990
and then the lions will ambush them.

245
00:39:51,880 --> 00:39:55,630
The elephants have found
some of their favourite food.

246
00:40:02,440 --> 00:40:05,390
Grasses are the staple diet of all elephants,

247
00:40:05,480 --> 00:40:08,750
but this herd concentrates
on digging up the roots,

248
00:40:08,840 --> 00:40:12,390
which have more nutrition and moisture
than the stems.

249
00:40:12,880 --> 00:40:14,390
It's the sort of behaviour

250
00:40:14,480 --> 00:40:18,110
that can make all the difference
in a place of serious shortages.

251
00:40:19,160 --> 00:40:22,710
Yet all this can change in an instant.

252
00:40:39,280 --> 00:40:43,870
The fortunes of many deserts
are ruled by distant rains.

253
00:40:43,960 --> 00:40:48,630
This water fell as rain
in mountains more than 100 miles away.

254
00:40:54,400 --> 00:40:56,230
It's known as a flash flood

255
00:40:56,360 --> 00:41:00,510
and called that because the water may run
for just a single day.

256
00:41:00,600 --> 00:41:04,590
It's an event that only happens
once or twice a year at the most.

257
00:41:25,080 --> 00:41:29,310
The sandy riverbed acts like
a giant strip of blotting paper,

258
00:41:29,400 --> 00:41:32,150
sucking up the water as soon as it appears.

259
00:41:41,840 --> 00:41:45,070
But every square metre of soil
moistened by this river

260
00:41:45,160 --> 00:41:49,190
will increase the chances of survival
for those that live here.

261
00:41:54,760 --> 00:41:57,910
Waterholes are filled temporarily.

262
00:42:02,560 --> 00:42:05,950
Elsewhere in Africa elephants drink everyday

263
00:42:06,080 --> 00:42:10,870
but the lack of water here means that
desert elephants can only refill their tanks

264
00:42:10,960 --> 00:42:13,590
once every four or five days.

265
00:42:15,160 --> 00:42:19,350
Within a week, the flash flood has produced
a flush of green,

266
00:42:19,440 --> 00:42:22,910
more than enough to draw the oryx
out of the dunes.

267
00:42:25,400 --> 00:42:29,190
It's a rare chance for them
to build up their food reserves.

268
00:42:37,520 --> 00:42:41,230
The flood has made life easier for the lions, too.

269
00:42:44,120 --> 00:42:48,750
The flesh of this oryx will keep the family going
for a week at the most.

270
00:42:49,160 --> 00:42:54,150
But for a while, the hunting will be easier
now that the river channel has turned green.

271
00:42:58,480 --> 00:43:01,350
The good times for lions and oryx are brief.

272
00:43:01,440 --> 00:43:03,310
But these are the short moments

273
00:43:03,400 --> 00:43:06,990
that make it possible
to live in deserts the year round.

274
00:43:12,840 --> 00:43:15,950
Death Valley is the hottest place on Earth.

275
00:43:16,040 --> 00:43:19,710
Yet even this furnace
can be transformed by water.

276
00:43:30,320 --> 00:43:35,030
A single shower can enable seeds
that have lain dormant for 30 years or more

277
00:43:35,120 --> 00:43:36,910
to burst into life.

278
00:43:45,280 --> 00:43:49,070
And there hasn't been a bloom like this one
for a century.

279
00:44:01,240 --> 00:44:04,630
The periods of boom in Death Valley are short

280
00:44:04,720 --> 00:44:08,510
but they're just frequent enough
to keep life ticking over.

281
00:44:17,120 --> 00:44:21,630
A sudden flush of vegetation
is what every desert dweller waits for

282
00:44:21,720 --> 00:44:25,070
and when it happens,
they must make the most of it.

283
00:44:44,480 --> 00:44:46,830
There is no other species on the planet

284
00:44:46,960 --> 00:44:50,750
that responds as quickly and as dramatically
to the good times

285
00:44:50,840 --> 00:44:52,910
as the desert locust.

286
00:44:53,800 --> 00:44:58,470
Eggs that have remained in the ground
for 20 years begin to hatch.

287
00:45:10,840 --> 00:45:15,470
The young locusts are known as hoppers,
for at this stage they're flightless.

288
00:45:15,560 --> 00:45:21,310
They find new feeding grounds
by following the smell of sprouting grass.

289
00:45:27,400 --> 00:45:31,310
Normally it takes four weeks
for hoppers to become adults.

290
00:45:31,400 --> 00:45:33,790
But when the conditions are right, as now,

291
00:45:33,880 --> 00:45:37,070
their development switches to the fast track.

292
00:45:42,320 --> 00:45:45,430
As the vegetation in one place begins to run out,

293
00:45:45,520 --> 00:45:48,870
the winged adults release pheromones,
scent messages,

294
00:45:48,960 --> 00:45:52,430
which tell others in the group
that they must move on.

295
00:46:03,840 --> 00:46:07,630
And when groups merge, they form a swarm.

296
00:46:29,400 --> 00:46:33,310
An adult locust eats
its entire body weight every day.

297
00:46:33,400 --> 00:46:38,150
And a whole swarm can consume
literally hundreds of tonnes of vegetation.

298
00:46:40,280 --> 00:46:42,510
They have to keep on moving.

299
00:46:43,880 --> 00:46:45,990
The swarm travels with the wind.

300
00:46:46,080 --> 00:46:48,910
It's the most energy-saving way of flying.

301
00:46:52,760 --> 00:46:54,470
Following the flow of wind

302
00:46:54,560 --> 00:46:58,230
means that they're always heading
toward areas of low pressure.

303
00:46:58,320 --> 00:47:02,990
Places where wind meets rain
and vegetation starts to grow.

304
00:47:05,200 --> 00:47:10,870
As they fly, swarms join up with other swarms
to form gigantic plagues

305
00:47:10,960 --> 00:47:14,870
several billion strong
and as much as 40 miles wide.

306
00:47:17,280 --> 00:47:21,190
They will consume every edible thing
that lies in their path.

307
00:47:34,480 --> 00:47:38,390
This is one of planet Earth's greatest spectacles.

308
00:47:38,520 --> 00:47:42,190
It's rarely seen on this scale and it won't last long.

309
00:47:42,680 --> 00:47:44,310
Once the food has gone,

310
00:47:44,400 --> 00:47:48,150
the steady roar of a billion beating locust wings

311
00:47:48,240 --> 00:47:53,990
will once again be replaced by nothing more
than the sound of the desert wind.

