1
00:00:29,360 --> 00:00:33,390
Both poles of our planet are covered with ice.

2
00:00:33,480 --> 00:00:38,430
They're the largest
and most demanding wildernesses of all.

3
00:00:39,960 --> 00:00:44,670
Nowhere else on Earth
is seasonal change so extreme.

4
00:00:44,760 --> 00:00:50,030
It causes the ice
to advance and retreat every year.

5
00:00:51,000 --> 00:00:55,070
And all life here is governed by that.

6
00:01:12,960 --> 00:01:16,470
When the first polar explorers headed south,

7
00:01:16,560 --> 00:01:21,750
giant cathedrals of ice marked
their entry into uncharted territory.

8
00:01:26,680 --> 00:01:28,590
Passing the towering spires,

9
00:01:28,680 --> 00:01:32,350
they must have wondered
what unearthly sights lay in store.

10
00:01:37,280 --> 00:01:41,230
As they battled on,
the ice became increasingly dominant,

11
00:01:41,360 --> 00:01:47,310
but nothing could have prepared them
for the ice world that finally loomed into view.

12
00:01:53,160 --> 00:01:57,470
Terra incognita, "the unknown land".

13
00:02:09,520 --> 00:02:12,230
At the southernmost extreme of our planet,

14
00:02:12,320 --> 00:02:17,510
the continent of Antarctica is as large
as the United States of America.

15
00:02:23,800 --> 00:02:27,310
Ninety per cent of all the world's ice is found here.

16
00:02:30,800 --> 00:02:37,070
This frozen world is largely deserted
until the start of spring.

17
00:02:42,040 --> 00:02:45,830
Adélie penguins in a hurry.

18
00:02:52,240 --> 00:02:54,150
The clock is ticking.

19
00:02:54,280 --> 00:03:00,790
Instead of waiting for the summer melt,
the new arrivals hasten south over the frozen sea.

20
00:03:12,480 --> 00:03:16,870
They have come here to breed,
but polar summers are so short,

21
00:03:16,960 --> 00:03:20,590
they must be in position before the thaw starts.

22
00:03:25,880 --> 00:03:30,910
As the sea ice retreats,
life can journey farther south.

23
00:03:36,560 --> 00:03:42,670
Antarctic waters are so rich that visitors come
from far and wide to harvest them.

24
00:03:50,840 --> 00:03:55,790
Vast numbers of chinstrap penguins
come ashore to breed.

25
00:04:03,920 --> 00:04:07,950
No bird will lay their eggs directly onto ice

26
00:04:08,040 --> 00:04:11,310
so bare rock is a vital commodity.

27
00:04:11,400 --> 00:04:14,430
The best patches are worth the climb.

28
00:04:19,320 --> 00:04:22,190
The cliff tops are soon stained pink

29
00:04:22,280 --> 00:04:26,190
with the droppings of tens of thousands
of nesting penguins.

30
00:04:34,720 --> 00:04:41,550
Only in a land almost entirely covered in ice
could bare rock be reckoned an oasis.

31
00:04:44,120 --> 00:04:48,390
Some will travel
into the heart of the continent to find it.

32
00:04:50,280 --> 00:04:55,830
These are nunataks,
the exposed peaks of vast mountain ranges

33
00:04:55,920 --> 00:04:58,790
buried in ice over a mile deep.

34
00:05:01,280 --> 00:05:06,070
The eerie silence here is only broken in spring.

35
00:05:13,120 --> 00:05:17,310
The snow petrels have arrived and are courting.

36
00:05:24,280 --> 00:05:29,310
Antarctic petrels now join
the most southerly bird colony on Earth.

37
00:05:31,160 --> 00:05:36,790
The birds have flown inland
for over 300 miles to reach this breeding site.

38
00:05:41,560 --> 00:05:46,990
Once their eggs have hatched, they will be forced
repeatedly to make the 600-mile round trip

39
00:05:47,080 --> 00:05:49,790
to gather food in the ocean.

40
00:05:51,080 --> 00:05:56,430
First, though, valuable nesting places
must be defended from property thieves.

41
00:06:03,560 --> 00:06:08,870
After laying their eggs,
the petrels take time out to clean their plumage.

42
00:06:29,440 --> 00:06:34,150
The south polar skua is a formidable opportunist.

43
00:06:37,520 --> 00:06:41,310
But the skuas have not chanced upon the petrels,

44
00:06:41,400 --> 00:06:43,710
they've been waiting for them.

45
00:06:47,320 --> 00:06:51,270
These birds do not need to go
to the ocean for their food.

46
00:07:08,920 --> 00:07:13,110
The skuas can survive further south
than any other predator

47
00:07:13,200 --> 00:07:17,230
by exploiting the petrels' desperate need
for bare rock.

48
00:07:27,840 --> 00:07:33,110
Even at the height of summer, less than
three per cent of Antarctica is free of ice,

49
00:07:33,200 --> 00:07:38,030
and nearly all of that exposed rock
is found in one place,

50
00:07:38,120 --> 00:07:40,750
the Antarctic Peninsula.

51
00:07:46,720 --> 00:07:50,630
Its long arm extends further north
than the rest of the continent,

52
00:07:50,720 --> 00:07:54,510
so spring arrives here first.

53
00:08:07,720 --> 00:08:10,710
The thaw unlocks sheltered bays

54
00:08:10,840 --> 00:08:15,270
that provide refuge from the relentless battering
of the Southern Ocean.

55
00:08:20,040 --> 00:08:23,190
In the depths, something stirs.

56
00:08:47,200 --> 00:08:49,150
Humpback whales.

57
00:08:49,240 --> 00:08:53,550
They have travelled over 5, 000 miles
to reach these waters.

58
00:09:00,680 --> 00:09:03,390
The whales are harvesting krill,

59
00:09:03,520 --> 00:09:08,310
shrimp-like creatures that begin to swarm here
as soon as the ice retreats.

60
00:09:22,840 --> 00:09:28,270
Diving into the heart of the swarm,
teams of whales spiral round each other

61
00:09:28,360 --> 00:09:30,390
in close coordination.

62
00:09:33,280 --> 00:09:38,910
Now they turn, blasting air from their blowholes,
and ascend towards their prey.

63
00:09:41,040 --> 00:09:46,230
The krill becomes concentrated
as the spiralling net of bubbles draws inwards.

64
00:10:13,160 --> 00:10:18,150
The team of whales work round the clock
for the boom is short-lived.

65
00:10:18,240 --> 00:10:20,230
Summer is already fading

66
00:10:20,320 --> 00:10:24,310
and the whales will soon
be forced north as winter returns.

67
00:10:28,520 --> 00:10:33,790
The sun's influence diminishes
and the ocean starts to freeze.

68
00:10:33,920 --> 00:10:37,550
The greatest seasonal change
on our planet is underway.

69
00:10:43,960 --> 00:10:49,710
The ice grows at an extraordinary rate,
advancing two and a half miles a day.

70
00:10:49,800 --> 00:10:54,350
In a matter of weeks,
the continent effectively doubles in size.

71
00:10:57,920 --> 00:11:01,110
Life flees from Antarctica.

72
00:11:07,520 --> 00:11:09,950
But one creature is just arriving.

73
00:11:15,240 --> 00:11:20,070
Every winter, emperor penguins
leave the comfort of their ocean home

74
00:11:20,160 --> 00:11:22,630
and begin a remarkable journey.

75
00:11:24,960 --> 00:11:30,430
They head towards their breeding grounds,
almost 100 miles inland.

76
00:11:52,720 --> 00:11:57,310
Eventually, the emperor penguins
reach the place where they were hatched,

77
00:11:57,400 --> 00:12:02,150
an area sheltered by icebergs,
trapped in the frozen ocean.

78
00:12:02,960 --> 00:12:05,750
Here they will raise the next generation.

79
00:12:12,520 --> 00:12:15,790
But first, each must find a mate.

80
00:12:18,560 --> 00:12:21,230
The males begin to serenade.

81
00:12:25,640 --> 00:12:30,910
And if a female replies, they pair up,
posing like statues.

82
00:12:35,160 --> 00:12:38,350
New couples quickly form a strong bond.

83
00:12:38,440 --> 00:12:41,870
They seem oblivious
to the noisy crowd around them.

84
00:12:44,640 --> 00:12:49,030
To cement their relationship,
the male steps out with his female.

85
00:12:59,080 --> 00:13:03,550
The brief courtship complete,
there isn't a moment to lose.

86
00:13:03,640 --> 00:13:09,030
With so much pressure to perform,
any male would struggle to stay on top.

87
00:13:16,720 --> 00:13:21,390
Several weeks later, and it seems
that most couplings were successful.

88
00:13:22,520 --> 00:13:26,150
But producing the egg has taken its toll.

89
00:13:26,760 --> 00:13:30,030
The females no longer
have the energy to incubate.

90
00:13:32,440 --> 00:13:34,390
The male takes over.

91
00:13:34,480 --> 00:13:37,350
It's still minus 20 degrees centigrade,

92
00:13:37,440 --> 00:13:41,590
so the transfer must be done quickly
or else the egg will freeze.

93
00:13:41,720 --> 00:13:46,830
With no bare rock to nest on,
the male tucks the egg into a special pouch,

94
00:13:46,920 --> 00:13:49,510
where he can keep it warm.

95
00:13:49,600 --> 00:13:53,190
It requires an extraordinary piece of teamwork.

96
00:13:57,440 --> 00:14:03,030
Driven by hunger, the exhausted females
now return to the ocean on their own,

97
00:14:03,120 --> 00:14:08,030
repeating the epic journey they made
with the males only a month before.

98
00:14:14,160 --> 00:14:17,150
Now the sun barely appears above the horizon.

99
00:14:18,560 --> 00:14:23,070
As the days shorten,
its warmth is withdrawn from the continent.

100
00:14:34,200 --> 00:14:39,510
With the females gone,
the colony undergoes a strange transformation.

101
00:14:40,520 --> 00:14:42,870
The males shuffle into groups,

102
00:14:42,960 --> 00:14:46,190
their eggs still tucked away above their feet.

103
00:14:48,920 --> 00:14:54,590
They lock together in tightly-packed huddles
as they struggle to keep warm.

104
00:14:58,200 --> 00:15:03,230
Speeding up the action reveals
how these huddles constantly shift and change

105
00:15:03,320 --> 00:15:08,110
as each penguin works its way
towards the warmer interior.

106
00:15:09,320 --> 00:15:13,350
Crammed into this scrum,
the birds are remarkably good-natured.

107
00:15:13,440 --> 00:15:15,070
But they have to be.

108
00:15:15,160 --> 00:15:19,830
If the huddle breaks, even for a moment,
precious heat escapes.

109
00:15:38,000 --> 00:15:41,990
It's imperative they reform as quickly as possible,

110
00:15:42,120 --> 00:15:47,830
for only by acting as one can the males
withstand the elements and protect their eggs.

111
00:15:53,400 --> 00:15:57,150
But their greatest test lies ahead.

112
00:15:57,280 --> 00:16:01,710
As winter advances,
frequent blizzards drive the temperature down.

113
00:16:02,960 --> 00:16:06,830
It's now 60 degrees below zero.

114
00:16:09,520 --> 00:16:14,790
The birds at the edge of the huddle
bear the brunt of the 100-mile-an-hour winds

115
00:16:14,880 --> 00:16:19,550
and so provide shelter
to those taking their turn in the middle.

116
00:16:27,720 --> 00:16:31,910
Abandoned by the sun,
the males are left alone with their eggs

117
00:16:32,000 --> 00:16:35,590
to face the coldest, darkest winter on Earth.

118
00:16:43,440 --> 00:16:49,510
At the northern extreme of our planet,
the sun rises for the first time in months,

119
00:16:49,640 --> 00:16:52,390
illuminating a very different ice world.

120
00:16:56,080 --> 00:17:02,830
Unlike Antarctica,
the Arctic is a vast frozen sea surrounded by land.

121
00:17:04,920 --> 00:17:08,230
Here winter is coming to an end

122
00:17:08,320 --> 00:17:12,630
but this bleak wilderness remains locked in ice.

123
00:17:20,120 --> 00:17:23,110
Eider ducks break the silence.

124
00:17:23,240 --> 00:17:26,350
They have stayed here,
braving the northern winter,

125
00:17:26,440 --> 00:17:29,430
instead of flying south to warmer climes.

126
00:17:33,440 --> 00:17:38,030
Flocks 40, 000 strong
sweep across the frozen wastes.

127
00:17:51,960 --> 00:17:55,470
They all have the same goal, a polynya,

128
00:17:55,560 --> 00:17:57,630
a permanent hole in the sea ice,

129
00:17:57,720 --> 00:18:01,710
kept open throughout the winter
by strong ocean currents.

130
00:18:05,760 --> 00:18:10,350
This unusual duck pond
provides an overnight sanctuary

131
00:18:10,440 --> 00:18:14,590
and, when day breaks, a rare chance to feed.

132
00:18:26,400 --> 00:18:32,910
Just 10 metres beneath the ice,
the sea floor is carpeted with dense mussel beds.

133
00:18:34,600 --> 00:18:38,750
These can only be reached
during a brief lull in the currents.

134
00:18:38,880 --> 00:18:44,270
The ducks must quickly prise the mussels free
before the tide starts to turn.

135
00:18:51,200 --> 00:18:53,790
The window of opportunity is short.

136
00:18:53,880 --> 00:18:58,070
As the current begins to build,
it's up, up and away.

137
00:19:09,760 --> 00:19:15,350
These permanent holes in the ice
provide seafood throughout the winter.

138
00:19:17,120 --> 00:19:19,350
The diners attract others.

139
00:19:25,920 --> 00:19:30,430
In the Arctic, any breach in the icy barrier
can be a lifeline.

140
00:19:34,920 --> 00:19:38,470
Musk oxen create their own.

141
00:19:38,560 --> 00:19:42,710
These giants have the strength
to smash through the frozen crust

142
00:19:42,800 --> 00:19:46,510
to graze on the vegetation below.

143
00:19:49,720 --> 00:19:53,950
The ice-breakers create an opening
for other over-winterers.

144
00:19:55,600 --> 00:20:00,710
Flocks of ptarmigan make unusual
grazing companions for the musk oxen,

145
00:20:00,800 --> 00:20:03,790
whose entourage grows throughout the day.

146
00:20:12,360 --> 00:20:16,950
This odd assembly of vegetarians
doesn't go unnoticed.

147
00:20:18,240 --> 00:20:20,310
An arctic fox.

148
00:20:25,240 --> 00:20:28,470
The musk oxen have recently given birth.

149
00:20:29,360 --> 00:20:31,790
For the fox, it's a chance to scavenge.

150
00:20:39,680 --> 00:20:44,630
But half a ton of mad hairy cow
is not to be trifled with.

151
00:20:53,880 --> 00:20:56,710
The calves are born well before the spring melt,

152
00:20:56,800 --> 00:21:00,990
giving them a head start
when summer finally arrives.

153
00:21:05,160 --> 00:21:08,710
It must get to grips with its new ice world,

154
00:21:08,800 --> 00:21:12,630
benign one minute, life-threatening the next.

155
00:21:18,640 --> 00:21:22,750
Even in spring, winds chill to the bone.

156
00:21:25,520 --> 00:21:31,110
The calf must stay close to its mother
to avoid getting lost in the sudden blizzard.

157
00:21:40,440 --> 00:21:41,910
Arctic wolves!

158
00:21:46,320 --> 00:21:50,270
In the whiteout,
the threat is almost impossible to detect,

159
00:21:50,360 --> 00:21:53,950
but the musk oxen
instinctively retreat to higher ground.

160
00:22:09,880 --> 00:22:12,670
Forming a defensive ring around their calves,

161
00:22:12,760 --> 00:22:16,550
the adults present a barricade
that few hunters could breach.

162
00:22:19,280 --> 00:22:22,710
But the wolves need not risk injury today.

163
00:22:24,960 --> 00:22:27,830
A calf has been left behind in the panic.

164
00:22:40,960 --> 00:22:45,470
With each passing day,
the sun climbs higher in the sky

165
00:22:45,560 --> 00:22:49,790
and its rays strike the Arctic more directly.

166
00:22:49,880 --> 00:22:53,630
It's spring and new life stirs.

167
00:22:58,280 --> 00:23:02,230
The polar bear cubs emerge from the den
in which they were born.

168
00:23:02,800 --> 00:23:07,630
Their mother stretches her legs
after five months under the snow.

169
00:23:12,880 --> 00:23:17,190
They are just two months old
and instinctively follow her lead.

170
00:23:33,200 --> 00:23:40,110
A steep slope makes the best site for a den,
but it's a tricky place to take your first steps.

171
00:23:59,200 --> 00:24:04,670
It may look like fun
but this is serious training for the task ahead.

172
00:24:04,760 --> 00:24:06,550
There is no food on the slopes

173
00:24:06,640 --> 00:24:09,710
and the family will need to head out
across the frozen sea

174
00:24:09,800 --> 00:24:12,390
before the mother's milk runs dry.

175
00:24:19,200 --> 00:24:21,510
Two weeks later, they are ready.

176
00:24:23,320 --> 00:24:27,150
Out on the sea ice, the female can hunt for seals

177
00:24:27,240 --> 00:24:31,470
but it will take all her mothering skills
to keep her cubs safe

178
00:24:31,560 --> 00:24:33,870
in this dangerous world of ice.

179
00:24:49,080 --> 00:24:52,990
The annual melt has begun.

180
00:24:53,880 --> 00:24:57,710
This is a challenging time for the bear family.

181
00:24:57,840 --> 00:25:02,990
One out of every two cubs
do not survive their first year out on the ice.

182
00:25:14,040 --> 00:25:19,230
As the sun's influence increases,
the sea ice seems to take on a life of its own.

183
00:25:27,920 --> 00:25:32,310
Glacial melt waters pour from the land,
mingling with the sea

184
00:25:32,400 --> 00:25:34,270
and speeding up the thaw.

185
00:25:39,600 --> 00:25:42,430
The seascape is in constant flux

186
00:25:42,520 --> 00:25:46,390
as broken ice is moved on by winds and currents.

187
00:25:55,400 --> 00:26:00,150
The ice is becoming too weak
to support a male polar bear.

188
00:26:08,360 --> 00:26:10,950
He attempts to spread his weight,

189
00:26:11,080 --> 00:26:15,350
but the ice that has supported him all winter
is rapidly disintegrating.

190
00:26:18,000 --> 00:26:22,950
Each year, as the climate warms,
the Arctic holds less ice.

191
00:26:23,040 --> 00:26:26,030
This is a disaster for polar bears.

192
00:26:26,120 --> 00:26:27,830
Without its solid platform,

193
00:26:27,920 --> 00:26:32,110
they can't hunt the seals
they need in order to survive.

194
00:26:35,200 --> 00:26:38,510
This may be a glimpse of the unstable future

195
00:26:38,600 --> 00:26:41,430
faced by this magnificent creature.

196
00:27:13,880 --> 00:27:19,270
As the ice disappears,
seabirds return to the high Arctic.

197
00:27:27,400 --> 00:27:31,110
Little auks arrive in their millions.

198
00:27:33,160 --> 00:27:37,390
In some ways,
these birds are the penguins of the north.

199
00:27:37,520 --> 00:27:42,670
They seek bare rock on which to lay their eggs
and they look rather like penguins, too.

200
00:27:49,240 --> 00:27:54,150
Unlike Antarctica, the Arctic
can be reached by land-based predators,

201
00:27:54,240 --> 00:27:57,710
which is why little auks
have kept the ability to fly.

202
00:28:03,080 --> 00:28:08,670
They use scree slopes to protect their eggs,
burrowing up to a metre beneath the rocks.

203
00:28:15,760 --> 00:28:19,030
At the height of summer, the sun never sets,

204
00:28:19,120 --> 00:28:22,550
but just skims the horizon before rising again.

205
00:28:28,280 --> 00:28:32,590
Migrants return to the Arctic from far and wide.

206
00:28:33,320 --> 00:28:38,310
They've come to make the most of the brief flush
of food and to produce their young.

207
00:28:40,280 --> 00:28:44,270
Sandhill cranes have travelled
all the way from New Mexico.

208
00:28:50,240 --> 00:28:55,470
Their chicks join the growing band
of youngsters exploring the tundra.

209
00:29:02,560 --> 00:29:08,390
For a few months each year, the Arctic becomes
"The land of the midnight sun"

210
00:29:08,480 --> 00:29:13,190
and 24 hours of daylight
allow animals to feed around the clock.

211
00:29:15,120 --> 00:29:20,150
The arctic fox finally has enough food
to raise her large family.

212
00:29:35,400 --> 00:29:39,990
If you choose to nest in the open,
you must be prepared for a fight.

213
00:29:48,840 --> 00:29:53,990
Arctic skuas will see off any trespassers,
even large vegetarians.

214
00:30:39,000 --> 00:30:44,310
The male polar bear's ice world
has finally vanished beneath him.

215
00:30:56,080 --> 00:31:00,870
While the female is still kept on land
by her dependent cubs,

216
00:31:00,960 --> 00:31:04,390
the male can take to the sea in search of food.

217
00:31:04,480 --> 00:31:08,070
Ducking and diving, he hopes to ambush seals

218
00:31:08,160 --> 00:31:11,430
resting on the remaining fragments of ice.

219
00:31:37,440 --> 00:31:43,230
In these new surroundings,
he is a surprisingly adept swimmer.

220
00:31:53,240 --> 00:31:55,950
Once an extremely rare sight,

221
00:31:56,040 --> 00:32:00,630
polar bears have recently been seen
over 60 miles from the shore.

222
00:32:14,360 --> 00:32:18,270
There is now no turning back for this bear.

223
00:32:18,400 --> 00:32:21,950
He is forced to head out into deeper water.

224
00:32:29,520 --> 00:32:34,350
His giant front paws help him
to fight the ocean currents.

225
00:32:54,880 --> 00:32:59,830
He seems at home in the sea,
but he cannot swim indefinitely.

226
00:33:03,400 --> 00:33:08,710
He will drown if he doesn't find land
somewhere in this vast ocean.

227
00:33:35,640 --> 00:33:40,070
Walruses are now gathering on low-lying islands.

228
00:33:40,160 --> 00:33:44,470
They gave birth on the sea ice,
but with this platform now gone,

229
00:33:44,560 --> 00:33:48,350
they need a new place
to haul out and nurse their young.

230
00:33:50,840 --> 00:33:55,870
After several days at sea,
the male bear finally makes landfall,

231
00:33:55,960 --> 00:34:00,030
drawn by the pungent smells
emanating from the island.

232
00:34:08,160 --> 00:34:12,750
By the end of the summer,
the bear has lost half his weight.

233
00:34:12,840 --> 00:34:17,790
With the ice long gone,
he is forced onto land in search of food.

234
00:34:27,040 --> 00:34:30,550
There will be no easy meals on this island.

235
00:34:30,640 --> 00:34:33,830
Walruses are the largest seals in the world.

236
00:34:33,920 --> 00:34:38,790
They weigh over a ton
and are armed with tusks a metre long.

237
00:34:41,560 --> 00:34:46,190
Exhausted from his swim,
the bear must regain his strength.

238
00:34:53,120 --> 00:34:57,110
The next day, a sea fog shrouds the island.

239
00:34:57,200 --> 00:35:00,150
The walruses sense that they are in danger.

240
00:35:03,120 --> 00:35:07,190
Using the fog as cover,
the bear approaches the herd.

241
00:35:12,320 --> 00:35:14,990
The adults close ranks around their young,

242
00:35:15,080 --> 00:35:18,390
presenting a wall of blubber and hide.

243
00:35:25,600 --> 00:35:30,270
He tests the barrier, but it stands firm.

244
00:35:31,680 --> 00:35:36,470
It appears that the world's largest land carnivore
has met his match.

245
00:35:44,320 --> 00:35:47,470
There must be a chink in the armour somewhere.

246
00:35:50,920 --> 00:35:52,310
Not here!

247
00:36:00,920 --> 00:36:06,230
This female walrus is shielding her pup,
if he can just prise her off...

248
00:36:13,280 --> 00:36:17,670
The bear's claws and teeth
can't penetrate her thick hide.

249
00:36:26,280 --> 00:36:30,390
With the herd retreating to water,
the bear must move quickly.

250
00:36:35,680 --> 00:36:39,230
Having failed with one,
he heads straight for another.

251
00:36:56,320 --> 00:37:00,710
The chance of his first meal in months
is slipping away.

252
00:37:07,520 --> 00:37:09,910
He seems increasingly desperate.

253
00:37:15,520 --> 00:37:17,070
It's now or never.

254
00:37:18,440 --> 00:37:22,230
He must avoid the stabbing tusks if he is to win.

255
00:37:29,040 --> 00:37:32,030
The flailing walrus is immensely powerful

256
00:37:32,160 --> 00:37:36,590
and drags the bear away from the shallows
towards the safety of the herd.

257
00:37:52,080 --> 00:37:54,070
It slips from his grasp.

258
00:38:02,720 --> 00:38:04,950
Only at the height of summer,

259
00:38:05,080 --> 00:38:10,470
when bears are on the verge of starvation,
will they risk attacking such dangerous prey.

260
00:38:15,240 --> 00:38:18,390
It was a gamble that this bear took and lost.

261
00:38:21,800 --> 00:38:28,070
The stab wounds he received from the walrus
are so severe that he can barely walk.

262
00:38:32,960 --> 00:38:35,590
The walruses are calm again,

263
00:38:35,720 --> 00:38:41,350
seemingly aware that the injured bear
no longer poses a threat to them or their young.

264
00:38:57,200 --> 00:39:01,510
Unable to feed, this bear will not survive.

265
00:39:13,760 --> 00:39:19,990
If the global climate continues to warm,
and the Arctic ice melts sooner each year,

266
00:39:20,080 --> 00:39:23,910
it is certain that more bears will share this fate.

267
00:39:45,480 --> 00:39:51,910
At the southern end of our planet,
fiery ribbons are illuminating the winter skies.

268
00:39:52,000 --> 00:39:54,350
The aurora australis.

269
00:39:57,760 --> 00:40:01,830
This light brings no warmth to the male penguins,

270
00:40:01,960 --> 00:40:06,470
who are still huddling,
defying the coldest conditions on the planet.

271
00:40:20,320 --> 00:40:23,310
Their ordeal is drawing to a close.

272
00:40:31,200 --> 00:40:37,270
Thirty days after it last set,
the sun rises once more on Antarctica.

273
00:40:59,360 --> 00:41:03,510
Their appalling trials have all been for this.

274
00:41:19,280 --> 00:41:23,430
Each father has just one meal left inside him.

275
00:41:24,600 --> 00:41:27,550
He has been saving it all winter.

276
00:41:28,360 --> 00:41:33,910
This single feed will sustain the chicks
for a few more days,

277
00:41:34,000 --> 00:41:36,950
but the males have not eaten
for nearly four months.

278
00:41:37,040 --> 00:41:41,350
If they do not eat soon,
they and their chicks will die.

279
00:41:51,520 --> 00:41:55,030
But there is hope on the horizon.

280
00:42:06,160 --> 00:42:11,230
The females are returning
and their bellies are full with fish.

281
00:42:17,680 --> 00:42:21,630
As they approach, waves of excitement
ripple through the huddle.

282
00:42:30,200 --> 00:42:37,150
Each female calls to her mate
and he, recognising her song, trumpets back.

283
00:42:40,000 --> 00:42:42,470
Reunited at last.

284
00:42:45,800 --> 00:42:48,750
The mother sees her chick for the first time.

285
00:42:53,200 --> 00:42:56,070
She's keen to start parenting,

286
00:42:56,200 --> 00:43:01,350
but the father needs persuading to surrender
the chick he has been caring for all winter.

287
00:43:06,000 --> 00:43:08,710
He must now put his chick at risk.

288
00:43:08,800 --> 00:43:11,950
In these temperatures it could freeze in seconds.

289
00:43:15,920 --> 00:43:18,270
The male will have to let go.

290
00:43:25,000 --> 00:43:28,790
Eventually, the transfer to the mother
is safely made.

291
00:43:43,600 --> 00:43:47,670
The chicks grow quickly
on a diet of fish and squid.

292
00:44:01,640 --> 00:44:06,590
Soon they are keen to explore,
but always with mother in tow.

293
00:44:09,200 --> 00:44:14,430
This chick is less fortunate,
its mother has not returned to claim it.

294
00:44:16,840 --> 00:44:19,710
Another orphan is searching for a new family,

295
00:44:19,800 --> 00:44:23,270
but this female already has a chick of her own.

296
00:44:31,600 --> 00:44:34,230
Some orphans receive too much mothering

297
00:44:34,320 --> 00:44:37,550
from penguins whose own chicks
have not survived.

298
00:44:37,640 --> 00:44:41,790
The urge to parent is so strong
that they will compete with one another

299
00:44:41,880 --> 00:44:43,990
to adopt any chick they find.

300
00:44:49,080 --> 00:44:55,430
Many of these squabbles end in tragedy
as the poor chick is trampled to death.

301
00:45:07,240 --> 00:45:11,950
Those chicks that do have parents
quickly learn survival skills.

302
00:45:14,040 --> 00:45:17,150
Even in spring,
they must huddle together for warmth,

303
00:45:17,240 --> 00:45:20,870
just as their fathers did in the depths of winter.

304
00:45:24,520 --> 00:45:27,430
A group of chicks has got lost in the blizzard.

305
00:45:34,400 --> 00:45:38,150
Cold and disorientated, they search for the colony.

306
00:45:44,880 --> 00:45:49,750
It will not be long
before the storm claims its first victims.

307
00:46:07,920 --> 00:46:12,910
By early summer,
the chicks are surprisingly well-developed

308
00:46:13,000 --> 00:46:16,470
and now look ready to take on the world.

309
00:46:17,960 --> 00:46:22,590
Those that survive their first year
have the best possible start in life

310
00:46:22,680 --> 00:46:27,230
thanks to the extraordinary hardships
endured by their parents.

311
00:46:28,200 --> 00:46:33,510
Parents who battled
with the Antarctic winter and won.

312
00:46:42,920 --> 00:46:48,070
In the Arctic, the two polar bear cubs
are now independent of their mother

313
00:46:48,160 --> 00:46:51,830
and they briefly reunite
where their home ranges overlap.

314
00:46:59,200 --> 00:47:02,310
Their time together will be fleeting.

315
00:47:02,400 --> 00:47:08,910
Most of their lives are now spent alone,
wandering the vast tracts of frozen ocean.

316
00:47:37,160 --> 00:47:41,670
Following their mother has prepared them
for life at the pole,

317
00:47:41,760 --> 00:47:45,590
an ever-changing land ruled by ice.

318
00:47:47,640 --> 00:47:49,750
Whether they are ready for the bigger changes

319
00:47:49,840 --> 00:47:55,190
that have begun to shape the ice worlds
of our planet remains to be seen.

