["OGUERE" PLAYING]
[MAN] Hey!
[IN SPANISH] Hey, ladies.
Are you looking for something?
We're just taking a ride.
Can't we pass?
No, sweetheart. You have to go back.
[ENGINE REVVING]
Listen...
Do you want to hang out
later back in town?
- What?
- I said...
[GRUNTS]
[TRUCK ENGINE STARTS]
[INDISTINCT PLEADING]
No, no, no!
[GUNFIRE]
[DISTANT SCREAMS]
- Julio.
- Pacho, you motherfucker.
Motherfucking dog!
[GERDA] Let me go!
- [THUMPING]
- [GRUNTING]
[GERDA] Let go of me!
Let me go!
Let go...!
You.
Mrs. Salazar.
Do you know what makes me happy, Pacho?
Makes me very happy?
That my sons didn't kill
your brother Alvaro.
Because he's going to live
the rest of his life...
as half a man. Half man, half...
[LIGHTER OPENS]
[FLICKING LIGHTER]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[LIGHTER CLOSES]
[WOMAN] Help!
Help!
[MELANCHOLIC GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com
[SAMPER] ...the great
event of the surrender
of Helmer Herrera, to Colombian justice.
And this incident marked the
end of the Cali cartel...
who were responsible, according
to international sources,
for more than 80% of the cocaine
trafficking in the world.
Throughout my campaign and presidency,
I committed to dismantling all
narcotrafficking networks,
and we're doing it.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] The Colombian
government was quick to claim victory.
The arrest of Miguel Rodríguez and
the surrenders of Pacho Herrera...
and Chepe Santacruz...
looked like big wins
in The War on Drugs.
But they were bullshit.
[CUMBIA MUSIC PLAYING]
The only real victory belonged
to the godfathers of Cali,
safely ensconced in a Bogotá jail...
Leave that there.
...still billionaires,
submitting to a justice that
they had bought and paid for.
They didn't need to
build their own prison.
Hello, sweetie.
The minimum security wing of
La Picota would do just fine.
They wouldn't be there long.
[IN SPANISH] Gilberto. How've you been?
[GILBERTO] Good, brother.
Grateful that we're all together.
The investment we made in
our friends can bear fruit.
And then all this will pass away
like some old joke you
can't quite remember.
For this, gentlemen, I propose a toast.
Of course you would.
[GILBERTO] Fucking Chepe.
Gilberto, I'd like to say a few words.
You all know this wasn't what I wanted.
So it's very hard for me to admit
that I know this is for the best.
And thanks to you, we're on the
verge of, how do you call it?
"A great victory."
We believe in you.
To my brother, Gilberto. Our leader.
Gentlemen of Cali... salud!
- Cheers!
- [CLINKING]
[CUMBIA MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC ENDS]
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[IN ENGLISH] Don't worry about it.
[GIRLS CHATTERING]
Agent Peña.
[IN SPANISH] Hello.
- [IN ENGLISH] Can we talk?
- Yeah. Give me a second.
[IN SPANISH] Go with your mom.
[IN ENGLISH] Checked with the embassy,
finishing up paperwork this afternoon.
You're on a flight tomorrow.
First thing.
Guillermo Pallomari.
You have any idea
where we can find him?
No. Why do you need him?
Gilberto and Miguel Rodríguez
gave six million dollars
to Samper's presidential campaign.
So unless we get Pallomari in the
States testifying on the cartel,
generating new indictments...
- What are you telling me?
- The godfathers won't stay locked up.
What do you think's gonna
happen to my family
if these men keep all their
money, all their power?
Well, Witness Protection Services
will provide security for
as long as you need.
Pallomari's wife is having an affair.
- With who?
- Some guy at her office. Fredy Moya.
Phones in the cartel safe
house, they're tapped.
I overheard a conversation between them.
It didn't sound like business.
And he can keep them in prison?
We find Pallomari or
the godfathers walk.
You're not gonna find him without me.
[CHUCKLES] You're right.
[DOOR BUZZER SOUNDS]
[IN SPANISH] Go ahead, sir.
Director.
Don Miguel.
Please, go ahead.
["SHOOK ONES PART II" PLAYING ON RADIO]
♪ To all the killers And
the 100-dollar billers ♪
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
- Hello.
- [MIGUEL] It's me.
- Where are we on Pallomari?
- We put Navegante on it, Dad.
I'll find him, don't worry about it.
And fucking Salcedo too, you'll see.
David, don't take your eye off Henao.
That motherfucker might see this as
an opportunity. Keep a low profile.
♪ You heard of us ♪
Sure, don't worry.
♪ The Mobb comes
equipped with warfare ♪
[EXHALES]
- How's María?
- I really don't know.
How come you don't know? Make
sure she's taken care of.
It's very important
you handle Pallomari.
That motherfucker could ruin everything.
Call me when it's done.
♪ Like they supposed to ♪
♪ They come around But
they never come close to ♪
[CHITTERS]
- Guillermo?
- I need your help, Gonzalo.
You know I can't get involved.
Nothing is going to happen to you.
When has anything happened to you?
I'm asking you for legal
advice, and quickly.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
I've decided that the best way
to get out of this situation
is to turn myself in to the authorities.
Yes, normally that would
be the case. Yes.
But the problem is you already have
a warrant out for your arrest.
An arrest warrant?
The police won't protect you. In
fact, they'll probably kill you.
I'm the head accountant.
And every dollar in this
organization, and every secret,
has been through this head.
It's all in here.
Tell whoever needs to know
I'm willing to negotiate.
Guillermo, my advice to you is to
get your family and leave Cali.
My wife's very attached to her work.
- What? I don't understand.
- You know her, she's stubborn.
She built her business
from the ground up.
[VOICE BREAKING] I can't
leave without her.
Look, Guillermo... this is not my
legal advice, but as your friend...
talk some sense into your wife.
Immediately.
[PANTING]
Can you get me a gun?
We'll have to look out for
ourselves the rest of our lives,
but if I help them...
maybe one day we can
come back to Colombia.
Are you insane? They almost killed us.
They almost killed us, and now you're
telling me you want to go back? To Cali?
Do you really think we can
come back to Colombia?
The moment we come back to Colombia,
they'll kill our daughters.
Are you doing this to make up for
the last four years of your life?
I'm a good man.
I was a good man.
I'll leave with the girls tomorrow.
I'm not waiting for you.
Wait for me, okay? Thanks.
That way.
[RAP MUSIC PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Keep looking for him. No
more fucking excuses.
Okay.
[BEEPS]
Yeah?
Have you heard from your father?
Yes.
David, I've been wondering about the
arrangement I had for my son and...
Arrangement?
I thought it was true love.
Your father knows I care about him.
[SNIFFS] That's beautiful.
Seriously.
But here's the thing...
You don't mean anything to me.
You're not my mother.
You're not my fucking problem.
- David...
- What?
What the fuck do I owe you?
María.
Open your legs for someone else.
You're good at that.
Okay?
[IN ENGLISH] Once we step off this
plane, whatever goes down is on me.
We are way off the well-lit path.
[WHIRRING]
Jorge.
["MUÉVELO" PLAYING]
[IN SPANISH] Good afternoon, Mr.
Salcedo.
Mr. Espinosa's still at lunch.
He should be back soon.
- We'll wait for him inside.
- Okay, sir.
[WOMAN] Another drink?
I need to go. See you next week.
[VAN NESS] Excuse me.
How are the girls here?
The best of Cali.
Open it!
Get in.
Get in, motherfucker!
[GRUNTING]
Okay.
[KEYBOARD CLICKING]
ACCESS RESTRICTED PASSWORD REQUIRED
- Good afternoon.
- I'm looking for Fredy Moya.
- Yes.
- The one wearing purple.
- Thanks.
[FREDY] Don't pull my chain.
I'm looking at the numbers.
Excuse me. You work with
Patricia Pallomari?
Javier Peña, DEA.
I'll call you back.
[IN ENGLISH] Patricia's taken
a temporary leave of absence.
That so?
You have any idea where I can find her?
I wouldn't know.
She in trouble?
No, but her husband is.
There's a warrant out for his arrest
and a pretty substantial reward.
Any information is helpful.
[PHONE RINGING]
- [PATRICIA] Hello.
- It's me.
Baby, I can't talk right now.
Call me back later.
No. Wait, I can't call you back. Wait.
Yes.
Yes, I'd have to check my
records in the office.
[WHISPERING] I can't talk.
- Wait.
- Patricia, the DEA was just here.
The DEA. Asking questions.
- [PATRICIA] What did you tell them?
- To go fuck themselves.
They want Guillermo, not you.
[PATRICIA] Can't talk.
Discuss it later.
[JORGE IN ENGLISH] That's her.
[FREDY IN SPANISH] They
talked about reward.
[IN ENGLISH] So, she used the line
in an apartment in the
north part of the city.
[IN SPANISH] We need to take advantage.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- [GUILLERMO] Need to use the bathroom.
- [BEEPS]
[SIGHS]
Work again?
Yes.
Excuse me.
Open the window this time.
This way.
[LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING]
[EXHALES]
I'd offer a drink, but I don't
pour liquor for Cali whores.
Have a seat.
Don Orlando, I'm here to
ask for your protection.
Why?
You don't feel safe?
I did what I had to
after my husband died.
Now I'm in your home... ready
to do what I have to again.
So what is it you're offering me?
[DARÍO] In here.
How was the drive?
It was easy.
Nice place.
Let me start by thanking
you for the meeting.
We're both busy men. I
won't waste your time.
But I'm a business man, like you.
The information you seek maybe,
maybe, maybe is in my possession.
If we come to an arrangement,
my information becomes yours.
You feel me?
On the phone, you told me you
know where Pallomari is.
Correct?
Look, let me put it this way...
Patricia and I are in love.
[CHUCKLES]
We want to be together.
So Guillermo's a problem for me.
From what I've heard, he's a
problem for you too. Am I right?
You are correct.
So maybe we can help each other.
If we come to an arrangement,
my information becomes yours.
[SNIFFS]
Okay.
- Let me fix you a drink. Okay?
- Sure.
By the way... are you guys
running Windows 95 yet?
Think we're going to wait for next year.
Where the fuck is Pallomari, you faggot?
[GROANING]
Did you hear me?
[YELLING]
Here's the milk. Just a few
minutes and then you go to bed.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- [WHISPERING] Get in your room.
- [PATRICIA] Who is it? Who is it?
I don't know. Get in your room. Quickly.
[DOORKNOB JIGGLING]
- [IN ENGLISH] Drop the gun! Put it down!
- Drop your weapon!
- [PEÑA IN SPANISH] It's okay.
- They're the gringos.
- Calm down.
- Do you know them?
- They came to my office.
- Put the gun down.
Close the door.
[IN ENGLISH] We're here to help you.
[IN SPANISH] Close the door.
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
[IN ENGLISH] Lower your gun.
You understand?
[PANTING]
I'd put the safety on.
Sorry.
Do you want to sit?
[CAR APPROACHING]
Okay, DEA, are we speaking English or
Spanish or...? I don't give a shit.
Colombians have a warrant
for your arrest.
- I know.
- And the cartel wants you dead.
I'm well aware of that.
The only way you survive this is if
we get you out to the United States.
Guillermo.
The United States.
[PEÑA] We have your ledger.
You decode it for us and you
testify on what you know...
That's quite a bit.
...and we make sure that you
and your family are safe.
Which place in the United States?
I'm not sure. We
have a program that...
[GUILLERMO] Yeah, I know. The program.
But if I'm giving up my life...
I want to know what I'm getting for it.
For instance, which kind
of house will we have?
My family requires a certain
amount of square footage.
It wasn't hard for us to find you
and it won't be hard for them.
You understand that?
This is your chance to
keep your family alive.
We will negotiate the details later.
This is the only option you have.
Do you understand that?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Why don't you pack your things,
as little as possible.
[IN SPANISH] No, Guillermo. We
can't leave for at least a week.
- You heard them.
- The company. I can't just leave.
- We must go.
- I need at least a week.
Okay!
Put the radio on the dash...
and your hands on the wheel.
How are you, Jorge Salcedo?
[IN ENGLISH] Help your kids
pack, let me talk to your wife.
Yeah.
[IN SPANISH] I know about Fredy Moya.
It's none of my business.
You're right. It's not your problem.
You realize what happens
if they find you?
And your kids?
I have to say goodbye to him.
We're in love. I can't leave like that.
Mrs. Pallomari, if you stay, you die.
Understood?
I'll be honest with you.
The truth is...
I was very disappointed to
hear you were the fucking rat.
But I still like you.
It's all good. I'm not
going to kill you.
David Rodríguez...
he wants to do it himself
personally, you know?
That's fine by me.
That way, our friendship
will remain intact.
[GROWLS]
- Let's go.
- [GUILLERMO] Come on!
- The jacket...
- Okay, that's it. Let's go.
[IN ENGLISH] We're on our way down.
[PEÑA OVER RADIO] Salcedo,
we're in the lobby now.
Are we clear?
Salcedo.
[IN SPANISH] Tell them to come out.
[IN ENGLISH] Jorge, we clear or not?
[IN SPANISH] Tell them to
come out, Jorge Salcedo.
[IN ENGLISH] All clear.
Copy.
All right, stay close.
[IN SPANISH] Let's finish this.
[COCKS GUN]
Put the gun down.
I don't want to kill you.
We both know that's a lie.
[SCREAMING]
[IN ENGLISH] Get down!
Get behind the car!
[IN SPANISH] Over there!
[BULLET SHELLS FALLING]
- [CHILDREN WHIMPER]
- [SIRENS SOUNDING]
[IN ENGLISH] What the fuck happened?
He has the keys.
- Let's move!
- Come on, get in the car!
Let's go!
- [FEISTL] Drive.
- Patricia!
[PATRICIA IN SPANISH] Don't look!
Don't look! Don't look! Don't look!
[SIRENS GETTING CLOSER]
Don't look! Don't look at that!
What the fuck is he doing here?
[IN ENGLISH] He saved your life!
Get in the fucking car!
[PATRICIA BANGING] Open! Open!
[SCREAMS]
Be careful, be careful. Okay.
[VAN NESS IN ENGLISH] Move, move, move!
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
[CAR DOORS CLOSING]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[BEEPS]
[DAVID IN SPANISH] What happened? Huh?
They killed Navegante.
And Pallomari?
The motherfucker's gone.
You sure?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
We're going to the airport.
We're going to catch those...
We're leaving, now!
Motherfuckers!
[PANTING]
You, come with me.
We're going to the airport.
Take the guys. Now, now, now!
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE]
[GRUNTING]
That's the North Valley, fuckers.
Who do they think they're messing with?
You just got smoked, bitches.
[GASPING]
Boss!
[GUILLERMO] Let's go. Out.
- [IN ENGLISH] Could you open, please?
- Yes.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
[IN SPANISH] Patricia, get out this way.
Careful, my love.
Okay.
[IN ENGLISH] What's this?
You're wanted by the CNP.
We can't aid the escape of a fugitive,
so you've gotta fly yourself out.
[IN SPANISH] Do you see that?
We have a private plane.
We have a plane just for us.
[IN ENGLISH] If you
could sign here, sir?
Me? Okay.
Yeah.
You have to pay for the plane.
Whatever you have on you.
I don't carry that kind of cash.
It's just a technicality. So
that it's not kidnapping.
Just a moment.
If it's just a technicality...
Thanks.
- Okay.
[IN SPANISH] Get on the plane. Go.
Everything is going to be fine.
Come on. Let's go.
Goodbye, Salcedo.
[AIRPLANE ENGINES WHIRRING]
[FLAMENCO MUSIC PLAYING]
[IN ENGLISH] Ladies and gentlemen,
my next witness has direct,
first-hand knowledge
of the criminal activities uncovered
by Operation Cornerstone.
Please state your name, sir.
Guillermo Pallomari.
And you were an accountant
for the Cali cartel?
No, I was the chief accountant.
The chief.
El jefe.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] Guillermo
Pallomari had a lot to say.
And he said it in federal courtrooms
from Miami to New York City.
This is the ledger of Mr. Pallomaro
that only he himself can interpret.
I'm sorry, Your Honor, my English is not
quite good, but his Spanish is awful.
Can you repeat my name?
"Pallomari." It's so simple.
[PEÑA] And people were interested
in what he had to say,
especially about the cartel's influence
with the Colombian government.
So that government
went on the defensive.
[IN SPANISH] And we have total
agreement in that these testimonies
that we have heard from Mr. Pallomari
are ridiculous and grotesquely false.
- Thank you very much.
- [PEÑA IN ENGLISH] The damage was done.
It would be most helpful
if the Colombian president,
who's head of the government
was as dedicated to fighting
narcotics trafficking
as many of the people
in his own government.
[PEÑA] The U.S. House and Senate began
making noise about decertification,
turning Colombia from an ally in
The War on Drugs into an enemy,
threatening to choke off
the vital foreign aid
that served the shadowy
interests of both nations.
And that scared people.
Enough to see justice finally done?
Well, governments don't work that way.
[CROSBY] Know how many
times I've gotten a call
from the Department of Justice
and State the same morning?
Count 'em on one finger.
Guess we have you to thank for that.
I'm headed over to the
National Palace right now,
to make clear to
President Samper himself
that the godfathers stay in jail.
- At least for the foreseeable future.
- But that's as far as it goes?
We drew up a draft indictment outlining.
President Samper's ties
to the Cali cartel.
Alleged ties.
And I suggest you keep
that draft to yourself.
The DOJ's not going to topple
a government, Agent Peña.
You can't tell me you're
surprised by that.
Some part of me was holding
out hope, I guess.
Well, you should tell that
part to grow the fuck up.
No, I mean it, Agent Peña.
You should be happy.
You played the system
like a goddamn fiddle.
[CHUCKLES]
You won.
Yes, sir.
[PEÑA] Another deal.
A compromise.
A charade.
A way for governments
who don't give a shit
about the war they're
supposed to be fighting...
to go on pretending they're winning it.
But it can't be won.
It'll never be won.
At least not until people
see it for what it is.
Not until they know the truth.
[IN SPANISH] You know what it means
if you go on the record, right?
There'll be a price to pay.
Press the button.
[CLICKS]
Let's start with your
name and occupation.
Javier Peña, DEA attaché in Colombia.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] And
so the truth got out.
The news that the Cali cartel had
donated to the president's campaign...
in exchange for virtual immunity...
turned Colombia upside down.
And when the highest-ranking DEA agent
in the country went on the record
and said not only did the
United States know about it,
but we allowed it to happen...
they couldn't hide from it anymore.
[REPORTER IN SPANISH]
An exclusive interview.
He accuses the country of
being a Narco-Democracy.
He said the country has
fallen into the abyss.
His words have not been well
received by the Colombian people.
The public is demanding an
official response from...
[TURNS OFF TV]
[IN ENGLISH] You didn't really call
the country that we're guests in
a "Narco-Democracy."
Are you saying it isn't?
- The State Department's livid.
- Good.
They're responsible. We all are.
Samper is not going anywhere.
Well, at least people know the truth.
I want you gone, Peña.
So do the Colombians.
I understand, sir.
You know... any aspirations
you had for your career...
just got dragged behind
the barn and shot.
I resigned from the DEA this morning.
[TROPICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[IN SPANISH] Recordings
that link the president
with narcotrafficking have been leaked.
[GILBERTO] The reality is
they need five million.
- [MIGUEL] Uh-huh.
- We're missing three, see?
- We have it.
- Yes?
Yes, that's done.
This scandal threatens elected
president Ernesto Samper's career
if the authorities confirm his campaign
was funded by narcotrafficking money.
[CHANTING] President Samper, the
only solution is your resignation!
Colombians can be certain...
that if they prove any money
transfer of any kind,
the deposit would've been
made behind my back.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] The Colombians
called the scandal "Proceso 8000."
And it set into motion
a series of events...
that finally brought the reign of
the Cali godfathers to an end.
Chepe Santacruz never did
make it back to New York.
Without the government's guarantee that
their sentences would be minimal...
Chepe decided that prison wasn't
the best place for him to be.
And so... he released himself...
and set out in search of new alliances,
with partners who could help
him rebuild the empire.
You won't believe who he chose.
Don Chepe.
[IN SPANISH] I was happy
to get your call.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] Predictably,
it wasn't much of a partnership.
It seems the Castaños expected a
larger contribution to their cause...
than Chepe was comfortable making.
[THUMPING]
So the alliance died quickly.
And Chepe Santacruz's wild ride...
came to an end.
Pacho Herrera didn't fare
much better staying in jail.
Vendettas in the drug game never end.
[CHEERING]
And Pacho's war on the Salazars...
made him some lifelong
North Valley enemies.
[SCREAMS]
Motherfucker!
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] And as for the
Rodríguez-Orejuela brothers,
political pressure from the U.S.,
and a disgraced Colombian president
who needed to prove he
was tough on narcos...
brought back the only
effective weapon we have
in The War on Drugs: Extradition.
All out of favors and
unlikely to find more,
they will spend the rest of
their lives in a U.S. prison.
The good guys didn't do much better.
BETRAYAL PAYS
Back in Colombia, Jorge Salcedo
was publicly branded a rat.
The danger that he put himself in to
ensure the success of our operation...
And in the States, despite testimony
that he was instrumental to our efforts
to capture and prosecute
the Cali godfathers,
he still had to plead guilty
to felony conspiracy charges.
And from there, Jorge Salcedo...
the guy who had the most to do with
bringing down the Cali cartel...
disappeared into the Federal
Witness Protection Program...
somewhere in the U.S.
A prison of its own.
You knew him, right?
Agent Camarena?
Of him. My first assignment
out of the academy
was a task force that searched
for him in Guadalajara.
It all started there.
Before him, we didn't even
know we were in a war.
Another hot one down there for you, huh?
You took down the big
players in Colombia.
Yeah, well... we'll make new ones.
Don't turn a victory
into a defeat, Javier.
The Colombian super-cartels are gone.
And whoever comes next are gonna be
fighting amongst themselves for years.
They're still only going to be a
shadow of what Medellín and Cali were.
And now it's time to take the fight to
the real enemy in The War on Drugs.
Mexico.
"The real enemy"?
Let me put in some calls.
I'll make this bullshit
resignation go away.
What else is a guy like you gonna do?
["XOCHICUICATL" PLAYING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[CHATTER IN SPANISH]
All right, fellas. Let's move.
Keep going.
- [BOAT MOTOR WHIRRING]
- Keep going.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER CAR RADIO]
[GRUNTS]
[IN ENGLISH] You helping
me with this or not?
I thought I was getting a partner.
Come on, Pop. Give me that.
[IN SPANISH] Stubborn.
[IN ENGLISH] Stand here for an hour
and you'll count 20 of 'em going by.
[IN SPANISH] So...
do you have to fix the fence
every time a storm hits?
Someone has to do it.
That's how life works.
[HORSE SNORTS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[IN ENGLISH] You thinking
of taking them up on it?
Mexico.
It's different there.
- Son, let me tell you...
- Dad.
I've done enough.
I'm through.
Hand me that cutter.
- [GRUNTS]
- [BOAT MOTOR WHIRRING]
["QUE NO QUEDE HUELLA" PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com
[MUSIC FADES]