[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] The Cali cartel
is an almost-perfect organism.
Even though we had cut off its head,
the body kept right on going,
making and selling cocaine.
They stuck to the plan.
And for a long time, that
plan had worked for them.
[IN SPANISH] The guy is innocent.
He didn't do any of it.
Easy, honey, easy, okay? Be careful.
The glove.
Screw the fucking glove, brother.
- That Fuhrman's a son of a bitch.
- He's an asshole.
- And he's been fucking the sister.
- Which one?
The sister! I don't even know her name.
Geraldo is fucking her, too.
[PEÑA IN ENGLISH] But
no plan is perfect.
Especially when you deal with a
substance as volatile as cocaine.
At some point... you're
gonna make a mistake.
And your enemies are
watching and waiting.
They're gonna see your
weakness and make a move.
See, that's the thing about plans.
No matter how perfect
you think they are...
however brilliant or
audacious they may be...
well, they can still go to shit
when that one thing goes wrong.
- [GLASS SHATTERING]
- [SCREAMING]
And once that happens,
there's no going back.
It's all downhill from there.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com
[SIGHS]
Oh, hey, hey.
[FEISTL] Think that's him?
[VAN NESS] Has to be.
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
[GEARS CHANGING]
Let's go.
[VAN NESS] Close enough.
Lift up your shirt. Turn around.
[IN ENGLISH] I'm unarmed.
Approach slowly, hands out.
- You told nobody about this?
- [VAN NESS] Nobody.
- And you weren't followed?
- We're clean.
You headed north to Yumbo
instead of east from Cali.
And then straight on to Rozo.
I had to make sure you are who you
say you are. That you're alone.
Get in the car.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're in the front seat.
I'm Chris Feistl. This is Daniel...
Daniel Van Ness. I know your names.
What about yours?
I don't want to be here
more than two minutes.
This is the only time we're
gonna speak face-to-face.
So you said you work for
the Rodríguez brothers.
I'm the chief of security
for the Cali cartel.
- You're the head of security?
- Yes.
I have valuable information for you.
In exchange, I want safe passage for
my family and myself to the States.
Once there, with full immunity,
I'll help you in any way I can.
Listen, here's the thing, man. You're
head of security for the cartel.
You have a lot more to offer
us than just testimony.
Like Miguel Rodríguez.
Is that gonna be a problem?
Besides the fact that we're
all gonna end up dead?
There's a security
system that I designed.
Safe houses, lookouts on every corner,
a radio communication system.
- We can work around all that.
- Maybe.
Then there's David, Miguel's son.
He personally controls his
father's security now.
- I don't even know where he is.
- But you can find out.
And if I do? The police? The military?
You can't trust them. I pay them.
We can get guys we trust, all right?
Don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it? [CHUCKLES]
No. I'll testify. That's it.
Let me ask you something. Why are
you doing this? Talking to us?
I'm not a murderer. I'm not like them.
I want to get my family out.
Well, we'd love to help
you with that, but...
we can't do that unless
you give us Miguel.
[VAN NESS] And honestly, we
don't need your testimony.
Bottom line, you have a better
option, you're free to take it.
I need to think about this.
Still didn't catch your name.
Jorge. Salcedo.
[EXHALES]
[CAR DOOR THUMPS]
I think we found a gold mine.
Guy says he's head of security for
the cartel and he wants to roll?
They don't call it the Cali
KGB for nothing, Chris.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
[PEÑA]Franklin Jurado.
One testimony from him and he can
take down the entire Cali cartel.
He travels on multiple passports.
So, he gets on a flight, we lose
him who the fuck knows where.
I need him on a plane today so that
he's testifying in Miami tomorrow.
[IN PAPIAMENTO] Okay, listen up.
[IN ENGLISH] We'll provide
Agent Peña and his men
with any support they require.
[IN PAPIAMENTO] Understood?
[IN ENGLISH] Okay, typically, he
goes to a cooperative credit bank
and then has breakfast.
- We sit on it and get him there.
- Hey, hey.
You plan to take him at the bank?
Mm-hmm.
You cannot do that, Agent Peña.
[PEÑA] Here's what you need
to know about Curaçao.
It's a smuggler's paradise.
And for the Cali cartel, you
can't beat the location.
Only 40 miles separates South
American coast from Curaçaon ports,
prized for centuries by smugglers,
slave traders, and now cartels.
Cruise ships filled with old people
next to speed boats filled with cash.
And what doesn't get smuggled through,
it ends up in banks. Hundreds of them.
Way back, some enterprising Dutchmen
set up a financial system
cloaked in old-world secrecy.
Their economy is so dependent on
money launderers parking their cash,
that you can make an arrest,
just not at or near a bank.
DI STREA BANK CURAÇAO
Of course, where do you think
Franklin spent most of his time?
All right, we tail him. And then we
catch him somewhere that suits us both.
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Okay.
Okay, let's go.
[JORGE IN SPANISH] Good
morning, gentlemen.
[ALL] Good morning.
As many of you know,
since Córdova's resignation,
I am the head of security.
It's festival time. That means
the city will be crowded.
The festival is not an
excuse to party on the job.
One more thing. David and his team will
now be handling security for his father.
Let's make them feel welcome.
And help them any way you can.
That's all, boys. Get going!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Wow. Look at you. You're sliding
into your new job like a glove.
You're a natural.
Look, David, if we're going to work
together, we need to cooperate.
Mm...
If you have questions or you want to
talk about your father's security...
I'm here.
Thank you.
I do have a question, Jorge.
How come none of your men
carry fucking guns? Huh?
Because we use our walkies
if we have a problem.
For what? To say goodbye
when you're getting clipped?
Do me a favor, Jorge.
You do your thing, I'll do mine.
All right?
Boss, you didn't mention the
DEA agents that are in Cali.
That's something David
might be interested in.
Listen, the last thing we need
right now is David and his crew
killing a federal agent, no?
Well, that's true.
For now, we'll monitor
the DEA ourselves.
Besides... I doubt they have much.
[AMPARO CRYING]
I don't want to leave New York, Chepe.
- [SOBS] Why, Chepe?
- My love...
I know you don't want to
leave New York. I know.
I don't either.
But if they connect this lab to us...
we're going to have every
cop in the city after us.
Hey, look.
Here it comes.
Spokesmen for the DEA say that the
cocaine lab that exploded in Queens
was operated by a Dominican gang.
Exactly! Thank you, lady.
Fucking Dominicans!
But Manuel de Dios, editor of La Prensa,
has discovered another
side to the story.
This lab, along with a number
of others in the area,
was recently seized by
Colombian gangsters,
led by a man going by
the name Victor Crespo.
- Motherfucker.
- In the next few days,
we will be publishing
an investigative series
about this criminal enterprise,
including pictures.
This operation is much
larger than it seems.
"No speak Spanish" my ass.
So that means we have
to leave, right, Chepe?
No, my love.
This man, he knows who you are, Chepe.
Don't worry. We're not going anywhere.
Is that so?
So do me a favor and fix this.
Did you hear me?
Motherfucker.
[MIGUEL] So a new surrender deal.
[NICOLÁS] Three years in jail.
All of you.
Turn in the illicit businesses, and
we can keep all of the legal assets,
as in the old plan. It's a good deal.
He would've told you himself,
but he thought it was best
for me to explain in person.
Besides, I helped negotiate the deal.
I understand. Thank you
for coming, Nicolás.
Give me an update, Uncle Miguel.
An update?
On our efforts to maximize
business before surrender.
So I can inform my father.
Tell your dad everything's
still on track here.
Pacho's settled new terms
with Amado Carrillo Fuentes
and is coming back soon.
And this accident in New York?
Chepe encountered an obstacle,
but you know Chepe.
I'm not worried.
Are we done?
One last thing.
Our friends in Bogotá are
concerned about their exposure.
Too many people know about the deal.
They worry about Mr. Pallomari.
My father would like you to handle it.
"Handle it"?
Do you know what you're talking about?
Do you have any idea?
Hmm?
Pallomari's our chief accountant
in Cali, and not easily replaced.
He's too valuable to just kill.
Tell your father I'll take care of it.
He doesn't have to
worry about Pallomari.
Thank you, Uncle Miguel.
Take care.
So now the little prince
is giving you orders?
His father's orders.
Have Salcedo put Pallomari
in one of the safe houses.
Keep an eye on him.
You decide if you're coming tonight?
Our Salsa Festival party, Dad.
It's important.
You know how I feel about parties.
That's Gilberto's thing, not mine.
Which is exactly why you should go.
Dad, you're the new boss here.
Please, show them.
Or at least have a good time before
we have to roll over and play dead.
[PEÑA] Now why would a Cali
godfather come out of hiding
and risk getting captured?
Because what good is being
the king if nobody knows it?
The biggest thing to come out of
Cali wasn't cocaine. It was salsa.
And every year, the two combined
at the annual Feria de Cali,
a week-long extravaganza of
parties and salsa concerts.
And the man who always presided
over the opening-night festivities?
Gilberto Rodríguez.
[IN SPANISH] Cheers, gentlemen!
[PEÑA] But with him in jail,
it was time for a new king.
[IN SPANISH] How would you
like to be my date tonight?
Hmm...
Where would we go?
Come here.
♪ Let's go dancing ♪
Do you like dancing?
[JORGE]As discussed with Don Miguel,
he'd like you to keep working from here.
Yes, I know what needs to be done.
Come in.
Guillermo, what's this? You've
got to be kidding, right?
- You're playing me for a fool.
- What's this?
This is unacceptable. I
need to speak to Miguel.
Talk to whoever you want. This is the
biggest apartment we have right now.
- Three bedrooms. Two bathrooms.
- Uh-huh.
A/C. Kids seem to like it.
- Kids, do you like it?
- Yes!
Really, Patricia. You
going to smoke inside?
What's the problem? This is a dump.
The boys are here.
Oh, now you're concerned about the boys?
Do not leave this apartment,
for your own safety.
Everything you've done for these people,
and this is how they repay you?
[IN ENGLISH] Yeah. Got it.
Thanks, Stoddard.
All right, last hit Duffy
and López had on Salcedo,
he was deputy chief of
security for the cartel.
All right. So that much is true.
Had a degree in engineering.
Business license for a bio-diesel
factory that went belly-up.
- Wonder why.
- Ex-military.
Served under a Carlo Córdova. Major.
Who became head of
security for the cartel.
Must have been how he got the job.
Wonder if he clipped his old
buddy to take his spot.
And he was connected to the purchase
of bombs in a plan to kill Pablo.
Oh, just that?
Does that sound like the
everyman who only signed on
- to protect Miguel's family to you?
- Okay.
So he's a scumbag. Last I checked,
he's our best bet to get Miguel.
Scumbags I can handle. What
I don't like are liars.
So when he calls back
with Miguel's location...
- how you want to play it?
- If he calls at all,
we ask the hard questions,
see how he holds up.
[HENAO IN SPANISH] I'm
telling you, they're done.
Gilberto's looking for
some new way to surrender.
And you heard about this thing
in New York with Chepe, right?
And Miguel's in charge
of everything here.
Better said, the Cali cartel is dead.
[AMADO] And you intend to...?
To do whatever I have to do
for the North Valley cartel.
Which is why I'm talking to you.
[SNIFFING]
It's funny how things change, isn't it?
So, Amado... what do you say?
[SIGHS]
I say you're no fucking
fun, that's what I say.
But we both see the future the same way.
Look, starting next week...
I'll only be shipping product for
my new North Valley friends. Good?
And what about the other
thing we discussed?
[SNIFFS]
[DAVID] Look, I need
you to make room here.
And I want you to take care of the
guests, get them everything they need.
I also want a bottle at
each of these tables.
But I want the good stuff. None
of that shit you serve here.
Understood?
I was told you needed me.
I need to talk about something.
Leave your bitch down here.
Come on.
[SIGHS]
You don't tell anyone about this, okay?
I was thinking about what you said...
if I ever need your advice, and...
I could use your help.
With your father's security.
He's coming to the party tonight.
He's coming here?
Unless there's another fucking party
I don't know about? Yeah, here.
What do you want me to tell you, David?
Public places are always bad.
I know.
Too many people.
When does he plan on arriving?
I was thinking around 11:00.
Well, what fucking time is best, then?
Well, I think ten is better.
It's less crowded. Maybe I can
take him up to the balcony.
You'll take care of it?
I knew I could count on you.
[SOFT CHUCKLE]
I just need this night to be perfect.
Everything has to go well.
You can relax. I think
we can manage that.
Boss, did you tell him
it isn't a good idea?
Of course, you think he listened?
He's an imbecile.
Pull over here.
Pinchadito said there's a
bad phone tap or something.
[PULLS HAND BRAKE]
Stay here. I'll be two minutes.
[PHONE RINGING]
[SIGHS]
- [IN ENGLISH] Hello?
- It's Salcedo. I only have a minute.
- You got us both.
- Listen.
Miguel's going to a party tonight.
Libre Club. Carrera Ocho. Ten o'clock.
It's gonna be crowded, so you have to
wait to get him until he's outside.
Is there any way we can
check this, Jorge?
No. You're gonna have to trust me.
And this promotion to security chief?
How'd that come about?
That's... really complicated.
Okay, we're just trying to understand
why you would call us the
day after you get a raise.
We don't have time for this right now.
He's going to be in the club
at ten o'clock. Carrera Ocho.
Take him outside.
[IN SPANISH] Hey. What's going on?
Nothing, boss.
- He bothering you?
- [WOMAN] No, sir.
I'm just buying fritters for my brother.
Great, let's go.
- You want some?
- Sure.
[IN ENGLISH] "Complicated." Everything
with this guy is complicated.
Still, there's something
about him I believe.
Enough to walk into a
cartel party blind?
For a chance to get
Miguel Rodríguez, maybe.
He's just stringing us along, Chris.
Or worse.
[CAR DOOR SLAMS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Stop! Hey!
[GRUNTS]
Hey! Come here!
[BEEPING]
[PANTING]
[HORN HONKING]
Get the back. Get the back.
Fuck!
[GRUNTS]
- [GASPS]
- Oh!
[PANTING]
Don't run.
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [CROWD SCREAMING]
Franklin Jurado.
Javier Peña, DEA.
You're being extradited for money
laundering and racketeering.
- My wife. You need to make sure...
- She's in Bogotá.
She'll meet us in Miami.
[PANTING]
[SECRETARY] Ambassador, I've
got Agent Peña, line one.
- Peña?
- We got him.
I'd like to get him
into the United States
before the cartel knows he's in custody.
I spoke to the Prime Minister this
morning. Extradition papers are set.
As soon as he starts
talking, you let me know.
- I'll update Justice.
- Yeah, will do, sir.
Agent Peña. Good work.
[BEEPS]
- [IN SPANISH] Let's see here.
- Zulema prays every morning.
Very good. And here?
- Worm...
- Dropper...
- Dad!
- Hi, kids!
[GIRLS SQUEAL]
I need to speak to you.
Okay. Girls...
please, go to your room
and finish your homework.
Something came up.
- What is it?
- I know how hard this has been for you.
I just want you to know that
I've almost got it figured out.
- All right.
- I'll tell you more tonight,
but for now, I want you to get
everything ready to leave.
Where are we going? How...
Do you trust me?
My love...
Paola... do you trust me?
Yes?
Everything will be all right. I promise.
Done. I'm finished.
I love that length on you.
Thank you, I like it, too.
[SALSA MUSIC PLAYS AT A DISTANCE]
And... a little extra for you.
And I have a little extra for you, too.
- I'll see you later.
- See you later.
[SNIFFS, COUGHS]
[IN SPANISH] You were the
one who approached my wife?
You enjoy it?
Using her to get to me?
[IN ENGLISH] Know what I'd be thinking
about if I were you, Franklin?
That if your wife wants to see you...
she's gonna see you in jail.
Drive hours every week.
Get felt up by some sweaty guard
whose only highlight at work
is getting his hands
under your wife's dress.
[IN SPANISH] You can
say whatever you want.
- You can't scare me.
- No...
[IN SPANISH] I can just ruin your life.
You know the brothers.
Pretty well.
What do you think will happen to them
without Gilberto running things?
You're young, Franklin. You have
your whole life ahead of you.
You really want to spend it in a cell?
Talk to me.
I'll get you a deal.
You and Christina...
can start over.
Have a new life.
In the United States.
I'm not going to say a single word...
until I see my wife.
Okay.
Then you'll have your witness.
[SIRENS AT A DISTANCE]
[IN SPANISH] Stop. Stop here.
[CHATTER OVER POLICE RADIOS]
Turn around.
[IN ENGLISH] Franklin. His
name is Franklin Jurado.
- Jurado or...
- [MAN] Yes, ma'am.
We've called his room several times.
We're unable to locate him.
Okay, well, did he check out?
Can you tell me if he's...
Have you seen him at all?
Sounds like you don't know anything.
We have not seen him and
he has not checked out.
I'm sorry, ma'am. I cannot help you.
Thank you for calling
Baoase Luxury Resort.
No, no, thank you. Thank
you for fucking nothing.
[CHIMES SOUND]
[IN SPANISH] Manny. Thanks for meeting.
Julia said you might have...
something on Crespo?
Well, yes.
It's something I hope you like.
How can I help you, Mr. Crespo?
Or should I say, Mr. Santacruz?
[CHUCKLES] Well...
I was hoping I could help you.
Where are you from?
- Cuba.
- Cuba! Gorgeous.
When you were young,
did you ever think you would come to
this country and do something special?
[CHUCKLES]
Well, I did.
I imagined myself coming here to
the United States, to New York...
and building something important.
That was also my dream.
The dream of a young
immigrant, like yourself.
And that's why I want to help you, to
make whatever dream you have a reality.
Whatever it is.
Regardless how much it costs.
In dollars.
You think you and I are the same
because we came to this
country with dreams?
Well...
My family fled Cuba because
we believed in freedom.
You came to sell cocaine.
Yes, we are both immigrants,
but we have nothing in common, Mr.
Santacruz.
My story is going to print.
Okay. Thank you for hearing my proposal.
Can I ask you a question?
How long will it take to get
to the airport from here?
I have no idea.
An hour or so.
[CHEPE LAUGHS]
I'll miss a lot about New York.
But not the traffic.
[LAUGHS]
[GUNSHOT]
["PARA TI CALEÑA" PLAYING]
- [MAN] Good evening, sir.
- Good evening. How are you?
[JORGE] Good evening.
Hello. How are you?
Good evening. Welcome.
Good evening.
[MAN] Good to see you, David. What's up?
Looks like the whole family showed up.
Why don't we have a drink upstairs?
You know what?
I don't want this many people up here.
Good evening! Welcome to the Cali Fair!
Let's give a warm welcome to
a friend of the festival,
and our patron, Mr. Miguel Rodríguez!
Come. Come here.
Come!
Come here!
Say a few words.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Thank you all for coming.
Please, enjoy the party.
["EL DÍA DE SUERTE" PLAYING]
[CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHS]
Your brother's a character.
His passion for tequila
exceeds his tolerance.
Well... my shift started already.
Bring me a pack of cigarettes
when you come back.
You're giving me a tip.
[IN ENGLISH] I told you he'd be here.
You came through.
I also said to take him outside.
It's too risky in here.
Tell your men to wait
until he's leaving.
[FLUSHING]
What men are you talking about?
Your men standing by the DJ booth.
We came to make sure you
were telling the truth.
We didn't bring any men.
The fuck are you talking about?
What?
Fuck.
- What's wrong?
- Fuck. You need to go.
- What?
- Just go!
[GUN COCKS]
Shh.
[IN SPANISH] We aren't here for you.
Where is Pacho?
Pacho!
[MUSIC BLARING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
I need to talk to you.
Don't interrupt me.
We have a problem. We
have to leave, now.
- Relax. It's a fucking party.
- We need to leave now!
- I said calm down! I'll say when we go.
- What's going on here?
We have to leave, sir. Please.
[GUNFIRE]
[DARÍO] Get down!
Go! Watch out!
[WAITER] Pacho!
[GUNSHOTS]
[SCREAMS]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[DARÍO] Watch out!
Stay there!
- Keep going!
- Careful! Get out of the way!
- Get out of the way!
Keep moving.
- When I run...
- They're over here.
[DAVID] Shit! Shit!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
Give me the gun.
[WHISPERS] Go ahead.
Are you all right?
[GRUNTS]
Motherfucker!
Álvaro!
[PANTING]
Shoot them! Shoot them!
Go!
Over there!
[YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
- Careful!
- Head down, sir.
Head down!
- Slow down.
- Move it!
Motherfucker!
- Go!
- Let's go! Move it!
This shit...
Little brother! I need you to shoot.
Your gun. Keep shooting at them!
Pacho.
Head down!
I'll drive, Enrique. I'll drive!
Over here!
[ENGINES START]
Who drove the car?
You got here by car. Who was driving?
- Me.
- Give me the keys.
Fuck you.
[JINGLES]
[PHONE RINGS]
Peña.
[CHRISTINA IN ENGLISH] There
are men at my apartment.
- Yeah, they're ours.
- Yeah, no shit.
Are you with them?
No. I saw them and I
freaked out, so I left.
They're meant to protect you.
Have you talked to anyone?
No, I tried calling Franklin, but
I couldn't get in touch with him.
What the fuck is going on?
We arrested Franklin.
You did what?
Christina, listen to me.
I... You fucking asshole.
- Listen to me.
- I told you I was gonna talk to him.
- I told you.
- Christina.
You want it? This is it.
As soon as we hang up the phone, you
get yourself to the American Embassy.
You don't talk to anyone,
you don't call anyone.
- You get yourself there.
- Okay.
[BEEPS]
- [IN SPANISH] Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Are we close?
Yes. It's just around the corner.
Thank you.
You saved me. Really.
Just tell your friends about me.
But only the ones with money.
[CHUCKLES]
[BRAKES SCREECH]
Why isn't this imbecile moving?
[HORN HONKING]
[STYLIST] When is this car gonna move?
[SCREAMS]
- Fuck!
- Oh, my God.
[IN ENGLISH] Oh, my God.
[IN SPANISH] God.
- Oh, my God.
- Go! Fucking drive! Oh, my...
[SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
- [CAR ALARM BLARING]
- [SOBS]
[WHIMPERING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[IN ENGLISH] We start with
just the basics. Okay?
Where they move the money,
where they keep the money.
Let me guess. It's his fucking lawyer?
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Agent Peña. Alan Starkman.
Mr. Jurado's lawyer.
Yeah. Your client has
indicated he's open to a deal
in exchange for testimony.
Before he learned that his
wife won't be joining him.
No. I've just spoken with his wife.
She's on her way to the
embassy in Bogotá.
Now, I was informed she never arrived.
Oh, go ahead. Check with your people.
It's my understanding that she met up
with Mr. Jurado's employers instead.
I guess she's had a change of heart.
Whatever deal you had
with my client... is off.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[IN SPANISH] Dad! Are you okay?
- Yes, I'm okay.
- Are you okay?
- [JORGE] Let's go inside.
- It's those North Valley motherfuckers.
- We got one of the shooters.
- They shot Álvaro, too.
Pacho is okay.
They're on their way back.
Are you okay?
- Close the damn door.
- What a fucking night.
Darío, please take her upstairs.
I'm coming soon.
What happened there?
It looked like...
you knew something was coming.
Jorge! You know what? I know why.
Because you are always working.
You saved my life tonight, Jorge!
- Dad, it wasn't my fault, I...
- One moment.
From now on, I want you back in
charge of my personal security.
Only you, Jorge.
Of course, Don Miguel.
And if you allow me, we don't know if
this will be the only attack or not.
So I need to know where
you are at all times.
Tomorrow is another day.
- [MIGUEL] Gilberto, it's me.
- Thank God!
- How are you, brother?
- We're okay.
Look, Gilberto, they tried
to kill Pacho, too.
- Pacho! No, it can't be...
- No, he's okay. He survived.
- He's on his way home.
- Thank God.
These North Valley motherfuckers, I'm
going to kill them. Sons of bitches.
Listen to me, Miguel.
Now's not the time for...
Everybody's watching.
- It could ruin everything.
- Look, Gilberto. They tried to kill me.
They tried to kill my son.
They tried to kill María.
They tried to kill Pacho.
Yes, I understand, brother, but...
for now, we can't afford to start a war.
Especially being so
close to the surrender.
What fucking surrender, Gilberto?
Before we can surrender, they'll
take everything from us.
- Brother, listen to me.
- Okay, no war. I understand.
You'll see.
Everything is going to be okay, brother.
Okay, Gilberto. Bye.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[IN ENGLISH] It's Salcedo.
- You alone?
- Yeah.
Get the fuck in.
How the fuck did you know where we were?
The same way I knew where to call you.
You think I'm gonna bring a gun here?
- We don't know what to think.
- Why didn't you have a team there?
Because you never gave
us a straight answer.
- Did you know that was gonna happen?
- You're serious?
How's the North Valley shooting
up the place gonna help me?
You look like a hero, escorting
Miguel out the back.
I had to do my job.
You're still not telling
us the fucking truth.
They killed the guy I replaced.
And they killed his wife.
And they're gonna do the same
thing to me and my family.
And you two are the only ones that can
help me get them out. You understand?
Yeah.
Then we need to trust each other.
- Yeah.
Tell me you know where Miguel is.
This is a SkyPager. All right?
It's untraceable. Even by you.
We'll be in touch.
[FEMALE REPORTER IN SPANISH]
Over 15 people were killed,
with dozens more injured
in a shootout tonight
at a Cali nightclub.
Reports say the shooting
started after 10:00 p.m.
[DOOR OPENS]
- I was worried.
- I'm okay. I'm okay. I'm okay.
- We're safe. We're safe.
- What happened?
It was the North Valley. I'm okay.
Where are we going?
Why do we have to leave?
What's going on?
Come with me. Come. Come. Come.
Tell me what's going on right now!
What I'm about to tell
you has to stay here.
You can't tell anyone, understand?
I'm working for the Americans.
It can't be.
I contacted the DEA.
I'm giving them Miguel.
In exchange, they will help
us get out of the country.
It's our only option.
There's no other way.
You're crazy.
They're going to kill all of us.
You're insane. What were you thinking?!
Paola...
[PEÑA]Things don't always
go according to plan.
You can use every hope and
prayer you have, take your shot,
and everything still goes to shit.
And when that happens, it's almost
like you never had a plan at all.
That's when people get desperate.
And things get dangerous.
[MIGUEL IN SPANISH] I want
to welcome Pacho, Chepe.
I'm sorry it's under
these circumstances.
North Valley attacked us.
Their intentions were clear.
They saw us as vulnerable
without Gilberto.
Weak, with me in charge.
They are trying to destroy us.
Take what's ours.
I...
All of us know there's only one
appropriate response to this.
One way to react against these people
who want to take everything from us,
what we've worked so hard to build.
War.
This is Gilberto's decision?
It's...
mine.
[PORRO MUSIC PLAYING]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com