Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
You're traveling
through another dimension-
a dimension not only of sight
and sound, but of mind,
a journey into a wondrous land
whose boundaries
are that of imagination.
Your next stop,
the twilight zone.
This is a jungle,
a monument built
by nature honoring disuse
commemorating a few years
of nature being left
to its own devices.
But it's another kind of jungle,
the kind that comes
in the aftermath of man's
battles against himself.
Hardly an important battle,
not a gettysburg or a marne
or an iwo jima.
More like one insignificant
corner patch
in the crazy quilt of combat,
but it was enough to end the
existence of this little city.
It's been five years
since a human being
walked these streets.
This is the first day
of the sixth year
as man used to measure time.
Perhaps a hundred
years from now, or sooner,
or perhaps it's already happened
two million years ago.
The place?
The signposts are in english
so that we may read them
more easily,
but the place
is the twilight zone.
Here, invader... eat.
Eat.
The only reason i can see
for our fighting
is that your uniform
is a different color
than mine.
Do you understand my language?
I suppose not.
Anyway, i repeat...
there's no longer
any reason for us to fight.
There are no longer
any armies.
Only rags of various colors
that were once uniforms
like the two sets
of rags we wear.
There are no more boundaries,
governments or noble causes,
therefore no reason
to fight.
Hear ye!
Know ye, by these present,
that i do
hereby declare peace
upon the entire world!
You're very pretty,
now that i see you clearly,
but i'm afraid the only way
i could convince you
of my honorable intentions
would be by force.
And i am terribly,
terribly sick of fighting.
Hello, again.
Precrassny.
Put it on.
Go away.
Go away!
You go to take your war
to more suitable companions.
This is civilian territory!
Precrassny.
This has been a love story
about two lonely people
who found each other
in the twilight zone.
Rod serling,
creator ofthe twilight zone,
will tell you
about next week's story
after this word
from our alternate sponsor.
And now, mr. Serling.
Literature is studded
with stories of ghost ships
and skeleton galleons.
And next week
onthe twilight zone
we take the old tale
of a flying dutchman
and give it
a coat of fresh paint.
This time the haunted ship
is an aircraft.
It lands
in a typical busy airport
and rolls up to the ramp,
and it's at this point
that you find yourselves
on a passenger manifest
of a flight that leads
only to the twilight zone.
It's called "the arrival."
Hi. This is ed sullivan
reminding you that
the colgate-palmolive company
also brings you star-studded
entertainment on our show
on most of these same stations.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org