As humans, we need training
in social skills...
...conversational distance.
Don't you hate these people
that talk into your mouth...
...like you're a clown
at a drive-through?
And handshakes is the worst.
There's absolutely no guidelines
for handshakes.
You know how many people-?
Too strong, too weak.
Sometimes they give you...
...the three-quarter handshake,
just the fingers.
Early release, late release.
Sometimes people
will dispute your release.
You've let go. They're hanging on.
I have actually said to people,
"Hey, the handshake is over."
Too many pumps,
coming in too high...
...too sweaty, from too far away.
Sometimes a guy will give you
a strong grip, late release...
...and pull you in for the
too-close conversation.
To him I say,
"That's three strikes. You're out."
You know, the timing
couldn't be worse.
Is there a good time to have
your parents stay with you?
I haven't been together
with Rachel for three weeks.
First I was on the road,
then my parents show up.
I'm getting a little backed up.
- When are they leaving for Paris?
- Not for three days.
- What about her place?
- She lives with her parents.
Really?
Maybe this will become, like,
a cool thing, living with your parents.
Then maybe baldness
will catch on.
Things will all be turning your way.
Hey, believe me,
baldness will catch on.
When the aliens come, who do
you think they're gonna relate to?
Who do you think's gonna be
getting tour of the ship?
The baldies.
My parents want your parents
over for dinner.
Good. I get the apartment
for at least one night.
I'm paying for this Paris trip.
It's their anniversary present.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Alec.
- This is Joey.
- Hey, Joey, how are you doing?
- Hey, listen...
...I was wondering if you'd be
interested in doing some work...
...for the Big Brother program.
I'm kind of running the local chapter.
What do you say, George?
- Well...
- Wouldn't you...
...like to be a Big Brother
to someone like me?
Please?
Well...
...sure, Joey, sure.
I would be thrilled.
That's great. Thanks.
I'll get in touch with you.
Wouldn't you like to be
a Big Brother-?
All right, Joey. That's enough.
Let's go. See you.
- What happened?
- What could I do?
Did you see the mug on that kid?
Wouldn't you like to pass the ketchup
to someone like me?
Please?
Have you noticed they moved...
...where they do the interview
on Jeopardy?
Yeah. It was in the middle
of Single Jeopardy.
- Now it's after Single Jeopardy.
- Yeah. It's much better, isn't it?
Oh, no comparison.
I gotta get my parents one
of those French-English dictionaries.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What?
Your parents are going
to Paris, right?
- Yeah.
- So I tell Alec...
...that I have to go to Paris
for an undetermined amount of time.
Then all I have to do
is buy postcards...
...and have your parents
mail them from Paris.
- What about little Joey?
- Who?
- He's probably better off.
- Yeah.
I'm trying to get out
of this Big Brother program.
When you get to Paris,
drop them in any mailbox.
- But there are no stamps on these.
- You gotta buy French stamps.
I'll reimburse you, of course.
Why are you doing this?
He wants this guy
to think he's in Paris.
- Why?
- Because George...
...is a deeply disturbed individual.
Oh, hey, Helen. Could I use
some more of your hand lotion?
I told you it was good. It's from
the Saks Fifth Avenue in Miami.
I'll remember that
if I'm ever in Florida.
Yeah, or if ever on Fifth Avenue
here in New York City.
- You can get some there.
- Yeah?
Say, those are nice pants.
I got a pair just like them at home.
That doesn't surprise me.
I bought these at Rudy's.
It's a used clothing store.
See, when people like you die...
...the widows,
they bring in their wardrobes.
- They make a bundle.
- Really?
My father's got a ton of old clothes
just sitting up in the attic.
- You think they're worth something?
- If they're vintage.
And you're a widow.
What happens if the husband dies
after the wife?
- Who brings the clothing in then?
- I suppose the children do.
Yes, I suppose they do.
All right. I got a 10:00.
I'll see everybody later.
Hey, I just remembered...
...my parents wanna have you
over for dinner before you leave.
- What about tonight?
- Tonight?
Yeah. They're making paella.
I don't think we can make it tonight.
We have plans.
- What plans?
- We have plans.
- Where did you get plans?
- Well, what about tomorrow night?
- Maybe.
Okay...
- ...I guess I'll tell them that.
- Okay.
- Hey, give them our best, though.
- Yeah.
- I'll call you later.
- So, what plans do you have?
- None.
So how come you're not
going over there for dinner?
Jerry, we don't care much
for the Costanzas.
We can't stand them.
- Really? Since when?
- Since always.
- We've never liked them.
- Why?
Well, they're so loud.
They're always fighting.
It's uncomfortable.
You never noticed?
I noticed. But they're
from your age group.
I didn't think you could detect...
...abnormal behavior
among your own kind.
Well, we do.
- Yeah?
- It's us.
Oh, come on up.
- It's Elaine. You have any problem?
- We adore Elaine.
- She's with her new boyfriend.
- What's he like?
- He's nice. A bit of a close talker.
- A what?
You'll see.
I really had no idea that you felt
this way about the Costanzas.
They're exhausting.
It's like being in an asylum.
- Hi.
- There she is.
- Hello, Elaine.
Hi, Mrs. Seinfeld.
Oh, this is Aaron.
- Hello, Aaron.
- Hello.
How long are you folks in town?
Three more days. Three more days,
and then we're off to Paris.
We're going with a select
charter group.
I love France.
I was just there last year.
In fact...
...you know, I still have
an envelope full of French francs.
I'll give them to you.
We can't take money.
No. It's a gift. From us.
Oh, that is so nice, Aaron.
Isn't he nice?
Has Jerry been
showing you a good time?
No, I haven't.
You know, I have a friend...
...who works at the
Metropolitan Museum of Art.
How'd you like
a behind-the-scenes tour?
- Really? You could do that?
- Easily.
- It wouldn't be any trouble?
- Of course not.
- When could we go?
- How about right now?
- I'm ready.
- Are you sure?
- Yes!
- Okay, let me get my coat.
Elaine, what do you say?
Well, I don't think so, Aaron.
I have plans.
How about you, Jerry?
I'm swamped.
You sure? You can examine
the artwork up close.
Maybe I'll try and catch up with you.
Yeah, that will happen.
All right. We're off.
- Okay. Bye.
- Let's go.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Have a good time.
- Bye.
- See everybody later.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Why would he ask your parents
to go to a museum?
- I don't know.
- What is that?
Maybe he was just trying
to be nice.
Have you ever heard of anyone
doing anything like this?
Wait a second.
He just did me a big favor.
- What?
- He got them out of the house.
- I can call Rachel.
Oh, no. I got the machine.
Rachel are you there? I got
the place to myself for a few hours.
Rachel, where are you?
Rachel!
Sorry, pal. Wish I could
help you out.
- They're not coming?
- No. They had plans.
How could they have plans?
What difference does it make?
They wouldn't lie to us.
- They're our dear friends.
- What am I supposed to do...
- ...with all this paella?
- They said tomorrow, maybe.
- Maybe?
- Maybe they don't like us.
Why wouldn't they like us?
Again with the pepper? What do
you gotta use all that pepper for?
- Keep quiet.
- You trying to set my mouth on fire?
I don't know what
the reason could be.
- Hello.
- Oh, hi.
What a day.
Jerry, you would not believe
the time we had.
Aaron is quite the tour guide.
Have you ever seen
those Impressionist paintings?
- Oh, sure, like Monet.
- Don't you think he had to be...
...nearsighted? Nobody would
paint like that if they could see.
It's all out of focus.
He's from the Impressionist school,
you know...
...like Monet, Manet,
Tippy-tippy-day-day.
I say that guy was painting
without his glasses.
Hello. Rachel.
Yeah.
No. They're back.
Jerry if you have something to do,
we can just sit right here and read.
Yes. Well...
...I'm sorry too.
Listen, I'll call you later.
Okay. Bye.
Well, I should be going.
Oh, thanks again.
- Goodbye.
- Hey.
- Oh, you must be Kramer.
I've heard about you.
Hey, you must be Aaron.
- Well, see you later.
- Yeah.
- Bye.
- Okay.
So, what are you guys
doing for dinner?
- We have no plans.
- Look at that, Helen.
Do you see what he's wearing?
That's the Executive.
- What is the Executive?
- The beltless trench coat.
- My father invented it.
- I sure did.
Raincoats were my business.
The Executive was a classic.
These haven't been made
in 20 years.
Why would they?
Nobody bought them then.
- He's wearing one.
- These are a hot item at Rudy's.
You don't say.
You know, I have boxes of those
sitting in my garage in Florida.
Get them up here.
You give me 25 percent,
I'll take care of everything.
- You got a deal.
- Yeah.
This is like the meeting
of Smith and Wesson.
I'll call Jack Klompus.
He's got a key to the garage.
- He can send them overnight delivery.
- You're gonna start shipping boxes?
- We're leaving for Paris in three days.
- He'll send them express.
- You're crazy.
- I'll tell you how crazy I am.
I'm paying for this trip
with these coats.
- I'm paying for the trip.
- So much the better.
Anyway, it's kind of a fluke thing...
...but I'll be leaving for Paris
in two days.
I will send you a postcard
when I get there.
- Paris, huh?
- Yeah.
You know, I feel terrible about Joey,
but it's a great business opportunity.
I don't even know how long
I'm gonna be away.
Where will you stay?
An apartment complex. The...
The Eiffel Towers.
Like I said, you'll be getting
a postcard in a few days...
...and again, I'm sorry.
George, you have no idea
how fantastic this is.
- Fantastic?
- Yeah.
We've been trying to reunite
Joey with his father...
...who lives in Paris.
But he's afraid to fly alone.
You know, he's kind of withdrawn...
...but he seems to take to you.
- So it's a perfect solution.
- Gee, what a coincidence.
And you'll send me a postcard.
Helen really seemed
to respond to Renoir.
I think she really connected
with the way he painted children.
And that Morty.
I'll tell you, that old guy's full of life.
He was convinced
Monet was nearsighted.
- I kept telling him-
- Aaron?
Yes?
Let me ask you a question.
How come you asked
Mr. and Mrs. Seinfeld...
...to go to the museum with you?
Well, they were in from out of town.
I thought they'd enjoy it.
You didn't feel uncomfortable...
...spending the whole
day at the museum...
...with two complete strangers
who are more than twice your age?
No.
It was fun.
You had fun
with Mr. and Mrs. Seinfeld?
Yeah.
They bought me a Coke.
How'd you get the idea
for the beltless trench coat?
I came home one night,
and I tripped over one of Jerry's toys.
So I took out my belt,
just to threaten him...
...and I got a glimpse
of myself in the mirror.
- How serendipitous.
- So that night, I cut off the loops...
...and the Executive was born.
He also had an idea
for a brimless rain hat...
...but that never materialized.
All right, come on. Let's play.
- Did you call Jack Klompus?
- I haven't been able to reach him.
I'll call him right now.
- Oh, come on.
- Just a second.
Jerry, have you seen
Schindler's List?
- No, I haven't seen it yet.
- You have to go.
- I'm going.
- You have to.
Okay.
- Hello, Jack?
- Yeah?
- Jack, it's Morty.
- Who died?
Nobody died. Jack, I want you
to do me a big favor.
- In my garage are a couple of boxes.
- What boxes?
- I'm gonna explain what boxes.
- All right. How the hell do I know?
Anyway, there are
these three big boxes...
...you can't miss them, I want you
to ship them here to New York.
I thought you were going to Paris.
I'm still going to Paris.
I got a big deal cooking here.
- What's in the boxes?
- Raincoats.
Raincoats?
You think you're gonna sell
those old crappy raincoats?
That's garbage.
I guarantee you, Doris won't let him
mail those boxes.
- When do you want these?
- Send them tomorrow.
So you think
they're coming tonight?
I don't know. They said maybe.
Of course they're coming.
They're leaving soon.
- If they don't come, they won't see us.
- Well, they better come.
I got all this paella.
I admire Morty and Helen
going to France.
We should take a trip.
Maybe a cruise.
Yes, a cruise.
A long cruise.
Just the two of you.
Georgie, what were you doing
poking around the attic last night?
- I wasn't in the attic.
- I heard noise.
- Maybe it was a mouse.
- Okay, that's it! We're moving!
- What?
- I will not tolerate infestation.
You haven't even seen one.
Don't you understand?
The very thought, the very idea.
I'll never be comfortable again.
All right, Frank. That's enough.
I guess I've been hanging
onto them for so long...
...because I couldn't accept the fact
that Dad was really gone forever.
They will get a good home,
won't they?
I gotta be honest, there's nothing
here too spectacular.
Oh, I beg to differ.
My father took great pride
in his appearance.
He was a very handsome man,
a Casanova, really.
I'll give you $200
for the three boxes.
Could you make it 225?
That was his high game in bowling.
Yeah, I'm in a good mood. Here.
Thank you.
Hey, George.
What are you doing here?
I'm just selling some of Dad's things.
That's what he would have wanted.
Oh, I got you.
- That'll do.
- Hey, guess what.
Morty Seinfeld and I are going into
business together, selling raincoats.
- That's swell.
- We worked it out...
- ...all over dinner last night.
- Dinner?
- You had dinner with the Seinfelds?
- Yeah, last night.
Was this something
you had planned?
No, it was spur of the moment.
Well, you know Morty. He likes to fly
by the seat of his vintage pants.
They had plans, huh?
They had plans!
Boy, I've never seen these before.
They just came in.
Part of my springtime
cruise collection.
- Two for $25.
- Oh, I'll take these. Yeah.
Hey, remember this raincoat
that you sold me?
Sure. That's the Executive.
- Do you have any others?
- I wish. They don't make it anymore.
Suppose I told you I have 50
in mint condition. You interested?
- Very interested.
- They're coming in from Florida.
- Bring them in.
- So you'll buy them?
I don't see what would
possibly stop me?
They had plans, huh?
They were busy.
They were busy
with their big plans, huh?
- What are you talking about?
- Mom and Pop Seinfeld.
- Look, I don't know.
- I know what they did last night.
- They had dinner with Kramer.
- It was a last-minute thing.
They won't have dinner
with my parents?
- Right.
- Something wrong with my parents?
- Absolutely.
- My parents are wonderful people.
- These the same people you live with?
- Yes.
- Are they coming tonight or not?
- I don't know what their plans are.
Okay. Fine.
It's gonna be very interesting...
...very interesting
if they don't show up tonight.
You know, my mother
made all this paella.
What is that, anyway?
It's a Spanish dish.
It's a mélange of fish
and meat with rice.
- Very tasty.
- I'll tell them.
- Could you do one other thing for me?
- Name it.
Would your parents
have any objections...
...to taking a little kid
to Paris with them?
It turns out that the kid's father
lives in Paris.
Is that a coincidence?
You know, Alec wants me
to take him over there...
...so I figure as long
as they're going-
You thought as long as
they're mailing postcards...
...it wouldn't be too much
to ask my parents to drag a child...
...who they've never seen
through the streets of Paris?
If you think it's too much,
they don't have to mail the postcards.
So where's he taking you?
Well, first we're going to a matinee.
I'm taking the afternoon off.
We're gonna go see My Fair Lady.
And then we're gonna
go to dinner.
- He knows all these fantastic places.
- You are one lucky girl.
Wish I could find a nice guy.
- Hi, Aaron.
- Hey, Joanne.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Hello, hello.
- Hello, Elaine.
I was able to finagle
two more tickets to My Fair Lady...
...and I thought, why not ask
Morty and Helen?
- Great.
- This is some office.
What's the square footage?
- You don't mind, do you, Elaine?
- Mind? Oh, of course not.
We can make a whole day of it.
This is some building.
Harry Fleming used to have
an office here.
There was a deli on the first floor.
You don't get corned beef
like that anymore.
What happened to that deli?
I really don't know, Mr. Seinfeld.
We better not.
They're gonna be here
any second.