When are they leaving?
In two days.
- It's been so long.
- I know.
Okay.
- It's only two more days.
- Right.
Thursday, 3:00.
- Oh, hi.
- We didn't know you had company.
Yeah. This is Rachel.
- Hi.
- Hello, Rachel.
- We'll come back another time.
- What other time?
- Whenever.
- Where you going?
- We'll drive around for a while.
- You don't have a car.
- We'll take a bus.
- Come on. Stop.
- No, we don't mind.
- I'll get a book.
No, it's okay.
I was just leaving anyway.
Are you sure?
Because we don't wanna-
No, it's okay.
- We'll go see Schindler's List, right?
- Definitely.
Okay.
- It was nice meeting you.
- Nice meeting you.
- See you later.
- Bye-bye.
Boy, that was some show.
- What show?
- My Fair Lady.
- When did you get tickets to see that?
- Aaron surprised us, and Elaine came.
Oh, Elaine? Really?
Well, that sounds interesting.
We saw Regis Philbin
get out of a limousine.
He looks better on TV.
- Hello.
- Hello, Jerry.
- Yeah?
- It's Jack Klompus.
Oh, hi, Jack.
So when are you coming down
to Florida again?
As soon as is humanly possible.
You know, I still got that pen,
the one that writes upside down.
Yeah. I should have kept it.
- So where's your father?
- Oh, he's right here.
- Yeah?
- Hello, Morty.
Listen, I can't get in the garage.
- What do you mean?
- There is something...
...wrong with the key.
The key doesn't work.
- You gotta jiggle it a little bit.
- I jiggled it.
I jiggled it for 15 minutes.
Tell him to come down here
and get his own packages.
You have nothing better to do
than worry about his boxes?
You gotta pull on the knob
as you turn it.
Get the hell out of here
with your knob!
What does he want from you?
My idiot son could open
that garage door.
What did I do?
Just do it first thing tomorrow.
I need it.
They'll be here first thing
Thursday morning.
Thursday morning?
You know we're leaving at 3:00.
Yeah, you're leaving at 3:00.
- How will you get this done?
- Don't worry about it.
Yeah, how you gonna get
all this done in time?
They were drinking
champagne in a buggy!
- First Kramer, then Elaine?
- Yeah.
- It's a slap in the face.
- What did we ever do to them?
I wanna know what we did to them.
What are they, too good for us?
A raincoat salesman.
- I could buy and sell him, like that.
- The hell with them!
The thing that bothers me the most
is the lying.
Well, let's forget about it.
We're going on a beautiful vacation.
Vacation?
Your mother and I are planning
on taking a cruise.
But I can't find any
of my vacation clothes.
They were in the attic.
The attic?
You haven't worn any
of those clothes for years.
How can I go on a cruise
without my cabana-wear?
I love those clothes.
A mouse! I saw a mouse!
It's the remote.
Where the hell are my clothes?
I love those clothes.
Lousy, moth-ridden crap.
I'm not crazy about used clothes.
I mean, they call it vintage...
...you know, to take your mind
off what it really is, nasty-wear.
Oh, it's clean, you know.
People wear underwear.
Yeah, well, they don't
wear iron underwear.
And that's what it's gonna take
to get me in those clothes.
I'll move into an apartment
after a strange person moves out.
Why would I wanna move
into somebody's pants?
There is no vintage underwear,
of course.
But it's not because a guy
couldn't sell his underwear.
It's because men
wear their underwear...
...until it absolutely disintegrates.
Men hang onto underwear
until each individual...
...underwear molecule
is so strained...
...it can barely retain
the properties of a solid.
It actually becomes
underwear vapor.
We don't even throw it out.
We just open a window...
...and it goes out
like dandelion spores.
That's how men throw out underwear.
We go- Then it's gone.
That's it. It's just...
- Hey, Jerry.
- So how was the movie?
Oh, really good. Really good.
- Didn't three hours go by like that?
- Like that.
What about the end, with the list?
Yeah, that was some list.
What'd you think
of the black and white?
The black and white?
The whole movie
was in black and white.
Oh, yeah, I didn't even realize.
You don't think about it.
There's so much going on.
Yeah. Yeah. I tell you,
I could see it again.
So Klompus has the key,
but the jerk couldn't open it up.
All you gotta do is jiggle it. You just
get it in there, jiggle it, jiggle it.
Look, I find this whole thing
very uninteresting.
- When you get the coats, come in.
- Oh, yeah. Hey, I'm on your side.
Hey. What, again?
I'm trying to buy some
of the clothes back.
Hey, wanna come over
for dinner tonight?
My mother made
all this extra paella.
Paella? Yeah, I'll be there.
Apparently, the Seinfelds
are too good for us.
I shouldn't say anything bad
about your partner.
No, no. We're not really partners.
I only get 25 percent.
Twenty-five percent?
It was your idea.
- Yeah, I know.
- You're doing all the legwork.
- That's right.
- He's ripping you off.
- You're right. He's ripping me off.
- You should be getting more.
- He's ripping me off.
- Don't let him take advantage of you.
Oh, it's you.
You're the one who sold me
the moth-ridden cabana crap.
You know, I've been thinking...
...why is Kramer getting 25 percent?
Well, he told you about the place.
So what?
Why is that worth 25 percent?
It's a finder's fee.
You know what a finder's fee is?
You find something, you get a fee.
A finder's fee is 10 percent,
no more.
Well, it's too late now.
Those are my coats.
I saved them, I stored them.
I've been waiting years
for this payoff.
Well, you're not gonna say anything.
Hey.
- I've been thinking about something.
- Yeah, so have I-
- I don't think the deal is fair.
- You don't think it's fair?
No, no. I found the place.
I set the whole thing up.
- I'm doing all the legwork.
- What legwork?
- There's legwork.
- If anything, you're getting too much.
- Too much?
- That's right. They're my coats.
Okay, look, I want 35 percent.
I'm thinking more like 15.
- No way I'm taking 15.
- Well, you're not getting 35!
All right, let's compromise.
- Twenty-five percent.
- Okay, it's a deal.
Moths are the scourge of my business.
All it takes is one moth to lay eggs.
Know what happens to the larvae?
They hatch everywhere.
Well, I'm sorry.
Here's your money back.
And I'll take the clothes.
This will hardly put a dent
in my fumigation bill.
- So where are the clothes?
- I burned them.
That's good.
Now, I know they're
your parents, Jerry...
...and they're very nice people.
But don't you think it's odd...
...that a 35-year-old man
is going to these lengths...
...to see that someone else's parents
are enjoying themselves?
I mean, don't you
find that abnormal?
It is a tad askew.
I mean, they're your parents,
and you don't do anything.
Why's this stranger doing it?
I've hardly been out with them.
See? See?
And I can't even say anything...
...you know, because
all he's really doing is being nice...
...but nobody's this nice.
This is, like...
- ...certifiably nice.
- You're right. He's insane.
Yes, he's insane.
That's what I think.
- So, what are you gonna do?
- I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
Oh, God. So how was the movie?
From what I saw, it was pretty good.
What do you mean,
"from what you saw"?
Well, I didn't actually get
to see the whole movie.
Yeah, why not?
I was kind of making out.
You were making out
during Schindler's List?
I couldn't help it.
We hadn't been alone in a long time.
It got the better of me.
- During Schindler's List?
- We're both living with our parents.
Did anybody see you
or say anything?
Oh, I don't think so.
I saw Newman, but he didn't see me.
Hello, Mrs. Seinfeld.
Hello, Newman.
Jerry's not here.
Having a nice trip?
Wonderful. We went to
the theater last night.
Oh, the theater.
- Because I was wondering-
- Wondering what?
Why I didn't see you
at Schindler's List with Jerry.
Well, we already saw it.
Oh, well, it's a good thing
for Jerry that you didn't go.
- Why is that?
- Well, he really seemed to have...
...his hands full,
if you know what I mean?
I'm afraid I don't.
Him and his buxom little friend,
Rachel...
...were going at it pretty good
in the balcony.
- What?
- Do I have to spell it out for you?
He was moving on her
like the stormtroopers into Poland.
Jerry was necking
during Schindler's List?
Yes.
And a more offensive spectacle
I cannot recall.
Anyway, I just really came up
to get some detergent.
- Jerry sends his laundry out.
- Oh, right.
Well, it was nice seeing you folks.
Oh, by the way...
...you didn't hear this from me.
Ta-ta.
Hi.
- What? What did I do?
- How could you?
- How could I what?
- You were making out...
...during Schindler's List?
What?
- No.
- Don't lie, Jerry.
Newman.
- How could you do such a thing?
- I couldn't help it.
We hadn't been alone together
in a long time.
We started up a little
during the coming attractions...
...and the next thing we knew
the war was over.
- Hello.
- Jerry.
- It's Jack Klompus.
- Hang on a second.
Dad, it's Klompus.
- Hello.
- Hello, Morty?
Listen. That key doesn't work.
- It's no good.
- You didn't get in?
Oh, I got in.
I had to break the window with a rock.
And then I got my hand
all cut up reaching in.
- You broke the window?
- He broke the window?
You wanted those damn boxes,
didn't you?
He should be on his hands
and knees thanking you.
- Did you send them?
- Yeah.
They'll be there
tomorrow afternoon, 2:00.
Tomorrow afternoon?
- Tomorrow afternoon?
I told you to send them express.
It was $10 cheaper
in the afternoon than the morning.
I figured, what the hell's
the difference?
- What did you do about the window?
- I gotta fix your window now?
All right, all right. Goodbye.
I don't think we'll make that flight.
What do you mean
you won't make it?
We have to make the flight.
We're with a charter group.
If we don't, the trip is off.
What's the difference?
We'll go some place else.
Someplace else?
What about Paris?
You don't understand.
I've come this far. I can't stop now.
I can't believe that you're doing all this
just to sell some stupid raincoats.
You don't understand.
Fashion is cyclical.
This thing could come back.
I think you're out of your mind.
I just don't understand
how all those clothes can disappear.
- Moths?
- Moths ate three boxes?
Well, you know what happens
when larvae hatch.
They're everywhere.
You know, I was thinking today.
I never liked
those Seinfelds anyway.
He's an idiot altogether.
- Oh, there's Kramer.
- Hello!
Hello!
Hey.
- Good evening.
- Hope you're hungry.
Paella.
- Here, let me take your coat.
- Oh, yeah. Thanks, buddy.
- Hey.
- That shirt.
- Where did you get that shirt?
- What?
That's my cabana shirt.
You stole my shirt,
you son of a bitch!
George, your friends up in the attic,
stealing my clothes!
Give me that back.
Give me that. Give me.
I bought it from Rudy.
Rudy! That skunk!
- I knew he didn't burn those clothes!
- Who's Rudy?
- What clothes?
- I sold your clothes yesterday.
You sold my clothes?
What do you mean,
you sold my clothes?
- I didn't think you wore them anymore.
- It's cruise-wear!
Kramer.
- I love that shirt.
- Oh, yeah.
That's because it's mine!
You look just like Frank...
...on our honeymoon.
Well, thank you.
- Who's this Rudy?
- Rudy's the guy...
...buying Morty's raincoats.
Morty Seinfeld? He's a bum.
The whole deal's
going down tomorrow.
- Morty's gonna miss his plane for it.
- Missing his plane?
- Wasn't that a charter flight?
- Yeah.
What happens to charter tickets
when you don't use them?
Well, I suppose they're wasted.
Yes, I suppose they are.
Tomorrow I'm going straight down
to this Rudy and get my clothes.
- A mouse!
- Egad! A mouse!
In the bedroom!
- You want the tickets?
- Yes.
You're gonna take this kid to Paris?
I get a free trip to Paris.
I go in the Big Brothers' Hall of Fame.
I mail my own postcards.
- You know I'm paying for these tickets.
- It's all right. I got lunch.
You should've gone
to the Costanzas' for dinner.
The paella was magnificent.
Have you ever had
really good paella?
- Not really.
- It's an orgiastic feast for the senses...
...a wanton festival of sights,
sounds and colors and...
Dad, you sure we're at
the right carousel?
- This is it.
- So how much are we gonna make?
Take it easy. I've been through
a million of these negotiations.
Two thousand? Three thousand?
That's giving it away.
This is a one-of-a-kind item.
- More? More than 3000?
- Just watch me do my thing.
- Say, Dad, isn't that one of yours?
- Look at this.
Look how this idiot packed it.
He didn't tape it.
He just flipped the flaps.
Wait. Hold it.
Kramer, you missed a couple.
Bonjour, welcome to
the Gateway to Paris charter flight.
Dad, isn't that your charter group?
Honesty. Hard work.
These are the values
that I was raised with.
The most important thing, Joey...
...is to be able to look yourself
in the mirror before you sleep.
Hey, I got news for you, four-eyes...
...there's no way you're staying
with us in Paris.
You burned them?
Those clothes are not yours to burn.
- Who are you, anyways?
- I'm the father.
- He said his father was dead.
- He said I was dead?
That's right.
Squeezed an extra $25 out of me.
That's what my life
is worth to him, $25?
- Hey, Frank!
- Oh, hey.
I want you to know that
I'm retracting our dinner invitation.
You don't have to retract it.
We never went.
I'm retracting that
it was ever offered.
I retract your retraction.
What are you, trying to unload
some junk of yours?
Will you excuse me, please?
We're conducting business here.
Keep them. I'm not interested.
- I thought we had a deal?
- That's another one of my shirts!
Not buying any more clothes
from anyone off the street.
The street?
I'm in the raincoat business 35 years.
- Maybe they have moths, like his stuff.
- My clothes don't have moths!
Because of his moths,
you're not buying my raincoats?
- That's right.
- I'm all ticklish.
Flight 433 now boarding
for Miami at gate 18-A.
- Flight 433 now boarding.
- Okay. Let's go.
It was so nice of you to come
to the airport to see us off.
Are you sure you can't stay
a little longer?
- No!
- Goodbye.
- Bye-bye.
- Take care.
- Okay, Jer.
- Bye-bye, Elaine.
- Bye-bye.
We'll call you when we get home.
Thank you.
I think she meant me, but...
Make sure Kramer uses good tape
to send back the raincoats.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- Aaron?
Aaron, are you okay?
I could've done more.
I could've done so much more.
- You did enough.
- No.
I could've called the travel agency...
...got them on
another flight to Paris.
- I could've got them out!
- You tried, Aaron.
- It was too expensive.
- This watch.
This watch could've paid
for their whole trip.
This ring.
This ring is one more dinner
I could've taken them out to.
Water.
- They need some water.
- Why?
They'll get dehydrated on the plane!
Get the Seinfelds some water!
Please!
Hi, Mr. Goldstein. Is Rachel home?
I'm afraid Rachel is not going
to see you tonight...
...or any other night for that matter.
- Why? What did I do?
- You know very well.
I heard about your behavior
at the movies the other night.
It was disgraceful.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
I will not allow
my daughter to be involved...
...with someone of such weak
moral fiber.
Fortunately, my postman happened
to witness the entire incident.
A heavyset fellow. I believe
he lives in your building.
- Now, if you don't mind...
- Rachel.
- Good night.
So my parents get home,
they open the door...
...my father flicks the light on, and
the whole place is cleaned out.
- Everything.
- Get out.
- How did that happen?
- The broken window.
Klompus never fixed it.
They just walked right in.
Boy, they could use a vacation.
They're taking one. The travel agent's
trying to set something up for them.
So how about that Aaron?
You know what drove me crazy
about him?
Did you ever notice he stood
too close to you when he talked?
No, I hadn't noticed.
Pair of bear claws, please.
- Hi, Newman.
- Hello, Jerry.
I happened to catch you coming out
of Schindler's List the other night.
Oh, were you there?
Yes, I was.
- It's a powerful film.
- Yeah.
- Shocking brutality, don't you think?
- Shocking.
- Yeah, well, that was nothing.
- Jerry! Jerry!
Where the hell is your father?
This is the best thing we ever did.
I hope those exterminators
know what they're doing.
Forget about them.
Let's just try and relax.
Personal distance is
a very important thing.
There's a new personal distance,
ATM distance.
When someone's using an ATM,
you wanna be about 6 feet back.
Don't you? Because people get
edgy around that ATM, don't they?
They got their money out,
their eyes are darting all around.
The other place I wanna be
6 feet away is a urinal.
You want some distance there too.
ATMs and urinals. I guess whenever
someone's taking valuables...
...out of their pants, you wanna give
them as much room as possible.