I, Claire Hale Underwood,
do solemnly swear
that I will faithfully execute the office
of President of the United States...
...I'm proud of her. She deserves this.
Even if it only lasts
for a couple of weeks.
And will, to the best of my ability,
preserve, protect, and defend
the Constitution of the United States,
so help me God.
Congratulations, Madam Acting President.
- Feel different?
- No.
- Liar.
- It's temporary. I'm only acting.
Oh.
You have to now carry this with you
at all times.
- The codes?
- Mmm-hmm. It's the law.
Governor, we just got word
that Vice President Claire Underwood
was sworn in as acting president.
- Were you aware?
Of course.
Do you have any comment?
God bless America.
If Monday's House vote
goes your way,
- and you win the presidency...
- Oh, I'll win, believe me.
You think this vote
will be the charm?
See, Congress is no different
than the rest of the country.
People are sick and tired
of all this confusion and chaos.
The public is not happy.
If you become president, would
Claire Underwood remain as vice president?
Not if she wants
what's best for the country.
But given the Twelfth Amendment,
would you have a choice?
Uh, no further questions,
everybody.
The governor's here to talk
to members of Congress.
- Thank you so much.
Thank you. Thanks, everybody.
- Will?
- I'm fine.
And Rasmussen changed his vote.
Well, he's been waiting a long time
to pay me back.
Creating a deadlock in Rhode Island
just gives him the spotlight.
- He can be convinced.
- Meeting's set for this afternoon.
Yes, but if we can't,
we lose Rhode Island.
He seems to be acting alone,
but that could change.
We will make gains this weekend.
- Shore things up by Monday's vote.
- Mmm.
Mr. President, it's possible
we may need to consider the other option.
A rescheduled election.
No, no, I'll get Rasmussen back in line,
and turn some others along the way.
We've arranged sit-downs
for you and Madam President
with all of the small states.
LeAnn and I can go door-to-door
in Rayburn, Longworth and Cannon.
Three of my favorite buildings
after this one.
What is it?
The McMurdo Research Facility
in Antarctica.
All live feed communications have ceased
or been disconnected.
However, we have been receiving
texts and e-mails
from an American scientist
stationed there,
claiming that an unidentified
occupying military force has landed.
You think the soldiers are Russian?
He thinks so.
They arrived via
unmarked research vessels.
We reached out to Moscow, but they're
denying any official involvement.
Surprise, surprise.
It's a brazen act of aggression.
Well, it's a crime of opportunity.
Petrov thinks the US government
has their eye off the ball.
Well, it doesn't.
Cathy, what's the most recent
communication we've received?
What I'm saying is this aggression
in Antarctica, by powers unknown,
is a direct result of the uncertainty that
our presidential situation has wrought.
Congressman Watts,
since when is Antarctica a concern
for the Congressional Black Caucus?
I hope you're not implying that the caucus
shouldn't have a voice
in international affairs.
I hope that's not what I'm hearing.
Thank you, Randy.
I've called a meeting tomorrow,
for the Congressional Black Caucus,
to discuss our positions,
both foreign and domestic,
before Monday's presidential vote.
Are you considering
shifting your support to Conway?
Well, all I can say at this time,
that the most important thing is unity...
and the public's faith
in the institution of democracy.
That's all for now.
You are in violation
of the Antarctic Treaty System.
A treaty the USSR signed in 1959.
- We're a new country.
- So you're admitting they are your troops.
I'm simply stating I need to interpret
agreements signed by the Soviet Union.
In which case, you'd be throwing out
decades of disarmament progress.
The Cold War is over,
Mrs. Acting President.
Well, then maybe
we need to revisit the treaty.
I'm not interested in revisiting a treaty.
I'm interested in staying in power.
And, Claire...
if I could be so familiar.
In my country...
once you're in office, you don't let go.
- Viktor.
- Mr. President.
You Americans certainly have
a lot of presidents these days.
Yes, you may think that
we're distracted, but don't fool yourself.
Distracted? No. No, no. Divided, yes.
American democracy is stronger
than your sad attempt
to take advantage of a bump in the road.
Oh, Francis, my eyes are on a landscape
that is so much bigger
than any one of your roads.
Well, Congressman Rasmussen,
we're just surprised to see you come out
on the wrong end of this, is all.
I mean, I suppose it must've been hard
losing the House majority leadership
all those years ago,
but there is a difference between
being bitter and being treasonous.
If it's new committee assignments
you'd like, we can certainly arrange that.
It's over.
Markets are in free fall.
Consumer confidence is at an all-time low.
What is this? A doodad? A doohickey?
A... pointless award?
Did I mention I hate useless things?
This nation is coming apart at the seams.
Because of you, because of
what you've done to this country.
There it is. How the righteous love to
bemoan their role in middle management,
and condemn those who actually
might have an effect on the world.
- Think of the party, Congressman.
- I am.
What did you think would happen
when you came in here, Francis?
That you could threaten me,
tell me the DNC'll throw money
at my primary opponent next cycle
if I don't play ball?
Or were you gonna flatter me?
"Elder of the party" this,
"bellwether senior member" that.
You know, I'm somewhat delighted that you
developed a personality at this late date.
But I would ask you to rethink this.
To come out this way on this thing
in the twilight of your career
will do nothing
but sully your Wikipedia page.
You have no idea, do you?
No one hears you walking the halls
of this building... not anymore.
- Who are you working for?
- Excuse me?
I served next to your jellied spine
for two decades.
You've never shown an ounce of courage.
You don't have what it takes for revenge.
So someone must have offered you
something rather sweet.
Take all of the two hours
you need to reconsider.
One more thing for your signature.
- You can leave this with me.
- Of course.
- And Miss Harvey's waiting.
- Oh, please send her in.
I'm on my way back to Rayburn.
You close the door, please?
What are our chances with a revote?
Or, rather,
what are the president's chances?
I want to know.
If it was in all 50 states, not good.
His unfavorables are still high.
Yours are still not.
But it's hard to argue
with close to 30 years' experience.
Maybe the president is right. Maybe
he does have a better chance in the House.
Don't defer, LeAnn.
Tell me what you think.
The revote in Tennessee and Ohio
is his best shot.
While it's what's best for Frank,
it may not be what's best for you.
Thank you.
You seem like a reasonable man.
I know how to listen,
if that's what you mean.
If the president regains his office...
"If" doesn't make
for a winning opener, Alex.
I'm here because I think he can win.
We often don't see eye to eye, he and I.
Uh, and yet, there are ways
we can work together.
Okay, maybe I made a mistake
with the committee.
I can be self-righteous.
I'm trying to clean up the party.
Our party.
And I end up speaking out of turn.
It's enough with the, "It's me, not you."
What can you deliver, Alex?
- I can get out of the way.
- Well, that sounds vague and inadequate.
I want to know what's up with
Terry Womack and the Black Caucus.
The president and Congressman Womack,
they have a good relationship.
Oh, I'm sure they do. But I would hate
to see Terry let you down.
If we lose Womack and the Black Caucus,
we're done on Monday.
There are a few freshmen
I could reach out to.
They might help keep the CBC together.
You wanna be minority whip.
Only if I deserve to be.
Huh.
I'm trying to get back. Congressman Lewis
is 20 minutes late as usual.
Is there a spot for him
on financial services?
Uh-huh.
Doug, stay where you are.
I thought you said
you were telling the CIA to stand down.
I did. So, contrary to your assurances
that Macallan would behave,
we're now dealing with a leak.
- He doesn't want trouble.
- How do you know what he wants?
You find him and you get him here.
As soon as he knows we've backed off,
he will disappear. I promise.
No, that word means nothing to me.
You have a statement?
You anticipate any other big WikiLeaks
info dumps coming down the pike?
- You'll know...
- When I need to know. I know.
Which is apparently whenever it hits CNN.
FBI was on high alert.
They investigated every threat.
- Calm down.
I am calm, Doug.
The public's not calm.
Every misstep is highlighted
and heightened.
They wanna know
what happened with their election.
We're fixing it.
Yeah... that's what they're afraid of.
The statement's about the FBI.
Everybody trusts the FBI.
Hey, who's Lisa Williams?
I don't know. Why?
Oh, somebody from the Herald called.
They were just wondering if you knew her.
I don't.
I need five minutes with this.
- Open or closed?
- Closed.
Am I good with that statement?
I marked it up. It's on my desk.
Throwing the election back
to the states, it gives us less certainty.
I don't think
we can get it done by Monday.
We've been working at it
for weeks, Francis.
Claire, don't let the office
make you careful.
The halls of Congress
have never failed me.
Yes, but the career politicians,
they are more entrenched than ever.
There's a new House,
with members you don't know.
We need to move the playing field
back to the imaginations of the people.
Oh, you have that much faith
in the voters in Tennessee and Ohio?
They're going to choose you.
I just know it.
All right.
Set up a meeting.
I'll hear them all out. You win.
Both of us. Both of us.
Good evening.
Eric.
- Feel like you're outside?
- Mmm.
Aren't you supposed to
limit it to 30 minutes?
- Oh, God, Jesus, no.
- Not if you calibrate the workout.
Oh, I'm feeling fine.
It's all about listening to your body.
It'll tell you when it's time to rest.
You should listen to the doctors
some of the time, Francis.
I know the Underwoods were worried.
Because they were ready to deal.
To deal with me.
- You're sure it's for real?
- Sure as I can be.
Okay, we'll be in touch.
Okay.
So call him back.
Making progress on a couple of Dems.
Think Congressman Alspaugh
is about to turn.
We'll see him on Sunday.
Why wait?
We need to meet with
the Congressional Black Caucus. Tomorrow.
They're in Underwood's pocket.
Yeah. Can you give us a second, everybody?
Uh, sure.
- Come on.
...Thank you.
I just got word from somebody inside.
Womack is losing control of the caucus.
If you win them, you win Monday.
We should try.
All right, fine. Let's do it.
- I'll set it up.
- Are we done here tonight?
You still have a few calls.
Mark, I was thinking,
maybe we could, um...
cancel tomorrow night in Philadelphia.
We can't cancel any trip,
or any event. We shouldn't.
A second to catch our breath
would be really helpful, I think.
This is what it is, Hannah.
If you need to take a break, you can.
Darling, we haven't slept all week.
You're exhausted.
- I... Just an idea.
- What's my next call?
But you're not enjoying yourself.
Because he won't listen to me.
He can't win in the House.
I'm not talking about him.
I'm talking about you.
What difference does it make
whether I'm enjoying myself or not?
Isn't that what this is all about?
Can't you just...
live in it for a second?
You are in charge.
- Yes, but...
- Come here.
- Come.
You could wake up tomorrow...
and...
I don't know, feed the children...
...start a war...
You know what? I'm sorry.
I shouldn't think out loud, that's all.
No, you're right.
Let's not talk about anything
that happens outside of this room.
The sanctions are meant to target
the oligarch class in Russia.
And the more members we have on board
before I sit down with President Petrov,
the quicker this will resolve itself.
We are. We are prepared to release
some of our strategic reserves
to keep prices down.
Contact Ambassador Caspi
and buy me 15 more minutes.
Uh, please don't think of this
as a deal with the Underwoods.
To be frank,
they could be gone by Monday.
That's not what I wish, of course.
But know that you are working more
with me on this than with them.
Congressman Watts.
Governor, we're so happy
you could join us today.
As am I. The black community
deserves so much better
than Frank Underwood's failed policies.
That we can agree on. I look forward
to hearing about your platform.
- Shall we?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry.
We have just a bit more private
caucus business to attend to first.
Excuse me?
This is a meeting
of the Congressional Black Caucus.
Well, I understand.
That's... why we're here.
I was told 9:00,
and it's already been an hour.
You should have been told 10:00.
And you will get your opportunity
to address us.
- I appreciate your patience.
I'm not gonna beg.
No, you're gonna smile.
The Muhammed Kalabi they arrested
in Tennessee
is not the Kalabi connected to ICO.
Can you prove it wasn't
just a bureaucratic mix-up?
Uh, not yet.
What else?
Uh, final voter suppression lawsuit
was kicked back to the lower court,
- SCOTUS deadlock is feeding the chaos.
- Do you read the paper, Sean?
Billy got a byline on that three days ago.
Declaration of war?
Underwood was so evangelical,
but hasn't mentioned it in weeks.
All right, that's enough. That's enough.
Lisa Williams.
What about Lisa Williams?
I saw you talking.
I thought she might be a lead
worth pursuing.
She's not.
She's using what she read in the paper
to get attention or a little cash.
I did some digging.
She and Rachel Posner both went
to a church called the Fellowship.
- Rachel disappeared...
- Stop.
No more conspiracy theories
about dead girls.
But people love stories about dead girls.
The next House vote
is the day after tomorrow.
The natives are restless, outraged,
just plain scared, actually.
They want to wake up in the America
that they fell asleep in.
Dig deeper on the Kalabi lead.
See if you can connect Underwood to it.
So, this is the James S. Brady
press briefing room.
And under our feet is
actually a swimming pool.
It was built by the March of Dimes
for President Franklin Roosevelt,
who had polio.
And this pool was really
the only way for him to exercise.
It was, uh, an open secret
that the president used a wheelchair
most of the time.
Which is why the White House
was one of the first wheelchair-accessible
government buildings.
- But everyone pretended he could walk?
- Yes.
- That's a bit of grace.
- Yeah.
A thing not spoken?
Yeah, this building literally changed
because of his disability.
But people just respected him,
respected his, uh...
Right.
That office used to carry
so much weight, so much, uh, respect.
You don't think it does anymore?
No, oh, no, no!
I'm not saying that.
I was giving you a hard time.
I know what you meant.
Anyway, sorry,
didn't mean to hijack the tour.
Moving on...
Gentlemen, we're ready for you now.
I could come here today
and talk about federal sentencing
disparities between crack and cocaine,
which obviously are racially motivated.
- I'm sorry, but are you asserting
that the crack epidemic
is exclusive to the black community?
No, not at all.
But I think it's fair to say
that sentencing discrepancies
have disproportionately
affected minority populations.
We're not one-issue voters.
Of course not. That's what I'm getting at.
The whole point of today's meeting
is to broaden our platform.
Republicans are always
dwelling on crime, Governor.
Well, I'm here to have a dialogue.
We expected you
to come in here with a plan.
And I do have a plan.
Concentrating on a few pieces
of onerous legislation is not a plan.
- Let's be clear...
- That kind of talk we've heard before.
- I'm a Republican.
- Oh, here we go.
You're not listening.
Look, I want to help you help yourselves.
Unbelievable.
That's my platform.
Well...
I've heard enough.
So, does anyone else have
any questions for the governor?
Well, I have a question.
What has Francis Underwood
ever done for you?
This little charade
this morning...
- Well done. Quite an act.
- Will.
- Governor.
- No, but really.
See, you may have differences with me...
You may have genuine differences with me.
But see, that's the operative word,
"genuine."
Can someone here please explain to me
why you all are still so loyal
to Francis Underwood and the Democrats?
One of these days
the members of this room will realize how
much you actually prop up the status quo.
And how's that working for ya?
Will, why don't we thank the gentlemen
and women for their time?
You've made a mistake.
What we're proposing is a new election
in the two states
that weren't able to provide
valid electors by the safe harbor date.
- Can we even do this?
Hold on. Hold on, everyone!
I'd like to know, where does
the attorney general stand on this?
Looking into it, but on board.
Bob, there's no precedent here.
There's no playbook.
We can look to the Constitution
for inspiration, but not for instruction.
Thursday's vote showed
Democrats are coming to their senses.
We lost one vote, Jordan.
We can go back and forth
like this forever.
As one of the few Republicans in the room,
it needs to be said.
The stability of our country
is more important than the presidency.
Not if people believe the president is
being chosen behind closed doors.
A process that is laid out
in the Constitution.
The same process that can keep us
gridlocked for the next two years.
The House should
and will decide.
Delaware has one congressman.
How will that play in Austin
when your opponent in two years
tells voters that you allowed
a state like Delaware
to have the same influence as Texas?
A lot of you incumbents will be in danger
of losing your seats.
And there it is.
Look. Look at them.
That is the look of contemplating loss.
Loss...
the only constituent that
anyone in this room really listens to.
I, for one, would like to hear how
the president feels about all this.
- Well, I've made my...
- I think we could...
No, Mr. President.
You haven't spoken much here.
We believe in one person, one vote.
If we take that away,
then what is this country?
- Isn't that right, Mr. President?
- Absolutely, Madam President.
Oh, wait, hold it.
Let me just move down a bit.
I keep slipping off the podium.
- Oh, you got me.
- That better?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah...
So the Lincoln...
- That was actually his office?
- Can we... can we not?
- Can you... can you move me up a bit?
- Oh, yeah.
...Okay.
- How'd it go?
- We'll see.
I need you to look over
the Antarctica statement again.
Whatever you need.
- Walk with me?
- Mmm.
I'm worried about Francis.
- Why?
- I might need you to save me.
- This is not going to work.
- Why?
If he loses, I still lose.
He cannot be on the outside looking in.
He'll win.
- You actually believe that?
- Sure... why not?
It was a wager.
The potential gains made it necessary.
It was a complete
waste of my time.
If you don't start turning things around,
you're going to be out
on your fucking ass. You understand?
I do.
I should explain something to you,
Governor.
If you ever
talk to me like that again...
I'll make sure you never win
another election in your life.
- Are you threatening me?
- No, I'm enlightening you.
- Hey.
- Governor Conway. Hello, sir.
How you doin'?
Take a peek,
if you don't mind, Captain?
- Governor.
I used to fly, too, you know.
What kinda max thrust
you get on these engines?
- Uh, about 6,400 pounds.
- 6,400 pounds.
I used to fly something a lot bigger,
a lot more power,
but it was so weighed down
with all the weaponry,
- it was like flying a tank.
Hey, um,
why don't you let me in for a second,
just flip me the controls?
I'm sorry, sir. I can't.
Come on, I... I just want to
feel the weight on the stick for a second.
I wish I could, but, uh,
you're not on the flight plan.
You know I've been in situations,
where, like, I've been shot at.
You realize that, right?
You don't think I can handle a twin engine
at 35,000 feet,
straight and level over some farm country?
I mean, come on, sir.
- Sir.
You should probably
go back to the main cabin.
You know I'm gonna
be the president, right?
- I hope so, sir.
- You hope so?
- I just mean I'm pulling for you, sir.
- I'm gonna be the president,
and you're going to flip me
those motherfucking controls.
Will, come on.
- What? What do you want?
- I just...
I need to talk to you
for a minute, please.
I was just talking to the pilots.
Okay, I need you to calm down, okay?
Breathe.
- Will, why don't you sit down?
- Why don't you shut the fuck up?
I'll fire you.
I'll leave you on the goddamn tarmac.
Okay.
What the fuck are you gonna do?
Sit down and try and act like an adult...
or at least like the next President
of the United States.
Sit.
- Who are they?
- Maybe Indonesian secret police?
What if we don't pay?
Are there other buyers?
I don't know.
I'll take care of it.
- How?
- Don't ask how.
I'll get Macallan back.
Obviously, this stays between us.
Say, "Thank you, Doug."
Thank you, Doug.
We met on a bus.
She was listening to music.
And I asked her to go
to this church I used to go to.
- Where was that?
- Maryland.
The Winter's Run Fellowship.
About an hour north of Baltimore.
So, then what?
I don't know. We just...
became friends.
And then it became more than that.
Started spending every night together.
At some point, she told me about this guy
who used to come around to check on her.
- What'd he look like?
- I never saw him.
Just sometimes she said he was coming,
so she couldn't hang out.
She wouldn't really
tell me anything about him.
Everything okay?
Yeah, do you mind?
I just need to see my friend up there.
Hey.
How are you doing?
Thanks.
You think there's oil there.
You're positioning to stake a claim.
There are no Russian troops in Antarctica.
We're willing to recommend changes
to the Antarctic Treaty parties.
What happens to you when
the Underwoods are ejected from office?
You teach international relations
at a university?
- Or work for a think tank?
- I haven't thought that far ahead.
I think you have.
How long do you expect
the world to believe
those aren't your soldiers?
- Do you like working for the Underwoods?
How loyal are you?
When the time comes,
will you stand with them... or not?
I leave tomorrow.
News of the sanctions will hit Monday.
Let's meet before you go.
You're a career diplomat, a professional.
Maybe that's why I trust you.
Then you take care of them,
so they feel good
and they take care of you.
So you feel good because...
I mean, Rachel was really beautiful.
You could tell that
from across the street.
I never saw her
from across the street, though.
Isn't that a funny thing to think about?
A lot of people, I think,
they spot the one they love
from across the street sometimes.
It's like they're running an errand,
and they happen to spot
the one they love across the street
running a different errand.
There's this sudden thrill, like...
while the person you love
is inhabiting the same world as you.
And they're just walking around,
buying, I don't know...
Vitaminwater, and maybe they know that
you love them while they're doing it,
and maybe it means
they're nice to a cashier.
I never got to see her
from across the street, though.
It just never happened.
I don't want you to burn yourself.
...No burning, no.
Rachel liked to smoke.
She said she was gonna stop,
but she would have a rule
that she'd only smoke
when we listened to
this one band we both loved.
Because of the ceremony.
"It should be a ceremony,"
it's what she said.
Well, even if it's gum,
I still prefer to step outside to chew it.
Like lighting a delicious cigarette.
The things we miss, the rituals...
Excuse me.
- She doesn't like me.
- She will.
Thanks for coming out here
and meeting with him.
You know you can't legally
remove Claire Underwood,
even if you win in the House?
- I'm working on that.
I'm not interested.
He needs you. I need you.
So does the country.
I'm not a politician.
I can give orders, I can follow orders
and I know when the hell to shut up.
And you're a steady hand,
which, again, the country needs.
- I'm not gonna be Conway's patsy.
- No, you're not.
- He's a difficult man to be around.
It's over. It's over.
The process chose Claire Underwood.
We'll get there.
You'll be called vice president,
but you will be, de facto, something more.
What were you doing there?
I asked Seth Grayson about Lisa Williams.
Why the hell did you think
that was an appropriate thing to do?
Didn't I tell you to drop this lead?
Is it still a lead?
Because nobody's on it.
Nobody's on it because she's a junkie,
and everything she said to me
is in the Lucas Goodwin manifesto,
which has been picked apart
by every message board
and conspiracy theorist on the Internet.
At first, Grayson said
her name didn't ring a bell,
but then he called me out of the blue
and asked me if we were
still looking into it. So I followed up.
You looked through my notes.
You're out.
- What?
- You're fired, Jeffries.
It's a story. I was following it.
I don't want you on my team.
Get out of my office.
We know we can win both states.
Why would we not take this deal?
No. The Underwoods want a revote
because they know
they can't win in the House. We can.
We need to make a deal that forces
Claire Underwood to resign.
- And why does that matter?
- If I may?
- Madam Speaker.
- Speaking from the Hill,
as vice president,
she'll have a public pulpit
to discredit your every move.
Oh, I'm going to exile Claire Underwood
to the Naval Observatory
and stack her schedule
with state funerals in Southeast Asia.
She'll never see the inside
of the West Wing, let alone the Oval.
You need Brockhart by your side,
supporting you.
I don't want to hear about Brockhart.
What matters is that
Will becomes president.
Underwood in office
can cause damage.
Whereas, if they lose, they're losers.
I want this election to be
between me and Francis Underwood.
Well, it isn't up to you.
Speaker McCarthy isn't letting
this particular bill to the floor,
unless we have an amendment attached
that removes Claire Underwood.
Oh...
Will...
Now, if you expect a willing partner
in the White House,
you'd better let that bill get
to the floor as is.
If you get to the Oval, Will, you're gonna
need the Speaker more than she needs you.
So, I'm gonna call her back,
and you are going to apologize.
Will.
Will, get back here!
Will!
Enough.
Shut the door.
You look like death.
I can't get in touch with the kidnappers.
It's been radio silence
for almost 24 hours.
There's rumors they don't even
have him anymore.
I can't keep this
from the president any longer.
Okay.
And then I'll tell him
what a big help you've been.
Sanctions hit in a couple of hours.
Deal with Secretary Durant
or with some very unhappy billionaires.
You will allow me to
exploit whatever oil I find in Antarctica.
And I'll tell you why.
I have something.
- Or rather, someone you need.
- What are you talking about?
Someone in your administration
was willing to pay a great deal of money
for his safe return.
Your Aidan Macallan.
He's here. In the Kremlin.
Who do you think orchestrated that leak?
Seems to know quite a lot.
Excuse me one moment.
The Secretary of State is here.
Madam Secretary.
Gentlemen.
- You must know Aidan?
- I don't believe I do.
Nice to meet you.
- You're American?
- I am.
Before we begin,
I'd just like you to know
that the president
and the former president are on the line.
Cathy...
You can pick up the phone,
if you like.
Mr. President.
It's best you come back
to Washington.
Find anything yet?
Not yet.
Thank you again, Mr. Barnes,
for letting me take a look.
I won't be long.
This is everything?
This is everything
they sent from Zoe's apartment.
I just, you know...
I just can't seem to throw anything out.
I mean, it's just papers, but...
Anyway, I'll leave you to it.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Yeah.
Okay.
The Black Caucus? Really?
I like Mark,
because I always know where he stands.
It's usually on someone's neck.
What did you buy yourselves,
another day?
Enough time to talk
to David Rasmussen,
who you clearly spoke to before.
And to meet with Jordan Sadowsky
and the rest of the Republican leadership.
And what happens Tuesday?
Or Wednesday?
Look, I... I can have David and the House
vote on this every single session.
Our backgrounds are different, but we're
both hardscrabble boys at heart.
We need the last word,
last blow, last move.
We can push the bill through the House
for a new election for president
in Tennessee and Ohio.
Speaker McCarthy
won't let that happen.
But I could... convince her
if you were to step down,
and our full tickets
president and vice president
run against each other
in Tennessee and Ohio.
Well, to hell with that.
We'll make the deal.
I think this is the right thing to do.
Tomorrow, I'll announce my intention
to step down after the revote.
I'll let the Speaker know
to put the bill on the floor.
We have one more outstanding
piece of business,
the Supreme Court nominee.
We'll need to appoint someone
to break the four-four deadlock.
Approve Congress' new election date.
- We, uh, have several people in mind.
- I want you to appoint Elizabeth Benson.
Well, she's liberal enough
for you to swallow,
and conservative enough when it counts.
We don't have time
for Senate hearings.
I can make a recess happen.
I'll see you on the campaign trail.
Where does that leave me, huh, Alex?
I went out on a limb here.
If we don't have
a vote in the House, then what?
- Mark Usher is your friend, not mine.
- Mark Usher's no one's friend.
Francis Underwood
hasn't won a thing, okay?
And there's a good...
More than a good chance that Will Conway
will be the next President
of the United States.
Could you give me a moment?
It's been a difficult few days.
...Better?
Yes.
We couldn't let the House vote
proceed on Monday.
Why not?
Because you would've lost.
Even if Conway took the presidency,
we would've had a foothold with you.
We could've sabotaged,
just like we did with the Walkers.
- The Conways are not the Walkers.
- It wasn't your decision to make.
Excuse me?
You said it yourself. You're only acting.
I agreed with Usher
because he will sacrifice everything
to get Brockhart into office,
which makes Conway weak, ready to lose.
I thought you saw what I saw.
I did. I do.
We're perfectly in sync, Claire.