So she's a dancer, right?
Broadway, summer stock, all that shit.
Who was telling me, Ginny...
Used to do a little dancing, right?
Taught ballet, years ago.
- Who's that?
- Nobody. Jersey.
Ralph Cifaretto's crew.
Anyway, I go over to her house
one night...
...she's dressed like a fucking cat,
like from that show.
Eye makeup, claws, the whole bit.
You okay?
Pardon me a minute, huh?
Hey. Donny, right?
John, how you doing?
What's the matter?
Not funny anymore?
- Bitch! You're fucking funny, huh?
- John!
- What's the matter with you? Please!
- Can't shut your mouth?
Funny, huh?
- Funny? Funny?
- Whoa, whoa, John! What the fuck?
- What'd he do?
- He's a cunt! A sorry sack of shit!
- Come on, let me get you out of here.
- No, no. Please.
Scumbag, let me buy you a drink.
What the fuck?
John?
- John?
- What are you doing still up?
Penny Serenade was on AMC.
John, your coat!
Is that the Burberry?
Oh, my God, what happened?
Nothing. I tripped.
- You tripped where?
- I don't know.
- The steps by Carmine's.
- John, your hand is bleeding.
I used it to break my fall. Jesus,
what is this, the Inquisition now?
I had a few cognacs.
Go to sleep.
For tax-deferred growth the annuity's
fine, but if I'm hearing you right...
...liquidity's the real concern?
Well, we do occasionally need
ready access to our money.
Honestly, guys, I'd recommend
a life insurance trust.
That, coupled with a growth-oriented
reallocation of your assets.
Including an assortment
of other investment vehicles.
What, like classic cars?
No. Stocks, bonds...
I think he's pulling your leg, Brian.
I gotta remember that one.
So great, we'll open an account,
get the paperwork started and...
Brian, look, no offense.
I know we're family,
but let me think about it.
Run it by my accountant.
Ginsberg? He's a CPA.
He's not an investment advisor.
Whatever, he knows about this stuff.
You know what? Talk to your
accountant. Two heads, huh?
- Dad, it's Uncle Sil!
- I gotta get that.
Say hello to Janelle.
I'll walk you out, Bri.
Hang it up, A.J!
Hey.
What happened?
- Hey.
- Hey, yourself.
What the fuck, John?
- I got nothing to say.
- You got nothing to say?
That fucking kid is in intensive care.
I thought he worked for Ralph.
And Ralph works for me.
So I ask you again, what the fuck?
Let it suffice that I know
and Carmine knows...
...that foppy cocksucker's
holding out on us.
Fernandez Paving, Ralph's contracting
company. We went over the receipts...
...for waterproofing at the Esplanade.
Ralph's more creative than Spielberg.
He's off almost four grand,
third time in a row now.
We agreed, no looting the job site.
First of all, that hasn't
been established.
Second of all, this is
how you handle it?
- Consider it a message.
- He's in Miami.
- They got phones down there.
- He's got a bad history, Tony.
Cute cocksucker could wind up dead.
What are you saying here?
He's a two-faced fucking prick.
- I thought Ralph was your friend.
- Right, that's rich.
Did you hear what my friend
said about my wife?
He made a crack about Ginny's weight.
Something about her having...
...a 90-pound mole on her ass.
Well, that's...
That's deplorable.
Who told you this?
What's important is that it was said.
If he said it, I didn't hear it.
He knows better than to make
a remark like that when I'm around.
She's fighting a weight problem
since the kids were born.
Weight Watchers, Richard Simmons,
fasting.
She works very fucking hard.
- You're telling me?
- It's different for women.
Body image, self-esteem.
I'll tell you, though...
...I never had a problem
with Ginny's weight.
To me, she's beautiful.
Rubenesque.
That woman is my life.
To think she's being mocked...
All right, look, John...
...I'm not gonna sit here and deny
that Ralph can be a fucking asshole.
And that was a horrible thing to say.
But even if it was said, you can't be
serious about him winding up...
- You know.
- She's the mother of my children.
I know she is, John. I know she is.
At least hear Ralph out.
How long we go back, huh?
All of us?
The kid last night...
...he was laughing.
About this?
I don't know.
All right.
You're right.
It's just been sticking in my craw.
So this kid gonna be okay?
I don't know. He's still unconscious.
My fucking temper.
Is he married, children, anything?
Lives with his mother.
I'll send her something nice.
I'm surprised he didn't call you.
Who knows? Maybe he'll be right back.
One sugar, right?
So how are things at Casa del Furio?
Ehh.
The Pakistani, the neighbor.
I want to make my garage into the
guesthouse, so my parents can visit.
He says to me because
of the rules I cannot do it.
Right, right, the zoning.
The man who sells me the house,
he says nothing.
As far as I remember, once title
has passed, you have no legal recourse.
Anyway, next week, I make a party
for the housewarm.
What a nice idea.
This is my real-estate exam.
There's one more prep course
I wanna take.
So next Sunday is the party.
We will be there.
Now, here, you see?
"Except in cases of demonstrable fraud,
transfer of title is binding...
...once the grantee registers the deed
with the county clerk."
Some people say college only serves
to show grad schools...
...you've managed to show up
four years in a row.
But volunteering at the Law Center
actually allows you to make a difference.
Last year, with our help,
over half a dozen crack babies...
...were reunited
with their natural mothers...
...several of whom are now in recovery.
Eventually with the help
of ACLU attorneys...
...you'll be filing court papers
and helping with legal research.
There's a sign-up sheet and some fliers
if you're interested. Thanks.
That's so true what you said about
college being an audition for grad school.
So much for higher learning, huh?
Living in the moment.
Check out the Law Center.
There's some really cool people there.
There were 15 guys at the dinner
when Ralph told that joke.
Could be anybody flapping their gums.
What I don't get is why.
- What's the upside of telling Johnny?
- To get in good with New York.
Loose lips sink ships.
First Johnny knows about flipping
the property by the Esplanade.
Now this shit.
How about Patsy?
He's had issues.
Maybe he's holding a grudge.
- Oh, you really think he's that cagey?
- Albert, then.
Wait a minute.
What if Vesuvio's bugged and
the fucking feds told Johnny?
- Conspiracy theories now?
- Why not?
Create a little dysentery
among the ranks?
First of all, the place is swept
once a week.
Second of all, there's
a lot more interesting shit...
...being talked about in there
besides Ginny Sack's fat ass.
Sil, the liquor inspector's here.
What do you think?
It's not possible, right?
Silvio talking to Johnny?
You never know, T.
Jason's always been
a well-adjusted young man.
So why now, Elliot?
Three years at Bard and suddenly
now as a senior this epic drift.
No focus, no drive.
He's actually talked about dropping out
and joining the Forestry Service.
Well, some people thrive on solitude.
Senior year. There's something
about the light...
...at the end of that tunnel
that can be very frightening.
Saskia's a senior.
Is she going through any of this?
Sask has always been highly motivated,
kineahora.
Where's Richard in all this anyway?
Jason barely speaks to him anymore.
- Since when?
- Right after the rape.
Jason may be feeling
guilty himself, Jen.
He's powerless to avenge you...
...and resents his father
for the same shortcomings.
- Oh!
- Hey, George Hamilton.
How's the back?
The masseuse down there, the Del Rey?
Magic fucking fingers.
- Tony call?
- On his way.
- He know you broke up with his sister?
- No, no. Not unless she told him.
- You know what that bitch was into?
- What?
She wanted to stick a dildo up my ass,
make believe she was pimping me out.
I told her, "Get the fuck out of here!"
- What the fuck?
- Whole family's nuts.
- Hi.
- Hey, Ton.
Hey!
- How are you?
- Hey, Ton.
How you doing?
Fellas, take this shit to my house.
Open some windows, air the place out.
For you. Florida's finest.
Thanks.
How's Donny K?
I was just asking them about that.
I gotta get over there,
get the full report.
Any idea who's writing
the family gossip column?
Funny thing about that, Ton, I don't
remember saying anything about Ginny.
Come on, Ralph.
I was sitting right there.
Then maybe I said something. I forget.
There was a lot of wine that night.
What about the land deal?
Frelinghuysen?
You forget and tell him that you,
me and Zellman made all that money?
Did I tell him about it? No.
But I sure as shit ended up
paying for it.
When you think about it,
Johnny's got some balls.
Big house, lining his pocket
with our hard-earned cash?
Who's he think's keeping
that fat bitch in Devil Dogs?
Whatever he is, he's also
Carmine's underboss...
...so you're gonna fucking placate him.
Oh, what, apologize?
No, you do that it'll be worse.
Whoever told him this,
it's your word against theirs.
You're highly fucking outraged.
- Hello?
- Hello, sweetie. It's your secret admirer.
- Is he there?
- Oh, hi, Ralph. One sec.
John, Ralph Cifaretto!
- I'll take it in there.
- Okay, honey.
- Yeah?
- John, it's me.
And?
And I'm calling to tell you
how appalled I am.
I just got back. I talked to Tony.
I love Ginny. I would never say
anything like that.
- That's not what I heard.
- From who?
From who, John?
I don't betray confidences.
Are you denying it?
Fuck yes, I'm denying I said it.
I don't believe you.
Just tell me who said this.
I'll put a bullet in their fucking eye.
You're a real weasel, you know that?
John, please.
Look, last year, when Tony and I had
our thing, that misunderstanding...
...you were the voice of reason.
You were the one that told me
to apologize.
So you're apologizing?
No.
If that's what it takes.
Why would you?
I thought you didn't say it.
- I didn't say it.
- You know something, Ralph?
Not only are you a thief,
you're a lying, fucking prick.
I should've let Tony chop
your head off a year ago.
What did I say? No apology!
I want you to sanction a hit
on Ralph Cifaretto.
What, are you fucking kidding me?
He violated my wife's honor.
Ralph slept with Ginny?
He insulted her.
He made a very insensitive joke...
...about her body
to some friends of ours.
- What did he say?
- I have to repeat it?
- My word's not good enough?
- Not if you want him clipped over it.
He said...
...she was having a 90-pound mole
removed from her ass.
The implication was her ass
is so big...
...she could have a mole that size
removed from it.
It's an off-color remark.
It was highly inappropriate.
You want, I'll demand he's taxed.
But clip him?
Is it all just about money?
I'll crack him good.
I'll ask for 200 grand.
Two hundred grand for insulting
my wife. What's next?
- He gets to fuck her for a million?
- He wants to fuck her?
I'm making a point! I'm talking about
my wife's honor here. My honor!
We depend on this guy.
There are millions of dollars at stake.
We can't afford it, John.
A roomful of guys making fun
of my wife...
...and you're not gonna let me deal
with this?
Not that way.
My answer's gotta be no.
I wanna sit down, then, with Ralph,
the fucking thief.
Get this Fernandez Paving
bullshit dealt with.
He was accused of a crime
of severe immorality.
They actually beat him for it
with sticks.
The truth was, he had a photograph
of Britney Spears with his belongings.
That's horrible.
Dad?
Thought I was in the wrong place.
What are you doing here?
I was looking for a glass of milk
to dunk these in...
...and I thought maybe you could
help me out.
Got a meeting in the city later.
Rahimah, this is my dad.
- How you doing?
- Hello.
- Want a doughnut?
- No, thanks.
- Well, I'll see you later, Meadow?
- Okay, Rahimah.
So, what's this your mother tells me
about you joining the Legal Aid Society?
South Bronx Law Center.
I'm volunteering.
They provide free legal counsel
for the indigent and disenfranchised.
And this Rahoomi, she's what,
your first client?
What happened to being a pediatrician?
I thought that was a great field
for you, the way you love kids.
Nothing happened to it.
I can't explore some career options?
Oh, defending fare beaters is a career?
Is that why you came here,
to annoy me?
Hey, you wanna help people. That's fine.
That's... That's very noble.
Really, I mean it.
Just don't be a sucker.
A lot of these indigenous types...
...they got plenty of money to smoke
crack and gamble and all that shit.
You ought to know.
Oh, I see. That's what this is, huh?
You're working with minorities now to
get back at me for being mean to Noel.
God, listen to you.
Believe it or not, the world
doesn't revolve around you.
Come on, let's...
Let's go to the bookstore.
You probably need a sweatshirt
or something.
Oh.
Hey, take it easy!
How was the traffic?
Tunnel was a little backed up.
This time of day, GW,
you zip right over.
All right, let's straighten this out.
I talked to the guy over at
Fernandez Paving, the accountant.
Fernandez's been using
this jerk for years.
Anyway, it turns out you're right.
He's adding 50 gallons of sealant
every 1000 yards.
Excuse me. I can't do this.
- What?
- John, what's wrong?
I can't listen to this bullshit.
- I'm trying to explain.
- Fuck you!
- John, please...
- Don't fucking "John" me!
- Hey, hey, we're trying to settle this.
- It's not about that.
I'm sorry, Carmine. I can't be
in the same room with this man.
Have you talked
to Jason La Penna lately?
Actually, I try not to.
When I came out, he acted all weird.
I can't believe I actually
kissed him once.
His mother tells me he's having
a rough time.
Jen? Please.
I'm sure she's overreacting.
Apparently he's talked
about dropping out.
He's okay, but Jason is like
the cliché psychiatrist's kid.
Slightest bump in the road, he knows
exactly what to say to get attention.
Hey.
Is there any of that crumb cake left?
Counter.
What's all that?
I'm consolidating some bills.
Maybe you don't care about
our future, Tony, but I do.
Where do you get that I don't care?
I met with your cousin.
Yeah, you met with Brian. You sat there
eating cake and making wisecracks.
It's boring to me, okay?
You gonna cry now?
What the hell is wrong with you?
When you ignore me, Tony...
...when you trivialize things important
to me, like our financial security...
...it makes me feel unloved.
That's your problem there,
because you equate love with money!
No, you equate love with money!
- Is it safe?
- We each got a new cell phone.
Talk on it once, you toss it.
Totally untraceable.
It's what the Taliban used to do.
Let's get started. My daughter-in-law's
coming here with the baby later.
Hello?
- Is he there?
- Yeah, Ton.
Okay, you're all set.
Just talk into there.
- Junior?
- Who's that? Tony?
Junior, it's Carmine. How you doing?
I'm going to the poorhouse,
that's how I'm doing.
When you had that RICO trial,
what'd that run you?
- A lot.
- Where you going?
I told you I gotta pick up Sophia.
Junior, can we do this already?
Yeah. Yeah, right.
Johnny and Ralph Cifaretto, right?
- Ralph insulted John's wife?
- That's correct.
- Who's on the wire now?
- It's John, Corrado.
So, what did Ralph do exactly?
He made a very hurtful remark,
not worth repeating.
It's not important.
Let's just agree it was unkind.
Let's point out, too, that it's only
been alleged something was said.
He "allegedly" said what he said
to a group of people, friends of ours.
If you weren't there,
how do you know?
I'm not at liberty to say.
All due respect, but this is bullshit.
Someone in my family's talking,
and you're not at liberty to say?
- I should be making the beef here.
- My nephew's right.
Let's stick to the issue. A horrible
insult was made against Ginny.
End of fucking story.
- What does he want done about it?
- I wanna avenge her honor. It's my right.
All right, fine. You tell me who told
you about it, we'll bring him in here.
He corroborates what you're saying,
I'll give you Ralph on a platter.
Is nothing sacred? I mean, this is
my wife we're talking about here.
If this were years ago, would
I even have had to ask?
I mean, what's happened to this thing?
For God's sake, we bend more rules
than the Catholic Church.
All right, look.
Let's assume for the sake of argument
Ralph said what you think he said.
- Is clipping him gonna unring that bell?
- Nobody's getting clipped.
- I want satisfaction.
- Will you accept an apology?
- That ship has sailed.
- You're being unreasonable, John.
Ralph's the only one
who can handle the Esplanade?
- Put Pontecorvo in there.
- There are millions at stake.
- Again with the money?
- Yeah, again with the money.
It's settled, John. So either name
a price or get the fuck over it.
John?
What would you say to a piece
of Ralph's company?
John? Just think about it at least.
- Hello?
- It's me.
What, are you still asleep?
No, I was doing something.
I took John to dinner last night.
Ralph's got a big problem, kid.
- I thought you squashed it.
- I did.
Problem is, I don't know
if John's hearing me.
- So, what are you gonna do about it?
- Me? Nothing.
- What does that mean?
- I didn't say nothing.
We share the Esplanade, Tony.
I don't want that apple cart upset.
Then somebody should do
something about it.
I appreciate your thoughts.
You saying what I think you're saying?
I didn't say nothing.
All right, then. I'll talk to you.
Twenty years I been friends with John.
Now he's gotta go.
All over a stupid joke.
I was fucking around.
For chrissakes! You never made
a joke about Ginny Sack?
- Not like that.
- Of course not.
Yeah, well, fuck him
and his highfalutin bullshit.
Who does he think he is,
Sir Walter Raleigh?
That's enough of you and
your stupid fucking remarks!
Go back to Miami and play volleyball,
whatever the fuck you do down there...
...while we clean up your fucking mess!
Maybe even keep your ass alive.
A mole on her ass?
What's the joke? I still don't get it.
It's not a joke, per se. It's...
You had to be there.
Real lack of standards, your generation.
My day, John was right. A man would
never stand for a remark like that.
Fucked up thing is, I don't like Ralph.
If he were drowning,
I'd throw him a cinder block.
But not protect one of my own captains?
Besides, it's too late anyway.
Carmine gave me the nod.
On Johnny?
That one's a slippery fuck, huh?
Him and those big fish lips of his?
Look at this.
The fifth question, and the poor prick
used all his lifelines.
John goes, Carmine's gonna position
himself for maximum deniability.
So you make it easy for everybody.
Take it out of the neighborhood.
- What, like an accident?
- Accident, stickup.
He could choke on a chicken wing.
The important thing is,
Johnny disappears.
With Johnny out, Carmine's gonna
put his son in there...
...fucking Brainless the Second.
Who knows, maybe there's an upside
to Johnny going.
He goes to Boston a lot,
visit his father.
Could happen up there.
You want my advice,
you'll call Lou Dimaggio.
The Atwell Avenue boys.
What, those sick old fucks
in Rhode Island?
They may be old, my little nephew,
but those dogs can still hunt.
My old man used to talk about them,
something to do with drugs.
Heroin.
Back in the '50s, it was raining cash
with that shit.
Dimaggio and his crew
never saw a dime.
The guy they worked for, Lenny Caputo,
he didn't believe in it.
For 15 years, everyone and their mother
was getting rich dealing H.
Everyone except these guys.
They're eking a living doing hits,
running swag.
Anyway, lo and behold, one day
Lenny gets pinched...
...for heroin trafficking.
It turns out the cocksucker's
been making a fortune...
...working with the melanzane.
And not only that...
...he's been selling out
his own guys to the feds...
...so he can keep his ass
out on the street.
Dimaggio and another guy in his crew
did eight years on a murder rap.
So much for loyalty, huh?
You go to Rhode Island and whatever
you do, don't mention drugs.
Coke, heroin, not even Tylenol.
So, what happened
to this Lenny prick?
Lou Dimaggio, his real name's Galina.
They called him Dimaggio after
the cops found Lenny and his wife...
...with their heads bashed in
by a baseball bat.
Anyway, that was Lou
while he still had his health.
We could do this ourselves, ninja style.
Father?
We're here to see Lou Dimaggio.
Oh, come in.
Hello. Silvio Dante.
We spoke on the phone.
Chris Moltisanti, how you doing?
- My name's Chris too.
- Oh, yeah?
- Are you into drugs?
- What?
No. What do you mean?
We don't work for drug dealers.
- No. No.
- Course not.
Want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Rose?
- Yeah, Pop?
- More Sanka.
Anyway, this is him.
John Sacrimoni.
He...
He'll be coming up through here
next few days.
He stays at the Boston Harbor Hotel.
The guy on the left.
- It's my birthday too.
- We're having cake later.
Carvel.
Chromosomes. Runs in the family.
There was a guy once, Tommy Neri.
Got him coming home
from the track one night.
Caught him good with a tire iron.
When he woke up, I held him down...
...while Frank cut his head off
with a hacksaw.
Silent as a mouse pissing on cotton.
If you like, we could arrange to have
that same thing happen again.
I don't know that we need
to be that overstated.
What'd you have in mind, then?
Nothing fancy.
As long as he disappears.
It's your money.
Yeah, about that.
Twenty grand, we said.
Half up front.
So...
...we'll call you then?
Pop, Father's here.
Would you like some cake?
Actually, we got a long ride back.
Have you seen my sweater,
the cable knit?
The white one? It shrunk.
I put it in the bag for Goodwill.
I told you I'd bring it up to Dad.
I'm sorry. It's in the basement,
near the card table.
- Hello?
- It's me.
I just hung up with a guy, Jerry,
from Fort Lauderdale.
That guy we're looking for,
he's at the Del Rey Hotel in Miami.
Our friend with the paving problem.
Send someone over there tomorrow
to take care of it, then.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
I'd feel a lot better
with the pope's blessing.
Just do as you're told.
I'll deal with the fallout.
Who was that, hon?
Nobody. A plumber for the store.
- What's that you're making?
- Fruit salad. You want some?
Low-fat whipped cream.
No. You enjoy it, sweetie.
Why did I have to come?
He's not even home.
Hey, look who's here.
Carmela, Anthony, how you doing?
We were passing by,
I figured we'd give it a shot.
- No, we weren't.
- Come, come, I show you.
I was working in the yard,
clear the weeds.
Next year I'll grow grapes
for the falanghina.
Gonna make my own wine.
It's gorgeous, Fur.
So that's the garage in question.
Anthony, don't wander off.
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- Just stay put.
We're leaving in five minutes.
So you're thinking of making that
an apartment for your parents?
A garage. I don't need it.
One time back in Naples...
...I work in the garden as a landscaper
for a very rich man.
Just me, I work there alone,
growing olives.
My hands in the dirt, the hot sun.
I was never so happy in my life
as when I work at that place.
Sometimes I get the smell of olives...
...in a restaurant, in the store maybe.
It makes me very sad.
You know, I'm not sure, but I think
if it was built before 1938...
...you can apply for a zoning variance.
Pre-existing non-conforming structure,
I think it's called.
I just got it back from the Martinizing.
They do a nice job over there.
Say hi to Dad for me. I put Allegra's
graduation picture in a frame for him.
Good.
- Love you.
- I love you too.
Careful driving.
Shit!
It's me!
Hello?
Why is the door unlocked?
Gin?
- Jesus, you scared the shit out of me!
- What are you doing?
- I thought you left.
- I forgot the sweater.
- What are you doing on the floor?
- I was getting the laundry together.
John...
What's this?
I thought you're on Atkins.
I was. I am.
It's hard, John. I'm trying.
This is how you try?
I'm not out of the house 10 minutes?
I was dizzy. I was having
low blood sugar.
What happened to fruit salad?
- You were supposed to quit smoking!
- Nicotine's an addictive substance!
What's wrong with you?
Why are you yelling?
Did I ask you to go on a diet?
Did I ask you to be thin for me?
The fasting, the NutriSystems,
those goddamn Deal-a-Meal cards?
It's the world, John, our culture.
Fuck that! Do you have any idea
what you've done?
- What do you mean?
- You lied to me! You lied!
I know I've gained weight
these last few years.
I see the other wives,
the way men look at them.
Don't I look at you like that?
Haven't I always?
It was your idea,
all this dieting nonsense.
I wanted you to be proud of me.
I am proud of you.
I love you.
Welcome to the Del Rey Hotel, ma'am.
- Can I get your bags?
- Oh, thanks.
Okay, go on into the lobby,
I'll meet you inside.
- Hello?
- Listen, it's me.
I talked to my guy,
we're calling it off.
I'm already out here though.
Like, right there.
We'll work something out, then.
Don't worry about it.
- I want half.
- All right, whatever.
Getting out?
No.
What's your fucking problem?
Oh, I love the pine flooring.
I know, it's so rustic.
This is pretty cool.
It's actually from Italy.
I'm so bored I feel like crying.
It's adorable, Furio, really.
I'm gonna be leaving soon.
Come on.
Stick around. Have some food.
Anything from our friends up north?
Carmine called. Johnny's still in town.
I'm not kidding. There's tons of toys
in there he said you could have.
They're back behind those boxes.
Bullshit, you're gonna lock me in.
Okay, fine. But don't say
I didn't tell you.
He gets them from Italy.
His father owns a steamship company.
Okay.
Go ahead, I'll get the flashlight.
Help! Let me out of here!
Gabriella, come.
Come on, dance. Come on.
- No.
- Go.
Silvio, you tell her, she can't wear
fancy shoes and no dance, come on.
- No, no.
- Shake it up a little.
- Come on, Dad, dance with me.
- No, no. No, thanks.
Tommy Tune over there.
Carmela, come here.
You come too.
Yeah, Carm, go ahead. Good idea.
Okay. You watch me,
you do the same.
Everybody, come on.
- That's it.
- God, I'm such a spaz.
- No, no, you're good. Come.
- Meadow.
Come on.
Nice.
- We'll be in fucking big trouble.
- It ain't gonna happen.
At least it's not just Jason
who's regressing.
Soprano? His own daughter was
going through the same thing.
I felt like such a fraud
giving him advice.
My own son has three years
on his daughter...
...and look how he's acting.
Jen, why do you still feel guilty?
Sometimes I wonder
if Richard had a point.
I shouldn't have gone down into
that garage that late at night.
I went to see Sask at school
the other day...
...and I'm in the parking garage
over there?
I was driving around for 20 minutes
when finally I spot someone leaving...
...this big Bluto sort of guy.
I must have crowded him
as he headed for his car.
Anyway, he turned around
and became quite confrontational.
And for a second, I'll admit,
I thought of you.
What are you getting at?
Parking garages are not
inherently dangerous places.
Jen, you cannot blame yourself
for what happened to you.
Turns out this guy was probably another
parent or, more likely, a repairman.
But if he had dragged me out of my car
and beaten me up...
...would I be saying, "Gee, I shouldn't
have tried to park my car?"
Anyway, enough about him.
Let's get back to you.
You wanted to see me?
You can tell Ralph I've decided
to accept his apology.
You know that kid you pissed on?
Donny K?
He's got fucking nerve damage
on his left side.
I'm sorry, Tony.
I bet you are.
I'll expect to hear from Ralph, then.
Why the big reversal all of a sudden?
No more weight remarks, Tony.
They're hurtful,
and they're destructive.
Oh, I agree.
Still awake?
I'm just reading.
Bought you something.
What's this for?
No reason.
I don't know if I believe that.
Put a call in to Ginsberg, by the way.
He's back from California.
Tony, this is beautiful.
What size is this?
I don't know, small.
I don't know if this'll fit.
Try it on.
See? I knew you could pull it off.
You look like a model.
Listen to him now.
Tony.
Tony!
I'm sorry, Tony.
- What's the matter?
- I can't. The music.
Meadow, turn it off!
What?
Meadow?
Meadow!
- What?
- The music!
Will you turn it down, please?
I'm going out.