Here, I made it with
a lot of milk and sugar.
It's more comforting that way.
You sure you don't want some eggs
or an English or something?
You're coming back?
I hope so. Immigration,
they make problems.
Well, maybe Tony can help with that.
Yeah.
Why are you still here?
I thought you were flying out to Naples.
I just drop off the shirts
from Patsy's guy.
But you should be on your way
to see your old man.
Cancer is everywhere in his body.
Cancer don't respect nothing.
- You know, it started in his guts.
- Do you need any money?
I'm good.
Please call. And let us know.
I'm sorry, Tony.
You're gonna have to get
somebody else to drive you.
It's not a problem. Go.
You think he wears a bag?
- Who wears what?
- You know, a colostomy bag.
Furio's old man.
- How the fuck would I know that?
- Because my ma...
...maybe, maybe not, has to get one.
- Could we not talk about this?
- We could talk about any topic you like.
Good.
It's just that with Ma
squared away to go to Green Grove...
For fuck's sake, Paulie,
everybody's gonna get old and die.
- Am I driving you tomorrow too?
- No, I'll drive myself.
- I got nothing else to do.
- I got an important meeting, that's all.
It's a delicate situation.
We lucked out with the weather, huh?
So how's the life of leisure?
I'm playing golf, ain't I?
Cocksucker.
Seriously, it's good you're pulling back
business-wise like we agreed.
My nephew, I told him.
I'm gonna be speaking...
...through him and
only him as time passes.
- Good.
- Plus Sil.
Good.
I don't wanna celebrate
my daughter's first kid in prison.
- Hey.
- All right, this sit-down in Perth Amboy.
- Get a pen and paper.
- Hold on.
I can't find a piece of paper.
- Shoot.
- All right, tell Paulie to let Patsy...
...run the car operation
while Furio's gone.
Tell Patsy he's got to kick
up 10 points.
Seven and a half to me,
two and a half to Paulie.
- Got it.
- All right, you and Sil, you figure out...
...who pays the Longshore Union and
how much. I'll back you up whichever.
What the fuck?
- I'm on it.
- All right.
- Carmela, a simple yes or no will do.
- Please.
- Artie. Hi, how are things?
- Fine.
They ever catch those muggers?
Did you leave room for dessert?
We'll have one zabaglione
and four spoons. Coffees all around.
Bri, can I ask you
a financial-related question?
The last thing the guy wants to do
is talk shop.
Go ahead and ask him anything.
It's all he likes to talk about.
No big thing. I was wondering
if you had any ideas what Tony...
...should do with the proceeds
from the property in Newark?
- A HUD?
- What?
Kid loves Paul Newman movies.
No more grappa for you.
You know what I'm talking about.
Uncle Junior's lot on Frelinghuysen Ave.
Oh, yeah, that.
It all went into the trust.
T-bills. I was able to lock you in
before the rates dropped.
What doesn't this kid
know about money?
You know, I trust him 1000%.
Thank you.
We have so many more
of the newborn size.
I think they're cheaper.
Next year we can put a notice
in the bulletin...
...that people whose last names
begin with A to K...
...bring the newborns and L to Z
bring the bigger ones. Or vice versa.
Whatever we give them, the girls
at our ladies' shelter should be grateful.
I mean, nobody told them to go
and have babies without husbands.
I remember his charity
toward my family when Jack died.
I didn't know how to pay the phone bill.
Jackie did everything.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Well, I pay bills, but other than that
it's the same with Tony.
Try to find out where the money is,
how much we have...
...and I get such resistance.
I didn't know what we had
until after I buried Jackie.
Well, was it enough?
Sort of.
Not really.
How much is enough, anyway?
I don't know, that's my point.
Doesn't anything ever change?
Women are supposed
to be partners nowadays.
I'm not a feminist,
I'm not saying 50-50, but Jesus.
You know, I put up with this
goomar shit. Pardon my French.
Well, I made my peace with it
best I could, anyway.
Isn't your cousin Brian
handling your money?
The big things, the investments.
He's doing well too.
You know, I do have
to give Tony credit there.
He did meet me halfway
with that, God bless him.
- Which was a big step for him.
- Maybe you have nothing to worry about.
I don't know. Tony pulls people into
his circle, I don't know what to think.
Good girl.
Titanium?
Track's freezing up.
It's too hard for aluminum.
Well, whatever she's got on
those feet, she's a winner.
A little colicky?
Yeah. You don't feel good,
big girl? You big girl.
Fuck this horse-whispering shit.
What is this costing us?
Oh, Tony, Valentina.
- Valentina, Tony Soprano.
- Hi.
She works in an art gallery.
Helping me to enlarge my collection.
And this, my Chiquita Banana,
is Pie-O-My.
- She's beautiful.
- There's no stopping this horse.
- She's gonna go to the Breeders'.
- We'll do the geldings next, Whitey.
Hon, can you come here a sec?
I think I have something in my eye.
Let Dr. Ralphie have a look.
- I don't see anything.
- Maybe you need more light.
The fuck?
- I can't believe you did this to me.
- It was a joke, hon.
- Nothing funny about it.
- There is from where I'm standing.
Besides, it's good luck.
- What?
- It's good luck to step in horse shit.
- Ask any horse person.
- It's true.
Then why aren't you
walking around all day...
...looking for horse shit
to stomp around in?
- It only works if it's an accident.
- Fucking sick, all of youse.
Fucko, where's the hose?
You know, it can be risky trusting him
to have a sense of humor.
- Did you think it was funny?
- What I think is funny...
...is what an 8-year-old boy
thinks is funny.
- Having any fun yourself?
- What, you taking a survey?
- Have any interest in art?
- Sure. The right thing, I do.
There's an artist down in New Hope,
specializes in horses.
Give him a photo,
he paints a beautiful portrait.
- It'd look great in your office.
- Have a look at my office...
...before you make that call.
Think about it. If you're interested...
...give me a call.
"La Paz."
- What's that, Puerto Rican?
- Cubana.
My mother was Italian.
My father Cuban.
You're a dangerous combination.
She gorgeous or what?
Sweet as sugar.
If there is anything you need,
anything at all, press this button.
- Which one?
- This one that I'm showing you.
- Safety first.
- A friend, Ms. Cirillo, might stop by.
She said she wanted
to see you before lunch.
Oh, Cookie.
Look, just like home. They're gonna
wait on you hand and foot around here.
Benny, put the boxes in the closet.
Oh, and go get the TV.
The both of youse carry it.
Come on, cowgirl.
Let's go down to the chuck wagon...
...and see what they're rustling up.
- Paulie, did they bring my bathmat?
- For the fifth time, Ma, yes.
Hey, look who's here
to make you feel at home.
- Cookie. Are you here too?
- Not yet, but it's all paid for.
- I'm gonna move in after my surgery.
- Minn comes twice a week for lunch.
And in the meantime
she's one of the girls.
- Look how you've grown up, Paulie.
- I know. I don't understand it.
When I was a kid,
you two were old ladies.
Now I'm old
and you two are still old.
So how's Chucky doing, anyway?
Still teaching?
He's been a high school principal
for the last 10 years or so.
- Bergen North.
- He must give you a lot of happiness.
- Except for that wife of his.
- All you ever been was nice to her.
- I know that.
- Come on, girls. I'll take you to lunch.
- I gotta use the WC.
- She just went 10 minutes ago.
Paulie, I don't want to embarrass
your mother in the dining room...
...so make sure that she knows
she can't sit with me...
...and Minn and our other girls.
- What are you talking about?
- We're a set group.
We eat together,
we play Scrabble for money...
...and there's really no room
at either table.
Come on now, Cookie.
I know you girls can work it out.
Fucking amazing.
This is how simple it is
to change inputs.
- Listen to that imaging in stereo mode.
- It's like Clapton's there at your house.
Tony.
Great, huh?
We can all watch movies
as a family now.
And listen to that.
I think it's great.
I'm going food shopping.
Maybe I'll get In the Bedroom.
- What time you want me to wake you?
- The movie.
Oh, yeah.
- Good.
- Have fun.
- Hello?
- Mr. Bolton, please?
- Chuck?
- Richard.
- Yeah, can you talk?
- Yeah, I'm on a hotel phone.
So how are you? What's going on?
I found him, Chuck.
I found the man who killed Helen.
- What?
- It was me they were after.
Who? Who are they?
Devlin MacGregor and Lentz.
Lentz was supervising
the protocol for RDU-90.
He knew I found out it was causing
liver damage. It was Lentz.
Richard, Lentz is dead.
What? How?
He died in a car accident last summer.
- Richard?
- Yeah.
Can you prove this about the drug?
Yeah, I think so.
I need your help, Chuck.
Call Bones at the hospital...
...tell him to give me
whatever help I need.
Beautiful-looking animal.
Great definition, carriage.
I'd love to paint her.
Good, good.
But what about this deadbeat?
There's no problem
cropping you both out.
We could set her in front
of the rail at the track...
...or if you'd prefer something more
pastoral, we can place her in a meadow.
I don't know about that, but can you
leave me in there and crop him out?
Easy. And frankly, it would be better.
Composition-wise.
Go for the pastoral,
much more dignified.
- And it comes framed?
- Exactly as you see that one.
Six thousand five hundred.
All right, you got a deal.
- To Pie-O-Mine.
- My.
- Your what?
- No, no, no, the name. It's "Pie-O-My."
I'll give you the whole thing now.
There.
I'd better get your receipt.
I'll just be a minute.
Let's not forget to drink
to the beautiful señorita...
...whose idea this was
in the first place.
I bet you say that to all the girls.
There's not that many. To tell
the truth, the ones that there are...
...they don't got many ideas.
We should probably start
heading back soon.
Yeah.
- On the way we could stop and eat.
- Yeah, we could definitely stop.
- Like that.
- Oh, yeah, so nice.
- Just like that.
- Yeah, that's so good.
Come on, let me up.
Let me up.
You can see cows from in there.
Sit down and eat
before it gets any colder.
- Looks good, doesn't it?
- Mine needed salt.
Jesus-fucking-Christ, these
fucking hicks can't even get this right.
You did this?
Oh, that's very mature.
It's not funny.
I thought you had an
8-year-old sense of humor.
Come here and give me a kiss.
I'm eating.
Not anymore, you're not.
What if I promise to be good?
How good?
Good.
Shit, I lost a nail.
We will not be mentioning
anything about any of this to Ralph.
I'll take it. Can you send it
to this person here?
Sure. You want to include
a card with this?
Yeah.
Let me have another one.
Round and round she goes.
Where she stops, nobody knows.
Place your bets. Be a winner.
- I'll take another card.
- Are you sure, dear?
For the love of God, Nucci,
how could you hit on 18?
Give me another one.
That should've been my card.
I could've had 21.
I was hoping for a three.
I'm not sure you understand
the fine points.
Maybe you ought to play roulette.
It's right over there.
Round and round she goes, where
she stops, nobody knows. Place your...
Goddamn it, Tony!
You did that to me
on our honeymoon.
I didn't like it and you promised
you'd never do it again.
- It's just cold water.
- Well, it's really unpleasant.
- Do you remember promising me?
- You could do it back to me.
- I don't wanna do it back to you.
- Why not? It's fun.
- Do you remember promising me?
- Yeah, so what?
So? This is one promise
I would like you to keep.
Whatever.
- This can't be Paulie.
- Chucky?
Come here, you pizza-face
son of a son of a gun, you.
Oh, God. Mr. Van Kowenberg,
what'd we say about those shoes?
The laces are in my locker.
I was gonna get them after study hall.
Get them now.
Come on, Paulie.
Hard to believe it's been so long.
This is for you.
That's a nice gesture, Paul.
- I really can't.
- Go on, I got lots of them.
You can't insult me.
- No more glasses.
- I had the LASIK.
- And your face cleared up pretty good.
- Cleared up in 10th grade.
See, there you go. Ninth was my last.
So did your mom tell you
I saw her over at Green Grove?
- She sees quite a bit of your mother.
- Well, that's just it, Chucky.
They're both residents,
but there seems to be an exclusion.
I don't blame your mother.
I blame that Minnie Matrone.
She's a malignant cunt.
Excuse me for saying so.
She eggs your mother on
and she don't even live there.
- I'm not sure I understand.
- I'm just asking you to talk to your ma.
See if she can include my ma
in more with the group.
It won't do much good.
Now, you know how these old gals are.
All I'm trying to do
is pay my ma back...
...for when I was a kid
and got into so much trouble.
She went to bat for me
how many times? With the nuns.
With the store owners
up and down 13th Street.
And let's face it, Chucky,
with the cops.
For all the bad I did...
Hell, I'm still capable
if I don't watch myself.
But with all of that
she always had my back.
I'll talk to my ma, see what
she says, but like I said...
- Whatever you can do.
- All right. Take care, all right?
Ale was always served
in pints and quarts...
...so "Mind your P's and Q's" means
watch your alcohol consumption.
I'll be right back.
Holy cow. So there's an origin
for everything?
- What's up?
- A little business.
- Like what?
- Why, you wanna hear this?
Well, we decided to give
a bigger percentage...
...to the union guys
than the customs guys.
You're shitting me, right?
That's what you guys came up with?
- Everybody seemed pleased.
- Goddamn it, I'm gonna have...
...to go there and do
a go-see with everybody...
...from the harbor master on down.
Which is what I was trying to avoid.
You want it renegotiated,
that's what we'll do.
Don't make me go to Perth Amboy.
I'm trying to free myself up
to do a little global thinking.
Right.
- So, girls, what's it gonna be?
- I'll have what I always have.
Chicken Mario?
Fifteen years of Chicken Mario.
Can't you try the veal chop for once?
Why are you giving me
a hard time? I like chicken.
- Hello, beautiful people.
- Oh, look who it is.
- Hey, Ton.
- Hi, how are you?
- Remember Valentina?
- Yeah, nice to see you again.
- Yeah, same here.
- You pulled that horse shit stunt?
We're gonna have some steaks.
- I'll have a steak.
- You don't need a steak.
- I know I don't need a steak.
- Do me a favor...
...don't fuck with the salt shaker.
- You like the sole?
- Scampi for me.
Chrissy.
Oh, I don't know, give me...
Come on, you're getting
anorexic over there.
I'm gonna go...
I gotta make a call. Okay?
You're wasting away, you know.
Come on, what are you gonna do?
Here.
- No, no, no, you keep it.
- I don't want your consolation prize.
Bet you have a standing order
at the store.
- I gotta be getting back to my table.
- What, to the blond?
Does she fuck you better than me?
Suck your dick better than me?
Come on.
Really, Tony, just tell me.
How come I can't see you again?
- You fuck Ralph.
- You got morals all of a sudden?
No morals, but I do got rules.
Some dago macho bullshit about,
"Don't fuck your friend's girlfriend"?
Yeah, that.
- But not just that.
- Then what?
Look, that day in the countryside,
that was...
- It was great.
- Did I do something wrong? I'll fix it.
No, you can't fix the shit
I'm talking about.
I just don't wanna be
where Ralph has been.
- You prick.
- A one-time thing is one thing...
...but to get into a relationship?
I gotta get back to my dinner.
You don't know anything.
Let me tell you what's really going on.
He doesn't fuck me. I swear to God,
he's some kind of freak or something.
- You two don't have sex?
- No. Well...
- Sort of, yeah, but not...
- All right, have a nice life.
Go ahead. Go ahead,
you go back first, I'll wait a minute.
We shouldn't go back together.
- Everything come out all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
How you doing?
- You want red, right?
- Right.
- Yeah.
- Tony. It's me, Valentina.
- You got no reason to be calling me.
- I have to tell you everything.
I mean, I didn't want to tell you
before because it's just so...
...embarrassing.
Where are you?
- I'm at Ralph's.
- Oh, Christ.
No, no, it's okay.
He left. Tony...
...Ralph does not have sex
like other people. Regular people.
It's all some kind of kinky shit.
Believe me, I am not hung up.
I've done a lot. I've done girls,
I've done threesomes and I've done...
- With him?
- No, Tony, please just listen.
Ralph is loco. For real, okay?
He just makes me do stuff,
not really even sexual.
Last night I just wanted him to fuck
me so I could get back at you...
...but all he wanted me to do
was drip candle wax on his balls.
Then he went into the bathroom
and jerked off.
Now, I don't call that having
sex with someone.
- Oh, Jesus H. Christ...
- Last week, I swear to God...
...he told me to rub his dick raw
with a cheese grater.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- I wouldn't do it. I told him to fuck off.
- My accountant is here.
- Will you call me?
I gotta go.
Mozzarella.
Let me ask you a question.
You think Ralph's a little...
...weird about women?
I don't know, Ton.
I mean, he beat one to death
just for...
I forget. Why was it again?
- Maybe you're feeling guilty.
- I don't see that.
- Why would I?
- Because he's a friend of yours...
...and you're cuckolding him.
Cuckolding is when a man
has an affair with another's wife.
She's not his wife anyway.
She's his goomar.
- And therefore has no status whatever.
- Goomars have status.
I mean, it's not like in the old days
when a man had a wife...
...and then sort of a second wife.
Used to be the men would
take out their wives on Fridays...
...and their goomars on Saturdays.
Or maybe it's the other way around.
Anyway, when I came up
it wasn't so formal.
A business associate of mine's
got two full families.
One up here, one down in Sea Girt.
And the second wife busts his balls
identical to the first.
Sounds like a complicated
arrangement.
- I'm afraid our time is up.
- Just give me another minute.
- I have a patient waiting.
- Well, let them wait.
You make me wait
out there all the time.
Just wanna ask you
if it's possible for a man...
...to go out with a woman
without really doing anything with them.
- You'll have to be more specific.
- He likes them to hurt him. And that's it.
And then he goes and he...
...takes care of himself. His own needs.
- He sounds like a textbook masochist.
- Like S & M.
The "M" part, yes.
I thought all that stuff was just,
like, a run-up to the act.
That's the case for many people.
But not for people with paraphilias.
For them, receiving pain,
being humiliated...
...becomes in and of itself
the sexual release.
Like many other things,
we believe it's rooted in childhood.
- We can continue this next week.
- Just one more second.
I received regular beatings
when I was a kid...
...but I'm not looking
for some woman...
...to hook up jumper cables
to my private parts.
It's not a simple one-to-one.
More than likely he had
a controlling and punishing mother.
She loved him, but showed
it only in connection...
...with some sort of violent
or abusive act.
Is everything about everybody
really about their mothers?
All right, back to the other thing.
If a guy like that is going
out with a woman...
...he could technically not have penisary
contact with her vulva.
It sounds like you're asking me...
...for personal information
I really can't give you.
Good morning, Pickwick Framing.
Hello?
It's heartbreaking
to hear those women talk...
...about what they were
and what they are going through.
The second woman, Joan,
her case is really not very unusual.
Her husband was the financial planner.
She really did not have much
involvement in the finances at the home.
- What are your thoughts?
- Women tend to have the feeling...
...that they're not confident.
Men tend to be overconfident, actually...
...in the financial area.
Women have to take responsibility...
...and have to accept the fact
that something like this...
You have to have a plan
if your husband doesn't come home...
...and you have
to do the finances.
You gotta get up, Ma.
You can't lie there day and night.
I wanna go home.
There is no more home, Ma.
We sold it. You know that.
They keep making me eat all alone.
That's that Cookie and Minn.
I tried to be so nice.
I bought Cookie a card
from the gift shop downstairs.
I cared enough and I sent the very best.
Don't you worry, Ma.
I'm gonna talk to the social director.
She's the one
to straighten this all out.
But in the meantime,
maybe you can make new friends.
But you gotta get up out of bed.
At least sit up.
You can't let it get to you.
My brother lived a full life,
he had lots of women.
That's the best you can hope for.
You gonna stay around awhile?
Since I left for America...
all I thought about...
was coming back here.
When I saw Naples from the airplane...
I got a hard on.
What do you expect? It's home.
I don't know, anymore.
Even the San Gennaro Cathedral.
I went to pray for my father.
There were hamburger wrappers
everywhere...
I don't think it's litter that's got you
turned around.
There's a woman.
So... go home to her.
You did the duties of a son.
She's the Don's wife.
Soprano?
He doesn't know.
You fucking her?
No.
I'm not even sure that she knows.
I never even kissed her.
Good, so you stay away.
No harm done.
I don't know if I can.
I love her.
You fucking crazy?
All the shit I pulled in my life,
I never fucked the boss's wife.
You know why? You know why?
Stop the rhetorical questions.
Because I know he would kill me
if he found out.
And they always find out everything,
these bosses.
Hello...
Hold on.
I have to take this.
My lawyer.
The only way you could have her
is if you killed the man.
I know this.
Eh, so? Don't be an idiot.
In my opinion, this is
one of the closest things...
...we're gonna find in Naples
to what you should open.
It's an all-day snack shop,
pizzeria, friggitoria and rosticceria.
Roast shop, fry shop, pizza shop.
Here are four examples...
...of the classic Neapolitan pride.
Dipped in a light batter,
fried till very, very crisp.
We've got those zucchini flowers.
Recognize those?
We're bringing her back
to the track in two weeks.
Lois says she's ready to race.
- Thanks.
- Thanks, hon.
I like my drink with extra olives.
You should know how
your regular customers like their drinks.
My regular customers
are the ones who pay.
I'll get you your olives.
- What do you have to give her shit for?
- She likes it. It's banter.
I don't think she likes it. Or you.
I don't give a flying fuck, my brother,
what any little slit thinks of me.
Does that include?
- What's her name?
- Who?
- You brought her to the stables.
- Oh, Valentina.
Her especially.
And her I'm crazy about.
I'm telling you,
this broad knows things.
I've never been fucked so long
or so good.
I may have to marry her.
- These enough?
- You know, no reason to be snotty.
My dear departed mother
used to say:
"You catch more flies with honey
than you can with vinegar."
Well, mine always told me not to let
myself be talked down to by losers.
She said you could tell everything about
a man by the way he treats women.
- You ever think about your mother?
- She's dead.
You two didn't get along
very well, right?
She had her demanding ways.
- When you were a kid did she ever...?
- No, I gotta go.
The mambo queen awaits.
I'm sorry your mom's having
a difficult adjustment period. Sit.
It's not her. It's the rest of them.
They single her out.
Sometimes I think this place
is like high school with wheelchairs.
Tell your mother to be patient.
Things will settle down.
All right, I'll talk to her again...
...but what the hell are you gonna
do for us? What we pay here.
I'm speaking from years of experience.
Your mother's going to have
to learn to accept responsibility...
...for her own behavior.
Like what?
Go ahead.
For one thing, she cries a lot.
She's always in tears.
At Mass, in the exercise room,
at music appreciation.
- She's got a big heart.
- Let me finish.
She doesn't always put her teeth in.
The girls don't like that.
- This is not good.
- Right. Also, she's a tattletale.
She tells on other girls
for the slightest infraction.
She's just not very adept
at making friends.
She's gonna have to make
more of an effort.
You might want
to talk to her about this.
- Hello?
- Hey, did Conny Contino...
...get those washing machines?
I don't understand.
You want to know this?
You go back on everything
Sil and me settle.
Oh, I don't got a right to be
concerned?
Hold on. Hold on.
- Go.
- Long time no see.
- Is this you?
- I am me.
- Yeah, well, I've been busy.
- I forgive you.
When can I see you?
I've got something to tell you.
- I told you the situation.
- Come on, Tony.
Just for a coffee or a drink
or something.
All right. You know the Coach House
on Route 21 in Passaic?
- No, but I can find it.
- Can you be there by noon?
- Nothing could keep me away.
- All right, I'll see you there.
All right, I want to see you
and Sil this afternoon.
Two o'clock, at the other place.
So sorry I'm late, I had to make up
this whole thing at work.
- All right.
- What can I get for you?
Evian or whatever.
So I'm here. What's this big thing
you have to tell me?
I broke up with Ralph.
- When?
- Last night. I just couldn't take it.
- He brought out this leather mask...
- All right, all right, all right.
This means we can be together.
Look, Valentina, I'm a married man.
I'm a happily married man with two kids.
I just wanna see you sometimes.
Couple nights a week.
I'm not gonna say I love you. I say that
too soon and I'm trying to work on that.
- But I really like you.
- I like you too, honey...
...but it's not gonna happen.
Why? Why not?
For one thing, I already took his horse.
- Nine thousand nine hundred.
- Interestingly, at $10,000...
...we're required to notify
the IRS of the transaction.
Oh, really?
I want it in something safe.
Something old economy,
maybe treasuries.
Don't you knock?
Listen, Jan, can we
shut this off a minute?
- I got something I gotta ask you.
- Sure.
It's a little awkward.
It's about Ralph.
- That scumbag?
- Yeah, well...
...I'm trying to find out
about his sex life.
And...
...who would know better?
He would. Ask him.
I can't.
I can only ask you.
I mean, is he weird about sex?
- Why are you interested in this?
- I got my reasons. Managerial.
You know, like the Army's got policies
about this shit on account of combat.
I have to tell you, Tony, I'm finding
this entire conversation insulting.
- Here we go.
- You're asking me to betray confidences.
I mean, no matter what either
one of us think of the guy...
Three thousand dollars.
- How'd you come up with that figure?
- It's a number I thought you'd say yes to.
You thought right.
So, what have you heard?
You pay me $3000,
I'll answer your questions.
He bottoms from the top.
I don't know what that means.
It means he has to control things,
but he pretends he doesn't.
Like, he'd make me fuck him
with a strap-on and call him my bitch.
- Shit like that.
- What about plain fucking?
I'm telling you,
he can't get hard that way.
And if he could, I don't think
that he'd want to.
Couldn't believe it when you called.
I was so happy.
I'm feeling pretty happy myself.
Why the big change of heart?
Well, I was never hesitating
because of you.
I just had to get my head
into a place...
...where I felt that I could
really commit, you know.
To lavish all the care on you
that you should have.
I don't see why I have to do
anything I don't want to.
Now, this is Green Grove.
Here the senior citizen is king and queen.
I know, but they told Charles
that this was just a warning.
These people don't fool around.
- You're afraid of them.
- Of course he is. And so am I.
This is a stupid thing
for your son to get hurt over.
I didn't live for 84 years to have
to be nice to somebody I don't like.
Haven't I earned that right?
Ma, I'm gonna have to say this. If you
can't get into the spirit of this thing...
...then we're gonna have to let
you live in a different home.
The Salvation Army has one in Irvington
that's supposed to be perfectly fine.
Coffee, Ton?
Got any decaf?
Decaf?
- No, forget it. Regular's fine.
- Well, I can make decaf.
Yeah, that'd be great. Thanks.
Is something wrong, Tony?
No. Why?
You out in the backyard
the last couple of days?
Me? It's freezing out there.
You sure?
- The pool guy come around?
- Why would he?
Check up on stuff? Something?
All right, I'm going upstairs.
It'll only take a minute.
You sure, Tony, there's not something
you wanna talk about?
No.
Like what?