I, eric, um...
And now...
It's...
Monty python's flying circus.
Michael norman randall
You have been found guilty
Of the murder
of arthur reginald webster
Charles patrick trumpington
Marcel agnes bernstein,
lewis anona rudd
John malcolm kerr
Nigel sinclair robinson,
norman arthur potter
Felicity jayne stone
Jean-paul reynard,
rachel shirley donaldson
Stephen jay greenblatt
Karl-heinz muller
Belinda anne ventham
Juan-carlos fernandez
Thor olaf stensgaard
Lord kimberley of pretoria
Lady kimberley of pretoria
The right honourable
nigel warmsley kimberley
Robert henry noonan
and felix james bennett
On or about the morning
of the 19th of december, 1972.
Have you anything to say
before I pass sentence?
Yes, sir. I'm very sorry.
"very sorry"?!
Yes, sir. it was a very,
very bad thing to have done
And I'm really very ashamed
of myself.
I can only say
it won't happen again.
To have murdered so many people
in such a short space of time
Is really awful
And I really am very,
very, very sorry that I did it
And also that I've
taken up so much
Of the court's
valuable time
Listening to the sordid details
Of these senseless
killings of mine.
I'd particularly like to say
A very personal and sincere
sorry to you, m'lord
For my appalling behavior
throughout this trial.
I'd also like to say
sorry, too, for the police
For putting them
to so much trouble--
For the literally hours of
work they've had to put in
Collecting evidence
And identifying corpses
and so forth.
You know, I think sometimes
we ought to realize
The difficult
and often dangerous work
Involved in tracking down
violent criminals like myself
And I'd just like them to know
That their fine work is at least
appreciated by me.
Oh, no, no.
We were only
doing our job.
No, no, really.
That's very good
of you to say that
But I know what
you've been through.
Oh, no, no.
we've had worse.
It was plain sailing,
apart from the arrest.
I know and
I'm grateful.
I'd like to apologize, too,
to the prosecuting counsel
For dragging him in here
morning after morning
In such lovely weather.
Well, I would have had
to come in anyway.
Ah, good. but what
a presentation of a case.
Oh. thank you.
Oh, no. it's a privilege
to watch you in action.
I never had a chance.
Oh, yes, you did.
Oh, not after that
summing up. great.
Oh. thank you.
And now I must come
to the jury.
What can I say?
I've dragged you in here
day after day
Keeping you away
from your homes
Your jobs,
your loved ones
Just to hear
the private details
Of my petty atrocities.
No, no.
It was very
interesting.
But you could have had
a much nicer case.
Oh, no, no, no.
murder's much more fun.
Yes. and so many of them.
Excellent.
We've had a terrific time.
I'm sorry. I'm very moved.
So, m'lord it only remains
For you to pass the most savage
sentence on me
That the law can provide.
Well, uh, not necessarily.
Uh, no, m'lord. the full penalty
of the law is hardly sufficient.
I insist I must be made
an example of.
Well, yes and no.
I mean, society at large...
Oh, no, m'lord!
Not with mass murder.
Oh, but in this case,
don't you think...?
Yes, yes.
Oh, come on, m'lord!
You've got to give me life.
No!
no. no.
Well, ten years at least.
come on.
Ten years?
Shame, shame.
Well, five then.
be fair.
No, no,
no, no.
I'm giving you three months.
Oh, my god, that's
so embarrassing.
I won't hear of it.
Give me six. please.
Well... all right.
Six months.
Thank you, m'lord.
But suspended.
Oh!
Three cheers
for the defendant!
Hip-hip...
Hooray!
For he's
a jolly good felon
a jolly good felon...
Which nobody can deny...
It's no good, spider.
You can't escape
that easily.
We're coming in
after you.
This way, davis.
Hmm. we'd best separate.
I'm going down there.
You check the
right ventricle.
Any sign of him, davis?
Why, no. nothing here.
All right.
We'll check the spleen.
Wait!
Oh, my god! he's down
the back of us!
Quick! we've got
to catch him
Before he
reaches the neck.
Oh, no.
too late, davis!
He's got out!
Oh! he's eating!
Run for it!
Ah!
Oh, my god!
We're here
in the stomach!
Oh...
This little-known
icelandic saga
Written by an unknown hand
in the late 13th century
Has remained undiscovered
until today.
Now it comes to your screens
for the first time
Fresh from the leaves
of iceland's history.
The terrible njorl's saga...
It's not that terrible.
No, I meant
terribly violent.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Erik njorl, son of frothgar
Leaves his home to seek
hangar the elder
At the house
of thorvald nlodvisson
The son of gudleif
Half-brother of thorgier,
the priest of ljosa water
Who took to wife thurunn,
the mother of thorkel braggart
The slayer of gudmund
the powerful
Who knew howal, son of geernon,
son of erik from vadalesc
Son arval gristlebeard,
son of harken
Who killed bjortguaard
in sochnadale in norway
Over gudreed, daughter
of thorkel long
The son of kettle-trout
The half-son
of harviyoun half-troll
Father of ingbare the brave
Who wed isenbert
of gottenberg
The daughter of hangbard
the fierce...
We apologize for an error
in the saga.
Evidently thorgier,
the priest of ljosa water
Who took to wife thurunn,
the mother of thorkel braggart
The slayer
of gudmund the powerful
Who knew howal, son of geernon,
son of erik from vadalesc...
Well, I'm afraid we're having
a little trouble
Getting this very exciting
icelandic saga started.
If any of you at home
have any ideas
About how to get this
exciting saga started again
Here's the address to write to:
Help the exciting
icelandic saga
18-b macnorten buildings, oban.
Hello, um, well
I was the third voice
you heard just now.
Uh, I'm sorry
about that terrible mess.
It wasn't all that terrible.
No, no, I meant terrible
in the sense of unfortunate.
Oh.
Anyway, um, our plea
For assistance has been answered
By the north malden
icelandic saga society
Who've given us some very useful
information about the saga
And so we carry on now
with "njorl's saga"
With our thanks going once again
To the north malden
icelandic saga society.
Erik njorl, son of frothgar
Rode off
into the desolate plain.
Day and night he rode
Looking neither
to right nor left
Stopping neither
for food nor rest.
12 days and nights he rode,
through rain and storm
Through wind and snow
Beyond the enchanted waterfall
Through the elfin glades
Until he reached his goal.
He had found
the rich and pleasant land
Beyond the mountains...
The land where golden streams
Sang their way
through fresh, green meadows
Where there were
halls and palaces
An excellent swimming pool
And one of the most attractive
Bonus incentive schemes
For industrial development
in the city.
Only 15 miles from excellent
Thames-side docking facilities
And within easy reach
of the proposed m25.
Here it was that eric njorl,
son of frothgar
Met the mayor
Mr. arthur huddinut,
a local solicitor.
Welcome to north malden.
Yes, everyone is welcome
to north malden
But none more so than the
businessmen and investors
Who shape our society
of the future.
Here at north malden...
And we apologize to viewers
of njorl's saga
Who may be confused
By so many references
to north malden.
And after a frank exchange
of views, we have agreed
To carry on showing
this version supplied to us
By the north malden
icelandic saga society
On the undertaking
that future scenes
Will adhere more closely
To the spirit
of 12th century iceland.
With moist eyes,
eric leaves this happy land
To return to the harsh
uneconomic realities
Of life in the land
of ljosa waters.
On his way,
eric rested a while
In the land of bjornsstrand--
the land of dark forces
Where gildor was king.
These were the dukes
of the land of bjornsstrand.
Proud warriors
who bore on their chests
The letters
of their dread name.
Uh, hello?
Is that the north malden
icelandic society?
Yes, that's right.
It's about this saga.
Oh, yes, the
icelandic saga.
Yes.
good, isn't it?
Well, uh,
well, I don't know
but, I mean, you promised us
that you would stick
to the spirit
of the original text.
Yes, that's right.
Well, I mean, a lot of these
things that are happening--
I mean, well, they just
don't quite ring true.
Well, it's a new
interpretation, really.
Well, we didn't want
a new int...
I mean, we wanted
the proper thing.
I mean, just look
what's happening now.
Banners were a
very important part
of icelandic
lore, mr. mills.
Well, then, I mean,
no, no, I'm sorry.
I just can't accept that.
it's gone too far.
I'm very sorry, but we'll have
to terminate the agreement.
Oh!
Well, you're just trying
to cash in
on the bbc's
exciting icelandic saga.
That's business,
mr. mills.
Well, that's as may be
but it's not the way
the bbc works.
Well, I'm very sorry
you feel that way
but, uh, you know,
if you ever want
to come to malden...
8:00 is a peak viewing hour
So naturally, we tend to stick
to our comedy output.
Unless, of course,
there's sport
Because, of course,
we know this is popular
And popularity
is what television is about.
Quite frankly,
I'm sick and tired
Of people accusing us
of being ratings conscious.
"ratings conscious"?
Transmitting bland garbage,
m'lord.
Mmm. thank you.
Now I'm really cheesed off!
I mean, it's not
your highbrow, bleeding plays
That pull in the viewers,
you know.
Thank you.
I mean, joe public
Doesn't want to sit down
and watch three hours
Of documentaries every evening.
Thank you.
he wants to sit down
And he wants to be entertained!
He doesn't want a load of...
No, really!
I'm absolutely fed up with it!
I really am!
case dismissed.
"case dismissed," m'lord?
All right-- five years.
Thank you, m'lord.
Call the next
case, please.
Call erik njorl
Son of frothgar,
brother of hangnor...
Call erik njorl
Son of frothgar,
brother of hangnor...
Call erik njorl
Son of frothgar,
brother of hangnor...
...the slayer of
gudmund's son...
You are erik njorl,
son of frothgar...
Get on with it.
Would you raise
your right hand?
He obviously can't
raise his right hand
You silly usher person.
Can you raise your right leg,
mr. njorl?
Can you raise any part
of your body, mr. njorl?
I see. well,
we'll skip that.
Well, just
take the book
In your right
hand, mr. njorl
Without raising any
part of your body.
Oh.
What is it now
You persistently silly usher?
He can't hold the bible, m'lord.
Oh, screw the bible!
Let's get on
with this bleeding trial!
I've got a gay lib meeting
at 6:00.
Superintendent lufthansa,
will you please read the charge?
Is a charge strictly necessary,
m'lord?
The press is here.
Oh! oh, sorry.
Um...
Right! here we go.
You are hereby charged:
One, that you did,
on or about 1126
Conspire to publicize a
london borough
In the course
of a bbc saga;
Two, that you were
Willfully and persistently
a foreigner;
Three, that you conspired
to do things
Not normally
considered illegal;
Four, that you were
caught in possession
Of an offensive weapon
Viz, the big, brown table
down at the police station.
The big, brown table
down at the police station?
It's the best we
could find, m'lord.
And five: all
together now!
Assaulting a police officer!
Thank you!
Call police constable pan-am.
Into the
witness box
Constable!
There'll be plenty of
time for that later on.
Now...
You are police
constable pan-am?
No! I deny that
to the last breath in my body!
Oh! sorry. yes.
Police constable, do you recognize
the defendant?
No! never seen him
before in my life!
Oh! yes! yes!
He's the one!
He done it!
I'd recognize
him anywhere.
Sorry, super.
Constable, will you please tell
the court
In your own words
what happened.
Oh, yes!
I was proceeding
in a northerly direction
Up alitalia street...
When I saw the deceased...
Standing at an
upstairs window
Baring her bosom
at the general public.
She then took off her...
Wait a tick!
Wrong story.
Oh, yes!
There were three nuns
in a railway compartment
And the ticket in...
No? anyway, I clearly
saw the deceased...
The defendant!
Defendant! sorry.
Sorry, super.
I clearly saw
the defendant
Doing whatever
he's accused of
Uh, red-handed.
When kicked, uh,
cautioned, he said...
"it's a fair...
cop, I done it all.
Right. no... doubt
about... that."
Then, bound as he
was to the chair
He assaulted myself
And three other
constables
While bouncing
around the cell.
The end.
Thank you,
thank you.
And for my next
piece of evidence...
I-i think you'd better
leave it there, constable.
Excellent evidence,
constable.
Thank you
very much.
Now, mr. njorl, will you
tell the court, please
Where were you on
the night of 1126?
Move any part of your body
If you were north of a line
from the humber to the mersey.
Is he in there,
do you think?
Hello, hello, defendant?
Are you there?
Coo-ee!
Defendant?
I think we better go
and have a look, maurice.
Don't call me maurice
in court!
Are you in there?
Mr. njorl?
This way, davis.
He's not getting away
this time.
We'll go down there and
through the left lung.
It was around
the left lung that...
Once again,
I've proved too clever for...
And now,
the stock market report
By exchange telegraph.
Trading was crisp
at the start of the day
With some brisk business
on the floor.
Rubber hardened,
and string remained confident.
Little bits of tin consolidated
Although biscuits sank
after an early gain
And stools remained anonymous.
Armpits rallied well
after a poor start.
Nipples rose dramatically
during the morning
But had declined
by mid-afternoon
While teeth clenched,
and buttocks remained firm.
Small, dark, furry things
increased severely on the floor
Whilst rude jellies
wobbled up and down
And bounced
against rising thighs
Which had spread to all parts
of the country by mid-afternoon.
After lunch,
naughty things dipped sharply
Forcing giblets upwards
with the nicky nacky noo.
Ting tang tong rankled dithely,
little tipples pooped
And poppy things went pong!
Gibble gabble gobble
Went the rickety rackety roo,
as the...
Eh, that'll teach you
to be normal.
Hmm?
Hmm.
Hello, mrs. premise.
Hello, mrs. conclusion.
Busy day?
Busy? I just spent
four hours
Burying the cat.
Four hours to
bury a cat?
Yes. he wouldn't
keep still.
Wriggling about,
howling its head off.
Oh, it wasn't
dead then?
Well, no, no.
But it's not at all
a well cat.
So as we were going away
for a fortnight's holiday
I thought I better bury it
just to be on the safe side.
Quite right.
You don't want to come back
from sorrento to a dead cat.
It would be so anticlimactic.
Yes, kill it now.
That's what I say.
Yes.
We're going to have
To have our budgie put down.
Really? is he very old?
No. we just don't like it.
We're going
to take it
To the vet tomorrow.
Tell me, how do they
put budgies down then?
Well, it's funny
you should ask that
But I've just been
reading a great big book
About how to put
your budgie down
And apparently, you can either
hit them with a book
Or you can shoot
them just there
Just above the beak.
Just there?
yes.
Well, well, well.
Of course, mrs. essence
flushed hers
Down the loo.
Oh, no, you
shouldn't do that.
No, that's dangerous.
Yes, they breed
in the sewers
And eventually you get
evil-smelling flocks
Of huge,
soiled budgies
Flying out of
people's lavatories
Infringing their
personal freedom.
Good morning,
mrs. cut-out.
Morning, mrs. cut-out.
It's a funny thing,
freedom.
I mean
How can any of us
be really free
When we still have
personal possessions?
You can't. you can't.
I mean, how can I go off
and join frelimo
When I've got nine
more installments
To pay on the fridge?
No, you can't. you can't.
Well, this, of course,
is the whole crux
Of jean-paul sartre's
roads to freedom.
No, it bloody isn't.
The nub of that is
his characters stand
For all of us in their desire
to avoid action.
Mind you, the man
at the off-license
Says it's an
everyday story
Of french
country folk.
What do they know?
nothing.
60 new pence
for a bottle of maltese claret.
I personally think that--
oh, beg your pardon--
I personally think that
jean-paul's masterwork
Is an allegory of man's
search for commitment.
No, it isn't.
yes, it is.
'tisn't!
'tis!
No, it isn't!
All right. we can
soon settle this.
We'll ask him.
Do you know him?
yes.
We met on holiday
last year.
In ibiza?
Yes. he was staying
there with his wife
And mr. and mrs. genet.
Oh, I did get on well
with madam s.
We were like that.
What was jean-paul like?
Well, you know,
a bit moody.
Yes.
yes.
He didn't join
in the fun much.
Just sat there
thinking.
Still, mr. rotter
caught him a few times
With a whoopee cushion.
Le captitalisme
et la bourgeoisie
Ils sont la meme chose...
Oh, we did laugh.
Oh, dear.
Well, we'll give
him a tinkle then.
Yes, all right.
She said they were
in the book.
Where's the paris
telephone directory?
It's on the dryer.
No, no.
that's budapest.
Oh, here we are.
Sartre, sartre...
It's 621036.
Oh, thank you, mrs. farley.
Hello? paris 621036, please.
And make it snappy, buster.
Bthe girl from ipanema
goes walking
Tall and young and tan...
Hello. hello, mrs. sartre.
It's beulagh premise here.
Oh, pardon.
C'est beulagh premise ici.
Oui, oui, dans ibiza.
Oui. we met...
Nous nous recontrons
au hotel miramar.
Oui, a la barbeque,
c'est vrai.
Est-ce que jean
est chez vouz?
Oh, merde.
When will he be free?
Oh, pardon.
Quand sera t'il libre?
She says he's spent
the last 60 years
Trying to work
that one out.
Oh, trez amusant,
madame s.
Oui, absolument.
A bientot.
Well, he's out distributing
pamphlets to the masses
But he'll be in
at 6:00.
Oh, well, I'll
ring b.e.a. then.
Oh, look! paris!
That's not paris.
Jean-paul wouldn't
Live here.
It's a right
old dump.
But this is
where they were wrong.
For this was no old dump,
but a town with a future
An urban eldorado where the
businessman of today can enjoy
The facilities of tomorrow
in the comfort of yesterday.
Provided by a go-getting,
go-ahead council
Who know just how loud
money can talk.
Interest rates...
Well, it's none
of my business
But we had
the same trouble
With one
of our icelandic sagas.
These people are terribly keen
But they do rather
tend to take over.
I think I'd stick to caribbean
islands if I were you.
Fine.
And now, back to the saga.
Here-- this is
not paris.
This is iceland.
Oh... well.
Paris must be
over there then.
Oh.
The girl from ipanema
goes walking...
Ooh, here we are.
Number 25.
Oh, yes.
flat one
Yves montand, flat three,
jacques cousteau
Flat four, jean genet
and friend...
Ooh, yes.
Flat five,
maurice laroux.
Who's he?
Never heard of him.
Flat six, marcel marceau
Walking against the wind,
limited.
Flat seven, indira gandhi.
She gets about
a bit, doesn't she?
Yes.
yes.
Flat eight, jean-paul
and betty-muriel sartre.
Oui?
C'est nous,
betty-muriel.
Excusez que nous
sommes en retard.
Entrez.
Oui, merci.
...mais je suis forte...
Oh, rubbish.
Bonjour.
Parlez vouz anglais?
Oh, yes. good day.
Hello, love.
How are you?
This is mrs. conclusion
from number 46.
Oh, nice to
meet you, dear.
Hello.
How's the old
man been?
Oh, don't ask.
He's in one
of his bleeding moods.
The bourgeoisie this,
it's the bourgeoisie that.
He's like a little child
sometimes.
I was only telling the raniers
the other day--
Of course,
he's always rude to them
Only classy friends we got--
I was saying,
"solidarity with the masses"
I said, "pie in the sky."
Ooh, you're not a marxist,
are you, mrs. conclusion?
No, I'm a revisionist.
Oh, good.
I mean, look at this place!
I'm at my wits' end--
Revolutionary leaflets
everywhere.
One of these days,
I'll revolutionary leaflets him.
If it wasn't for the goat
You couldn't get in here
for propaganda.
Well, very well.
Can we, uh, pop in
And have a word
with him?
Yes, come along.
Thank you.
But be careful.
he's had a few.
Oh.
Mind you, he's good as
gold in the morning--
I've got to
hand it to him--
But come lunchtime, it's
a bottle of vin ordinaire.
Six glasses and he's
ready to agitate.
Uh, coo-ee!
Jean-paul?
Ah, it's only us.
Oh, pardon,
c'est meme nous.
Oui.
Jean-paul, your famous
trilogy, rues a liberte
Is it an allegory of man's
search for commitment?
Oui.
Told you so.
Oh, coitus.
Today, we look
at a vanishing race
A problem people
who are fast disappearing
Off the face of the earth...
A race who one might say
are losing a winning battle.
They live
in a sunshine paradise
A caribbean dream
where only reality is missing...
For this is whicker island...
An island inhabited entirely
by ex-international interviewers
In pursuit
of the impossible dream.
The whole problem
of whicker island
Is here in a nutshell.
There are
just too many whickers.
The light-weight suits...
The old school ties...
The practiced voice
of the seasoned campaigner...
Cannot hide
the basic tragedy here.
There just aren't
enough rich people left
To interview.
You can't teach
an old dog new tricks
And so you find them...
Sitting beside
elegant swimming pools...
Sipping martinis...
And waiting
for the inevitable interview.
I talked to the island's
only white man, father pierre.
Father pierre, why
did you stay on
In this colonial
campari-land
Where the clink
of glasses mingles
With the murmur of
a million mosquitoes
Where waterfalls of whisky
wash away the worries
Of a world-weary whicker
Where gin and tonics jingle
in a gyroscopic jubilee
Of something
beginning with "j"?
Father pierre, why
did you stay on here?
Well...
Mainly for the interviews.
Well, there you have it.
A crumbling...
Empire in the sun-drenched...
Caribbean, where the cliches
sparkle on the waters...
Like the music of repeat fees...
And so...
From whicker island...
It's...
Fare...
Well, and...
Bon...
Voy...
Age.