Come out!
You can’t run anymore!
We’ll shoot!
Give up already, Abdul Hakim!
So ya wanna fight, huh?
You’re such a…
STRAY DOG STRUT
Amigo!
How’re all you 300,000 bounty hunters
in the solar system doing?
It’s time for BIG SHOT, the show that
brings you information about fugitives!
Well, well, first up for today,
is this guy: Abdul Hakim.
He’s known as a serial pet thief.
This time, he snagged
a test animal…
…from a research facility,
and is on the loose.
The good news is that he’s
worth a whopping 8 million!
The conditions are as always.
Bring him in alive to
collect your reward.
If you kill him,
kiss your reward good-bye.
He’s the biggest we’ve had in a while.
Do your best to get this guy
How’s it look?
It’s done for.
Man, why does everything?
Hey.
Doctor? You got information?
About Abdul Hakim.
—I’ll take it!
—I’ll give a discount. 300.
I got his post-plastic surgery picture.
Too much. 20 down.
All right, 280.
On one condition.
What’s that?
Sock him one.
He trampled over me.
If you want, punch him a dozen times.
I’ve got the goods.
This one should be something big…
Yeah, see you in six hours.
He had a very conspicuous suitcase.
That info’s included
in the deal, right?
Oh, all right.
It was something that could
carry a small woman inside.
Treasure?
Can’t really say,
The way he handled it
sure didn’t seem that way,
Ni-lai-la!
If you feel lethargic,
have some ginseng hei-sui.
You’ll last a week with it!
If you’re tired,
have sugarcane hei-sui.
You ate too much?
Then have pineapple hei-sui.
Gimme some lao-chu.
Thank you.
Here you go.
Sorry. My apologies, bro.
Hey, I said I’m sorry!
What, can’t say anything?
Wh— What? Ya pickin’ a fight?
My treat.
Drink.
And now, the loot.
Even if I overhaul this whole craft,
I’ll have some change!
Guess I’ll go eat Peking Duck with it.
As they say, “Don’t count
chickens before they hatch.”
I got this one nailed shut!
Well, give it what you got.
So all three went down?
Seems that way.
And Hakim is around here?
Dammit, he doesn’t even know how
much that thing is REALLY worth.
A pet shop?
A shady one at that.
Hey, bro, you can buy
anything here on Mars.
From guns to human lives.
If ya wanna know,
show me what ya got.
The chain on this one is long.
Must be the “Way of the Dragon” model.
Oh, you can tell?
That’s a rare one from the ’30s!
It sure is an antique.
Try the store called Animal
Treasure off of Caiphon Road.
I’m sure you’ll find something there.
Okay, I’ll look… but I’ll decide if I
want to buy it from you after I see it.
Oh, all right.
Run out of funds changing your
face around too much, Hakim?
W-Wait a sec…
Hey, don’t move.
You sure are restless, changing
your face around this much.
What the?
Hold it. I don’t want any
of this business here.
All of my babies are very sensitive!
You open it.
Why do I?!
There seems to be some
sort of misunderstanding…
Hurry it up!
Oh, fine.
A dog?
A Welsh Corgi.
It’s cute, but it’s everywhere.
Not a particularly rare species.
And how much is it worth?
With the suitcase, about this much.
200K?
No, no, 200, 200!
No way!
You don’t like it, you take care
of it yourself. Like eating it.
It is a puppy…
Sorry to bother you. Please continue.
I guess the Peking Duck
has been overcooked.
At least give me 300…
No can do.
280?
A no is a no.
250!
ZERO. I’ll take it back.
This again?
What is it this time?
Someone! Catch my babies! Hurry!
—There it is!
—All right!
Hakim?!
God dammit, what’s going on?!
—Gangway!
—What the hell?
WAIT, dammit!
Hey, what the hell do you want?!
Bounty hunter?
Animal rights syndicate?
Your story brings a tear to my eye.
Risking your life on a dog
that’s only worth 200 woolongs.
What?
What I want are the 8 million woolongs
hanging from your neck.
Not bad.
What?!
Dammit!
Shuddup!
I’m in a rotten mood right now!
There, there.
Here, lemme put on a collar.
A dog instead of a duck, huh?
Forget about that!
You know anything about it?
Yeah. This is a Welsh Corgi.
A total mongrel.
Totally?
Totally. Completely worthless.
Shit, this gives me a headache.
And all this is
because of this mongrel…
The dog is worthless,
but the owner is worth something.
Well, at least you should get
to know this critter well.
Man, I hate kids and critters!
They’re nothing but trouble!
I got something!
All right!
It’s big!
Here it comes!
Pull on the line!
What time is it now?
I-I-It’s 4 o’clock now.
Two hours…
Who was that with Hakim? His ally?
Seems that way.
We got no clues?
We have to do something.
If that falls into police hands,
we’re in deep shit.
Seems that way.
All our work will be worthless if our
experiments get revealed to the public.
Seems that way.
How much does he think we
put into that “data dog”?
Why don’t YOU do this?
Didn’t your grandma teach you
to finish what you start?
She was dead before I was born.
Sorry to hear that.
Anyway, we have the joker in our hand.
Just do what we planned.
Give me code name “snoop.”
Yeah. It’s me.
I had some trouble.
No big deal…
Hey, wait, Michael!
I want to postpone the meeting a bit.
As I said, it wasn’t that big a deal…
Impossible? Why? Hey, wait!
And this is our plan?
Hey, you!
You have something you
want to know, right?
Wait!
My little Peeko can
answer your questions!
You have something you
want to know, right?
See, little Peeko is telling me…
…that you’re looking
for someone or something.
Well, where there’s
this dog, there’s Hakim.
Seeing loud and clear.
We’re counting on you, pooch.
We must resort to the dog whistle.
But that’ll cause a big mess.
I don’t care.
We’ll draw attention to ourselves!
We have no choice!
Shall I?
Do it.
I can’t hear anything.
I said before that
humans can’t hear it.
Oh, that’s right.
This is so farfetched…
Will this really attract?
Oh, it’s moving.
Something is now on the move.
Wait! Babies, what’s
wrong with you guys?!
Hey, wait!
It got away, Jet!
Huh? Hakim?
No, the dog!
It’s close, it’s close!
What you are looking for is nearby.
In fact, right in
front of your eyes…
Hey, wait, you need to pay!
I’ll pay when I am rich!
You can’t be serious…
Goddammit, what the hell is going on?!
Happy?
Yes, very.
—Excuse me…
—Outta my way!
You, what are you doing?
Hakim!
Dammit!
It’s just a dog, after all.
Hakim!
Spike, he’s headed for Interstate 6.
Great!
If he thinks he can outrun me,
he’s welcome to try.
Don’t get too hotheaded!
What part of me is hotheaded?!
There he is!
This is payback from earlier!
…the hell are you doin’?!
This guy is mine!
What the?
Now!
Stop that!
Shit!
This is why I hate critters!
Amigo!
How’re all you 300,000 bounty hunters
in the solar system doing?
It’s time for Big Shot, the show that
brings you information about fugitives!
So, you remember Abdul Hakim
who chose a rather…
…flashy way of turning
himself in last week?
Yeah! Of course!
Apparently, he stole what’s
called a “data dog”…
…created in an illegal
experiment of some research firm.
Wow! What’s that?
I’m not sure myself, but apparently,
it’s a very intelligent pooch.
I hear that it’s
priceless among collectors.
That’s a surprise!
I wanna have a dog like that!
But they say it’s still missing.
I wonder where it went?
Really
But now, a commercial!
Can’t be…
Hey there! When you’re done cleaning,
feed the komodo dragons!
I want you to work your ass off!
Yeah…
Hey, hey!
Hey, don’t jump on there!
That’s cold!
That’s why I said we should
throw out mongrels like this one!
But you’re the one
that brought it here!
In any case, we have to do
something about the ticks.
Shit…
I’m gonna salt you
and eat you, dammit!
Well, it’s time for us to go.
See you next time!
Good luck!!
Aishiteta to nageku niwa…
Too much time has passed by…
…amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
…to lament that we were deeply in love.
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo…
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart…
…iyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
…cannot heal all the tears in it.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
The real folk blues.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta…
Sitting in muddy water…
…jinsei mo waruku wa nai…
…isn’t such a bad life…
…ichido kiri de owaru nara…
…if it ends after the first time…
COMING EPISODE
“Nothing is permanent.”
It’s a fact of life.
The bell tolls for the great
ones who will someday fall.
Money makes the world go round…
…but debt piles up
before you know it.
I wandered through
all the reaches of space…
…and there I met a cowboy.
A session to the tune
of an off-key melody:
HONKY TONK WOMEN
Honky Tonk Women.