Confirmed.
To our new relationship,
and our new friendship.
And, to prosperity.
The view from here makes me
sad that I must leave so soon.
It’s an amazing sight.
Next time, we should
have dinner together.
The Cantonese cuisine that
our head chef makes…
…is just about as superb
as this scenery.
That’s a wonderful
invitation, however…
To think that the day that I’d dine
with an executive from the Red Dragon…
Rest assured,
the food will not be poisoned.
I can finally take a breather.
Thank God.
Doing things like this
won’t do you any good!
Times have changed!
The syndicate cannot survive
just by fighting alone!
O-Only if…
…S-Spike returned…
…someone like you would…
BALLAD OF FALLEN ANGELS
I don’t feel up for this.
Wha?
I said, I don’t feel like doing this.
Then there’s no choice.
Wait, Spike.
I can’t burden you.
Don’t say stuff like that.
You know who that is, don’t you?
Superficial stuff, yeah.
Then…
Good money.
Easy to get info on him.
We also have a lead.
What makes you scared?
Spike, you’re deliberately
avoiding the subject.
Are you hiding something from me?
So… what happened
to that arm of yours?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Nothing.
So, you have no intention of telling me?
I could ask you the same.
Why is this door so damn narrow?
Oh? Am I interrupting something?
None of your business.
We’re supposed to be comrades!
That’s awfully cold of you!
What do you mean, comrades?
Troublemakers should keep
themselves outta this.
Well, I don’t care.
So, who is this? What’s he up to?
Don’t look without asking us.
What do you mean?
He’s just there on the screen!
Spike!
Hey, wait, Spike!
I’m taking off.
Spike!
Shit, I won’t be responsible for you!
Roger that.
Dammit! He’s such a…
Mao Yenrai.
A bounty of 28 million
for the alleged murder…
…of an executive from
an opposing syndicate.
Amazing! And you guys are after him?
What, did you have a fight?
Shut up. You’re being obnoxious.
—You’re such a kid.
—I said, you’re being obnoxious!
He can do whatever the hell he pleases.
Oh, God…
He’s throwing such a huge fit.
You there, Jet?
I got something big for ya!
Something big?
Excuse me, madam,
but I need to see your ticket.
Oh, I don’t have anything like that.
Well, then, I am afraid that
you cannot enter the hall…
But, they told me I didn’t need one.
You know. The guy in the box seat…
Him.
Mao Yenr…
Can you park my vehicle for me?
If it’s not one, it’s the other…
Why do they all do
everything as they please?!
There’s a protective
encryption on this thing.
You worried?
Just watch.
These are decrypted like this…
See? And then, I input “Mao Yenrai”…
The bounty part sure
seems to be true, but…
Is this Sir Mao’s seat?
I looked all over for it.
Actually, I…
We were waiting for you.
U-Um…
They are performing,
so please stay quiet.
Hold it right there!
I’m not letting you get away!
Whatcha doin’?!
Give it back!
Shit. Give it back, you dumbass!
Really, kids these days!
I’ll hand you over to the cops!
Y-You!
Yo.
Hey, isn’t it bad for you to
drink it in one shot, Annie?
You coming back to life
is worse on me than this glass.
What terrible treatment!
The words of the dead are meaningless.
But I’m alive.
No, you died three years ago!
That’s how things work here.
I know.
The fact that you came here… means you
have something you want to know, right?
If it’s not much, I can be of help.
Anastasia…
Stop it! There are only two people
that can call me by that name…
So, what do you want to know?
Mao Yenrai.
What happened to him?
Mao-taijin?
There’s a reason for this…
No need to talk, Miss Valentine.
We have done a background
check already.
Rest assured, it will be
held in a safe location.
Please, to your seat.
You’re trembling…
Who… are you?
Vicious.
You know…
I won’t say anything bad to ya.
Don’t get yourself involved
with Vicious anymore.
But I know saying that is useless.
Sorry.
You’ve never listened
to what others say.
On top of it,
you’re a stubborn showoff!
It can’t hurt you to listen to
your elders once in a while…
About Mao…
He had a lot of people looking
for you after you were gone.
He said that you still
had to be alive…
You’re finally back, but Mao is…
Stop it already.
This is for Mao!
I’ll take that one for Mao.
What are you up to now…
to need something like that?
Where’s the broad?
She lost sanity looking at
the bounty figure and took off.
Right now she’s probably
somewhere, screwing up.
I see.
I’ll tell you something.
You won’t get the bounty for Mao.
He’s already dead.
He was killed.
Internal discord.
Do you understand?
This is a trap! I’m sure of it!
Yeah. I know all that.
You know?!
Then what, you’re Mao’s?
I owe him one from before…
I’ll tell you something, Spike.
This arm. It’s the price I paid
for being over-spirited…
…and running ahead of the game.
You understand?
I don’t wanna go, either.
Then…
Let’s just say,
duties of the life I live.
Tee hee. I’ve been caught.
You…
Come to the place we specify,
Otherwise, my life is over.
So they say,
Lesse… the time to meet is…
It’s because you did as you please.
You’re being cold.
We’re comrades, remember?
You reap what you sow.
Take care of it all yourself.
Hey, wait!
Where is it?
You’re really gonna come?
Don’t worry.
I’m not going there to save you.
Spike!
Angels that are forced from
heaven have to become demons.
Isn’t that right, Spike?
I’m only watching a dream
that I never awakened from.
I’ll wake you up right now.
Don’t be so anxious, Vicious.
It’s our first meeting
in a while, right?
A plea for your life?
Hardly.
Something like that doesn’t
work on you, remember?
After all, you even kill
those who’ve saved your life.
He was a beast who lost his fangs.
That’s why he’s dead.
The same goes for you.
Now, we want you to drop your gun.
What’s wrong? If you don’t hurry…
Are ya tryin’ to kill me?
Oh man, what the hell’ve I done…
Yeah?
Thank God! Jet? Spike is…
Not my problem!
God dammit!
Spike.
Do you know what your face
looks like right now?
What?
The same blood runs in you and me.
The blood of a beast who wanders,
desiring the blood of others.
I’ve bled all of that blood away.
Then why are you still alive?!
Just like that…
…sing for me.
Oh, you’re finally up.
You’ve slept too much.
It’s been three days.
What? I was worried about you.
You have to be thankful to me!
Tone-deaf.
Oh, well…
Aishiteta to nageku niwa…
Too much time has passed by…
…amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
…to lament that we were deeply in love.
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo…
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart…
…iyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
…cannot heal all the tears in it.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
The real folk blues.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta…
Sitting in muddy water…
…jinsei mo waruku wa nai…
…isn’t such a bad life…
…ichido kiri de owaru nara…
…if it ends after the first time…
COMING EPISODE
But you know what? What a tough
world we live in nowadays…
What are you talking about?
This guy, that guy… They’re all trying
to put a lid on something that stinks.
Yeah.
Can we let things go on like that?
I’m asking you,
what are you talking about?
World affairs, man! World affairs!
With all these lids about,
the world’ll be buried in lids!
I don’t really get it…
With stuff like that,
you can’t see the truth!
Truth, huh?
So lids like that…
I’ll crush them all away!
Next Episode: “Sympathy for the Devil”.
SYMPATHY FOR THE DEVIL
That sounds… smelly.