(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
Hey! (GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
No word then, Master Bruce?
None. And I've scoured the entire city.
No one has seen either Robin
or Dick Grayson for two days.
I really should remain
upstairs then, sir.
Lest he call.
Oh, by the way, this came for you
an hour ago by messenger.
No. It can't be.
MAN: So.
They know your identity, detective.
Who are you? How did you get in here?
You must forgive Ubu, detective.
He is well-trained.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am he who is called Ra's al Ghul.
The Demon's Head.
I thought you were only a legend.
I am quite real.
And as I am sure you realize by now,
my reputation for resourcefulness
is well-deserved.
As you can see,
we have a common problem.
Your ward was abducted
on the same night as my daughter.
You do remember my daughter?
- You're Talia's father?
- Yes.
But surely you would not expect her
to mention me by name. (COUGHS)
Keep your distance! I am merely old.
Older, perhaps, than you can imagine.
But not so old that I cannot
assist you in your search.
I get the message. Okay, then.
For openers, look at the blade.
It's used by a cult of mercenaries
based in Calcutta.
Even the rope appears to be made
of a hemp indigenous to that area.
Well done, detective.
You are worthy of your reputation.
To India, then.
Come, I have an aircraft waiting.
(GRUNTS)
UBU: Infidel!
RA'S: Forgive my servant.
He feels that no one should precede me.
Call it overzealousness.
I think I'll call it strike one.
BATMAN: You still have me at a loss,
Ra's al Ghul.
Just how did you learn who I am?
I control a vast
global organization, detective.
Obviously, Batman's activities
require certain costly implements.
It was a simple matter for my people
to learn which wealthy Americans
were amassing what Batman might require.
The one who matched my daughter's
description of you was Bruce Wayne.
Next time I'll have to glue my mask on.
(COUGHING)
Do you need help?
I need nothing.
As Napoleon told me,
a strong will can fuel a frail physique.
How can you be certain, detective,
that those we seek are to be found here?
I make it my business to know
things like that. Here.
There's an incense shop.
Infidel!
- (GRUNTS)
- (SHATTERING)
Okay. That's two.
(GRUNTING)
Yes.
(GRUNTS)
No!
Yes. Unless you tell me how to find
the mercenaries who did this.
They have fled with the boy
and the woman. (WHIMPERS)
Where?
To Malaysia. In a pagoda
in the shadow of Mount Merapi.
I know nothing more, I swear it!
Look at it, detective,
one of the last of the rain forests.
The world depends upon its oxygen,
yet the rich see only
profit in its destruction.
You who belong to the overclass
have much to answer for.
Bruce Wayne donates millions of dollars
a year to preserve these forests.
RA'S: Which are being depleted
at the rate of 120,000 acres a day.
Does your money solve this problem? No.
It will take more than wealth,
it will take power.
And, I fear, ruthlessness.
Humankind must be forced to serve
the planet instead of its own appetites.
And you're the one
who'll do the forcing?
I am qualified, yes.
But I may not have sufficient lifetimes
left to me.
Master, ahead. Look!
RA'S: In the shadow of the volcano,
just as the Indian said.
Let us hurry.
The next piece of
our puzzle surely waits within.
(SNARLS)
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(SNORES)
Sweet dreams, tabby.
Congratulations, detective,
on thwarting our tormentors.
Obviously, our quest was meant
to end here.
Maybe, maybe not. Look at this.
A map of the Himalayas.
There's a faint scratch,
almost certainly made by
a fingernail tracing a route.
Indeed. I am familiar with that area,
and the nearest field large enough
to accommodate my aircraft
is 100 miles from our destination.
So I will arrange for a helicopter
when one is needed.
After you.
Hmm.
RA'S: The mountain in question
is directly ahead.
I've radioed for my men.
They await me on the mountaintop.
- While I descend the hard way.
- You must search for clues.
If we perceive any danger,
we can signal you with...
(COUGHS)
Master, we must get you
to one of the pits.
- Pits?
- Ignore him, detective.
We must stay on the hunt
for the sake of the children.
All right. If that's the way
it's to be played.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
- Robin.
- Huh?
- Batman!
- You okay?
Am I glad to see you.
I'll have you free in a minute.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- Been here long?
- A couple days, I think.
I still don't know who grabbed me.
I do.
(CLAPPING)
BATMAN: Ra's al Ghul.
Obviously, your little accident
wasn't fatal.
I imagine you and Ubu left the chopper
when I wasn't looking.
Indeed. At the moment it exploded,
it was proceeding on automatic pilot.
So how long have you known, detective,
that I planned your ward's capture?
Almost from the beginning.
How could you have known
that Robin and your daughter
were abducted on the same night?
Unless I had done the abducting?
Exactly.
And do you think I'd have let you
take me anywhere in your plane
unless I suspected
you meant to lead me somewhere?
For one thing, there were
all those would-be assassins.
They knew where we'd be and when.
Someone had to be tipping them off.
That someone had to be you.
Then there was Ubu.
Always by his master's side,
always very picky about letting you
go ahead of everyone else.
Except in Malaysia, where you knew
there was danger waiting.
I am deeply impressed.
As am I.
Ready to go?
Well, if you say so.
Though it was just starting
to get interesting.
The master gave you
no permission to leave.
I didn't ask for any.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
And that's three.
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
(GROANS)
Wait. I can't let you leave like this.
My father meant you no harm.
- He had a funny way of showing it.
- RA'S: My time is short.
I have no sons.
I need a man to assume my position
when I am gone.
BATMAN: Then it was a test? But why me?
Because you are most worthy.
That is now proven beyond any doubt.
And because my precious daughter
loves you.
Forget it.
Then this means we must be enemies!
You will regret this insult, detective.
You will... (COUGHING)
Father!
(RASPY BREATHING)
- He's dying!
- I've had it with your little games.
No game, I swear it!
(WHEEZING)
Pulse is bad. He can't fake that.
We must take him to the Lazarus Pit.
You want us to put him in that?
You're crazy!
No, listen to me,
I know it is difficult to believe,
but the pit is what keeps him alive.
What has kept him alive for 600 years.
- Batman?
- Please, you must believe me!
BATMAN: We have no choice.
He's stopped breathing.
We've killed him.
No. All is well.
(BUBBLING)
(WHIRRING)
(YELLING)
(EVIL LAUGHTER)
(TALIA GASPS)
Put her down!
I said put her down!
(LAUGHING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)