(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXPLOSION)
You do good work, Mr...
What did you say your name was?
Nitro, Mr. Daggett,
on account of explosives
are my business.
I assume Crocker explained
the terms of your employment, Mr. Nitro?
Sure. There's an old gas line
running under the whole block.
I make it look like
the pipeline ruptured,
so the job can't be traced to you.
It's to be done while I give my speech
to the Gotham Better Business Council.
9:00 exactly.
Trust me, when the hands
on that watch hit nine,
boom.
As expected, the city zoning board
today rejected a request
by the Daggett Development Corporation
to raze a block of landmark brownstones
along Gotham's Park Row.
Thirty years ago,
Park Row was Gotham City's
most glamorous address.
But, in recent years,
the area has suffered a decline.
And today, it is a slum better known
as the infamous "Crime Alley."
But, to its inhabitants,
many of whom
spoke at the zoning board today,
Crime Alley is the only home they have,
and they fear its loss.
Others, like Roland Daggett, director
of the Daggett Development Corporation,
see the situation differently.
It's tragic.
Park Row may be an historical landmark,
but it's also a breeding ground
for crime.
Of course, as much as we disagree
with the zoning board's decision,
our hands are tied.
(GRUNTING)
Roland Daggett
is up to something, Alfred.
That almost goes without saying,
doesn't it, sir?
I don't know what it is yet, but I will.
You don't want to be late
for your 8:00 appointment, sir.
Have I ever been late?
No, sir.
Not once in all these years.
(ENGINE RUMBLING)
Help! Help!
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS)
Help! Somebody help my mommy!
(STAMMERING) Those men in our apartment,
they'll hurt her.
I climbed out the window.
Where?
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Lady, you and your kid
were told to clear out.
(FURNITURE SMASHING)
You didn't listen.
Maybe you'd like to be carried out.
No! Please!
(BATARANG WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTING)
Yah!
Mommy! Mommy!
(GASPS)
Thank you.
What did they mean,
you were warned to clear out?
Couple of days ago, these three show up,
say they're working
for some corporation.
They tell everyone on our block
they got to leave.
But, where are we gonna go?
He's never been late before.
I'd better look for him.
Where you off to, Miss Thompkins?
Just looking for a friend, Maggie.
You be careful.
Maggie, I've lived in Park Row
for 30 years.
It's my home.
I'm not afraid here.
What are you doing here?
This building is condemned.
I saw you on the news.
You work for Daggett.
Oh, my gracious!
(GASPING)
(YELPS)
(ENGINE RUMBLING)
(ENGINE STOPS)
(GASPING)
I'm looking for Dr. Thompkins.
She said
somebody was supposed to meet her.
You?
Where is she?
Leslie went looking for you.
I told her to be careful.
Bad things happen to people
in Crime Alley.
I know.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
CROCKER: Urban redevelopment, lady.
That's what this is all about.
Uh, tell me if the rope's too tight.
All set. We just gotta do
that old hotel down the street.
And then when 9:00 rolls around...
Boom! Instant slum clearance.
Next stop, mini-mall.
You can't destroy that hotel.
This block may be abandoned,
but that building
has people living in it.
CROCKER: Hey, we told them to leave.
They stand in the way of redevelopment,
they get bulldozed.
Nothing personal. Just business.
You're insane.
You won't get away with...
(MUFFLED SPEECH)
(BOMB TICKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Alfred, did Leslie call?
ALFRED: No, sir.
- Is anything wrong?
- We missed each other.
- I'm on my way to her apartment.
- (SIREN WAILING)
Something's come up, Alfred.
I'll be in touch.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
MAN: Now, you're gonna listen to me!
I want justice, Gotham City!
(GUN COCKING)
Who's the hostage?
Some clerk from Daggett Development.
Wrong place at the wrong time
with an eviction notice.
Ten seconds, we make our move.
BATMAN: If you go,
the hostage might be hurt.
- I'll do it.
- You'll do it?
Who do you think you are?
Oh.
You took my job, Gotham City!
You took my home!
Somebody's gotta pay for that!
I pick you.
(WHIMPERING)
BATMAN: Put the gun down!
Who said that?
Batman!
Whoa.
So, you're working for Daggett, too?
(GUNSHOTS)
BATMAN: I won't ask twice.
(BOTH GROANING)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Thanks for the help.
Good thing you showed up.
BATMAN: Leslie?
Poor Doc Thompkins. She's in trouble.
(GASPS)
What trouble?
Uh, nothing.
I didn't see them grab her.
I didn't see nothing.
What do you mean? Who grabbed her?
I don't know! Let go of me! Let go!
Where did you get this blasting cap?
And where's Dr. Thompkins?
(STAMMERING) Two guys, they grabbed her.
She dropped it.
I thought I could sell it.
Get a few bucks.
Where are they?
Corner of Finger and Broom.
That's all I know, honest!
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(BOMB TICKING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
may I introduce our speaker,
a bold force for progress,
a man of vision
with the will to execute his dreams,
Roland Daggett.
(ENGINE HUMMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
- WOMAN: He's hurt!
- He's passed out!
MAN: Help!
WOMAN: Help!
(HORN HONKING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Perfect. Just perfect.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(PASSENGERS SCREAMING)
- Look out!
- Runaway trolley!
MAN: Get out of the way!
The trolley's coming!
PASSENGERS: Don't leave us!
(PASSENGERS CLAMORING)
(THUDDING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(PASSENGERS SCREAMING)
(WHEELS SCRAPING)
(THUDS SOFTLY)
MAN: Oh, my goodness. Thank God.
WOMAN: Thank goodness. I was so afraid.
WOMAN 2: Let us out of here!
I've never been so scared
in all my life.
(THUDDING)
BATMAN: Hello, Crocker.
- Long time no see.
- CROCKER: Batman?
(STAMMERING) What are you doing here?
Meeting a friend.
What are you doing here, Crocker?
CROCKER: No. None of your business.
BATMAN: Somebody is trying
to run the people
in this neighborhood out of their homes.
Your boss, Daggett,
wouldn't know anything about this,
would he?
CROCKER: No. No, of course not.
(NITRO EXCLAIMS)
How about you, Nitro?
(GRUNTS)
You told your parole board
you gave up the arson-for-hire game.
(STAMMERING) I did. I'm clean.
BATMAN: Really?
Then what's this?
You crazy? This stuff is dangerous.
Talk to me, Nitro.
After Daggett lost his appeal
to the zoning board,
Crocker hired you to level
this whole neighborhood, didn't he?
That's it. That's right. You got it.
Don't tell Daggett I talked.
Where's Leslie Thompkins?
The old lady? In there.
Listen, we gotta get out of here.
It's almost 9:00.
(MUFFLED GROANING)
(BOMB TICKING)
- (TICKING STOPS)
- (GASPS)
(CLOCK SHATTERING)
Don't worry about me.
They're blowing up the old SRO Hotel.
You've got to get the people out.
DAGGETT: Gentlemen,
Gotham City is at a crossroads.
As businessmen,
the choice we face is clear.
It's time we decide where we stand.
Are we for progress or against it?
For the future or for the past?
For the weak or for the strong?
(BOMB TICKING)
In short,
we cannot allow
the underclass to hinder us
from building a better tomorrow.
(EXPLOSION)
(INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
Mr. Daggett. Mr. Daggett.
Any comments on this tragedy?
MAN: Does this affect your plans
for redevelopment, Mr. Daggett?
It's a sad fact,
but you have to expect
violence in Crime Alley.
These people don't value
human life like we do.
BATMAN: Nobody values human life
like you do, Daggett.
I diffused the bomb at the hotel.
All your punks managed to destroy
were a few condemned buildings.
Once they confess,
you're finished.
I'm shocked.
Shocked to learn that arson
was the cause of this tragedy.
Thank heaven the criminals responsible
have been caught.
- But, Mr. Daggett, you told us to...
- DAGGETT: Officers,
I believe your duty is clear.
Excuse me.
LESLIE: Let it go.
Daggett won't escape the law forever.
There's nothing you can do now.
And besides,
you have an appointment to keep.
This used to be a beautiful street.
Good people lived here once.
Good people still live in Crime Alley.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)