(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
NARRATOR: Previously on Batman...
That's what ain't good for you.
Having to keep going back
to Daggett for more of that stuff.
You're right, Teddy. I can't.
I'll have to find a way
to get lots of this stuff on my own.
I think our Mr. Hagen
has outlived his usefulness.
I want him dealt with.
- HAGEN: No.
- Sweet dreams, slimeball.
(HAGEN GROANS)
BATMAN: "Bruce Wayne
sought for questioning"
"in attempt on executive's life"?
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
REPORTER 1: Mr. Wayne,
what was it like to be in jail?
REPORTER 2: How do you respond to the
charges that you assaulted Lucius Fox?
- (ALL CLAMORING)
- No comment. My client has no comment.
- Let us through, please.
- REPORTER 3: Mr. Wayne, over here.
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
REPORTER 3: Mr. Wayne, Mr. Wayne,
over here.
REPORTER 4: Over here.
REPORTER 4:
Mr. Wayne, could you talk to us?
Imagine, Lucius Fox thinking
I would harm him.
And he's been with you,
what, ten years now, sir?
Then whoever impersonated you
did an uncanny job.
BRUCE: "Whoever" is right.
Bell said he didn't know.
He had to be lying.
But I know where to get the truth.
HAGEN: Move it, Lupus.
I want all this stuff
out of here by sunrise.
Ah, Matt, come on,
you don't have to do this.
You made a comeback before.
You can do it again.
Comeback?
Comeback? From this?
Face it, Teddy, Matt Hagen is history.
This time, for good.
He's never coming back again.
GERMS: My contact on the force
says Bell hasn't cracked, so far.
Good. Well, I'm afraid we still have
quite a mess to clean up.
Sooner or later, I will take control
of Wayne Enterprises.
Their marketing operation
will instantly give me
a distribution network that would
take me years to build on my own.
Till then, my takeover plan
will have to be revised.
Now that our actor friend,
Hagen, is no longer available to us.
Okay, Mr. Daggett, who do you want
me to take out now?
I want everything wrapped up
by the time I tape that show tonight.
We're going to settle the Fox matter
once and for all.
But, Mr. Daggett, he's in a hospital.
All those sick people...
Okay, Mr. Daggett.
But, Matt,
you thought it was all over
for you once before,
and you were wrong then.
You know, when you had your accident.
Of course I thought it was over.
I figured I was lucky to be alive.
Just like I thought I was when Daggett
came to visit me at his clinic of his,
asking me to be his first test subject.
How could I say no?
He told me his Renuyu formula
could do in minutes
what plastic surgery would take years
to accomplish.
It wasn't so bad,
except for all those jobs
you had to do for him in return.
But, hey, it worked.
I mean, you had your biggest hits
after the accident.
Yeah. Some of the best parts I ever had.
Matt! You're changing.
And you didn't use your hands this time.
You didn't even try.
You did it automatically,
like a reflex or something.
Unbelievable.
You know what this means, don't you?
It doesn't have to be over.
You can go on.
We can go on.
Wow!
You can even form clothes
out of your skin.
But, how?
The formula must've soaked
every cell in my body.
It's... It's some kind of miracle.
- What... What are you doing?
- No.
No. You broke my concentration!
It won't work, don't you see?
It's too hard.
It's like tensing a muscle.
I can't keep it up for long.
My career, my life...
It is gone!
And I can never get it back!
(CRASHING)
I'm not an actor anymore.
I'm not even a man.
(SOBBING)
HAGEN: Pull in here.
TEDDY: The hospital?
Sooner or later, Daggett will
send someone to finish off Fox.
Once I know who it is, I can
take his place.
And if Daggett thinks I'm his henchman,
I can walk right up to him and,
"Bam!"
Goodbye, Mr. Daggett.
(CHUCKLING)
(CRIES OUT)
- (GASPS)
- Hey!
(GASPS)
Let me out of here. Please.
All these viruses and bacteria,
I could be infected.
I know.
Now, the man who impersonated
Bruce Wayne,
I want his name.
I, uh, I don't know who, uh...
Hmm. Crimson fever.
Lousy way to go.
No cure, you know.
The name. Now!
Okay, okay, it was Hagen.
Matt Hagen, the movie actor.
It's the truth. I swear!
Then, how did he fool Fox?
He's good, but no actor,
no makeup, is that good.
I... I don't know.
You're crazy!
Last chance.
- Talk!
- All right. He had something.
Something nobody else had. He could...
MAN: Nice going, Batman.
But I'll take it from here.
- This is my collar.
- Just a moment.
(GRUNTS)
What in the name of...
Shut up.
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Relax, Germs.
You won't have to hang around here
too long.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
What in the name of heaven...
Back off!
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
(GROANING)
All that shape-changing
takes a lot out of you, doesn't it?
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
(MUFFLED SOBBING)
Tomorrow on Gotham Insider,
my guest will be pharmaceutical king,
Roland Daggett,
whose new product can perform
miracles even plastic surgery can't.
Not even the Batman can stop me, Teddy.
And that means,
Daggett won't have a prayer.
Matt, please.
You don't want to do anything crazy.
Why don't you try to get some shuteye?
(GROWLS)
Don't you dare patronize me!
I told you, I don't need rest.
I don't need food!
And I don't need you!
(GRUNTS)
Ah!
ALFRED: I've acquired the Matt Hagen
films you requested, sir.
Good, because now I'm sure that
that thing I fought
at the hospital is Hagen.
His condition is apparently
the tragic result
of an experiment conducted
by Roland Daggett.
Hagen apparently transforms,
unconsciously sometimes,
like a reflex action.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(APPLAUSE)
FEMALE ANCHOR: A face-lift in a jar?
- I love that idea. That's interesting.
- (PEOPLE MURMURING IN AGREEMENT)
If you'll watch the monitors,
you'll see that with Renuyu,
you can smooth away wrinkles,
reshape imperfections.
Literally, remake your face
however you choose.
- Oh, that's great!
- Yeah.
(ALL MURMURING)
Amazing stuff, Rolly.
I see we have some questions
in our audience.
I'd like to ask Mr. Daggett
about the rumors I've heard.
I hear he's selling Renuyu
through direct marketing
because stores won't carry it
due to its harmful side effects.
Well, that's, uh...
Absolutely untrue.
What about the addictive properties
of Renuyu, Mr. Daggett?
How, once you're hooked on it,
you can't stop using it
without horrible pain?
No. I mean...
That's just not so.
Why don't you show them
what an overdose can do, Daggett.
(VOICE CHANGING)
Why don't you tell them about me?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
- (GUNS COCKING)
- Huh?
BOTH: Huh?
(GRUNTS)
You again.
Hagen, listen to me.
There is no Hagen.
It's only me now, Clayface.
(YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
See? I figured out
how to manage this thing pretty good.
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
What are you doing? Stop it!
Look at them, Hagen.
Look at what you used to be.
No. No.
Turn them off.
You can play those roles again, Hagen.
Let me help you find a cure.
No! Hagen's gone.
Make him stop haunting me!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Stop it. Stop it. Turn them off.
I can't control it.
I can't be all of them. Not all at once.
(SCREAMING)
Stop!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Mother of mercy.
It looks just like Bruce Wayne.
(SCREAMING)
You know what I'd have given
for a death scene like this?
Too bad I won't get to...
Read the notices.
I'm just glad to know
it wasn't really Bruce Wayne
who attacked me.
Thank you, Mr. Fox.
All charges against Wayne have,
of course, been dropped.
And Roland Daggett remains in custody.
BATMAN: Mmm.
ALFRED: My word, sir.
I should think after all this,
it would be time to rest.
Look.
A piece of clay left behind
when they took Hagen's body away.
Watch.
Electricity has no effect on it?
BATMAN: Exactly.
I wouldn't be surprised
if the body they took
to the morgue was only a shell.
Don't forget, first and foremost,
Hagen was an actor.
He said it himself, Alfred,
he called it a scene.
Maybe the greatest scene of his career.
See you around, Matt.
A death scene so real,
it fooled us all.
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING IN HAGEN'S VOICE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)