(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
ROBIN: Previously on Batman...
ROBIN: Everything was going great
until that Marin business came up.
You ever hear of
a crook named Billy Marin, Alfred?
- Hey, that's the guy the...
- Come on, honey, we're on.
Dad!
Does he have anyone?
No. No family.
I may be able to help.
ROBIN ON RADIO: You can't take this one.
Zucco's mine.
- Sorry, Robin.
- But I've waited half my life.
- Batman out.
- Oh, no, he's not gonna ace me out.
- Master Dick, you...
- Not this time, Alfred.
Maybe not ever again.
(CONSOLE BEEPING)
I told you to sit this one out, Robin.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
You're a real piece of work, Batman.
Okay, I'll find Zucco on my own,
just like I did before.
Ha-ha!
En garde.
BRUCE: Try using more control.
You're wasting a lot of energy.
DICK: Oh, yeah? (GRUNTING)
(YELLING WILDLY)
(GROANING)
BRUCE: See?
It's finesse, not strength.
Finesse, huh?
Hey. Okay, now you're gonna get it.
(LAUGHING)
Whoa!
- Too slow, huh?
- (GIGGLING)
(ALFRED CLEARING THROAT)
Forgive the interruption, sir.
But Lieutenant Gordon
is here to see you.
He asked to meet with you in private.
Uh, why don't you hit the showers, Dick?
It's almost time for dinner.
Uh, yeah, sure.
GORDON: I dropped by to let you know
you might not
have to keep the boy much longer.
Oh?
We just started putting these up
and already we got a few bites.
Zucco's been spotted
on the Lower East Side.
Off the record,
we hear he's trying to skip town.
- BRUCE: How soon?
- Could be tonight.
This Batman's got Zucco real spooked.
Zucco's friends too.
Nobody will touch the guy.
And if Zucco gets away?
GORDON: We could lose him for good.
You sure you want to get off here?
Yeah.
Hey, ever pick up this guy?
Can't say as I have.
Who is he, your old man or something?
DICK: Yeah, something.
(INAUDIBLE)
(WIND WHISTLING)
ZUCCO: Who you looking at, boy?
No one.
- (WHIRRING)
- Huh?
(WHIRRING GROWS LOUDER)
LENNIE: Who do you think taught you
how to grift, Chi-Chi?
You don't go skimming money from me.
(STAMMERING) But I ain't,
Lennie, honest.
Oh, yeah? We'll just see about that.
CHI-CHI: No! Wait! (GRUNTING)
(STAMMERING) Lennie, look,
I can explain.
LENNIE: We're beyond explanations.
DICK: Leave her alone.
This kid belong to you?
CHI-CHI: Let go of me.
I said leave her alone!
(LENNIE GRUNTING)
You little creep.
When I get my hands on you...
Get away, kid. Jump!
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
DICK: Come on!
LENNIE: Hey. Hey, let me out!
- (BANGING)
- There's roaches in here. Roaches!
(LAUGHING) So when's
the last time you ate, kid? Christmas?
(WITH MOUTH FULL)
Sorry, but I'm kind of in a rush.
Hey, you can't expect to find
this uncle of yours at this hour.
This is the only place around
that's still open. Right, Berty?
BERTY: Mmm-hmm.
Hey. I know that deadbeat.
- You do?
- Yeah. He's been here.
Always barking orders, never tipping.
(SCOFFING) I've seen him come
from that building across the basin.
That place has been
condemned for years, right?
Yeah, and may it
fall on his head, the louse.
(CLATTERING)
(METAL CRUMPLING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Let go of me!
The circus boy.
My little material witness.
What are you doing here?
- Ow! Why, you...
- DICK: Hey!
I was just about to
leave town because of you.
Looks like I'm gonna have
a change in travel plans.
- (SMACKING)
- (GROANS)
BATMAN: Only place you're going
is up the river, you scum.
You creep! I hate you! I hate you!
ZUCCO: (GROANING) Get away!
(YELLING)
(SCREAMS)
DICK: (SHOUTING) Help!
(YELLING)
So much for the Bat and the brat.
Help! Help!
(YELLING)
Hang on.
He's gone. He got away.
No! You had him.
You let him go! You let him.
Why? Why'd you do it? Why?
Where are we going?
Home.
DICK: Man, oh, man.
Is this where you live?
This is where I work.
You're the first...
Correction, second person to see it.
Why'd you bring me here?
Because I wanna know
just how badly you want Tony Zucco.
What do you mean?
Who are you?
(GASPS)
I take it Master Dick's visit
will now be indefinite?
You're out there somewhere, Zucco.
But you can't hide from me.
- I've been taught by the best.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
WOMAN ON RADIO: And just
a few hours ago,
Batman apprehended
a suspected extortionist,
Ferris Dolan of 210 Trumbell Avenue.
Mr. Dolan and other men
were reportedly sabotaging
a midtown construction site
at the time of his capture.
(SIZZLING)
Come on, Dolan.
You gotta have his address somewhere.
(LINE RINGING)
(PHONE RINGING)
ZUCCO: Yeah, who is it?
Hello? Hello?
Who's there? Ugh.
ROBIN: Gotcha.
I don't like it.
You sure Batman didn't follow you?
No. And Dolan's no squealer.
You got nothing to worry about.
(EXCLAIMS)
Don't tell me
what I've got to worry about.
I'm not back in town five minutes,
five minutes, and he's on my tail.
You don't know the Bat. He don't let up.
He's a dark angel of death, man,
and he wants me.
Uh, why you, boss?
How should I know?
- (CEILING CREAKING)
- What's that?
What's what?
Shh. Listen.
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
It sounds like rats.
Yeah, rats.
(GOONS YELLING)
Boss, calm down, okay?
You're starting to worry us.
(WOOD CRACKING)
(ALL YELLING)
Mama.
(GROANS)
(LAUGHING)
Aw, what's the matter, Bats?
You twist your knee?
Looks like you could use
a little protection about now.
And protection is my racket. (LAUGHING)
Nine years, creep.
Nine years of looking over my shoulder.
No more.
I'm sending you straight to a bat box.
(GUN CLICKING)
No!
(GAS HISSING)
(ALL COUGHING)
(BATMAN GROANING)
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
What are you deadbeats
standing around here for?
Get out there!
Now!
GOON: Where'd he go?
ZUCCO: Not far.
You saw how he was limping.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
ZUCCO: Spread out.
- (GASPS)
- (SMACKING)
(SHIP'S HORN BLOWING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
(GROANING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTING) Mick! Mick, he's over here!
Get him. Get him!
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Round and round we go, hey, Bats?
Ride's over!
No, boss! Don't! Wait!
You can't! You'll hit us!
ZUCCO: Sorry, boys.
You pays your money,
and you takes your chances.
(ZUCCO YELLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
I don't believe this.
You're through, Zucco.
Forever.
Is that so, birdy boy?
(GRUNTING) Huh?
I've waited a long time.
(YELLING)
(GROANING)
(WHIMPERING) Keep away from me.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
No. Don't. Please.
BATMAN: Robin!
Enough.
You can't let your emotions
get the best of you.
Stuff your advice, Batman.
You and your stone-cold heart.
You don't know how I feel.
How could you?
(SIRENS WAILING)
Batman, I...
I didn't mean to...
I'm sorry.
(WHIMPERING)
ROBIN: You were right, you know,
not bringing me along.
You knew I'd take it too personally.
It wasn't that, Robin.
It wasn't that at all.
Zucco's taken so much,
caused you so much pain.
I couldn't stand
the thought that he might...
Take you too.
Come on, partner.
It's been a long night.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)