(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(BARKING)
MAN: Kimberly?
Kimmy.
Mojo, you came back.
MAN: Sure. I said I would, didn't I?
Uh-huh.
MAN: Look what I got for you.
Oh. It's beautiful.
Thank you, thank you.
MAN: (CHUCKLES) You're welcome, sweetie.
Now, don't worry. I know that
what you've really been hoping for
is a pearl necklace.
Well, I haven't found
just the right one yet,
but Mojo promises
he'll bring you one next time he visits.
Oh.
MAN: Kimmy, what's wrong?
KIMMY: Next time better be soon
or you might not find us.
Mommy says we're moving.
MAN: (GASPS) Moving?
KIMMY: She says things will be
better for us someplace else.
(KIMMY GASPS)
Kimberly, who are you talking to?
Nobody, Mommy, just Mojo.
Oh, I'm sorry I missed him.
I would've said, "Hi."
KIMMY: He really was here, Mommy.
I know, honey. I know.
Now go to sleep, okay?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
Hey! Who locked the bathroom?
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
A most handsome selection, Mr. Wayne.
I'll take it.
What in the devil?
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Holy smoke, look!
(ALL GASPING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Police! Police! Over this way!
(GASPS)
Help, security! I've been robbed.
- Look at that!
- What the heck?
(ALL GRUNTING)
Nobody moves till we figure out
what's going on here.
Hey! My piece. It's been stolen.
Mine, too.
(WHISTLING)
Argh! Ahhh!
Oh!
Footsteps?
Who are you?
I know you're in here.
(COUGHING)
MAN: Cute. Real cute.
You were better off
blowing smoke, Batman.
See, I guess I'm what you'd call
a burnout case.
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Too bad about these
high ceilings, huh, Batman?
I mean, all this lousy echoing
kind of makes it hard
to get a fix on me, doesn't it?
Especially, since you wouldn't see me...
(GRUNTING)
if I were standing right next to you.
(LAUGHING)
Argh!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
MAN: See you around, Batman.
Too bad you can't say the same.
(LAUGHS)
A better life somewhere else, huh?
Where your dear old dad can't find you,
that's what she really means.
Well, don't you worry.
She's never going to
take you away from me.
I won't let her. You hear me?
I won't let her.
(KISSES)
Bye, sweetie. Have a nice day.
HELEN: I'll be back in an hour.
Hey, babe.
Long time.
Not long enough.
Did they tell you about the parole?
I'm living in Gotham now.
I don't care what you do, as long as
you don't do it within 100 feet of me.
The restraining order?
You don't need that anymore, Helen.
When I was still a bum,
it made sense, but...
What do you mean, "was"?
Come on, babe. Look at me!
How many all-night gas stations
did you have to knock over for that?
Keep it.
Everything is different now,
can't you see that?
I can give Kimmy
everything she'll ever need.
You stay away from her.
Come on, babe.
If you could just let her see me...
Keep your hands off me.
I told her all about you.
She knows you're
not supposed to go near her.
Helen, please.
Cut me some slack, here, will you?
I'll give you anything you want.
Want?
All I want is for you to disappear.
Okay.
But just remember the old saying,
"Be careful what you wish for."
SCIENTIST: I understand
your concern, Mr. Wayne.
But I don't think you need to worry
that Wayne Tech is responsible
for this invisible man.
After all, no equipment is missing.
But, I seem to remember,
last year, hearing something
about an invisibility project.
You mean that inventor Carrows.
Yeah, I remember him.
The one who wanted us
to go into business with him,
developing that plastic.
Uh-huh. The "cloak of invisibility"
he called it, right?
So, what happened?
Well, we were interested
in hearing more, Bruce.
But, Carrows withdrew his proposal
before we could close a deal.
Lucius, see if you can locate him.
I'd like to talk to him.
Don't bother.
He passed away a couple of months ago.
But I've heard that his old assistant,
Sam Giddell,
was trying to carry on his research.
(RATCHET CLICKING)
(GRUNTS)
Okay, you, come out of there.
I don't know
what you think you're doing.
Argh!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) You.
I didn't know.
Are you Giddell?
(STAMMERS) What do you want?
Where were you the day before yesterday?
Here. All day. And I can prove it.
The building security saw me.
You can check.
Working kind of late, aren't you?
I wanted to prep
the last of the stuff for disposal.
This is that invisibility plastic
your boss created?
Mmm-hmm.
- How does it work?
- Here, let me show you.
It's really quite remarkable.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
See those filaments
embedded in the plastic?
Mmm-hmm.
Run an electrical current through them,
and the stuff bends light
instead of absorbing it,
so you can't see it.
But in the process,
the plastic becomes toxic.
I know. I read the report.
I've spent the last two months
trying to correct the problem,
but it's hopeless.
So, you were just going to dump it?
Yes, it's too dangerous.
Funny thing is,
some of it seems to be missing.
- Who else would know about this stuff?
- Only the other assistant.
Actually, he was
more like an errand boy.
An ex-con.
Name is Ventrix. Lloyd Ventrix.
- Mrs. Ventrix?
- (GASPS)
I'm looking for your husband.
It's urgent.
Oh, Mojo, it's exactly what I wanted.
LLOYD: I'm glad.
Now, come on.
I want to show you
something real special.
- (CHUCKLES) Where are we going?
- You'll see.
And prolonged exposure to the plastic
can damage the mind,
as well as the body.
You say he can make himself invisible?
(GASPS) Mojo!
- Who?
- Kimberly!
(GASPS)
Kimberly.
Kimberly!
Kimmy!
(CRYING)
I thought Mojo was just
her imaginary friend.
I never thought...
What's that?
A tranquilizer dart.
How long ago did you see your daughter?
Five minutes ago.
I put her to bed and...
Batman?
LLOYD: Here we are.
(GASPS)
- You want me to get in your car?
- Now, Kimmy...
But it'll look
like the car's going by itself.
Won't we get in trouble?
No, Kimberly, we won't.
I don't know.
(SIGHS) I'll tell you what,
maybe if I let you see me,
you'll feel better.
Hi, Kimberly.
(GASPS) You're a man?
I gotta go, Mojo.
I'm not supposed to be with strangers.
Mommy told me. (GASPS)
But I'm not a stranger, Kimberly.
I'm your daddy.
My daddy? Get away!
Mommy says you're not allowed
to come near me.
She says you're a bad man.
She says that's why they locked you up.
Never mind that!
You're coming with me,
whether you want to or not.
BATMAN: Not in this lifetime, pal.
(GRUNTS)
Mommy, Mommy!
Kimberly?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
I didn't know he could fly, too.
(HORN HONKING)
Give it up, Ventrix.
The suit is toxic. It'll destroy you!
Don't hand me that.
I'm not feeling any pain.
At least, not like you're gonna feel.
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
Argh!
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Ventrix, the suit,
it's poison!
LLOYD: So, what if it is?
I don't care.
As long as I have it,
I can take my daughter back,
whenever I want!
Her mother won't be able to stop me,
and neither will you!
No!
Peekaboo.
Ow!
(LLOYD GRUNTING)
Oh!
Get ready for your biggest
disappearing act, Ventrix.
The one where no one sees you
for 10 to 20.
KIMMY: Me and Mommy are moving.
And even if Daddy gets out
of jail this time,
he'll never find us.
Kimberly? Who are you talking to now?
Just Batman, Mommy.
Oh. Him, again?
But he really was here, Mommy.
I know, honey.
I know.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)