(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Be sure the bulbs are spaced far enough
apart for proper root growth,
and remember to give the seedlings
plenty of sunlight.
(WHISTLING)
Add just enough water. Then...
(PATIENTS PROTESTING)
Hey, I was watching that.
And now you're watching this.
MAN: (CHUCKLING) Next, a dog drinks milk
out of his owner's mouth.
Change it back.
Oh, no, no, no. Don't want to.
Guard!
What's the problem?
Don't look now, Sonny Jim, but
the plant lady's gone wackers again.
He started it. I was just sitting here.
That's right. You're always blaming me.
And the children wonder why we fight.
Crazy.
I know you are, but what am I?
Okay, okay, you'll watch this quietly,
or you'll go back to your cells.
Jawohl!
I don't care.
You hold my hand, and I'll slug you.
Guard!
Just kidding. Just kidding.
Yeesh, Pammy, lighten up.
This is Summer Gleeson live at
Gotham Palisades Boardwalk,
where it's opening day
at billionaire Cameron Kaiser's
latest showplace resort.
Total price tag for this
fun-seeker's mecca, nearly $300 million.
It's true, Summer.
I set out to create the most opulent
gambling resort in the world.
After all, what's a few million
here and there
as long as my guests are happy?
Gotham's elite have turned out
in style for the opening.
Bruce Wayne,
perhaps you can give us a hint
about the top secret theme
of Mr. Kaiser's new casino.
Looks like we'll find out
together, Summer.
- (APPLAUSE)
- (DRUMROLL)
Ladies and gentlemen, the wait is over.
I officially welcome you, one and all...
- To Jokers Wild.
- (HEAD LAUGHING)
Say what?
SUMMER: Oh, just disgusting.
MAN: Psst! Summer, we're on the air.
Oh, uh... There you have it.
Let's get a reaction from the guests.
- Uh, Mr. Wayne.
- No comment.
Mr. Kaiser, why build a casino
seemingly in honor
of one of history's
most notorious outlaws?
Summer, please.
My joker is a classic symbol,
long associated with cards and games.
I can't help it if there's a passing
resemblance to some criminal fruitcake.
(JOKER GRUNTS)
How dare that smug, preening fool
try to cash in on my image!
Now who should lighten up?
Don't get cute with me, Red.
He's ripping me off. I'll protest.
Yeah, I'll sue.
Then I'll rip his lungs out.
And I will, too.
Take it easy.
(GROANS) I feel dizzy.
Sick... Everything's spinning.
Oh! Need a doctor.
PAMELA: Oh, Joker?
Thanks for the smile.
(GROANS)
Hang on. I'll get Dr. Bartholomew.
Yes. Hurry. Please.
(LAUGHING)
Sucker.
JOKER: What a maroon. Ha!
I know you are, but what am I?
The Joker!
(CACKLING)
Exit stage left, laughing all the way.
- Hey!
- Excuse me.
- There he is!
- Get him!
Step right up and play
everyone's favorite game,
"What's the Joker got in the pail?"
Maybe a deadly poison?
Or maybe just something
to make the floor nice and slippery.
- Hey!
- Look out!
I always did know how to make an exit.
(ALARM BLARING)
Ta-da!
Don't try this at home, kids.
(WHOOPING)
(THUDDING)
Peekaboo.
Sorry, no riders.
(YELLS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Now to treat Mr. Cameron Kaiser
to a real blowout opening.
(CACKLING)
I didn't mind driving down here
at a moment's notice
with your equipment.
And I was happy to dream up
a plausible alibi for your date.
But staying in this horrid place
pushes even my tolerance.
Mine too.
But I'm convinced
it wasn't Kaiser's original goal
to make a Joker-themed casino.
- See?
- But why the deception?
That's what I intend to find out.
(HEAD LAUGHING)
"Camelot." Hmm.
Looks like Kaiser
broke the bank on this place.
What an interesting hobby
you've got, Cameron.
Hey, you.
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
Where are you? Come out and fight.
(LAUGHING)
(WHISTLES)
Jumpin' Jiminy Christmas.
It's an homage to me.
I'm kind of sorry I have to blow it up.
Go on and open table six.
We got players waiting.
Hmm.
(SNIFFING)
Then again, all work and no play...
(CACKLES)
Good evening, folks.
The game is blackjack.
Joker's rules, of course.
(GIGGLES)
Ooh! Blackjack already.
Lucky me.
- Hey.
- What?
Hold on.
JOKER: Don't be sore losers.
We're here to have fun.
Mr. Kaiser, that dealer's
doing something screwy.
I'm calling security.
No. Wait.
Ooh! Mercy me. Another blackjack.
One might think I had
an ace up my sleeve.
Let him deal.
Yes, sir. You're the boss.
(JOKER CACKLING)
- Try your luck, friend?
- Why not?
Say, don't I know you?
Sure. Bruce Wayne.
Huh.
So this is how your family
made all those billions.
The secret's out. And you are?
Oh, just a nameless clown,
shuffling my life away.
Too bad it has to be in such
gruesome surroundings.
Don't care for the decor?
Not hardly. All those horrible faces
grinning at me.
That would do things
to my mind after a while.
Who says you have one?
Yeah, I'd be ready
for the laughing academy
if I had to stare
at that ugly clown all day.
- Why I ought to...
- Hit me.
(GASPS)
Twenty.
Oh, lucky me. Twenty-one.
How nice. A little something
for the Wayne Charity Fund.
Good night.
(GROWLS)
He's here.
Place your bets, folks.
(ALL GASP)
- BATMAN: You.
- Huh?
- Batman.
- It's Batman.
I don't believe it.
- It is Batman!
- What's he doing here?
Whoops! Time to cash out.
- Hey!
- Hey.
MAN: Stop that guy.
(CACKLING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(CACKLING)
Here's where I get off.
Whoo!
Not bad for a starter,
but the real fireworks
are still to come.
Whoops! Coming through. Hot stuff.
One side, please.
I wouldn't take odds on this place
lasting the night. (CHUCKLES)
(JOKER HUMMING)
MAN: Helipad.
I want my personal 'copter
ready for takeoff in 20 minutes.
Yes, sir, Mr. Kaiser.
(GASPS)
Going somewhere?
First you trash my penthouse,
then my casino.
You gonna wreck something else?
If I didn't know better, I'd say
you wanted this place destroyed.
After spending 300 million to build it?
That's not good business, my friend.
I've seen the unpaid bills.
Building this casino has bankrupted you.
That's why you turned it
into a target for the Joker.
Once he destroys it,
you'll collect the insurance money.
You hit the jackpot, Batman.
But I've got too much at stake
to be stopped now.
(YELLS)
Ah! You again.
- What do we do with him, boss?
- Send him down to his friend.
(JOKER HUMMING)
- Huh?
- (ELEVATOR DINGS)
(GROANING)
Kind of slow on the reflexes, eh, Batsy?
That car crash must have taken
more out of you than I thought.
(CACKLING)
Wakey, wakey.
(GROANING)
(STRAINING)
Thought you'd like to be conscious
for your own demise.
I really put some effort into this one.
Once I spin the wheel,
you, the casino
and that strutting fool Kaiser
will all be blown sky-high.
Not bad, eh?
You won't get Kaiser.
He's been playing you for a patsy.
Eh?
He's counting on you
to blow this place up
so he can collect the insurance.
By the time you get clear,
Kaiser will be miles away,
laughing at you.
I hate it when you make sense.
I'll settle my score
with Kaiser, man to clown.
But that still doesn't
let you off the hook.
(WHEEL WHIRRING)
How about that, Bats?
Looks like your number's up.
(CACKLING)
(STRAINING)
- Get me out of here now!
- Yes, sir.
(MAN GRUNTING)
What happened?
Some clown jumped me
and grabbed my 'copter.
Mr. Kaiser's up there.
What are you circling for, you fool?
- It was a scheme worthy of me, Kaiser.
- (GASPS)
The way you got me riled up
and turned me loose on this place.
You... You were supposed to
destroy the casino.
Yeah, but then I realized
it'd be more fun to get rid of you
and run the show myself.
But you can't!
Oh, please, Mr. Kaiser,
you of all people should've realized
there'd be a joker in the deck.
(CACKLING)
Why can't he ever stay dead?
(GUNSHOTS)
JOKER: Gotcha!
Yes.
(HEAD LAUGHING)
That's it. Chew him up and spit him out.
(JOKER CACKLING)
Stop! You'll kill us all!
(GROANS)
- (CHIMING)
- (AUTOMATED VOICE WHOOPING)
And so it ended for both ex-billionaire
Cameron Kaiser and the Joker.
Ah! Enough of this rubbish.
PAMELA: Hey!
ALL: We were watching that.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
And was returned to Arkham.
Ah, you bunch of no-good,
whacked-out losers.
You make me sick.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)