Men, uh...
flip around the television
more than women, I think.
Men get that remote control
in their hands...
they don't even know what
the hell they're not watching.
You know, they just keep going.
"Don't even know
what I'm watching."
"What are you watching?"
"I don't care. I gotta keep
going." "Who was that?"
"Isn't that your father?"
"I don't know what it was."
"I gotta keep going!"
Women don't do that. See, now,
women will stop and go,
"Well, let me see
what the show is
before I change the channel."
You see, but men just fly.
Because women, you see,
women nest, and men hunt.
That's why
we watch TV differently.
Before there was
flipping around,
before there was television,
kings and emperors and pharaohs
and such had storytellers
that would tell them stories.
That was their entertainment.
I always wonder, in that era,
if they would get, like,
30 storytellers together
so they could still flip around.
Just go, "All right,
start telling me your story.
"What's happening? I don't want
to hear any more. Shut up.
"Go to the next guy.
What are you talking about?
"Is there a girl in that story?
No? Shut up.
"I don't want to hear
that either. Shut up.
"No, go ahead.
What are you talking about?
I don't wanna hear that.
I'm going to bed."
She's pregnant?
Mm-hmm.
Leslie is pregnant?
Oh, see?
There is no justice.
She's the performance
artist, right?
Yeah, performance artist.
She's a real performer,
a real trooper.
What's her husband's name again?
Chip? Kip?
Skip?
Todd.
Todd...
Oh, yeah.
He's a Kennedy.
No, he's not.
Come on, he's a third
cousin or something.
By marriage.
Oh, by marriage, yeah.
We went to the wedding.
You should have
heard them talking
about Chappaquiddick.
Tried to blame the whole
thing on bad directions.
That woman was unequivocally
the worst date of my life.
Oh, pardon me
for trying to set you up
with a beautiful,
intelligent woman.
What, you don't think
I can attract
beautiful, intelligent women?
Thin ice, George, very thin ice.
Maybe for her new
performance piece,
she'll give birth on stage.
She stopped performing.
Oh! What a huge blow
to the culture.
Can you believe this guy?
He holds a grudge like Khomeini.
She dragged me
down to that warehouse
on the waterfront in Brooklyn
to see one of her performances.
Oh, when she's on stage
cooking dinner
for some celebrity?
God...
She's cooking dinner for God.
She's yelling and screaming,
and the next thing I know,
she throws
a big can of chocolate syrup
all over my new red shirt.
It was an accident!
Oh, yeah, accident, right.
She was aiming right at me,
like she was putting out a fire.
So for the rest of the show,
I'm sitting there
with chocolate over my shirt.
Flies are landing on me.
I'm boiling!
I'm fantasizing all the things
I'm going to say to her,
and later, finally,
backstage when I talk to her,
I'm like a little
groveling worm.
I'm... "What kind of chocolate
was that?"
"Do you throw
any other foods?"
He thought he still had a shot.
And then, then, then!
She leaves with somebody else.
Never even...
never even said goodbye.
Never called me back,
never apologized, nothing.
Like I was dirt.
Whatever happened to the shirt?
I still have it.
The collar's okay.
I wear it under sweaters.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
She asked me to give her
a baby shower.
Asked you?
You're not gonna
do that, are you?
Anyone else, never,
but Leslie...
I have a problem
saying no to her.
For some reason,
I seem to want her approval.
Let Maria Shriver
give her a baby shower.
Ask not what I can do for you,
ask what you can do for me.
Ich bin ein sucker.
Oh...
Would you two stop
with the Kennedys?
Why does everybody make such
a big deal about the Kennedys?
I mean,
what is this fascination?
Who cares?
It's all so boring.
Look, she doesn't deserve
a baby shower.
She deserves a baby monsoon.
She deserves Rosemary's baby.
I do have one
teeny little problem, though.
Never said goodbye.
Never apologized. Nothing.
See...
I was gonna give
the shower in my apartment...
But?
My roommate has Lyme disease.
Lyme disease?
I thought she had
Epstein-Barr Syndrome.
She has this
in addition to Epstein-Barr.
It's like Epstein-Barr
with a twist of Lyme disease.
How did she get Lyme disease?
I don't know.
She did some outdoor version
of Hair
in Danberry, Connecticut.
They still do that play?
It's a classic.
With the nudity?
I guess. She must've rolled over
on a tick during the love-in.
Never said goodbye. Hah!
"Goodbye."
Explain to me how
this baby shower thing works?
What do you want to know?
Well, I mean, does it ever erupt
into a drunken orgy of violence?
Rarely.
There's no hazing of the fetus,
or anything, is there?
No. Mm-mm.
When is this supposed to be?
Saturday.
Well, I have a show
in Buffalo on Saturday.
They're not gonna
bust up my apartment,
or anything, are they?
No, I'll take
full responsibility.
You won't regret it.
You know, because I've
seen these pregnant women,
and they sometimes misjudge
their fetal girth...
and they'll... just like
one wrong turn,
the whole buffet is,
like, right off the table.
Someday, before I die,
mark my words,
I'm gonna tell that woman
exactly what I think of her.
I'll never be able
to forgive myself
until I do.
And if you do?
Well, I still won't be
able to forgive myself,
but at least
it won't be about this.
What are you doing this for?
Look at you!
Quiet. I'm trying
to get a picture.
But you don't have to do this.
The guy is waiting in my house!
Leave me alone!
It's a one-time fee.
150 bucks.
Why live like this?
I'm not getting illegal cable.
Oh, so what are you gonna do?
You gonna wait for
the cable companies
to resolve their dispute?
They're gonna be
in court for years.
No, I read in the paper...
Oh, oh, the paper, yeah.
Well, they might
hook us up again.
Oh, God, you're so naive.
All cable companies care about
is the big mamoo.
Oh... look at you.
You're banging things.
It's just pathetic.
You're just wasting your life.
I'm offering you 56 channels.
Movies, sports, nudity,
and it's free for life!
Stop shouting.
You're ruining the reception!
Can you hear yourself?
Can... Do you know
what you're saying?
What you're suggesting
is illegal.
It's not illegal.
It's against the law.
Well, yeah.
Just... just hold this.
Can you hold that?
Look, will you at least
let me bring the guy over?
He's an amazing man.
He's a Russian immigrant.
He escaped from the gulag.
He's like the Sakharov
of cable guys.
He'll slow your gas meter.
He sells slugs, Jerry.
Slugs for the subway.
He's a real
human rights nut, huh?
Yeah. He's intense, man.
I don't know.
What if I get caught...
Oh, you're not gonna get caught.
Look, let me get him, man.
It's the 90's. It's Hammer time.
Come on.
Just let me get him.
Jerry, Jerry,
this is the cable man.
You know, why don't we wait,
because I'm going
out of town tomorrow.
Tomorrow okay.
No problem.
Yeah, you'll have
the whole thing installed
by the time you get back.
No, every time I turn on a TV,
sirens are gonna go off.
They're gonna track me down
like a dog. I know it.
No, no. Look, now, Jerry, Jerry,
it's no risk. I swear.
The Mets have 75 games
on cable this year.
Put it in.
You won't regret it.
♪ Yeah, Jerry's going to be
A cable boy ♪
♪ A cable boy
A cable boy... ♪
Mr. Steinfeld?
Seinfeld.
We're with the FBI.
Want to tell us
about your cable hook up?
My cable hook up? What about it?
It's been illegally installed,
Mr. Steinfeld.
It has? I've been out of town.
How did you know?
Hey, Jerry, I had to tell them.
I had to.
I had no choice.
Ah, they were onto the scam
from the very beginning.
You're in very serious trouble,
Mr. Steinfeld.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Hold on.
We're just patsies.
We're just a couple of users.
We never sold the stuff.
What about the Russian guy?
The Russian guy's
the guy you want.
Mr. Seinfeld?
Agent Stone, FBI undercover.
No, Jerry!
No!
Cable boy...
Cable boy?
What have you done
to my little cable boy?
Excuse me, can I get
something to drink?
I'm afraid not.
Well, what's with this airline?
What, are you cutting out
the drinks now?
No, sir,
we're flying into a blizzard.
Please fasten your seat belt.
We're making
an emergency landing.
Are they gonna go over
the instructions again?
My name is Bill.
I might be the last person
you ever see.
Not afraid of flying.
Although, many people do have
fear of flying,
and, uh,
I have no argument with that.
I think fear of flying
is quite rational
because human beings cannot fly.
Humans have fear of flying
the same way
fish have fear of driving.
You put a fish behind the wheel,
and they go, "This isn't right.
"I shouldn't be doing this.
I don't belong here."
Sounds like a rough trip.
Oh, there were fire engines,
ambulances all along the runway,
and then when we landed safely,
they all seemed so disappointed.
So the college canceled the gig?
Oh, there was so much snow,
the roads were closed.
I really appreciate you
picking me up.
Thanks again.
Ah, forget it.
No, really, an airport run.
It's nothing.
No, it's one thing
if I asked you,
"Could you do me a favor?"
but to suggest it...
When you told me what you
went through on the plane,
it makes you stop and think.
I appreciate having
a real friend.
You know, if Richie Brandis
did this, I'd be suspicious.
You know, he's always got
some ulterior motive.
Ulterior motive...
Oh, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Don't take the bridge,
get off here.
We can't go back to my place.
Elaine's having the shower.
What, tonight? Now?
Yeah, yeah.
I forgot all about it. Uh...
All right, it's no big deal.
We'll go back to your place.
My place?
No, no, no, I hate my place.
I don't want to go back
to my place
Well, you want to get a bite?
Well, yeah, I would,
it's just I, you know,
I just ate a whole pot roast.
Well, so what should we do?
Well, shouldn't we at least
drop off your bag?
Red shirt!
That's the red shirt!
What are you talking about?
You're wearing
the chocolate shirt!
I am. What a strange
coincidence.
Ah-ha! Nice try, my friend,
but you got to get up
pretty early in the morning.
You gotta let me go over there.
What are you gonna do,
badger a pregnant woman
at her own baby shower?
Are you gonna take it off and
make her rinse it in club soda?
No, I'm gonna hold it
under her nose,
so she can smell
the scent of stale Bosco
that I had to live with
for three years.
I'm gonna say, "Remember
this shirt, baby?
Well, now...
it's payback time!"
We just bought an apartment
on Riverside Drive.
Bernard Goetz's mother
used to live there.
So where's Todd?
Up in Hyannis Port.
Oh, my God.
Hyannis Port?
With the Kennedys?
Who else is up there?
Is Rose up there?
Ah, ha, ha.
So when's your due date?
March 20th, 9:00 a.m.
You know the time?
I'm having
a planned C-section.
My therapist told me
if I go through labor
I might get psychotic.
Uh, Leslie, Leslie,
what ever happened
to Sergeant Shriver?
Is... is he still
with them?
You don't hear much
about him these days.
Is he, like,
out of the loop, or...
Elaine, who catered this, Sears?
What is this?
What are you doing here?
Ah, we're putting in the cable.
I'm having a party here.
You can't do this now.
Oh, we have to do this now.
Who is this guy?
Well, which one?
Both of them.
Oh, they're Soviet cable guys.
Okay.
Does Jerry know about this?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's all authorized. Yeah.
Well, you can't.
You can't do this now.
Elaine, do you know
how booked up this guy is?
If I send him away now,
it's gonna take Jerry
months to get him back.
He won't like that.
All right. Just do it fast,
and then get out.
All right. Anatole?
Giddy up. Go.
Look, it's only gonna take
a few minutes.
Then you and the gals
can take a load off
and watch something on Lifetime.
And what if we go up there?
What are you gonna say to her?
What am I gonna say?
Yeah.
What did you go out with me for?
Just to dump chocolate
on my shirt,
and then dump me altogether?
I don't deserve
that kind of treatment.
You don't have
the common courtesy
to return my calls?
To apologize?
You think
I'm some sort of a loser
that likes to be abused
and ignored?
Whose shirt can be ruined
without financial restitution?
Some sort of a masochist
who enjoys being humiliated?
You think you can just avoid me?
Like I have
some sort of a disease?
You have the disease!
You may be beautiful and rich
and physically
just unbelievable,
but you sicken me.
You disgust me!
You and everyone like you!
You'll never say that
to her face.
Watch me.
Yeah, I eat the whole apple...
core, stem, seeds...
just everything.
Kramer...
Kramer, look at him.
Look, he's eating all the food.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, you know,
there are many differences
between American
and Soviet cultures
that you're not aware of.
See, in Russia,
the cable guy, oh, they got
the whole run of the house.
Yeah, that...
That's tradition. Yeah.
You ever eat the bark
off of a pineapple?
Kramer! Kramer!
Hey... Wow, man.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were out of town.
The show was canceled.
There was a blizzard.
I can't believe you told Kramer
it's okay to put cable in
during the shower, Jerry.
Look, look,
they've eaten everything.
Jerry, what a surprise.
I thought you were out of town.
Well, Leslie, sometimes
the road less traveled is...
less traveled for a reason.
George,
don't even think about it.
Don't even dream about it.
About what?
Kramer! Kramer!
Hey.
Leslie...
Yeah?
George...
George Costanza.
Hi.
I guess you don't remember me,
but we actually went out
a couple years ago.
Once.
Remember?
Vaguely.
Yeah. You took me
to see one of your shows.
And?
And, um...
it was quite good.
In fact, you even
incorporated me into the show.
I'm not actually a performer,
although my parents
felt I had talent.
Jerry?
Remember me?
I'm sorry...
Mary Contardi.
No? Doesn't ring a bell, Jerry?
We had a date three years ago.
You took me
to one of your shows.
Oh, I... I think I remember.
Told me you had a great time.
Said you'd call me the next day.
Well, I'm sure I meant to call.
I probably just lost your...
Liar!
You were never going to call me!
You thought you could waltz
through the rest of life
and never bump into me again,
but you were wrong, Jerry!
You were wrong!
I... I...
What do you think,
I'm a poor pathetic wretch?
I didn't think that...
Some person who could be
dismissed and ignored?
Some insignificant
piece of dust?
Some person who doesn't deserve
your respect and your attention?
Well, you're the one
that doesn't deserve
my respect and my attention!
You're the insignificant
piece of dust!
Actually, I never had
any formal training.
I guess I'd be
better suited for improvs...
Oh!
Thanks a lot.
Oh, bye.
I'm so sorry you have to go.
Yeah, I really have to be going.
All right, listen,
I've changed my mind
about this whole thing.
I don't want the cable.
Look, Jerry, don't be a fool.
You don't want?
No, I don't want.
So just tell what I owe you
for your trouble, and...
$400.
You told me 150.
Well...
I'm going.
Obviously.
Oh, Leslie, I am so sorry
about everything that went on
here tonight.
You know, I had no idea...
Elaine, you know,
I was watching you tonight,
and I realized something.
You're just like
you were in college.
Oh... Thank you.
What was I like in college?
Come on, let's go.
I'll be right back.
I'm not paying $400.
I don't even want the thing.
What are you gonna do?
Every woman
on the face of the earth
has complete control
of my life...
and yet I want them all.
Is that irony?
Why can't I meet a Kennedy?
I saw John Junior once downtown.
I was on a bus.
I hit the... ding.
It didn't stop.
All right, I said I had
a good time and I'd call, but...
who takes that literally?
Hey, come on over.
Doctor Zhivago's on cable
in five minutes.
I'm making popcorn.
What do you do
at the end of a date,
when you know you don't want
to see this person ever again
for the rest of your life?
What do you say?
It doesn't... No matter
what you say, it's a lie.
"I'll see you around."
See you around.
If you're around,
and I'm around,
I'll see you around that area.
You'll be around other people,
you won't be around me,
but you will be around.
"Take care now."
Ever say that to somebody?
Take care...
Now.
Because I'm not gonna
be taking care of you.
So you should take care now.
"Take care, take care."
What does that mean?
"Take care."
"Take off." Isn't that
what you really want to say?
"Take off now."
Get out of here.