I'm not a foodie.
I don't...
"Oh, this is too rare."
"Oh, it's too salty."
Just eat it and shut up.
I'll eat anywhere,
whatever they're having.
I have eaten rolls
off of room-service trays
in hotel hallways.
I have. That's not a joke.
This is my life.
I don't know.
Somebody left it.
Why would somebody poison a roll
and leave it in the hallway
for some comic coming down
at 2:00 in the morning?
Why would they do that?
Sometimes,
you go to a nice restaurant,
they put the check
in a little book.
What is this,
the story of the bill?
"Once upon a time,
there were
some very hungry people..."
What is this?
A little gold tassel
hanging down...
Am I graduating
from the restaurant?
What is this about?
You want some of mine?
Take some of mine.
Why do I get pesto?
Why do I think I'll like it?
I keep trying to like it.
It's like I have to like it.
Who says you have to like it?
Everybody likes pesto.
You walk into a restaurant,
that's all you hear.
Pesto. Pesto. Pesto.
I don't like pesto.
Where was pesto 10 years ago?
Look at that guy.
Mm-mm-mm-mm!
I'll bet you
he's getting hair transplants.
Anytime you see a guy that age
wearing a baseball cap,
ten to one... plugs.
Well, the thing
about that painting
is with the colors and, um...
Oh, yeah, plugola.
Oh, one more thing
about the car...
let it warm up for a minute.
Yeah, that's a tough minute.
It's like waiting in the shower
for the conditioner to work.
I don't understand
why he couldn't take a cab.
Who?
Elaine is having a, uh...
house guest?
She's picking him up
at the airport tonight.
A guy?
Yes, it's a guy.
He's from, uh, Yakima, right?
Seattle.
Everybody's moving to Seattle.
It's the pesto of cities. So?
Oh, well, you tell.
Well, from what
I can piece together,
our friend here
met a gentleman...
Ed.
Who was in town
on a business venture,
and, uh...
We, uh, shared
an interpersonal experience.
So, they went out a few times,
but, apparently,
when the fellow returned home,
he discovered
that the Benes tattoo
does not wash off so easily.
On some people.
Ooh...
So, he's coming in
to stay with her for a week.
It was just gonna be a weekend,
but, then,
somehow it became a week.
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho!
Wait a second. All right, okay.
I'll take that.
All right. All right, okay.
What happened?
Oh...
The, uh, busboy left the menu
a little close to the candle.
I'm sorry for the disturbance.
Mm. I'm never eating here again.
Yes.
Nice going.
Thank you.
That ought to get us a free dessert.
Yeah.
I think the busboy's in trouble.
Did I get him in trouble
because of what I said?
I just told him what happened.
He didn't do it on purpose.
He pointed at me.
Why did they point at me?
I said I would never eat here
again,
but I...
he had to know I was kidding.
I didn't say anything.
I can't believe it.
He's going.
He's fired.
Oh, I said it in a kidding way.
I didn't know he'd get fired.
He'll probably
kill his family over this.
What if he's waiting for me
outside?
He pointed at me.
Did you see him point?
A lot of ex-cons become busboys.
They seem to gravitate
toward it.
Was it my fault?
Maybe I'll try that pesto.
Look, I feel bad for him too,
but he'll get another job.
I mean, let's face it.
It's not a profession
where you embellish your resume
and undergo a series
of grueling interviews.
Like you really know busboys.
Oh, like you do?
Hey, at least I was a camp waiter.
Camp.
It was a fat camp!
Those kids depended on me.
Elaine?
Yeah.
Busboys are always
changing jobs.
That's the business.
I know. I work with these guys.
I talk with them
in the kitchens
at the comedy clubs.
Why don't you try
to get him another job?
I'd love to,
but I don't know
anything about him.
He could be one of those people
that walks around the street
pricking people with pins.
I don't know
if you people are aware of this,
but I am one clever chickadee.
What, did you get
the busboy's number?
His phone's been disconnected,
but I was able to obtain
an address...
1324 Amsterdam Avenue,
apartment 4-D.
Now, I did my job.
May I have the car keys, please?
How did you get all this?
Does the word charm
mean anything to you?
No.
So now you're going
to his apartment?
I really think this is nuts.
I'd like to apologize,
I want to tell him
I didn't mean
to get him in trouble.
So you're going now?
Yeah, I wanna see
if there's anything I can do,
maybe get him another job.
Maybe I'll hear of something.
Maybe the fat camp.
You're not going?
I would, but I have to
pick up Ed at the airport.
I just don't think
you should go alone.
Can't you wait
till after my set?
It'll take too long.
Hey.
Take the K-man,
a little support.
I don't, uh...
What? What? Take me where?
Where?
Uh...
Um...
Look, I really
appreciate your coming,
but, um...
if you wouldn't mind...
try not to say too much.
What am I going to say?
I don't know.
Well, I'm not an idiot.
Certainly not.
Then we're cool.
Y... Yeah.
Yeah, w-w-we're cool.
Uh, I'm sorry to bother you.
I was in the restaurant earlier,
and I, uh, was wondering
if I could talk to you
for a few minutes
about what happened.
Thanks.
Um...
I... I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
It's just that, um,
I think I may have...
without realizing it...
Um, been responsible
for getting you fired.
And... and I just...
I wanted you to know
that I did not intend
for that to happen.
He's a hell of a guy.
This is, uh...
a guy I know.
Kramer...
Habla espanol?
Oh, my God.
Si.
¿Como se dice...
waterbed?
Anyway, I... I, um...
I just wanted to let you know
that I'm really sorry
that happened,
and if I can help out
in any way,
I'll certainly be glad
to do that.
Well, I guess that's about it.
You got anything to drink?
Agua.
Oy, oy... um.
You know, we really
should be going.
I'm gonna get a glass of water.
Hurry up.
Paquita.
¿Paquita?
His cat's gone.
La puerta esta abierta.
La puerta esta abierta!
Who left the door open?
Come on! Come on! Help me look!
Psst. Psst...
You know, the cats,
they run away all the time.
You know, my aunt,
she had a cat,
ran away,
showed up three years later.
You never know.
They got things in their brains
where they can remember
where they're from.
Unless, of course,
somebody else
starts feeding her.
See, that's what
you got to worry about.
Ah.
Once again,
Antonio,
I can't even begin to say
how deeply, deeply sorry
I am about everything.
The job... the cat...
The lamp.
There's wire sticking out.
Yeah?
Here's my card.
Uh, I'm in real estate,
so if you're ever looking
for something bigger,
something nicer...
Maybe not right away.
Anyway, heh...
You ought to get
that wire fixed.
Uh, I got the door.
George, stop worrying
about this guy.
It wasn't your fault.
Come on. He's not stalking you.
Hey.
He doesn't even know
where you live.
Who told you to give him
your business card?
That's Elaine.
Kramer...
George wants to know
when you want to go
look for the cat again.
Well, it's been a week.
It's up to the cat now.
Kramer says
it's up to the cat now.
It'll be on your conscience.
Oh? How do you figure?
How do you figure?
Because you're the one
that left the door open.
Why was I in charge
of closing the door?
Why was he in charge
Because you came in after him.
So?
So the last person in
should close the door.
Let me talk to him.
Call... Call him
from your house.
He's calling you now.
Okay.
Ed's downstairs.
Can I have the car keys?
No hello?
You got any aspirin?
Hello.
Now, lookit,
you guarantee me
this car's gonna get me
to the airport
tomorrow, no problem?
Guarantee?
Hey, it's a car.
Because if there's even
the slightest chance
of any problem at all,
I don't want to take it,
because if I don't get this guy
on a plane to Seattle,
and out of my life,
I'm going to kill him
and anyone who tries to stop me.
So, did you have
a nice week together?
I heard a little ping
in the car the last time.
What was that ping?
There's no ping.
Why are you so wacky?
Oh, Jerry.
You cannot imagine how
much I hate this guy,
and he hasn't even
done anything.
It's the situation.
He's a wonderful guy,
but I hate his guts.
Have you two been, uh....
No!
I told him
I've been having my period
the last five days.
I'm sleeping all squished over
on the edge of my bed,
but I've only got
14 hours to go,
and nothing can go wrong now.
I think I've taken care
of everything.
I've confirmed
the plane reservation,
I've checked the weather.
What's your airport route?
Mm. I've got it
all mapped out.
I'm taking the tunnel.
What about the Van Wyck?
I spoke to a cab driver.
For 5 bucks, he turned me onto
the Rockaway Boulevard shortcut.
Ooh.
This plane
leaves at 10:15.
We're getting up
at about 8:00.
That gives us
enough time, right?
Are you still using
that same old alarm clock?
Oh, no, no, I bought
a new one today.
It's got everything.
If you oversleep
more than 10 minutes,
a hand comes out
and slaps you in the face.
Flying doesn't make me nervous.
Driving to the airport, uh,
can make you very nervous
because, when you're flying,
when you're getting on a plane,
If you miss that plane,
there's no alternative.
On the ground, you have options.
You have buses,
you have taxis, you have trains.
But when you're taking a flight,
if you miss it, that's it.
No airline goes,
"Well, you missed the flight.
"We do have a cannon leaving
in about 10 minutes.
"Think you'd be interested
in that?
"It's not a direct cannon.
"You have to change cannons
after you land.
"I'm sorry,
where are you going, Chicago?
"Oh, Dallas. All right.
Wait a second.
"That's about Dallas.
Texas, anyway.
"You should hit Texas.
Are you ready?
"Make sure you get out
of the net immediately,
because we shoot the luggage in
right after you."
Get up!
The alarm didn't go off.
It's 9:15!
You're gonna miss the plane.
It's 9:15?
Yes. Yeah. It's 9:15.
Mm. We'll never
make it.
I'll leave tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Are you crazy?
No. Now, now, let's go.
Let's go.
Let's go. You get dressed.
You get dressed.
Can I shower?
Shower?
Are you out of your mind?
Well, I gotta shower.
I'll feel dirty all day.
Forget the shower.
The shower's out.
Just move it.
Put your clothes on.
Where are you going?
I'm going to the kitchen.
The kitchen?
Got a bag of cashews in there.
No, they're not in the kitchen.
They're not in the kitchen.
Here, put your pants on.
What's the big deal?
Put your pants on!
I'll go tomorrow
or the next day.
No, you've got your ticket.
You have to go now.
We'll never make it.
Don't say that.
Well, it takes
45 minutes to g...
It takes 45 minutes
to get there.
That'll only leave me
five minutes
to get to the plane.
Shut up and pack!
And then what if
I don't make the plane?
You'll have already left,
then what do I do?
Oh, you're talking too much.
Where's my sweater?
What?
My brown sweater.
What? What sweater?
My brown sweater!
What? You didn't bring
a brown sweater.
I had a brown sweater!
Here. Here!
You want a sweater?
You want a brown sweater?
You got a brown sweater.
That's not mine.
I can't take your sweater.
It's brown!
What are you doing?
No, there's no time for folding.
There's no time for folding.
I think that's it.
My shoes, you packed my shoes!
Shoes? Shoes?
Shoes weren't invented
until the 4th century.
People walked around
for thousands of years
without them!
Let's go. Let's go!
Anywhere in the city?
Anywhere in the city,
I'll tell you
the best public toilets.
Okay.
54th and 6th.
Sperry Rand Building,
14th floor, Morgan Apparel.
Mention my name,
she'll give you the key.
All right. 65th and 10th.
Are you kidding?
Lincoln Center,
Alice Tully Hall, the Met.
Magnificent facilities. Come on.
I never knew
I could drive like that.
I was going faster
than I've ever gone before.
Yet it all seemed
to be happening in slow motion.
I was seeing
three and four moves ahead,
weaving in and out of lanes
like an Olympic skier
on a gold-medal run.
I knew I was challenging
the very laws of physics.
At Queens Boulevard,
I took the shoulder.
At Jewel Avenue,
I used the median.
I had it. I was there.
And then...
I hit the Van Wyck.
They say no one's ever
beaten the Van Wyck...
but, gentlemen, I tell you this:
I came as close
as anyone ever has,
And if it hadn't been
for that five-car pileup
on Rockaway Boulevard,
that numbskull...
would be on a plane for Seattle
right now...
instead of looking
for a parking space
downstairs.
Oh.
There, there.
Hey, the busboy's coming.
The busboy's coming!
The busboy's coming?
You don't mean here?
Yeah. I just buzzed him in.
He's on his way up.
He's coming up?
Check you out later.
Where are you going?
He's coming to settle the score.
No, you three
all know each other.
There's no point
in me getting involved
at this stage of the game...
He's not going to do anything.
I guarantee it.
Oh, the hell with it!
Let him kill me. I... I...
Antonio!
Antonio, in here.
Hey, Antonio, how's it going?
Three nights ago...
A gas main
beneath the restaurant exploded,
killing five people
in my section,
Including the busboy
who replaced me.
I... I... I... I...
If I'm not fired that night
because of you
and your thoughtless,
stupid, insensitive remarks,
it would have been me.
You saved my life!
Come on...
Yeah?
It's Eddie.
He's coming up.
And the very same night
of the accident,
while looking for Paquita,
I find a job in a restaurant
Where they pay me almost twice
what I was making before.
And...
when I returned
to the apartment,
Paquita, perhaps
frightened from the explosion,
had miraculously returned.
Well...
Now I must go.
For today, I am starting
my new and wonderful job,
and I am... I am very late.
Thank you.
Thank you all.
Hey, watch where you're going.
You almost knocked my head off.
Hey, why don't you
watch where you're going, okay?
Because you bumped into me.
Who do you think
you're talking to, pal?
Hey, get your hands off me!
You go to hell!
He'll get another job.
He's a busboy.
It won't be for a while.
At least not till
after the cast comes off.
It was that fall down
the stairs, that's what did it.
That's not how it happened.
It's when he fell on him
with his knee.
Ugh. That was awful.
Poor Antonio.
Oh. Thanks.
So... much longer?
Till when?
Till he goes back to Seattle,
or till he can feed himself?
I guess it's not important.
Take care of yourselves.
I should probably get going too.
If I don't feed Paquita by 7:00,
she goes all over everything.
Mm.
Take it easy.
Yeah.
How are you doing?
First of all, I can't believe
that people actually do fight.
People have fistfights in life.
And I can't really believe
we have boxing, either.
It's really
kind of an amazing thing.
To me, the problem with boxing
is you have two guys
having a fight
that have no prior argument.
Why don't they have the boxers
come into the ring
in little cars,
drive around a little bit,
have a little accident,
they get out...
"Did you see my signal?
Look at that fender!"
Then you'd see a real fight.