My parents live in Florida now.
They moved there last year.
They didn't want
to move to Florida,
but they're in their 60s,
and that's the law.
You know how it works.
They got the leisure police.
They pull up in front
of the old people's house
with the golf cart,
jump out, "Let's go, Pop!
"White belt, white pants,
white shoes!
"Get in the back!
Drop the snow shovel!
Right there! Drop it!"
I am not much
for the family gathering.
You ever sit there,
and the conversation's
so boring, it's so dull?
And you start to fantasize.
You know, you think,
what if I just... got up
and jumped out that window?
Just crash right through
the glass, you know?
Come back in.
There's broken glass,
everybody's all upset.
"No, I'm all right.
I was a little bored there.
"No, I'm fine. I came back.
I wanted to hear a little more
"about that Hummel collection,
Aunt Rose.
Let's pick it up right there."
You have so many nice jackets,
I don't know why you had
to bring this jacket.
Who wears a jacket like this?
What's wrong with
that nice gray one?
You have beautiful clothes.
They sit in your closet.
Morty, you can't wear this.
Are you getting that?
I thought you were getting it.
Should I pick up?
Do you want me to get that?
I'll get it!
Hello?
Hi.
Would you make this thing lower?
I can hear it on the street.
Hey, Jer, how did you do?
We won. I made an incredible
play in the field.
It was a tag-up at third base.
I threw the guy out
from left field on a fly.
We'll be in
the championship game Wednesday
because of me.
It was the single
greatest moment in my life.
This is your greatest moment,
a game?
Well, no. Uh...
Sharon Besser, of course.
You know what my greatest moment
was, don't you?
1946. I went to work
for Harry Flemming...
and I came up with the idea
for the beltless trench coat.
Jerry,
look at this sport jacket.
Is this a jacket
to wear to an anniversary party?
Well, the man's
an individualist.
He worked for Harry Flemming.
He knows what he's doing.
But it's their 50th anniversary.
Your mother doesn't like
my taste in clothing.
You know, I spoke
to Manya and Isaac
on the phone today.
They invited you again.
I think you should go.
First of all,
I made plans with Elaine.
So bring her.
I don't even know them.
What is she, a second cousin?
I mean, I met them
three times in my life.
I don't know her either.
She made me fly
from Florida for this,
and then she criticizes
my jacket.
At least come and say hello,
have a cup of coffee,
then you leave.
How come he gets to leave?
If I wind up sitting
next to uncle Leo, I am leaving.
He's always grabbing my arm
when he talks to me.
I guess it's because
so many people have left
in the middle
of his conversation.
And it's always
about Jeffrey, right?
Yeah. He talks about him
like he split the atom.
The kid works
for the Parks department.
Morty, you coming in?
Oh, yeah!
I forgot all about it.
Hey. How'd you do?
We won. We're in
the finals on Wednesday.
Yeah!
What is this about?
I'm completely changing
the configuration
of the apartment.
You're not going to believe it
when you see it.
Whole new lifestyle.
What are you doing?
Levels.
Levels?
Yeah. I'm getting rid
of all my furniture,
all of it,
and I'm going to build
these different levels.
You know, with steps.
And it will all be carpeted.
A lot of pillows.
You know, like ancient Egypt.
Hmm.
You drew up plans for this?
No, no, it's all in my head.
I don't see how you can get
comfortable like that.
Oh, I'll get comfortable.
When do you intend to do this?
Oh, should be done by
the end of the month.
You're going
to do this yourself?
It's a simple job.
Why? You don't
think I can, huh?
Oh, no. It's not
that I don't think you can.
I know that you can't,
and I'm positive that you won't.
Well, I got the tools,
I got the pillows,
all I need is the lumber.
Hey, that's some big job.
I don't see it happening.
Yeah, well, this time...
This time, you're wrong.
Come on, I'll even bet you.
Seriously?
I don't want you betting.
Morty, don't let them bet.
A big dinner, with dessert,
but I got till
the end of the month.
I'll give you a year.
No, no...
No, no, no. A month.
End of the month.
It's a bet.
Seriously,
do you want to switch chairs?
No, no.
I'm fine.
Oh, Jerry,
you listening to this?
Yeah, Uncle Leo.
So...
So now the Parks commissioner
is recommending Jeffrey
for a citation.
Right, for the, uh,
reducing of the pond scum?
No, no, no.
For the walking tours.
Oh, yeah, where the people
eat the plant life,
the edible-foliage tour.
That's exactly right.
He knows the whole
history of the park.
For two hours, he's talking
and answering questions.
But you want to know something?
Whenever he has a problem
with one of these
high-powered big shots
from the Parks department,
you know who he calls?
Mickey Mantle?
Jerry. Jerry.
Did you taste these peas?
These... These peas
are great.
These peas are bursting
with country-fresh flavor.
Mm, phenomenal peas.
Mm.
Are you ready for dessert?
Well, actually, we do have
to kind of get going.
You're going?
Oh, uh, I don't
really eat dessert.
I'm dieting.
Yeah, I can't
eat dessert either.
The sugar makes
my ankles swell up
and I can't dance.
Can't dance?
He's kidding, Manya.
Is that a joke?
So did you hear
Claire's getting married?
Yeah, yeah.
I hear the fellow
owns a couple race horses.
You know, trotters,
like at Yonkers.
Horses.
They're like big riding dogs.
What about ponies, huh?
What kind of
abnormal animal is that?
And those kids
who had their own ponies...
I know, I hated those kids.
In fact, I hate anyone
that ever had a pony
when they were growing up.
I had a pony.
Well, I didn't,
uh, really mean a pony per se.
When I was
a little girl in Poland,
we all had ponies.
My sister had pony.
My cousin had pony.
So, what's wrong with that?
Nothing. Nothing at all.
I was just merely expressing...
Should we have some coffee?
Who's having coffee?
He was a beautiful pony.
And I loved him.
Well, I'm sure you did.
Who wouldn't love a pony?
Who wouldn't love a person
that had a pony?
You.
You said so.
No, see, we didn't have ponies.
I'm sure at that time in Poland,
they were very common.
They were probably
like compact cars.
That's it!
I had enough!
Have your coffee, everybody.
She's a little upset.
It's been an emotional day.
I didn't know she had a pony.
How was I to know
she had a pony?
Who figures an immigrant's
gonna have a pony?
Do you know
what the odds are on that?
I mean,
in all the pictures I saw
of immigrants on boats
coming into New York harbor,
I never saw one of them
sitting on a pony.
Why would anyone come here
if they had a pony?
Who leaves a country
packed with ponies
to come to
a non-pony country?
It doesn't make sense.
Am I wrong?
I'll drive you to the airport.
No, we're taking a cab.
I just hope
that the whole pony incident
didn't put a damper on the trip.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
It was a misunderstanding.
Hey, I agree with him.
Nobody likes a kid with a pony.
Well, if you ever talk to her,
tell her I'm sorry.
Elaine too.
She feels terrible.
You know, you should
give Manya a call.
Maybe I will.
Oh, hey.
Hey.
I, uh, just came to say goodbye.
Need any help with those?
Oh, it's nothing.
I got it.
So, how are your levels
coming along?
Uh, well, I decided
I'm not going to do it.
Really?
What a shock.
Goodbye, Jerry.
Take care.
We'll call you.
Bye, Jer.
Bye, Dad, take it easy.
Bye, Mr. Kramer.
Yeah, so long, Morty.
So... when do I get
my dinner?
There's no dinner.
The bet's off.
I'm not going to do it.
Yes, I know
you're not gonna do it,
that's why I bet.
There's no bet
if I'm not doing it.
That's the bet,
that you're not doing it.
Yeah, well, I could do it,
I don't want to do it.
We didn't bet on
if you wanted to do it,
we bet on if it would be done.
And it could be done.
Well, of course,
it could be done.
Anything could be done,
but it only is done
if it's done.
Show me the levels.
The bet is the levels.
I don't want the levels.
That's the bet!
Man!
Hello.
No.
Oh, hi.
No, they just left.
Oh, my God.
Hang on a second.
Maybe I can still catch them.
Ma! Ma, up here!
Don't get in the cab!
Manya died!
Who'd you talk to?
Uncle Leo.
And when's the funeral?
I don't know.
He said he'd call back.
You know what this means,
don't you?
We lost the supersaver.
Those tickets are nonrefundable.
She just had a check-up.
The doctor said she was fine.
Unless...
What?
Nothing.
You don't think...
What, the pony remark?
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
She was an old woman.
You don't think I killed her?
You know what that flight back
will cost us?
It was an innocent comment.
I didn't know she had a pony.
Maybe we could get
an Army transport flight.
They got a base in Sarasota,
I think.
I mean, the whole thing
was taken out of context.
It was a joke.
That's probably Uncle Leo.
Hello?
Yes, I know.
Well, it's just
one of those things.
Sure, sure.
We'll see you then.
The funeral's Wednesday.
Wednesday?
What...? What Wednesday?
2:00, Wednesday.
Ah...
What?
I got the softball game
on Wednesday.
It's the championship.
So you're not obligated.
Go play in your game.
I didn't even know the woman.
So don't go.
I mean, I met her three times.
I don't even know her last name.
Jerry, no one's forcing you.
I mean, who has a funeral
on a Wednesday?
That's what I want to know.
I mean, it's the championship.
I'm hitting everything.
I don't have a dress to wear.
And you,
you don't have anything.
I got my sport jacket.
You're not wearing
that to a funeral.
What's wrong with it?
It looks ridiculous.
What, I'm going to buy
a new sport jacket now?
I don't know what to do.
You know what this funeral
is going to wind up costing me?
Oh, boy.
We don't understand death,
and the proof of this
is that we give dead people
a pillow.
And, I mean, hey, you know,
I think if you can't stretch out
and get
some solid rest at that point,
I don't see
how bedding accessories
really make the difference.
I mean, they got the guy
in a suit with a pillow.
Now, is he going to a meeting,
or is he catching 40 winks?
I mean, let's make up our mind
where we think they're going.
I actually like ponies.
I was just trying
to make conversation.
What time is your game?
2:45.
And what time is the funeral?
Two o'clock.
How long does a funeral take?
Depends on how nice
the person was,
but you got to figure
even Oswald took 45 minutes.
So you can't do both.
You know, if the situation
were reversed
and Manya had some
mahjong championship,
or something,
I wouldn't expect her
to go to my funeral.
I would understand.
How can you even
consider not going?
You know, I've been thinking.
I cannot envision
any circumstance
in which I'll ever have
the opportunity
to have sex again.
How's it going to happen?
I just don't see
how it could occur.
You know, funerals
always make me think
about my own mortality
and how I'm actually
going to die some day.
Me, dead.
Huh, imagine that.
They always make me
take stock of my life
and how I've pretty much
wasted all of it.
and how I plan
to continue wasting it.
I know, and then
you say to yourself,
"From this moment on,
I'm not wasting any more of it."
But then you go, "How?
I mean, what can I do
that's not wasting it?"
Well, is this a waste of time?
What should we be doing?
Can't you have
coffee with people?
You know, I can't believe
you're even considering
not playing.
We need you.
You're hitting everything.
He has to go.
He may have killed her.
Me? What about you?
You brought up the pony.
Oh, yeah,
but I didn't say
I hated anyone who had one.
Who's going to play left field?
Bender?
Bender? He can't play left.
He stinks.
I just don't see what purpose
it's going to serve, you going.
I mean, you think dead people
care who's at their funeral?
They don't even know
they're having a funeral.
It's not like she's hanging out
in the back going,
"I can't believe
Jerry didn't show up."
Maybe she's there in spirit.
How about that?
If you're a spirit,
and you can travel to other
dimensions and galaxies,
and find out
the mysteries of the universe,
you think she's gonna want
to hang out
at Drexler's funeral home
on Ocean Parkway?
George, I met this woman.
She is not traveling
to any other dimensions.
Do you know how easy it is
for dead people to travel?
It's not like getting on a bus.
One second.
It's all mental.
50 years they were married.
Now he's moving to Phoenix.
Phoenix?
What's happening
with his apartment?
I don't know.
They've been in there
since, like, World War II.
Rent's $300 a month.
Three hundred a month?
Oh, my God.
Although this may seem
like a sad event,
it should not be
a day of mourning,
for Manya had
a rich, fulfilling life.
She grew up
in a different world,
a simpler world,
with loving parents,
a beautiful home in the country,
and, from what I understand,
she even had a pony.
Oh, how she loved that pony.
Even in her declining years,
whenever she would speak of it,
her eyes would light up.
Its lustrous coat,
its flowing mane.
It was the pride of Crakow.
Well, the game's starting
just about now.
It was good that
the two of you came.
It was a nice gesture.
I'm not a doctor yet,
Uncle Morty.
I'm just an intern.
I can't write a note
to an airline.
You got your degree.
They don't care.
They just want to see something.
I just wanted to say
how sorry I was.
Jerry, you want
to hear something?
Your cousin Jeffrey
is switching parks.
They're transferring him
to Riverside,
so he'll completely revamp
that operation.
You understand?
Yeah.
He'll do in Riverside now
what he did in Central Park.
More money.
So... that's your cousin.
You don't understand.
I've never paid full fare.
Once again, I just wanted to say
how sorry I am
about the other night.
Oh, me too.
No, no, no.
She forgot all about that.
She was much more upset
about the potato salad.
So I understand
you're moving to Phoenix.
Yeah.
My brother lives there.
I think Manya
would have liked Phoenix.
Mm. Gorgeous,
exquisite town.
So, what's happening
with your apartment?
Of course, it's very hot there.
I'll have to get
an air conditioner.
Oh, you can have mine.
I'll ship it out to you.
But what about
that big apartment
on West End Avenue?
Although they say
it's a dry heat.
Dry, wet.
What's happening
with your apartment?
I don't even know
if I should take
my winter clothing.
I have an idea.
Leave the winter clothing
in the apartment,
and I'll watch it for you,
and I'll live there,
and I'll make sure
that nothing happens to it.
Oh, the apartment.
Jeffrey's taking the apartment.
Oh, Jeffrey.
You know Jeffrey.
Yeah, from what I understand,
he works
for the Parks department.
It's raining.
It's raining?
The game will be postponed.
We'll play tomorrow.
Believe me,
I wouldn't bother you
if the Army hadn't closed
that base in Sarasota.
Here, scribble
a little something here.
I can't.
I'll get in trouble.
Oh, for God's sake.
Who gets picked off in softball?
It's unheard of.
Never happened to me before.
I remember saying to myself,
"Why is Jerry
so far off the base?"
I'll have to live
with this shame
for the rest of my life.
Then in the fifth inning,
why did you take off
on the pop fly?
I thought there were two outs.
I couldn't believe it
when I saw you running.
I thought maybe they had
changed the rules or something.
It was the single
worst moment of my life.
What about Sharon Besser?
Oh, well, of course, 1973.
Makes you wonder,
though, doesn't it?
Wonder about what?
You know.
The spirit world.
What, you think Manya
showed up during the game
and put a hex on me?
I never saw anyone
play like that.
But I went to the funeral.
Yeah, but that doesn't
make up for killing her.
Maybe Manya missed the funeral
because she was off visiting
another galaxy that day.
Don't you think she would
have heard I was there?
Not necessarily.
Who figures an immigrant's
going to have a pony?
What is the pony?
What is the point of the pony?
Why do we have these animals,
these ponies?
What do we do with them,
besides the pony ride?
Why ponies?
What are we doing with them?
I mean, police don't use them
for, you know, crowd control.
"Hey, uh, you want to get back
behind the barricades?
"Hey.
"Hey, little boy.
"Yeah, I'm talking to you.
Just... Behind the barricades."
So somebody, I assume,
genetically engineered
these ponies.
Do you think they could
make them any size?
Could they make them,
like, the size of a quarter
if they wanted?
That would be fun for Monopoly,
though, wouldn't it?
Just have a little pony,
and you put him on the...
"Baltic.
That's two down, go ahead.
"Hold it.
Right there, Baltic.
Yeah, fine. Right there.
Hold it right there."