Sold, ladies and gentlemen,
to Ms. Veronica Vreeland for $200,000.
Bored? We've only been
here 10 minutes.
Ten minutes for you,
10 hours for me.
I know it's for a good cause, but...
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
this magnificent timepiece
from the reign of Louis XVI.
Who will start the bidding at $400,000?
You've gotta be kidding.
I wouldn't use that for a doorstop.
Right on time, as usual.
I have a bid of $500,000.
Do I hear $550,000?
Good afternoon.
Have they sold the Louis XVI yet?
No, the bidding just started.
How did you...
I gotta see my optometrist.
I have a bid of $585,000. Do I hear six?
Come, come. This is a one-of-a-kind item
ladies and gentlemen. Who'll give six?
Six hundred thousand.
Six hundred thousand?
I've heard that time is money,
but this is ridiculous.
Like you said, it's for charity.
I have $600,000 from Mr. Bruce Wayne.
Do I hear $650,000?
Need I remind you, this timepiece
was once owned by Marie Antoinette.
Relax, Dick. It's almost over.
You're not gonna believe this,
but I thought I just saw the Clock King.
Well, he was there.
I have $650,000. Going, going, gone.
Blimey!
A trial run, and it went like clockwork.
Hmm. Got one.
I have $650,000. Going, going, gone.
Blimey!
Back up.
There. Freeze it.
That must be the hand
everyone talks about.
The one that's quicker than the eye.
So we don't have
another invisible man running loose.
Then who could it be?
I think it's Temple Fugate,
the Clock King.
What makes you think that?
Let's just call it a hunch.
Better warn Mayor Hill, Jim.
I doubt that time has healed
Fugate's wound.
6:15, sir. Time for breakfast.
I've also brought you your medicine
and the timer
so you can take your pills on schedule.
You think of everything,
don't you, Harold?
It is my job, sir.
How goes your research, if I may ask?
Well enough.
The iron ball has dropped
a mere tenth of a millimeter
since the experiment began last week.
An extreme temporal discontinuity.
And the accelerated effect
is just as dramatic.
Five minutes ago, that plant was a seed.
Amazing, Dr. Wakati.
Why, the possible applications
are mind-boggling.
Indeed.
We could get rid of radioactive waste
in minutes instead of eons
put terminally ill people in stasis
until a cure is found.
The question is, is mankind civilized
enough to make the proper use of it?
You're right, Doctor.
It's very important that this device
be kept in the right hands.
I hope you're having
a pleasant evening, Mr. Mayor,
because it's time for you and me
to renew our acquaintance.
It's going to be a big ceremony, Jim.
Fugate? No, I'm not worried.
I've got a platoon of officers
around the building.
He can't get in the door
without bumping into a blue coat.
He's still on the phone.
You really think our guy will show up?
Sure as night follows day.
What am I thinking?
Going to be a nasty fall, dearie.
What the...
Ah!
I think that's our cue.
You! How did you get past...
Good evening, Mayor.
Nice to see you again too.
And whose life are you ruining now?
A poor pensioner,
a malnourished orphan perhaps?
Naughty, naughty.
What?
Where did you...
I don't think so.
Even if you could climb the building,
you won't be leaving this way,
Mr. Mayor.
I've waited a long time for this.
Please, Fugate, don't hurt me.
If it's any comfort, my revenge
will encompass more than just you.
I intend to pass a most timely sentence
on the entire judicial system.
Get ready.
My eyes!
Robin. Grab the hypo.
Get off me.
What?
You clumsy...
You...
Hey, you. Stop!
Look. Over there. That's him.
Let's get him.
- Come on.
- Stop.
- Hold it right there.
- You're under arrest.
- Don't move.
- Freeze.
The Batmobile.
Ah!
- Hey!
- Where'd he go?
- Look out.
- Hey, watch it.
It was like a nightmare.
First he was here, then there.
My heavens.
If you hadn't set that trap...
Well, at least we've got the pieces
from Fugate's broken thingamajig.
Maybe we can find out how he made it.
I don't think Fugate made that device.
He's not a scientist.
Well, we'll soon find out who did.
All our patrol cars are equipped
with tracking devices.
We should be able
to run Fugate down pretty quickly.
Harold.
What are you doing in my room?
I called for you but got no answer.
I thought something might be wrong.
There is something wrong, old man.
Why are you wearing that?
I'm afraid I haven't been
altogether candid with you.
What... What are you going to do?
You'll find out, my good doctor,
all in good time.
I want a dragnet over
a five-mile radius.
He couldn't have gotten far.
With any luck, time is on our side.
You think the police will find him?
Doubtful, but I have an idea.
With his knowledge of train schedules
He would know when the next
commuter run would pass.
It's no accident
that he ditched the car where he did.
Only one train passed there in the last
six hours, heading for the mountains.
I don't get it.
There's nothing out that way.
Nothing except Cranston Estates.
So you say this guy
lives out there?
What's his name, this Professor Wataki?
Wakati. He's the father
of quantum temporal theory,
the structure of time.
What's going on?
Fugate's booby-trapped the car.
We're trapped in time.
What's going on?
We've been put in a bubble of slow time.
The outside world is moving
much faster than we are.
Look.
Hours are passing like minutes.
Why didn't the car's sensors
pick up the booby trap?
He probably set it just a nanosecond
or two out of phase with reality.
But that's the least of our problems.
E still equals MC squared, last I heard.
Mass increases with speed.
If a car hits us
while we're frozen like this,
we might trigger an atomic explosion.
There it is.
Hey!
Nearly as I can figure,
we've lost almost 48 hours.
Then we'd better not
waste any more time.
I think we've found the professor.
How do we get him out?
Same way we got ourselves out.
Don't, Harold.
Batman?
Just make sure nobody fiddles
with the props.
No problem.
He was the one person
in the world I trusted.
Is it any wonder I prefer
being a recluse?
What else did he say, Dr. Wakati?
He was babbling.
Said something about the Mayor,
about how he was finally
going to get his day in court.
Day in court?
The new courthouse.
The Mayor is dedicating
it today at 10:00.
That's two minutes from now.
We'd better call the cops and...
You can't. I have no phones.
Your phone won't work, Batman.
This area is a dead zone.
I chose it so my experiments would
be free of electromagnetic interference.
It'll take at least a half hour for us
to make it back on the bikes.
You have 30 seconds to show us
how to use these.
Wow, faster than a speeding bullet.
And so, my friends,
it is my privilege
to officially bring Gotham City's
new courthouse to order.
By all means, Mr. Mayor,
usher the new building in with a bang.
This could be dangerous.
Better stand back.
Oh, to savor the moment
as long as possible.
No. It can't be.
Too late. It's triggered.
Slow down.
Looks like time just ran out.
It's a shame that you've decided
to keep this device a secret.
It would seem that the world
is not quite ready for it yet.
Gee, that's too bad for Fugate.
I'm sure he'll wish he had something
to make the days pass quicker
where he's going.