Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
At last, my quest has come to an end.
Not so fast, samurai!
Aku!
Your efforts are in vain, samurai.
This gateway into the past is forever...
...beyond your reach!
Poor samurai.
Once more you failed!
As you lie smashed and defeated...
...so lie your hopes of going home.
Till we meet again.
Sorry.
What sort of creature are you?
l man like you.
l have never seen man fly.
l no fly.
Jump good.
-Jump really good.
-Yeah.
Can you teach me to jump good?
Tribe show me.
l show you tribe.
Tribe show you how jump good.
There!
Tribe.
You are one of these creatures?
No, l man.
-Then how?
-They raise me.
They say long ago l with other tribe.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Keep moving.
They say I stray from tribe.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Keep moving.
And so l became new member of tribe.
And as you see, whole tribe jump good.
So l jump good.
Yes.
Danger. Must hide!
What?
l'm sorry.
That is not your food.
Leave here, and you will not be hurt.
-Who are they?
-Other tribe.
Why do you not defend what's yours?
We peaceful like flower.
Know not how to protect ourselves.
Other tribe take food, smash home,
never leave us alone!
We pick up pieces,
replant somewhere else.
We scared.
Now, like before,
we find new home.
l could show you how
to defend yourselves...
...how to protect what is yours.
And we show you to jump good.
They agree.
We learn to protect and defend.
-And they will show me to jump good?
-No.
l mean yes.
Let's do it.
Let's do it!
You jump good.
Thank you, friend,
for everything you have shown me.
Friend.
Hungry? Here food.
Still hungry? Here more.
Take it!
Never come again.
-Aku!
-Samurai fool.
Your efforts are in vain again.
This gateway to the past
is once more beyond your rea--
You can fly?
No. Jump good.
[ENGLlSH]