Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
What happened here?
They came from nowhere.
They left as mysteriously as they came.
To the east. They left to the east.
They appeared out of nowhere.
First came explosions.
We tried to defend ourselves.
But our attempts were futile.
And then there was fire.
We didn,t stand a chance.
They were relentless.
They destroyed the city. All of it.
Then left as mysteriously as they came.
Madness. This senseless destruction
must be stopped.
They, they, they...
...left to the--
To the east.
Hello!
ls there no end
to this senseless destruction?
Why? Why did you destroy
all of those villages?
To lure you to us. To draw you out.
-What?
-Yes. We have been hunting you.
We have come to destroy you.
Your search is over. Come and get me.
Run. Run. Run!
You can't hide forever.
-Who's there?
-l am Extor...
-...the one who created those monsters.
-What?
l set out to construct the ultimate assassins
to hunt you down and destroy you.
I worked tirelessly day and night until
my machines of doom were completed.
Each were designed with a unique tool
of destruction.
Countless days were spent analyzing
your fighting technique.
They were the deadliest war machines
ever created.
And their power source came from
the world,s most ultimate evil:
Aku.
You have outdone yourself, Extor.
Now to test their power of destruction.
-Test them? How?
-By destroying your village.
No. You can't. We had an agreement.
Fool! Now, my children, destroy.
No, no, no!
Aku promised to spare my village
if l would build the assassins for him.
l was a fool to trust him.
Now l want to correct my mistake.
l want to destroy my creations.
And with your help,
the assassins can be defeated.
l'm sorry. But l cannot help you.
What?
Your creations are too powerful.
Any form of attack that l attempted failed.
The blade of my ancient sword cannot
cut through the futuristic technology...
...that you have created.
lt seems Aku has finally won.
Wait, wait, wait.
-Your sword can cut them.
-What?
Of course, on your own
you are not strong enough...
...to cut through
their adamantium metal.
But with my last scientific invention,
you can cut through them like butter.
-What is it?
-Well, quite simply...
...it's a cybernetic,
synaptically linked...
...dino-dexteric, isometric poly-duritanium
power gauntlet.
How will this help me?
You see, this arm will enhance
your strength...
...to give enough power to cut
through any metal...
...even the adamantium
that the assassins are built of.
With your skill and this arm,
you are the only one who can defeat them.
Will you help now?
Yes, l will help.
-High-five.
-What?
-l do not understand.
Never mind.
We see you have made
some modifications.
Altering your original combat chassis
will not help you.
-Do not prolong the inevitable.
-Enough.
Yes!
Wow! Hey, watch it.
Oh, no. The power is drained.
You are no match, samurai.
Fool. Your sword does not match
the power of Aku.
Wrong. This sword carries the history
and strength of my people.
lts power is immeasurable.
Great ancestors, hear my plea.
What are you doing?
lf l am worthy,
grant me the strength...
...to vanquish this evil abomination
and send it back to--
Jack!
Jack, snap out of it.
l honor all who trust me.
My cause is worthy, great ancestors.
Jack!
Let my sword be your instrument
of justice.
All too easy.
Unbelievable.
Yes!
The sword. The samurai.
High-five.
[ENGLlSH]