Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
We are free.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving us...
...from the tyranny of the Cossacks.
Can it be?
My home.
Father. Mother.
Well, look what l found.
Almost.
Dry your tears, my son...
...for nothing worth having
is easily attained.
Sometimes you must fight
for what is yours...
...and for what you believe in.
Remember, my son...
...it is not one's outward brawn...
...but rather one's inner strength
that makes them mighty.
What was that?
Hey, where's the ball?
Help!
Help, anyone!
Help! Our village is being attacked.
You must help us!
[ENGLlSH]