Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
This land.
The land of the magic worm.
Legend has it the worm can grant
any wish.
My wish:
To return to the past.
Worm, l summon you.
-Who beckons me?
-l do.
-Jack.
-You know of me?
Of course l do. l'm magic.
Magical, isn't it?
You've come for a magic wish,
haven't you?
Yes. l--
lt's not that simple.
You see, only one of us
is the real magic worm.
And you're going to have to guess--
-Which one--
-ls which.
-Then l get my magic wish?
-Not quite--
Big boy.
Either one you choose gets to eat you.
Eat me? What magic is that?
Let me explain.
lf you guess right, you will be transported
to a magical place...
...where your innermost desire
will be granted.
But if you guess wrong,
you'll be digested for 500 years.
-So all l have to do is guess?
-That's right.
No, wrong. You have to play
a little game.
Smashing idea.
Oh, jolly.
Knock-knock.
-You're supposed to say, ''Who's there?''
-Who is there?
Banana.
Now you say, ''Banana who?''
-Knock-knock.
-Who's there?
-Banana.
-Banana who?
-Knock-knock.
-Who's there?
-Banana.
-Banana who?
No, wait. Scratch that. Try again.
Knock-knock.
-Who's there?
-Now you're asking the questions.
Okay, you start.
-Knock-knock.
-Who's there?
-Enough.
-Okay, we'll ask you a question.
What's your favorite color?
-What trick is this?
-No trick.
Answer it.
-Blue?
-Wrong.
l mean red. Red.
-Too late.
-Final question.
-Very well.
-One of us tells only lies.
The other tells only truths.
By asking us only one question...
...you must decide which
is the real magic worm.
-Only one.
My question will be--
Yes?
lf you were your brother, which one would
you say is the magic worm?
-Which one are you asking?
-lt doesn't matter.
-That's easy. lt's him.
-Of course, it's me.
Then l choose you.
He knows.
What made you choose me?
l told you it was him.
Yes, me.
lf you were the truth-telling one,
what you said is a lie.
You will answer truthfully
what your lying brother will say.
So l can say the answer will be
the opposite of what you say.
But if you're the lying
worm...
...you'll say what your truthful
brother will say. But it'd be a lie.
So the answer will also be
the opposite of what you say.
Understand?
-We--
-Of course.
Go on, sir.
Hey, don't hog it all.
Little did he know we're both liars.
Magic? l haven't done that since
l was a little larva.
When does the magic begin?
There's no magic, is there?
Excuse me.
We heard a noise coming from over here.
How did--? Where did you come from?
My family and l have been lost
in these woods for a very long time.
You must be very hungry.
Yes, we are very hungry.
You are welcome to share my food.
That is very kind. Thank you.
Our village was attacked and destroyed
by robot bandits.
We were one of the few families
who were lucky to escape.
We have been hiding in these woods,
hoping the bandits wouldn't find us.
lt has been a long time
since we have eaten.
But it seems like luck has looked kindly
upon us once more.
l am sorry. l wish l would have found
your village earlier.
l might have been able to help.
Be careful.
This sword is very sharp.
You can hurt yourself.
The food is ready.
l have been able to find
some good--
My sword.
Get him!
This is not your--
Give us the food,
and your life will be spared.
You mean my sword?
Hungry?
Come get some.
That smell.
lt smells like...
...metal.
What's going on?
Why are you looking at me like this?
What are you doing?
It is told that there is a fairy...
...that has the power to grant
one wish in her lifetime.
l finally got me the one and only
magical wish-giving fairy.
But she was captured
by a greedy gargoyle.
And when l wake,
l'm gonna wish me wish.
Goodnight, me pretty.
l'll see you in the morning.
Do not be afraid.
Who are you?
They call me Jack.
l've come to help you.
lf you free me, l will grant
any wish you desire.
Thank you.
No, wait.
What sorcery is this?
You shouldn't have done that.
l tried to warn you.
Now we're both stuck,
and we'll never get out.
There must be a way.
-Well, he has the key.
-Yes.
But you must be careful,
or we will never be free.
Do not worry. l will get us out.
Wait. Jack.
Please, lower your voice,
or you'll awaken him.
How does this work?
So you think you can just sneak in here
and steal me fairy.
Nobody steals my fairy!
-Are you all right?
-Yes. But--
Do not worry. This won't take long.
Stop. You'll get the sword stuck too.
Jack, what did you do?
-l saved you. l destroyed the gargoyle.
-But we're still trapped.
-l have the key.
-But you don't have the magic words.
Magic words? What magic words?
The ones the gargoyle knew.
Now we'll never get out.
l wish we were free.
[ENGLlSH]