Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
My clothes.
Rabbit! Rabbit!
Come out, rabbit!
What manner of place is this?
Hey, why don't you watch
where you're--? Naked!
Sir, l apologize for what l am about to do,
but l must borrow your clothes.
My what?
Although they lack the comfort,
durability and style of my gi...
...these humble garments will have to
hold me until l regain my proper attire.
Now to go find that rabbit.
That's the hoodlum that stole me cats!
-Mine too!
-And mine.
-After him!
-Wait, please-- l did not--
You'll never get away, you no good--
Go on, say it.
Cat burglar!
l am terribly sorry, mister.
Do you need a ride?
Yes, please. Quickly.
Take us away from this vicinity.
-Get back here, you thief!
lt seems as though that angry mob
is trying to get your attention.
Please, we must leave immediately.
The urgency in your grip tells me
you are in grave danger.
l will take you the heck out of here.
We are not going anywhere.
lt seems we are too heavy.
l will release some ballast.
We have to get higher.
l'm afraid we are too heavy.
lt seems that l have another customer.
Thank you, sir. Come again.
Please, take a number.
lf we don't take off soon, l think you'll
be forced to share my taxi services.
We would be able to rise higher if only
we had some weight left to drop.
Well, the cat's out of
the bag now, my friend.
-What was that?
-What was what?
-Oh, look at that. A white rabbit.
-White rabbit?
Up there! After him!
Open the door! We're coming in!
Hello.
Forgive us, lady.
We was in pursuit of a thief.
You haven't seen one about, have you?
No, l have not.
He must have gone this way. Come on!
Oh, there you are.
We've been looking all over for you.
Have you any idea what time it is?
Hurry. You're on.
At last, princess of hearts,
l have you right where l want you.
And this time, there will be no escape.
Your line.
You're supposed to scream.
My fair prince will rescue me.
Yes, yes. Your prince might come...
...but he will be too late to save you
from the Cheshire dragon.
Aku.
Fear not, princess of hearts,
for l have come to save you.
Look, it's the princess of hearts.
Just like in the play.
Please, l don't have time.
And she's wearing the magic apron.
-l want it.
-l want the dress.
-l want the blouse.
-No, wait. Stop.
l want her hair.
You're not the princess.
Hey, you. You can't run
around here almost naked. Stop.
Calling all units.
Calling all units. Almost-naked man
running loose in terminal.
I repeat, almost naked.
Arrest him immediately.
There he is. Hold it right there, mister.
-Stop.
Why, he's almost naked.
Calling for backup. Calling for backup.
Look out for an almost-naked man
on the A train.
-Stop right there.
-Not another step.
We've got you now, buster.
No, please, you don't understand.
Hey, that's him.
The almost-naked man.
Stop him!
What was that? Let's check up front.
Have you seen
an almost-naked man on the train?
No, sir. l can't say l have.
Well, if you do, please notify us.
Yes, sir. Of course.
Come on. Let's check the cargo hold.
Look! Nobody's driving the train.
Are you crazy, man? Get back in there.
What are you waiting for?
Hurry, or we'll crash.
Wake up. Wake up.
We are about to crash.
Don't you know what you're doing?
Use the trackball, man.
l've got you now, rabbit.
Hey, put me down, you.
Let me go!
Hey, mister, what's the big idea?
My sword and my gi,
what have you done with them?
Take it easy.
They're in my backpack.
-Your backpack?
-Sure.
My sword.
Did not your parents teach you
it is wrong to steal?
l don't have any parents.
l'm all alone.
l saw your stuff just sitting there,
so l took it.
l'm sorry.
l was hungry.
Your sword and bathrobe looked valuable.
Almost as valuable as robot slug tusks.
Robot slug tusks?
-Will these do?
-Wow, mister. Thanks.
l'll never go hungry again.
A stranger world than this
l fear l have yet to visit.
[ENGLlSH]