Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
As far as the eye can see,
the land is desolate...
...and full of despair.
Shadows crawl across the earth
and black out the light.
Darkness oozes from every crevice.
Hope has been eradicated.
Only terror reigns.
Yet there is one that mocks
my omnipresent evil...
...with his existence.
He possesses a sword
which could destroy me.
They call him...
...Samurai Jack!
Despite my efforts,
he has not yet been destroyed.
But now l, Aku,
dark lord of all darkness...
...will make the final move...
...and annihilate Samurai Jack forever.
From deep within the bowels
of the pit of hate...
...l summon Demongo!
What is thy bidding, my master?
You are one of my
most powerful minions.
You possess the ability to steal...
...the essence of
the mightiest of warriors...
...or the deadliest of beasts.
You have never failed me.
The more essence l take...
...the more powerful l become,
my master.
And l have stolen the essence
of the greatest of warriors.
l cannot be defeated.
Find Samurai Jack.
Destroy him and enslave his essence.
Samurai Jack.
A prize indeed.
The greatest of all warriors.
Yes.
What better way to get rid of him...
...than have his essence
imprisoned for all time?
lt is as good as done, my master.
lf you seek conflict, you have found
the wrong man to deal with.
You are mistaken.
l am the dealer of destruction...
...the merchant of doom.
And l seek you, Samurai Jack.
-Who are you?
-Aku has sent me to destroy you.
-Aku?!
-My master tires of your existence.
You are a powerful foe.
Perhaps too powerful for my master...
...but not for me.
My name is Demongo.
l have come...
...to capture your warrior's essence.
Merchant of doom?
You are a fool, samurai.
Do not meddle in things
you do not understand.
Titan, destroy the samurai!
You've met your match, samurai.
Crush him!
Crush, crush, crush!
Stop your whining.
lt's just a scratch.
Now get him!
Curses.
You are next.
-l know these warriors.
-They, too, were once thorns in Aku's side.
But now l, Demongo,
control their essence...
...as l will control yours.
Prepare yourself, samurai,
for annihilation.
You cannot win, samurai.
l am more powerful.
A power fueled only by the strength
and skill of the great warriors...
...whose essence you have stolen,
Demongo!
Without that, you are nothing.
You are wise, samurai.
But who cares?
When l have your essence...
...l will be the greatest warrior.
lt cannot be.
How is it possible?
l just defeated them.
Yes, you did.
But they are essence.
You cannot defeat essence.
You may defeat them again
and again and again.
But l command the essence...
...of thousands
of such powerful warriors.
Even one as mighty as you
cannot defeat them all.
We shall see.
lt is futile.
You still think you can win.
How commendable.
How futile.
So many.
There, you fools. There.
Destroy. Destroy Samurai Jack!
l want his essence!
Yes! Yes! Fight! Fight!
lt's just a matter of time, samurai.
Only a matter of time before...
...my defeat.
There must be a way to defeat Demongo.
A way to stop Demongo
from using essence.
Essence of trapped warriors.
Trapped essence.
Free the essence,
Demongo has no power.
How do l free the essence?
Yes. From within.
How do l get inside?
lmpossible!
And l free your essence!
My essence.
Where is all my essence?
No!
You have failed me, Demongo.
No, master. Please forgive me.
No.
Once again the saga continues.
[ENGLlSH]