Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Greetings, lmacandi.
l am Aku, master of the planet Earth.
l have traveled far to offer you
the greatest hunt.
A great prey runs free on my planet...
...terrorizing all that l have worked for.
Many have attempted to capture
this elusive target.
l present this challenge to you,
lmacandi...
...for you are the greatest hunters
of the universe.
l bring you countless treasure
if you accept.
And if you succeed,
the skies will darken...
...and a rain of priceless jewels
will flood your world...
...making you rich
beyond your wildest dreams.
Our race has existed
for countless eons.
The hunt is our way of life.
lt runs through our veins.
lt makes us rich.
Rich beyond material wealth.
We accept your challenge,
but we need not your treasure.
Our reward is the thrill of the hunt...
...for we are lmacandi.
Yes, you are truly unique creatures.
l wish you a good hunt.
This was a waste of our time.
This prey is not worthy to continue.
Let us inform Aku
that he can have his prize.
Aku? No!
l will not be delivered to Aku
like some animal.
We hunt, my brothers.
Never before have l encountered hunters
of such caliber.
Excuse me.
l must commandeer your chariot.
Like heck you will--
Hey, man, you,re on it backwards!
Congratulations, lmacandi.
You are undoubtedly
the greatest hunters of the universe.
All that have preceded failed.
But you...
...you have captured the one being...
...who ran free on this world of mine.
Yes, truly this was
our greatest hunt...
...and this samurai
has proven himself...
...as the mightiest
and most elusive of prey.
Yes, yes.
Now, please hand him to me.
-No.
-What?!
l cannot.
A prey that has provided
such an intense and noble hunt...
...has earned its right to run free.
lt is the way of the lmacandi.
lnsolent fool!
l will take what is mine.
No, you will not!
No!
What happened? Where am l?
You have given us the greatest hunt.
You have earned your freedom.
It is our way, the Imacandi way.
Run free, Samurai Jack.
Run free.
[ENGLlSH]