These seas, thousands of miles
from nearest land,
are the most sterile on our planet.
These are marine deserts.
But here live the swiftest
and most powerful of all ocean hunters.
Simply finding them
is an immense challenge...
but we are about to follow them
as they search for their food
in this little known part
of the seas...
the open ocean.
Striped marlin -
voracious predators
that can grow to three metres long.
They hunt mainly in daylight,
searching the tropical oceans
from close to the surface
down to depths of 100 metres or so.
Normally, the fish they feed on
are widely dispersed,
but sometimes their prey
gathers in dense shoals,
like these sardines.
This feast may last
for over an hour...
time enough for other hunters
to reach the scene.
juvenile tuna join in
the feeding frenzy.
The noise attracts a giant -
a sei whale.
it's 14 metres long
and 20 tonnes in weight,
and has an appetite to match.
Soon, the only sign
that the sardines ever existed
are scales sinking
down into the abyss.
Such feasts don't last long.
Within a few short days,
waters that once swarmed with food
will have been cleaned out.
The hunters must move elsewhere
and once again search the seemingly
featureless open ocean.
A manta ray - immense,
five metres across
from the tip of one wing-like fin
to the tip of the other.
it's travelling Economy,
wasting as little energy as possible
as it glides through the waters
of the tropics.
The remora fish that accompany it
travel more economically still
by hitching a lift.
Their host is searching for food -
plankton,
the minute fish and invertebrates
that float near the surface.
it needs lots of them
and may cruise for days before
it finds a good feeding ground.
Dusk, at the edge
of a Pacific island,
3,000 miles
from the nearest continent.
Here, surgeon fish
have assembled to spawn.
As they perform
their nuptial dances,
they discharge clouds of eggs
and sperm into the water.
The manta must have known
this was about to happen,
for it arrived at exactly
this critical moment,
and it is not the only one
to do so.
0thers are here, too.
Now, they just need to sweep
the water into their mouths
and sieve out the eggs.
Within an hour,
the whole event will be over.
Any surviving eggs
will be so dispersed
that they are not worth collecting.
But other perils await them
as they join the clouds of eggs
and larvae and tiny fish
that drift through
the surface waters of the open ocean.
These are the eggs
of yellow-fin tuna.
if the hatchlings survive,
it will take them two years
to become adults.
in three years,
they could be nearly two metres long
and weigh 200 kilograms.
Perhaps only one in a million
will live as long as that.
They and the other animals
and microscopic plants
of the plankton
constitute the basis of all life
out on the open ocean.
A storm petrel
dancing on the water.
But this is no amiable waltz.
it's a hunt.
As they hover facing into the wind,
they pick out morsels from near
the surface, including eggs.
0nly a tiny percentage
of the developing eggs
will survive long enough to hatch.
These newly emerged tuna
are only three millimetres long,
and although they CAN swim,
they're still very vulnerable.
it will be many weeks before
they can swim strongly enough
to make any real headway
in the ocean.
After the sun goes down,
other predators
rise from the depths
to attack the floating multitudes.
Darkness shrouds the arrival
of battalions of dangerous,
drifting predators.
These shimmering comb jellies -
sea gooseberries -
trap their prey
with sticky, net-like webs.
0ne ill-timed fin stroke
could bring certain death
to a hatchling fish.
There are many kinds
of these comb jellies -
all of them very effective hunters.
By dawn,
most of the nocturnal feeders
will have returned to the depths.
The surviving hatchlings, however,
have already started
on their travels.
Vast current systems
like immense rivers
carry them around the ocean basins.
The boundaries between
these masses of moving water
form invisible barriers that
can trap plankton and nutrients
carried up from the depths.
So, parts of the ocean
become rich with food
for days or even weeks at a time.
This attracts vast schools
of plankton-feeding fish,
like these sardine.
They take in water
through their mouths
and expel it through their gills,
sieving out the plankton which is
then funnelled down their throats.
The immense schools travel
along the boundaries of the currents,
seeking the spots
where the plankton is thickest.
As the position of the current
boundaries changes constantly,
so does both the supply of plankton
and the numbers of fish.
A small pod
of Pacific spotted dolphin,
20 miles from the coast of Panama.
Like all predators,
they seek parts of the ocean
where their food is thickest.
They cover as much
as 100 miles in a day,
and while they travel,
they play.
They have detected
the sound of schooling fish
from hundreds of metres away,
and start to track down the shoals
using sonar,
leaving their toys behind them.
For the hunted,
there are few places to hide.
Schooling mackerel.
They have already sensed the sonar
beams of approaching dolphin.
Their only defence
is to gather into a ball.
Any fish that stayed out of the
shoal would be quickly picked off.
Within it, there is
at least S0ME chance of survival.
The noise of the attack
alerts another predator -
a sailfish, one of the fastest fish
in the ocean.
it has detected rapid vibrations
in the water,
and is searching for the cause.
Sailfish rely on eyesight
for their final approach,
so they hunt mainly in daylight.
When sailfish become excited,
they change colour,
lighting up with blue stripes.
Since mackerel eyes are especially
sensitive to blue and ultraviolet,
these colours confuse them,
making them easier to catch.
Far below, a blue shark
returns from a squid-hunting trip
in the cold darkness
300 metres down.
it's heading for the surface
to reheat in the warmer water.
As it ascends, it detects the smell
of oils and proteins
shed into the water
by the panicked mackerel.
The trail leads both the shark
and its attendant pilot fish
towards an easy meal.
Scraps and casualties
float in the wake
of the passing mackerel school.
Throughout the ocean,
predators and prey
are locked in a deadly
three-dimensional contest
of hide and seek, played out
over immense distances.
To survive, they must travel.
The huge four-metre-long
blue-fin tuna has special blood vessels
that enable it to keep
its body temperature warmer
than the surrounding water.
As a result, they can survive
in much colder conditions
than any other tuna,
and they travel thousands of miles
away from their spawning grounds
in the tropics to hunt in cold seas
where the food supply is richest.
0cean travellers
come in many guises -
and few are stranger than this...
a crab that spends
much of its life afloat.
it's a worrying passer-by
for booby birds with delicate toes.
Many floaters are little more
than jelly enclosed in membranes
but they may drift
for vast distances.
And turtles,
like these olive Ridleys,
migrate thousands of miles
every year.
The ocean is full of such wanderers
riding the currents and doing
their best to avoid enemies
while they search for food
and a safe place to breed...
which is exactly
what these rays are doing -
forming the two-mile high club,
gathering together
for courtship on the wing,
far above the ocean floor.
More nomads - flying fish.
They seem to be
on every large predator's menu,
so their whole life is spent
on the run in the open ocean.
They don't scatter their eggs
but lay them on pieces of flotsam
like this palm frond.
if the quality of water is right,
they will attach their eggs
to the frond
which will then serve as a kind
of life-raft for their offspring.
But it's not only flying fish
that seek nurseries.
Any piece of floating debris
can serve as a shelter
under which baby fish can hide.
The only drawback
is that predators like this wahoo
check up on who's hanging about
in the shadows.
The wahoo may trail the flotsam
for weeks.
Few bits of flotsam
are without their quota of lodgers,
even man-made junk attracts them,
and some,
like this oceanic trigger fish,
defend their squatters' rights
with vigour.
The triggers, in fact, tend
to claim all the prime residences.
0ut here, even discarded netting
can provide valuable shelter,
so, in a bizarre twist,
a wrecked trawl net like this
can end up as a sanctuary for fish
until it finally sinks.
A single large piece of flotsam
can be the reason why several
square miles of open ocean,
instead of being empty,
will support a fish population
of hundreds of tonnes.
This huge clump of seaweed
is doing exactly that.
it's a giant kelp plant,
ripped from rocks
off the coast of California.
Now, it's floating
above thousands of metres of water,
held up by its gas-filled floats.
Young rockfish are growing up in
the safety of its shadow.
Giants also seek out
this algal flotsam.
This is a sunfish.
it can measure as much as four
metres from fin tip to fin tip.
Rather surprisingly,
it has the record as
the heaviest bony fish in the sea.
Sunfish spend much of their time
at depth, where they feed on jellyfish,
but it's cold and dark down there
so from time to time, they seek
a little rest and recuperation
and warm up near the surface.
They too are looking
for floating kelp plants...
not for shelter,
but because here they can find
a particular kind of fish
that only lives in such places.
Half-moon fish.
The sunfish form up
in an orderly queue.
They have a problem.
Their skin is covered in parasites.
The hungry half-moons will help.
The sunfish turn their heads
as a clear invitation
to their personal hygienists.
The half-moons nip off and eat
every parasite they can find.
if the half-moons don't do the job,
there is another rather
drastic treatment available here.
Gulls rest on the floating kelp...
and if the sunfish
send the right signals,
the gulls will investigate.
Their beaks can dig out
the most stubborn parasites.
But even the very best
of health clinics
can only trade
on a temporary basis.
The seaweed rafts are rotting
and will eventually lose
their buoyancy.
Then their lodgers
will have to find a new home.
if they can't, they will be eaten
or die
and sink down into the abyss.
But the open ocean is not entirely
devoid of permanent shelter.
A volcano is erupting
from the sea floor
and it's still growing.
it has formed an island
some 70 miles
from the coast of New Zealand.
Some juvenile
reef fish have already arrived,
carried here by a lucky current.
Now they are growing up
in the shelter of the weeds
around the island's fringes.
More plankton and juvenile fish
are being swept by currents
straight towards the island,
but now there's
a welcoming committee.
Schools of trevally and blue maomao
are patrolling the surface water.
All are in search of a meal.
These one-kilo fish
snap up every morsel
of plankton they find.
At times, the currents
sweeping in from the open ocean
bring with them all kinds of small
creatures in dense concentrations.
These are mysid shrimps.
Very little that is edible
is left after such feasts.
islands are far from being
safe havens for plankton.
The Pacific 0cean, however,
is peppered
with over 23,000 islands,
as well as countless other
submerged mountains - sea mounts -
whose summits do not break
the surface.
juvenile fish
for their first few months
would do well to avoid such places.
These yellow-fin tuna, however,
are now more than six months old
and 40 centimetres long -
big enough to be able to eat fry,
so sea mounts for them
are promising feeding grounds
where they may hunt
for several months.
The base of a sea mount.
As currents sweep towards it,
they're deflected
up its towering walls.
The water coming from the depths
carries both nutrients
and plankton to the surface.
Numerous reef fish
take up permanent residence,
feeding where the currents
are strongest
and the plankton most dense.
Where the cold water mixes
with warmer water at the surface,
there's a strange,
shimmering effect -
a clear sign that the currents
are running strongly.
But these currents attract
more than just coastal fish.
Giants come here
from the open ocean -
hammerhead sharks,
and in great numbers.
During the day,
they circle the sea mount looking
for small fish at the reef edges...
but not in order to eat them.
They, like the sunfish,
are looking for cleaners
to rid them of their parasites.
White-tip reef sharks
gather here, too.
They D0 eat reef fish...
but they prefer to hunt at night,
when the reef fish are sleepy
and easier to catch.
Far better to rest by day
and allow the cleaners
to do their work.
Even swarms of breeding trigger
aren't a serious temptation.
These triggers spend
much of their time in open water,
but they've come to the sea mount
to spawn.
Trigger eggs are good food,
and the planton feeders
gather what they can
before the current
sweeps them away.
This community is here because
of the nutrients and plankton
the sea mount deflected
into the surface waters.
But ocean-going hunters
are never far away.
Silky sharks specialise
in picking off injured fish
and constantly check over
the residents around the sea mount.
At some times of the year,
seasonal changes make the currents
especially rich in nutrients,
and the ocean around the sea mount
becomes a virtual soup of plankton.
At such times, hunters gather
in astonishing numbers.
Bonito, smaller relatives
of the tuna.
They are searching
for still smaller plankton feeders
that have been attracted
by the bloom.
So are these jacks,
and their prey is nearby.
A school of anchovetta
has strayed up near the surface,
even though it's broad daylight
and hunters are on the prowl.
These small fish
can already feel the vibrations
of the approaching predators.
Swimming at speed,
they have formed into a ball,
and now they must wait
for whatever comes.
They've been detected.
At first, the sheer scale
of the bait ball
seems to daunt the predators...
but now the bonito arrive
and launch the first attack.
Still the bait ball holds together.
The young yellow-fin tuna move in.
The speed of this attack
is so great
that groups of anchovetta are
splintered from the main fish ball.
Before long,
the currents will shift,
and the ocean will become once more
a blue tropical desert,
plankton-free,
and the hunters
will have to move on.
Spinner dolphins,
still searching for food.
Their twisting leaps are,
apparently, purely social displays.
Since the hunting has been good,
many hundred have gathered together
in this exuberant super-pod.
But now the spinners
are starting to hunt once more.
Their skill in tracking food
is not a secret.
Yellow-fin tuna must be aware of it,
for they regularly follow them,
but only adult tuna in their
second or third year of life
have sufficient stamina to keep up
with the fast-moving spinners.
These are another kind -
common dolphin.
They too are on the move.
As they travel - ever inquisitive -
they pay a call
on one of their larger relations,
a pilot whale.
The whale is not hunting.
it's on its way to its breeding
grounds in the Mediterranean.
Pilot whales normally hunt
in small family groups,
but in mid-summer they head
for traditional socialising grounds,
where they will assemble in
super-herds several hundred strong.
Already, two families
have joined together.
The males are competing
for the favours of the females.
As the weeks pass by,
these group rubbing sessions
will become more overtly sexual,
but now
it's just flirting in the sun.
Timing in the ocean can be crucial.
in summer, the northern Atlantic
waters are beginning to warm.
The hunting is good here,
and by june,
predators from southern waters
are heading towards the Azores.
These are more common dolphin.
Like most oceanic dolphins,
they too often travel in huge herds
containing many different families.
There is seldom enough prey in any
one place to feed such numbers...
so small groups leave the super-pod
and set off on hunting expeditions.
This group will be away
from the main herd for many hours.
By midday, they're nearing
the islands of the Azores,
900 miles west
of the Portuguese coast.
0ther hunters are already here -
Cory's shearwaters.
Half a million of these birds
breed on the Azores every year
and scour the nearby ocean
for food.
There's insufficient wind
to support gliding flight,
and since flapping is a waste
of energy, they sit out the calm,
clustered in rafts
and riding the gentle swells.
By mid-afternoon, the dolphin
are starting to hunt in earnest.
As the sea breeze picks up,
the shearwaters
take to the air once more.
0ut to sea,
the dolphin have found prey.
They are driving a shoal of small
mackerel up towards the surface.
The shearwaters crowd the skies,
following the dolphins' every turn.
The mackerel
are still some metres down...
but when the baitfish
come sufficiently close,
the airborne division
makes its move.
Far from being mere bystanders,
the shearwaters become
underwater predators themselves.
incredibly, they can dive
down to depths of several metres.
The hunting dolphin prevent the
mackerel from escaping downwards,
and both predators
gorge themselves.
Soon, the diving birds
outnumber the dolphin
and even drive them away
from their meal...
but another squadron of predators
arrives to replace the dolphin -
adult yellow-fin tuna.
These are giants, two metres long.
They are heading
directly for the bait ball.
Despite the arrival
of the giant fish,
the shearwater continue
to press home their attack unfazed.
Eventually, the tuna move on,
leaving the shearwaters
to battle among themselves.
As long as a predatory fish
or a dolphin remains at the scene,
the mackerel can't escape to safety,
but when the little skipjack tuna
start to move away,
gradually the bait ball sinks
into the depths towards safety.
The shearwaters follow it down
to the very limit
of their breath-holding ability,
perhaps as deep as 15 metres.
At last, even they are forced
to leave their quarry.
However good or bad
this summer's feeding may be,
within three months,
winter will be on its way
and the temperature of these waters
will drop by a few degrees.
Then the ocean hunters
will abandon the Azores once more.
As ever, they will move on,
searching for another
feeding opportunity -
the next pulse of life in the distant
reaches of the open ocean.