It's only in the last 50 years,
with the invention of the aqualung
that we've gone underwater
to see what lives there,
We all love dolphins,
They're the playful,
popular face of the ocean,
But most of what lives underwater
is out of sight,
and so, out of mind,
Even in the 20 years
that I've been diving,
there have been big changes
in our seas,
It's clear that our oceans
are now in real danger,
Flying over miles and miles
of ocean, you get the impression
that things aren't too bad,
but below the surface there's
a multitude of man-made problems,
0f all of them, probably
the most destructive is fishing,
and it's the WAY we catch fish
that's the problem,
Blue fin tuna, king of the sea,
They are exquisitely designed
for the open ocean,
They can grow up
to three-quarters of a tonne,
and can swim at 50 miles an hour,
faster than any other creature
in the sea,,,
apart from us,
They have few natural predators
when fully grown,
It is believed that these blue fin
are now endangered,
There's no place in the ocean
where we can't pursue them,
They just can't escape us,
Fishing has become
incredibly hi-tech,
so much so that we can
pretty much capture anything
anywhere in the world nowadays.
These blue fin tuna boats
beneath me have every mod con.
They have incredibly big engines,
use depth sounders, GPS,
and they even have spotter planes
spotting the fish for them.
I got about eight fish over here.
They just went down.
They're on my left side.
So the blue fin tuna,
travelling at 50 miles an hour,
hasn't got much of a chance,
The moment it comes to the surface,
somebody will spot it.
Go at 12 o'clock.
Five or six boats.
Here they're being hunted on one
of their major migration routes,
It's thought they swim
from the Gulf of Mexico
up the eastern seaboard
of the U,S, to Canada each summer,
Their routes are so predictable,
that they can be caught
year after year,
While these fisherman
are still catching them,
scientists are tagging the fish,
trying to discover how many
separate populations there are,
what their movements are,
and just how many fish are left,
Marine scientist and
keen sports fisherman Carl Safina
fishes off Long Island, New York,
He loves fishing for blue fin,
but these days
he has to target other species,
I've been fishing off shore
since I was 12
with my fathers and my uncles,
and we used to see
lots of blue fin tuna -
a lot of small ones
and a lot of big ones.
Now, er...there are so few tuna,
that people...sport fish
for sharks now.
Safina is so concerned
by this decline
that he's campaigning
with the National Audubon Society
to try and save these tuna,
What we do know about blue fins
in the western part of the Atlantic -
the part of the Atlantic
off the U.S. and Canada -
is that, er...from the mid 1970s
until the late 1990s,
the population has declined
by roughly 85 per cent.
In New England, where most
of the Western Atlantic blue fin
are caught commercially,
fishermen just don't believe
these government figures,
They claim there are mistakes
in the analysis,
so they're naturally
very sceptical
about the quotas
the government imposes,
Scientific research in the ocean
is expensive,
and the politics surrounding
this fish are complicated,
but one thing is indisputable -
these fish sell
for vast amounts of money,
(SAFINA) The blue fin tuna
was worth a few cents a pound
and often sold as cat food
until some people realised
that if they airlifted them
to Japan -
if they sent them to Japan
in airplanes -
the price would go from a few cents
to many dollars per pound.
Tsukiji market in Tokyo is the
biggest fish market in the world,
Before I came to Japan,
I'd heard a lot about it
but I just wasn't prepared
for the scale of it,
This warehouse
is just the frozen section,
In another section, there are
rows and rows of fresh tuna,
and amongst these are
a frightening quantity of blue fin,
The Japanese are by far the biggest
importers of blue fin tuna
in the world,
This is big business.
These blue fin
are fetching £60 a kilo,
so in today's auction,
a dealer would expect
to get £12,000
for this one fish alone.
But the market fluctuates madly,
and some blue fin here
have fetched more than £100,000,
Tuna fisherman don't accept the
blue fin numbers are right down,
but most scientists
firmly believe that they are,
Many people want blue fin tuna
listed as CITES Appendix I,
in other words, a total ban
on all fishing of them.
Unless this is done,
there is no way that those involved
in the market will give up -
there's too much in it for them.
This market is not just about tuna,
There's every conceivable type
of fish here,
Nearly 50 per cent of the food
eaten in Japan
comes from the sea,
compared with the world's average
of about 15 per cent.
They eat enormous quantities of fish,
of every species imaginable,
but unfortunately, some of
those species are in deep trouble.
This is a swordfish,
In the Atlantic, its numbers have
more than halved since the 1960s,
and many restaurants
have now taken it off the menu,
Marlin are a favourite
amongst game fishermen,
and some species are down
by 90 per cent,
While shark meat is on sale
in many Japanese markets,
by far the biggest trade
is in shark fins,
and that trade is Asia-wide,
About 100 million sharks
are caught every year,
Admittedly,
this IS the biggest market,
but there are hundreds of markets
all over the world
selling huge quantities of fish,
and it's not just one day a week,
it's day after day.
You might find
some really strange creatures here,
ones which are
totally unfamiliar to us,
but it's often the more common
species that are threatened,
and those you can find on sale
at home.
This is Billingsgate Market,
the largest fish market in London,
Here you can buy all the familiar
fish which we love to eat,
but in the UK, we're eating fish
whose stocks are dangerously low,
Most of us have no idea
that these fish are in trouble,
even the most common ones
such as cod,
At the moment, the worst problem
is with cod in the Irish Sea
which is really in a very,
very depressed state indeed.
The north-east Arctic stock
off the coast of Norway
is not in very good shape.
The Canadian stock and the North
Sea stock are not in good shape.
About the only one that's doing
reasonably well is in Iceland.
And if that one goes the same way,
there will be no Atlantic cod.
There simply will not be any cod
for sale.
So is this a normal size
for a cod these days?
That's an average size, yeah.
(SHEPHERD ) When you buy fish in the
supermarket or fish and chip shop,
as a consumer
you have no way to tell
whether this is from a stock
that is overfished or that isn't.
- These are from the North Sea?
- Yeah, they're Scottish.
We know that fish stocks
do collapse
and sometimes they recover -
the herring collapsed
and recovered.
A stock of mackerel in
the North Sea in the 60s and 70s
collapsed under very heavy fishing
pressure by purse-seiners,
and it has not come back.
In 30 years, it has not come back.
Sole and plaice
are fully exploited
and could not sustain
any further fishing pressure.
The herring also
is fully exploited.
There's no room for expansion.
Now, with so much fishing pressure
in surface waters,
fishermen are going deeper and
deeper to find fish for the market.
We're seeing things here that we'd
never have heard of 20 years ago.
This is a black scabbard
and it lives at about 1,000 metres.
So are these fish in trouble?
It's hard to say,
because like everything else
that lives in the deep,
very little is known about it.
Scientists don't really know
what's going on down there,
and they're only just beginning
to find out,
Scientists from Tasmania
are now using hi-tech cameras
mounted on submersibles
to study the effects of fishing
on the deep sea,
0nly in the last 30 years
have we had the technology
to fish the deep,
But in many places, the fishing
pressure has been intense,
This particular fish
is now on our menus,
These white fish
are the fillets of a deep sea fish
called orange ruffie.
You may have noticed them
in your supermarket recently.
They can live at depths
of 1,500 metres,
and like a lot of deep sea fish,
they live a very long time.
These ones could have been born
during World War II.
They could even have been around
during the Victorian era.
It's believed that orange ruffie
can live to a staggering
150 years old.
As well as living longer,
these fish mature later
at about 30 years old,
If you take them out
before this age,
they won't be able to reproduce,
There won't be a future generation
of orange ruffie,
For many years, the fishing
pressure here was huge,
Thousands of tonnes
were scooped up for the market,
and sold around the world,
At times, so many were caught,
there wasn't even the market
for them, They were just dumped,
Fortunately, the New Zealand
and Australian fisheries
recognised the problem in time,
They now monitor the fish stocks
carefully,
The fish may be safe,
but the habitat they rely on isn't,
In the deep sea,
there are animals so new to us
and so strange,
it's as if we are in another world,
Despite its remoteness,
the deep sea habitat is now
under threat, and once again,
it's the method of fishing
that is causing the real damage,
Deep sea fishing nets are huge,
They dredge up life
indiscriminately,
Corals and sponges
hundreds of years old
are being ripped off
the seabed and destroyed,
What a trawler does,
particularly in the deep sea,
where fishing effort
is concentrated around sea mounts
which are very hard rock,
to protect the net from the rock,
they have steel balls on them
about half a metre in diameter.
That net is pulled along
at say three knots,
smacking into the rock,
smack, smack, smack, smack.
So this net basically comes along
and mows that thing down,
just rips it off, it's history.
It's got no chance of living
after that.
You can't see
the damage done at depth,
but if the same was done on land,
you'd be horrified,
If we wanted to catch cows,
for instance,
we'd hang a net from a helicopter,
and drag that through the paddock.
We'd not only catch a few cows,
we'd catch the dog, the car,
the farmyard, the barn,
we'd catch the farmer's wife,
we'd catch the stuff
that we weren't going for.
0'Shea is concerned
about many of the animals
that are being brought up
from the deep,
most of them unintentionally,
He's monitoring
the damage being done
from his lab in New Zealand,
0ne of the most spectacular things
we've received in fisheries'
bi-catch is this large gorgonian.
It's like a black coral.
It's closely related,
and this specimen is 700 years old.
So it was 700 years
when the net ripped it off the
bottom of the sea. Now it's dead.
When you add up the pieces,
you'd have three metres
in height from the sea floor,
and that must be the equivalent
of an underwater forest.
It's tragic that this
should be ripped from the floor.
This particular species was very
common between 700 and 1100 metres
off our coast,
but like everything,
that is very fragile,
and if we put a steel ball over it,
it would be crushed to pieces.
0'Shea has a particular
fascination for deep sea squid,
but he's worried
that many are disappearing
before we've even had a chance
to see them alive in the wild,
let alone understand them,
This species used to be very common
around New Zealand.
It's gone.
The only reason
an animal like this is gone,
is it's so stupid, it's so slow,
it got attacked by a trawler net,
and the trawlers have been going
in the area for so long
that we've made this animal
extinct.
With every single dive
to the deep ocean,
scientists are discovering
new species,
Some may have properties
that could be invaluable to us,
Sponges are animals,
but they're rooted to the bottom
and can't get away from something
that's trying to eat them
or grow over them,
so they produce chemicals
to ward off predators
or other encroaching sponges,
It's these chemicals that interest
marine scientists in Florida,
They collect sponges from the deep,
and take them back to the lab
for analysis,
The challenge to us
as drug discoverers
and marine biologists
is to figure out
why the organism is producing it,
and then apply that knowledge
to figure out
what might be
an appropriate drug target
for that chemical compound.
Pomponi's team is using chemicals
from the sponges in trials,
They believe the chemicals will
prevent the growth of cancer cells
in humans,
Ideally, we want something
that will kill
a certain type of cancer cell,
so it will be very specific
for certain types of cancer,
and, so far, the results
are very encouraging.
So, yes, we think that this will
be useful as a treatment
for certain forms of cancer.
So far, we've only explored
two per cent of the deep,
We could be in danger of losing
a treasure-trove of species,
before we've even discovered them,
(P0MP0NI) If we lose...
that biological diversity
that occurs in the deep ocean,
and it does,
then we lose
that chemical diversity,
and we lose the opportunity
to discover new drugs.
It's not just the deep that's
in danger, Shallow water habitats
like coral reefs
are having a hard time, too,
Part of the problem
is the growing trade in reef fish,
and it's often the market demand
for luxury fish
like groupers, coral trout and
wrasse that's behind the problem,
They're being fished out
at an alarming rate,
Fish on coral reefs
that were once a staple food
for local people,
are now in high demand
as a delicacy
in major cities around the world,
The majority goes to mainland China
and cities like Hong Kong,
It's a huge market
and some 30,000 tonnes of reef fish
come into Hong Kong every year,
The fishermen are having to go
to coral reefs
further and further afield
as stocks dry up,
Some now travel 3,000 miles
on a single fishing trip
to find reefs with fish,
People like their fish fresh -
very fresh,
so much so
that the cost of live fish
is ten times
the cost of fresh dead fish,
and the fish in the marketplace
are getting smaller and smaller,
Dr Yvonne Sadovy is worried about
the amount of juveniles sold here,
This beautiful animal
is a humphead wrasse,
and he's called humphead wrasse
because of his hump on his head.
The other one is the giant grouper.
This is a giant grouper.
There's several of them,
and these are juveniles.
This one is probably
a late teenager,
but still not an old
or well-developed fish,
and the majority
that we see of these species
are young, juvenile fish.
Humphead wrasse should be able
to live for more than 20 years,
but they rarely reach that age,
They're taken out far too young,
If you have fisheries which take
large numbers of juveniles,
these animals have not had
a chance to reproduce,
so where's the next generation
going to come from?
If you take too many juveniles,
slowly what happens is
you don't get enough adults
in the next generation,
and slowly the populations
decline in numbers.
So that's what my concern is,
that if this is part of a trend -
that we're seeing more
and more juveniles being taken -
then that does not augur well
for these species.
But much more serious than
the possible loss of a few species
is the loss of an entire habitat,
especially one
which supports thousands
upon thousands of species,
Coral reefs are the most diverse
communities in our oceans,
Many of them have grown up
over hundreds,
sometimes thousands of years,
and over that time, a fantastic
number of animals and plants
have evolved with them,
The intricate structure
built by the corals themselves
provides protection
from predators,
important breeding sites,
and endless feeding opportunities,
But now the coral itself
is under threat
from man,
Today, dynamiting is commonplace,
It's an efficient way
to kill the nearby fish,,,
but just one blast will completely
flatten a patch of reef,
There are lots of other threats
to reef right across the world,
Sometimes it's pollution,
they get covered by sediment,
and global warming
is certainly playing its part, too,
Here in south-east Asia,
80 per cent of reefs
are either in danger of dying,
or are dead.
A lot of it's been dynamited,
but now a more sinister method
of fishing is being used.
It's fast, it's effective,
but it's highly illegal.
Fishermen are using
the poison cyanide.
Fishermen squirt sodium cyanide
into crevices
where fish take refuge,
Cyanide starves the fish of oxygen,
so they come out into the open
dazed and much easier to catch,
Not all these fish are for food,
Many of them
are for the aquarium trade,
They're purely a luxury item,
The corals themselves
die in just a few weeks,,,
and the whole reef
becomes smothered in algae,
That was a reconstruction,
but this is real life,
Members of the International Marine
Alliance in the Philippines
are trying to save
their few remaining reefs,
They suspect these men
have been fishing illegally,
and want to find out
where they've been fishing,
but the fishermen are wary,
They are afraid to tell us
where the places are
because there might be
some retaliation
from the other villagers
in this village.
They hide the bottles
underneath the boat,
and when...another boat approaches,
they just ditch this
so that nobody could see it.
These men know
they could end up in jail,
It's so hard to police
the coastal area of the Philippines
because it's a very long
coastal area.
Also, if you jail them,
you don't have enough room in jail.
We were taken to a jail
on the island of Koron,
These men have been arrested
for illegal fishing,
and they're awaiting trial,
They've been locked up for months,
but the trader, the middle man,
is still free,
I don't think we can lump
all the blame on the fishermen,
because first is that, er...
they do not know anything better.
They are afraid of being caught,
but they say there's
no other method to catch fish.
When they've been squirted
with cyanide,
fish don't die immediately,
but the damage HAS been done
and their internal organs
gradually pack up,
The trader has to move them fast
as they will die
in just a few weeks,
Cruise is sure that the importers
know when cyanide has been used
because the mortality rate
is so high,
but they simply choose
to ignore it,
An importer would know immediately
that there's something wrong
with his fishes,
but they keep on importing
from the same exporter
in the Philippines
or in other countries.
The majority of tropical fish
caught in Indonesia
and the Philippines
are exported to America
and to the UK,
Fortunately, responsible importers
like the owner of this shop
refuse to buy fish
that have been caught by cyanide.
A customer can't tell
how a fish was caught.
The responsibility lies with us
to check with the shopkeeper.
And if you don't,
it may only take a couple of weeks
before your ornamental fish
is as dead as the reef
it came from,
(BING CR0SBY) # Gone fishin'
# By a shady, wady pool... #
(L0US ARMSTR0NG)
# Shangri La, really la!
# I'm wishin' I could be
# That kind of fool
(Shall I twist your arm?)
# I'd say no more work for mine
(Welcome to the club!)
# 0n my door I'd hang a sign
# Gone fishin'
# Instead of just a-wishin'
# Bah-boo-bah-bah-boo-bam...
# 0h, yeah! #
This abandoned net
is made of tough nylon
which won't easily disintegrate,
If it isn't removed,
it could carry on killing like this
for years to come,
If one small net on one reef
can cause this much damage,
imagine what fishing nets do
on a global scale,
0ur fishing methods today ensure
that we catch more and more,
but a lot of what is caught
is thrown away -
simply chucked overboard,
usually dead,
Modern fisheries
are very destructive.
They catch what they're after -
and everything else.
The United Nations tells us
that up to 30 million metric tonnes
a year are caught
and then thrown overboard
dead or dying.
That's one quarter to one third of
the annual catch around the world.
I'm talking about not just
non-target fish species
but turtles, marine mammals,
birds such as albatrosses,
even whales on occasion.
No matter how magnificent,
no animal is spared
in our hunt for food,
But what's even more ridiculous,
is that often the fish that
we would eat are thrown away
if the boat is targeting
a different species,
And there's one particular fishery
where the waste is phenomenal,
Prawn or shrimp trawling
is the most destructive fishery
in the world.
Prawn or shrimp trawling
occurs throughout the tropics.
The nets are dragged along
the bottom where the shrimp live.
Those nets hoover up
everything in their path.
Up to 15 pounds of other species
are discarded
for every one pound of shrimp
that's caught.
Worse still are the quantities of
juvenile fish that get thrown away,
Hundreds of thousands of tonnes
of young fish
are discarded every year,
fish that would otherwise grow
to become an important
and valuable source of protein,
And all this
for just a handful of prawns,
The fishermen recognise
the problem and asked for help,
so Dr Steve Keneally is looking
at the prawn fishing industry
in New South Wales, Australia,
Here, the industry is huge,
They catch over a thousand tonnes
of prawns a year,
Keneally has invented
a bi-catch reduction device -
a BRD -
which lets smaller, immature fish
escape from the net,
This cording gets towed along
at the back of the net,
at the back
of the whole operation.
The catch that enters a trawl net
ends up at the back of this bag.
We did some trials and experiments
and found that, at a certain
point where this material changes,
you get a back pressure of water,
and by putting
in open square meshes
just at that point where that back
pressure of water is occurring,
the water will flow up and out
through that square mesh panel.
Little fish inside this net
feel that back pressure of water
and immediately head upwards
and out through
the open square mesh panel.
Keneally is experimenting
with two different nets,
This first one is
a conventional prawn fishing net,
0K, this is the catch
from the control cording -
that is the conventional cording
without any BRD in it.
As you can see, there's quite a lot
of small fish in the catch,
and, hopefully, in the other
cording with the BRD installed
there'll be a lot less fish
and still the same quantity
of prawns.
This is the net with his bi-catch
reduction device in it,
It's immediately obvious that fewer
fish have been accidentally caught,
So that's the difference
in bi-catch.
Most of the smaller fish
have escaped,
so at least they should have
a chance to breed,
You just have to look
with your own eyes
and there's no doubt
that there's a 60 per cent
reduction or more in bi-catch.
Keneally's device has gone
a long way to reducing the waste,,,
but he knows that
it's not the whole answer,
I don't think we can ever have
a situation
where we only catch the things
we're trying to catch.
With just about
every fishing method,
you're going to catch undersized
organisms of the target species.
To get to the position
where we don't catch any bi-catch
for prawn and shrimp,
I don't think we'll ever get
to that point,
at least not
in the foreseeable future.
But there is possibly
another way -
one where there may be
no bi-catch at all,
It's fish farming or aqua culture,
Already it's producing
huge quantities of fish,
Could fish farming be the solution?
At the moment, one in every
four fish that we eat is farmed,
but over the next 25 years,
it's thought that figure will double
so that half the fish
we eat will be farmed.
So is this the answer? Can we
really protect our fish stocks,
the juveniles,
the fragile marine habitats?
Is fish farming the solution
to all our fishing problems?
If aqua culture is one of
the answers, then surely the people
with the highest incentive
to get it right are the Japanese,
They're already very advanced
in farming fish,
They're even trying to raise
large predatory fish like tuna,
and in particular, blue fin tuna,
Here in Koshimoto in western Japan,
they're going for broke.
Swimming around beneath me
in this enclosure,
there are 50 fully mature
blue fin tuna,
These tuna were caught in the wild
and are now being fattened up
for market, They're fed generously
so they'll be in prime adult
condition when they're sold,
Here they've taken tuna farming
to the next stage,
They're not just holding them,
they're breeding these blue fins,
They hope that these fish
will breed in three years' time,
and so complete
the whole life cycle in captivity,
Then, they won't have to take
any more blue fin tuna
from our oceans,
(INTERPRETER) Japan is the largest
tuna consuming nation in the world.
And we're also very concerned
about diminishing stocks
of blue fin tuna in the wild.
Aqua culture has its own set
of well-known problems,
Most worrying are pollution
and the mixing of captive-bred fish
with wild stocks,
But there's another issue,
These tuna are fed a staggering
amount of fish every day,
They're being fed valuable protein
which should be food
for the poorer people of Asia,,,
so now the Japanese are trying
to develop a substitute feed
either from vegetable matter
or from animal products,
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
(INTERPRETER) And we hope
further development
will enable us to use
more artificial feed in the future.
But they haven't succeeded yet,
and they still take huge quantities
of low value fish
to feed one big luxury fish,
In other parts of Asia
which are poorer than Japan
and where fish stocks
are heavily depleted,
they are also turning
to aqua culture,
And tiger prawns
are the biggest money earner,
More than half a million tonnes
of prawns are produced a year,
nearly all of which are exported,
It's big business
and it employs a lot of people,
But just like tuna,
the prawns are carnivorous
and need to eat fish - fish
that have been ground into pellets,
When they're farmed
as intensively as they are here,
they need a lot of feed,
If you have, er...
three square metres of pond for
one tiger prawn, that's extensive -
nature will feed the prawn -
but if you have 30 of them
in one square metre,
then you have to provide
some kind of food.
I think the latest figures
are about two -
two kilos of fish -
to produce
one kilo of prawn.
Substitute feeds may help,
but they could come too late,
In the meantime,
low value fish are fed to prawns
which are then exported
to the West,
These fish should be feeding
local people,
It's the...
little fish that's there
that's being bought by...people,
by Filipino families for their food,
by low income families
and middle income families,
that will not be available
to these families.
But there's another issue,
Thousands of intensive farms
have been built in coastal areas,
destroying a valuable marine
habitat - mangrove forests,
Mile upon mile of mangroves
have been cut down,
The coastline has been stripped
of its natural protection,
And there are many important
ecological reasons why mangroves
should be protected,
To many people, mangroves
are just a mass of gnarled roots
where the bottom is sludgy,
and the air is full of mosquitoes,
but get underwater,
and it's a very different world.
The intricate root system provides
a natural nursery for young fish,
They spend their later life
on coral reefs or in the open sea,
The roots provide protection
from predators
which is vital
for small, vulnerable fish,
In the shelter of mangroves,
fish can feed and grow
in relative safety,
Again, it's the habitat
that's under threat,
We're destroying it
without a thought for the animals
that depend on it,
Perhaps the answer might be
to set aside some areas of the sea
so that the animals that live there
have a chance,
When land animals need protecting,
we usually do something about it -
the huge game reserves in Africa
are a classic example -
but for some reason,
we treat our seas very differently.
This is the island of Skomer,
a very beautiful reserve
that offers excellent protection
for the birds and plants
that live here.
It also calls itself
a marine nature reserve,
one of only two
in the whole of Britain.
You'd think a marine reserve
would offer total protection
for all life under the sea,
but amazingly, you can fish here.
Even commercial fishermen
can operate here.
In the time of our grandfathers,
there were natural marine reserves,
inaccessible to fishing fleets,
There, the fish could grow
to maturity undisturbed,
But with modern fishing technology,
there's practically nowhere
we now can't fish,
0nly a tiny percentage of the ocean
is a safe sanctuary,
Something like one third
of one per cent of the oceans
are within marine-protected areas.
That's a very tiny fraction
and it's equivalent to something
like the size of South Africa.
However, we're not protecting those
areas well enough at the moment,
and only something like
one ten thousandth of the surface
of the oceans
is protected
from all forms of fishing.
That's equivalent to the size of
Holland and it isn't nearly enough.
Roberts wants areas set aside
which are T0TALLYprotected,
There are some small areas
where they've done this
like this reserve off
the north island of New Zealand,
Since fishing stopped 25 years ago,
the stocks have recovered
and the water is now teeming
with fish,
And it's not just fish -
everything's doing well,
Lobsters are abundant again,
and they're getting a lot bigger,
Scientists monitor stocks carefully
and keep a close eye on how all the
animals in the reserve are doing,
This five-kilometre-wide reserve
produces the same number
of lobsters
as a 100-kilometre stretch
of unprotected coastline,
Fishermen are allowed to fish
right up to the boundaries,
The lobsters are now so abundant
within the reserve
that they spread out
into the surrounding waters,
(R0BERTS) So what these
no-take zones provide to fisheries
is an increase in the replenishment
to their fisheries.
The spawning stocks are
like deposits in a bank account.
Even the behaviour of the fish
has changed,
0nce scared of man, the fish
are perhaps a little over-friendlyI
Roberts believes that between
ten and 20 per cent of our oceans
should become no-take zones,
and that we should protect
large areas
of different marine habitats -
the deep sea, coral reefs,
mangroves,
as well as key spawning grounds,
That way, fish can grow bigger
and older
and stocks will recover,
He also believes
that migration routes and feeding
grounds should be protected,
particularly the routes taken
by the largest marine animals -
the whales -
as they circumnavigate the globe,
It's a simple idea,
and one that Roberts believes,
with the public's help,
is possible,
0nce people realise
what's going on,
and they begin
to bring to bear pressure
on the politicians
and decision-makers,
we'll see moves taking place
to establish the areas
that we need to set aside
from fishing.
We CAN make that choice,
We've done it before -
we brought back the great whales
from near extinction,
Most of them can live free
from the threat of a whaling boat -
but it took
international co-operation,
and that only came about
once the public realised
how close the whales were
to being wiped out.
Whaling was a huge industry
right up until the 1970s,
Some species nearly disappeared
from our oceans,,,
altogether,
We recognised this just in time,
so we did something about it,
We do now know what's happening
in our oceans,
We know they're in trouble
and that we're to blame.
We can't hide
behind an out of sight,
out of mind attitude any more.
We know what's down there -
the extraordinary diversity
of life.
0ur oceans are S0 precious,
so vital to the planet.
If we care about that,
then, surely,
we can look after them.