I don't understand
why the numbers are so low.
- It doesn't make any sense.
- Turnout's bad.
I hear at Politico, they're concentrating
mostly on Conway art.
Shut up or you're fired.
...division rivals.
...The fighting was quite a spectacle
but, unfortunately for hockey fans,
that was just about the only action
to be seen in last night's game.
Will, Mark's here.
- Mmm.
- Hope you got some sleep.
No, not really.
Even went for a run, but...
You hungry?
Um, I just wanted to connect
before the rest of this day kicks in.
I spoke to Marshall.
No, I told him.
Things are looking good.
Very good.
I really want to thank you for everything.
I mean, the ad and...
I had nothing to do with that ad.
No, of course, but...
to thank you for your support.
This is all you.
Listen...
I'm... choosing my words
very carefully here.
You need to get ready.
Today's gonna be a good day.
You can sleep
when you get to the White House.
...Or maybe not.
Get yourself together, Will.
I'll see you in a bit.
Are you ready...
to catch me?
Doug, LeAnn...
do you have a moment?
Reporting live
from the Piedmont Hotel,
the excitement is definitely...
Better not let them see
the name on your credentials.
Those folks out there love
their president.
I love pound cake.
- Doesn't mean it's good for me.
How are you doing, Seth?
- You got some foundation right here.
- Oh, jeez.
And we call it the news.
...I'm doing commentary.
Which means eventually
someone gets to ask me
if my articles
affected the president's loss.
Or his win.
I wish you the best, Seth.
You'll land somewhere.
You're that type.
We're going to have a great night tonight.
You don't have to spin me.
How shall I say this?
When I was single,
I always picked the loser's party.
I met the last Mrs. Hammerschmidt
drowning in tequila shots
at the Bob Dole ballroom.
And here I am... single again.
- You're not in Texas anymore.
- Doug, please.
- Please what?
- Don't think you know me.
Look, I just want to be sure
that you're ready for...
Macallan will do what he has to.
I like to win.
Trophies, medals, staring contests.
You name it.
You understand that, you understand me.
Hello, everyone.
Well, it's still early.
There's a lot more election
to be had today.
And we just want to apologize that,
because we have a little more work to do,
we're not gonna be able to get over
to the ballroom
as early as we would like to.
But once we do get there,
we are going to shake the hand
of each and every one of you,
to thank you for all the extraordinary
work that you've done for us.
That's right, a round of applause
all the way around.
And we'll see you all
at the party a little later.
Better?
- Yeah, a little.
First time I've fucked a president.
- Oh, don't say that.
- Marshall said...
I'm not a president yet.
Almost.
I got to put on a suit.
- People will be here soon.
- Will...
can't you let yourself feel it?
Almost.
- Ready when you are, sir.
- Put the governor on, please.
- Hello.
- Mitch, this is the president.
I understand you've been briefed.
Oh, Mr. President...
this is catching us all
off guard over here.
State, local, we had no idea.
I understand.
I'm with the vice president,
the secretary of state Durant,
and on the line with us
is Counterterrorism Director Green.
Governor, sir, I'm sorry,
but we needed to act.
I contacted
local law enforcement directly.
Well, it took a while to get to me.
Mitch, the counterterrorism director
will be sharing information
that we must keep amongst ourselves.
We do not want to do anything
that affects today's voting.
Forty-five minutes ago,
we raided the home
of Muhammed Kalabi, sir.
On Deaderick Ave.
- Yes.
- It's near the Coliseum.
The suspect was not in his apartment,
but we did find bomb-making material.
- Jesus, uh...
- Now, Mitch...
the last thing we want
is for you to panic.
You must know that you have the full
support of the federal government here.
Um, it...
Well, what... what's next?
We believe his target is
one of the voting centers.
We know
you have soldiers in place,
security measures and checkpoints.
Director Green is on his way to you.
There will be a command center
out of the FBI office in Knoxville
where we will coordinate.
My family voted
at the Coliseum this morning.
Mitch, listen to me.
Whatever you need, we will provide.
How are the Ohio numbers?
It's hard to gauge
with turnout this low.
That was kind of the point.
For the other side, not Democrats.
The governor's worried.
Do you have any numbers?
No, just what we gave you.
I would think that the president might
have access to some numbers that we don't.
When I get them, you'll get them.
- We're worried.
- Hang in there.
I'll touch base with you
after the three o'clock wave.
If you could all just give me
a moment, please. Thank you.
You better head over to the ballroom.
One of us should make an appearance.
Sir, the day has finally arrived.
Yes, and let's see
just how long this day lasts.
Imagine my surprise when the NSA called me
about Muhammed Kalabi just...
moments before you did.
Situation is still unfolding.
On Election Day?
Francis...
it's been quite a journey
working with you.
Kalabi slipped into the country,
and he's planning a terrorist attack
against a voting center in Tennessee.
And that is a terrifying proposition.
Well, I may need you to stay around
the White House a bit longer, Cathy,
until this situation is resolved.
Of course.
I was only saying...
it's been a good run.
As if she could ever get under my skin.
I don't need to get to the party just yet.
Sweaty palms,
eager to pay me their last respects.
When what they really want to do
to show their respect
is to empty their bullets in my body,
just to make sure that I'm dead.
Patti, I'm so sorry to keep you waiting.
Miss Harvey was just telling me that
there's been a change in the schedule.
Yes, unfortunately,
we're in a bit of an emergency.
Uh, but I hope it will be resolved soon.
Tom, hello.
- You know Mr. Yates, don't you?
- Yes, we met at the convention.
So LeAnn will be at the hotel.
She can reach me if you feel I need
to be there sooner rather than later.
Uh, in case it's later...
I want you to think
four years down the road.
- I'm sorry?
- They trust you.
Four years is no time.
We have a car waiting.
So we're shaking hands today?
I think it's best we keep it like that.
Well, shake it like you mean it.
How's that?
So you want me to just head
over to the ballroom?
No.
I do like looking at you
across a large room.
Victory.
This is for when you win.
I wrote a concession speech as well.
With increased security
at polling places across the country,
will fewer Americans
vote for the president this year
than in any election in recent memory?
Particular attention is being paid
to typical battleground states,
Ohio and Pennsylvania,
where voter turnout
has become a central issue
that could make all the difference
in this historic election.
You know,
if turnout is low in Philadelphia...
the Underwoods are going under.
You need a better in than that.
You look like you've been chewed up
and shit out twice today.
Seems like you're having trouble focusing.
You ever see a doctor about that?
Um, what?
Oh, 'cause I feel pretty comfortable
diagnosing you
- with too much on your fucking mind.
Hey, let me get you something real.
I'm celebrating.
Two Oban.
Celebrating what?
Oh, you know Tom Hammerschmidt's
long lead team?
You're looking at the newest member.
That guy never gives up.
Mmm. I tell you what he's up to,
feed him things from you.
Don't you think it's a little late
for quid pro quo?
Oh, the Underwoods could still win.
We'll see.
Either way,
you still have a couple more months.
Yeah.
- I'll land somewhere.
...Your phone.
Can somebody give me
a second today, you know?
Shit. Excuse me.
Hello?
...while reports are coming in
of a possible attack
at a Knoxville voting center.
Now, let's take a live look...
Tennessee?
What's going on in Tennessee?
...it's a very chaotic scene
at the moment.
What?
...there's a lot happening right now.
Police are... are, of course, trying
to keep everyone calm and safe here.
And we will bring you...
Where the hell were you?
Tennessee.
What the hell's going on in Tennessee?
Muhammed Kalabi, the ICO guy
from Syria who burned the effigy.
What's the plan?
I stand before you this evening
as vice presidential candidate,
as the First Lady of the United States,
and most of all...
as a citizen of this great country.
Despite the violent incident
at the voting center in Knoxville,
which the president
is attending to as we speak,
we want to assure anyone
who's considering not voting
that it is not only safe to vote,
it is your duty to do so.
It doesn't matter if you're a Democrat.
It doesn't matter if you're a Republican.
Our nation needs you to vote today.
Violence cannot beget apathy.
We must make our voices heard.
Seth!
Witnesses report
an FBI and Homeland presence
at the Knoxville voting center.
Do you believe this is ICO-related?
Seth, please! Come on.
- And the FBI isn't talking.
- Neither are you, Gina.
This isn't a presser,
because I didn't schedule one.
- We're just trying to find out...
- That's two, Gina.
If you're looking for a strikeout,
I'm happy to oblige.
No? Good.
There's no questions at this time.
The First Lady's statement stands as is.
I will have updates for you
on Tennessee as I get them.
Is everyone clear?
Thank you.
Seth!
I'm told everything just went wrong.
- The FBI had the bomb guys there...
- But, Mitch...
...for crying out loud!
...injuries didn't go
beyond scrapes and bruises.
Oh, I don't know about that, Shawna.
Twelve people were taken to the hospital.
Look, is there any status
on Green's ETA?
- Secretary Stewart and I...
- Yes. Just a moment, sir.
...cannot make a determination without...
- You need to take this.
What? What?
What the hell is this?
Hello.
Governor. Mark Usher here.
I think we met at the conference
in Sun Valley.
Yes, that's right.
Well, I wish I were calling
under better circumstances.
I wanted to know
what you're going to need.
I can get some excellent people
down there fast in case you...
you're feeling like you need
the extra security or...
You there?
I'm right here, yeah.
I spoke to Shawna a few minutes ago,
and we agreed that we
absolutely cannot disrupt this election.
You called my secretary of state?
Well, she called me.
She is a leader of the party
in Tennessee. As are you.
Do I need to remind you, sir,
that yours is a red state,
and every Republican in it
is counting on you?
- Thank you, Mr. Usher.
- Now, hold on.
Shawna just wanted to ask
what can be done and what can't be done.
She's like the rest of us,
trying to figure this thing out.
Because of the scale of a possible threat
which we're still trying to determine,
and because of the importance
of these, uh, voting centers,
we're asking the governor to declare
- a state of emergency...
- Will, could you please sit?
I don't like it.
Three o'clock wave said Tennessee's
locked up, no matter what.
Love, no one can see.
What the hell?
...be potentially disturbing.
They don't bark
when there's a bomb.
What do you mean, "They don't bark"?
The canine units don't bark
when there's a bomb, Mr. President.
Yeah, but the whole building heard it.
They're trained to sit down
when they detect a bomb.
- So did they sit down?
- No.
Then there was no bomb.
We think the barking was provoked.
Provoked?
Director Green, that'll be enough.
These dogs are
our last line of defense, sir.
I think ICO got in there today.
And thank God they didn't get a bomb off,
but whatever operative they got in there,
I think, was used to provoke the riot.
I said that is enough.
You think ICO
got all the way in that building
and then just decided
not to set off a bomb?
- Well, there are...
- We are not going to disrupt the voting.
Mitch, would you please
talk some sense into him?
- I...
- If we don't suspend,
the Bureau cannot guarantee
the safety of these centers.
Unacceptable. Find Kalabi.
The governor does not wanna have to
institute a curfew this late in the game.
- And, Mitch...
- Uh, yes, sir.
...you are not closing the polls.
You think we should?
I can't weigh in on this.
I need to talk to Shawna.
...How many scandals should the public
be expected to endure
before they say, "Enough"?
Before they say, "I'm staying home"?
Before they lose complete faith
in this democratic republic?
This is a trend that dates back
at least to when Nixon avoided jail time.
...Okay, we're out.
- You're good.
- I don't need fans, Sean.
Just genuine appreciation.
Would you like a drink?
One is brown and one is not.
- It's gonna be a long night.
- That's not what I hear.
So, Tennessee...
Is the question.
And?
My date knew nothing.
Are you making the rounds?
Crowd's a little older
than I'm used to, but...
yes, they're a talkative bunch...
that don't say much.
I'll take the brown one.
That's Patricia Whittaker over there.
Chairperson of the DNC.
She slapped me once in a bar in Omaha.
For the life of me, I can't tell you why.
There's something wrong with Tennessee.
Your date is either lying or denying.
What did you mean by this?
On the back of the speech?
Nothing. Forget it.
"There's still time"?
There's still time for what?
What are you doing?
You and your husband.
Getting ready to win an election.
I see the way you're acting.
Do you realize we have
every intention of winning today?
Sure.
But then what?
I used to go to this cabin... up in Maine.
The windows don't close properly.
You can smell the ocean all summer long.
I do think it's better
you go to the ballroom.
If you have not voted, I assure you,
you will get the chance.
But I cannot, in good conscience,
allow balloting to continue
until I am satisfied that it is safe.
To that end, as nightfall approaches,
I am announcing an enforced,
state-wide curfew, effective tonight.
If you are not in your home
by 8:30 p.m. central time,
or by 9:30 in the eastern parts
of this state,
you will be subject to detention
and possible arrest.
What the hell's going on?
What's going on is we're gonna win
Pennsylvania and Ohio.
That puts you over 270.
The polls are still open.
People are still voting.
My gut says they're ours.
That's 272 without Tennessee.
That asshole's
suspending the vote.
That's up to his secretary of state,
and she's on our side.
- She's gonna have a choice after this?
- Governor, listen to me.
I mean, how long
do we let Francis Underwood
get away with this kind of shit?
Huh? How long?
He won't get away with it.
...He won't.
That was Tennessee governor...
Trust me.
Bullshit.
Voting centers
all across the state are being shut down,
and anyone not in their homes
by 8:30 central time, or 9:30...
Five o'clock wave from Philly.
I think we're home.
...detention and possible arrest.
This announcement...
That Tennessee shit is crazy.
Crazy shit happens all the time.
This convenient?
Spare me the conspiracy talk.
The government's not that powerful...
or competent.
A man can ask.
We're looking at
255 Underwood, 245 Conway.
Pennsylvania and Ohio?
Still too close,
but it's almost six o' clock.
When we change Tennessee
from Conway to undecided...
- That brings Conway down to...
- Two thirty-four. Still way too close.
Yes, but we don't yet know
that he's locked in the western states.
Those states have been locked up
for ten years.
Red, red, red and they'll be red again
by the end of the night.
It's gonna come down
to Pennsylvania and Ohio.
Conway needs both.
You only need one.
Matthews?
He'll push back.
He might even go public.
What about the other five states in play?
The lawyers are waiting.
We can generate lawsuits,
argue suppression, but...
Still not enough.
Olmstead's losing in Ohio,
and he's not taking it well.
I spoke with his chief of staff,
Tanya, this morning.
He's getting clobbered
in the northern part of the state.
Low turnout in Cleveland's not helping.
But he could still pull it out.
He's not going to win and he knows it.
How much time do we have?
Ohio closes in two hours.
And most people voted this morning.
Some of these states are baked in already.
Claire and I need the room for a moment.
Yes, sir.
- LeAnn, we'll call you back.
- Yes, sir.
Why did you ask him to leave?
Because I just wanted
to look in your eyes one more time
before we do this.
Francis...
we're doing this.
He can't save us.
He invented term limits.
Doug!
...Get me LeAnn Harvey back on the phone.
Yes, sir.
Do what you have to do with Ohio.
- I'm on it.
LeAnn, get the lawyers ready.
- I can't do this.
- Yes, you can.
- No, no, no, no, no!
- And it needs to be done quickly.
It's too sloppy.
Why are you here if LeAnn called me?
Do I really have to explain to you
what will happen if you don't do this?
I don't care if he loses.
I'm not talking about the election.
I'm talking about you.
What will happen to you?
You have everything you need.
The Pastebin link was sent to you.
Where's LeAnn?
She's not here,
and I'm short on time.
Governor, I'm sorry,
but there's only one way to play this.
We need you to pull your poll workers and
your machines from those three counties.
The Republicans would crucify me.
They own that area.
But those are the precincts
that are most likely to be threatened.
"Likely to be"?
Hey, what are you...
What are we talking about here?
Terrorist chatter.
Related to Tennessee?
Yes, sir.
Well, I'm gonna need
more than your word on that.
Oh, I'm sorry, but the intelligence
is classified, Governor.
Then read me in.
'Cause I'm not doing this
without seeing tangible proof
with my own eyes.
You can tell Francis.
The other thing is,
with Ohio turnout so low,
people could accuse you
of engaging in voter suppression.
What?
The voting centers and the troops
were the president's idea.
But you signed on to them,
and that's what matters.
You're losing your election, sir.
The signs are clear.
That'd be a real shame
for the Democrats to be down a governor.
But here we have
this confluence of events.
Your disappointing returns on one hand
and the chatter on the other.
I need proof.
Otherwise, people will think...
That you shut down voting
in Republican precincts
to guarantee your own win.
Now I'd say it's a good thing that the NSA
just picked up on some credible chatter.
This dangerous world left you no choice.
Oh... thank you.
Governor, I was just handed
the classified intel.
Are you on a secure server?
- Yes, I am.
- Please hold.
I'm sending the files over right now.
You're doing the right thing, sir.
We don't want blood on our hands.
I don't care where they're taking
the voting machines.
Just stay...
You chain yourself to one of them
if you have to.
Good.
I'm gonna find an Ohio judge.
Voting centers in Ohio
have been closed for almost two hours.
And Conway's got a judge.
He's petitioning to reopen.
But even if they stay closed,
would Ohio get us there?
Other states might be in play.
Rumblings of suppression
are out there, although...
- Well, what else do we have?
- Voter intimidation in Idaho.
What do you think? Should I call them back
and have them file?
I like it.
It has the most resonance
with what's happened in Tennessee.
I also like an assemblyman
we have in Georgia.
There's a congressman in Maryland.
That's one of the states
that didn't request the troops.
But wait. Don't we need something
coming from a voter?
There's a voter in Mississippi.
Said she was too scared to vote.
That TV essentially told her not to go.
Well, that sounds like a bit of a stretch.
That could be a plus for us, sir.
Really open things up.
If Ohio stays shut,
there could be a ripple effect.
This is all uncharted territory.
All right, let's put a pin
in Georgia and Maryland,
and let's keep
the Ohio voting centers shut down,
and see where that gets us.
Pennsylvania has gone to Conway.
Even if Ohio is still too close to call
and the president does well
in the Northwest,
he can't counter
Conway's gains in the South,
in what would typically be
Underwood territory.
The people have spoken.
I can't believe this.
The president apologizes
that he couldn't be here tonight,
but he wanted me to let you know
that concession is inevitable.
All the states haven't been called yet.
The president still has time if he needs...
Guys, we fought a good fight.
But, unfortunately,
this is the reality of the situation.
- Jesus.
Well, I guess that's that.
...Yeah, this is Will.
I wanted to be
the first to tell you
congratulations, Mr. President-elect.
Well, thank you, Mr. President.
Oh, what? You think I learned
nothing from Al Gore?
We kept them on the edge
of their seats, didn't we?
I guess that means the system is working.
I guess it does.
You're about as tough an opponent
as they come, Francis.
Well, I've had a lot of practice.
Now, you be sure to give my regards
to Hannah and the children.
Thank you, Mr. President. I'm...
sure I'll be calling on you
for advice in the very near future.
Well, I look forward to that.
He conceded?
- Yeah.
...We did it.
We did it.
Excuse me, sir.
General Brockhart
is on his way over to the suite.
Thank you.
Sources are telling us
that Francis Underwood
conceded to Governor Conway
- on the phone only a short time ago.
I suspect their numbers
are matching up with ours,
which would put Ohio
in the Republican column.
Enough to make William Conway
the next president of the United States.
- Hello?
- Tanya, put him on the line.
Hang on, let me see if I can get him.
He's my secretary of state,
and he has the power to do it.
Well, then you need
to tell him what to do.
He says he can reopen
and extend the voting day into tomorrow.
Tell him it's not safe.
I've done that, Doug!
Obviously, he doesn't seem to care.
Underwood conceded already.
Do not trot out your secretary of state.
Voting cannot resume.
Now, if you have any doubt,
you swallow it right now.
I'm worried about the party.
What this could do to the party.
Roger, this is so much bigger
than the party.
I feel like I'm risking
my entire career here.
You are.
And if you don't do what I'm telling you,
it's over for sure.
What?
How many hours is it gonna take him
to spit out the fucking words in public?
Hey, screw this. Screw protocol.
I'm heading down there.
- No, you're not.
- It's already tomorrow, Mark.
I mean, this is insane.
- I want to make my speech!
- Ohio is still in play.
What?
What are you talking about?
...fear from continued terrorist threats
and the disturbing news
coming out of Tennessee...
I was forced to close
a number of our polling places.
Fuck me.
And in accordance
with the Ohio secretary of state,
the vote is suspended
until further notice.
Now, I know this may put
our electorates in question...
...but I had no choice.
New Jersey might not certify.
There's been a variety of irregularities.
Same with Illinois.
Looks like Nevada's making noises, too.
I'm having déjà vu.
You ever get that?
Are you seriously asking me
about déjà vu?
Never mind.
It's gone.
You never get déjà vu?
Everybody does.
I don't.
Don't look so worried, Doug.
You just felt familiar for a second.
It's over.
Now, the presidency
hangs in the balance.
At least six states
will not have certified vote totals
on Election Night 2016.
Good evening.
I guess I should say good morning. Um...
Will wishes he could be here himself...
but we've been advised
that goes against protocol.
I know...
you're disappointed.
Are you okay with the word disappointed?
Shouldn't we acknowledge their outrage?
I'd say we should tread lightly.
For now, we're just asking
for their patience.
Okay, let's do it.
Never a dull moment
in this country.
Will wishes he could be here himself,
but we've been advised
that would go against protocol.
I know you're disappointed
that the change you were hoping for...
...that you voted for,
has to wait a little longer.
And, finally,
a night of electoral indecision,
with lawsuits being filed
in nearly every state,
has ended with the mayor of Honolulu,
in the last state to close its polls,
refusing to honor the results
of the election and filing a lawsuit.
...Was Hawaii one of ours?
No, I don't think so.
Claire,
could you do me a little favor?
I have a splitting headache.
Could you rub my temples for a moment?
Of course.
No, actually the pain
is right behind my eyes.
Could you just...
rub my eyes for me?
But you hate that.
I know,
but I think I'll like it this time.
You can do it harder.
Even harder than that.
There's no coming back from this.
Oh, I know exactly what we're about to do.
If we fail, it's on both of us.
I won't be able to protect you.
And what a relief that will be...
for both of us.
The American people
don't know what's best for them.
I do.
I know exactly what they need.
They're like little children, Claire.
Children we never had.
We have to hold their sticky fingers
and wipe their filthy mouths.
Teach them right from wrong.
Tell them what to think
and how to feel and what to want.
They even need help
writing their wildest dreams,
crafting their worst fears.
Lucky for them...
they have me...
they have you.
Underwood.
2016.
2020.
2024.
2028.
2032.
2036.
One nation...
Underwood.
Doug, LeAnn...
do you have a moment?