The general talked about
killing the president.
That, along with Conway's outburst
on the plane...
- That sounds worse than it was.
- No, that sounds exactly as bad as it was.
What's surprising to me is...
the campaign couldn't get
their hands around this.
I mean, Harry Marshall is as good
as they come, but...
First they denied,
and then they equivocated...
I mean, that's just, like, ridiculous.
You just come out,
"I apologize. We misspoke."
Everybody knows the drill here.
And it's not like the Republicans
rushed in to save the day either.
- Uh, off message throughout.
- They got quiet.
Which I will never understand.
Will Conway was a rising star
in the party.
Look, it's hard to compete
with the Underwood machine.
Oh, God. Let's not do the whole
"black helicopters" crazy stuff.
...It's ridiculous.
Look, we need to accept
Underwood won the election.
People need to accept the outcome
and move on.
I'm gonna agree with Van.
I think we need to take a moment
to appreciate the Constitution.
- It bent, but it never broke.
- That's right.
And in the end, as we all know,
it came down to the Electoral College.
You don't have to say the words, Governor.
I think I do.
Congratulations, Mr. President Elect.
- There's no script for this one?
- Country first, sir.
I'm glad to hear you say that, Will.
I want to start to help the country
heal again.
Are we done?
We are done. But Will...
I would very much like to show the country
that our two parties can work together.
So I was hoping that you might consider
becoming my transportation secretary.
I think it would send a powerful message
if you agreed to join my cabinet.
You think I'd... make a good...
transportation secretary?
Oh, yes.
That's what you give
the congressman from nowhere.
I'll be declining.
Well, I'm so sorry to hear that, Will.
And I wanted to wish you the very best.
You and your wishes
can go fuck yourselves!
What do I do now?
...everyone thought
it would happen.
No one thought that
Underwood would win again...
I don't know.
Acknowledging defeat
is never easy.
Doing it in public
is a living hell.
- Well, at least the cameras like him.
Do I look satisfied?
You look somewhat satisfied.
- Good.
- Not good. Francis, enjoy this moment.
- You deserve it.
- You mean "we."
We made it to the other side.
Yes.
But what is on the other side?
Victory.
With a whiff of defeat.
It's taken a long time to get here,
but we're here. Cheers, Francis.
Everything gets easier from now on.
Mmm.
They're ready for you.
- Hannah.
- I don't want to go.
- Hey.
- No.
Fine.
I'll do it on my own.
I'm gonna say, this is a crucial moment.
For both of you. How you handle tonight.
The party abandoned me. Your party.
I'm not the Republican Party, Will.
I work for candidates.
I worked for you.
Listen, you lost.
But more than half the country
still considers you their president.
This is what's required.
Go down there, give your speech.
Concede.
As I accept all of your letters
of resignation
and dissolve my old cabinet,
I wanna welcome each and every one of you
to my new cabinet.
- Congratulations, Mr. President.
- Thank you, Cathy.
And I especially wanna thank my wife.
Madam Vice President...
thank you for your unending
and unwavering support.
Your steady hand kept this country
running this past month.
I owe her more than I can possibly fathom.
And she owes me.
Not true. You were with me all the way.
I would like to make my first 100 days
as the duly elected president
as productive as possible.
Of course, there are many challenges.
Shoring up the economy,
securing our nation from ICO
and reducing unemployment.
But the biggest challenge that we face,
and the one that I'm going to need
all of your help on,
is reuniting a country that has never been
more divided than it is today.
I believe we can meet this challenge,
and that's where I'm gonna need
all of your help.
So let's let the healing begin today
and let's make history together.
I thank you all
for your continued service.
Now let's get back to work.
I need a minute.
I think we should see what we can do
about making Usher persona non grata.
I don't think that's wise to start a war.
We've just won the White House.
This is exactly when we should strike.
This is a moment
that we have the political capital...
Usher needs to be managed carefully.
Mr. President?
Take a breath, Doug.
We've only just landed on our feet here.
Sir, Madam Vice President,
this is the type of person
that we used to crucify in the House.
Yes, but we're not in the House now.
We're here.
We have a full term ahead of us.
There's gonna be a great deal
that we're gonna be able to accomplish,
the three of us.
I appreciate that, sir.
But Mark Usher will become a problem.
Well, everyone becomes a problem,
eventually.
...LeAnn's out.
What?
Why?
She screwed up.
Well, is it something
I need to get ready for?
The Underwoods want this
handled indirectly.
So what exactly are we saying?
She's being pushed out.
Okay, but the campaign's over.
Is it necessary to say anything?
We need to distance this administration
from her and her work. Her tactics.
So it needs to be a leak.
Reach out to the people who don't like us.
They'll be prime to go with it.
Okay, so when we respond...
- On the record or...
- On.
What did she do?
She showed some very poor judgment.
I'm trusting you to be discreet.
We won, Seth. Changes need to be made.
You know I'm off politics.
Surprised you reached out to me.
You're a highly-respected
journalist.
Just here for the inauguration
and the parties.
Hmm.
So I imagine you've heard
that I'm on the outs.
They're not telling the whole story.
So what happened?
An acquaintance of mine stole
classified documents from the NSA
and took off to Russia.
They're blaming me for it.
What did this acquaintance take?
That's just the thing.
I have no idea.
If you could find him, talk to him,
he would tell you
that I had nothing to do with this.
Who is he? What's his name?
Aidan Macallan.
He'll talk to you.
He respects you.
Tell him that I'm okay.
That I'm going to be okay.
I'm a firm believer
in boots on the ground.
Well, we're there for the oil.
Let's not pretend.
Oh, I'm not denying how crucial it is
to protect the oil supply.
But it's in the world's best interest
that we're the ones keeping an eye on it.
- On the world or the oil?
- Both.
Oh. Well, that explains
your strong interest in Antarctica.
I do focus on things and people.
I tend to get attached, but I think
it makes me better at what I do.
And what are you focused on now?
Petrov. Ahmed Al Ahmadi. To begin with.
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
I just...
Uh... I'll run this by you tomorrow.
Yes, tomorrow.
Sorry for the interruption.
He's one of our speechwriters.
Tom Yates has quite a reputation.
Well, if his books are any indication,
he has lived quite a life.
My father wore striped socks.
Do you think the president will be
sympathetic to our agenda?
"Our agenda"? That's very presumptuous.
Well, there are regions in the world that
are important to our national security
and they have to be protected.
Would you like to join us
at the inaugural ball?
Oh, no, I can't.
Something terrible always happens
when I go to a party.
Uh, by the way,
my husband is not managed by anyone.
- That's not what I'm asking.
- Isn't it?
I'm asking for your help,
Madam Vice President. That is all.
Evening.
Oh, my God. Come in.
I'm sorry. Sit down, sit down.
Aren't we working out tonight?
Oh, I just don't think
I'm gonna have the time for it.
- But come sit for a minute.
- If you're too busy, I understand...
No, no. Join me for a minute.
I want you to hear something.
"This is the dawn of a new era.
It's a time for peace.
A time to respect the past
and embrace the future.
A time..."
Time to what?
"A time to hear all the voices.
For there is nothing more lonely...
or terrifying...
than feeling unheard."
- What do you think?
- It's interesting. I like it.
- This is for...
- My inauguration, yes.
Where does it go from there?
What do you say?
Uh, uh...
"America, I hear you.
Whether you voted for me or not,
I hear all of you."
Now, what do you think
my great-great-great-grandfather
would think of all this?
- Awesome.
- In the original sense of the word.
- Yeah.
How long you in town for?
Leaving tonight, actually.
I thought you were here
for the inauguration.
- I got a tip I have to move on.
- Mmm. What's the tip?
- Mmm-mmm.
We used to have a rule about shoptalk.
- Did we?
- Mmm-hmm.
Fair enough.
What's your read on LeAnn Harvey?
That she's hard to read.
That's what I like about her.
- You trust her?
Kate, come on.
You look tired.
I'm working eight days a week.
I mean, you always looked tired, but now
you look tired in a... not sexy way.
Sorry to disappoint.
I actually have to get back there
in a minute.
Oh, it's little late
to head back to the office, right?
I've been there since last Tuesday.
Honestly...
I know this sounds weird...
There's no place I'd rather be.
The way you say that sounds so... rote.
I don't know...
What am I supposed to say to that?
I just want to know how you're doing,
that's all.
I'm just asking about you,
this person I'm sitting with.
Where'd you go, Tom Yates?
- Hi.
- I was looking for you.
Not very hard, then.
I need to talk to you.
Okay.
I'm done.
With the speechwriting,
I don't want to do it anymore.
I want to get back to some other stuff
I was working on.
No offense. I mean,
I know writing speeches is writing...
but it's not what I really wanna do.
Okay.
You sure?
Yes.
We'll transition you out.
But you'll need to have a reason
to be here.
Special advisor? Are you kidding me?
- There's speculation that he's already...
- It's not speculation, Seth.
People know that Mark Usher
is working for us in some capacity.
- I mean, isn't that enough?
- Clean up this release.
Uh, reaching across party lines,
that sort of thing.
- And get it ready, just in case.
- Of course.
That's it.
I know you're not happy about this.
- What has he done to earn the title?
- This is not about him earning anything.
He's already getting classified memos.
Why does she want this?
"She"?
I'm sorry. The vice president.
What she wants is
for this administration to succeed.
And what I want is for you
to befriend him. Get to know him.
We want him to think he's managing us
while we're busy managing him.
She has been pursuing Francis Underwood
for a long time.
- I don't wanna talk to her.
- Aidan...
How does she even know I'm here?
Miss Baldwin is a very good journalist.
Yeah, going public
will not help you, or me.
You'll tell her how you manipulated
the American mood, hmm?
- How you helped steal an election.
- That would be it for me.
You're a valued guest
of the Russian state.
I want my passport back.
An American passport is the last thing
that will keep you safe.
I'll take my chances.
This will make you famous, hmm?
A whistle-blower.
I don't wanna be famous.
But you do want to be free.
You spent $15,000 at The Capital Grille?
What the fuck are you eating?
- This is Romero using the House Ethics...
- It's a liability.
And you should know better.
How did you not disclose this, Terry?
I want to pull him off
his committee assignments.
Put him on Science.
See how he likes NASA briefings.
I'd like to hold off on that.
Romero's about to become
an ally to the president.
And why's that?
Because he was able
to find out about your tab.
It's because he's relentless.
Because in four years,
35% of the vote in Arizona will be Latino.
Because he's the future.
This is how it starts.
I gotta get back to the Hill.
You know, Doug...
you and I, we've been around long enough
to see the guard change.
And it changes because the people
at the top forget how they got there.
Romero's trying to change the guard, Doug.
And we are the guard.
If Congressman Womack has nothing to hide,
he has nothing to fear.
We all have something to hide,
Congressman Romero.
It's time for a change in the leadership.
The president would like
to be a friend to you,
but you're making it very difficult.
We can guarantee the immigration ban
will be lifted in the next week.
Come on. Are we doing this again?
You offer me some racist gesture.
And I, what? I'm a friend forever?
Ban isn't even sustainable.
What matters to you?
- The president's attention.
- You have it.
- His full attention...
- You know, that's enough.
What is it that you really want?
I want Medicare coverage
bumped up to where it was.
There are retirees in my district.
We're here now
because you want a bump in Medicare?
Come on, Congressman.
And two seats to the inauguration.
- We are two days out.
- On the dais.
You are going about this entirely wrong.
You came here. You asked me.
I'm telling you.
I want to be there
when Francis Underwood says to me
that there will be an increase
in Medicare.
He does that, I'm his friend.
Well, I think I speak for the president
when I say that's not going to happen.
Mr. Stamper, I really appreciate
all the work you do for him,
but you and I know
that my bloc is growing.
All I'm looking for is a line
in his address.
Two seats and a line.
- The balls on him.
- I told him it was highly doubtful.
- I can get back to him with a firm no.
- Or you could give him a line.
His promises are unreliable.
Look, I know Alex.
We met on Conway's campaign.
Once he's in, he's in.
Sir, we have to be very careful
with what we're giving away.
He's capable of giving this administration
an enormous amount of grief.
He's asking for a gesture.
Oh, I'd say it's a little more than that.
I completely agree. He's going after
the people who got us here.
He's not wrong, is he?
There are some in leadership
whose time has come and gone.
Look... I'm just here to make sure
your four years turn into eight, but...
it's up to you, of course.
But we're talking about two seats...
one line...
Give him what he wants.
Alex.
Tilda. It's lovely to see you.
- How are you, Congressman?
- Oh, I'm fine.
It's good of you all to be here.
It's a big day.
Listen, why don't the two of you
take my seats?
Oh, thanks,
but we're already on the aisle.
I insist.
You'll be right in the president's
line of vision when he...
says what you want to hear.
Please. I can be anywhere.
Okay.
- Thank you, Mark.
- Sure.
I, Francis J. Underwood,
do solemnly swear...
That I will faithfully execute...
The office
of President of the United States.
The office of Pres...
Yes, here we go again.
Secretary of State. That's what I wanted.
That's all I wanted.
That's what I was promised.
And now, here I am,
President of these United States.
You made this bed, America.
You voted for me.
Are you confused?
Are you afraid?
Because what you thought
you wanted is now here.
And there you are, staring back,
slack-jawed, bewildered,
wondering if this is what
you actually asked for.
This democracy,
your democracy, elected me.
And if you think it was hard getting here,
you're beginning to understand
what I'm willing to do to stay.
I look across at this crowd gathered today
and I know that
these are not my supporters.
I'm looking at people who are waiting,
with a smile on their face,
for their turn.
And the most vicious among them
are the ones who are smiling
and clapping the hardest.
Power is a lot like real estate. Remember?
- So help me God.
America, I hear you.
I hear all your voices.
I hear your struggles, your concerns,
but most of all, I hear your hope.
Opportunity and security is
what we all want.
And in my first 100 days,
I will reach across party lines
and devote my administration,
your government, to securing them.
For too long we have ignored our seniors
and the healthcare they depend on.
That is why I am committed
to fixing Medicare
before I devote one more dime
to the program.
AmWorks was only the beginning.
We have to learn to live
without entitlements,
because we are not an entitled people.
I believe in your sweat.
I believe in your hard work.
And a job,
that's what I'll promise you today.
You couldn't give him one line?
We give no quarter
to those that are disloyal.
The message sent today
wasn't just for him.
- Alex feeds off of retribution.
- So do I.
- Is he worth the fight?
- There is no neutrality.
I expect total loyalty
or you are an enemy.
Understood, Mr. President.
What are you thinking?
# Let mortal tongues awake #
# Let all that breathe partake #
# Let rocks their silent break #
I have a soft spot
for that patriotic stuff.
Please spread your arms and legs.
Excuse me?
Otherwise, there is no interview.
And if you would please
take off your jacket.
- I'm a journalist.
- I know.
I read you when I was living in London.
- So I'm not a spy.
- I know you're not a spy.
Does anyone even use that word anymore?
So the interview won't be happening here.
- Uh, we agreed...
- We need to move you to another location.
Oh, and I'm sorry,
you cannot use your own crew.
- That's unacceptable.
- Then the interview will have to wait.
We cannot trust your people.
And you wouldn't want to endanger
Mr. Macallan, would you?
Are you coming, Miss Baldwin?
And your cell phone needs to stay here.
...Thank you.
You have a lot of support out there,
no matter what the president did
or didn't say.
There are people eager to work with you.
I should tell you...
I'm encouraging the Republicans to
restart the Declaration of War Committee,
to investigate the president.
That's bold.
- I'm not trying to impress you with that.
- It's risky.
You don't want an enemy
in the White House.
- But you're in the White House now.
And you're what to me?
Why don't you let me help you?
Everybody doesn't have to lose
for you to win, right?
Is Sean Jeffries there?
- Who's calling?
- Who's this?
I work for Tom Hammerschmidt.
I don't understand
why I was transferred to you.
The receptionist is a friend of mine.
I know him. She knows him.
Well, I've been trying
to reach him all day.
I can take a message.
- No, I'll try him later.
- Look, he doesn't work here anymore, so...
- I'm his girlfriend.
- That's all right.
- Who is this?
- Don't worry about it.
Hey, it's Seth Grayson.
I've got something for you.
LeAnn Harvey, she's being pushed out.
Yeah, she's out.
Yeah, well, you're the only one
that's got me telling you at this point.
Okay. I'm writing the release right now.
All right, bye.
Hey, it's Seth Grayson.
Yeah, I got something for you.
Kate Baldwin's people were ready to go,
but the FSB replaced the crew.
You have something on your tooth.
Do we know where they were going?
No, but they're still being tracked.
Kate Baldwin was never
supposed to talk to him.
- This interview cannot happen.
- We still have time.
No, we don't.
We need to go in.
And there might be some
unforeseen consequences.
I don't think Aidan would reveal anything
that would endanger me... or anyone else.
How far back do you and he go?
Far.
That's all.
I'm sorry it has to end this way.
I don't need your sympathy.
You almost ready?
God damn it. I can't find my "F."
Someone must have stolen it.
I'm sure it will turn up somewhere.
Tom, you look very handsome in a tuxedo.
I act like a man that can wear a tuxedo
and suddenly I'm a man
who can wear a tuxedo.
...This should do for now.
- I just saw that Eric Rawlings arrived.
- Yes.
Tom, we'll meet you downstairs
in just a few minutes.
Sure.
Stamper tells me that we'll have a bead
on Macallan's location
in about an hour or so.
I just spoke to Jane Davis.
Her contacts are ready and waiting.
- We'll have distance, Francis.
- We'll owe her.
You look very beautiful. Presidential.
You look beautiful. Vice Presidential.
Here we are.
The night of Zoe's death.
Who does that look like to you?
Just another white guy
waiting for the train.
Look closer.
I know who you think it might be, but...
I'm really not sure.
Yeah, shut that door.
Gerald Ford's son used to sneak up
these stairs to go to the roof,
play Led Zeppelin to his friends.
Teenagers are teenagers,
doesn't matter where.
And this... is where Viktor Petrov
put out his cigar.
- That guy seems like a real piece of work.
- Oh, believe me, he is.
So are you.
No, I don't know about that.
- What are you doing?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
And what are you sorry about?
I thought you wanted something
that you don't.
So what is it that you think I wanted?
We can go back up. I'm...
I'm really s...
You know, they say the most vulnerable
part of the human body...
is the throat...
and that you never really know
how you feel about somebody...
until they have their hands
around your throat.
So tell me.
How do you feel now?
Congratulations, Mr. President.
Before I forget,
LeAnn Harvey wanted me to say hello.
How is she?
Well, she wanted me to tell you
that she's... she's all right.
She's gonna be all right.
What does that mean?
She's, um, taking a leave of absence.
Well, that's what they're calling it,
but it... it seems that she's being
pushed out of the administration.
- Mmm-hmm.
- She's the one who told me you were here.
Suggested I talk to you.
LeAnn hired you, isn't that right?
Friend of the family?
Uh...
Yeah, um,
are we starting the interview now?
No, no. We're just talking.
But we should be ready soon.
I'm sorry.
Can I, uh... Can I just have a second
before we start?
- I think so. Sure. Um...
- Okay.
Um... Yeah. I'm...
I'm gonna need some air.
No, I just... I just need a second, okay?
Of course. Get some air.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey. I want your phone.
I need your phone. Take this.
One call.
One.
Hello?
LeAnn, it's me.
My God, Aidan.
I know you're in trouble.
Here's the plan.
All right. Get a pen.
Write down this number.
He... he's a lawyer.
He can get you out of the country.
Once you're in Russia, I can protect you.
I'm sorry.
Why?
Oh.
How long do I have
before they come and get me?
They're right outside.
And if I run?
Uh, people will get hurt.
You don't want to do that.
I like Texas.
Maybe it's the sun or the dust,
but people kind of squint
when they say hello.
I always liked that.
I never should've left.
You've always been very good to me.
I liked your mother.
I liked her a lot.
I'm really sorry.
Don't be.
There's a guard
on the second floor working with us.
He'll escort you to a corner
where a cab will be waiting.
Someone will open the door. Just...
get in.
So you don't miss Texas?
No, I do.
I'm trying
to find some peace with this
and you're not helping.
- Just a couple more questions.
- I'm moving, you know.
- I got a new job...
- Mr. Barnes?
They ruled your daughter's death
an accident.
I am starting to doubt that.
- Could we just go over one or two more...
- You know what?
I just can't keep doing this.
- Stop calling me, please.
The interview
will not be happening.
Someone will escort you
back to your hotel.
Mr. President.
I hope I'm not too late to the party.
I'd say you were just in time
to make your grand entrance.
Well, when all this started,
I don't think I imagined myself
- standing here with you tonight.
- Congratulations, Mr. President. Again.
- Oh, thank you.
...Um, should I wait for you?
No, no. I'll see you inside the party.
So... how's Romero?
Well, Romero wants to get the Republicans
to restart
the Declaration of War Committee.
What a lovely inauguration gift.
Don't tell me you're surprised.
I'm not.
I'll see you inside. Get a drink.
Well, don't you look stunning.
It's been a long night, Frank.
- I need to get home.
- Oh, come on. Do me the honor.
Not tonight.
No, absolutely.
- Doug! Don't you look good.
- Thank you, Madam Vice President.
- Have you seen Francis?
- Not for a little while, no, ma'am.
Well, the party's breaking up.
I want him to say goodbye to people.
- Yes, ma'am. I'll let him know.
- Um, Doug?
I have a question for you.
Just a small thing.
- What is it?
- Why weren't you at the beheading?
- What?
- The night James Miller was beheaded.
We were all there, the four of us.
Francis, Tom, LeAnn and myself.
Why not you?
You see Francis,
tell him I'm looking for him.
Yes, ma'am.
- I thought you got lost.
- No. I just needed a break.
- Shall we bid our guests farewell?
- No, the night is young.
Look what I found.
They're restarting the committee.
I thought we killed that committee.
Nothing ever really dies
in the House.
It just plays in front of a smaller
and smaller audience.
- This is serious.
- I know.
But let's enjoy the rest of the party.
Hey.
What do you do here?
I work for them.
The president asked me to make sure
that you get home safely.
- I have a car for you.
- I thought I'd stay a little while longer.
The president has
an early morning tomorrow. Right this way.
The tour guide?
- What?
- Yes.
WTF. What am I supposed to do
about the tour guide?
The press briefing room, Tom, really?
I didn't think anyone would care.
Well, should I... keep her on
or let her go?
I mean, it was rather unprofessional
on her part.
She's good at her job.
Tom...
don't cheat on my wife.
Mr. Barnes?
Do you want to get a coffee
somewhere away from this?
I keep thinking about what you said.
I found this with her things.
It was Father's Day...
the last time I heard from her.
We weren't close.
I was surprised she called.
I mean, I was happy, of course, but...
Can I hold on to this?
I didn't know...
that she was in trouble.
When the police asked if I thought
she was suicidal, I said, "Maybe."
I didn't know her, really.
Neither did I.
I'll look into this.
Okay.
Thank you.
Politico. Five minutes on Morning Joe.
- Was a press release really necessary?
- You're taking a leave.
The press release said
that you were taking a leave
to consider your career options.
This has to look real. You know that.
What if they need to meet with me?
Then they'll meet with you.
I could have security escort you out.
So since Usher is special advisor now,
where does that leave you?
Like I said,
they'll call you if they need you.
I can be a friend to you, you know.
- It doesn't have to be like this.
- I don't have any friends.
I landed him
at the Jordanian Embassy in Paris.
When do we plan to get him out?
Well, as I understand it,
you don't yet know
what Mr. Macallan may have told
President Petrov.
I want Macallan back here
sooner rather than later.
It's better if these things don't happen
on American soil.
- Yes, but I make those decisions.
- Of course, Mr. President.
And rest assured,
neither of your fingerprints
are anywhere near this.
So what do we do about LeAnn?
She's been involved in election fraud,
for Christ's sake.
She's made a lot of mistakes.
- Yes, but lots of people have.
- Yes, but some people run their course.
It's hard to know who to trust these days.
Isn't it?