Why do you keep playing with that?
Because I'm skeptical.
Do you think this really works?
Oh, it's just about
making the candidate seem familiar,
so that the voter sees herself in him.
But... you've gone too far.
There.
Congratulations, Francis.
You have my vote.
- When do you leave for New York?
- Now.
- Then I'm back for the event with Cathy.
- Mmm.
It's very risky, what Macallan is doing.
Do you think it's worth it?
- Danton and Sharp just lawyered up.
- They don't want to testify?
And there's no way subpoenas get them
in front of the committee
before the election.
There's a rumor the committee's trying
to make a deal with Garrett Walker.
No, Walker doesn't want
to do damage to the party.
So why did Jim Matthews agree to appear?
I'm already getting pummeled
with questions about it.
- Does he have anything to say?
- Uh, even if he pleads the Fifth,
they get a perp walk
that implicates the president.
I didn't know anyone actually ate those.
I look forward to this stuff all year.
Do we have anything
on the committee members?
Nothing too juicy yet, I'm afraid.
Vice chairman had an affair
with a young male staffer
before he came out to his wife. Old news.
Committee chairman's squeaky clean
other than a minor back-tax issue.
I did find some revenge porn
on the chairman's chief of staff,
but I don't think it's worth much.
Is it enough to scare her?
Embarrass her, probably.
More than that, probably not.
I gotta say, they look
a lot better on you, Mrs. Underwood,
than they would on Governor Conway.
Maybe that's why
he didn't wanna pay for it.
These masks will be distributed
to all MTA engineers,
conductors and maintenance workers.
And this model is highly effective
in case of a chemical attack.
And I believe Mayor Adalardi would like
to say a few words.
Absolutely.
Safety in all branches
of the public transportation system
is my number one priority.
- Ken?
- That means subways, that means buses...
- It's fine, I know him.
What are you doing here?
- What? This is my stop.
- Oh.
- Well, you look well.
- Well, I can't complain.
Can't complain, except...
Well, I'm sure you heard about Tim.
Corbet? No.
- Beth didn't call?
- No.
Oh, man.
I hate to be the one to tell you this.
Tim went out on the Arkansas River.
He's been missing for two days now.
I thought for sure
the president would have heard.
I mean, I can't imagine
how Frank's gonna take this.
Oh, my goodness!
Beth and the kids must be so distraught.
Sure. But Frank and Tim's relationship
was special.
It's great to see you, Claire.
Would you ask Frank to give me a call?
- Mrs. Underwood?
- Uh, just one moment.
See that gentleman I was speaking to?
Go ask him to wait for me, please.
Governors,
we are running out of time.
The fact that you are here at this
emergency meeting on such short notice
tells the American people that you are
as concerned about their safety as I am.
Terror is unacceptable.
I do not accept it.
But we will not be deterred
by Washington's failure to address it.
We will work together,
side by side, fighting back.
State by state, city by city,
neighborhood by neighborhood.
Because, make no mistake...
we are engaged in the battle of our time.
The question of what it is
to be an American,
the very essence of American-ness,
how we choose to lead our lives,
open and free, is on the line.
Fear is un-American.
And yes, the irony of saying those words
to you on Halloween, of all days,
is not lost on me.
But although we may choose, as Americans,
to scare ourselves once a year for fun...
no one else tells any American when
to shake in their boots at any other time.
So I am issuing an executive order,
by virtue of the authority vested in me
as President of the United States
and commander in chief
of the armed forces.
By our Constitution
and the laws of our land,
including Section Blah-Blah
of the Blah-Blah Act
and Section Blah-Blah of Title Blah-Blah,
Paragraph Bullshit-Bullshit.
In case you have no idea what's going on,
I'm swelling these states'
National Guard troops
to create secure public spaces
on Election Day.
I'm urging these governors
to consolidate their polling sites
and create quote, unquote "voting centers"
so that people feel safe
to come out and vote.
I'm commending Governor Sally Morrison
of the great state of Arizona,
for giving us all such a good example
of voting centers
as used in their recent primary.
But what I'm really doing is
seducing the governors of five key states.
New Jersey, Nevada, Illinois,
Ohio and Pennsylvania.
Messrs. Harcourt, Nuñez, Gallinard,
Olmstead and Matthews.
Oh, you remember Matthews, don't you?
Former vice president
to President Garrett Walker.
Nothing but a provincial
and petty pen-stealer.
But I need him.
I need all five on my side
if I'm gonna win this election.
Matthews, in our history,
he's the biggest known unknown.
Oh, and I almost forgot.
The boy wonder is here.
My worthy opponent.
Out of his element and stuck in mine.
But, you see, in politics,
stature is everything.
And wouldn't you say that
Willy C is getting shorter by the minute?
These border restrictions
the president is proposing...
should the military play a role
in enforcing them, General?
I think we need to take a step back
and look at
our national security priorities.
And what constitutes appropriate
deployment of our serving men and women.
As veterans, this issue is a personal one
for Governor Conway and me.
- Would you and...
- I'll tell you something else.
You won't hear this
from the governor himself,
but his military career is distinguished
by exceptional acts of bravery.
In particular, the incident for which he
was awarded the Purple Heart stands out.
Speaks to the kind of commander in chief
he will be.
Demonstrates what I call fearless wisdom.
Someday soon, America needs
to hear the full story of that day.
Thank you for your time,
General Brockhart.
Glad to talk to you.
Coming up next on Special Report,
we take a look at...
I swear to God, if Underwood puts soldiers
on those borders,
I'll be the first to tell them
not to listen.
In terms of allocation of funds,
it's our water supply
that keeps me up at night.
Roger, are you talking about
protecting the infrastructure?
Infrastructure and water sources.
Reservoirs, the dams,
the tunnel delivery systems...
All of it, yes.
Protection from terrorism, sure,
but the voters see even greater dangers.
Structural, environmental,
toxins from algae.
Algae's quite a problem for us.
The big question here,
are the feds doing all they can do?
Well, the feds want to do even more.
That's the reason
that we're all meeting here today.
Now, look, gentlemen, all I can see
is that we're in violent agreement
with each other.
I mean, Roger,
how long have we known each other?
How far do we go back?
You knew me when I had hair,
Mr. President.
It doesn't change the fact
that my constituents are saying,
"Give me a bridge, not a war zone."
All I'm saying is that
we need to anticipate threats
when we can and thwart them.
I'm saying that we're days away
from an election,
and I don't wanna upset the apple cart.
- Excuse me for just a moment.
Will, have you seen this?
All right.
I'll deal with him later.
- Tell me exactly what she said.
- Just that she heard it from Ken Caswell.
I checked with the local authorities
in Salida, sir.
It doesn't look good.
- The chances of...
- Amp up the search.
Whatever materials and personnel they need
in addition to what they have, give them.
And reach out to Beth Corbet.
I'd like to speak to her directly.
Yes, sir.
I haven't slept
a good night's sleep since 2012.
But I guess elected officials don't sleep
so our constituents can.
The proof of success in fighting terror...
is something the public never hears about.
A certain city in my state wears
the biggest target in the nation.
The city and state of New York...
has scored silent wins for 15 years...
without a declaration of war.
Now...
in most cases...
I would argue
the states can take care of themselves.
- Mr. President!
- Well, by all means, continue, Governor.
What... what was that part
you were talking about? Insomnia?
My point is,
we're all Americans in this room,
and we all love this country.
And I'd like to thank the president
for the opportunity
to discuss this very important topic,
and apologize for, uh,
being on such a tight schedule.
Well, we are enormously grateful
that the governor took the time
to come and join us today.
I'm just trying to understand.
Claire, if I said anything
to offend you, it was entirely...
I mean, you know me. No filter.
And that's what worries me.
I'm just operating on instinct, Ken.
- Did you come down here with an agenda?
- No. I mean...
I have been trying to reach Frank,
but today was just...
I saw that you were appearing at an event
and I showed up to say hi.
I... I really do work around here,
on a street called "Wall," you know?
But then you made reference to something
about two very close friends
that's nobody's business, including yours.
And you even said so yourself, Ken,
that you have an awfully big mouth.
I...
I lost a dear friend.
I loved Tim. Everybody did.
And you implied Francis especially.
Well, yeah. I mean...
That was a whole other thing.
In what way?
In...
What do you want me to say?
I'm sure
I don't know anything you don't.
I'm just very interested
in your perspective.
Frank worshipped Tim,
would have done anything for him.
I don't know.
If the world were a different place
back then... who knows?
That was a long time ago.
And then he met you.
And lucky him.
Look, in terms of my firm and...
and trying to get the president's ear...
I mean, yeah, it's a little embarrassing
that my friend of 30-whatever years
didn't have time to pick up the phone.
He should have called you back.
Francis and Tim were very good friends.
But, you know, Ken, the older I get,
I learn that assumptions are dangerous.
Sure. Okay.
It was great to see you.
So where is she?
Change of plans.
She needed to stay in New York.
She asked me
to put something together for this.
Yeah? Well, something came up.
The vice president will be
filling in for her.
Oh, my...
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
Uh, we played in a terrible band
together back in the day.
Before adulthood and alimony
came crashing down.
- Two exes? Wow.
- Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
So, uh, where's the First Lady?
- Something came up.
- Hmm.
I'd love to ask you a few questions
about working on the campaign.
I'm just a speechwriter.
Exactly.
How the hell did that happen?
Welcome to
the Council on Foreign Relations
and this special event
on Crossing Borders: The Way Forward.
I smell a swing state party.
Tone, Rick.
You didn't have to round up dozens of
governors just to talk to the five of us.
You're here because
there have been concerning threats
in exurban counties
in each of your states.
Could you be more specific?
We're keeping an eye on Hunterdon,
Elko, Jefferson counties.
Also Chester and McHenry.
Which is why it's crucial that we work
with your states' administrations
leading up to the election.
Every one of those precincts is
a typically Republican stronghold.
This isn't about party affiliation.
As the president said,
this is about security.
Now, we believe this course of action,
the voting centers
with the added law enforcement,
will give us everything that we need
to protect the integrity
of the ballot box.
Okay, but speaking for Governor Olmstead
and maybe all of our bosses,
how can we be sure that these measures
won't discourage everyone
from getting to the polls?
- I.e., Democrats.
- It's a chance we have to take.
But we don't believe
it'll play out that way.
We're in an extremely close race in Ohio.
Preventing further acts of terrorism
is just about all that matters, Tanya.
Now, I do realize
with these heightened threats
comes an additional strain
on the governors of your states.
So...
I say to each and every one of you...
tell me how we can help.
Putting aside
the very real moral questions,
how is shutting down the borders
even feasible?
I know this policy is going to hurt
some people,
but let me explain why it's necessary.
And the vice president should
feel free to jump in.
But is it fun?
- Putting words in the Underwoods' mouths?
- That's not what I do.
It's more like the opposite.
I just try and articulate...
what's on their minds and in their hearts.
That's how you see your job?
Basically, my job is to remain invisible.
Were you with them that night?
The night Jim Miller was killed?
I'm not gonna answer that.
- I'll take that as a "yes."
- Don't.
I'm just trying to understand
what you do.
Then you're missing the point.
I'm not the story, Steve. I'm just not.
You make yourself sound replaceable.
I am.
- I serve at the pleasure of the president.
- And the First Lady?
The Democratic
vice presidential candidate...
Yeah. Her, too.
But you write speeches for both of them?
Most often for Mrs. Underwood.
Articulating what's on her mind
and in her heart?
Mmm-hmm.
- I'm just a mouthpiece.
- Mmm.
Has she put you in charge
of any other parts?
Wow.
You're still an asshole, man.
Good luck with the alimony.
- That was rough.
- It went fine.
It's not sustainable.
I mean, what do you think?
- About what?
- About the president's rush to war.
At least half the Beltway seems to think
it's outrageous.
It is outrageous.
We could resign our posts,
you know, in protest.
I bet we can convince others
of the cabinet to do the same thing.
Outrageous by design, I was going to say.
It's smart, what the president's doing.
- It's serving him in the polls.
- Donald.
Let's... take a step back for a moment.
I underestimated you. I did.
When you were acting president,
my faith was less than full.
But now, I understand
the terrible box you were in, the forces...
Cathy, I'm gonna... I'm gonna stop you.
I honestly don't know
what you're talking about.
Are you telling me your plan is just
to phone it in until January 20th?
Come on, Donald. What's happened to you?
Back in the day,
you and Marjorie were at the forefront
of every progressive cause,
literally fighting the good fight.
These people...
can we really let them do this?
You wanna walk down memory lane,
Cathy? Okay.
Remember the convention?
Remember the Politico article?
I offered you an out.
You should've taken that opportunity
to resign, then and there.
- Circumstances were nothing like this.
- Sure they were.
You just didn't want to see it.
And, just so you know,
right before her mind was truly gone,
Marjorie called it.
She saw the unholy alliance
you were making with Frank Underwood.
She called it.
So this meeting
between our bosses today...
The president is looking forward
to a productive discussion
with Governor Matthews.
There's no one else here.
Can we cut the crap?
You want us to engage
in voter suppression.
It's not a phrase I'd ever use.
Fine. Call it "motor depression"
for all I care.
We get it. White people are the problem.
Republicans. Understood.
But my boss doesn't happen to be
up for reelection.
I'm listening.
I have two words for you. "Slag heap."
Matthews wants the EPA
to name a slag heap
on the outskirts of Philadelphia
as a Superfund site.
I seriously doubt
that can happen before the election.
I think you should battle
your doubts, Doug.
The governor is willing
to let the past stay in the past.
But unless the Underwood administration
is bearing top-tier gifts,
you've got a lot of fucking nerve
asking for favors from the former VP.
On the other hand,
if you make things right,
Matthews will do his part.
Don't you always feel sorry
for the horse?
Who's in the conference room?
- You mean the lady brigade?
- What?
That's what they call
the NSA forensic auditors.
Yeah, I... I didn't know
they were scheduled for today.
That's their routine. They just show up.
Welcome to the NSA.
Hey, boss.
Oh.
May I, Mr. President?
Well, that's what
they're there for.
I won't take up much of your time.
I know you have a busy afternoon.
- Well, I've got a little time.
- I'm curious.
Why do you think the committee
decided to call you first?
Because I asked them to.
Well, this emergency governors' conference
of yours came up and, uh...
I'm sure you recall,
I don't much like DC,
so I figured why not make it
one-stop shopping?
Yes.
But, of course,
we both know that executive privilege
could've negated your having to appear
at one of those shops.
Jim?
I'm going to help you with your slag heap.
I hope that means that I can count on you.
Of course that's what it means.
We're members of a tiny brotherhood,
you and I, of ex-VPs.
When, and if, Garrett Walker appears
before this committee,
do you think he'll...
betray the party?
- You mean you?
Well, that would be the same thing.
Now, I don't know what really happened
on your journey to replace me
as vice president
and then Garrett as president.
I only know what my gut tells me.
But I'm willing to say fuck my gut.
Bottom line is I can help you
with this committee or I can hurt you.
Now, I can say that I know nothing...
and that what I saw in Garrett Walker
was a troubled man.
And I can leave it at that.
What do you think?
Oh, I can't tell you what to do, Jim.
But I can say, as one ex-VP to another,
that this cleanup in Pennsylvania
is gonna be worth about
$300 million and 10,000 jobs.
And that's not bad
for an afternoon's work.
I like the new rug.
Oh, thank you.
I didn't have much to do with it.
It was really Claire's design.
- Good to see you, Mr. President.
- You, too.
Governor Scanlon.
Mr. President.
You've been on my mind.
I wanna talk to your boss
about the Declaration of War Committee.
So... if you're hoping to intimidate him
because of the back taxes,
you can save your breath.
His closet is back to being clean.
What about yours?
- You're a pig.
- Hey, I didn't watch it.
I'm just the messenger.
- Be mad at the dude who posted it.
- I am.
There are ways to get rid of it.
It's a goodwill gift.
To let you know I'm serious.
Look, I'm guessing, sooner or later,
I get called.
And if that happens,
I could plead the Fifth.
I could press-secretary them all day long.
But I'd like to have another option
on the table.
Yeah, I can't be
a public witness myself...
but if you offer me
anonymity and immunity...
I can testify privately.
Tell the committee
where the bodies are buried, so to speak.
But, just to be clear, you're telling me
you have evidence the president engaged
in criminal activity?
Not evidence regarding the president, no.
I have a lot of information
about his chief of staff.
Doug Stamper.
Talk to your boss. Let me know.
Uh, Bridget, total non sequitur...
You have a very elegant neck.
Mr. Grayson?
Sean Jeffries. I'm with the Herald.
Sorry, I don't have a free hand.
- How long have you been with the paper?
- Thirteen months. Style section.
Oh, that would explain
why I don't know you.
Man's tie is a window into his soul.
We just ran a piece on it.
Oh, yeah?
So, uh, what does my tie say about me?
It says you're a dedicated civil servant
with the bank account to prove it.
Anyway, recognized you,
just wanted to say hi.
I mean, unless we can buy you a drink.
You know, uh, Cam Lawder?
Lobbyist for Mercedes-Benz?
Next to him is, uh, Kim Feldshuk,
works at the DoD.
And that's Randy Beauford.
Personal trainer for fat Washington fucks.
We're going old school this afternoon.
Come on, join us for a quick one.
"Mouthpiece"?
I don't know why he was talking
to the press in the first place.
An unfortunate choice of word
for Tom, no doubt.
But still, it'll play itself out.
But what I want to know is,
what do you see?
Why don't you like Yates?
Uh, Tom is an important part of the team.
His speeches have been...
Oh, look.
He has more responsibilities than that.
You know it. So that bothers you.
I... just wouldn't want anyone to infer
a personal investment on his part
that isn't useful to the campaign.
I suppose all I'm saying is that
I won't let anything happen
to the First Lady or you, Mr. President.
I appreciate that, LeAnn.
We are fucked, Mr. President.
Pardon my French.
I don't care about your French.
Why am I even talking to you?
Well, the NSA
has sent in auditors.
If I don't erase my files,
cover my tracks...
We're a week away from the election,
Mr. Macallan.
- Cover your tracks.
- Okay. In which case,
I need to let hackers temporarily invade
a Capital East Telecom switching center.
Meaning what?
Well, the center covers
most of the US government cyber traffic.
But if I'm in and out in 20 minutes,
I think the damage will
look mischief-level.
Messed-up connections, that sort of thing.
- What if it takes you longer?
- Uh, it won't,
because another ten, 20 minutes and...
Do it.
All right.
Well, I'll start it at 4:00 p.m.
Uh, as soon as I'm done,
I'll anonymously send out
a fix to the problem.
- No.
- Sir?
LeAnn will contact you
about when to send out the fix.
- You'll wait for her.
- Okay, but just to be...
She'll let you know.
Oh.
I just saw the Haines article.
I have no idea what Tom was thinking.
Yes.
It was sloppy.
Agreed. I'll talk to him.
Are you all right?
How was New York?
My events went well.
And? What aren't you telling me?
I bumped into Ken Caswell.
- Does he know any more?
- No, um...
- Why didn't you call him back?
- What?
His Treasury business.
The oversight legislation.
I understand you don't care about it.
Fine.
But you can't ignore loose ends like that.
You owed him your ear.
Well, I didn't realize it was gonna
become so personal.
I am the President of the United States,
for Christ's sake. I'm a bit busy.
The past doesn't disappear
on command, Francis.
Not even for presidents.
What did he say to you?
Ken's got a big mouth.
I'm sorry about Tim. I'm sorry he's gone.
I know how you felt about him.
Or, I can imagine.
Listen to me.
You know you're the only person
I've ever truly loved.
You know that, right?
And listen.
Something else is about to happen.
Welcome back.
Reception is sketchy. Good trip?
I just came back to get changed.
I need to get back to Francis.
You mad at me?
You shouldn't have said that.
I know. I know we need to be careful.
Careful is far too small a word
for what we need to be.
Okay.
But don't you get tired of being
far bigger than careful all the time?
- I don't know what's going on.
- Me neither.
Seems to be some kind of
network disturbance.
I lost connection on my server.
You know what I'm tired of?
This role. First Lady.
'Cause it's never felt right.
It's only eight more days
to the vice presidency.
- Mmm-hmm. What's my role?
- What?
What am I to you, anyway? Or you, to me?
I mean, are you my girlfriend?
And when you win...
does that make me, like, First Boyfriend?
First Concubine?
About that article... I'm sorry.
I hate apologies.
I'm sorry.
I looked over at you.
I watched you watching.
- When?
- Did it even affect you?
The beheading?
- Why would you ask that?
- I had no sense of what you were thinking.
None.
Of what I was thinking? I wasn't thinking.
I was thinking, "Don't think."
And I'll tell you something else.
I never said I like being careful.
- God damn it.
- What's wrong?
The GPS thinks
we're back at the White House.
- Did you reach the campaign office?
- Trying. I can't get a signal.
Oh, wait. Here we go.
I can't miss this flight.
- It's ringing.
- Good.
- How long do you think?
- Now it stopped.
There's a pile-up on the highway.
I'm doing the best I can.
Hello?
Hello!
- Tanya, let me try your phone.
- I'm having the same issues.
- Can you get through to the office?
- No, Governor, I can't.
Garrett is a good man.
- A trustworthy man?
- Absolutely, Mr. Romero.
And is he the kind of man
who would knowingly participate
in campaign finance fraud?
I wouldn't say that, exactly. No.
How well do you know
President Underwood, sir?
I've known the president four years.
Isn't it a fact
that it was Francis Underwood
and not President Walker who first
suggested you should resign?
To the best of my recollection, no.
And isn't it true that the source
of campaign funds you received
as the president's running mate
was connected
to a pay-for-play scheme that reached
all the way from Missouri to China?
To the best of my knowledge, no.
Did you receive any campaign donations
through Raymond Tusk's firm, Clayton West?
Not to the best of my recollection.
Do you think your recollection
or knowledge will improve
as the day goes on?
Excuse me?
Beth.
I want you to promise me
that you'll call me
anytime you need anything.
You were the love of Tim's life,
you know that.
Well, I should probably...
Yes. You, too.
Goodbye.
Thank you, Felix.
Uh, would you like me
to prepare it for you, sir?
No, I'll be fine. Thank you.
The first question to ask yourself...
"Is the damper open?"
Never allow yourself
to be overcome with smoke.
Conflagration relies on airflow.
That's what the grate is for.
Now, I like a one-inch base of ash.
It's helpful, but of course they clean up
around here too soon to do that.
Now, as for the architecture of the logs,
I prefer the upside-down method.
Largest logs right along the base.
Then medium-size logs after that.
Small logs.
And then finally, kindling...
and tinder.
Now, of course, back home,
dead palmetto fronds are ideal.
But, of course, here in Washington,
we have to use whatever garbage
we find lying around.
But then, if a man cannot use
what's right in...
God damn it, Tim.
If a man is not smart enough to be able
to use whatever is in front of him
and still make it work...
well, then...
that's just a failure of the imagination.
...right here. And I'm thinking...
"Wait, do I tell him? Do..."
Uh, I gotta take this.
Hey.
Your testimony can't be private.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Just wanted to let you know.
What's a "flash blood warning"?
It's coming up on everybody's phones.
Thanks for the drinks.
Tom, stop. No. I... I have to get back.
Come on.
No.
Tom!
And, finally,
you strike your match...
you ignite your kindling...
and then you blow.
It's happening, sir.
Citizens should be advised,
a wave of disruptions is
currently affecting
Internet and cellular service
in the DC area.
Expect traffic and travel delays
as authorities are still trying
to determine the scope of the problem.
- Are we gonna make this flight?
- I don't know.
Unconfirmed reports speculate
the disruptions may be connected
to a cyber-attack
with possible ties to ICO.
- My God.
- What?
Maybe they were right.
Maybe we should have said yes
to the offer of those troops.
National Guard on patrol makes us look
weak right before an election. Forget it.
- But, Governor...
- I made my decision, Tanya.
Not yet.
They're patching through the heads
of all the carriers, sir.
Gentlemen and ladies, can you hear me?
Yes, Mr. President.
Good. Then tell me how in God's name
this has happened.
Uh, we don't know yet, sir.
We're still working on the problem.
We're reaching out
to as many people as we...
Did we just lose them?
Is this a joke?
The Ohio governor is calling
from a payphone.
This is the president.
Mr. President, I've changed my mind.
If the offer's still open,
I'd like to accept additional troops
for the state of Ohio.
Just say the word, Roger.
Whatever you need.
My fellow Americans, the facts are these.
The greater District of Columbia area
and the immediate region beyond
have undergone what we suspect is
an ICO-sponsored cyber-attack.
The attack was aimed at the district's
main telecom switching center.
In addition to intermittent outages,
a considerable amount of havoc
has been wreaked.
Traffic lights have been disabled.
One area train has been derailed.
The system that maintains our sewers
has been tampered with.
The perpetrators were
targeting the government
and their ultimate purpose, though foiled,
was to disrupt all
mid-Atlantic transportation networks.
Events like these underscore the urgency
of my request to Congress
for a declaration of war.
Tonight, I can only suspect Congress will
spend a dark night of the soul,
after which they will reconsider
their paralysis and choose to act.
Capital East Telecom has informed me
that it's repairing the network
as fast as possible,
but that it will take at least
a couple more days to be fully restored.
It is an unfortunate but undeniable fact
that we will continue
to experience attacks until ICO
and other terrorist groups like it
are eliminated swiftly and completely.
Thank you. May God bless you.
And may God bless
the United States of America.
We off?
- Good evening, Ted.
- Hi, Hannah.
I saw your interview.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't
bring up the details of my combat record.
You were a hero that day.
You should use it, Will.
Governor,
aren't you worried about
bringing your kids out
in the middle of a terrorist attack?
It'd be scarier to keep the kids at home.
The streets are safe. Life goes on.
You've got to be kidding me.
What's on your mind, Governor?
What's on my mind?
I mean, you see what's going on here.
This is all him.
It's a man who's never served.
Wouldn't know what a real war was
if it jumped up and bit him in the ass.
I mean, a declaration of war?
He's putting American lives in danger.
- War is real!
- Nightcap?
- You don't screw around with it.
- Why not?
This is what happens.
This is what happens
when you throw around a word like "war."
All hell breaks loose.