Chapter 10 - "The Unknown"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Oh!
Huh?
- Greg?
- Did you fetch for me
- the Golden comb?
- Will that work?
- This is a honeycomb.
- Golden comb of honey.
Greg! Oh!
Oh!
- Gre-e-g!
- Huh?
Never mind that, Gregory.
You've brought me the first two items ...
a golden comb and
a spool of silver thread.
It's just spider web on a stick.
- Now I want the sun.
- The sun?
Here.
Lower the sun out of the sky
- and into this China cup.
- Uh, well, that sounds impossible.
Anything is possible if you
set your mind to it, right?
But hurry, the sun will
- be setting soon, and ...
- Hey, yeah, that's it.
* Duh dih-dunh *
* dunh-dunh din-dunh *
* duh din-din dunh *
See, that old sun's going
right down into this old cup.
You have figured it out, and
I thought you might give up.
Give up? I'll never give up.
Just got to wait, just got to wait.
Yes, just sit there
in the cold and wait.
Huh?
- Ohh.
- What the...
- Ohh. Ohh.
- Beatrice?
- Wirt!
- Beatrice!
- What are you doing out here?!
- I saw Greg!
- What?!
- I saw Greg.
He was w-with someone.
This way!
- Or wait. Um...
- Beatrice, you should go home.
I can't ... not yet.
Not until Greg is safe.
- Okay.
- We should hurry.
- I ... I think it was that way.
- Thank you, Beatrice.
Ohh.
Here! Edelwood!
You see? This will give
us some oil, won't it?
Yes, we'll keep that light of
yours shining, won't we?
Come on.
Ohh!
Aw! You...
Oh! Oh!
* ...darkness *
* there is a light for
the lost and the meek *
* hard woe and fear *
* are easily forgotten *
* when you submit
to the soil of the Earth *
Woodsman, I knew you would come.
I have something for you.
Oh! Oh!
What have you done?!
Why, I've given you another edelwood.
- No!!
- He will burn nicely in the lantern.
No! I won't do this!
You've been grinding up lost
souls for years.
I didn't know!
I didn't know this is where
the edelwood trees came from!
And would it have mattered?
Would you have just let your
daughter's spirit
burn out forever?
Feed the lantern.
- No.
- I suppose, after all these
years, you just don't
care for her anymore.
Hold your tongue, or I'll
remove it from your mouth!
Do not speak of my daughter.
She would not wish this.
- Let's get you free.
- Ahh.
No.
I only wish to help you, woodsman.
You need oil,
- or else your daughter will ...
- I told you to hold your tongue!
Greg?
- Greg!
- I thought it was this way.
- A light.
- A lantern.
It looks like the woodsman's.
- Whoa. What happened here?
- Greg!
Greg! Are you...
- Wirt?
- Oh, Greg!
Wirt, I did it.
I beat the beast.
Aw, geez, the leaves are even
- growing inside of him.
- No.
I was just eating leaves.
I'm sorry, Wirt.
No, no, Greg.
It's my fault we ended up here.
Everything's been my fault.
- I-I should have been more ...
- No, I mean
- my rock facts rock.
- What?
I ... I stole it, Wirt.
I stole it from Mrs. Daniel's
garden. I'm a stealer.
- And that's a rock fact.
- What?
- No, Greg, that doesn't matter.
- It does matter.
You have to return it for me, okay?
No, you can give it to her yourself.
Come on, we got to get
Jason Funderberker home, right?
Jason Funderberker ...
the perfect... frog name.
- Greg? Greg?!
- Let's get him out of this! Come on!
Yeah. Yeah...
- Come on!
- It's gonna be fine, Wirt.
Give me my lantern.
- Your lantern?
- No way. We need this thing.
Yeah, I'm keeping this.
I have to get Greg home.
Your brother is too weak to go home.
He will soon become part of my forest.
- I won't let that happen!
- Well, then, perhaps we
- better make a deal.
- Deal?
- Ohh.
- I can put his spirit in the lantern.
As long as the flame stays lit,
he will live on inside.
Take on the task of lantern bearer...
or watch your brother perish.
Come here.
- Okay.
- Wirt!
Wait. That's dumb.
- What?
- That's dumb.
I'm not just gonna just wander
around in the woods
- for the rest of my life.
- I'm trying to help you.
You're not trying to help me.
You just have some weird obsession
with keeping this lantern lit.
I-It's almost like your soul is
in this lantern.
Are you ready to see true darkness?
Are y...
Are you?
Don't! Don't!
Here, woodsman.
I've got my own
problems to take care of.
This one's yours.
My brother and I are going home.
She was never in the lantern,
was she, beast?
Listen, woodsman.
Listen to me.
- Wirt...
- Come with us.
I ... I got to go home, too,
admit to my family it's my fault
they're bluebirds.
- What?!
- The scissors that'll make
- your family human again.
- You had them all along?!
I-I used them to escape
Adelaide, and then ... then...
Yeah, I-I was sort of mad at you.
Oh, you...
wonderful mistake of nature!
You see, woodsman?
All who perish here will become
trees for the lantern.
Cut them down with your ax.
Go! Now!
No!
Stop!
You'll never see your daughter
again, woodsman.
Are you really ready to go back
to that empty house?
No! Woodsman!
- Goodbye, Beatrice.
- Goodbye, Wirt.
* One is a bird *
* two are the trees *
* three is the wind in the leaves *
- Help.
- Wirt!
* Four are the stars *
- # Five with the moon #
- Wirt? You ok?
- Can you see me, Wirt?
- Hmm. Where am I?
- The hospital.
- Hosp... ital?
- Greg! Where's Greg?!
- And then... Wirt!
I was telling them about the
time we almost got ...
Yeah, and you were there, too,
Jason Funderberker.
- Me?  - Not you.
Jason Funderberker, my frog.
Our frog.
- Our frog.
- Our frog?
- No, not your frog.
- Hey, so... uh... about this...
Yeah, so, I don't have a
tape player, so...
- Uh, yeah.
- So maybe we can listen to this...
You can listen to it at my
house. Yes.
Maybe ... Maybe we should listen
to some other tapes first,
though, and sort of
work our way to this one.
This one is a little bit...
Uh, yeah, I mean, y-you can listen to it...
And so the story is complete,
and everyone is
satisfied with the ending.
And so on and so forth, and yet,
over the garden wall...
* How the gentle wind *
* beckons through the leaves *
- # as autumn colors fall #
- Father?
* dancing in a swirl *
* of golden memories *
* the loveliest lies of all *
- Honey? Eat your dirt.
- Mom, stop calling it dirt.
What are you gonna do about it,
turn us into bluebirds again?
Mom...
Now, eat your dirt.
* the loveliest lies of all. *
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~