Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed,
and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar...
An airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
Oof!
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Would you sit down?!
If we hit a bump,
you'll go flying off!
What's bugging you anyway?
It's what Avatar Roku said.
I'm supposed to master
all four elements
before that comet arrives.
Well, let's see.
You pretty much mastered airbending,
and that only took you 112 years.
I'm sure you can master
three more elements by next summer.
I haven't even started waterbending,
and we're still weeks away
from the North Pole.
What am I gonna do?!
Calm down.
It's gonna be ok.
If you want,
I can try and teach you
some of the stuff I know.
You'd do that?
We'll need to find
a good source of water first.
Maybe we can find a puddle
for you to splash in.
Nice puddle.
Yeah!
Don't start without me, boy!
Remember the reason we're here.
Oh, right.
Time to practice waterbending.
Great. So, what am I supposed to do?
You could clean the gunk
out of Appa's toes.
So, while you guys
are playing in the water,
I'm supposed to be hard at work
picking mud
out of a giant bison's feet?
Mud and bugs.
Ok.
Whoa! Whoa!
Oof!
Someone's changing our course.
What's the meaning of this mutiny?
No one told you to change course.
Actually, someone did.
I assure you,
it is a matter of utmost importance,
Prince Zuko.
Is it something to do with the Avatar?
Even more urgent.
It seems I...
I've lost my lotus tile.
Lotus tile?
For my pai sho game.
Most people think the lotus tile
insignificant.
But it is essential
for the unusual strategy
that I employ.
You've changed our course
for a stupid lotus tile?
See, you, like most people,
underestimate its value.
Just give me 10 minutes
to check the merchants
at this port of call.
Hopefully, they'll have
the lotus tile in stock
and I can get on with my life.
I'm lucky to have such
an understanding nephew.
Yeah, don't get too happy.
You've got to do me next.
This is a pretty basic move,
but it still took me
months to perfect.
So, don't be frustrated
if you don't get it right away.
Just push and pull the water
like this.
The key is getting
the wrist movement right.
Like this?
That's almost right.
If you keep practicing,
I'm sure eventually...
Hey, I'm bending it already!
Wow! I can't believe
you got that so quickly.
It took me two months
to learn that move.
Well, you had to figure it out
all on your own.
I'm lucky enough
to have a great teacher.
Thanks.
So, what's next?
This is a more difficult move.
I call it streaming the water.
It's harder than it looks,
so don't be disappointed if...
Nice work.
Though the over-the-head
flair was unnecessary.
Sorry.
Well, don't stop now.
Keep 'em coming.
Well, I kind of know
this one other move,
But it's pretty hard.
I haven't even totally
figured it out yet.
The idea is to create
a big, powerful wave.
So, like this?
Aang!
Looks like I got
the hang of that move.
What else you got?
That's enough practicing for today.
Yeah, I'll say!
You just practiced our supplies.
Down the river.
Uh, sorry.
I'm sure we can find some way
to replace all this stuff.
My life was hard enough
when you were just an airbender.
Please, put me down!
See the wonder in this bag!
Who's brave enough
to look into this bag?!
Wow!
We've got exactly
three copper pieces left
from the money that King Bumi gave us.
Let's spend it wisely.
Uh, make that
two copper pieces, Sokka.
I couldn't say no to this whistle.
It doesn't even work.
See? Even Momo thinks
it's a piece of junk.
No offense, Aang,
but I'll hold the money from now on.
Earth Nation! Fire Nation!
Water Nation.
So long as bargains
are your inclination,
you're welcome here!
Don't be shy.
Come on by!
Oh, you there!
I can see from your clothing
that you're world traveling types.
Perhaps I can interest you
in some exotic curios?
Sure!
What are curios?
I'm not entirely sure,
But we got 'em.
Huh?
I've never seen
such a fine specimen of lemur.
That beast would fetch me a hefty sum
if you'd be interested in bartering.
Momo's not for sale.
Look at this, Aang!
It's a waterbending scroll.
Check out these crazy moves.
Where did you get
a waterbending scroll?
Let's just say I got it up north
at a most reasonable price...
Free.
Wait a minute.
Sea-loving traders
with suspiciously acquired merchandise
and pet reptile birds?
You guys are pirates!
We prefer to think of ourselves as
high-risk traders.
So, how much for the traded scroll?
I've already got a buyer...
A nobleman in the Earth Kingdom...
Unless, of course, you kids have
200 gold pieces on you right now.
I know how to deal
with these guys, Katara.
Pirates love to haggle.
Watch and learn.
What say ye to the price of...
One copper piece?
Ha ha ha ha!
The price is 200 gold pieces.
I don't haggle on items this rare.
Ok, two copper pieces.
It's not as amusing
the second time, boy.
Aang, can we get out of here?
I feel like we're getting weird looks.
Aye! We be casting off now!
What was that all about, Katara?
Yeah, I was just starting
to browse through
their boomerang collection.
I'll just feel a lot better
once we get away from here.
Hey, you!
Get back here!
Well, well.
Look who's come to their senses.
Told you the haggling would pay off.
There they are!
Get 'em!
Nobody's going nowhere!
I don't think these pirates
are here to trade with us.
Get back here!
You little...
Come on!
This way.
Let's cut 'em off!
Whoa!
Oof!
Oh! Oh!
My cabbages!
This place is worse than Omashu!
Aha!
I hope that lemur of yours
has nine lives.
Now, who gets to taste
the steel of my blade first?
No, thanks.
Haa!
Grab on tight!
Aang, I thought we were
running away from the pirates.
Just hang on.
Whoa!
Ow!
I used to kind of look up to pirates,
but those guys are terrible.
I know.
That's why I took this.
No way!
Isn't it great?!
No wonder they were
trying to hack us up.
You stole their waterbending scroll.
I prefer to think of it as
high-risk trading.
Ha ha ha.
Good one, Katara.
Sokka, where to you think they got it?
They stole it from a waterbender.
It doesn't matter.
You put all of our lives in danger
just so you could learn
some stupid, fancy splashes.
These are real waterbending forms.
You know how crucial it is
for Aang to learn waterbending.
Whatever.
Well, what's done is done.
We have it.
We might as well learn from it.
I've checked all the shops
on this pier.
Not a lotus tile
in the entire marketplace.
It's good to know this trip
was a complete waste of time
for everyone!
Quite the contrary.
I always say
the only thing better than
finding something you are looking for
is finding something
you weren't looking for
at a great bargain.
You bought a sungi horn?
For music night on the ship.
Now, if we only had some woodwinds.
Oh, this place looks promising.
Oh, that is handsome!
Wouldn't it look
magnificent in the galley?
We lost the water tribe girl
and the little bald monk
she was traveling with.
This monk, did he have
an arrow on his head?
I just want to try
this one move first,
and then it's all yours.
Here, hold it open for me.
The single water whip.
Looks doable.
Ow!
Ha ha ha!
What's so funny?
I'm sorry, but you deserved that.
You've been duped.
She's only interested
in teaching herself.
Aang will get his turn
once I figure out the water whip.
Ugh! Why can't I get
this stupid move?!
You'll get it.
You've just gotta shift your weight
through the stances.
There. See?
The key to bending is...
Will you please shut your air hole!
Believe it or not,
your infinite wisdom
gets a little old sometimes!
Why don't we just
throw the scroll away
since you're so naturally gifted?!
What?!
Oh, my gosh, Aang.
I am so sorry.
I don't know what came over me.
But you know what?
It won't happen again.
Here, this is yours.
I don't want to have
anything to do with it anymore.
It's ok, Katara.
What about Momo?
He's the real victim here.
I'm sorry, Momo.
And what about me?
There was that time you...
No more apologies.
Shouldn't we stop to search the woods?
We don't need to stop.
They stole
a waterbending scroll, right?
Mm-hmm.
Then they'll be on the water.
Shh.
Momo, go back to sleep.
Shh!
Shoot!
Come on, water! Work with me here!
Ok, what if I... Ow!
Ok, Katara,
shift your weight through the stances.
Ugh!
Ah! No!
Let go of me!
I'll save you from the pirates.
Tell me where he is,
and I won't hurt you or your brother.
Go jump in the river!
Try to understand,
I need to capture him
to restore something I've lost...
My honor.
Perhaps in exchange,
I can restore something you've lost.
My mother's necklace.
How did you get that?!
I didn't steal it
if that's what you're wondering.
Tell me where he is.
No!
Enough of this necklace garbage.
You promised the scroll.
I wonder how much money this is worth.
No!
A lot, apparently.
Now, you help me find what I want,
you'll get this back,
and everyone goes home happy.
Search the woods for the boy
and meet back here.
Fine.
Huh?
Where did she go?
I don't believe it.
What's wrong?
She took the scroll.
She's obsessed with that thing.
It's just a matter of time
before she gets us all in deep...
Whoa!
I've got him. Come on!
Oh, what?
I'm not good enough to kidnap?
Aagh!
Nice work.
Aang, this is all my fault.
No, Katara, it isn't.
Yeah, it kind of is.
Give me the boy.
You give us the scroll.
You're really gonna
hand over the Avatar
for a stupid piece of parchment?
Don't listen to him.
He's trying to turn
us against each other.
Your friend is the Avatar?
Sure is.
And I'll bet he'll fetch a lot more
on the black market
than that fancy scroll.
Shut your mouth,
you water tribe peasant!
Yeah, Sokka,
you really should shut your mouth.
I'm just saying,
it's bad business sense.
Just imagine how much the Fire Lord
would pay for the Avatar.
You guys would be set for life.
Keep the scroll.
We can buy 100 with the reward
we'll get for the kid.
You'll regret breaking a deal with me.
Thanks, Momo.
I owe you a bushel of apples.
Hey!
Aah!
Aang, are you there?
I'm over here! Follow my voice.
Where? I can't find you!
I'm right here!
Uh, never mind.
I'll find you!
Run!
Katara, you're ok.
Help me get this boat
back in the water
so we can get out of here.
We need a team of rhinos
to budge this ship.
A team of rhinos...
Or two waterbenders.
Everybody in!
Are you so busy fighting
you cannot see your own ship
has set sail?
We have no time
for your proverbs, uncle.
It's no proverb.
Bleeding hog monkeys!
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, that's my boat!
Maybe it should be a proverb.
Come on, uncle.
Sokka, can't you make it
go any faster?
I don't know how.
This thing wasn't made
by the water tribe.
Whoa!
Oof!
Hey! You did the water whip.
I couldn't have done it
without your help.
Will you two quit
congratulating each other
and help me out?
That's good.
Wah!
Hah!
Aang, look!
Oh, no!
Aah! Oh!
Have you lost your mind?
This is no time for flute practice!
We can stop the boat.
Aang, together,
push and pull the water.
It's working.
It's slowing down.
We're doing it!
But we have another problem.
Whoa! Whoa!
Jump!
I knew a bison whistle
would come in handy.
Thanks, Appa.
Yeah, we owe you one.
My boat!
Prince Zuko,
you're really going to
get a kick out of this.
That lotus tile
was in my sleeve the whole time!
Aang,
I still owe you an apology.
You were just so good at waterbending
without really trying.
I got so competitive
that I put us all in danger.
I'm sorry.
That's ok, Katara.
Besides, who needs
that stupid scroll anyway?
Is that really how you feel?
The scroll!
First, what did you learn?
Stealing is wrong.
Unless it's from pirates.
Ha ha ha!
Good one, Katara.