Water, earth,
fire, air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his
airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
- Yay! Yay!
- Aang's back!
I knew it.
You signaled the Fire Navy
with that flare.
You're leading them
straight to us, aren't you?
Aang didn't do anything.
It was an accident.
Yeah, we were on the ship
and there was this booby trap,
and, well, we...
We boobied right into it.
Katara, you shouldn't have
gone on that ship.
Now we could all be in danger.
Don't blame Katara.
I brought her there.
It's my fault.
A-ha!
The traitor confesses!
Warriors, away from the enemy!
The foreigner is banished
from our village.
Sokka, you're making a mistake.
No, I'm keeping my promise to dad.
I'm protecting you
from threats like him.
Aang is not our enemy.
Don't you see?
Aang's brought us something
we haven't had in a long time... Fun.
Fun? We can't fight firebenders
with fun!
You should try it sometime.
Get out of our village, now!
Grandmother, please,
don't let Sokka do this.
Katara, you knew going on
that ship was forbidden.
Sokka is right.
I think it best
if the airbender leaves.
Fine, then I'm banished, too.
Come on, Aang, let's go.
Where do you think you're going?
To find a waterbender.
Aang is taking me to the North Pole.
I am?
- Great!
- Katara!
Would you really choose him
over your tribe,
your own family?
Katara, I don't want to come between
you and your family.
So you're leaving the South Pole?
This is goodbye?
Thanks for penguin sledding with me.
Where will you go?
Guess I'll go back home
and look for the airbenders.
Wow.
I haven't cleaned my room
in 100 years.
Not looking forward to that.
It was nice meeting everyone.
Let's see your bison fly now, Airboy.
Come on, Appa, you can do it.
Yip yip!
Yeah, I thought so!
Aang, don't go.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you, too.
Come on, boy.
Katara, you'll feel better after you...
You happy now?
There goes my one chance
of becoming a waterbender!
All right, ready our defenses!
The Fire Nation could be
on our shores any moment now!
But I got to...
And no potty breaks!
Yeah, I liked her, too.
The village!
Appa, wait here!
Oh, man!
Oh, man.
Sokka! Get out of the way!
Where are you hiding him?
He'd be about this age,
master of all elements.
I know you're hiding him.
Show no fear!
Hey, Katara. Hey, Sokka.
Hi, Aang.
Thanks for coming.
Looking for me?
You're the airbender?
You're the Avatar?
Aang?
No way.
I've spent years preparing
for this encounter,
training, meditating.
You're just a child.
Well, you're just a teenager.
If I go with you,
will you promise
to leave everyone alone?
No, Aang, don't do this.
Don't worry, Katara.
It'll be ok.
Unh!
Take care of Appa for me
until I get back.
Head a course to the Fire Nation.
I'm going home.
We have to go after that ship, Sokka.
Aang saved our tribe.
Now we have to save him.
Katara, I...
Why can't you realize
that he's on our side?
If we don't help him, no one will.
I know you don't like Aang,
but we owe him and...
Katara, are you going to talk all day
or are you coming with me?
Sokka!
Get in.
We're going to save your boyfriend.
- He's not my...
- Whatever.
What do you two think you're doing?
You'll need these.
You have a long journey ahead of you.
It's been so long since I've had hope,
but you brought it back to life,
my little waterbender.
And you, my brave warrior,
be nice to your sister.
Yeah, ok, Gran.
Aang is the Avatar.
He's the world's only chance.
You both found him for a reason.
Now your destinies
are intertwined with his.
There's no way we're going to catch
a warship with a canoe.
Appa!
You just love taking me
out of my comfort zone,
don't you?
This staff will make
an excellent gift for my father.
I suppose you wouldn't
know of fathers,
being raised by monks.
Take the Avatar to the prison hold
and take this to my quarters.
Hey, you mind taking this
to his quarters for me?
Ugh!
So, I guess you've never fought
an airbender before.
I bet I can take you both
with my hands tied behind my back.
Silence.
The Avatar has escaped!
Go.
Fly.
Soar.
Please, Appa, we need your help.
Aang needs your help.
Up.
Ascend.
Elevate.
Sokka doesn't believe you can fly,
But I do, Appa.
Come on, don't you want to save Aang?
What was it that kid said?
Yee-ha?
Hup-hup?
Wa-hoo?
Uh, yip yip?
You did it, Sokka!
He's flying!
Katara, he's...
I mean, big deal.
He's flying.
Aah!
You haven't seen
my staff around, have you?
Thanks, anyway.
Sorry.
My staff!
Looks like I underestimated you.
What is that?
Appa!
Aang, no!
Aang! Aang!
Aang!
Did you see what he just did?
Now that was some waterbending.
Aang, are you ok?
Hey, Katara.
Hey, Sokka.
Thanks for coming.
Well, I couldn't let you
have all the glory.
I dropped my staff.
Got it.
Ha!
That's from the water tribe!
Katara!
Hurry up, Sokka!
I'm just a guy with a boomerang.
I didn't ask for all this
flying and magic.
Yip yip! Yip yip!
Huh?
Shoot them down!
Good news for the Fire Lord.
The Fire Nation's greatest threat
is just a little kid.
That kid, uncle, just did this.
I won't underestimate him again.
Dig this ship out and follow them.
As soon as you're done with that.
How did you
do that with the water?
It was the most amazing thing
I've ever seen.
I don't know.
I just sort of did it.
Why didn't you tell us
you were the Avatar?
Because I never wanted to be.
But, Aang, the world's been waiting
for the Avatar to return
and finally put an end to this war.
And how am I going to do that?
According to legend,
You need to first master water,
then earth, then fire, right?
That's what the monks told me.
Well, if we go to the north pole,
you can master waterbending.
We could learn it together!
And, Sokka,
I'm sure you'll get to knock
some firebender heads on the way.
I'd like that.
I'd really like that.
Then we're in this together.
All right,
but before I learn waterbending,
we have some
serious business to attend to
here, here, and here.
What's there?
Here we'll ride the hopping llamas.
Then way over here we'll surf
on the backs of giant koi fish.
Then back over here
we'll ride the hog monkeys.
They don't like people riding them,
but that's what makes it fun!