Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed,
and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Absolutely not.
The Yuyan archers stay here.
Your request is denied,
Commander Zhao.
Colonel Shinu, please reconsider.
Their precision is legendary.
The Yuyan can pin a fly
to a tree from 100 yards away
without killing it.
You're wasting their talents
using them as mere security guards.
I can do whatever I want
with their talents.
They're my archers,
and what I say goes.
But my search for the Avatar is...
Is nothing but a vanity project.
We're fighting a real war here,
and I need every man
I've got, commander.
But...
That's final!
I don't want to hear
another word about it.
News from Fire Lord Ozai?
It appears I've been
promoted to admiral.
My request is now an order.
This should bring your fever down.
You know what I love
about Appa the most?
His sense of humor.
That's nice.
I'll tell him.
Ha ha ha!
Classic Appa.
How's Sokka doing?
Not so good.
Being out in that storm
really did a number on him.
I couldn't find
any ginger root for the tea,
but I found a map.
There's a herbalist institute
on the top of that mountain.
We could probably
find a cure for Sokka there.
Aang, he's in no condition to travel.
Sokka just needs more rest.
I'm sure he'll be better by tomorrow.
Not you, too.
Relax. It was just a little cough.
I'm fin...
That's how Sokka started yesterday.
Now look at him.
He thinks he's an earthbender.
Take that, you rock.
A few more hours
and you'll be talking nonsense, too.
I'm going to find some medicine.
Uh, maybe it's safer if I go on foot.
Keep an eye on them, guys.
Ha ha!
You guys are killing me.
We haven't been able to pick up
the Avatar's trail since the storm,
but if we continue
heading northeast...
What do they want?
Perhaps a sporting game of Pai Sho.
The hunt for the Avatar
has been given prime importance.
All information regarding the Avatar
must be reported
directly to Admiral Zhao.
Zhao has been promoted?
Well, good for him.
I've got nothing to report to Zhao.
Now get off my ship and let us pass.
Admiral Zhao is not allowing ships
in or out of this area.
Off my ship!
Excellent.
I take the pot.
But you're all improving.
I'm certain you will win
if we play again.
It says here
that the Avatar can create tornadoes
and run faster than the wind.
Pretty amazing.
Aw, that's just a bunch
of Fire Lord propaganda.
There's no way that's true.
Katara, please, water.
Listen carefully, Momo.
I need you to take this
to the river and fill it with water.
Got it?
Hello. I'm sorry
to barge in like this,
but I need some medicine
for my friends.
They have fevers
and they've been coughing...
Settle down, young man.
Your friends are going to be fine.
I've been up here
for over 40 years, you know.
Used to be others,
but they all left years ago.
Now it's just me and Miyuki.
That's nice.
Wounded Earth Kingdom troops
still come by now and again.
Brave boys,
and thanks to my remedies,
they always leave in better shape
than when they arrived.
That's nice. Are you almost done?
Hold on.
I just need to add
one last ingredient.
Oh, sandalwood?
Oh, yes... No, that won't do.
Banana leaf? Eh, nope.
Ginger root?
Uh-uh.
Oh, where is that pesky little plant?
Is everything ok?
It's been almost an hour
and you haven't given
the men an order.
I don't care what they do.
Don't give up hope yet.
You can still find the Avatar
before Zhao.
How, uncle?
With Zhao's resources,
it's just a matter of time
before he captures the Avatar.
My honor, my throne, my country...
I'm about to lose them all.
Oh, here's what I was looking for.
Plum blossom.
Finally. Thanks for all your help.
Hands off.
What do you think you're doing?
Taking the cure to my friends.
Oh! Ha ha! This isn't a cure.
It's Miyuki's dinner.
Plum blossom is her favorite.
What about my friends?
Well, all they need
is some frozen wood frogs.
There's plenty of them
down in the valley swamp.
What am I supposed to do
with frozen frogs?
Why, suck on them, of course.
Suck on them?
The frog skin excretes a substance
that'll cure your friends,
but make sure you get plenty.
Once those little critters thaw out,
they're useless.
You're insane, aren't you?
That's right.
Well, don't stand there all day.
Go!
Uh! Whoa!
Uh, I think you dropped this.
Aah!
A frog!
So this is the great Avatar,
master of all the elements.
I don't know how
you've managed to elude
the Fire Nation for 100 years,
but your little game
of hide and seek is over.
I've never hidden from you.
Untie me and I'll fight you right now.
Uh, no.
Tell me, how does it feel
to be the only airbender left?
Do you miss your people?
Oh, don't worry.
You won't be killed like they were.
See, if you die, you'll just be reborn
and the Fire Nation will have to begin
its search for the Avatar
all over again.
So I'll keep you alive,
but just barely.
Blow all the wind you want.
Your situation is futile.
There is no escaping this fortress
and no one is coming to rescue you.
Water.
Momo should be back any minute.
No, Momo.
Water.
Wa-ter.
Aang, what in the world
is taking you so long?
All clear.
Go on in.
We are the sons and daughters
of fire, the superior element,
until today, only one thing
stood in our path to victory...
The Avatar!
I am here to tell you
that he is now my prisoner!
This is the year Sozin's Comet
returns to grant us its power!
This is the year the Fire Nation
breaks through
the walls of Ba Sing Se,
and burns the city to the ground.
What? No!
Don't leave, frogs. My friends
are sick and they need you.
Please go back to being frozen.
Aah!
Who are you? What's going on?
Are you here to rescue me?
I'll take that as a yes.
My frogs!
Come back!
And stop thawing out!
Wait!
My friends need to
suck on those frogs!
How many times
do I have to tell you, Momo?
We need water.
Wa-ter.
Oh, forget it.
Aang, please hurry.
Who is this Aang kid
you keep talking about, your highness?
I want a full transcription
of my speech
sent to the Fire Lord,
Along with glowing testimonials
from all of the ranking officers
present, and...
Sir, shall I hold off
sending that speech to the Fire Lord?
There. On the wall!
Aah!
The Avatar has escaped!
Close all the gates immediately.
Stay close to me.
Aah!
Take this.
Jump on my back!
Give me the next one!
Hold your fire!
The Avatar must be captured alive.
Open the gate.
Admiral, what are you doing?
Let them out.
Now!
How could you let them go?
A situation like this requires...
Precision.
Do you have a clear shot?
Knock out the thief.
I'll deliver him to the Fire Lord
along with the Avatar.
Quick! Recover the Avatar!
You know what the worst part
about being born
over 100 years ago is?
I miss all the friends
I used to hang out with.
Before the war started,
I used to always
visit my friend, Kuzon.
The two of us, we'd get in and out
of so much trouble together.
He was one of the best friends
I ever had...
And he was from the Fire Nation,
just like you.
If we knew each other back then,
do you think
we could have been friends, too?
Where have you been, Prince Zuko?
You missed music night.
Lieutenant Jee sang
a stirring love song.
I'm going to bed.
No disturbances.
Suck on these.
It'll make you feel better.
Aang, how was your trip?
Did you make any new friends?
No.
I don't think I did.
Mm!
This is tasty.
Mm, mm!
Ptooey!
Aah!