Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills were great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Let's go, Appa! Come on, boy.
Look, I'm sorry, but Katara and Sokka
aren't coming
to the Fire Nation with us.
If they got hurt,
I'd never forgive myself.
So get your big butt
off the ground and let's go!
Uhh...
Aah!
I think his big butt
is trying to tell you something.
Please don't go, Aang.
The world can't afford to lose you
to the Fire Nation.
Neither can I.
But I have to talk to Avatar Roku
to find out what my vision means.
I need to get to the fire temple
before the sun sets on the solstice.
That's today!
We're not letting you
go into the Fire Nation, Aang.
At least not without your friends.
We got your back.
Ew!
It's a long journey
to the crescent island.
You'll have to fly fast
to have any chance
of making it before sundown.
Good luck.
Thank you for your...
Go!
Ah.
Having trouble sleeping?
Uh!
Seen the Avatar lately?
Come on, boy.
We've got a long way to go.
Faster!
Sailing into Fire Nation waters.
Of all the foolish things you've done
in your 16 years, Prince Zuko,
this is the most foolish.
I have no choice, uncle.
Have you completely forgotten
that the Fire Lord banished you?
What if you're caught?
I'm chasing the Avatar.
My father will understand
why I'm returning home.
You give him too much credit.
My brother is not
the understanding type.
There they are.
Helmsman, full steam ahead.
Aang, we got trouble.
Yeah, and it's gaining fast!
Really, Prince Zuko,
couldn't you shoot them down
with something more fragrant?
Huh!
On my mark.
Fire!
Fire ball!
I'm on it!
We have to get out of Zuko's range
before he shoots
another hotsticker at us!
Can't you make Appa go any faster?
Yeah, but there's
just one little problem.
A blockade.
Technically, you are still
in Earth Kingdom waters.
Turn back now,
and they cannot arrest you.
If we fly north,
we can go around the Fire Nation ships
and avoid the blockade.
It's the only way.
There's no time!
This is exactly why
I didn't want you to come.
It's too dangerous.
And that's exactly why we're here.
Let's run this blockade.
Appa, yip yip!
He's not turning around.
Please, Prince Zuko.
If the Fire Nation captures you,
There is nothing I can do.
Do not follow the Avatar.
I'm sorry, uncle.
Run the blockade!
The Avatar...
And the banished prince.
This must be my lucky day.
Commander Zhao, what are your orders?
Shoot the bison down, captain.
But there's a fire navy ship
out there, sir... One of our own.
What if it's hit?
So be it. It belongs to a traitor.
Ignite!
Launch!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Appa, are you ok?
Prince Zuko, the engines are damaged!
We need to stop and make repairs!
Do not stop this ship.
Launch!
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Sokka!
Aah!
Oh!
Ready.
Fire!
Aah!
Huh!
Aah! Ooh!
We made it!
We got into the Fire Nation. Great.
Where do you think
the Avatar is headed, sir?
I'm not sure,
but I bet a certain
banished prince will know.
We're on a collision course!
We can make it.
The boarding party is ready
to apprehend Prince Zuko, sir.
Wait. Cut the engines
and let them pass.
Sir?
There it is...
The island
where Roku's dragon took me.
You did it, buddy. Nice flying.
Oh, you must be tired.
No, I'm good. Refreshed and ready
to fight some firebenders.
I was talking to Appa.
Well, I was talking to Momo.
I don't see any guards.
The Fire Nation
must have abandoned the temple
when Avatar Roku died.
It's almost sundown.
We'd better hurry.
Wait. I think I heard something.
We are the fire sages,
guardians of the temple of the Avatar.
Great. I am the Avatar.
We know.
I'll hold them off. Run!
Uh! Uh! Uh!
If the Avatar contacts Roku,
there's no telling how powerful
the boy will become.
Split up and find him.
Follow me!
Do you know where you're going?
Nope.
Wrong way!
Come back!
I don't want to fight you.
I am a friend.
Firebenders aren't our friends.
I know why you're here, Avatar.
You do?
Yes. You wish to speak to Avatar Roku.
I can take you to him.
How?
Uh!
This way.
Find him!
Time is running out! Quickly!
What's he up to, uncle?
Why didn't Commander Zhao arrest me?
Because he wants to follow you.
He knows you'll lead him
to the prize you're both after...
The Avatar.
If Zhao wants to follow
our trail of smoke,
then that's exactly
what I'll let him do.
Avatar Roku once called
this temple his home.
He formed these secret passages
out of the magma.
Did you know Avatar Roku?
No, but my grandfather knew him.
Many generations of fire sages
guarded this temple long before me.
We all have a strong
spiritual connection
to this place.
Is that how you knew I was coming?
A few weeks ago,
an amazing thing occurred.
The statue of Avatar Roku...
Its eyes began to glow.
That's when we were
at the air temple.
Avatar Roku's eyes
were glowing there, too.
At that moment,
we knew you had returned to the world.
If this is the Avatar's temple,
why did the sages attack me?
Things have changed.
In the past, the sages were loyal
only to the Avatar.
When Roku died, the sages eagerly
awaited for the next Avatar to return,
but he never came.
They were waiting for me.
Hey, don't feel bad.
You're only 100 years late.
They lost hope that the Avatar
would ever return.
When Fire Lord Sozin began the war,
my grandfather and the other sages
were forced to follow him.
I never wanted to serve the Fire Lord.
When I learned you were coming,
I knew I would have to
betray the other sages.
Thank you for helping me.
We'll follow these stairs
to the sanctuary.
Once you're inside,
wait for the light to hit
Avatar Roku's statue.
Only then will you be
able to speak with him.
No!
Shyu, what's wrong?
The sanctuary doors... They're closed.
Can't you just open them
with firebending,
like you opened that other door?
No. Only a fully realized Avatar
is powerful enough
to open this door alone.
Otherwise, the sages must
open the doors together
with five simultaneous fire blasts.
Five fire blasts, huh?
I think I can help you out.
Uncle, keep heading north.
Zhao will follow the smoke trail
while I use it as a cover.
Hmmm.
This is a little trick
I picked up from my father.
I seal the lamp oil inside
an animal skin casing.
Shyu lights the oil-soaked twine,
and ta da!
Fake firebending.
You're really outdone yourself
this time, Sokka.
This might actually work.
The sages will hear the explosion,
so as soon as they go off,
you rush in.
It's almost sunset. Are you ready?
Definitely.
Ooh!
Uh! Uh!
They're still locked!
It didn't work.
Why won't it open?! Uh!
Aang, stop.
There's nothing else we can do.
I'm sorry I put you
through all this for nothing.
I don't get it.
That blast looked as strong
as any firebending I've seen.
Sokka, you're a genius!
Wait. How is Sokka a genius?
His plan didn't even work.
Come on, Aang. Let her dream.
You're right.
Sokka's plan didn't work,
but it looks like it did.
Did the definition of genius change
in the last 100 years?
Come quickly!
The Avatar has entered the sanctuary!
How did he get in?
I know, but look at the scorch marks,
and down there.
He's inside.
Open the doors immediately
before he contacts Avatar Roku.
- Huh!
It's the Avatar's lemur.
He must have crawled
through the pipes.
We've been tricked!
Aah!
Now, Aang.
Aang, now's your chance!
The Avatar's coming with me.
Uh! Uh!
Uh!
Close the doors, quickly!
- Uh!
- Aah!
Go!
He made it!
The light hits the statue,
and I talk to Roku.
So why isn't anything happening?
- Huh!
Why isn't it working?
It's sealed shut.
It must have been the light.
Avatar Roku doesn't want us inside.
Why isn't anything happening?
I don't know what I'm doing.
All I know is airbending.
Please, Avatar Roku, talk to me.
It's good to see you, Aang.
What took you so long?
Why did you help the Avatar?
Because it was once the sage's duty.
It is still our duty.
What a moving
and heartfelt performance.
I'm certain the Fire Lord
will understand
when you explain why you betrayed him.
Commander Zhao...
And, Prince Zuko,
it was a noble effort,
but your little smokescreen
didn't work.
Two traitors in one day.
The Fire Lord will be pleased.
You're too late, Zhao.
The Avatar's inside,
and the doors are sealed.
No matter. Sooner or later,
he has to come out.
I have something very important
to tell you, Aang.
That is why,
when you were in the spirit world,
I sent my dragon to find you.
Is it about that vision...
The one of the comet?
Yes.
What does it mean?
100 years ago,
Fire Lord Sozin used that comet
to begin the war.
He and his firebending army
harnessed its incredible power
and dealt a deadly first strike
against the other nations.
So the comet made them stronger?
Yes, stronger than you
could even imagine.
But that happened a hundred years ago.
What does the comet
have to do with the war now?
Listen carefully.
Sozin's Comet will return
by the end of this summer,
and Fire Lord Ozai will use its power
to finish the war once and for all.
Aah!
If he succeeds, even the Avatar
won't be able to restore
balance to the world.
Aang, you must defeat the Fire Lord
before the comet arrives.
But I haven't even started
learning waterbending,
not to mention earth and fire.
Mastering the elements takes years
of discipline and practice,
But if the world is to survive,
you must do it by summer's end.
When those doors open,
unleash all your firepower.
How's Aang gonna make it out of this?
How are we gonna make it out of this?
What if I can't master
all the elements in time?
What if I fail?
I know you can do it, Aang,
for you have done it before.
The solstice is ending.
We must go our separate ways for now.
But I won't be able
to come back to the temple.
What if I have questions?
How will I talk to you?
I am a part of you.
When you need to talk to me again,
you will find a way.
A great danger awaits you
at the temple.
I can help you face the threat,
But only if you are ready.
I'm ready.
Ready...
No! Aang!
Fire!
Avatar Roku!
- Uh!
Uh!
- Oh!
Avatar Roku is going to
destroy the temple.
We have to get out of here!
Not without Aang!
Huh!
We got your back.
Thanks. Where's Shyu?
I don't know.
Uh! Uh! Uh!
No prince, no Avatar.
Apparently the only thing I do have
is five traitors.
But, Commander,
only Shyu helped the Avatar.
Save your stories for the Fire Lord.
As far as I'm concerned,
you are all guilty.
Take them to the prison hold!