Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
Unh!
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Huh.
Where's Momo?
Hang on, Momo!
Uhh!
All right, you too.
This is going to take forever.
That works.
These are Fire Nation traps.
You can tell from the metalwork.
We'd better pack up camp
and get moving.
Uh-uh! No flying this time.
What? Why wouldn't we fly?
Think about it.
Somehow Prince Zuko
and the Fire Nation keep finding us.
It's because they spot Appa,
he's just too noticeable.
What? Appa's not too noticeable.
He's a gigantic fluffy monster
with an arrow on his head!
It's kind of hard to miss him.
Sokka's just jealous
because he doesn't have an arrow.
I know you all want to fly,
but my instincts tell me
we should play it safe
this time and walk.
Who made you the boss?
I'm not the boss, I'm the leader.
You're the leader?
But your voice still cracks.
I'm the oldest, and I'm a warrior!
So I'm the leader.
If anyone's the leader, it's Aang.
I mean, he is the Avatar.
Are you kidding?
He's just a goofy kid.
He's right.
Why do boys always think
someone has to be the leader?
I bet you wouldn't be so bossy
if you kissed a girl.
I've kissed a girl!
You just haven't met her.
Who? Gran-Gran?
I've met Gran-Gran.
No, besides Gran-Gran.
Look, my instincts tell me
we have a better chance
of slipping through on foot,
and a leader has to
trust his instincts.
Ok, we'll try it your way,
O wise leader.
Who knows? Walking might be fun.
Walking stinks!
How did people go anywhere
without a flying bison?
I don't know, Aang.
Why don't you ask Sokka's instincts?
They seem to know everything.
Ha ha, very funny.
I'm tired of carrying this pack.
You know who you should
ask to carry it for a while?
Sokka's instincts!
That's a great idea.
Hey, Sokka's instincts,
would you mind...
Ok, ok, I get it!
Look, guys, I'm tired, too.
But the important thing is that
we're safe from the Fire Nation.
Run!
Huh!
We're cut off!
Sokka, your shirt!
Aah!
If you let us pass,
we promise not to hurt you.
What are you doing?
Bluffing.
You, promise not to hurt us?
Unh.
Uhh...
Nice work, Sokka. How did you do that?
Uh... Instinct?
Look!
Uhh!
Unh!
Down you go.
Uhh!
They're in the trees!
Ha ha ha!
Hah!
Unh!
Hey, he was mine.
Gotta be quicker next time.
Unh!
Uhh.
Man!
Hey.
Hi.
You just took out a whole army
almost single-handed.
Army?!
There were only, like, 20 guys.
My name is Jet,
and these are my freedom fighters.
Sneers, Longshot, Smellerbee,
The Duke, and Pipsqueak.
Pipsqueak, that's a funny name.
You think my name is funny?
It's hilarious!
Unh!
Um, thanks for saving us, Jet.
We're lucky you were there.
I should be thanking you.
We were waiting to ambush
those soldiers all morning.
We just needed the right distraction.
And then you guys stumbled in.
We were relying on instincts.
You'll get yourself
killed doing that.
Hey, Jet, these barrels are filled
with blasting jelly.
That's a great score.
And these boxes are filled
with jellied candy.
Also good.
Let's not get those mixed up.
We'll take the stuff
back to the hideout.
You guys have a hideout?
You want to see it?
Yes, we want to see it!
We're here.
Where? There's nothing here.
Hold this.
Why? What's this do?
Aah!
Aang?
I'll get up on my own.
Grab hold of me, Katara.
Nice place you got!
It's beautiful up here.
It's beautiful, and more importantly,
the Fire Nation can't find us.
They would love to find you,
wouldn't they, Jet?
It's not going to happen, Smellerbee.
Why does the Fire Nation
want to find you?
I guess you could say
I've been causing them
a little trouble.
See, they took over a nearby
Earth Kingdom town
a few years back.
We've been ambushing their troops,
cutting off their supply lines,
and doing anything we can
to mess with them.
One day, we'll drive the Fire Nation
out of here for good,
And free that town.
That's so brave.
Yeah, nothing's braver
than a guy in a tree house.
Don't pay any attention to my brother.
No problem. He probably
had a rough day.
So, you all live here?
That's right.
Longshot over there,
His town got burned down
by the Fire Nation.
And we found The Duke
trying to steal our food.
I don't think he ever
really had a home.
What about you?
The Fire Nation killed my parents.
I was only eight years old.
That day changed me forever.
Sokka and I lost our mother
to the Fire Nation.
I'm so sorry, Katara.
Today, we struck another blow
against the Fire Nation swine.
I got a special joy
from the look on one soldier's face,
when The Duke dropped down
on his helmet
and rode him like a wild hog-monkey!
Now, the Fire Nation
thinks they don't have to worry
about a couple of kids
hiding in the trees.
Maybe they're right.
Or maybe, they're dead wrong.
Hey, Jet, nice speech.
Thanks.
By the way,
I was really impressed
with you and Aang.
That was some great bending
I saw out there today.
Well, he's great. He's the Avatar.
I could use some more training.
Avatar, huh? Very nice.
Thanks, Jet.
So I might know a way
that you and Aang
can help in our struggle.
Unfortunately,
we have to leave tonight.
Sokka, you're kidding me.
I needed you on an important
mission tomorrow.
What mission?
What are you doing?
Shh. It amplifies vibrations.
Good trick.
Nothing yet.
Wait, yes!
Someone's approaching.
How many?
I think there's just one.
Good work, Sokka. Ready your weapon.
Wait! False alarm.
He's just an old man.
What are you doing
in our woods, you leech?
Please, sir, I'm just a traveler.
Uhh!
Ohh! Unh!
Do you like destroying towns?
Do you like destroying families?
Do you?!
Oh, please, let me go. Have mercy.
Does the Fire Nation let people go?
Does the Fire Nation have mercy?
Uhh!
Jet, he's just an old man!
He's Fire Nation! Search him!
But he's not hurting anyone.
Have you forgotten that
the Fire Nation killed your mother?
Remember why you fight!
We got his stuff, Jet.
This doesn't feel right.
It's what has to be done.
Now let's get out of here.
Come on, Sokka!
Sokka, look what The Duke gave me.
Ow, quit it!
Hey, Sokka. Is Jet back?
Yeah, he's back. But we're leaving.
What?
But I made him this hat.
Your boyfriend Jet's a thug.
What?!
No, he's not.
He's messed up, Katara.
He's not messed up.
He's just got a different way of life.
A really fun way of life.
He beat and robbed
a harmless old man.
I want to hear
Jet's side of the story.
Sokka, you told them what happened,
but you didn't mention
that the guy was Fire Nation?
No, he conveniently
left that part out.
Fine, but even if he was Fire Nation,
he was a harmless civilian.
He was an assassin, Sokka.
See? There's a compartment
for poison in the knife.
He was sent to eliminate me.
You helped save my life, Sokka.
I knew there was an explanation.
I didn't see any knife.
That's because he was concealing it.
See, Sokka?
I'm sure you just
didn't notice the knife.
There was no knife!
I'm going back to the hut
and packing my things.
Tell me you guys aren't leaving yet.
I really need your help.
What can we do?
The Fire Nation is planning
on burning down our forest.
If you both use waterbending
to fill the reservoir,
we could fight the fires.
But if you leave now,
they'll destroy the whole valley.
We can't leave now
with the Fire Nation
about to burn down a forest!
I'm sorry, Katara.
Jet's very smooth,
but we can't trust him.
You know what I think?
You're jealous that he's a better
warrior and a better leader.
Katara, I'm not jealous of Jet.
It's just that my instincts...
Well, my instincts tell me
we need to stay here a little longer
and help Jet.
Come on, Aang.
Sorry, Sokka.
Let's go.
Huh?
Now listen.
You're not to blow the dam
until I give the signal.
If the reservoir isn't full,
the Fire Nation troops could survive.
But what about the people in the town?
Won't they get wiped out, too?
Look, Duke, that's the price
of ridding this area
of the Fire Nation.
Now don't blow the dam
until I give the signal.
Got it?
Ow!
Where do you think
you're going, ponytail?
Sokka.
I'm glad you decided to join us.
I heard your plan
to destroy the Earth Kingdom town.
Our plan is to rid the valley
of the Fire Nation.
There are people living there, Jet,
mothers and fathers and children.
We can't win without
making some sacrifices.
You lied to Aang and Katara
about the forest fire.
Because they don't understand
the demands of war.
Not like you and I do.
I do understand.
I understand that
there's nothing you won't do
to get what you want.
I was hoping you'd have an open mind.
But I can see you've made your choice.
I can't let you warn Katara and Aang.
Take him for a walk.
A long walk.
You can't do this!
Cheer up, Sokka.
We're going to win a great victory
against the Fire Nation today.
Jet, I'm sorry about how
Sokka's been acting.
No worries. He already apologized.
Really? Sokka apologized?
Yeah, I was surprised, too.
I got the sense that maybe you.
Talked to him or something.
Yeah, I did.
I guess something you said
got through to him.
Anyhow, he went out
on a scouting mission
with Pipsqueak and Smellerbee.
I'm glad he cooled off.
He's so stubborn sometimes.
Uhh!
All right, we're here.
Underground water's trying
to escape from these vents.
I need you guys to help it along.
I've never used bending
on water I can't see.
I don't know...
Katara, you can do this.
What about me?
I know the Avatar can do this.
Yes! Good job.
This river empties into the reservoir.
A few more geysers
and it will be full.
Look, there's another steam vent.
Ok, you two keep it up,
I'll go check on things
at the reservoir.
When we're done,
we'll meet you over there.
Actually, probably better
if you meet me
back at the hideout when you're done.
I bet that's enough.
And I'm not just
saying that to be lazy.
Let's catch up with Jet
at the reservoir.
I thought we agreed
to meet Jet back at the hideout.
Well, we finished early.
I'm sure he'll be happy to see us.
Come on, move along!
How can you stand by and do nothing
while Jet wipes out a whole town?
Hey, listen, Sokka,
Jet's a great leader.
We follow what he says,
and things always turn out ok.
If that's how Jet leads,
Then he's got a lot to learn!
Hey!
Unh!
While you two are up there,
you might want to practice
your knot work.
Hey, Smellerbee.
You going to eat your lychee nuts?
Ooh.
What are they doing?
Hey, those are the red barrels
he got from the Fire Nation.
Why would they need blasting jelly?
Because Jet's going to
blow up the dam.
What?
No, that would destroy the town.
Jet wouldn't do that.
I've got to stop him!
Unh!
Yes, I would.
Jet, why?
Katara, you would, too,
if you just stop to think.
Think about what the Fire Nation
did to your mother.
We can't let them do that
to anyone else ever again.
This isn't the answer.
I want you to understand me, Katara.
I thought your brother
would understand, but...
Where's Sokka?
Katara.
Unh!
I need to get to the dam.
You're not going anywhere
without your glider.
Unh! Uhh! Unh!
I'm not going to fight you, Jet.
You'll have to
if you want your glider back.
Hah!
Unh!
Aah!
Ohh...
Unh!
Why, Jet?
I can't believe I trusted you.
You lied to me!
You're sick, and I trusted you!
What are you doing?
You're too late.
No!
Unh!
Sokka's still out there.
He's our only chance.
Come on, Sokka.
I'm sorry I ever doubted you.
Please...
No.
Sokka didn't make it in time.
All those people.
Jet, you monster!
This was a victory, Katara.
Remember that.
The Fire Nation is gone,
and this valley will be safe.
It will be safe,
without you.
Sokka!
I warned the villagers of your plan,
Just in time.
- What?!
- At first, they didn't believe me.
The Fire Nation soldiers
assumed I was a spy.
But one man vouched for me,
the old man you attacked.
He urged them to trust me,
and we got everyone out in time.
Mrs. Pretty!
Sokka, you fool!
We could have freed this valley!
Who would be free?
Everyone would be dead.
You traitor!
No, Jet. You became the traitor
when you stopped
protecting innocent people.
Katara, please, help me.
Good-bye, Jet.
Yip, yip.
We thought
you were going to the dam.
How come you went to the town instead?
Let me guess.
Your instincts told you.
Hey, sometimes they're right.
Um, Sokka?
You know we're going
the wrong way, right?
And sometimes they're wrong.