Water, earth,
fire, air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his
airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Nice try, Pupil Sangok.
A couple of more years,
and you might be ready
to fight a sea sponge.
Whoa!
Would anyone care for
a rematch with Katara?
Katara, you've
advanced more quickly
than any student I've ever trained.
You have proven
that with fierce determination,
passion, and hard work,
you can accomplish anything.
Raw talent alone is not enough.
Pupil Aang!
Yes, Master Pakku?
Care to step into
the sparring circle?
I figure since you've found time
to play with house pets,
you must have
already mastered waterbending.
I wouldn't say mastered,
but check this out!
So, they don't have palaces
in the Southern Tribe?
Are you kidding?
I grew up in a block of ice.
It's not exactly a cultural hub.
Sokka, this is wrong.
What's wrong?
We're taking a walk!
I'm engaged.
It just feels...
I know what you need.
You need to meet my good friend Appa.
Who?
Appa and I go way back,
don't we, boy?
Aagh! Easy!
Down, boy!
No, up!
Looks like you haven't been
giving Appa enough attention.
So, how does this work?
You hanging on tight?
Mm-hmm.
Yip, yip.
Oh, my goodness!
Wow!
I can't believe you do this every day.
Yeah, we pretty much live up here.
Is it always this cold in the sky?
Not when you're with someone.
It's beautiful up here.
Yeah.
Whoo, yeah!
Good times, good times.
Hey, look.
What's happening?
Oh, no.
Soot. YUE: What?
I've seen it before.
Right before my village was attacked.
It's soot mixed with snow.
But why?
It's the Fire Nation.
They've closed in on the North Pole.
And from the looks of this stuff,
I'd say there's a lot of them.
This will truly be one for
the history books, General Iroh.
Just think. Centuries from now,
people will study
the Great Admiral Zhao,
who destroyed the last
of the Water Tribe civilization.
You're lucky you're here to see it.
Be careful what you wish for, Admiral.
History is not always kind
to its subjects.
I suppose you speak from experience.
But, rest assured,
this will be nothing like
your legendary failure at Ba Sing Se.
I hope not, for your sake.
Tell the captains to prepare
for first strike.
We'll be landing soon.
Do you have a plan?
I'm working on it, Uncle.
What's wrong? We have to go!
No, Sokka.
Wait.
I can't see you anymore.
Not at all.
What? We're just friends.
I wish we could just be friends.
But I like you too much,
and it's too confusing
to be around you.
I'm marrying someone else.
You don't love him, do you?
You don't even seem to like him.
But I do love my people.
You're not marrying them!
You don't understand.
I have duties to my father,
to my tribe.
I have to do this.
Good-bye.
The day we have feared
for so long has arrived.
The Fire Nation is on our doorstep.
It is with great sadness
I call my family here before me,
knowing well that some of these faces
are about to vanish from our tribe.
But they will never vanish
from our hearts.
Now, as we approach
the battle for our existence,
I call upon the great spirits.
Spirit of the ocean,
spirit of the moon, be with us!
I'm going to need volunteers
for a dangerous mission.
- Count me in.
- Sokka...
Be warned.
Many of you will not return.
Come forward to receive my mark
if you accept the task.
The stillness before battle
is unbearable.
Such a quiet dread.
I wasn't there when the Fire Nation
attacked my people.
I'm gonna make a difference this time.
Yip, yip!
Katara!
I'll take it from here, boy.
Appa!
Thanks for the rescue, buddy.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Men, you'll be infiltrating
the Fire Nation navy.
That means you'll all need
one of these uniforms.
What's your problem?
Fire navy uniforms
don't look like that.
Of course they do.
These are real uniforms captured
from actual fire navy soldiers.
When, like, 100 years ago?
85.
The Fire Nation doesn't wear
shoulder spikes anymore.
The newer uniforms
are more streamlined.
How do we know we can trust this guy?
Such bold talk for a new recruit.
Sokka is from our sister tribe, Hahn.
He is a capable warrior,
and I value his input.
Now, our first objective
is to determine
the identity
of their commanding officer.
His name is Zhao.
Middle-aged, big sideburns,
bigger temper...
Sokka, I want you to tell
everything you know to Hahn.
He's leading this mission.
Hahn, show Sokka your respect.
I expect nothing less
from my future son-in-law.
Princess Yue's marrying you?
Yeah. What of it?
Nothing. Congratulations.
Stop those fireballs!
It's almost twilight, Admiral.
As your military consultant,
I must advise you to halt your attack.
The waterbenders draw their power
from the moon,
and it is nearly full tonight.
You should wait
and resume the attack at daybreak.
Oh, I am well aware
of the moon problem.
And I'm working on a solution.
But for now, daybreak it is.
They've stopped firing.
Aang!
I can't do it.
What happened?
I must have taken out
a dozen fire navy ships,
but there's just too many of them.
I can't fight them all!
But you have to.
You're the Avatar.
I'm just one kid.
If you are fishing
for an octopus, my nephew,
you need a tightly woven net,
or he will squeeze through
the tiniest hole and escape.
I don't need your wisdom
right now, Uncle.
I'm sorry, I just nag you because...
Well, ever since I lost my son...
Uncle, you don't have to say it.
I think of you as my own.
I know, Uncle.
We'll meet again.
After I have the Avatar.
Remember your breath of fire.
It could save your life out there.
I will.
And put your hood up.
Keep your ears warm.
I'll be fine!
Let me tell you, Sokka,
I've courted a lot of girls,
but Yue is the finest.
And she comes with the most perks.
Perks?! What does that mean?
I mean,
Yue's nice and everything,
but the points I'll gain
with the chief aren't bad either.
Princess Yue is wasted
on a self-absorbed weasel like you!
Whoa, hang on!
What do you care?
You're just a simple rube
from the Southern Tribe.
What would you know of the political
complexities of our life?
No offense.
You're just a jerk without a soul!
No offense!
That's enough!
Sokka, you're off the mission.
All right, fall in, men!
Everybody listen to what I say,
and we'll take out this Admiral Cho
in no time!
It's Admiral Zhao!
Where are they going?
They're coming up for air somewhere.
The legends say the moon
was the first waterbender.
Our ancestors saw how it pushed
and pulled the tides,
and learned how to do it themselves.
I've always noticed
my waterbending is stronger at night.
Our strength comes from
the spirit of the moon,
our life comes from the spirit
of the ocean.
They work together to keep balance.
The spirits.
Maybe I can find them
and get their help.
How can you do that?
The avatar is the bridge
between our world
and the spirit world.
Aang can talk to them!
Maybe they'll give you the wisdom
to win this battle.
Or maybe they'll unleash
a crazy-amazing spirit attack
on the Fire Nation!
Or wisdom. That's good, too.
The only problem is,
the last time you got
to the spirit world by accident.
How are you going
to get there this time?
I have an idea. Follow me.
So, is this the way
to the spirit world?
Ha ha ha. No.
You'll have to get there on your own.
But I can take you
to the most spiritual place
in the entire North Pole.
I never thought
I'd miss grass this much!
It's so warm here!
How is that possible?
It's the center
of all spiritual energy in our land.
You're right, Yue.
I can feel...
Something.
It's so...
Tranquil.
Be quiet!
Is something wrong, Sokka?
Oh, no.
Hahn's out there
on the top-secret mission,
while I'm here
sharpening my boomerang.
Everything's fine.
Listen to me.
I took you off the mission
for selfish reasons.
I have a special task in mind for you.
What, you want me
to scrub the barracks?
I want you to guard my daughter,
Princess Yue.
Oh. Sure.
That shouldn't be too hard.
Why is he sitting like that?
He's meditating.
Trying to cross over
into the spirit world.
It takes all his concentration.
Is there any way we can help?
How about some quiet?!
Come on, guys,
I can hear every word you're saying.
Is he ok?
He's crossing into the spirit world.
He'll be fine as long as
we don't move his body.
That's his way back
to the physical world.
Maybe we should get some help?
No. He's my friend.
I'm perfectly capable
of protecting him.
Well, aren't you a big girl now?
No...
Yes.
Hand him over
and I won't have to hurt you.
Hyah!
I see you've learned a new trick.
But I didn't come this far
to lose to you.
You little peasant.
You've found a master, haven't you?
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah...
Aah! Uh!
It's daybreak at last.
Let's write history.
You rise with the moon,
I rise with the sun.
The Water Tribe can try
to resist the inevitable,
but their city will fall today.
Aang?!
What happened?! Where's Zuko?!
He took Aang.
He took him right out from under me.
Where did they go?