Water, earth,
fire, air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his
airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
I'm not one to complain,
but can't Appa fly any higher?
I have an idea.
Why don't we all get on your back,
and you can fly us to the North Pole.
I'd love to.
Climb on, everyone.
Sokka is ready for takeoff.
Look, we're all just a little tired
and cranky
because we've been flying
for two days straight.
And for what?
We can't even find
the Northern Water Tribe.
There's nothing up here.
Aagh!
They're water benders.
We found the Water Tribe.
He's heading north.
The Northern Water Tribe.
The Avatar
needs to master waterbending.
He is looking for a teacher.
Then what are we waiting for?
Let's go get him.
Patience, Captain Li.
This isn't some little earth village
we can just march into.
The Water Tribe is a great nation.
There's a reason they've survived
100 years of war.
The frozen tundra is treacherous.
The landscape itself
is an icy fortress.
We'll need a massive invasion force.
There it is!
The Northern Water Tribe.
We're finally here.
I can't believe
how many waterbenders live up here.
We'll find a master
to teach us no problem.
This place is beautiful.
Yeah.
She is.
Winter, spring.
Summer and fall.
Four seasons.
Four loves.
For love
Tonight, we celebrate the arrival
of our brother and sister
from the Southern Tribe.
And they have brought with them
someone very special,
someone who many of us believed
disappeared from the world
until now...
The Avatar.
We also celebrate
my daughter's 16th birthday.
Princess Yue is now of marrying age.
Thank you, Father.
May the great Ocean and Moon Spirits
watch over us
during these troubled times.
Now, Master Pakku
and his students will perform!
Hi there. Sokka, Southern Water Tribe.
Very nice to meet you.
So, uh...
You're a princess, huh?
You know, back in my tribe,
I'm kind of like a prince myself.
Ha! The prince of what?
A lot of things!
Do you mind? I'm trying
to have a conversation here.
My apologies, Prince Sokka.
So, it looks like
I'm gonna be in town for a while.
I'm thinking maybe we could...
Do an activity together?
Do an activity?
Very smooth.
Master Pakku,
meet your newest student:
The Avatar.
Just because
you're destined to save the world,
don't expect any special treatment.
My friend and I can't wait
to start training with you...
After we relax for a couple of days.
If you want to relax,
then I suggest
visiting a tropical island.
If not, I'll see you both at sunrise.
Good night.
For the last time,
I'm not playing the sungi horn.
No, it's about our plans.
There is a bit of a problem.
I'm taking your crew.
What?
I've recruited them
for a little expedition
to the North Pole.
Uncle, is that true?
I'm afraid so.
He's taking everyone...
Even the cook.
Sorry you won't be there
to watch me capture the Avatar,
but I can't have you
getting in my way again.
No!
I didn't know you were skilled
with broadswords, Prince Zuko.
I'm not.
They're antiques.
Just decorative.
Have you heard of the Blue Spirit,
General Iroh?
Just rumors.
I don't think he is real.
He's real, all right.
He's a criminal
and an enemy of the Fire Nation.
But I have a feeling justice
will catch up with him soon.
General Iroh, the offer
to join my mission still stands...
If you change your mind.
I've waited for this day
my whole life.
I finally get to learn from
a real waterbending master!
Good morning, Master Pakku!
No, please! March right in!
I'm not concentrating or anything.
Uh, this is my friend... Katara...
The one I told you about.
I'm sorry.
I think there's been
a misunderstanding.
You didn't tell me
your friend was a girl.
In our tribe, it is forbidden
for women to learn waterbending.
What do you mean, you won't teach me?
I didn't travel
across the entire world
so you could tell me no!
No.
But there must be
other female waterbenders
in your tribe.
Here, the women learn from Yagoda
to use their waterbending to heal.
I'm sure she would be
happy to take you
as her student...
Despite your bad attitude.
I don't want to heal. I want to fight!
I can see that.
But our tribe has customs, rules.
Well, your rules stink!
Yeah!
They're not fair.
If you won't teach Katara, then...
Then what?
Then I won't learn from you!
Well, have fun teaching yourself.
I'm sure you'll do a great job.
Wait!
Aang didn't mean that.
You can't risk your training for me.
You have to learn from Master Pakku,
even if he is a big jerk.
Why don't we get started, then.
Princess Yue, good morning!
Hey, how about that picnic last night?
Boy, your dad sure knows
how to throw a party.
I'm happy you enjoyed yourself.
Well, it wasn't as much fun
after you left.
So, I'm still hoping
we can see more of each other.
Do an activity, you mean?
Yes, at a place...
For some time.
I'd love to.
I'll meet you on that bridge tonight.
Great! I'll see you...
Aagh!
Sorry.
That's ok. It was worth it.
See you tonight.
I'm very impressed.
You all seem highly qualified
for the mission I have in mind.
That's some tasty gold.
What do you need us to do?
I believe you're acquainted
with Prince Zuko.
Um, hi.
Are you Yagoda?
Are you here for the healing lesson?
I guess I am.
Welcome!
You're moving the water around,
but you're not feeling
the push and pull.
I'm trying.
Ahh!
Maybe that move
is too advanced for you.
Why don't you try an easier one?
Thanks for the lesson.
So, who's the lucky boy?
Huh?
Your betrothal necklace.
You're getting married, right?
Oh, no.
I don't think I'm ready for that yet.
My grandmother
gave my mother this necklace,
and my mother passed it down to me.
I recognize this carving!
I don't know
why I didn't realize sooner.
You're the spitting image of Kanna.
Wait!
How do you know my gran-gran's name?
When I was about your age,
I was friends with Kanna.
She was born here...
In the Northern Tribe.
She never told me.
Your grandmother
had an arranged marriage
with a young waterbender.
He carved that necklace for her.
If gran-gran was engaged,
why did she leave?
I don't know.
That's always been a mystery to me.
She left without saying good-bye.
Good luck!
The crew wanted me
to wish you safe travels.
Good riddance to those traitors.
It's a lovely night for a walk.
Why don't you join me?
It would clear your head.
Or just stay in your room
and sit in the dark.
Whatever makes you happy.
Whoa!
Careful with the blasting jelly.
Ooh!
Uncle?
Uncle, is that you?
Aah!
Zuko!
Zuko.
Hi, Princess Yue.
I made you something.
I carved it myself.
It's a bear.
Actually, it's supposed to be a fish.
See, it has a fin.
Oh.
I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
I shouldn't have
asked you to come here.
How's warrior training going?
That bad?
No, it's Princess Yue.
I don't get it.
One minute,
she wants to go out with me,
and the next,
she's telling me to get lost.
So, how's waterbending training?
Master Poop-head won't teach her
because she's a girl.
Why don't you just teach her, Aang?
Why didn't I think of that?
At night, you can teach me
whatever moves
you learn from Master Pakku.
That way,
you have someone to practice with,
and I get to learn waterbending.
Everyone's happy!
I'm not happy.
But you're never happy.
Come on, Aang.
Master Pakku said this move
is all about sinking and floating.
I got it!
That was amazing!
That wasn't me.
I was just showing Katara a few moves.
You have disrespected me,
my teachings, and my entire culture.
I'm sorry, I...
You are no longer welcome
as my student.
What do you want me to do?
Force Master Pakku to take Aang back
as his student?
Yes. Please.
I suspect he might change his mind
if you swallow your pride
and apologize to him.
Fine.
I'm waiting, little girl.
No!
No way am I apologizing
to a sour old man like you!
Uh, Katara...
I'll be outside
if you're man enough to fight me.
I'm sure she didn't mean that.
Yeah, I think she did.
I'm devastated
to hear about Prince Zuko.
Just devastated.
The Fire Lord will not be pleased
when he learns who was responsible.
You know who was behind the attack?
Yes. Pirates.
We had a run-in with them
a while back.
They wanted revenge.
So, have you reconsidered my offer?
Yes, I accept.
It will be an honor
to serve as your general.
To the Fire Nation.
To victory!
Are you crazy, Katara?
You're not gonna win this fight.
I know. I don't care.
You don't have to do this for me.
I can find another teacher.
I'm not doing it for you.
Someone needs to
slap some sense into that guy.
So, you decided to show up?
Aren't you gonna fight?
Go back to the healing huts
with the other women,
where you belong.
Fine.
You want to learn to fight so bad,
study closely.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Ow!
You can't knock me down!
Go, Katara!
Well, I'm impressed.
You are an excellent waterbender.
But you still won't teach me,
will you?
No.
This fight is over.
Come back here. I'm not finished yet.
Yes. You are.
This is my necklace.
No, it's not. It's mine. Give it back!
I made this 60 years ago...
For the love of my life...
For Kanna.
My gran-gran
was supposed to marry you?
Our plan is working perfectly.
Zhao doesn't suspect a thing.
You didn't have to do this.
No nephew of mine
is going to stow away on a ship
without some backup.
Thank you, Uncle.
Someone's coming.
Stay hidden
until we get to the North Pole
and the Avatar will be yours.
Good luck.
I carved this necklace
for your grandmother
when we got engaged.
I thought we would have
a long happy life together.
I loved her.
But she didn't love you, did she?
It was an arranged marriage.
Gran-gran wouldn't let your tribe's
stupid customs run her life.
That's why she left.
It must have taken a lot of courage.
Go get her.
What do you want from me?
Nothing.
I just want you to know
I think you're beautiful.
And I never thought a girl like you
would even notice a guy like me.
You don't understand.
No, no.
See, that's the thing.
I think I do understand now.
You're a princess, and I'm...
I'm just a southern peasant.
No, Sokka.
It's ok.
You don't have to say anything.
I'll see you around, ok.
Ok, now I'm really confused!
Happy, but confused.
I do like you... A lot!
But we can't be together.
And not for the reason you think.
It's because...
I'm engaged.
I'm sorry.
Not bad. Not bad.
Ha ha ha ha.
Keep practicing,
and maybe you'll get it
by the time you're my age.
Hey, Katara.
What do you think you're doing?
It's past sunrise.
You're late.
Good to see you here.
You, too.
My fleet is ready.
Set a course
for the Northern Water Tribe.