Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed,
and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar...
An airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
Oof.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
I can't believe I lost him.
You did everything you could.
And now we need to
do everything we can
to get him back.
Zuko can't have gotten far.
We'll find him.
Aang's gonna be fine.
Ok.
It's all right.
You stay here, Momo...
In case Aang comes back.
Yip, yip!
Om.
Hello?
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I just really need to find
the moon and the ocean spirits.
Go away.
You're still here?
Yes, I need...
Om!
Perhaps that thing will help you.
Chase it!
Finally.
Come back!
Hello, Aang.
Roku?!
Huh?!
Shelter!
Roku, the water tribe is under attack!
I need to find
the ocean and the moon spirits.
The ocean and the moon
are ancient spirits...
They crossed over
from the spirit world
to the mortal world
very near the beginning.
There is only one spirit I know of
who is old enough to remember...
Who?
The spirit's name is Koh,
but he is very dangerous...
They call him the Face Stealer.
When you speak with him,
you must be very careful
to show no emotion at all...
Not the slightest expression...
Or he will steal your face.
I finally have you,
but I can't get you home
because of this blizzard.
There's always something.
Not that you would understand.
You're like my sister.
Everything always came easy to her.
She's a firebending prodigy...
And everyone adores her.
My father says she was born lucky.
He says I was lucky to be born.
I don't need luck, though...
I don't want it.
I've always had to struggle and fight,
and that's made me strong...
It's made me who I am.
I don't need to remind you
we have a time limit.
If we don't defeat the water tribe
before the full moon rises,
they will be undefeatable.
I assure you...
I have everything under control.
I intend to remove
the moon as a factor.
Remove the moon?
How?
Admiral Choi!
Prepare to meet your fate!
Whoa!
As I was saying.
Years ago, I stumbled upon
a great and powerful secret...
The identity of the moon spirit's
mortal form.
What?!
I was a young lieutenant
serving under General Xu
in the Earth Kingdom.
L discovered a hidden library...
Underground, in fact.
I tore through scroll after scroll.
One of them contained
a detailed illustration...
And the words "moon" and "ocean."
I knew then that these spirits
could be found...
And killed...
And that it was my destiny to do so.
Zhao, the spirits
are not to be trifled with!
Yes, yes, I know
you fear the spirits, Iroh...
I have heard rumors about your journey
into the spirit world.
But the ocean and moon
gave up their immortality
to become a part of our world.
And now they will
face the consequences.
Phew!
You're just a curly-tailed bluenose.
Show no fear.
Show no emotion at all.
Hello?
I'm looking for a spirit named Koh.
Welcome.
Thank you.
My old friend, the Avatar...
It's been a long time.
You know me?
How could I forget you?
One of your previous incarnations
tried to slay me...
Maybe 800 or 900 years ago.
I didn't know that.
Why did he... Or I... Try to kill you?
Oh, it was something about
stealing the face
of someone you loved.
Of course, that's all behind us.
Why should I hold a grudge against you
for something in a past life?
After all...
You're a different person now.
You've come to me with a new face.
Guess we'll be here awhile.
Don't worry.
Prince Zuko can't be getting too far
in this weather.
I'm not worried
they'll get away in the blizzard.
I'm worried that they won't.
They're not gonna
die in this blizzard.
If we know anything,
it's that Zuko never gives up.
They'll survive... And we'll find them.
It's been a long time
since I've added
a child's face to my collection.
So...
How may I help you?
I need to find
the moon and the ocean.
Their spirit names
are "Tui" and "La... ".
Push and pull.
And that has been the nature
of their relationship for all time.
Please, help me find them.
An entire culture could be destroyed
if I don't get their help.
Oh, you think you need their help?
Actually, it's quite
the other way around.
Someone is going to kill them!
What do you mean?
How can I find them and protect them?
You've already met them, actually.
Tui and La... Your moon and ocean...
Have always circled each other
in an eternal dance.
They balance each other:
Push and pull, life and death,
good and evil...
Yin and Yang.
The koi fish!
I must be going now.
We'll meet again.
The spirits are in trouble!
I need to get back
to the physical world!
A friend is here to guide you back.
Hei Bai!
We'll be following this map
to a very special location.
And when we get there...
We're going fishing.
This is where I came in...
But how do I get back?
Good riddance.
Momo!
Momo?
Oh, no...
Where's my body?
Look!
That's got to be Aang!
Yip, yip!
Huh?!
Welcome back.
Good to be back.
That won't be enough to escape.
Appa!
Whoa!
Here for a rematch?
Trust me, Zuko,
it's not going to be much of a match.
Hey, this is some quality rope.
We need to get to the oasis!
The spirits are in trouble.
Wait... We can't just leave him here.
Sure, we can.
Let's go.
No.
If we leave him, he'll die.
Yeah, this makes
a lot of sense...
Let's bring the guy
who's constantly trying to kill us.
Are you ok?
I feel faint.
I feel it, too.
The moon spirit is in trouble.
I owe the moon spirit my life.
What do you mean?
When I was born,
I was very sick and very weak.
Most babies cry when they're born,
but I was born as if I were asleep,
my eyes closed.
Our healers did everything they could.
They told my mother and father
I was going to die.
My father pleaded
with the spirits to save me.
That night... Beneath the full moon...
He brought me to the oasis
and placed me in the pond.
My dark hair turned white.
I opened my eyes and began to cry...
Waah!
And they knew I would live.
That's why my mother named me Yue,
for the moon.
I am a legend now.
The Fire Nation will for generations
tell stories about the Great Zhao,
who darkened the moon.
They will call me
Zhao the Conqueror...
Zhao the Moon-slayer...
Zhao the Invincible!
Get it off!
Don't bother.
Zhao, don't!
It's my destiny...
To destroy the moon
and the Water Tribe.
Destroying the moon
won't just hurt the Water Tribe,
It will hurt everyone...
Including you.
Without the moon,
everything would fall out of balance...
You have no idea what kind of chaos
that would unleash on the world.
He's right, Zhao.
General Iroh,
why am I not surprised
to discover your treachery?
I'm no traitor, Zhao.
The Fire Nation needs the moon, too.
We all depend on the balance.
Whatever you do to that spirit,
I'll unleash on you tenfold!
Let it go now!
There's no hope now.
It's over.
No...
It's not over.
You're alive?!
You tried to have me killed!
Yes, I did.
You're the Blue Spirit...
An enemy of the Fire Nation!
You freed the Avatar.
I had no choice!
You should have chosen
to accept your failure,
your disgrace...
Then at least you could have lived.
It's too late...
It's dead.
You have been touched
by the moon spirit.
Some of its life is in you.
Yes, you're right...
It gave me life.
Maybe I can give it back.
No!
You don't have to do that.
It's my duty, Sokka.
I won't let you.
Your father told me to protect you!
I have to do this.
No!
She's gone.
Good-bye, Sokka.
I'll always be with you.
It can't be!
Take my hand!
I've decided to go to the South Pole.
Some other benders and healers
want to join me.
It's time we helped rebuild
our sister tribe.
What about Aang?
He still needs to learn waterbending.
Well... Then he better get used to
calling you Master Katara.
The spirits gave me a vision
when Yue was born.
I saw a beautiful,
brave young woman
become the moon spirit.
I knew this day would come.
You must be proud.
So proud...
And sad.
I'm surprised, Prince Zuko,
Surprised that you are not
at this moment
trying to capture the Avatar.
I'm tired.
Then you should rest.
A man needs his rest.
You, too, Momo!
Come here!
Iroh is a traitor,
and your brother Zuko is a failure.
I have a task for you...