Dwarfed by the vast expanse
of the open ocean,
the biggest animal
that has ever lived on our planet.
A blue whale, 30 metres long
and weighing over 200 tonnes.
it's far bigger
than even the biggest dinosaur.
its tongue weighs
as much as an elephant.
its heart is the size of a car,
and some of its blood vessels
are so wide
that you could swim down them.
its tail alone
is the width
of a small aircraft's wings.
its streamlining,
close to perfection,
enables it to cruise at 20 knots.
it's one of the fastest animals
in the sea.
The ocean's largest inhabitant
feeds almost exclusively
on one of the smallest -
krill, a crustacean
just a few centimetres long.
Gathered in a shoal,
krill stain the sea red,
and a single blue whale in a day
can consume 40 million of them.
Despite the enormous size
of blue whales,
we know very little about them.
Their migration routes
are still a mystery,
and we have absolutely no idea
where they go to breed.
They are a dramatic reminder
of how much we still have to learn
about the ocean and the creatures
that live there.
0ur planet is a blue planet.
0ver 70 per cent of it
is covered by the sea.
The Pacific 0cean alone
covers half the globe.
You can fly across it non-stop
for 12 hours
and still see nothing more
than a speck of land.
This series will reveal
the complete natural history
of our ocean planet
from its familiar shores to
the mysteries of its deepest seas.
By volume, the ocean makes up
97 per cent of the earth's
inhabitable space,
and the sheer quantity
of its marine life
far exceeds that
which inhabits the land.
But life in the ocean is not
evenly spread. it's regulated
by the path of currents
carrying nutrients,
and the varying power of the sun.
in this first programme, we will
see how these two forces interact
to control the distribution of life
from the coral seas
to the polar wastes.
The sheer physical power
of the ocean
dominates our planet.
it profoundly influences
the weather of all the world.
Water vapour rising from it forms
the clouds and generates the storms
that ultimately
will drench the land.
The great waves that roar in
towards the shores
are dramatic demonstrations
of its power.
Waves originate far out at sea.
There, even gentle breezes
can cause ripples,
and ripples grow into swells.
0ut in the open ocean,
unimpeded by land,
such swells can become gigantic.
it's only when an ocean swell
eventually reaches shallow water
that it starts to break.
As it approaches the coast,
the water at the bottom of the swell
is slowed by contact
with the seabed.
The top of the swell,
still travelling fast,
starts to roll over
and so the wave breaks.
The ocean never rests. Huge currents,
such as the Gulf Stream,
keep its waters constantly
on the move all round the globe.
it's these currents
more than any other factor
that control the distribution
of nutrients and life in the seas.
A tiny island lost
in the midst of the Pacific.
it's the tip of a huge mountain
that rises from the sea floor
thousands of metres below.
The nearest land is 300 miles away.
isolated sea mounts like this one
create oases
where life can flourish
in the comparatively empty expanses
of the open ocean.
But all the creatures that swim
beside it would not be here
were it not for one key factor -
the deep ocean currents.
Far below the surface,
they collide with the island's flanks
and are deflected upwards,
bringing with them from the depths
a rich soup of nutrients.
Such up-wellings attract
great concentrations of life.
Most of the fish here
are permanent residents
feeding on plankton -
tiny floating plants and animals
nourished by the richness
brought up from the depths,
and they attract visitors
from the open ocean.
Tuna.
The plankton feeders
are easy targets.
All this action attracts
even larger predators.
Sharks.
Hundreds of sharks.
These silky sharks
are normally ocean-going species,
but the sea mounts
in the eastern Pacific
like Cocos, Mapelo
and the Galapagos,
attract silkies in huge groups
up to 500 strong.
Silkies seem to specialise
in taking injured fish
and constantly circle sea mounts
on the look out for the chance
to do so.
But silkies are not
the only visitors.
Hammerheads gather
in some of the largest shark shoals
to be found anywhere in the ocean.
Sometimes, thousands will circle
over a single sea mount.
But these sharks are not here
for food.
They have come for another reason.
Some of the locals
provide a cleaning service.
Following the last El Nino year,
when a rise in water temperatures
gave many sharks fungal infections,
the number of hammerheads
visiting the sea mounts
reached record levels.
Nutrients also well up
to the surface
along the coasts of the continents.
This is Natal
on South Africa's eastern seaboard.
it's june,
and just off-shore,
strange black patches have appeared.
They look like immense oil slicks
up to a mile long.
But this is a living slick:
millions and millions of sardines
on a marine migration
that in terms of sheer biomass,
rivals that of the wildebeest
on the grasslands of Africa.
These fish live mostly
in the cold waters south of the Cape,
but each year
the coastal currents reverse.
The warm Agulhas current
that flows down from the north
has been displaced
by cold water from the south,
and that has brought up
rich nutrients.
They in turn have created
a bloom of plankton,
and the sardines
are now feasting on it.
As the sardines travel north,
a whole caravan of predators
follow them.
Thousands of Cape gannets
track the sardines.
They nested off the Cape
and timed their breeding
so that their newly-fledged chicks
can join them
in pursuing the shoals.
Below water, hundreds of sharks
have also joined the caravan.
These are bronze whaler sharks,
a cold water species that
normally lives much further south.
These three-metre sharks
cut such great swathes
through the sardine shoals
that their tracks
are visible from the air.
Harried by packs of predators
and swept in
by the action of the waves,
the sardine shoals are penned
close to the shore.
Common dolphin are coming in
from the open ocean to join the feast.
There are over a thousand of them
in this one school.
When they catch up with the sardines,
the action really begins.
Working together, they drive
the shoal towards the surface.
it's easier for the dolphins
to snatch fish up here.
Now the sardines have no escape.
Thanks to the dolphins,
the sardines have come within
the diving range of the gannets.
Hundreds of white arrows
shoot into the sea,
leaving long trails of bubbles
behind each dive.
Next to join the frenzy
are the sharks.
Sharks get very excited
when dolphins are around.
They can feed particularly well
once the dolphins
have driven the sardines
into more compact groups
near the surface.
As the frenzy continues,
walls of bubbles drift upwards.
They are being released
by the dolphins
working together in teams.
They use the bubbles
to corral the sardines
into ever tighter groups.
The sardines seldom cross
the wall of bubbles
and crowd closer together.
Bubble netting in this way,
enables the dolphins to grab
every last trapped sardine.
just when the feasting
seems to be almost over,
a Bryde's whale.
The survivors head on northwards,
and the caravan of predators
follows them.
Nutrients can also be brought up,
though less predictably,
by rough weather.
Particularly near the poles,
huge storms stir the depths
and enrich the surface waters,
and here, in the South Atlantic,
the seas are the roughest
on the planet.
And very rich seas they are, too,
for here, the cold Falklands
current from the south
meets the warm Brazil current
from the north,
and at their junction
is food in abundance.
These black-browed albatross
are duck-diving for krill
that has been driven up
to the surface.
Like all albatross,
black-brows are wanderers
across the face of the open ocean.
A feeding assembly on this scale
is a rare sight.
Most of the time, the birds
of the open sea are widely dispersed,
but these feeding grounds are close
to an albatross breeding colony,
and a very special one.
This is Steeple jason,
a remote island
in the far west of the Falklands.
it has the largest albatross colony
in the world.
There are almost
half a million albatross here,
an astonishing demonstration
of how fertile the ocean can be
and how much food it can give
even to creatures
that do not actually live in it.
Nutrients by themselves
are not enough to generate
these vast assemblies.
The heat and light from the sun
is also essential
for the growth of the microscopic
floating plants -
the phytoplankton.
And it's the phytoplankton that is
the basis of all life in the ocean.
Every evening, the disappearance
of the sun below the horizon
triggers the largest
migration of life
that takes place on our planet.
0ne thousand million tonnes
of sea creatures
ascend from the deep ocean to
search for food near the surface.
They graze on the phytoplankton
under cover of darkness.
Even so, they are far from safe.
0ther marine hunters follow them,
some travelling up
from hundreds of metres below.
At dawn,
the whole procession returns
to the safety of the dark depths.
The moon, too, has a great
influence on life in the oceans.
its gravitational pull
creates the daily advances
and retreats of the tide.
But the moon has more
than a daily cycle.
Each month, it waxes and wanes
as it travels round the earth,
and this monthly cycle
also triggers events in the ocean.
The Pacific coast of Costa Rica
on a very special night.
it's just after midnight
and the tide is coming in.
The moon is in its last quarter,
exactly half way
between full and new.
For weeks,
the beach has been empty,
but that is about to change.
At high tide, turtles
start to emerge from the surf.
At first, they come
in ones and twos,
but within an hour,
they are appearing
all along the beach.
They are all female
Ridley's turtles,
and over the next six days or so,
400,000 will visit this one beach
to lay their eggs in the sand.
At the peak time, 5,000
are coming and going every hour.
The top of the beach
gets so crowded
that they have to clamber
over one another to find a patch
where they can dig a nest hole.
A quarter of the world's population
of Ridley's turtles
come to this one beach
on a few key nights each year.
The rest of the time,
they are widely distributed
through the ocean,
most, hundreds of miles away.
This mass nesting is called
an arribada. How it's co-ordinated
is a mystery,
but we do know that arribadas start
when the moon is either
in its first or last quarter.
Forty million eggs are laid
in just a few days.
By synchronising their nesting,
the females ensure
that six weeks later,
their hatchlings will emerge
in such enormous numbers
that predators are overwhelmed,
and a significant proportion of baby
turtles will make it to the water.
But why do the females
use a cue from the moon
to help synchronise their nesting?
Part of the answer to that
becomes clear at dawn
on the following morning.
The day shift of predators
are arriving for their first meals.
Vultures have learnt
that the returning tide can wash
freshly laid eggs out of the sand.
The risk of eggs being exposed
by the surf
may be partly why
turtle arribadas tend to occur
around the last or first quarter
of the moon.
it's on such days as this when
the moon is neither full nor new,
that the tides are weakest
and the sea is likely to be calmer.
So it's easier for the female turtles
to make their way through the surf,
and harder for eggs
to be washed out of the sand
and taken by vultures.
The moon's monthly cycle
and its influence on the tides
triggers many events in the ocean,
from the spawning of the corals
on the Great Barrier reef
to the breeding cycles of fish,
but there's an even longer rhythm
that has the most profound effect
of all -
the annual cycle of the sun.
The sun's position
relative to the earth
changes through the year,
and it's this
that produces the seasons.
in the north, spring comes
as the sun begins to rise
higher in the sky.
0ff the coast
of north west America,
the seas are transformed by
the increasing strength of the sun.
Here in Alaska,
the coastal waters turn green
with a sudden bloom
of phytoplankton.
Herring that have spent the winter
far out to sea
time their return to the shallow
waters to coincide with this bloom.
They come in vast numbers
and initiate one of the most productive
food chains in all the oceans.
Humpback whales
are at the top of that food chain.
They have spent the winter
breeding in the warmer
tropical waters off Hawaii,
but there was little food there.
This herring bonanza
provides the majority of their food
for the year.
Stellar and Californian sea lions
also return from the open ocean
each year to feast off the herring.
The herring, however,
have not come here for food.
They are about to breed.
Nothing deters them
as they head
for even shallower waters.
Now the waters are so shallow
that glaucous-winged gulls
can snatch live fish
from just below the surface.
in spite of these attacks,
the herring swim on
until they reach the vegetation
that the females need
if they are to lay.
Each female produces
around 20,000 eggs,
and they're very sticky.
After the females have spawned,
the males release their sperm
in vast, milky clouds.
Soon, the excesses
of the herrings' sexual spree
creates a thick white scum
on the surface.
Through the season,
curds of sperm clog the shores
for hundreds of miles
from British Columbia in the south
to Alaska in the north.
After a few days, this gigantic
spawning comes to an end,
and the herring
head back out to deeper waters,
leaving behind them fertilised eggs
plastered on every rock
and strand of vegetation.
They time the spawning so that two
weeks later, when the eggs hatch,
the annual plankton bloom will be
at its height, and the fish fry
will have plenty to eat.
in the meantime,
these eggs provide food
for armies of different animals
below and above the surface.
Millions of birds arrive to collect
a share of the herrings' bounty.
Some of it is easily gathered,
for millions of eggs have been
washed up onto the shore.
This encapsulated energy
is particularly valuable
to migrating birds.
These surfbirds are on their way
to their breeding grounds in
the Arctic and come down to refuel.
Stranded herring eggs
are just what they need.
Bonaparte gulls collect the eggs
just below the surface
of the water.
Further out in the bay,
huge flocks of ducks have gathered.
They're mostly surf scoters -
diving ducks that can feed
off the bottom several metres down.
There are such huge quantities
of eggs,
that even a big animal like a bear
finds it worthwhile
to collect them.
The spawning of the herring
is a crucial event
in the lives of many animals
all along the coast.
The whole event coincides
with the plankton bloom,
and within three short weeks,
it's all over.
The migratory birds leave
to continue their journey north.
They will not come back until
the herring also return next year.
As the herring spawning finishes,
other migrants
are starting to arrive offshore.
Grey whales.
They have followed the sun north,
and they too are seeking the food
generated by the bloom
of the phytoplankton.
Krill are feeding off it, and these
whales are feeding on the krill,
skimming it from the surface
with the filter plates of baleen
that hang from their upper jaws.
Grey whales make
one of the longest migrations
of any marine mammal -
a round trip of 12,000 miles or so
from their breeding grounds
off Mexico
along the entire coast of North
America up to the Arctic 0cean.
They travel close to the coast,
with the males and non-breeding
females leading the way.
The last to start are cows
that have just given birth.
They have to wait until their calves
are sufficiently strong
to tackle such an immense journey.
Their progress is necessarily slow.
The mothers stay with their young,
and even a strong calf
only travels at a couple of knots.
They stick even closer
to the shore,
often within just 200 metres.
Killer whales.
They have learnt that grey whales
follow traditional routes.
The killers have no trouble
in overtaking the calf
and its devoted mother.
Normally, they continually call
to one another,
but now they have fallen silent.
The grey whale and her calf
have no idea
that they've been targeted.
Catching up with the grey whales
is the easy part for the killers.
They have to be cautious
for they are only
about half the size of the mother.
She can inflict real damage
with her tail.
But the killers are after her calf.
As long as the mother can keep it
on the move, it will be safe,
and she does her best
to hurry it along.
At first, the killers avoid getting
too close but just stay alongside.
They know that the calf, going at
this speed, will eventually tire.
After three hours of being harried,
the calf becomes too exhausted
to swim any further.
The mother has to stop.
This is the moment the killers
have been waiting for.
They start to try and force
themselves between mother and calf.
A calf separated from its mother
will not be able to defend itself.
Time and again,
the black fins of the killers
appear between the grey whales.
At last the killers succeed,
and now they've got the calf
on its own,
they change their tactics.
They leap right onto the calf,
and try to push it under.
They are trying to drown it.
The calf snatches
a desperate breath.
The mother becomes
increasingly agitated.
Frantically, she tries to push
her calf back to the surface
so that it can breathe.
But now it's so exhausted
that it has to be supported
by its mother's body.
The killers won't give up.
Like a pack of wolves, they take
turns in harassing the whales.
Now, the whole pod is involved.
0ne of them takes a bite.
Soon, the sea is reddened
with the calf's blood,
and the killers close in
for the final act.
The calf is dead.
After a six-hour hunt,
the killer whales
have finally won their prize.
The mother, bereft,
has to continue her migration north
on her own.
She leaves behind
the carcass of a calf
that she cherished for 13 months
in her womb,
for which she delayed
her own journey to find food.
The 15 killer whales spent over
six hours trying to kill the calf,
but having succeeded,
they've eaten nothing more
than its lower jaw and its tongue.
Valuable food like this
will not go to waste in the ocean.
Before long, the carcass
will sink to the very bottom
of this deep sea,
but even there its flesh
will not be wasted.
0ver a mile down, in the total
darkness of the deep ocean,
the body of another grey whale,
a 30-tonne adult.
it settled here
only a few weeks ago.
Already, it has attracted
hundreds of hagfish.
These scavengers, over half a metre
long and as thick as your arm,
are only found in the deep sea.
They have been attracted
by the faint whiff of decay
suffusing through the water
for miles around.
With their heads buried
in the whale's flesh,
they breathe through gill openings
along their sides.
They're very primitive creatures -
not even true fish
for they lack jaws.
They feed, not by biting,
but by rasping off flesh
with two rows of horny teeth.
in just a few hours,
a hagfish can eat several times
its own weight of rotting flesh.
Next to arrive,
a sleeper shark.
it moves so slowly
to conserve energy -
an important strategy
for so large an animal
surviving in such a poor habitat.
Sleeper sharks live
over a mile down,
and grow to over seven metres long.
They can go for months
without food, slowly cruising along,
waiting for rare bonanzas
such as this one
to arrive from above.
A whole range of different
deep-sea scavengers
will feast on this carcass
for a long time
before all its nutriment
has been consumed.
18 months later,
all that is left is a perfect
skeleton stripped bare.
The sun's energy, that was captured
and turned into living tissue
by the floating phytoplankton,
has been transferred
to another link in the food chain,
and has ended up as far away from
the sun as it is possible to be -
at the bottom of the deep sea.
But some energy
also returns from the deep.
Millions of opalescent squid
are on their way to the shallows.
They've come up here to mate.
As the males grab the females,
their tentacles flush red.
For most of the year,
these squid live
at a depth of around 500 metres.
They are part of these breeding
schools for a few weeks.
just one school was estimated
to contain animals
that weigh around 4,000 tonnes.
Wave after wave
rise from the depths,
and soon the seabed
in the shallows
is strewn with dense patches of
egg capsules several metres across.
As each female
adds another capsule to the pile,
the males fight
to fertilise its contents.
The squid make their huge journey
into the shallows
because their eggs will develop
faster in the warmer water here,
and when the young emerge,
they will find more food
more easily than they would
in the ocean depths.
Dawn the next morning,
and the seabed for miles around
is covered in egg capsules.
The squid have all gone.
Many have died,
but some will have returned
to their home in the deep.
They will not return
to the light of the sun
until the next time they are
driven up by the urge to spawn.