0ur planet is a blue planet.
Nearly three-quarters of its surface
is covered by the oceans.
Their enormous size, and the fact
that we know so little about many
of the creatures that live there,
presented the makers of this series
with some very difficult challenges.
The series took the best part
of five years to make
and we filmed
in nearly 200 locations worldwide.
Much of the behaviour
of the animals in this series
had never been filmed before
and some was new to science.
To get it,
the Blue Planet team were helped
by researchers at the cutting edge
of marine science all over the world.
This film is about how we worked
with those scientists
and were able to see
so much that is new.
0ne of the least known and hardest
animals to film is the blue whale.
It roams thousands of miles of open ocean
and can move at 30 miles an hour.
You have to be very lucky
even to catch up with one.
This...
This immense body is just the tip
of the flank of the biggest creature
that exists on the planet -
the blue whale.
0ver 30 metres long and weighing
as much as 200 tonnes,
it's larger than the biggest dinosaurs.
And yet its migration routes
are still largely unknown
and we have no idea
where blue whales breed.
The biggest research project
trying to solve these mysteries
is based off California,
working with one of the largest
remaining populations of blue whales.
Marine biologist Bruce Mate
is pioneering a new technique
which uses electronic radio tags
to send signals to satellites.
Amazingly, we don't know where most
whale species are at least half the year,
and it's really important
that we know their critical habitats -
where they feed, breed,
calve and migrate,
because those are the areas
that they can't do without,
We have to be very careful not to
frighten them off but, as we approach,
you can see the flukes,
you can see the head start to rise,
When it blows,
you know you're in the presence
of a HUGE animal,
There's a sense of intimidation there,
just by the sheer size of the animal,
Squeeze in,
- All rightI
- 0h, yeahI
The dart is little more than a pinprick
to the whale and, in under six months,
it will fall off.
The little tag sends up signals
to the satellite
that records the whale's exact position
each time it surfaces to breathe.
The latest results confirm
that this population commutes each year
from 0regon in the north to Mexico
and Costa Rica in the south,
with many whales overwintering
in the Gulf of California.
For three years,
we had cameramen on standby
all along this migration route
using a microlight and helicopters
to try to film blues from the air
without disturbing them.
The microlight was specially adapted
for landing on the water
so the cameraman could jump in
ahead of the whale for an underwater shot.
But soon the whales headed
out of microlight and helicopter range,
and we had to follow them south
into the Gulf of California.
There, we worked with another
marine biologist, Diane Gendron.
If we want to do an estimation
of the population,
an estimation of the numbers
of blue whale
who use the Gulf of California,
we need to know if we're looking
at the whole population
or just part of it,
And that's what we're doing
with the aerial transect -
trying to estimate
the number of blue whale
that use the Gulf of California
during winter,
Pilot Sandy Lanham has an expert eye
for spotting blue whales from the air.
For the last ten years,
she's worked with biologists
studying these animals in the Gulf.
What's really exciting
is that there are early indications
that this may be the place
that blue whales come with their calves.
For our cameraman Rick Rosenthal
it was a unique opportunity
to get rare footage of a blue whale mother
with its young.
Marilee, we've just got,,,
The spotter plane also provided
crucial information to a boat-based team
trying to catch up with the whales
down at water level.
The whales are only
on the water's surface
for two minutes.
Then they dive for 20.
But, as their tails go down,
they leave a patch of smooth water
called a footprint -
a clue to where they're heading
and where they might resurface.
You know, with experience,
you have an idea of the distance
a whale moves underwater,
looking from where you started moving,
With Diane's knowledge
and special permits,
our team managed to get really close
without disturbing the whales.
The open ocean is a vast wilderness
between the continents -
a big, blue arena where finding anything
is extremely difficult.
Somewhere out in this marine desert,
there are amazing dramas
played out every day
and the Blue Planet team
invested over 400 days
of often unsuccessful filming trips
far out to sea.
The day is still young,
It's a little after four in the afternoon,
Historically, this is about the time
that the predator hour starts up,
Probably the open ocean,
which I like to call liquid space,
is the most difficult area to work
in the ocean,
People wonder
how we even film out there -
do we just throw the camera in
or wander about for days on end?
There's hours of boredom,
Nothing goes on, Nothing,
Patience, patience,
Looking, looking,
After six weeks searching
off the Pacific Coast of Panama,
our crew finally caught up
with some fast-moving
and unusual dolphins -
spinners.
I look for dolphins, marine mammals
aggregating, coming together -
a successful predator
goes where the food is,
If we can find those patches,
then that's going to be
paydirt for us as well,
A pod of dolphins like this
is often accompanied
by other predators such as tuna.
0ur team thought that following dolphins
might lead them to some exciting action.
Right behind the dolphin school,
a massive bunch of tuna came by,
I dove down and one school
was crossing in front of me,
then all of a sudden - vroomI -
another big, massive school,
Eventually, the team struck gold -
a ball of baitfish corralled
at the surface by predators.
,,on that outside edge there,
You have to be quick
to film a bonanza like this,
because soon the baitfish
will be eaten and it'll be all over.
You have to be careful, too. This frenzy
is no place for the inexperienced.
0ne of the things -
when you are in the water,
sardines will often swarm you to try
to hide around you from the predators,
I could see a piece of the bait ball
break off and come directly at me,
The fish were on me and the tuna knew it,
The tuna were rocketing out of the deep,
just for a second, I felt I had become
part of this feeding frenzy,
I felt like a big sardine
in the middle of the bait ball,
Finally, when it was all over,
all that remained was a shower
of fish scales from the sardines,
slowly sinking into the deep,
And me,
0n the other side of the world,
another Blue Planet team was looking
for more gentle creatures -
one of the world's smallest whales,
pilot whales.
So little research
has been done in the open ocean that
normally we worked without scientists.
But here we had advice
from the local experts.
This site in the Alboran Sea
is very important for some species
that are in decline in the Mediterranean,
like the common dolphin,
the bottlenose dolphin,
the sperm whale
or even the pilot whale,
We have a lookout post on the masts
and we tow a hydrophone
behind the ship
that detects the clicks or the whistles
that these animals use to communicate,
It's just like a clock, you know,
a very rhythmic sound,
Common dolphins and pilot whales
are curious animals,
If you go straight into them,
usually they'll go away,
But if you spot them
and then stay at a distance,
they're like children - very curious -
and they'll actually go towards you,
(HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAKS)
Cameraman Mark Gottlieb
describes what it was like
to get so close to so many whales.
Their sounds filled the water,
It was an amazing experience,
(C0NTINU0US SQUEAKING)
I stayed with the whales
for about two hours,
They were very tolerant, but it's sensible
to respect their potential power,
A calf came very close to check us out,
The male was escorting
the mother and calf,
making sure nothing came too close,
which in this case was me,
As I saw the calf coming towards me,
it was obvious
that the male didn't want me there,
It was very important
to leave the calf alone,
The male came up
and swished his tail right in front of me
and nearly knocked me out,
so I just stayed there
and let them swim off on their own,
(RICARD0 ) The presence
of film crews on a ship like this
is definitely very important,
We are not just doing the research
for academic purposes
but for conservation,
so public awareness is an important part
of our programme,
It's no use for us just
to come up with scientific results,
We have to get through to the public
and politicians that take the measures,
The open ocean's ultimate filming
challenge is the world's fastest fish -
Billfish.
Spectacular predators
like marlin and sailfish
are extraordinarily difficult
to locate and film.
We finally caught up with them
off Mexico,
where Rick Rosenthal used the birds
to guide him to the action.
(RICK) There's a Mexican legend about
the frigate bird, which they call tijereta,
or scissor tail,
The height that the frigate bird flies
above the surface of the sea
is directly proportional to the depth
where the predators are swimming,
This opportunity only came after a total
of 400 days scouring the open ocean
and many failed trips.
You're pumped up, you're hunting,
you're hunting with a camera,
You have to filter out an awful lot
of what's going on around you,
get specific,
get into where the action is,
It was an exciting
but dangerous moment.
These underwater javelins can travel
at over 70 miles an hour.
Suddenly, tuna arrive
to attack the very same bait ball.
And finally, almost unbelievably,
a sei whale.
We got itI
Will it come up again?
Where the hell are you? Get goingI
Help Doug, Help Doug,
You have a wish list of things
you'd want to film,
And, if you're in these gatherings,
you'd certainly hope that some day
a whale would come in and feed
and you're in there,
In this programme,
we were at the right time,
We followed groups
of whales feeding,
We had put a cameraman
or two in the water,
At the same time,
we were filming from the surface
so we could get proper coverage,
0f all the ocean habitats,
the coasts are the most dynamic
and demanding.
Life here is harsh and there are
few permanent residents.
But when the conditions are right,
the coast can be extremely rich -
and that is exactly
what happens each June
off this coast in Natal, South Africa.
For two seasons,
our crew of six cameramen
and their extensive back-up team
came to try and film
one of the ocean's greatest spectacles.
Change speed underwater,
Six to 115.
They were here for an annual event
called the sardine run.
Millions and millions
of tonnes of sardines
migrating northwards along the coast
with the changing currents.
So much food inevitably attracts
masses of predators.
It was this predation
the team were hoping to film.
The sardine run stretches for miles,
and the microlight was constantly
searching for pods of common dolphins
that would lead them to the action.
0nce the microlight
had discovered hunting dolphins,
it passed on the location
to the boat-based teams.
And it wasn't just dolphins,
but hundreds of sharks
that were also attracted by the fish.
Before diving in, the team put special
explosive tips on their shark sticks.
If things looked really dangerous, these
could be used to frighten the sharks away.
En gardeI 0ne - two - three, GoI
Very few people
dive with the brown shark,
because we see the sharks
in shallow water
during the sardine run only,
When we are surrounded by sharks,
we feel fear,
And suddenly the dolphins come,
We hear them before we see them,
And then we start to relax,
Scientific research on the sardine run
is still in its early stages.
But underwater filming
reveals some very exciting
new behaviour among the dolphins.
Working together in teams,
they release walls of bubbles
to corral the sardines
into ever-tighter balls.
This bubble-netting behaviour
allowed the dolphins to feed
on every last sardine left behind
while the rest of the migration
continued north.
Monterey Bay,
on the coast of California.
Every year, a pod of killer whales
arrives to hunt grey whales
as they migrate north
through these waters.
0ur cameramen Doug Allan
and Tom Fitz spent eight weeks
over two seasons
trying to film the action.
We had these killer whales,
We started following them but,
as you can see, the sea's got up,
It's 30 - 35 knots,
We couldn't keep up with them,
0ur team was advised
by marine biologist
Nancy Black,
who had spent 14 years watching
killer whales in Monterey Bay
but had never seen
a single complete kill.
The boat-based team was supported
by keen-eyed spotters who every day
scoured the bay from the air
looking for grey whale mothers
and their calves taking a shortcut.
(NANCY) During the spring,
when the mothers and calves
come through,
the grey whales migrate north,
When they cross Monterey Bay,
they have no shore protection,
There's no place for them to hide,
and the killer whales
are out looking for these mother/calf
pairs of grey whales,
Killer whales can travel at over 20mph.
The challenge was
trying to keep up with the action,
whatever the weather at sea.
(NANCY) We were out there
at the perfect time,
right before the attack happened,
with the killer whales
in pursuit of the grey whales,
It's the first time that we've seen it
all the way from the start to the end,
The killers kept up the hunt
for five hours until, eventually,
the calf was so exhausted
that the mother was forced to stop.
And we had to watch
as the pod came in
to finish off the calf right in front of us,
just a few metres away.
Killer whales seem to work
in certain roles,
0ne female actually positioned herself
between the mother and calf grey whale,
She was in there, pushing him away,
The others had roles around the outside,
They seemed to be really co-ordinated,
It was the first time we'd had a chance
to document that,
We spent a long time with them that day,
(D0UG) If they'd taken a mind to,
they could have flipped us over,
But, on the other hand, I think
they were concentrating on the whale,
and we were able to get closer
but not interfere, which was important,
By the end,
I was just completely
emotionally drained,
After a six-hour hunt,
the fifteen-strong pod of killer whales
ate nothing more
than the calf's lower jaw
and its tongue.
The coral seas
are the richest in the ocean.
Their diversity and richness of life
is unmatched.
Blue Planet filmed worldwide in pretty
well every major coral reef system.
But some of the most exciting places
we worked were remote islands
far off the Pacific coast
of Central America,
like the Galapagos, Malpelo and Cocos.
This is a big event,
This is a place in this vast ocean,
and the deep water currents come in
and hit this island,
And it upwells -
brings all the nutrients up,
So the little fish feed on the nutrients,
the bigger fish feed on the little fish,
then the sharks feed on THEM,
We came out here
without any experts, by ourselves,
just out looking around
trying to find sharks,
trying to find good things to film,
And we found a bunch of them,
Finding oneself
among so many silky sharks
was an extraordinarily exciting
but perhaps worrying experience.
I don't think you have
anything to be worried about
or frightened of,
They're a very curious shark,
They come right up to you,
which makes it good for photography,
They bump you,
they push off
your camera with their nose,
I think they want to find out what you are
and what you're doing here in their world,
When they bump me, I bump them back
to let them know, ''Hey, I'm here
and I'm something to be reckoned with, ''
No sooner had they arrived than
the silky sharks started to disappear
into the open ocean,
never to be seen again
on that particular trip.
At night, a completely new collection
of animals emerges onto the reef
and we were determined to film
some of the things that happen
under cover of darkness.
But lighting the reef to look
as if it were lit by moonlight
requires a well co-ordinated team
and a complex lighting set-up.
For filming at night,
especially sharks in a big area,
we needed quite a bit of light,
Little battery lights wouldn't do,
We brought in a generator
and cables coming down
to 650W lights,
I don't think the sharks were
disturbed at all by the light,
These sharks are clued in
to little electronic impulses
from each other
and also from the prey,
Filming in the tidal seas
is all about timing.
The lives of the animals that live here
are dominated by the daily advance
and retreat of the tides.
But it's not just the daily cycle
that's important.
The monthly cycle of the moon
also has a massive effect
on the oceans.
And on the Great Barrier Reef
in Australia,
it seems to be the key factor
co-ordinating the mass spawning
of the entire reef.
We were there
to try and film that spectacle
but, as yet, it's still not
properly understood by science.
It was only 20 years ago
that they discovered that the whole
of the Barrier Reef went off,
Basically it goes off
on three or four nights,
They've been working on it ever since
but they still don't know an awful lot,
So, for the scientists,
this is really exciting,
and we tracked that down to one
small, encrusted brown multipore,
It was Craig's advice that allowed us
to get there at just the right time.
With three cameramen and a complex
lighting rig, we were determined to film.
But, for Martha,
there was a lot of tension
as she waited on deck.
It's frustrating not being able
to speak to them or see them,
If you're filming topside, you can interact
and you know
what the cameraman's getting,
But, on the back of a boat, at night,
you have no idea what's going on,
That first night,
there was no sign of the spawning.
The worry was that the lights might be
interfering with the coral's behaviour.
Craig thinks it's important
not to have light on the coral at all,
He actually got us to turn the lights off
on here and that light over there off
because it was producing a cast
on the reef,
He thinks it might be affecting the corals,
Well, we have to light it
in order to film it,
Well, I white-balanced,
I switched,,, I had the light on,,,
He obeyed instructionsI
Craig thought the light
might affect the spawning
so I thought I'd just leave things
as they are,
I wasn't told that,
(PETER) This is a practice lighting,
(MARTHA) It was, you're quite right,
Tantalisingly, for two more nights,
there was little sign of the spawning.
But, eventually, on the fourth night,
something started to happen.
Some of the corals began to release
sperm in clouds into the water.
But this was not
the mass-spawning spectacle
the team had come to film.
For the cameramen,
it was rather frustrating work
as they picked away, trying to get
the pictures needed to build up the story.
It just takes such a long time,
I mean, it doesn't go in one big bang,
It just goes 1,,, 2,,,
Quite a lot of eggs go off,
but they don't go off in vast numbers,
They just sort of waft out gently,
4,,, 5,,, 1,,,
We would follow one egg,
you know, one egg,,,
You wait five minutes
and you might get two,
Watching a lump of stone
getting ready to spawn is,,,
(PETER) Now, this,,, We've gone up
and we've got the main light,
We're not balanced for that
so I just had to adjust it,
- That's mine,
- I know, I know,
Finally, on the fifth night,
it seemed it was all going to happen
and Martha could hardly suppress
her excitement.
Ye-e-e-esI
But there was a problem. At the last
minute, Peter's camera had failed.
He worked desperately to fix it
in the few hours remaining
before the spawning was due to happen.
(MARTHA) We're in go mode
for tonight,
We're in go mode tonight,
- With colour,
- 0h, there'll be some colour there,
No guarantee what it's likeI
There'll be some colour there but,,,
(MIKE) ,,but no spawning yet,
Luckily,
on the fifth night,
the team WERE all set
to film a spectacular mass spawning
of the coral reef.
The seasonal seas that occur
in the temperate regions of the world
are probably the most productive
parts of the ocean.
But they're hard places to work in.
Their very productivity
reduces water visibility,
and the weather is often rough
and unpredictable.
The Blue Planet
came to temperate waters off California
to film some exciting new behaviour
in harbour seals,
first observed by biologist
Teri Nicholson.
Harbour seals are incredible,
I guess what I love about working
with them is dispelling the myth
that they are these funny,
rock-looking objects on shore,
When you get underwater with them,
they have an incredibly complex
and dynamic social life,
They're very curious
and very cool to be with,
Teri discovered that young male seals
seem to learn
an extraordinary courtship song
by closely mimicking older males.
(DEEP GUTTURAL GURGLES)
(SHE IMITATES THE SEALS' S0NG)
I know it sounds much more intense
than that, but I'm a femaleI
These vocalisations kind of allow males
to feel each other out
and figure out
who are the males to stay away from,
who they can potentially be harmed by,
They're bigger and more dominating
than other males that they can overcome,
The biggest lesson I've learned
is that, to look at harbour seals
and understand their behaviour,
you have to look underwater,
Amost everything interesting
these animals do occurs underwater,
Hundreds of miles to the north,
off Prince William Sound, Alaska,
another Blue Planet team came in search
of one of the least-known sharks -
salmon sharks.
These unusual relatives
of the great white shark
have never been observed
behaving naturally underwater,
and we were keen to try and get
unique images using a remote camera
attached to a pole.
Director Hugh Pearson could watch
the action via a monitor on the surface.
It was great to try and film
something very new,
Also, it just fitted in
so well with our story,
because the whole theme
of the temperate programme
is the seasonality of the seas,
And this story is totally seasonal,
The salmon sharks wait for the salmon
to spawn, and then they move in,
(PETER) 0bviously, we're hoping
that we're going to get them
actually behaving naturally
and fishing amongst the salmon
in the thick numbers that we're told,
(HUGH) The timing for us
to come here is absolutely vital,
because, for most of the year,
the scientists think they're out feeding
in the North Pacific on whatever's there,
But they follow the salmon in
and the salmon only run in for maybe
a month or so during the summer,
It's not just the sharks
that are after the salmon -
there's a big fishing industry here.
Marine biologist Ken Goldman
works with the fishermen,
who help him catch sharks
for science.
The salmon sharks are becoming
an important resource
for the state of Alaska,
There's a large interest in sport fishing,
It's becoming big news
for game fishing,
The state and the federal government
are interested in managing this species
before the population
begins to decline
because of the fishing,
Catching and tagging
a 4-metre shark is hard work.
But Ken hopes it might provide
vital information about population size
and where the sharks go to breed.
They've only ever been seen here
off Alaska
and then for just one month
each year.
The rest of their lives
remains a mystery.
(KEN) That'll be fine, That's good,
This is often the only close-up look
that Ken ever gets of his shark.
And he was as fascinated
as we were to see
what pictures would emerge
from our camera on a pole.
This is a 3-minute selection
of some of the good stuff we got,
(KEN) This kind of activity
is what I don't get to see,
Even when I look over the side
of the boat,
I get a top view, I don't see the side of it
or get to look up underneath it,
What's the distance from the camera,,,
That's nice,
It's probably 10 foot
when you start to see him,
(KEN) They probably see
that camera at 30 feet,
Who knows? But theirs are adapted
to that environment where ours are not,
(HUGH) Do you think from that
- that they're very visual predators?
- Yeah,
By exploiting the shark's visual sense,
we hope to lure them closer to get
some more powerful images still.
You get that silver-sided salmon
doing what you're doing,
You're moving it along,
it's something visual
going through the water,
You can't really see it
without a video shot like this,
where it comes in, turns its head to it,
then turns away - curious and cautious,
And then comfortable enough
to go for it,
It's a new look, This is a shark
that so little is known about,
and few people have had the opportunity
to see them underwater,
So, every time, the behaviours are
either confirming something we suspect
or showing us something new, or
something we didn't think they could do,
It's absolutely wonderful to see,
You learn stuff every time
you watch something like this,
The frozen seas in the Antarctic
and the Arctic, for some,
are the most beautiful
of all ocean habitats.
But it's dangerous to be lulled
by their beauty.
For the animals
that have to survive at the poles,
and our teams who had to work there,
conditions could hardly be harsher.
This is not a day to be looking
for bears,
It's about minus 15
with 20 knots of wind,
The wind chill
is something ferocious,
Doug Allan made several trips
to the Arctic island of Svalbard
to try and film polar bears hunting.
I've got this little guy here,
He comes with me on all my trips,
And, if I put him down here
by the window, facing out,
hopefully he'll bring in the real thing,
So, do your stuff,
Polar bears hunt far out
on the frozen sea ice,
which is a dangerous place to work.
And finding a white bear
in this white wilderness
requires much patience and experience.
God, that was so frustrating,
We had this female and cub, We'd been
watching her for the last 3 or 4 hours
doing a bit of hunting,
never very close,
Anyway, she came in
to a nice position,
And then I took a few steps
towards her,
She was a long way away but she just
completely reacted the wrong way,
I lost all her confidence
and now she's,,,
pissed off,
And it's such a nice day for filming,
And I thought we had it and,,,
0h,,,
If anything, working in Antarctica is
even more demanding than the Arctic.
Here you can be thousands of miles
from civilisation
and everything you need
has to come in by sea or air.
We were fortunate
to have the support of scientists
on the Italian Antarctic programme
who kindly let us share
a temporary research base
they'd set up miles out
on the edge of the frozen sea ice.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
The Italian programme is involved
in a wide range of Antarctic research,
but here they were concentrating on
the communities of animals and plants
that live under the ice.
By measuring the amount of light
that reaches algae under the ice,
they hope to monitor the frozen sea's
productivity - one vital way
to gauge the health
of the Antarctic 0cean.
Their hole also provided
a unique opportunity for Doug.
It's quite nice,
Really big platelets of ice,
Very impressive when Mark's crawling
in amongst it trying to find a space
for the light centre,
Very nice, Browns, greens,
all kinds of colours,
A Weddell seal came by and gave us
a quick once-over,
But most of our work
was concentrated at the ice edge.
We were there to film Emperor penguins
as they returned to their breeding colonies
from feeding far out to sea.
A remote camera under the ice helped us
predict when the penguins would emerge.
0K, I think that's it, That's it,
Back in the Arctic, on Svalbard,
after weeks of patience,
Doug was finally getting close
to a polar bear and its cub.
You have to work very carefully
to gain her confidence.
It's five o'clock in the morning
and I think we've just cracked it,
We had a female there
with the cub,
and she did quite a lot
of pouncing about,
50 to 80 metres away,
just a nice sort of distance,
And do you know what she did
when she was finished?
She was so relaxed,
she sat down
and gathered the cub in to her,
and suckled it head-on to the camera,
I tell you,
the weight off your mind when you get
something like that is incredible,
Sixty per cent of our planet
is covered by ocean
more than a mile deep.
The deep is by far the largest
of all the ocean habitats.
And yet it's the least known.
You need the very latest technology
to explore this last frontier.
As you descend, the light diminishes and
pressures increase to dangerous levels.
Within 1,000 metres,
it's 100 times that on the surface
and only a handful of submersibles
worldwide can dive any deeper.
You're flying around in this very small
ball of air - a glass bubble,
zooming around,
And it's just a wonderful feeling
to think that the chances are excellent
that no one else has ever seen
anything you're looking at
on that entire dive,
We joined
the Johnson Sealink submersible
from the Harbor Branch
0ceanographic Institute
to film a completely new community
of animals only discovered in the '90s.
This brine lake
is surrounded
by thousands of mussels,
and there are extensive fields
of tubeworms nearby,
all existing without the sun's energy.
Filming was a real challenge.
Every single thing you do
is done remotely,
You barely twist this knob
and the iris jerks,
And, you know, you see
that kind of stuff - it's frustrating,
Beautiful, close-up images of tubeworms,
revealed for the very first time.
These worms live 1,000 metres down,
but we wanted to dive
a lot deeper than that
and had to use
a far stronger submersible.
This is ALVIN,
operated by the Woods Hole
0ceanographic Institute.
It's a reinforced titanium tank
with tiny windows,
which allows it to dive
as deep as three miles.
We joined ALVIN on a number
of different expeditions.
This time we were diving over a mile
down into the San Diego trench
about 40 miles
off the Californian coast.
I'll be tracking you on 12,5,
Crammed into the tiny sphere
just 2 metres wide was the pilot,
chief scientist Craig Smith...
and, once again, our cameraman
Mike deGruy.
500 metres, Five - zero - zero,
Craig was keen to return
to a particular location
that he had visited
on a previous expedition
18 months before.
I hear sonar target,
North-east at 60 metres,
The sonar found its target -
the skeleton of a 40-tonne grey whale.
After a year and a half on the seabed,
this was all that was left.
But we first filmed it
as a fresh carcass
after just six weeks on the bottom.
0riginally, the dead whale had
washed up on the coast of California.
With Craig's advice,
we'd paid a local fisherman
to drag it out to the San Diego trench,
where it was to be sunk.
Easier said than done.
We put 5,000 pounds of weight on it
and it was still sticking halfway
out of the water,
We stabbed it full of holes
with cleansing knives
and a big spear that the first engineer
made from the ship,
He also shot it full of holes
with his ,45 automatic pistol,
The gas coming out of it
when you cut holes in it was horrible,
But the hard work proved worthwhile.
The carcass attracted
an extraordinary variety
of deep-sea scavengers.
SharkI SharkI
0h, geeI He's right out here,
0ut of nowhere, a sleeper shark,
a real deep-sea specialist,
and never filmed at this depth before.
These sharks and thousands
of hagfish stripped the carcass bare
and this was all that was left
18 months later when we returned.
Craig's main interest in returning
was to collect pieces of bone
to take them to the surface.
For Mike, it was another opportunity
to film this eerie
but fascinating spectacle.
It's amazing, It's just evolved,
When we first got down there,
it looked like no meat, all skeleton,
I thought, ''Ah, well, that's great, ''
Big rib cages and hagfish
moving through - totally picked clean,
Unbelievable, Then, as we settled in,
and started looking in detail,
we saw mats of all these worms, and
suddenly meat, hagfish grinding away,
There's still meat on it
a year and a half later,
It was great, And it looks terrific,
Everything worked, Hah, I'm happy,
Craig was delighted to get so many
specimens lifted to the surface,
even if they were less than fragrant.
They do smell pretty bad,
0n the surface, Craig could get
a really close look
at the life living on the bones.
0n a previous expedition,
he found 178 species on one vertebra.
There's a fascinating community
of animals
that seem to be able to survive
in the darkness
by breaking down the energy
trapped in the whale's bones.
What really fascinates Craig about the
new species discovered on dead whales
is that some are also found in
one other special deep-sea habitat.
Two miles down
along the mid-oceanic ridges,
extraordinary volcanic activity
emerges out of the seabed
in hydrothermal vents.
Scientists were amazed
to discover among these vents
one of the richest oases of life
in the deep ocean.
Since they were first discovered,
a new species has been revealed
every ten days.
And what fascinates Craig
is that some of these species
are exactly the same as those
found on his dead whales.
Remarkably, Craig believes that
his whale skeletons may be providing
vital stepping stones of energy
for larvae journeying
to colonise a new vent.
Like so much in the marine world,
this science is breaking
the frontiers of knowledge
and new discoveries
are made every day.
The satellite tags on the blue whales
are still operating today,
providing Bruce Mate
with new information round the clock.
We've seen animals
tagged on the same day
go in dramatically different directions,
In the first seven weeks,
one went up to southern 0regon,
one was down on the Baja coast,
one was 1,200 miles offshore,
Some of those animals have gone all
the way down to the Costa Rican dome,
which is about eight degrees north
of the equator and 400 miles offshore,
Despite all the efforts
of researchers worldwide,
we still do not know
where these giants go to breed.
Like so much about our blue planet,
it remains a mystery.
(HUGH) I don't know if we got that shot,
(PETER) We'll get it again,
Go on, get your act together,
Bloody producers,
Can't get the staff,