I received this notification
There's nothing for you
But I've been notified
There's nothing
Check it yourself if you wish
When shall I come again?
When you get another
"notification, perhaps"
Enough of this nonsense!
Who is it?
"I can hear you breathe, you skunk"
I'm sorry
I'm off to empty the dust-bin
The chute's out of order
"I know, I know"
My milk hasn't been delivered
They only deliver every second one
Want to be the milk woman?
I'm too busy
So is the one who used to deliver milk
Yes?
Good morning
What can I do for you?
I heard you were looking for
someone to deliver milk
How old are you?
Nineteen
You still at school?
"No, I'm employed at the post office"
I live in the neighborhood
Do you realize a milkman
get up at five...
in the morning every day?
I get up early anyway
This is the gas-works
emergency service
I have a gas leak to report
Are you sure?
"Yes, You see, I can smell it"
"I can hear it, too"
Where is that leak?
In my gas stove
Have you turned the gas off?
"Your address, please?"
"No. 4, Piratow street"
Flat No.376
Our man will be there soon
Who is it?
The milkmen
You forgot to put the empty bottle out
Yes
Tomek...
Have you got a girl-friend?
No
I suppose nobody's ever told you
"You see, girls pretend to be"
"unceremonious, they kiss boys..."
But actually...
prefer them to be subtle
Should you ever want to
"bring somebody to the flat,"
you're quite free to
I haven't a girl-friend
Tomek!
Good morning?
"I talked to you the last time,"
didn't I?
Yes
I've received another notification
"Well, I don't know"
This is my second visit here
"I know, Madam"
But there's nothing
And the second notification which
seems to be false...
"Quite a mess you have here, eh?"
I'd like to talk to an older person
Pardon?
An older person
The postmaster or somebody
I'll be back
"Yes, Madam?"
This is the first one
It's several days old
And this is the second one
"Two notifications about money orders,"
but there's no money
"And no order, either"
These are notification all right
What's wrong?
But there's no money
I'd like to see the orders
Who's the sender supposed to be?
I don't know
It says twenty-four thousand
Then how do you know the money
was sent to you at all?
"Why, this is the second notification"I got
But the official's told you
"there's nothing, hasn't he?"
That's impossible
I keep getting those...
Mr. Wacek!
"Yes, Madam?"
Take a look at these!
Ordinary notifications
They're from your area
Did you write them out?
"No, it wasn't me"
I always write with a pencil
Don't you hear?
They aren't from our office
I found these in my own post-box!
And there's the stamp of
you office on them
The post office isn't mine
It's national
You must have wrote them out yourself
You'd better inform the police about it
"Yes, you're right"
"May I have the notifications, please?"
"Oh no, you're not getting them"
They're forged
"Just look at her,"
tried to swindle money!
Want anything from me?
I'd like you to know
There wasn't any money
And the notifications?
That was my doing
Why?
I wanted to see you
To see me?
You wanted to see me
"You cried yesterday, didn't you?"
How do you know?
I've been peeping at you...
I've been peeping at you
through the window
Get out!
"Get out of here, but quick!"
I'm counting three
One...
Two...
Are you looking at me now?
Yes
I moved the bed for you
Can you see it?
Have a good time
Hey!
You there!
You bum!
Come here!
Come right down!
You're a coward
"Ah, so it's you, baby, eh?"
Now put your hands up!
And never try that trick again
"At you age, it isn't good for you"
I thought it was you
Want to come in? I'm alone
You're looking swell
"Hardly a fighter, eh?"
"Tell me, why are you peeping at me?"
Because I love
I really do
And what do you want?
I don't know
To kiss me?
No
Or perhaps...
to go to bed?
"I mean, to make love to me?"
No
Then what do you want?
Nothing
Nothing?
Could I ask you to a coffee-shop?
Buy you some ice-cream?
Sorry
How long have you been watching me?
One year
Remember what you said that morning?
Repeat it
I love you
There's no love
There is
No
Got any friends?
"Just one, but he's away"
for the present
Where is he?
In Syria
Serving in the Polish UN troops
I'm living at his mother's now
It's across the street from
I can guess that
"He used to peep at you, too"
Did he tell you about it?
"When he was leaving, he gave me his
"binocular and showed me your window
What did he say?
Well...
Out with it
A nice...
Go on
A nice chick... Likes a screw...
I know now
"All right, so you love me and work"
"at the post office, what else?"
I learn foreign language
And how many have you
learned already?
Bulgarian...
"That's nice, but what for?"
We had two Bulgarian kids back
at the orphanage
Then I learned English
"Right now, I'm learning Portuguese"
You're a funny kid
"No, I just have a good memory"
I remember everything
From the very beginning
Do you remember the moment
"you were born, too?"
I sometimes seem to remember it
And your parents?
Do you remember a boy...
A slender one...
Used to visit me last autumn...
"I remember him, he brought you milk
and"bread rolls, and collected some parcels"
"That's him, he went abroad"
and never came back
I liked him
"I liked him too, I guess"
"Well, he went to Austria"
and then to Australia
To Australia?
I used to steal you letters
I didn't know they were from him
I work at the post office
You've encircled me
"Delivering my milk,"
summoning me to the office...
"sending gas-fitters to pester me,
"stealing my letters
"Ah well, it doesn't really matter"
Give me your hand
Now stroke me
Look
Experienced men do it this way
Our bus...
Let's make a deal
"If we manage to catch it, you'll visit me"
"If we fail, you won't, O.K.?"
Then give me your hand
What else do you know about me?
Tell me what you see from your window
when I'm having company
It's called making love
I once watched you do it
I don't anymore
It's got nothing to do with love
Tell me what I do on such occasions?
You take your clothes off...
and theirs...
"you take their clothes off, too"
Then you both lie down on the bed
"Sometimes on the floor, too"
Where else?
In the kitchen...
You close your eyes...
then you raise your arms
Can you imitate it?
Ever had a girl?
No
Do you play with yourself while
looking me do it?
Not anymore... I used to
Know it's a sin?
Yes
"But now, I only..."
think about you
Don't say anything now
"You know I'm naked underneath,"
don't you?
A woman who wants to be with a man...
gets wet inside...
And that's what I am right now
You have gentle hands
Don't be afraid
Finished?
"Well, did you like it?"
"See, this is what love is"
You can go to the bathroom
Wipe it away with a towel
"I'm sorry, please come back"
I'm not home
I'm sorry
Did I wake you up?
No
I'm looking for...
He forgot his coat at my flat
Come on in
You'd better lie down
Is he out?
No
He's in a hospital
What happened?
Nothing serious
"He'll be out in several days,"
a dozen maybe
I'd like to visit him there
"You know, he only just left"
my flat...
I know
I'm afraid...
I...
I harmed him
"No, please don't go in there"
He'll be back
Please tell me what happened
You'll think it's funny
He fell in love with you
This is his field-glass
He used to peep at you through it
"Must have stolen it somewhere,"
I guess
"He had binoculars before that,"
about a year long
"And here's his alarm clock,"
set on half past eight
"You come home about that time,"
don't you?
More or less
"He's fallen on the wrong person,"
hasn't he?
Yes
I take care of him
"You have a son of your own, don't you"
He's away
And he's sure to go away again
as soon as he's back
He's been running away all his life
Never wanted to stay with me
I'm an old woman
I neither need nor want anything
But I'm afraid to be alone
I like to have somebody next to me
Good night
May I perhaps phone you...
ask about his health?
There's no phone in this flat
"Excuse me, Madam"
What is his name?
Tomek
Closed
What are these deletions
supposed to mean?
Please never delete anything
Excuse me
The number of your flat?
I've got nothing for you
Do you know what happened
to that boy?
Used to work at a counter
in your post office
He cut his veins
"Unhappy love, they say..."
Do you know his name?
"Sorry, you'll have to"
ask the postmistress
Hello?
"Is that you, Tomek?"
Say something
I've been looking for you everywhere
I went to several hospitals
I wanted to find you...
to let you know you were right
"Do you hear, Tomek?"
You were right
I don't really know what to say
How to say it
"That you, Magda baby?"
Yes
This is Wojtek speaking
"Good morning, I mean, Good evening"
Was it you who phoned
just a moment ago?
"Yeah, but I couldn't get through"
Damn it
Did you hear what I was saying?
No
Excuse me
Is he back?
Not yet
I don't peep at you anymore