Eleven... twelve...
Thirteen... fourteen...
I couldn't go on
Dad?
Could you think of
something, Dad?
Kermit running away.
From Miss Piggy...
riding a sledge at sixty-two
kilometers per hour
Piggy chasing him, skiing at
eighty-seven kilometers per hour
How much later has she left?
Three minutes
Fix the numerical value
It'll catch up 626seconds later
I made it, Dad
She'll catch up with him in ten
minutes and twenty-six seconds!
Hi
Come on in
Cold, isn't it?
Say, somebody dies abroad
Would his obituary be
published, too?
Possibly...
You see, there are paid ads
You pay, they publish °¶
Why do people die?
It depends...
Heart failure cancer...
Accidents, or just old age...
I mean, what is death?
Death?
The heart ceases
to pump blood...
Blood fails to reach the brain...
Everything stops... stops dead...
...and that's it
What remains?
Everything you did
The memory of what you did,
of you as a person
Memory's quite important,
I guess
You remember there was
somebody who walked
with a funny leap,
or who was a kind man
You remember his face, his smile...
the gap in his front teeth...
Come on, Pawel, not yet
What do you want?
It's too early
Turned sour, eh?
Yeah...
It says here, a requiem mass...
may her soul rest in peace...
You never said anything
about the soul
It's just a way to bid farewell...
There isn't any soul...
Aunt Irena says there is...
Some people just find
life easier if they believe in it...
What about you?
Me?
I really don't know
What are you thinking about?
It's nothing... it's just...
I was so glad in the morning when I
managed to get that calculation right
And then the pigeon came
for the bread crumbs
But I went shopping
and saw a dead dog
I knelt over him, and I said
to myself, what good is it?
Who needs the information
how long it will take
Miss Piggy to
catch up with Kermit
It doesn't make any sense
Which dog was it?
The one with the yellow eyes
You could always find him
at the dust-bins
Yes?
Maybe he's better off where he is
now. How do you think
We have visited School No 218
to talk to the head-master
I see you distribute milk
to the children
Yes, We've made
an arrangement with the dairy
The children get a glass of milk
each during the long break
But this milk tastes foul
The children pour it down the toilet!
Not in our school,
during the long break
What is it that you've got?
A guinea pig
What for?
I brought it to biology classes
But the teacher is scared of it
Look, it's got sharp teeth,
hasn't it?
Pawel!
Just one more time!
What's for dinner?
Soup and something
to follow, right?
Sure it is, I'm hungry
Some TV people came to
our school today
Why?
I don't know, something about milk
They told us to run about
Did you?
Of course I did
Want to take your bag home?
Yes, I've got a great thing
to show to you
See?
Stop at the door
Which door?
The front one
O.K. I'm ready
Now watch it,
it's going to lock it...
Has it?
Yes
Now it's going to unlock it
So it has
Go to the bathroom
But don't touch anything
Watch the tap
Water
Look what I programmed
I got a letter from Mum,
saying what
she does during the day,
hour after hour
Well, I fed that into its memory,
and I added the time
difference, too
It's now...
thirty-three minutes past three...?
Mama 15.33
She's asleep
Ask it what she's dreaming about
what does she dreaming about?
I do not know
It doesn't know
Do you know what you
Mum's dreaming about?
No, I guess I don't
Why that's simple, you...
Me?
Of course
She's dreaming about you
Not about Dad?
Who knows...
Know what he's doing?
More or less...
Christ!
What is it?
I'm hungry
Let's go
I wish Dad let me try his one
It would surely know
what Mum's dreaming about
Care for a race?
O.K.
Do you want odds?
Not today, well
Go!
That was good
Want me to wash the dishes?
No, thanks
I'll do it
I want to show you something
Hey, Pawel
Come here!
That was when you brought
that pink pen-case for me?
Right, I had them developed
Know who it is?
Yes
Is he... kind?
Yes...
And wise?
How do you think... Does he know
what people live for?
I guess He does
Dad says we all live to
make life easier...
...for those who come after us
But sometimes we fail
Yes, that's right
Sometimes we fail
You know...
What matters in life is that
you can do some thing for others
help them...
Whenever you do somebody
a favor, no matter how small
You feel they need you
And then, life's easier
There are big and
small things you can do
Say today, you liked the ravioli
and that made me happy
Life is...
...a present
a gift, you know
I say
Dad's you brother, right?
Don't you know?
Ah, you mean,
Why we're different?
Your father and I...
We grew up in a Catholic family
But you Dad noticed very early...
...that a lot of things could be
counted and measured...
And then he started to believe that
everything could...
He still thinks so today
I guess he has doubts sometimes...
but he won't admit it
A life like your Dad lives
may seem more reasonable
But it doesn't mean
there's no God
...for your Father, too...
Know what I mean?
I'm not sure
There is God
It's very simple... if you believe
Do you?
Do you believe in God?
Yes
Who is He?
What do you feel?
I love you
Exactly... And this is what God is...
Checkmate!
That's would be too simple
She's already won six games
Checkmate
Seven
But look, she'll use
the queen as a shield,
and then we've got her
where he want her
Checkmate
I told you...
She plays routine games
Well, what happens now?
The bishop - and checkmate
Checkmate
Congratulations
Thank you
Is that you, Pawel?
Yes
Have you talked to your father?
Hey, Dad... It's Aunt Irena
Well?
She wants to know
if it's all right with you
Irena?
I enrolled him for religious
instruction. Has he told you?
Well, if that's what he wants
Of course, if that's what he needs
I talked...
to the priest
Oh, you did?
They're building a new church
not far from your house
The priest is a young man
I think Pawel's going to like him
How about tomorrow?
No, thanks, I can manage...
Well, bye
Pawel...
Did you switch it on?
No, I never touched it
Hey, mate
what do you want?
I am ready
Switch yourself off, will you?
What if - if it really
wanted something?
Like what?
I don't know, but you asked him
Hey, mate, what do you want?
Just trying to be funny
It's half past nine, time to bed
Are you going out?
Yeah... But I'll leave
the lights on for you
Have you checked
the thermometer?
Yes, it's fourteen degrees
below zero
Think Mum's going to phone
before Christmas?
I guess so
Group one: Juda, judasz, judzic
Group two: Podbechtywac,
podskakiwac, podkopywac...
Group three: Dranstwo, zaprzanstwo,
swinstwo, koltunstwo, panstwo
These are associative fields
Now...
Take a word which does not exist
in the Polish language
But which we find rather
easy to understand
The problem only arises when we try
to translate it into another language
In exceptional cases only,
a foreign language
become one's own
intimate language
We may have a very good
rational knowledge
...of that language
We may be able to use it to
discuss most intricate problems
Have an immense vocabulary
But - that's it
how could we get...?
To what's hidden deep
behind the separate words
syllable and letters?
How could we discover that
language's cultural heritage?
How could we formulate its
connections with history, politics
...culture and everyday life
How to know and understand...?
...all that creates the
spirit of a language,
its metasemantics...
or perhaps even
its metaphpysics?
According to Elliot, poetry is...
...untranslatable
But was Elliot necessarily right?
Imagine a translator who...
...is able to accumulate
the entire knowledge
there is about words
or about a language
A translator who has
an unlimited memory...
that can be drawn from any time
Used in an unconventional way,
a computer may be something -
somebody - liomebody - like that
Consider that instrument
it seems to discern just two figures,
zero and one
But actually it not only has something
that might be called intelligence
but also a kind of consciousness
it select which means it makes a choice
Or perhaps it might be
called conation?
As I see it,
an appropriately...
programmed computer may have...
it's own taste
Aesthetical preferences...
Individuality...
Ah, yes...!
For our next class...
Please choose a line of any text...
and do what i did
with that word I conceive myself
I hope it's not too much
for homework
Is it?
That's good
Look,
I left it here for one hour only
Would tea freeze, too?
Yes
Just touch it
Hey, be careful... it's glass
Great, isn't it?
Leave it in the tub...
No, let's leave it here and
check what happens
Nothing, it's going to melt as
soon as a thaw sets in, what else?
Or maybe during the day,
in the sun...
Let's calculate it
You promised?
Oh, all right
It would be wrong to assume that
the temperature never goes up
Say, it's below zero during the
night only About ten hours
But we need precise data
O.K.
All right, call the Meteorological
Institute and ask them...
about the temperature
near the ground today
yesterday, and the
day before yesterday
Hello... Is this the
Meteorological Institute?
I need information
about the temperature
near the ground, please... today...
Yesterday...
And the day before yesterday
Yes, in Warsaw
Thank you, good-bye
What's the pressure formula?
P equals F divided by S
Fine... Now, the temperature?
Eleven today, fourteen yesterday
and twelve and a half
the day before yesterday
There's been frost
for eight days now
Well?
As you see: Maximum load is
257kg/m2<
It means a fellow three times
your weight
...can skate safely
Really?
Can I have them?
Have what?
What I was to get for Christmas,
From Mum and you
Can I have them?
I found those skating boots...
Where?
In the counch...
Can I have them?
Lake depth: 3.5m
Maximum load: 257kg/m2<
How's the size?
They're perfect
Well, then... Put off
your clothes and go to bed
I'm going for a walk
by the time I'm back
You asleep?
No, I've been
watching them shine
I checked the ice
That's why I couldn't sleep
I guessed where you went
It's all right
But promise never to come close
to where the river falls into the lake
Keep a distance of fifteen meter,
right? The river never freezes
O.K., fifteen meters it is
It's a shallow river but I don't
want you to take a bath in it
Where's your elephant?
Asleep
Is Pawel home?
No, why?
I don't know
Mum wanted to know
Good evening...
Ewa Jezierski speaking...
Is Pawel home?
Marek hasn't returned yet...
Oh, good evening, Madam
No, Pawel isn't here
But he's having the English lesson
tonight, what time is it?
Past four...
They ought to be back by now
They'll be back any minute
For you see, something's happened...
I don't know
Something happened in the
neighbourhood I'll go bring them back
Piotrus!
No, wait! My Coat
Sonny!
Is Pawel here?
What's the matter with you?
A nasty case of flu, I couldn't
lecture today, I dismissed them
When was that?
Right after they came
Where are they?
I don't know
Take it easy... come in!
She's ill
The boys aren't there
The ice broke on the lake
This can't be true
It broke...
Don't get excited
It couldn't have
But it did... Please go there
I'll be all right
Have you seen
Pawel anywhere?
At school, today morning
He told me a dream he had
But not now?
No, he said he'd
call me on the phone
one, two, three, four, five...
...ten...
Pawel!
Is that you, Irena?
Has Pawel phoned you?
You mean, when?
Lately... Today?
Yes, after school,
I asked him to lunch
but he couldn't,
he had that English lesson
He hadn't and that's the problem
Where is he?
I don't know... not here
Is anything wrong?
Well... The ink got spilled
The ink bottle cracked and
it got spilled, all of a sudden
But I mean, is anything
wrong with Pawel?
I don't know
They say the ice broke
on the lake
But he said, you figured it out
The ice is strong enough
They say it's cracked
I'm coming
I'm off to look for him
Pawel? Where are you, Pawel?
Over
This is your father calling...
Pawel? Over
Mummy!
Mummy...
Jacek darling!
Where have you been, sonny?
We've been playing in that old car
Come on, dear, we're going home
Excuse me, sir
Pawel was...
to phone me in the afternoon
Do you remember me, sir?
That boy might know something
Which boy?
The small one, Jacek
Please wait a moment
He didn't play with us
He skated on the lake!
On the lake!
I am ready...