Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
You are truly the Emperor's son.
You look just like him.
Yes, l know.
Your presence here means only one thing.
Aku has returned.
And you, little samurai,
have become the world's only hope.
This will be your new home.
Your training begins tonight.
Your father, the Emperor,
shortly after you were born...
gathered together the chiefs
of all the great tribes of the world.
We devised a plan.
A plan that would prepare you
for the ultimate battle...
against the ultimate evil.
Aku must be destroyed...
and only you can wield
your father's magic sword.
Together, you are the one instrument
that can stop this evil.
But tonight,
you will become one of us.
This represents the lion,
the mightiest of earth's creatures.
lts courage and strength unmatched.
This is the mark of rain,
nature's greatest asset.
lt has the power to give life
and to take it away.
And this sun is you, little samurai.
For you are the one light...
that will stand against
the coming darkness.
Now come.
Your new family is anxious to meet you.
l am the son of the chief of these people.
l am their future king!
My son, l see
you have met your new brother.
l hardly think he is fitting
of a prince's brother, father.
Son, you will show some respect!
And this is your new brother,
like it or not.
Yes, father.
This is the Umlangata.
lt is made
from our land's strongest trees.
We have five styles of technique.
The cheetah.
The monkey.
The snake.
The scorpion.
And the antelope.
Enough!
Come, let me show you our land.
Find the boy!
We cannot find him.
The great evil spirit
has promised us great treasure...
if we deliver the little child of light skin.
No.
l think your training here is complete.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "