Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Very good,
my Warrior of the Night.
You are truly
a master of darkness.
You have passed the test.
You may have the power
to finally destroy the Samurai.
Now go and rid my world of that fool,
once and for all!
What were those things?
They're attacking my village.
You must help us!
Show me.
My mother!
You must leave now!
Run!
My boy!
My boy is gone!
Run!
Shinobi, Warrior of the Night.
Trained to use
the darkness of the shadow.
l know your arts as well.
But l have been trained
to use the light.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "