Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
l would like some hot water, please.
Over there.
Thank you.
" All right "
Wassup, y'all?
Da Samurai is in da house!
Da Samurai!
That's right.
Ain't no bout adout that.
Don't call me bad.
Call me badder.
l'm the samurai dude
who invented rude.
There ain't no stoppin'
this booty-kicking brother.
And this here is my mama.
Don't you be talkin' bad 'bout my mama
or she'll give you a whoopin'.
Ain't that right, mama?
That's right, baby.
'Cause...l...am...
Da Samurai!
Catch, sucka!
Wassup, fellas?
Nice hat.
That's better.
Yeah! Now, that's what l'm talking 'bout.
What kind of swill
are you trying to serve me?
Now, you lucky l'm in a good mood...
'cause mama would knock you out.
Well, hello.
l didn't see you up on the menu.
You must be the chef's special...
'cause you sure ain't no appetizer!
Hey, now!
Release the female.
'Scuze me, darlin'.
lt's whoopin' time.
Look out!
lt's helicopter time.
Here it comes.
The crazy eight!
Then there's the sucker punch.
Did you look up?
Sucka! Yeah!
And finally, the monk dunk!
Monk...
dunk!
Any more suckas
wanna mess with me?
Oh, you want some?
That's right!
Nobody messes with Da Samurai.
Now, gimme something l can really drink!
Yes. Yes, sir.
Bounty hunters!
Samurai Jack!
Yes, Samurai, it is l.
These are my newest
and mightiest assassins.
Bye-bye, Samurai.
Destroy him. Destroy him!
More hot water, please.
So you're Samurai Jack?
The poser who's been biting my style.
Nah, that's all right, son.
You looked pretty good out there.
Your little moves be lookin' all right...
almost as good as mine.
Thank you.
Say what? Say what?
Yo, no, don't you turn your back
and walk away from me!
Didn't you hear who l am?
l believe everyone heard who you are.
Say what?!
Snap! lt's like that, huh?
Well, here's a 4-1-1,
Samurai Jack.
l am Da Samurai...
and, you see, you are a samurai...
but there can only be one samurai.
So me and you
are gonna throw down...
and after me and mama
whoop your sorry butt...
l will be the one and only samurai.
Excuse me.
May l please have some more hot water?
- l guess so.
- Thank you.
You got to be kidding me!
You know, l think l done figured it out.
You're scared to fight me!
You don't want none of this.
That's right, isn't it?
Thank you very much.
l'm sorry.
Can l bring you anything, sir?
Yeah...
Lookin' for this?
Very well.
Well, let's get this party started, fool!
Outside.
We will fight outside
in the shadow of leaves.
What?
Yeah, but it's raining...
Oh, l get it.
l wouldn't want to spoil
your reputation for you.
All right, Jack.
Draw.
- What the heck is that?
- lt is your weapon.
Man, l didn't say
l wanted to go fishin'.
You got to be kiddin' me with that!
You crazy.
l like it. l do like it.
Draw your weapon and quit stallin'.
Baby, l'm ready to get maulin'!
lt is your weapon
that remains to be drawn.
Man, l said l ain't gonna fight you
with that old toothpick.
You have not yet earned
the right to face my blade.
Earn your...?
All right, fine.
l'll earn your blade.
Now, come on!
Well, come on!
l ain't got all night!
Got to save some time for the honeys.
He who runs with aggression
walks without dignity.
Now l see your tactics.
You gonna bore me to death.
You can never defeat another
if you know not how to defeat yourself.
Man, what is this, story time?
Man!
l'm gonna tear you a new...
You know how much
l paid for those things?!
He who wears a mask
cannot see what lies within himself.
Now, what the heck
is that supposed to mean?
l'll teach you to play me the fool!
Why, you...
The shell of an oyster
only hides the pearl inside.
What kind of...
l'm finished playing around
with these old silly sticks.
When l finish you off,
l'm gonna do it with a man's weapon...
not some old...
Don't you be shushing me
when l'm talking!
- Now, l told you that l'm...
- Be quiet!
Later, Jack!
Man!
l guess l...
l guess l ain't so bad after all.
Man, that was pretty amazing.
Look out!
You have taken the first step...
toward the true path
to the way of the samurai.
Yo, sensei!
What's the second lesson?
What's tomorrow, three and four?
You got a videotape l can look at?
Gimme some homework, man!
Should l just think
positive thoughts? Wassup?
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "