Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
There is no escape.
Unpredictable.
lllogical.
lmpossible.
He is The One.
Quickly, rescue him!
Do not be alarmed.
You are in fine operating condition.
- Where am l?
- You are in the city of Andromeda.
Well, the city is up there.
You're down here
in the sewers of Andromeda...
our home.
How did l get here?
Well, you were in a battle,
a battle with Mondo-bot...
and you were not doing so badly.
But he is too powerful!
Damn him!
Who is this Mondo-bot?
Come with me. l will explain.
Our city needed a protector,
so we built Mondo-bot...
the most powerful
defense unit ever created...
able to protect us
against any oppressor.
But something went wrong.
Horribly wrong.
The Mondo-bot turned on us.
He began to attack
and destroy everything.
We have lived here ever since.
l am sorry.
l wish there was something l could do.
Well, there is.
You see, you are The One.
- The One?
- Yes.
We built Andromeda
on a magical ancient city of giants.
Giants that are capable
of destroying the Mondo-bot.
l still do not understand
how this involves me.
Well, you wield the same weapon
as the giants.
Show me!
Swim into the city of giants.
There. That will make you
breathe under water.
There, you will find the key.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "