(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
(FLATLINE TONE)
(CRACKING)
(ELECTRONIC FIZZLING)
(ELECTRONIC DRONING)
(GASPS)
(SNIFFS)
(SIGHS)
(DRONING STOPS)
(DISTANT DRONING)
Hello?
(WATER RUNS)
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
Ah!
(DRONING STOPS)
(WIND BLOWS)
Hello?
Hello.
Can you help me?
Do you know who I am? I... I...
I can't remember who I am.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Hello?
Do you know who I am?
Please!
I can't remember.
(PANTS)
(DOORS OPEN AND CLOSE)
Please, help me!
Help me!
Help me, please.
Oh! Help!
Help me! He's got a gun! Help me!
Hey! We have to go!
Come on!
- (GUNSHOT)
- Oh, my God!
- Oh!
- (GUNSHOT)
Oh, my God!
Stay back!
Back! Get back!
Get back. Back!
(SHOUTING)
Let me in. Let me in!
Help me! Help me!
- Shit!
- Jesus!
There's a door round there.
It's locked.
- You don't know that!
- There's a keypad.
We should try it.
Get down! Anybody stands up,
they'll shoot their heads off.
He's trying to kill me! What's going on?
Shut up! I'm trying to think!
He can see you. Get back.
Oh, my God!
What's wrong with those people?!
Why aren't they helping us?
They're just watching...
- Where the fuck have you been?
- What?
Get that extinguisher.
- (SCREAMS) I can't! I can't do it!
- Get it.
Get it now!
(PANTING) OK... OK... OK... OK... OK...
Come on.
Quickly. Slide it to me.
Damien, if he comes through,
you grab him and you grab his gun.
I can't...
- You can.
- He'll shoot me!
You have to!
I'm going to smash the lock off that door,
you help him with gun guy.
He can't shoot all of us.
If he fires, he has to reload.
We either rush him or run, OK?
I can't do this!
We have no choice!
Help him.
(GRUNTS)
- Damien!
- Oh, my...!
(GLASS SMASHES)
Get him!
(LAUGHING AND JEERING)
(GRUNTING)
(DAMIEN SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOT)
Get down.
Shh!
(WHISPERS) Fuck!
- (WHIMPERS)
- Shh!
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
(DISTORTED CARNIVAL MUSIC)
- (ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
- No!
We have to go. Come on.
- (CAR APPROACHING)
- Shit.
Stay down.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Shit.
Stay down.
(WHIRRING)
Who are they?
Why do they look like that?
They like scaring people.
What?
OK.
We have to run for that opening.
- No, they'll see us!
- If they're busy with him
we can lose the Hunters, OK?
No.
- You just stay with me. OK?
- OK.
Ready? Come on!
Wait.
(PANTING)
Wait!
The Onlookers sometimes wait
in the windows, keeping lookout.
I'm pretty sure that's how they find us.
Through the cameras somehow.
Onlookers spot you and a few minutes later
the scary bastards turn up.
- This is mad, this is just mad.
- Look!
You have to hold it together and do
what I say or you'll get us both killed.
What? I...
I woke up in this house
and I don't even know if it's my house.
- I don't even know who I am.
- You must know something.
Ah!
I think this is my daughter.
But you don't know?
She could be anywhere.
Maybe you tried to kill yourself.
Would that explain it?
There was pills.
I don't blame you.
Lots have tried that fun fork in the road
since it started.
Since what started?
You really don't know?
No.
There was a signal.
Like pictures, flashing pictures.
They just appeared on every TV,
every computer,
- anything with a screen.
- Argh!
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
(PANTING)
I saw it. I saw it.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Get down.
They did something to people. Like,
almost everybody just became Onlookers,
started watching, filming stuff,
like spectators who don't give a shit
about what happens.
That's, like, nine out of ten people now.
But not us.
Some of us weren't affected.
I don't know why.
Like that man with the gun,
and that woman.
I call them Hunters.
You might've noticed that's what they do.
They seemed normal to begin with,
but then they realised
they could do what they wanted,
and they started taking stuff,
nicking cars cos they could,
doing what they like.
And not just with things - with people.
It got worse and worse.
And now they've got an audience.
So this... this thing on the TV, the...
The signal.
That's what's doing it?
That's what's making them act like this?
I guess they were always like that
underneath.
Just needed the rules to change,
for no-one to intervene.
What are we going to do?
Do? Do nothing. We get out.
Where's "out"?
We're here.
We need to head south of here.
They've knocked the transmitters out,
it's OK there.
The TV transmitters, they carry it.
There's only one between us and the
safe zone and we're going to knock it out.
See, it's here.
White Bear.
What?
White Bear...
Uh! Ungh!
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
(DISTORTED VOICE) A picnic
with my two best friends.
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
Jesus, what is it with you?
White Bear. You said, "White Bear."
So?!
Look, whatever's wrong with you,
you have to keep it together, OK?
Listen to me!
- Don't go out there.
- What's your problem?
Huh?
You want something to look at?
Cos I'll give you something to look at!
- We have to get out of here.
- No, I want to talk to him.
I wanna talk to you!
- Ah!
- It's not so funny now, is it?
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
Put it down.
I just want to see
what they're looking at.
I said put it down.
It's dangerous.
Their phones, they're dangerous.
It's the signal. The images are on them,
they're on the screen.
What?
Don't look at it!
Don't look at it.
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
WOMAN: Jemima...
(HYPERVENTILATING)
No! No, this is all wrong.
This is all wrong!
They're coming. Run!
Run!
(ENGINE APPROACHING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Get in!
Get in. Come on.
Come on.
Come on, now!
They're coming! Quick.
Come on, hurry up.
Get in.
(WHIRRING)
You nearly killed us back there.
Yeah, well, I wasn't expecting you
to be there, was I?
I've just saved your lives.
A wee "thank you" would be nice.
I should've just run yous over.
Who are you?
It's not a hard question, is it?
I know... I know you.
Do you?
Well, where did we meet, if you know me?
No. Didn't think so, yeah.
- She's confused. She's not in a good way.
- Yeah, I'll say.
So what are yous doing out here anyway?
Heading south.
That's not a good move.
It's all blocked up down there.
There's a transmitter there.
- If we can knock it out...
- I don't think you understand.
When I said, "It's not a good move",
that means I'm not driving you down there.
I know a safe place we can go.
The woods.
Your safe place is in the woods.
How'd you know that?
I don't... I don't know.
Christ, maybe you do know me.
Yeah, we pull up and we get out.
We talk. There's no-one chasing us.
- Mystic Meg.
- And then what happens?
We eat.
Told you. No bars.
They'll never find us here.
That your daughter?
Yeah, I think so.
Where is she?
I don't know.
What did you do to your wrists?
Dunno.
History of mental illness?
Yeah, I bet you do. Lay money on it.
What about you?
What about me?
Mental illness, weaknesses...
Everyone's got weaknesses.
Yeah, you two have got more than most,
I'd say.
That's why yous are on the receiving end,
you see. Vulnerable.
Receiving end of what?
This. Everything that's going on.
- Easy pickings.
- What's your weaknesses, then?
My weaknesses?
Show you if you want.
Wanna see it?
Wait there. Don't move.
You're gonna like this.
Not a lot!
- This better not be naturism.
- Yeah, in your dreams.
(THUMPING)
Ta-da!
Run, and I'll shoot you in the back.
Right, come over here.
Stand there.
You. Here, put this on.
- (ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
- Put it on. Backwards,
so it covers your eyes.
Put your hands on her shoulders.
Keep them there.
You're her eyes now, all right?
And that is a shotgun, OK?
If I pull this trigger,
it's going to cut yous both in half.
So no funny business, all right?
Right, off you go.
Straight ahead.
Keep going through the trees.
Come on, pick up the pace.
Got a lovely playground for you
down there.
That's it, through here.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
That's it, straight ahead.
Grab her!
Right, now take her balaclava off.
Get down there.
Oh, fuck.
Come on.
(WHIMPERS)
Head towards that ladder.
Get down there.
Right, stop.
Get on your knees, both of yous.
Give me that bag.
Fucking bag.
- You, get down.
- (CRIES OUT)
Stop whingeing.
(SOBS)
Stop fucking crying!
- (MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
- Stop it! (GROWLS IRRITABLY)
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm down in that wood spot.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Easy. I'll just lash them to a tree
or something like that, you know.
Just hurry up and get down here.
I want to get started.
It's going to piss...
Fuck!
(GUNSHOT)
Your mate's fucked off.
You're in double trouble now, missus.
Get up on that log. Now!
Move!
Get your hands through there.
Get your hands through there!
Right through.
Push your arms up.
Push them! Get them up there!
Are we going to put a show on
for these guys today, eh? (LAUGHS)
Eh?
(SOBS AND PANTS)
Let's see what Daddy's got
in the bag, shall we?
Oh...
- Oh!
- (WHIRRING)
Oh, Mama.
- Help me! Help me!
- (WHIRRING)
Please, just help me!
Why are you doing this to me?
- Whoo-ha! Oh, yeah!
- You've got to stop him! Please!
Help me, please! I'm a human being!
They're not gonna help you.
They're gonna watch.
What I'm gonna do here, darling, is just
gonna push this straight through your...
- (SCREAMS)
- (GUN COCKS)
Help me!
- (GUNSHOT)
- (SCREAMS)
(PANTING AND SOBBING)
(SOBBING)
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you!
For what?
For coming back for me.
I came back for this.
There's more like him on the way.
(PANTS HEAVILY)
Come on!
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SHRIEKS)
White Bear's not far from here.
If we step on it we might be able
to shut it down before they get to us.
- What happens if we can't shut it down?
- We can.
- How? Do we hack into it, or something?
- We don't hack anything.
We burn the control room down.
It's not hard, we just slosh a load
of petrol round, strike a light...
Fucks the electrics or something.
Here.
In the bag.
It's the plans
for the transmitter compound.
I've been planning this, you know.
- (ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
- (CAMERA CLICKS)
Jemima?
(ECHOING) Lie down for me, darling. Go
on. It's a game.
Yeah, just like what Teddy does.
Lie down for me, darling.
- (ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
- (SCREAMING)
Turn around!
- What?
- White Bear,
there's something not right
about White Bear. I remember now!
You remembered the woods, too.
Sorry if I don't trust your hunches.
OK. Looks clear.
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
OK.
(UNZIPPING)
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
(CLANKING)
He was good for something, after all.
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
(WIND BLOWS)
Hurry up, we need to go!
Come on...
Get out.
Come with me.
(ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
A picnic with my two best friends.
- (ELECTRICAL FEEDBACK)
- Come on.
This way.
Oh, shit.
They'll be here any minute.
Give me the plan.
The transmitter tower's over there
and the cabling runs underground
into that building. Come on!
Thought so.
Let's go!
(BUZZING)
(BEEPING)
(MORE MACHINES BEEPING)
(BEEPS)
Get back.
Or everything goes up.
I mean it... stay back.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- Stay back.
- (WHIRRING)
(SCREAMS)
(RUMBLING)
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING
CONTINUES)
(WHISPERS) What?
Thank you.
So, I guess you're wondering
why you're here.
(WHIRRING)
Well, it's time to tell you who you are.
(GASPS)
You've looked better.
- Do you recognise him?
- Uh... Yeah.
Your fiancé, lain Rannoch.
Or, should I say, was your fiancé.
In case you haven't guessed,
the pair of you aren't very popular.
But I'll tell you what you are, though.
- (GASPS)
- You're famous.
The trial of Victoria Skillane
finally concluded today,
the verdict - guilty.
Together with her fiancé lain Rannoch,
whose death in custody
had delayed the trial,
Skillane abducted six-year-old
Jemima Sykes just miles from her home,
prompting a nationwide search
amidst emotional pleas
from her parents.
For months, the youngster's
disappearance had been a mystery,
the sole clue being
her distinctive white teddy bear,
discovered in a lay-by
two miles from the family home.
The white bear became an enduring
symbol in the hunt for Jemima,
a hunt that ended in a local forest.
Jemima's body was found here.
It had been wrapped
in a sleeping bag and burnt.
The couple were caught
after harrowing footage of
Jemima's torture and murder
was discovered on a mobile phone
in Skillane's possession.
Lain Rannoch,
identified by his distinctive tattoo,
killed the youngster
as Victoria Skillane held the camera.
Breaking down in tears,
Skillane admitted to filming
Jemima's final moments,
claiming her fiancé had pressured her
into helping him,
maintaining she was under his spell.
The jury was not convinced by
Skillane's story,
and neither was the judge,
who labelled her
"a uniquely wicked
and poisonous individual".
"You were an enthusiastic spectator
to Jemima's suffering.
"You actively revelled in her anguish,"
he said,
adding her punishment would be
proportionate and considered.
By hanging himself in his cell,
many believe lain Rannoch
evaded justice.
The public mood is now focused on
ensuring his accomplice can't do the same.
Patrick Lacey, UKN.
(SOBS) I'm sorr...
(WAILS)
Please...
Oh, don't start crying.
Crocodile tears are making me sick!
- (SCREAMS)
- (AUDIENCE JEERS)
(SOBS)
WOMAN: Murderer!
MAN: Murderer!
(JEERING STOPS)
There were no tears
when you watched him do what he did.
You filmed what he did.
A poor wee girl,
helpless and terrified,
and you just watched.
How do you like it now?
(SHOUTS) How do you like it?!
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
MAN: Murderer!
Murderer!
Get her out of here.
Throw her back
to where she came from.
(AUDIENCE JEERS AND SHOUTS)
(WAILS)
No! No! Please...
No! Please...
(AUDIENCE SHOUTS OUT)
Good evening, citizens!
(SHOUTING AND CHEERING)
Thank you so much
for coming tonight.
OK!
We're at the climax of our day.
Take as many photographs as you want,
take as many photographs
as you can,
but, most importantly,
what I need from you
is to shout and scream
and let that bitch know
that yous are out here.
(CHEERING)
Let's get this show on the road!
Murdering bitch!
Evil witch!
Dirty whore!
Burn the bitch!
(CHEERING AND JEERING)
Murderer!
Burn in hell!
(OBJECT HITS WINDOW)
(GASPS)
(SHOUTING AND CHEERING
CONTINUES)
(WILD CHEERING)
(CAMERAS CLICK)
Kill me.
Please just kill me.
(SOBS) Please...
That's what you always say.
# Doo-ba-doo-ba-do... #
You've had a bad day,
but this will wipe it clean.
Get you in the mood to start again.
No! Please!
Get off me!
What are you doing?
Takes about 30 minutes...
(ELECTRONIC CHIRP)
...for it to fully do the business.
(WHIMPERS)
So while it does...
...why don't we watch
some in-flight entertainment?
Please, no...
Healthy stuff, like apples...
Please stop.
You should enjoy this.
You shot it.
... made it together,
so that my two friends...
Erm... A picnic for me
and my two best friends.
(RAPID ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (ELECTRONIC DRONING)
(SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
- (SCREAMS AND GASPS)
- (ELECTRONIC DRONING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(SOBS) Help me...
(ANGUISHED SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
OK, everyone, we're about to head
into the park
so I'll hand you over to Baxter.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Thank you. All of our roles are very,
very important, yours included.
Now, yours come
with some basic rules. Rule number one -
no talking.
Not just to her, but each other
as well, OK, unless it's essential.
We're trying to get her to believe
that yous are all mesmerised.
(ALL LAUGH)
I know, I know, I know.
But she's believed it up to now.
Morning. Ticket, please.
Thank you.
JEM: OK, rule number two -
keep your distance.
I can't stress the importance
of this one enough, OK?
Don't forget,
she's a dangerous individual.
Imagine that she's an escaped lion.
Now, yesterday, she threw a projectile,
and we will step in if she gets too close.
We're all equipped with Tasers,
but then we're into story shutdown
and we've all wasted a day.
So it's best to keep your distance,
at least three metres back.
You can use your camera zoom.
BAXTER: Last, but not least -
enjoy yourself.
That's probably the most important
rule of all, OK?
Take lots of photographs, run around
through the woods, but try and stay safe.
We'll be keeping an eye on you,
making sure you're all OK.
So get out there, enjoy yourselves
and let's make this show happen, people!
Come on!
(CHATTER)
(GASPS)
Ow!
Look, there she is.
JEM: Don't know yet.
I'm kind of knackered.
Hmm. Me, too.
BAXTER: She's just leaving her house now.
Two minutes tops.
Right you are.
We're on.
(WHISTLES A TUNE)
(GASPS AND PANTS)
Watch out!
VICTORIA: He's trying to fucking kill me.
What's going on?
JEM: Get that extinguisher.
It's OK, they've gone.
(ALL LAUGH)
Convincing, eh?
(WHISTLES)
Right you are. Two minutes.
(SOBBING)
Help!
(SHE WHIMPERS)
(DRILL WHIRRS)
Help me!
(AUDIENCE CHATTERS)
Early screamer.
It's an early screamer tonight.
So keep the noise up...
...and let's go!
(SHOUTING AND JEERING)
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
(GASPS) Ow!