Erstwhile on "Fargo"...
You're not gonna prove
my Ed did anything wrong!
It's unprovable!
Lou: There was a cleaver
in the man's head, son,
which Noreen said was you.
Not to mention there's a war
going on up in Fargo
that you may have started
when you ran over that
Gerhardt boy.
Floyd: You take care
of this butcher.
He doesn't live through
the night.
Already dead, believe me.
He just doesn't know it.
Peggy: Sheriff?
Hank: Go inside now, Peggy.
Go now.
Ed home?
Ed who?
No, Peggy, hey, hey.
When I find ya, darlin',
I'm gonna make you bleed.
Uhh!
Ed:
I need to find Peggy.
You're still in my custody.
You look worse than me.
Hank:
don't tire yourself.
We know where he's headed.
♪♪
♪ Wherever you go ♪
♪ hey! ♪
Hon?
♪ Wherever you go ♪
♪ hey! ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
Peggy.
Have you actualized
fully?
What?
Have you actualized
fully?
I don't know.
I mean, I'm trying.
Do you feel cold sometimes,
even when it's hot?
Sometimes.
Do you understand the difference
between thinking and being?
What do you mean?
Do you understand the difference
between thinking and being?
I --
to be
is simply to exist.
Try it.
Try simply being.
I'm sorry.
But how is sitting here
gonna help me be
the best person I can be?
Ah.
You want an explanation.
Well, kinda.
The human mind, aroused by
an insistence for meaning,
seeks and finds nothing
but contradiction and nonsense.
Okay.
It's just practically,
I'm saying.
Uh, as a person,
a married person,
a woman who's worried
she's not living up
to her full potential.
Think or be.
You can't do both.
You're saying...
don't think about
the person I want to be.
Just be that person.
Peggy.
don't think about
the person I want to be.
Just be that person.
Peggy.
Peggy, are you okay?
We were just talking,
and -- and it all
finally makes sense.
This lady has lost her mind,
brother.
Shut up.
She's seeing people
who are not there.
I said "shut up."
And here I am,
tied up for no reason,
a concerned citizen
just walking past,
and I -- and I hear
a cry for help.
No, you're a Gerhardt.
And you're shit on my shoe.
Why don't you come here
and let me wipe you off?
Okay. The cops are coming.
Who knows who else.
Okay, no time to pack.
Just the clothes on our back.
-Okay.
-Okay?
Okay.
Did you --
no.
It was him.
He's the leader,
i think.
Then we take him
with us.
Peggy.
We're taking his car?
Yeah, they'll be looking
for ours.
I understand now, hon.
Come on.
Everything,
what I have to do.
That's good.
Now, watch your head.
♪♪
Got one.
Gunshot.
Lou: Got another.
Gerhardts,
I'm thinking.
No sign
of Ed or Peggy.
I'm calling a medic.
Yeah.
Probably a good idea.
This is just embarrassing.
I'll get an a.P.B. Out
on the Gerhardt boys,
and, uh, see about starting
the hunt for Ed and Peggy.
don't -- don't tell Betsy
I'm down.
Yeah, she scares me
more than you, so...
I'm gonna call.
Oh, you s...
I've just been doing it
all wrong.
Both of us.
We make a trade, hon,
is what I'm thinking.
Wanting things,
pretending to be
something we're not.
Selling their man back to 'em
for freedom.
It's like
when you're a kid and --
and you need permission
to go to the washroom, and --
and you raise your hand and wait
for the teacher to call on you.
But meantime,
you just have to go so bad.
I should've looked
at his wallet.
But you just go.
Know exactly who
we're dealing with here.
You just go.
You don't ask.
Till then, hon,
we stick to the small roads,
out of the way motels,
and we just -- we keep moving.
A road trip.
Wait. Hold the phone.
Uncle Grady's got that --
that hunting cabin
outside canistota.
It's empty now.
We go there and hole up.
See?
We're moving now.
Things are flowing.
Not trapped anymore.
Well, i-i mean,
that was our home.
Yeah, but I mean energy-wise,
you know?
I mean,
you got to admit,
we were stuck in the mud.
Emotionally, I mean.
And -- and now,
we're flying.
We -- we got a plan.
That's what matters.
We -- we -- we got a plan
for how to get out of this.
See it then be it.
That's from lifespring.
Except -- except the cops.
We -- we got to figure out --
we're gonna figure this out.
Right now,
i just got to keep us alive.
You're doing it, hon.
We both are.
We're actualized.
♪♪
Oh, I like it.
How come
we've never come here before?
You said uncle Grady
smelled like athlete's foot.
Remember?
Hon.
What?
In case he gets feisty.
Ohh.
Oh, no.
Aah!
Ooh.
-Ohh!
-Ooh!
Good thinking, hon.
My tongue. My tongue.
What?
I bit my tongue
half off.
You're dead,
in case you were wondering.
You and your whore.
Zip your lips.
Dodd Gerhardt.
I'm gonna have fun
taking her apart.
No.
That's good, yeah?
Yeah.
I saw a little convenience store
up the road.
Gonna go make the call.
Oh, hon, there's a --
a phone near the bathroom.
Yeah, I'm gonna use a pay phone.
Make it untraceable.
Oh, smart thinking,
Ed blumquist.
What are you gonna say?
Well...
You know, uh...
"If we give him
back to you,
you got to promise
we'll go unmolested."
What if they say no?
Well, then, I'll show them
which part's the flank steak.
Yeah, uh, it's, uh...
Is this
the Gerhardt headquarters?
Good.
Well, this is the butcher.
And, uh, i-i need to talk
to who's in charge.
No, not your butcher,
the butcher.
Yeah.
From luverne.
So, let me talk
to who's in charge.
I got Dodd.
You heard me.
Yeah.
What do you mean a message?
don't they --
i-i mean I got Dodd.
Did you tell them that?
Just -- just tell them
I'll call them back, okay?
♪♪
Foot's
on the other shoe now.
Shut up.
Oh, now that's just rude.
Come on,
for shit's sake!
Hey.
Ed'll be back any minute,
so don't get any ideas.
I got four daughters,
you know.
I'm not a bad guy.
You called me a whore.
I heard.
I swear to Christ,
when I'm free,
you're gonna see
the back of my hand.
We're gonna be spending
some time together,
so you need to be civil.
Go to hell.
Ow! Bitch!
Ohh!
Bitch.
What did I just say?!
You gonna be nice?
Yeah.
Okay, okay, all right!
All right!
Good.
Now, I'm making beans.
You want some beans?
No.
No what?
No, thank you.
That's better.
I got to say this whole thing
has just been...
And, I mean,
I'm sorry about your brother.
I am,
but it was an accident.
And this whole thing
has just been so --
I mean, I'm trying
to stay positive.
That's one thing.
If you spend any time with me,
you'll see.
Positive Peggy
is what they call me.
But this whole thing
has just been super hard on Ed.
He's a little more delicate,
you know?
I mean, he's a big guy and all,
but deep down, I mean,
this whole thing has just been
really hard on him.
And it's my fault.
I know.
I mean...
I hit the guy.
Your brother.
And I'm sorry about that.
I am.
And he was...Stepping out
into the road.
Didn't even look
where he was going.
No. No.
No.
And so, Ed, you know,
all he did was clean it up.
And then you sent
those other fellas,
and, I mean, what were
we supposed to do?
You know?
So, now I'm hoping --
we're both hoping --
that we can just
smooth this all over now
and everything can go
back to normal.
Oh, wait.
No, you said you didn't want
beans, didn't you?
No, it's okay.
They're good.
Really good,
good stuff.
No, i-i mean,
i should've...
Well...
Everything
that's been going on,
and I mean, here I am,
trying to actualize fully,
you know?
And I mean,
that's no small thing.
To review and reflect,
contextualize.
Not just keep making
past mistakes.
Will you listen to me
nattering on.
Oh, hey, hon.
We're just --
I made some beans.
You want some?
Ed:
No, that's okay.
What happened to him?
Oh, well, now,
we don't need to talk
about that, do we?
Water under the bridge.
Hon, did you stab
the hostage?
Yes.
No.
I mean, I had to teach him
some manners is all
if we're gonna be
spending time together.
And him so angry when we're
the ones who should be angry.
I mean, when you get
right down to it,
it's our shop
that burned down.
Help.
Our house
we had to leave behind.
She's crazy.
Keep her away from me.
Hon.
Help.
Hon. Hon.
Hmm?
They're -- they're not
gonna want him back
if we --
if we cut him up too much.
Oh, I hardly stuck him
at all.
-I'm hurt real bad.
-Shut up.
I think
she punctured a lung.
How'd it go with the family?
They gonna negotiate?
Had to leave a message.
Well, you --
you said we had him.
Yeah, but it -- it was just like
a flunky or something,
so I said I'd call back.
Okay,
well, maybe there's --
sounds like there's a war
going on up there.
Maybe they're busy.
Yeah, but I mean, if he's such
an important guy, you know?
Well, hon, don't...
don't doubt yourself, Ed.
That was my undoing.
See it then be it, right?
So, just...Have some beans
and call back.
They'll be home
next time for sure.
Good?
Hon, you got to stop
stabbing him.
Water.
Did you spit in this?
What?
Tequila.
Pour it in front of me.
Here you go, chief.
Looking for a couple.
Redheaded man and a blond woman
driving a blue Lincoln.
White couple?
Didn't you guys try to start
your own country a while back?
Wounded knee.
What happened there?
Didn't you feel like
being Americans anymore?
I'm not from there.
Yeah.
See, well, I'm not sure
i want to serve alcohol
to a man who doesn't want
to be an American.
How about a man who did
three tours in Vietnam
who's got a purple heart
and a bronze star?
Who, you?
You're welcome.
- Me, oh, my, oh.
- Where you going, Geronimo? Huh?
You gonna grab
your bow and arrow there?
I don't think
his teepee's here.
No.
We're talking to you,
shit bird.
Is that a teepee?
Ooh.
What are you doing,
buddy?
Ooh.
Just wanted
a glass of water.
Oh, shit bird's thirsty.
Get a load of that.
Is he crying, Earl?
I think he's crying.
Huh?
Aah!
Whoa, now.
Now, hold on.
Aah!
-Aah!
Aah! Aah!
No, look.
I called the cop--
Freeze, cochise!
Excuse me, your lordship.
I got to go to the John.
Well, i-i can't risk
untying you.
Not after before.
Yeah, but I'm gonna...Pee
in my pants in a minute here.
Well, that's okay,
i guess.
No.
Look, I'm not gonna --
not gonna pee in my pants
like a half-wit.
I got rights here.
Peggy: He's right, hon.
There's, uh, what do ya --
the Geneva convention.
Are we talking number one
or number two?
What?
You got to pee
or you got to poop, I'm saying?
Geez, kid, I got --
I'm gonna blow a sack here.
Hon, you're gonna have to...
Help him with his pants.
I'll do it.
-No.
-No, no.
No, i-I'll do it.
Hurry up.
Come on.
Now...
I'm gonna open your drawers,
okay?
I can't hold it.
Come on.
Well..
don't --
don't pee on me.
I'm -- I'm
helping you out here.
-don't look at me.
-Yeah, I'm hel--
ahh!
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Ahh.
-Done?
-Yeah.
Well, okay.
Uh, I'm gonna go make the call.
You'll be okay?
Affirmative.
Hey, doll.
I got some chablis on ice.
♪♪
How you doing?
You know,
with a song in my heart.
Warm for march.
Yeah, has been, I guess.
No opinion required.
Just factual.
The hippies want you to believe
the planet's heating up
because of
my wife's hair spray.
Yeah.
That's, uh...
I don't know about that,
but...It's been warm.
Saw you earlier
on the phone.
Yeah,
down at the lake there.
Having a-a holiday,
i guess you'd call it.
No phone
at the cabin, so...
Wrong time of year
for a holiday.
Can't swim,
can't hunt.
Yep,
it's been pretty quiet.
These, too.
Yep,
just you and the moose.
Yeah.
Just us and the moose.
Going crazy down there,
to be honest.
I bet.
How about a pack of cards?
Just 39 cents.
Yeah, sure. Okay.
You know what?
On the house.
For you and the missus.
Well, thanks.
It is, uh,
you and the missus, yeah?
Say, what -- what time
do you open in the morning?
Usually around 7:00,
unless I sleep in,
which I don't.
Just between you and me,
if you could eat a rooster,
I'd have done it by now.
Okay, then.
Stupid.
Hi. Hi, there.
I'm good, thanks.
How are you?
Well, fantastic.
I'm trying to reach
the southnik hotel.
It's in sioux falls.
Uh, just the front desk,
please.
Okay. Great.
Uh, hi. Um, I'm looking for
one of your guests,
last name heck.
Yeah, spelled just like that.
First name constance.
Okay, I'll wait.
Hello?
Oh, gosh,
did I wake you?
No, I'm...
Where are you, sweetie?
You're missing the seminar.
I know,
and I feel terrible,
but we're kind of
in a little trouble.
You and Ed?
Yeah.
Well...
It's a long story,
but I'm dealing with it.
How's it going?
What?
The seminar.
Is it amazing?
Oh, it's...
You should come.
There's still time.
I wish.
Although, I did have
kind of a breakthrough.
Like a-a vision, you know?
I can see things
a whole lot more clear now.
And I -- maybe I don't need it
as much anymore.
Well, vision's important,
but --
yeah, so I just wanted to call
and say thanks.
I know you paid
for the room and --
don't be silly.
The room.
I'm just glad you're --
and -- and maybe --
I mean,
where are you?
Maybe we could meet
for a drink.
You could fill me in,
tell me about your vision.
Oh.
No. No, no, no, no.
Better not.
I mean,
we're out in the woods here.
Not -- not far,
but like I said,
we had some trouble
and we're hiding out.
Ooh.
Sounds romantic.
No. Well, sort of.
Ed and me,
it's not been easy lately,
but we're
coming together now.
Working as equals,
which is --
-that's great, hon.
-Mm-hmm.
Yeah, so I should go.
Hey, you know --
you know,
there's all this great material
here as part of the course.
Workbooks and the like.
And since you already paid,
i got them right here.
Maybe I should send them
to you.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Real eye-opening stuff.
I mean,
I've made more progress
since this morning
than ever maybe.
Tsk. Not sure how long
we'll be here is the thing.
Sure.
But, I mean, mail service
is what, three days?
Yeah.
Just -- no, no.
C-can you hold onto it for me
if it's not too much
of a bother?
It's no problem.
You said you're close.
I'll just --
where are you?
I'll jump in the car
and --
wait till you see
this workbook.
It's like a road map to
unlocking your inner go-getter.
We're -- I don't know
exactly where we are.
I think southwest,
near vermillion.
The lake.
It's a kind of cabin.
Well, i-I'll just --
is there a phonebook there?
A piece of mail?
I'll come over with
the workbooks and you could --
like I said, I made more
progress in hours than ever --
no, you're sweet,
but like I said,
we're hiding out,
so I'll just --
I'll call you
as soon as it's over, okay?
I'll give you a call.
Okay?
Yeah? But...
Okay, bye.
I tried.
You heard.
He's looking at us.
Hmm?
-Make him stop.
-Stop looking at us.
Where am I supposed to look?
Just close your eyes.
I'm not tired.
I don't care.
don't you do it.
Hey.
Thanks, hon.
God damn it.
Man:
The perfect grind every time.
And now back to
the south Dakota morning movie
"operation eagle's nest"
starring Ronald Reagan.
Okay, I'm gonna give it
one more go
and not take no
for an answer.
Go get 'em, hon.
We must hide.
He's coming.
Marie...
You must make me a promise.
If something
should happen to me --
no.
don't say it.
You must continue on
without me.
This war
is bigger than us.
No.
And our love.
Shh.
Smoke.
He's trying
to force us out.
But we can't go out there.
If we stay here,
we burn in our own little hell.
We have no choice.
But he'll shoot us down.
Us?
No.
Pierre,
what are you suggesting?
I will be your shield.
One of us must make it
across the border.
Take that, you Nazi rat.
Come on.
Hurry!
♪♪
I'm telling you
I've got your man.
I've got your boss man,
and you --
well, you know what, sir?
Uh...
I-i might just call over
to the other side,
see if they want him.
Thank you so much for your help.
Bye-bye.
Uh, Fargo, please.
It's the Pearl hotel.
Hi. Uh, I'm looking for,
uh, Mike Milligan.
He's, uh --
he's with a party of fellas.
Kind of rough types.
No, ma'am, I'm not a reporter.
He left his wallet in my store
the other day,
and, uh,
it's got 100 bucks in it,
so I thought
he might want that back.
Bag 'em
and drop 'em in the woods.
We tell the boss
the Gerhardts got 'em.
Hello?
Mike Milligan?
Yes.
Today's your lucky day,
Mike.
I've got Dodd Gerhardt
in the trunk of my car.
You want him?
Sir...
If I kiss you when we meet,
would that be inappropriate?
What? I don't...
Nothing, just...
Well, it's been a day.
But the fact is I do.
I do want him.
The question is,
what do you want?
Well, I got the whole
Gerhardt family after me,
and I need you
to make them stop.
Oh. Then I think you and i
can make a deal.
Well, that's good, then.
That's real good.
Uh, meet me in sioux falls
tomorrow morning, 8:00.
There's a motel
off the interstate here.
Motor motel, I think.
It's two stories.
8:00 A.M.
Yeah, and no funny business,
either, you hear?
'Cause I've killed people
before,
and I'm not afraid
to do it again.
Maybe you heard of me --
the butcher of luverne.
I have heard of you.
And may I say, brother,
i like your style.
Announcer: This capacity crowd
is ready to go.
And we're getting ready
for the puck.
Man: Well, like I was saying,
groundhog saw his shadow.
Did it seem like six more weeks
of winter to you?
Well, not that I'm complaining,
mind you.
I mean,
I'm just passing time here
till they carry me out of here
toes up.
Okay, then.
And that will get a whistle
and draw a penalty.
I can't believe
they're calling a penalty.
Looking for a redhead.
Well, uh
Not sure
i can help you there.
Redhead, heavyset.
Okay, well, there's a bar
a mile or so up the road.
You could potentially meet
a fat-type girl there.
I'm not looking for a girl.
I'm looking for a man.
Heavyset, he parts his hair
in the middle.
Look,
this is a family place.
We sell motor oil and pop
and, you know,
maps for tourists.
Get a lot of tourists?
Not so many, no.
Sometimes people
on their way to rushmore.
He's driving
a blue Lincoln.
Heavyset,
redheaded man.
L-look, if you're not gonna
buy something,
i-i think
you should leave.
Yeah.
You know him.
No.
Look...
All I know is fella comes
in here two, three times,
uses the phone outside.
Redhead?
Yeah.
Heavyset, like you said.
One time comes in
and says something like, uh...
Yeah.
"We're going crazy
down there at the lake."
See, this time of year,
not much to do --
at the lake.
Yeah.
We were just --
h-he wasn't agitated, uh,
but that's what he said.
"We're going crazy
down there at the lake."
Even bought
a pack of cards.
Okay.
...shot and scores!
Unbelievable!
Hon.
Hon?
Son, you got yourself
a woman problem.
How I know is
they've been plaguing me
my whole life.
What's the joke?
Can't live with them,
can't turn them into cat food.
Personally, I don't see
the value in all that talking
and the mood swings and
the lack of rational thinking,
which, brother, your bitch
has got that in spades.
See,
the male of the species
has got the potential
for greatness.
Dodd:
Look at your kings of old.
Napoleon,
kublai Khan, Samson.
Giants made
of muscle and steel.
But these women,
even in those Bible movies,
you see a Delilah
and, uh, scheherazade...
I want to tell you
my own private belief here.
I think Satan is a woman.
Think about it.
With her snake tongue
always undermin--
see?
What did I tell you?
No matter
what you do to them,
these goddamn twats
just won't stop
till you put them down.
Aah!
-Aah!
-Ohh!
Ed?
Ed? Are you okay?
Are you okay? Ed?
Is he...
Is he dead?
I don't know.
Watch him, Ed.
Yeah,
my eyes are open now.
I could almost hear
Mike Milligan
drooling
over the phone.
He'll know
what to do with you.
Dodd: My neck.
Something -- something's wrong.
Ohh.
Step away from him now.
Oh, thank Christ.
Get me out of here.
Sit down, both of you.
What if we say no?
Just shoot 'em,
you half breed.
I'm hurt real bad here.
I can't feel my legs.
Thinking
of getting a haircut.
How do you...?
Something professional.
Shorter,
like on the sides and back.
Well, I mean,
you got the bone structure.
Jesus Christ,
you mongrel...
Just shoot these two
and get me
to a goddamn hospital.
Oh, my god!
Can you do it?
Huh?
Haircut.
Can you do it?
Look, w-we thank you
for --
shut up.
Can you do it?
Yeah. Yeah.
Um...Let me just, uh --
let me...
Can you...
Can you sit?
And...I'll go get
the scissors.
Ed, can you make sure --
our guest may be thirsty.
What?
Oh.
Uh...You want a pop?
No pop.
I said sit down.
Not sure
how sharp they'll be.
No funny tricks.
No.
I mean, you saved us.
And...We're grateful for that.
Aren't we, Ed?
Of course we are,
and...
You know, if there's anything
we could do to repay you...
...you just...
Professional, you said?
Yeah.
Tired of this life.
♪♪
Aah!