♪ Mama, can I huh,
mama, can I huh, huh ♪
♪ can I, mama,
won't you please let me ♪
♪ mama can I, huh ♪
♪ That's the sweetest
little dress ♪
♪ Sally, where'd you get
the pattern? ♪
♪ Made me one just like it
out of yellow dotted Swiss ♪
♪♪
♪ Yes, I guess we got the
earliest garden in the county ♪
♪ beneath the strawberries are
a heap of snappin' green beans ♪
♪ too bad about your boy ♪
♪ mama, make Willie
quit pulling at my hair ♪
♪ mama, ouch! Ouch!
Mama, just make Willie quit it ♪
♪ Tommy, if ya
don't put down that stick ♪
♪ I'm gonna wear you out
with it, boy, be quick ♪
♪ come quick, Sammy Jean stuck
her finger in a coke bottle ♪
♪ can't get it out 'cause
it's stuck, stuck, stuck ♪
♪ now, I told you my mama
didn't raise no fool ♪
♪ I can do anything
if I got the right tools ♪
♪ mama, can I huh,
mama, can I huh, huh ♪
♪ can I, mama,
won't you please let me ♪
♪ mama can I, huh ♪
Jeremy Kleiner
up in Winnipeg writes...
"Feel better, boss man."
That's nice.
And then, uh...
Carter Bunch says,
"Keep fighting, you old cuss.
You'll outlive us all."
Indian Joe sent porn.
Get these to the chinaman--
the usual disbursement.
Get your dad and uncles.
We need to talk.
You finish your chores?
Yes, sir, I've been helping
grandma with the bank.
Uh, she sent me
to get you.
Wants us all together
up in the house.
Dodd's inside.
Fought in the trenches
in France-- World War I.
He was an artillerieschuetzen,
my granddad, a gunner.
Blasted mustard gas
at the Allies.
Had them dancing
like poisoned rats.
Brits caught him in a raid,
hung him by his thumbs
for six days straight.
So this, what we're doing,
this is nothing.
Are you listening to me?
Is he listening to me?
Cut off his ears.
Wake him up.
He's dead, I think.
Weak.
Uh, Uncle Dodd?
Doc's finished.
Grandma wants us.
Who were the goons?
Kansas City.
They want to buy us out.
So they came to you,
then?
They came to see your father,
but he's not well.
So they talked to me
as his surrogate.
I should've been there.
Geez, dad.
Don't be such a baby.
Shut up.
She shouldn't be
in here.
She's old enough.
I told her to stay.
She's a girl.
And girls grow up
to be women...
and change boys' diapers.
Where's
your little brother?
Rye?
Haven't seen him.
Who knows with that kid?
Probably neck deep in some pussy.
With a girl, you know.
What's the offer?
He talks to you.
Where is he?
Said he had things to do
out of town.
- I saw him yesterday.
- What things?
What's the offer?
The world's becoming
more corporate--
this was their pitch
to me.
And in this new world,
there's no room
for family business.
So war.
They're offering
to buy the whole operation,
then pay us to run it.
Bottom line.
Bottom line-- very little
changes on the ground.
We may
actually earn more.
But instead of running it,
we report to them.
- To who?
- Kansas City.
Balls.
What'd you say?
I said, "Thank you very much.
I'll consult with my partners."
Meaning grandpa.
No.
The stroke.
Your father's not
in a lucid state.
Nor will he be...
possibly ever.
What are you saying?
I'm saying your grandpa
built this business,
but he's no longer
capable of running it.
We should have a moment
of silence, maybe.
As new boss, I say we tell
these Kansas City schvantzes
to go to hell
in the fast lane.
- Now, hold on.
- What?
You think
it should be you?
No, stupid. Mom.
Boss
can't be a woman.
Who says?
Think about it.
Mom's the one
with ties to Winnipeg.
History with Carter B
and the Solkerk crew.
Suppliers trust her.
Should be mom.
Hell, yes.
I vote for grandma.
Shut up.
We're not voting.
I'm oldest.
I'm boss.
End of story.
Give us a minute.
Not you.
Sit.
Eat something.
This moment...
How things go
in the next few weeks--
will decide--
- That's why I--
- Let me finish.
Your grandfather left the ashes
of the Weimar Republic
and came to this country
to build a name for himself.
He built an empire
from a shoe-shine box.
And then, and only then,
did he send
for your father.
Ma, I know the story.
No, you don't.
'Cause if you did,
you'd know that you are
just a small part of it.
That's what an empire is.
It's bigger
than any son or daughter.
Eat.
I'm not hungry.
I'm your mother.
You will eat with me.
Your time will come.
It will,
but this isn't it.
And if you stand by me now,
I promise you that as soon
as this crisis is over,
I'll hand you your legacy,
and I'll turn my thoughts
to the grave.
Now, we need to find Rye.
Can you do that for me?
Yes, ma'am.
Wherever he is,
whatever he's doing,
bring him home.
If you're a betting man,
I'm saying.
Well, I think
history's proven people
of the Germanic persuasion
don't surrender easy.
But you can kill them.
Unless the woman,
being a woman--
maybe we can scare her.
No.
I think we cut a deal
with one of the sons.
The youngest maybe--
Rye.
The olders are--
Well, you know,
how a lobster's got
a pincher claw
and a crusher claw?
Which one's which?
Pardon?
Which son
is which claw?
You know what?
Forget it.
I don't want anything to do
with your facacta metaphor.
Management says acquire
the territory, we acquire it.
Whether that's cash down
or sending bodies to the morgue,
that's up to the Krauts.
First Gerhardt to switch sides
gets a shiny, red apple.
No, I know.
I know, uh-huh.
No. No, Sheriff says
it's a local matter.
Yeah.
Okay, then.
- Papa.
- That's me.
- Papa!
- Did you get some sleep?
Oh, a couple hours.
You know,
went pretty late.
- Papa, papa!
- What? What?
What can I make ya?
Uh, eggs would be good.
Not a bother.
I could do oatmeal, maybe.
Tell me a story.
Something about the smell
of eggs right now...
Okay,
coffee's fine.
Uh, okay, uh...
Once upon a time, there was,
uh, an oyster.
What's an oyster?
- It's a shellfish.
- Fish?
Yeah, close enough.
Lou sleeping?
Uh, he had a call
with the brass.
Should be down soon.
Apparently, one of your victims
was a judge.
- A judge, huh?
- Uh-huh.
The older woman.
Out of North Dakota.
Huh.
Papa!
Hello. Yes?
What's the story?
What story?
About the oyster.
Oh, uh, yeah.
Sorry,
Lieutenant called.
Judge, huh?
- Ah, Betsy told ya?
- Yeah.
Yeah, a municipal judge
up in Fargo.
Huh.
Oh, yeah.
One day, the, uh...
The oyster got caught
in the net.
Fisherman pulled him up,
all set to eat him.
Uh, except,
he happened to have his--
his daughter in the boat,
and she said...
"Daddy, how would you feel
if I peeled
the roof of your house
and ate you?"
Was that you?
It was.
That's the story
of how your mom and me
came to eat hot dogs
for dinner once again.
Hey, so, knowing she's a judge,
that change anything?
Well, you know,
I guess we got to ask ourselves,
was this judge just in the wrong
place at the wrong time,
or was this whole mess
about her?
Gonna be late
for work, huh?
Oh.
Yeah, I don't think
I'm going in today.
Well, got to keep up
appearances, though, right?
You said.
Geez, hon, your eye.
Aw, no, it doesn't hurt.
It just-- it looks bad.
Well, maybe I should
stay home, too.
No, you should go.
Just tell them you hit your head
or something.
I got to...
There's to much stuff
to do here.
I-I-- The car's got
to be cleaned, the floors.
I mean...
Yeah.
Are you with me?
Good.
Bear's thrown in with mom,
and that's his loss.
Distributors will stand with me
if I press, but we need Rye.
So, when you find him,
you bring him to me first.
You understand?
Not her-- me.
There you go.
Thanks.
Remember to cook them
all the way through this time.
- Oh, thank you.
- Hey, there, Peggy.
- Hey.
- Expecting your husband.
Yeah, he had--
at dinner last night--
I think
it was some bad clams.
You know, from a can.
Never trust anything comes
from the sea.
We came from the sea.
Tomorrow, for sure.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
A Desperado, I heard.
The Sheriff thinks
a pair of them gunned down
those poor people
at The Waffle Hut
one after another in cold blood.
I mean, first Watergate,
and now this?
What's the world coming to?
Sorry, Mrs. Colson.
The car wouldn't start.
I'll ditch the coat
and get your squared away, okay?
- Big night?
- Huh?
Got a hangover?
Oh, no, it's, uh,
just a migraine.
You talk to Ed?
Did I...
About the seminar--
next weekend.
Got us a room
at the Southnik Hotel.
Oh, yeah.
I don't know.
It's a lot of money,
and we're saving up right now
so Ed can buy
the butcher shop.
What I'm hearing is
you think your husband's
more important than you--
his needs.
No, I just...
We got a plan, you know?
The word "we" is a castle, hon,
with a moat and a drawbridge.
And you know what gets locked up
in castles?
Dragons?
Princesses.
Don't be a prisoner
of "we."
Take the seminar.
It'll give you a key
to the castle.
Yeah.
Oh, hey, you don't know what
happened to all the TP, do ya?
The what's that?
Had a case of TP
in the back last week.
Somebody took it.
Yes, sir, I know I said it
was a local matter last night,
but I slept on it, you know?
And, uh, given the level
of violence
and with no apparent suspects
and, uh...
and the fact that one
of the victims was a judge...
Right, in North Dakota,
which means
you're gonna have all kinds
of interstate issues.
So, my thought is,
uh, you know, all--
all the more reason for me...
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Well, I'll coordinate
with Sheriff Larsson
and head up to Fargo
first thing tomorrow.
Yep.
Yeah, I know.
We-- You said all that,
but my point...
What I'm trying to...
I've got the money, see?
I've got...
Uh... I-- I mean, I will have.
So you just need
to hold the Selectrics
for me until, uh...
So just... hold them, okay?
Don't...
And I'll call you back.
Hi, there.
Money troubles?
What?
Oh, no.
He... double-billed me
for something is all.
Just... straightening things out.
I see.
Yeah, we're not really open
is the thing.
Uh, waiting for the--
for new models to come in.
So closed--
temporarily.
That's okay.
We're not really customers.
Okay, well...
Rye Gerhardt.
Is that your name,
or...?
I mean, geez,
I-- I met the guy,
of course, uh,
once or..
twice.
Are ya...
Did you need
a character reference, or...?
That's good.
I like that--
"a character reference."
How about you
just tell us where he is?
Seeing as he works
for you and all.
Well, isn't that what you told
Big Jim Suggs?
Over at the Pig 'N Poke
yesterday.
Had a few drinks.
Told him you had a Gerhardt
in your pocket.
I never...
Ow!
Kids today love to talk
on the phone,
but I'm a big believer
in correspondence,
friendly or otherwise.
If you've got a complaint--
it's my motto--
put it in writing.
For instance, last week,
I bought one
of those new automatic
coffee makers at Sears.
You know,
the one with the clock inside.
And the thing is--
pardon my French--
a real piece of shit.
So what do I do?
Dear General Electric,
the coffee maker that I bought
at Sears on 11 March
makes a noise
when it's brewing
that sounds like a fat man
having a heart attack.
Stop!
And it forces me
to ask the question--
Is this why
our once-great nation
is going down the crapper?
Yours in peace and harmony,
Mike Milligan.
- The judge.
- Go on.
All I said was,
"Talk to her."
What judge?
Mundt.
Judge Mundt!
Mm.
"Talk to her"--
That's what you said?
Yeah.
Why?
What happened?
- There he goes. Watch him.
- Don't let him get away, man.
Get a rope and go hang him.
♪ one hour ahead of the posse ♪
♪ the bloodhounds
are hot on my trail ♪
♪ last evening,
I shot down my sweetheart ♪
♪ this morning,
I broke out of jail ♪
♪ my pinto is tired and hungry ♪
♪ and I'm feeling weary
and gone ♪
♪ we started ahead
of the posse ♪
♪ and we got to keep going on ♪
♪ the sheriff aswored
he would get me ♪
♪ he's riding with 20 and 5 ♪
♪ but I ain't afeared
of that posse ♪
♪ for they'll never
get me alive ♪
♪ one hour ahead of the posse ♪
♪ no turning to left
or to right ♪
♪ we must win the race
to the river ♪
♪ or there'll be
a hanging tonight ♪
♪ we're gonna hang him tonight ♪
♪ one hour ahead of the posse ♪
♪ and now I'm inside
of my goaaaaaal ♪
♪ at last we have beaten
that posse ♪
♪ may the Lord have mercy
on my soul ♪
You said
to remind ya I got
that specialist appointment
Tuesday.
Dad
said he'd watch Molly.
I'll drive ya.
Ya sure?
- Ya got the case.
- I'll drive ya.
We feel so special, don't we,
getting daddy for lunch.
Daddy!
Uh, Captain said wait
on going up to Fargo.
He needs to work out some kind
of chain-of-command BS.
So...
Hon?
Sorry.
I got a wild hair.
Something's not adding up.
Stay here, okay?
Mm-hmm.
What's daddy doing?
Work stuff.
You want
to build a snowman?
What are you gonna call
this snowman, Molly?
Maybe Bob.
Yeah.
_
All right,
we got the bottom.
Next,
we need to make the body.
I need you to find me some
sticks for the arms.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
- Mama!
- Yeah?
Look what I found.
Can I keep it?
_
No, hon,
that's got a rip.
That's trash now,
okay?
Okay, okay.
Hon!
Look at this!
Look what I found.
Oh, that's great,
hon.
I just--
I found it in the bushes.
- Fingerprints.
- Yeah, I know. Geez.
I got it by the barrel.
What's that?
Well, mama's doing
daddy's job again.
Go, mama!
Oh.
You okay, hon?
Yeah,
I stood up too fast is all.
Help you, Officer?
Sir, please roll up your window.
My friend up front doesn't like
to talk to strangers.
Well,
he's gonna talk to me.
Rock County.
It's like, "What's that town
on The Flintstones?"
Is that where we are?
On The Flintstones?
All right, that's it.
Out of the car-- all of ya.
Your friends, too.
Come around
the driver's side here.
Okay...
Let me see some IDs.
I'm gonna reach
in my pocket.
Now them.
Mike Milligan.
And two named Kitchen.
Brothers, yeah?
Yes, sir, that's us.
Kansas City.
What's this about, Sheriff,
if I'm okay to ask?
Now, if I were
to search you three,
would I find weapons?
Well, sir, you have
nothing to fear from us.
We're just passing though town
on our way to points south.
Thought we'd stop
for some waffles.
Gale's idea.
Heard you had some
real good ones around here.
So you can imagine our surprise
when we find the place closed
and, apparently,
the scene of a crime.
What size shoes
you boys wear?
Now, that is
a truly odd question.
Last time I checked,
I was a 10.
Boys?
Now, I'm gonna go ahead
and guess the boys are an 11
and not a 2,
which would make them toddlers.
Now, unless there's
some law been broken,
think it's time
for us to be on our way.
I promised the boys' wives
I'd have them home for supper,
and I am, if nothing else,
a man of my word.
Okay.
I got your names
and your plate number.
I'm gonna radio ahead
and make sure
you make it out of State.
If not,
I'm gonna put out an APB
and have you boys
rounded up.
And then
we'll talk again.
You understand?
I do.
And isn't that
a minor miracle?
The state
of the world today
and the level of conflict
and misunderstanding,
that two men could stand
on a lonely road in winter
and talk calmly
and rationally...
while all around them,
people are losing their mind.
You have a nice day.
Good night, Noreen.
Okay, then.
Don't be silly.
I'll give ya a ride.
Ya sure?
I-I don't want
to be a bother.
No bother.
Come on, sexy.
Get in.
♪ dancing alone in the madness ♪
♪ there is no sadness ♪
Right to the right.
Ooh,
you're a lifesaver.
It's a real mess.
Thanks, doll.
Shouldn't have had
all that ginger ale.
♪ they got some
crazy little women there ♪
♪ and I'm gonna get me one ♪
♪ they got some
crazy little women there ♪
♪ and I'm gonna get me one ♪
Ed?
Ed!
♪ well, I might take a plane ♪
♪ might take a train ♪
♪ if I got to walkin',
I'm going just the same ♪
♪ I'm going to Kansas City ♪
♪ Kansas City, here I come ♪
♪ they got some
crazy little women there ♪
Geez!
What happened to your car?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
Uh, just a dust-up.
Ed had a few too many last night
and hit a tree.
Uh, he's fine, though.
Just shook up.
What about you?
Me? Oh, no.
I-I wasn't-- I was home.
Those bills
aren't gonna pay themselves.
You're kind of a bad girl,
aren't you?
Yeah, you are.
I'm usually able to tell
right away,
but you had me fooled.
Oh, it's nothing.
I just bumped it
is all.
In the dust-up?
Thought you weren't
in the car, you said.
It's okay. You don't have
to tell the truth.
I'm not even mad
about the TP.
Next time, just ask,
though.
Or maybe
that's what you like.
Huh?
Breaking the rules.
Thanks for the ride,
okay?
I just--
I-I got a real bad headache,
like I said before,
and maybe I-I'll just see you
at work tomorrow,
okay?
Sleep well, now.
I didn't expect
you'd still be here.
Yeah.
Found possibly the murder weapon
over in the bushes there.
Betsy did, I mean,
if I'm being honest,
which I try to be.
So now I'm wondering
what else I missed.
Ah.
Anything interesting
on the car I called in?
Oh, those fellas
were positively fascinating.
Nothing actionable,
though.
Cook fell funny is the truth--
why I'm still here.
Got stuck in my head--
a callback.
I've heard it referred to once
as a convergence.
You know, one thing
reminds you of another.
Yeah.
Want to talk about it?
Not especially.
We had a guy on the boat,
liked to smoke cigars
for breakfast.
Picked up the habit
from his granddad, he said.
This was
on the Bo De river,
seventy... four.
Ah.
So I'm on the wheel.
This kid comes out.
'Cause what
could he have been? 19?
Lights his shit stick,
and then...
Never
even saw it coming.
Shot him
right through the cigar.
A one-in-a-million shot.
And the look on his face
when he fell--
just like the cook.
Bafflement.
Yeah.
This...
German captain
hung himself-- 1945.
Found him in a bunker
during the mop-up.
Face all purple,
eyes bugged out.
Then, in '62,
I'm responding
to a suicide.
Fella's in his bathroom,
swinging from an electric cord.
You never know.
Mm.
War stories.
Yeah.
Different now, though.
After WWII,
we went six years
without a--
without a murder here.
Six years.
And these days, well...
Sometimes wonder
if you boys
didn't bring
that war home with ya.
Hey.
Burning it
at both ends, huh?
Uh, y-yeah.
Yeah.
Double shift for me.
Hear what happened?
- At that Waffle Hut, yeah.
- Yeah.
Real mess.
- Mm.
The killer still
at large, they say?
Yeah, we think so.
Anyway,
saw your light on.
You know, Molly loves bacon
for breakfast.
I seem
to remember we're out.
So, I thought, if you don't
mind, I'd pick some up--
be there
when she woke up.
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
Um...
So, uh,
you want fat back, or...?
Well, lean,
if you got it.
- Okay.
- 1/3 of a pound.
Mm.
So, how's Peggy?
Yeah, she's, uh...
She's doing... good.
Yeah, doing real,
you know...
Work's good, she says.
Yeah, I think Betsy's coming
in this week for a trim,
which, uh... don't know
why I know that.
Wives.
They talk whether
we're listening or not.
- Yeah.
- Oh, yeah-- Oh.
No, it's, uh--
it's on the house.
Oh, no, no.
Let me.
No, I-I-- I got it.
I got it.
You gonna get that?
Yeah.
Why is it taking so long?
Yeah, it's just, uh...
My wife.
- Uh, I'm almost done.
- Right.
Well, can ya hurry up?
I don't like being here
by myself.
Thanks.
Ed?
Yeah?
Yeah, I still got to...
You know, it takes time,
grinding a whole--
No, I-I know. I...
I just miss ya is all.
No, I-I miss you,
too, hon.
It's just--
I'll make
some oatmeal, okay?
And we can have breakfast
when you get home.
Okay.
I love ya.
Love you, too.
Bye.