Am I, uh...
What are we waiting for?
What?
The arrows.
Gayle's putting in the arrows
on Reagan.
Yeah, I know.
It's...
They said...
Jenny came by the trailer,
and she said five minutes, so...
Well, there's a lot of arrows.
So...
- Should I just go back to my...
- No.
No, it's, uh...
Jenny said...
What did Jenny say?
They're... they're...
they're putting in the arrows.
Yeah, I know.
But how long?
Doll, just find out,
will you?
'Cause the Chief is wearing
moccasins here.
It's goddamn February.
So, what's he like,
anyway?
Who?
Dutch. Reagan.
Ronnie?
Oh, he's a prince.
He's a real class act.
Yeah.
Can I get
a blanket?
This is the actual field,
they tell me.
What?
It's the actual battlefield...
Massacre at Sioux Falls.
I think 300 of your people...
braves...
died here, what,
100 years ago?
I'm from New Jersey.
Sure, but...
Yeah, you're... you're...
you're an Indian, right?
So...
so that... that...
that's got to be, uh...
Got to be what?
No, I'm just saying this battle,
it was the last big battle
before the end of the...
And what came after...
whew!
And, look, I'm a Jew,
so believe me,
I know tribulation.
Yeah. Smoke?
Any minute, he'll be out.
All right, nobody moves.
Everybody is still dead.
It is a crisis of confidence.
It is a crisis that strikes
at the very heart and soul
and spirit of our national will.
_
We can see this crisis
in the growing doubt
about the meaning
of our own lives
and in the loss
of a unity of purpose.
_
Is he kidding me?
...has been taken out
of the home of John Wayne Gacy...
The erosion of our confidence
in the future
is threatening to destroy _
the social and the political
fabric of America. _
That's what I'm trying
to engage with here
is this untapped potential
of yours
to sort of think
a little bit.
♪ I can't sing, I ain't pretty
and my legs are thin ♪
Confidence in the future
has supported everything else.
♪ I might not give a answer
that you want me to ♪
_
Hey, there. Sorry.
Are you kidding me?
You said noon, yeah?
Hold on, now...
Said 11:00, not noon.
What?
Say that again.
- Okay.
- Say it again.
Okay, okay!
Where's the goddamn money?
I gave it to Ollie,
like, yesterday.
Don't lie.
I mean,
I'm... I'm getting it.
It's just a little late.
The hell you say.
I did the rounds.
Everybody paid.
'Course they're
gonna say that.
So you got the money.
Well, you know,
maybe I needed it for me,
for something I...
No, you earn for the family,
not for yourself.
Yeah.
But you're the oldest,
and then there's Bear,
and that's the throne.
What am I ever gonna be
except the kid you send out
for milk?
You're a Gerhardt.
That's like Jupiter
telling Pluto,
"Hey, you're a planet, too."
What?
If I'm this royalty,
how come you got me
doing bullshit collections
like some nobody chump?
Everybody earns.
That's the law.
Yeah, but what if I got
ambitions, you know?
You wear short pants
till you prove you're a man.
I'm a man.
You're the comic
in a piece of bubble gum!
Well, I mean, says you.
You got till tomorrow to bring
the collection money you owe.
Or what?
You make me wait for you again,
I'll cleave your skull.
This is the month's cash,
all in.
You'll see the problem
right away.
Light.
Mm.
About time.
Give me a break.
Soon as you ladies
are done dancing...
You're right.
We're light,
even though
the transport dollars went up.
It's the local business...
gambling and drugs...
and whores.
Meine keine gute soehne?
Don't pin this on me.
Or me.
We earned.
But not Rye.
No.
But even without his nut,
we shouldn't be
this short.
It's like we're a balloon
leaking air all over.
Spit it out.
What are we talking
about here?
Tell me, God damn it.
Another outfit.
I'm taking care
of it.
From the south.
Don't know where.
- I said I'd handle it.
- They're coming hard.
Son, I'm the iron fist
of God.
There's not a sane man
in three states
who would dare to...
Some pissant crew
from south no place?
You bring me these
hirnlose mutter fotzen
and I'll grind their bones
to make my...
Otto? Otto?
_
All right, hear me.
I'm saying tomorrow
has never been closer
than it is right now.
It's 11:00
in the morning.
Metaphorically, I mean.
Hi, friend.
Be with you in a...
Check never came,
is my point.
I'm owed for work I done.
Me and the boys,
we're owed.
Giddyup there, cowboy.
Wait your turn,
short round.
What'd you say?
You heard me.
Jesus. Just...
It's in the mail, okay?
The check.
Just... if it hasn't come
by Tuesday,
I'll write you another.
Yeah, that's right.
You better run.
Come on, now.
He could call a cop.
He's not calling anybody.
Guys like that, they're just big
on the outside.
So, where's this
miracle contraption?
Behold the future.
I'm talking money
hand over fist.
A typewriter.
A self-correcting IBM
Selectric II electric typewriter
with patented
high-speed type ball.
They're not just
for women anymore.
And you're sure
we're the only...
Sole distributor,
Midwest region.
Assuming you're willing
to forget certain debts
owed to your family
from the, uh...
Gambling.
Yeah, which, you know,
I'm not proud.
So, as soon as you talk
to the judge
and she unfreezes
the accounts,
well, then we can turn on
the money spigot.
The what?
The spigot.
It's like
where you hook up a hose.
Like a fire hose?
Any hose.
I'm saying once we get
those typewriters,
the money...
there'll be no stopping it.
Uh, which judge, again?
♪ people of the Earth,
can you hear me? ♪
♪ came a voice from the sky
on that magical night ♪
♪ and in the colors
of a thousand sunsets ♪
♪ they traveled through
the world on a silvery light ♪
_
You're the comic
in a piece of bubble gum!
♪ the people of the Earth
stood waiting ♪
♪ watching as the ships came
one by one ♪
♪ setting fire to the sky
as they landed ♪
♪ carrying to the world
children of the Sun ♪
Welcome to Waffle Hut!
- Shit, lady.
- Table or booth?
Just, uh, the counter.
♪ children of the Sun ♪
♪ all at once came a sound
from the inside ♪
Special's tuna melt and fries.
Pie is humbleberry.
Just coffee.
♪ everyone felt the sound
of their heartbeat ♪
♪ every man, every woman,
every child ♪
Everything's
taken care of.
You see? They didn't charge us
for the fries.
Sugar?
Uh, you know,
you're freaking me out a little.
♪ through the doors
to a world of another time ♪
Honey, I don't know about
your day, but my day was crazy.
♪ and on the journey
of a thousand lifetimes ♪
♪ with the children of the Sun ♪
Now he squeezes and the mustard
goes all over his shirt.
And he now has no shirt to wear,
so now...
I got to pay up.
I'll meet you
at the cash register.
How was everything?
Oh, yeah. Real good.
- Oh, good.
- ♪ no more gravity ♪
I'll get your change.
♪ nothing holding them down ♪
- There you are.
- Thanks.
♪ floating endlessly ♪
♪ as their ship leaves
the ground ♪
Hi.
No.
What do you mean, "No"?
Whatever you're selling,
I ain't buying.
First of all,
I'm not selling anything.
- And second...
- He needs to make me another burger.
This one's a coaster.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey. Your majesty.
You're gonna change your mind
about something... a case.
Or what?
Or you'll find out,
is what.
This isn't one of those optional
check "A" or "B" scenarios.
I'm gonna change your mind.
One day, the Devil came to God
and said,
"Let's make a bet
between you and me
for the soul of a man."
And from on high
they looked down on Job,
a devout man, religious.
And the Devil said,
"I can change his mind
and make him
curse your name."
And God said,
"Try and you will only fail."
So the Devil begins.
He kills Job's herds
and takes his fields.
He plagues him with boils
and throws him on the ash heap.
But Job's mind
remains unchanged.
So I ask you, son,
if the Devil couldn't
change Job's mind,
how the hell
are you gonna change mine?
What?
You're a little dim,
aren't you?
Listen, this is...
There's two ways
this can go.
- Is one of them the hard way?
- Easy...
You know what?
There's a fella needs to get
his hands on some typewriters.
Ugh. Christ.
And you're gonna...
You're with that fool.
- Yeah. You're...
- Okay. _
Son, you have three second
to pick your ass up
and get out of here,
or I'm gonna squash you
like a bug.
Okay, look, bitch...
I'm the one do...
God damn, my eyes.
Now scram
before I call the cops.
Oh, crap.
Sh...
Shit.
"'Oh, whocky!' Cried Joel.
'See what you've done,
Polly Pepper?'
but Polly didn't hear.
Over the big, flat door-stone
she sped and met Ben
with Little David
coming in the gate.
His face was just like
Phronsie's!
And with a cold,
heavy feeling at her heart,
Polly realized this was no play.
'Oh, Ben!' She cried,
flinging her arms
around his neck
and bursting into tears.
'Don't! Please.
I-I wish you wouldn't.
Phronsie's got 'em,
and that's enough.'
'Got what?' Asked Ben,
while Davie's eyes grew
to their widest proportions.
'Oh, measles!' Cried Polly,
bursting out afresh.
'Hatefulest, horridest measles!
And now you're taken!'
'Oh, no, I ain't,'
responded Ben cheerfully,
who knew what measles were.
'Wipe up, Polly.
I'm all right.'"
"'Only my head aches
and my eyes feel funny.'
Polly, only half reassured,
gulped down her sobs
and the sorrowful trio
repaired to mother.
'Oh, dear me,'
ejaculated Mrs. Pepper,
sinking in a chair at the dismay
at the sight of Ben's red face.
'Whatever will we do now?'"
This is a funny book, huh?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Phone call, hon.
It's the shop.
Okay, you.
Sleep, huh?
Okay.
I'll be back in a minute
to tuck you in.
Okay.
Murder, Eunice says.
Three of them
over at the Waffle Hut.
Hey, uh, you...
you had your thing today.
Yeah. This morning.
You feel okay?
Compared to what?
Love Canal?
Hmm?
Solverson.
Yeah, okay.
Tell him not to go inside.
Hank on his way?
Okay. You too.
Got to go, hon.
You okay
getting her to bed?
Yeah. She's six,
not, you know, Pol Pot.
Okay. Call if you need,
you know, whatever.
Mm-hmm.
I left my rig there.
I hope that's okay.
I'm the one
who called it in, see?
Stopped for waffles,
you know?
With the blueberries.
They come frozen this time
of year, I know, but...
I-I put my coat on her.
It seemed only right.
Yeah.
"Yeah," it's okay
about the coat, or...?
Yeah.
Well, this is a deal.
I count three dead.
Saw the waitress
in the parking lot?
Mm.
I think she caught one there,
then staggered out.
Gunman followed,
made things permanent.
That's Henry Blanton.
Got the single-season touchdown
record in 10th grade.
31.
Still stands.
Yeah. Don't know her.
North Dakota plates
on a Mercedes outside.
Tourist,
you're thinking?
Mm...
How's Betsy?
You mean you didn't call her
before you came over?
Well, yeah.
Just being polite.
Give you a chance
to talk about your feelings,
should you be
so disposed.
She's good. Yeah.
Ordered this kit
of recipe cards.
Saw it on the TV.
So now every night,
we eat delicacies of the world.
Mm. Some men like that.
Variety.
Mm.
She put a soufflé
on the table last night...
perfectly good casserole...
and lit it on fire
with a kitchen match.
Huh?
Oh, which reminds me...
you're invited
for dinner tomorrow.
- 6:00?
- Mm-hmm.
I'll bring a suit of armor.
Skid marks.
Yeah. I see them.
'Course, connecting those
to this deal here
would be what we call
"jumping to a conclusion."
Based on
the number of bodies,
I'm thinking we've got one car
too many in the parking lot.
Yeah.
So, the shooter's got
a wound or two in him
from the steak knife.
Two blood trails lead out.
One to the waitress,
now deceased.
The other to the road here,
where he absconds,
leaving a few dollars
behind.
Uh-huh.
Why not take his own car?
Unclear at this time.
There's a shoe
in that tree.
There sure is.
So, uh, this a local matter
or do the State Police want it?
We do not.
Local matter it is.
And, of course, any support
the State can provide.
Yeah, of course.
See you tomorrow night,
then, eh?
6:00.
Be ready for anything.
That's a shoe, all right.
Okay, then.
Noreen?
Hmm?
Ed's leaving.
Okay, then.
Oh, hey. May as well
take these with you.
Boolie Hendricks paid
but never picked them up.
Chops?
Mm.
Wasted meat's a crime.
Or it should be.
Okay, then.
B-8. B-8.
So, Ho Chi Minh...
Jesus, kid. Keep up.
Ho Chi Minh
was just a front man.
Enemy number one
straight out of central casting.
AKA a stuffed shirt for
the military industrial complex.
The what's that, now?
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
Ike's farewell address?
The military
industrial complex.
Wheels inside wheels,
special interests.
N-33. N-33.
I thought
there'd be a band tonight.
- Boys.
- I-17.
I-17.
Balls.
Tell this dipshit pissant
about Ike's farewell address.
You mean
the military industrial complex?
See? He knows.
'Course,
we've been to war.
Nothing complex about it.
How come
you're in uniform, then, Lou?
Didn't you work
this morning?
Three dead
at the Waffle Hut.
No shit.
Yeah, a real mess.
Women, too.
Hank's thinking
botched robbery.
Oh, sure.
That's what
they want you to think.
Who?
They.
B-11.
You know,
the powers that be.
It's a classic story.
Oswald acted alone.
The girl
in the polka-dot dress.
The what, now?
The girl in the...
After Kennedy the other
was shot... Robert, in LA...
People saw a woman
in a polka-dot dress
running out of the hotel
yelling, "We got him!"
But who did they arrest?
I-23. I-23.
An A-rab. Racist pricks.
It's a diner robbery
in Minnesota, Karl.
Not a presidential
assassination.
Oh, sure.
That's how it starts...
with something small
like a break-in
at the Watergate Hotel.
But just watch.
This thing's
only getting bigger.
G-53. G-53.
Well, I better get home.
Betsy had
her chemo today.
God!
What is it, Karl?
It's just... God damn.
Unacceptable
is what it is.
A woman like that
in the prime of her...
With a young daughter.
N-40. N-40.
Tell her if John McCain
could hold out
for 5 1/2 years
against Viet Cong thumbscrews,
she can beat this cancer
bullshit in her sleep.
I'll make sure
to mention that.
♪ I don't worry ♪
♪ 'long as you're by my side ♪
- Hey, hon?
- In the kitchen.
♪ just hold me, darlin' ♪
Boolie Hendricks
paid for chops
and never picked them up,
so I figured...
- Hi.
- Hey.
Uh, hon, you're getting blood
on the tile.
Oh. Sorry.
I'll put them in the fridge.
Hamburger helper?
- And Tater Tots.
- Yum.
♪ oh, yes, I do ♪
Should I...
Oh, hon. Don't.
I just got that stuff
organized.
Yeah, but my chair.
Where am I supposed to...
- Well, sit there, huh?
- Yeah.
I'll move that stuff tomorrow.
Promise.
- Bon appétit.
- Mm.
♪ and your love's true ♪
♪ that you love me, darlin' ♪
♪ just as much as I love you ♪
♪ and, darlin', I love you ♪
So, you think there was
an accomplice and a getaway car?
Your dad called.
You know him.
Likes to talk things through
before he goes to bed.
We got glasses.
Tastes different
in a glass.
Molly go down okay?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you know,
I forgot earlier...
She made you something
at school today.
Yeah?
She knows
I don't smoke, right?
You could start.
Hmm.
Your dad said he'd be over
Sunday in a suit of armor.
Ugh. Geez.
You light one soufflé
on fire...
So, I'm getting excited
about this seminar.
- The which?
- You remember, hon.
It's next weekend.
Constance is taking me.
Lifespring.
Everybody's doing it.
Oh, yeah.
I really think this course
is gonna help me actualize,
you know, fully.
Re-examine
old reflex patterns...
the ones that keep my life
from working.
From...
'Cause we're doing great,
yeah?
Oh, yeah.
I just mean me, you know?
As a person.
- Yeah.
Well, Bud asked again
if I was interested
in maybe taking over
the butcher shop.
Mm.
Said he's thinking of retiring
end of the year.
Just had
the end of the year, huh?
Yeah, I guess he means
this year,
but wouldn't that be great?
Me owning the shop,
maybe you take over
the salon one day.
You know, unless we got
a whole litter of kids by then.
Yeah, that's...
We talked about that.
We're trying,
but it takes time, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course.
Though, uh... hon...
"trying"... I mean,
last time I checked,
there's just the one way
to make a baby, you know?
Did that last weekend,
didn't we?
It was Bear Lake last weekend.
You said
you didn't want to...
- not with Kevin and Sally...
- Hon.
I ju...  I just... uh...
I just love you, is all.
So, so much.
And, come on,
our kids would be amazing.
Oh, shoot!
Here.
Hon, let me...
No, it-it's fine.
I'm... I'm such
a bumble sometimes.
What the heck?
I-I love you, too, hon,
so, so much.
Maybe we should...
Maybe do it right now.
Here?
No, silly.
In the bedroom.
Come on.
Geez. I better go see
what that...
We can...
I'll wear that nightie
you like.
What the...
Hon?
Didn't I tell you?
I kind of hit a deer.
You hit a...
Are you... you okay?
Yeah, no, I-I'm just,
you know, shook up, mostly.
Geez.
Well, insurance
should cover most...
Actually, I... I think
I need to sit down, hon.
Can we go
in the kitchen?
Heck, hon,
did you bring the deer home?
Hon, don't.
Hon.
Hon! Come back!
Don't.
Ah, geez.
T-there's a...
It's a man.
There's a man in the...
Oh, my God.
Oh... oh, my God.
Hon.
Geez, hon.
Sorry. Are y-you okay?
No, it's... I'm fine.
- Who...
- You got to believe me.
I-I thought he was dead.
What?
When I hit him,
I thought he was...
You hit him?
You hit him with the car?
You... you said a deer.
You hit him.
Why... why didn't you go to
the police or the hospital?
He ran out
into the road, hon.
What was I supposed to do?
Yeah, so...
so you brought him home,
made dinner...
Hamburger Helper.
I panicked, okay?
We... we got to call
the police.
Why didn't you call
the police?
- No.
- We gotta... Maybe he's not...
No, no. No. I... I...
Hon, listen to me.
I ran over him.
Hit and run.
And... and then you stabbed him
with a gardening tool.
The cops... do you think
they're gonna believe us?
I don't know.
But... but people are gonna
look for him.
But... but look. Look.
I-I was careful.
I-I drove the back way
all the way home.
You drove the...
Hon, a-a man's dead.
Well, that's why
we have to clean it up and...
and tell people
I hit a deer or...
We could run.
What?
Go to California.
Calif...
No.
We have a life here, hon.
A family.
I'm gonna buy the shop.
- Okay, then. - Okay, then.
- Okay, then.
And we're gonna start
a f-family.
Well, start again,
I'm saying.
I don't want to.
Okay, then...
You...
Then, hon, look at me.
If we're gonna
get clear of this,
then we're gonna have to
clean it up.
Pretend it didn't happen.
'Cause if this comes out,
if this...
then all the things
you want,
that we want...
that's over.
I go to jail
and maybe you also.
And then there's no shop
and no family.
No kids.
Okay.
Okay, then.
We...
we clean it up.
We clean it up.
Well, should we call that
Saturday?
I suppose we better.
She'll be up at 5:00 anyway
wanting to play dolls.
And I know how fond you are
of your doll-playing time.
Good night,
Mr. Solverson.
Good night, Mrs. Solverson,
and all the ships at sea.
O-Otto?
Otto! No!
No!
Oh! Otto!
Live!
Get the doctor! Go now!
Now!
Otto.
Call the doctor. Go!
_
So, as you see
on page 16 of the prospectus,
the main component of our
Northern expansion strategy
involves the absorption of
the Gerhardt Family Syndicate,
headquartered in Fargo, ND.
Now, the Gerhardts control
trucking and distribution
for the entire Northern Midwest.
It's a family business
started in 1931
by Dieter Gerhardt...
...now deceased,
and taken over in 1950
by his son Otto.
Now, not in the report
but of relevance
to this meeting,
Old Otto had a stroke yesterday
in the family compound
in North Dakota.
Leaving who in charge?
Unclear.
His wife, Floyd, she's tough,
but, you know, a girl.
And then there are the three
sons... Dodd, Bear, and Rye.
And of course they all want
their shot at the throne,
which the boys in Research
think provides
a tactical opportunity for us
to move aggressively
to acquire or absorb
their operation.
And if you can't
and the current
business owners resist?
We liquidate.
Approved.
♪ go to sleep, you little babe ♪
♪ your mama's gone away
and your daddy's gonna stay ♪
♪ didn't leave nobody
but the babe ♪
♪ go to sleep, you little babe ♪
♪ everybody's gone
in the cotton and the corn ♪
♪ didn't leave nobody
but the babe ♪
♪ you're a sweet, little babe ♪
♪ you're a sweet, little baby ♪
♪ honey in the rock
and the sugar don't stop ♪
♪ gonna bring a bottle
to the baby ♪
♪ don't you weep, pretty baby ♪
♪ you and me
and the Devil makes three ♪
♪ don't need no other lovin', baby ♪
♪ go to sleep, you little babe ♪
♪ come on, lay your bones
on the alabaster stones ♪
♪ and be my ever lovin' baby ♪