You really can't get good help
these days.
Phew!
I understand your help
is the very best money can buy.
You see, I'm the one who had you hired.
Then I owe you something special.
This particular assignment is one
from which I will derive
- exquisite pleasure, Miss...
- Call me Candice.
Call me Bane.
Come on, boss. Hit it again.
Again.
Come on, boss. No wonder Batman's
running rings around you.
Just can't get good help these days.
So I have heard.
Candice, when Jake here comes around,
tell him he's fired.
Now, let's do a little business,
Mr. Bane.
They'll never pin it on me, but that
little fiasco cost me an easy $10 mil.
You almost didn't get paid.
You're lucky these diamonds
didn't get nabbed in the smuggling bust.
No, Mr. Thorne,
you're the lucky one.
I'm making my secretary
available to you.
She can provide any background
you might need on your target.
My needs have already been met.
I'm paying you to go after Batman,
not Killer Croc.
But the Batman will surely be
on the reptile's trail.
I will observe the bat in action
and when I understand how he thinks
and fights, I will break him.
Now, where do I find this Killer Croc?
Load the truck. We'll get the safe.
Batman.
No time for this.
Come on in, Batman. The water's fine.
He is mine to destroy, monster.
Over my dead body.
As you wish.
That's Croc.
Somebody's helping us out.
Somebody tough.
He could be a crime-fighter, you know?
Somebody trying to be like us,
trying to help us clean up Gotham.
What do you think, Batman? Do you...
What?
I think you're right
about one thing, Robin.
Whoever did this was tough.
This was done with bare hands.
- I didn't think you'd mind some company.
Visiting hours are over.
Hmm...
How do these traction things work?
When my bones heal,
I'll show you firsthand.
Okay, okay.
What do you want?
Who did this, Croc?
Why should I tell you?
If you wanna suffer in silence,
that's fine by me.
Ahhh!
Okay, okay.
He was huge.
He had these tubes in his head.
Pumped him up twice as big
right in front of my eyes.
And he had an accent.
South American or something.
See? That wasn't so hard.
You'll know hard, Bats,
once he sucks that juice into his brain
and snaps you in two.
Don't bet on it, Killer.
Later, gator.
You seem to have a ding
in your door, sir.
He trashed my car, Alfred.
Between a couple of guys,
that's real personal.
Nice to see you haven't lost your sense
of humor in the face of adversity.
Something Croc said reminded me of
a Cuban prison experiment I heard about.
Peña Duro Prison, for lifers only.
- Then we're looking for an escapee?
- That's right.
And there's only been
one escape in 25 years,
three years ago.
Computer, run background file
on Project Gilgamesh.
Gilgamesh. Named after the warrior?
The ultimate warrior.
A chemical plan to create super soldiers
out of hardened prisoners.
It was abandoned when they got
more than they bargained for.
- And what was that, sir?
- They got Bane.
After he escaped,
Bane went into business for himself
as a freelance assassin.
Price per job, $5 million.
So, the question is,
who wants to eliminate me?
That line is forming
around the block, sir.
Let me put it this way.
Who has $5 million to spend?
I have anticipated his every move.
Very soon now, I will allow you
the pleasure of drawing the mask
from Batman's decimated face.
With Batman out of the way,
Gotham could be yours.
So could I.
And what about your employer?
Well, accidents do happen.
See you tonight.
You're here late, Candice.
Just leaving, Rupe.
He's out there somewhere, Bane.
Yes. Probably closer than we think.
It is over
before it begins.
I think not.
You have courage for one so small.
You can yet be of use to me.
I'd like to speak to you
about your new boyfriend.
You've been stood up.
He knew you'd come.
He was obsessed with you in prison.
He's read everything about you.
He knows you better
than you know yourself.
Bet it's for you.
I've been watching you, Batman.
Were I a common sniper,
you'd have never reached the phone.
What do you want, Bane?
Something more personal between foes.
What do you value most, Batman?
Perhaps I should say
whom do you value most?
Robin.
I want his mask, Bane.
Patience. Soon you will have them both.
Been nice hanging with you.
Welcome to my arena, Batman.
Prepare to meet your master.
I will break you!
My legs. Get the weights.
Come here, sweetie.
I got something to discuss with you.
Toys. You try to fight me
with pathetic little toys.
You've got nothing.
Beg for mercy.
Scream my name!
Never.
You are beaten.
Now I will break you.
Huh?
No! No! The venom!
Can't stop it!
No! Help me!
You can't do this to me!
I am invincible!
I am Bane!
Let her go.
I know where she's headed.
Is this the best you can
throw at me, Rupert?
Go on, Candice, take his mask.
Thought you might like
to hear this, Rupert.
It's a new release.
Maybe we'll call it,
"Better Luck Next Time."
With Batman out of the way,
Gotham could be yours.
So could I.
And what about your employer?
Well, accidents do happen.
Candice!