Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago the four nations lived
together in harmony
Then, everything changed
when the fire nation attacked.
Only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar,
an airbender named Aang
And although his
airbending skills are great
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
We won't be able
to mount a massive invasion
without the earth king's armies.
But the solar eclipse will still leave
the Firenation vulnerable.
So we're planning a smaller invasion.
Just a rack-tack team of our friends
and allies from around the Earth Kingdom.
It's better for now
that no one knows that I'm alive.
You used to be the pride of the Firenation.
Now look at you.
Look what you've become.
Look, you guys keep telling me
I need to sleep.
But I can't.
The invasion is tomorrow.
You've been training for this
since the day we met.
You can do this.
You're ready.
During the meeting
I was the perfect prince.
The son my father wanted.
But I wasn't me.
Evil and good are always
at war inside you, Zuko.
It is your nature.
Your legacy. Born in you
along with all the strive
is the power to restore balance
to the world.
Book three: Fire
Chapter ten: The day of black sun,
Part 1: the Invasion
Made by elpiedro from
http://santahelp.wordpress.com
Top of the morning, Momo.
- Sounds like you slept well.
Like a baby moose line
I'm ready to face the Firelord.
So what's your strategy
for taking him down?
Gonna get your glow on and hit him
with a little avatar state action?
I can't. When Azula shot me
with lightening
my seventh chakra was locked.
Cutting off my connection
to all the cosmic energy in the universe.
You know what I just heard?
Blabla... spiritual... mombo jumbo
blabla... something about space.
Oh no, Sokka, do you think
the fog will delay the invasion?
No, that is the invasion.
You made it, dad.
Were you able to locate everybody
I told you to find?
I did. But I'm a little worried, Sokka.
Some of these man aren't
exactly the warrior type.
This place ain't nothing like a swamp.
What you recon that is?
Some sort of Firenation exploding trap
would eat you.
It's just a rock, dude.
Well, I'll be.
Is it just me or are those fellows
a little lose in the leafhead.
I just wish they would wear pants.
Pants are an illusion
and so is death.
Hi, Katara.
Haru, it's so good to see you.
Toph, this is Haru. When we met him
his town was controlled by the Firenation.
So, he had to hide his earthbending.
Katara inspired me and my father
to take back our village.
You helped us found our courage, Katara.
No we're here to help you.
No way, is that...
Hypo happy to see blind bandit.
- You guys here for a rematch?
Negatory, the boulder and the hypo
no longer fight for others entertainment.
Now we fight for our kingdom.
Sweet.
Was that a new invention?
Yes, but unfortunately
the incendiary capabilities
of peanut sauce
proof to be a failure.
You're making peanut sauce bombs?
They are destructive
- And delicious.
Were you able to complete work
on the plans I send you?
Yes, I was and I think the Firenation
will be quite surprised.
Aang, my dad and I made this for you.
A new glider.
This is amazing.
And as a special feature
I added a snack compartment.
I'm sure that will come in handy.
I bed you tired of being
in this cell, old man.
Well, too bad. You're never
stepping outside this walls again.
Breakfast.
Careful, Ming. Don't get too close.
His stantial will knock you right out.
I snuck in some yj tea.
I know you like rare teas.
Thank you, Ming. Ever since I was put
in here, you've very kind to me.
Don't worry.
You'll do great.
Good morning everyone.
As you know
today we're invading the Firenation.
I mean I know you know that because
otherwise why else would you be here?
Anyway...
The Firelord palace is here.
Uh, no, uh wait, uh wait,
uh wait, it's here.
There's an eclipse today
and Aang is gonna fight the Firelord.
And the firebenders
won't have any fire to use.
That's good for us.
I'm sorry, let me start
at the beginning.
Katara and I discovered Aang
frozen in an Iceberg.
Now I didn't like Aang at first
but I grew to love him over time.
Then we went to the southern air temple
where Aang used to live.
And then we met Suki as an Kaoshi warrior.
When he says the beginning
he means the beginning beginning.
Got Haru arrested
and now he's wearing a moustache
which you feel looking
at the front row, you can see it.
Thank you, Sokka. It's okay,
why don't you take a break?
Let me just clarify
a few points for everyone.
Today is the day of black sun.
And I want to thank you all
for your self sacrifice and your courage.
There are two steps to the invasion.
A naval stage and then a land stage.
To gain access to the Firenation capital
we have to get past
our first major obstacle here
The great gates of Azula.
Next, we hit the land and we hit hard.
We must fight past their battlements
and secure the plaza tower.
Once we do that,
it's up to the royal palace.
At that point the eclipse will begin.
- Excuse me, the boulder is confused.
Isn't the point
to invade during the eclipse,
when the firebenders are powerless?
The eclipse will only last eight minutes,
not enough time for the whole invasion.
And the royal palace
is heavily guarded by firebenders.
So, that's where we'll need
the eclipse advantage the most.
When this is finished,
the avatar will have defeated the Firelord.
We'll have control over the Firenation
capital and this war will be over.
We've been looking everywhere for you.
The boats are ready to leave.
I messed up Aang.
- What?
The invasionplan was my moment of truth.
And I completely flopped it.
I just fell apart.
That speech wasn't your moment of truth.
That was just public speaking.
And nobody is really good at that.
My dad is, he explained the perfectly
and inspired everyone.
Like a real leader should.
Your moment of truth isn't going to be
in front some map.
It is going to be out there,
on the battlefield.
You seem so confident about everything,
how do you know we're gonna to win?
Because I already failed the world
once at BaSing se.
I won't let myself fail again.
There they are, the great gates of Azula.
- I don't see any gates.
Katara, you and the swamp benders
whip up a fog cover.
We'll sneak by them statues just like
we sneaked by that fire navy blockade.
Keep it up, we’re almost through.
Everyone to low deck.
Let's hope your invention works.
No one is onboard, sir.
- Where did they go?
You really had done yourself
this time, son.
Yeah, congratulations, Sokka.
You managed to invent...
a worse way of traveling than flying.
Helmet?
I just came up with the idea.
The mechanist did all the work.
Don't sell yourself short, my boy.
It was your idea to use waterbending
to make the subs sink and float.
Brilliant, Though your original designs
were a bit difficult to decipher.
Unfortunately, there's one problem
I couldn't fix.
The subs have a limited air supply.
Before we land on the beaches
we'll need to resurface.
Lunch time, general Iroh.
And this time I brought you
an extra bowl of rice.
Thank you, Ming.
Your little gestures of kindness
have made my days in prison bearable.
I think you should take
the rest of the day off.
What?
- You don't look well.
Maybe you should go home and rest.
No, I feel fine.
Trust me, it is better
that you are not here this afternoon.
So, this is it.
Are you ready for the Firenation
to know the avatar is alive?
I'm ready.
I hope you kick
some serious Firelord but, twinkletoes.
Everyone, listen up. The next time
we resurface it will be on the beaches.
So stay alert and fight smart.
Now break time is over,
back in the subs.
Aang...
- Katara, I...
You go first.
We've been through
so many things together
and I've seen you grow up so much.
You're not that little goofy kid
I found in the iceberg anymore.
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
I'm really proud of you.
Everything is going to be different
after today, isn't it?
What if I don't come back.
- Aang, don't say that. Of course you...
Katara, what are you doing?
It's time to submerge.
What? Right, I'm on it.
I'm sorry, Mai.
What do you know?
It did come in handy.
Everyone in position.
Earthbenders, in your tanks.
This is going to be a rough ride.
Ready, the torpedo.
Launch!
We're a man dale.
Where a tornation is you!
Hey, you.
Where have you been?
Communing with nature.
It takes while to collect this much seaweed.
Dad, look out!
Sokka, we've got to take out
those battlements. It's our only chance.
I've got an idea.
You two take out that battlement.
I got this one. Watch each other’s backs.
Dad?
- Dad!
I know I've made some bad choices.
But today I'm gonna set things right.
How does that feel, Dad?
A little better,
I need to get back to the troops.
You're hurt, badly.
You can't fight anymore.
Everyone is counting on me
to lead this mission, Katara.
I won't let them down.
Can't you heal him any faster?
- I'm doing everything I can.
I'll do it.
No offence, Sokka. But you're not
exactly Mr. healing hands.
No, I'll lead the invasion force.
- Don't be crazy, Sokka.
Maybe I'm a little crazy,
but the eclipse is about to start...
and we need to be up the volcano
by the time it does.
You can do this.
I'm proud of you, Son.
I still think you crazy.
But I'm proud of you too.
Listen up everyone,
I want the tanks in wedge formation.
Warriors and benders in the middle.
We're taking that tower
and heading for the royal palace.
CHARGE!
That's strange.
The avatar is back!
Hello?
Anyone home?
The Firenation is falling back.
Sokka, we're on our way to victory.
No.
No, no, NO!
Firelord Ozai, where are you?
Dad!
You’re on your feet again.
Thanks to your sister.
I’m in no shape to fight
but maybe there is someway I could help.
Everything’s going smoothly
and the eclipse hasn’t even kicked in yet.
Let’s hope our luck holds out.
Katara, you seem distracted. Is something wrong?
Yeah…. Is that… is that Aang?
What?
Please tell you’re here because the Fire Lord turned out to be a
big wimp and you didn’t even need the eclipse to take him down
He wasn’t home. No one was.
The entire palace city is abandoned.
They knew.
Aang: It’s over.
The Fire Lord is probably long gone. Far away on some
remote island where he’ll be safe during the eclipse.
No. My instincts tell me he wouldn’t go too far.
He would have a secret bunker.
Somewhere he could go so it’ll be safe during a
siege but still be close enough to lead his nation.
If it’s an underground secret bunker we’re
looking for, I’m just the girl to find it.
The Mechanist gave me this timing device.
It looks like we’ve got about 10 minutes until the full eclipse.
10 minutes to find the Fire Lord.
We can still do this.
We can still win the day.
Wait. If they knew we were
coming, it could all be a trap.
Maybe we should use the time we have left to
make sure all of us get out of here safely.
Everyone who’s here today came prepared
to risk everything for this mission.
They know what’s at stake.
If there’s still a chance and there’s still hope,
I think they would want Aang to go for it.
What do you think?
You’re the one who has to face the Fire Lord.
Whatever you decide, I’m with you.
I’ve got to try.
Do you feel anything down there
Yep. There are natural tunnels criss-crossing
through the inside of the volcano.
Anything else?
Is there a structure somewhere?
There’s something big, dense, and made of
metal deep in the heart of the volcano.
Sokka: Sounds like a secret bunker to me.
Aang: Stay safe. We’ll be back soon.
Toph: This way! That one’s a dead end.
Sokka: What would we do without you?
Toph: Perish and burn in hot magma.
Yeah, pretty much.
Toph: The tunnel continues on the other
side and it leads right to the bunker.
Sokka: We’ll have to be fast but careful.
Aang: How was that careful?
Sokka: I was wrong.
We need to be fast, careful and lucky.
Sokka: There’s no floor!
It’s just a river of lava.
Aang: Climb aboard and hold on tight.
Sokka: That’s some door!
Not a problem.
I am so glad we added you to the group.
Retreat! Everyone move to secondary
defensive position! Retreat!
Bato: The eclipse is only minutes away.
We should be able to make it up the hill
by the time it starts
and secure the entire palace
by the time it’s finished!
We can wait here if you want.
No. I want to press
forward with the others.
War Minister Qin: The Fire Lord’s chamber is that way down
the hall to the left and up the stairs. You can’t miss it.
Thanks.
Sokka: Only 30 seconds
until the total eclipse.
I’m ready. I’m ready to face the Fire Lord.
Azula: So, you are alive after all.
I had a hunch that you survived.
It doesn’t matter, I’ve known
about the invasion for months.
I’m ready to face you.
Fire Lord Ozai: Prince Zuko,
what are you doing here?
The Mechanist: The eclipse is starting.
Put on your eclipse glasses.
Fire Lord Ozai: Why are you here?
I’m here to tell the truth.
Fire Lord Ozai: Telling the truth during the
middle of an eclipse. This should be interesting.
Zuko: First of all, in Ba Sing Se, it was
Azula who took down the Avatar, not me.
Fire Lord Ozai: Why would
she lie to me about that?
Zuko: Because the Avatar is not dead.
He survived.
What?!
Zuko: In fact, he probably is leading this invasion.
He could be on his way right now.
Get out! Get out of my sight right now
if you know what’s good for you.
That’s another thing.
I’m not taking orders from you anymore.
You will obey me
or this defiant breathe will be your last!
Think again! I am going to speak my
mind and you are going to listen.
Where is he? Where is the Fire Lord?
Hm, you mean I’m not good enough for you?
You’re hurting my feelings.
Stop wasting our time and
give us the information.
You’re powerless right now, so
you’re in no position to refuse.
And stick to the truth.
I’ll be able to tell if you’re lying.
Are you sure? I’m a pretty good liar.
I am a 400 foot tall purple platypus
bear with pink horns and silver wings
Okay you’re good, I admit it.
But you really ought to consider
telling the truth anyway.
When I left Ba Sing Se,
I brought home some souvenirs.
Dai Li agents.
Bato: Surround the periphery!
We have to secure the palace
by the time the eclipse is over.
Otherwise, we’ll be in for
the fight of our lives.
Tyro: Stop! Surrender peacefully
and we won’t harm you.
We’ll never surrender.
Er okay, we surrender.
Hakoda: There it is. The Fire Nation
royal palace. We’ve come so far.
It’s not over yet.
Zuko: For so long, all I wanted
was you to love me, to accept me.
I thought it was my honor that I wanted but
really, I was just trying to please you.
You, my father, who banished me
just for talking out of turn.
(points a sword at Ozai) My
father, who challenged me;
A 13-year-old boy to an Agni Kai.
How can you possibly justify
a duel with a child?
It was to teach you respect.
It was cruel! And it was wrong.
Then you have learned nothing.
No, I’ve learnt everything!
And I had to learn it on my own.
Growing up, we were taught that the Fire Nation
was the greatest civilization in history..
And somehow, the war was our way of sharing
our greatness with the rest of the world.
What an amazing lie that was. The people of
the world are terrified by the Fire Nation!
They don’t see our greatness, they hate us! And we deserve it.
We’ve created an era of fear in the world.
And if we don’t want the world to destroy itself, we
need to replace it with an era of peace and kindness.
(laughs mocking) Your Uncle
has gotten to you, hasn’t he?
Yes. He has.
I can’t pin her down. She’s too quick.
Wait! Aang, Toph, stop attacking.
Don’t you see what she’s doing?
She’s just playing with us.
She’s not even trying to win this fight!
Not true, I’m giving it my all.
You’re trying to keep us
here and waste all our time!
Um, right. I think your
friend just said that genius.
And since you can’t see, I should
tell you I’m rolling my eyes.
I’ll roll your whole head!
She’s just baiting you again.
Okay, so what do we do? Just ignore her?
We don’t have a choice.
We just have to get out of here and
find the Fire Lord on our own somehow.
It’s a trap. Don’t say I didn’t warn you.
Ignore!
So, Sokka’s your name right? My favorite
prisoner used to mention you all the time.
She was convinced that you
were going to come rescue her.
Of course, you never came
and she gave up on you.
Come and get it…
Where is Suki?!
Zuko: After I leave here today, I’m going
to free Uncle Iroh from his prison
and I’m going to beg for his forgiveness.
He is the one who has been a real father to me.
That’s just beautiful. Maybe he can pass
down to you the ways of tea and failure.
But I’ve come to an even
more important decision.
I’m going to join the Avatar.
And I’m going to help him defeat you.
Really? Since you’re a full blown traitor
now and you want me gone, why wait?
I’m powerless, you’ve got your swords,
why don’t you just do it now?
Because I know my own destiny.
Taking you down is the Avatar’s destiny.
(sheathes his swords) Goodbye.
Coward! You think you’re brave enough to face
me but you’ll only do it during an eclipse.
If you have any real courage, you’ll
stick around until the Sun comes out.
Don’t you want to know what
happened to your Mother?
What happened that night?
My father, Fire Lord Azulon, had commanded
me to do the unthinkable to you, my own son.
And I was going to do it. Your Mother had found
out and swore she would protect you at any cost.
She knew I wanted the throne
and she proposed a plan.
A plan in which I would become Fire
Lord and your life would be spared.
Where’s Suki? Answer me!
Sokka, she won’t talk.
Where are you keeping her?!
Your Mother did vicious,
treasonous things that night.
She knew the consequences and accepted them.
For her treason, she was banished.
So she’s alive.
Perhaps. Now I realize that banishment is far too merciful
a penalty for treason. Your penalty will be far steeper.
Oh. Sounds like the firebending’s back on.
Dad’s all the way at the end of the hall and down the secret stairway
on the left. I’m sure he’ll be more than happy to see you now.
Sokka: I fell for it!
I used up all our time.
It’s not your fault, Sokka. Azula was ready for us.
She had every move planned out.
And now it’s too late.
Maybe it’s not too late. The eclipse is
over but I can face the Fire Lord anyway.
No. I don’t think that’s a good idea.
But I’m ready! I came here with a job
to do and everyone’s counting on me.
The Fire Lord knew we
were coming this time.
We thought we had surprise
on our side but we didn’t.
It just wasn’t our day.
What we need to do now is go help our friends.
I guess you guys are right.
You’ll have another chance.
I know you will.
Bato: What should we do, Hakoda?
Shouldn’t something have happened by now?
I don’t know.
But now that the eclipse is over, I expect we’re
going to see some firebenders any minute.
The Mechanist: My own invention.
Oh this is terrible!
They’re back!
It was all a trap. Azula knew we were
coming and she’s plotted out every move.
We just got to get to the
beach as fast as we can.
If we can make it to the submarines,
maybe we can get away safely.
Aang: They’ve got air power, but so do I!
I’m going to do what I can to slow them down.
Katara: Appa, you and I can help too.
Everyone, let’s get back to the subs!
We can’t keep them all back.
They’re too many of them!
Let’s join the others.
Uncle!
Where is my Uncle?
Warden Poon: He’s gone.
He busted himself out.
I… I’ve never seen anything like it!
He was like a one man army!
Try and find cover!
I think we’re about to see some bombs.
Why aren’t they turning
around to attack us again?
They’re headed for the beach.
They’re going to destroy the submarines!
How are we all going to escape?
We’re not.
Then our only choice is to stand and fight.
We have the Avatar, we could still win!
Yes, with the Avatar we could
still win on another day.
You kids have to leave.
You have to escape on Appa together.
What? We can’t leave you behind.
We won’t leave anyone behind.
You’re our only chance in a long run.
You and Sokka have to go
with Aang somewhere safe.
It’s the only way to keep hope alive.
Bato: The youngest of our
group should go with you.
The adults will stay behind and surrender.
We’ll be prisoners but we’ll
all survive this battle.
Tyro: I’ve got some experience
with the Fire Nation prisons.
It’s not going to be easy but we’ll get by.
They’re at the beach already!
The Mechanist: Bye, son.
Teo: Bye, Dad. I’m really proud of you.
The Duke: I’ll miss you, Pipsqueak.
Pipsqueak: Take care, The Duke.
Haru: I’ll be back for you Dad.
Tyro: If we don’t escape on our own first.
We lost today but we’ve
never been this close.
We tasted victory and that
counts for something.
We’ll miss you Dad.
Bye Dad. We won’t be apart for
too long this time. I promise.
Thank you all for being so brave and so strong.
I’m going to make this up to you.
Captain: Should we follow them, Princess?
No. They’re too fast.
It doesn’t matter, they’ll be back.
I know just the place for us to go where we’ll
be safe for a while. The Western Air Temple.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk