Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the Fire nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar...
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great, ...
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
So, what's the new plan?
The new plan, is the old plan.
You just need to masters all four element and
confront the Fire Lord before the comet comes.
Where am I supposed
to get a firebending teacher.
Hello. Zuko here,
I think it's time I join your group...
and taught the avatar firebending.
And I know my destiny is to help you
restore balance to the world.
I think you're supposed to be
my firebending teacher.
Zuko: I know you're nervous, but remember… firebending
in and of itself is not something to fear.
Ok. Not something to fear.
But if you don't respect it, it'll chew you up
and spit you out like an angry komodo rhino!
Now show me what you've got.
Any amount of fire you can make.
Maybe I need a little more instruction.
Perhaps a demonstration?
Zuko: Good idea.
You might want to take a couple steps back.
What was that!? That was the worst
firebending I've ever seen!
I thought it was, nice.
Why is this happening?
- Maybe it's the altitude.
- Yeah, could be.
- Just breathe, and...
- That one kind of felt hot.
Don't patronize me.
You know what it's supposed to look like!
Sorry Sifu Hotman.
And stop calling me that!
Sokka: Hey, jerks. Mind if I watch
you two jerks do your jerk bending?
Get out of here!
Ok, take it easy. I was just kidding around.
Jerk bending, still got it.
Listen everybody; I've got some pretty bad news.
I've lost my stuff.
Don't look at me.
I didn't touch your stuff.
I'm talking about my firebending.
It's gone.
I'm sorry.
I'm just laughing at the irony.
You know… how it would have been nice for us
if you lost your firebending a long time ago?
Zuko: Well it's not lost.
It's just weaker for some reason.
Maybe you're just
not as good as you think you are.
Toph: Ouch.
I bet it's because I changed sides.
That's ridiculous.
Aang: I don't know. Maybe it isn't.
Maybe your firebending comes from rage...
..and you just don't have enough anger
to fuel it the way you used to.
So, all we need to do is make Zuko angry…
easy enough.
Ok, cut it out! Look…
even if you're right...
I don't want to rely on hate and anger anymore.
There has to be another way.
You're gonna need to learn to draw
your firebending from a different source.
I recommend the original source.
How's he supposed to do that?
By jumping into a volcano?
No. Zuko needs to go back to whatever
the original source of firebending is.
So is it jumping into a volcano?
I don't know. For earthbending,
the original benders were badgermoles.
One day, when I was little,
I ran away and hid in a cave.
That's where I met them.
They were blind, just like me...
so we understood each other.
I was able to learn earthbending...
not just as a martial art,
but as an extension of my senses.
For them, the original earthbenders,
it wasn't just about fighting.
It was their way of interacting with the World.
Aang: That's amazing, Toph. I learned from the monks,
but the original airbenders were the Sky Bison.
Maybe you can give me a
lesson sometime buddy.
Well, this doesn't help me.
The original firebenders were the dragons,
and they're extinct.
Aang: What do you mean? Roku had a dragon, and
there were plenty of dragons when I was a kid.
Well, they aren't around anymore, okay?
Ok, ok. I'm sorry.
Zuko: But maybe there's another way...
The first people to learn from the dragons
were the ancient Sun Warriors.
Sun Warriors? Well, I know they
weren't around when I was a kid.
No, they died off thousands of years ago, but their
civilization wasn't too far from where we are now.
Maybe we can learn something
by poking around their ruins.
It's like the monks used to tell me.
Sometimes, the shadows of the past can be felt by the present.
So, what?
Maybe you'll pick up some super old Sun Warrior energy
just by standing here they stood 1000 years ago?
Zuko: More or less. Either I find a new way to
firebend, or the Avatar has to find a new teacher.
We've been riding for hours. I don't know why,
but I thought this thing would be a lot faster.
Appa's right, Zuko. In our group, typically we start
out our missions with a more upbeat attitude.
Zuko: I can't believe this.
Aang: Don't worry.
You'll get the hang of it.
Whoa!
Zuko: Even though these buildings are ancient,
there's something eerily familiar about them.
I can tell the Fire Sages’ temples
are somehow descended from these.
Ok, we learned something
about architecture.
Hopefully, we'll learn something about firebending too.
The past can be a great teacher.
Zuko, I think the past
is trying to kill me.
I can't believe it. This booby trap
must be centuries old, and it still works.
Aang: There's probably a lot more.
Maybe this means we shouldn't be here.
Where's that upbeat attitude
you were talking about?
Besides, people don't make traps unless
they've got something worth protecting.
Look. This seems promising.
Though I'm not sure what this tells us
about the original source of firebending.
They look pretty angry to me.
Aang: I thought the dragons were
friends with the Sun Warriors.
Zuko: Well, they had a
funny way of showing it.
Zuko, something happened to the dragons in the last 100 years.
Something you're not telling me.
My great-grandfather Sozin happened.
Zuko: He started the tradition of hunting dragons for glory.
They were the ultimate firebenders.
And if you could conquer one, your firebending
talents would become legendary...
and you'd earn the
honorary title "Dragon".
The last great dragon was conquered
long before I was born, by my Uncle.
But I thought your Uncle
was, I don't know, good?
He had a complicated past.
Family tradition, I guess. Let's just move on.
It's locked up.
Wait. It's a celestial calendar.
Just like the Fire Sages have in their temples.
I bet that Sun Stone opens the door, but only when
sunlight hits it at just the right angle, on the solstice.
Monkey feathers! The solstice again?
We can't wait here that long.
No we can't.
But we might be able to speed time up.
Let's see if we can outsmart the Sun Stone.
Nothing's happening.
Come on...
You know, Zuko, I don't care what everyone
else says about you, you're pretty smart.
Relax. They're just statues.
It says this is something
called The Dancing Dragon.
Zuko, get over here.
I want you to dance with me.
- What?
- Just do it.
Let's follow the steps of the statues.
Aang: Don't you see? These aren't dance moves.
These statues are giving us a lesson.
I think this is some kind
of Sun Warrior firebending form.
This better teach us
some really good firebending.
Hurray! Wait.
What exactly is that?
It's some kind of mystical gem stone.
- Well, don't touch it!
- Why not?
Remember what happened
out there with those spikes?
I'm just very suspicious of giant,
glowing gems sitting on pedestals.
It feels almost alive.
Oh, no, it's another trap!
Ugh, I can't pull free.
It's like some kind of glue.
I can't move. Zuko, do something!
Me? I can't move either.
It stopped.
At least we have air. Maybe if we
stay calm we can figure a way out of this.
You had to pick up the glowing egg,
didn't you?
At least I made something happen. If it were up to
you, we'd never have made it pass the courtyard.
Help!
Who are you yelling to?
Nobody's lived here for centuries.
Well, what do you think we should do?
Think about our place in the Universe?
Sun Warrior Chief:
Who is down there?
For trying to take our Sun Stone,
you must be severely punished!
We didn't come here to take your Sun Stone.
We came here to find the ancient origin of all firebending.
Ham Gao: Yeah, right. They are obviously
thieves, here to steal Sun Warrior treasures.
Aang: Please, I don't normally
play this card, but... I'm the Avatar.
Just hear us out.
My name is Zuko, Crown Prince of the Fire Nation.
Or at least, I used to be.
I know my people have distorted
the ways of firebending...
to be fueled by anger and rage.
But now I want to learn the true way...
the original way.
When we came here, I never imagined
the Sun Warrior civilization was secretly alive.
I am truly humbled to be in your presence.
Please, teach us.
If you wish to learn the ways of the Sun, you
must learn them from the masters Ran and Shao.
Ran and Shao? There are two of them?
When you present yourselves to them, they will examine you.
They'll read your hearts, your souls, and your ancestry.
If they deem you worthy,
they'll teach you. If they don't,
you'll be destroyed on the spot.
Sun Warrior Chief:
If you're going to see the masters,
you must bring them a piece
of the eternal flame.
This fire is the very first one.
It was given to Man by the dragons.
We have kept it going
for thousands of years.
I don't believe it.
Sun Warrior Chief: You will each
take a piece of it to the masters...
to show your commitment to
the sacred art of firebending.
Um, Mister Sun Chief, sir?
Yeah... I'm not a firebender yet.
Couldn't my friend here
carry my fire for me?
No.
This ritual illustrates the essence of Sun Warrior philosophy.
You must maintain a constant heat.
The flame will go out if you make it too small.
Make it too big, and you might lose control.
I'm sorry. I'm just a little nervous.
It's like a little heartbeat.
Fire is life, not just destruction.
You will take your flames up there.
The cave of the masters
is beneath that rock.
- Hurry up.
- I can't.
If I walk too fast, my flame will go out.
Your flame's gonna go out because it's too small.
You're too timid. Give it more juice.
But what if I can't control it?
You can do it.
I know you can. You're a talented kid.
Facing the judgment of the firebending masters
will be very dangerous for you. Your ancestors
are directly responsible for the dragon's disappearance.
The masters might not be so happy to see you.
Ham Gao: I know I wouldn't be.
But once they find out I'm the Avatar...
Have you forgotten that you vanished allowing the Fire Nation to wreak
havoc on the world? The decline of the dragons is your burden too.
We could turn back now. We've already
learned more about fire than we hoped.
No, we're seeing this through to the end. We're gonna meet
these masters and find out what's so great about them.
What if they judge us and attack us?
Well, we're the Fire Prince and the Avatar.
I think we can take these guys in a fight, whoever they are.
- Bring 'em out.
- Chanters!
Sun Warrior: Those who wish to meet the masters
Ran and Shao will now present their fire.
Sun Warrior Chief: Sound the call.
What's happening?
- Zuko, my fire went out.
- What do you want me to do?
Give me some of yours.
- No, just make your own.
- I can't.
Get some from one of those warriors.
Hurry. Stop cheating off me!
Quit being stingy!
- These are the masters.
- You still think we can take 'em?
Shh. I never said that.
Oh, here it comes.
Any moment now… dinner for the masters.
- Quiet, Ham Gao.
- What? Everyone's thinking it.
Zuko, I think we're supposed
to do The Dragon Dance with them.
What? What about this situation
that you think they want us to dance?
Well, I think they want us
to do something. Let’s just try it.
Fine.
Judgment time.
I understand.
Their fire was beautiful.
I saw so many colors, colors I've never imagined.
Aang: Like firebending harmony.
Sun Warrior Chief: Yes. They judged you, and
gave you visions of the meaning of firebending.
I can't believe there are still living dragons.
My Uncle Iroh said he faced the last dragon and killed it.
So, your Uncle lied.
Actually, it wasn't a total lie. Iroh was the last outsider to face the masters.
They deemed him worthy and passed the secret onto him as well.
He must have lied to protect them,
so no one else would hunt them.
All this time,
I thought firebending was destruction.
Since I hurt Katara, I've been too afraid and hesitant.
But now I know what it really is… it's energy, and life.
Zuko: Yeah. It's like the Sun, but inside of you.
Do you guys realize this?
Well, our civilization is
called the Sun Warriors… so yeah.
That's why my firebending was so weak before.
Because for so many years, hunting you was my drive…
it was my purpose. So when I joined
you, I lost sight of my inner fire.
But now, I have a new drive. I have to help you
defeat my father and restore balance to the world.
Now that you have learned the secrets,
and you know about our tribe's existence,
we have no choice but to imprison you here forever.
Just kidding. But seriously, don't tell anyone!
Aang: With this technique the dragons
showed us, Zuko and I would be unstoppable.
Sokka: Yeah, that's a great
dance you two learned there.
It's not a dance. It's a firebending form.
We'll just tap-dance our
way to victory over the Fire Lord.
It's a sacred form that happens
to be thousands of years old!
- Oh yeah? What's your little form called?
- The Dancing Dragon.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk