Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the Fire nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A handred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar...
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
You have no idea what this
war has put me through.
Me personally.
The Fire nation took my
mother away from me.
I'm sorry.
You might have everyone else here
buying your "transformation",
but you and I both know you've struggled
with doing the right thing in the past.
So let me tell you something right now.
You make one step backward, one slip up, give
me one reason to think you might hurt Aang,
and you won't have to worry
about your destiny anymore.
Watch out!
What are you doing?!
Keeping rocks from crushing you.
Okay, I’m not crushed.
You can get off me now.
I’ll take that as a thank you.
Come on,
we can get out through here!
What are you doing?
Go ahead, I’ll hold them off.
I think this is a family visit.
Zuko, no!
Come on,
we gotta get out of here.
What are you doing here?
You mean it’s not obvious yet?
I’m about to celebrate
becoming an only child!
I can’t get him to go in there.
Appa hates tunnels.
Aang, there’s no way
we can fly out of here.
We’ll have to find a way.
We need to split up.
Take the tunnel and get to the stolen airship.
No, the fire nation
can’t separate our family again.
It’ll be okay,
it’s not forever.
I can clear that away
and we can fly out through there.
Umm, there’s an awful
lot of fire in that general direction.
We’ll get through, let’s go.
She’s not going to make it.
Of course she did.
Wow, camping. It really seems
like old times again, doesn’t it?
If you really want to
feel like old times, I could, uhh…
chase you around a
while and try to capture you.
Haha.
To zuko. Who knew after all those times he
tried to snuff us out, today, he be our hero.
Here, here.
I’m touched.
I don’t deserve this.
Yeah, no kidding.
- What’s with her?
- I wish I knew.
What’s with him?
This isn’t fair. Everyone else seems
to trust me now. What is it with you?
Oh, everyone trust you know?
I was the first person to
trust you, remember? Back in ba sing se.
And you turned around and
betrayed me. Betrayed all of us.
What can I do to make it up to you?
You really want to know?
Hmm, maybe you could re-conquer
ba sing se in the name of the earth king.
Or, I know.
You could bring my mother back.
Opps, wrong tent.
Sorry.
Do you need to talk to sokka too?
Nope. Not me.
Well, hellooo.
Uh, zuko. Yes, why would
I be expecting any one different?
So what’s on your mind?
Your sister, she hates
me and I don’t know why!
But I do care
what she thinks of me.
Nah, she doesn’t hate you.
Katara doesn’t hate anyone.
Except maybe some
people in the fire nation.
No, I mean, uh, not people who are good
but used to be bad. I mean, bad people.
Fire nation people who are so bad, who have
never been good and probably won’t be ever!
Stop. Okay, listen.
I know this may seem out of nowhere,
but I want you to tell me
what happened to your mother.
What?
Why would you want to know that?
Katara mentioned it before when we were
imprisoned together in ba sing se...
And again just now
when she was yelling at me.
I think somehow… she’s connected
her anger about that to her anger at me.
It’s not a day
I like to remember.
I’m going to find mum.
Many of the warriors have seen the black
snow before and they knew what it meant.
A fire nation raid.
We were badly outnumbered.
But somehow, we managed to drive them off.
As quickly as they came,
they just left.
I was so relieved
when it was over but,
that’s because I didn’t
know yet what have happened.
I didn’t know
we lost our mother.
Wait. Can you remember any details
about the soldiers who raided your village?
Like,
what the lead ship looked like?
Yeah… sea ravens. The main ship had
flags with sea ravens on them.
The symbol of the Southern raiders.
Thanks, sokka.
No problem.
Thanks for stopping by.
Thought he never leave.
Suki.
You look terrible.
I waited out here all night.
What do you want?
I know who killed your mother.
I’m going to help you find him.
I need to borrow appa.
Why? Is it your turn to
take a little fieldtrip with zuko?
Yes, it is.
Oh. What’s going on?
We’re going to find the
man who took my mother from me.
Sokka told me the story of what happened.
I know who did it. And I know how to find him.
Umm… and what exactly
do you think this would accomplish?
I knew you wouldn’t understand.
Wait, stop, I do understand.
You’re feeling unbelievable pain and rage.
How do you think I felt about
the sandbenders when they stole appa?
How do you think I felt about the fire nation
when I found out what happened to my people?
She needs this, aang.
This is about getting closure and justice.
I don’t think so.
I think it’s about getting revenge.
Fine! Maybe it is. Maybe that’s what I need.
Maybe that’s what he deserves.
Katara, you sound like jet.
It’s not the same.
Jet attacked the innocent.
This man, he’s a monster.
Katara, she was my mother too.
But I think aang might be right.
Then you didn’t
love her the way I did.
Katara…
the monks used to say that
revenge is like a two-headed ratviper.
While you watch your enemy go down,
you’re being poisoned yourself.
That’s cute. But this isn’t
air temple pre-school. It’s the real world.
Now that I know he’s out there,
now that I know we could find him,
I feel like I have no choice.
Katara, you do have a choice.
Forgiveness.
That’s the same as doing nothing.
No it’s not. It’s easy to do nothing.
But it’s hard to forgive.
It’s not just hard,
it’s impossible.
So you were just
going to take appa anyway?
Yes.
It’s okay, because I forgive you.
That give you any ideas?
Don’t try to stop us.
I wasn’t planning to.
This is a journey you need to take.
You need to face this man.
But when you do,
please don’t choose revenge.
Let your anger out
and then let it go. Forgive him.
Okay, we’ll be sure
to do that guru-goody-goody.
Thanks for understanding aang.
Yip yip.
You know,
you’re pretty wise for a kid.
Thanks, sokka.
Usually it’s annoying but right now,
I’m just impressed.
I appreciate that.
So…
can I borrow momo for a week?
Why do you need momo?
We need to find the
fire navy communication tower.
All the navy’s movements
are coordinated by messenger hawk.
And every tower has to be
up to date on where everyone is deployed.
So once we find the communication tower, we
bust in and take the information we need.
Not exactly. We need to be
stealthy and make sure no one spots us.
Otherwise, they’ll warn the Southern raiders.
Long before we reach them.
Okay, Southern raiders.
There.
On patrol near whale tail island.
Whale tail island, here we come.
You should get some rest.
We’ll be there in a few hours.
You’ll need all your strength.
Now, don’t you worry
about my strength. I have plenty.
I’m not the helpless
little girl I was when they came.
I’m going to find mum.
Mum!
Just let her go
and I’ll give you the information you want.
You heard your mother, get out of here!
Mum, I’m scared.
Go find your dad, sweetie.
I’ll handle this.
I ran as fast as I could.
Dad! Dad! Please, I think mum’s
in trouble! There’s a man in our house.
Kya!
But, we were too late. When we got there,
the man was gone. And so was she.
Your mother was a brave woman.
I know.
There! See those sea raven flags?
It’s the Southern raiders.
Let’s do this.
So there I was and
I was like, you know, you could…
this is it, katara.
Are you ready to face him?
Who are you?
You don’t remember her?
You will soon. Trust me.
What?
What’s happening to me?
Think back. Think back to your
last raid on the Southern water tribe.
I don’t know what you’re
talking about. Please, I don’t know!
Don’t lie! You look her in the eye and you
tell me you don’t remember what you did.
It’s not him.
He’s not the man.
What?! What do you mean he’s not?
He’s a leader of the Southern raiders!
He has to be the guy!
If you’re not the man
we’re looking for, who is?
You must be looking for yon rha.
He retired 4 years ago.
Yon rha,
you lazy piece of work, I need something.
Yes mother, what is it?
The tomato-carrot
from your garden are too hard for my gums.
I need something soft and juicy.
Would you like something else
from the garden? I would be happy to…
forget your stupid garden!
Get your grimy hind to the
market and buy me some real food!
Hello?
Did you see someone?
Hello? Is someone there?
That was him.
That was the monster.
Nobody sneaks up
on me without being burned.
We weren’t behind the bush.
And I wouldn’t try firebending again.
Whoever you are, take my money.
Take whatever you want, I’ll cooperate.
Do you know who I am?
No, I’m not sure.
Oh you better remember me like your life depends on it!
Why don’t you take a closer look.
Yes, yes. I remember you now.
You’re the little water tribe girl.
Just let her go and I’ll
give you the information you want.
You heard your mother,
get out of here!
Mum, I’m scared.
Go find your dad, sweetie.
I’ll handle this.
Now, tell me. Who is it?
Who’s the waterbender?
There are no waterbenders here. The fire
nation took them all away a long time ago.
You’re lying. My source says there’s one
waterbender left in the Southern water tribe.
We’re not leaving until
we find the waterbender.
If I tell you, do you promise
to leave the rest of the village alone?
It’s me.
Take me as your prisoner.
I’m afraid
I’m not taking prisoners today.
She lied to you.
She was protecting the last waterbender.
What? Who?
Me!
I did a bad thing.
I know I did and you deserve revenge.
So why don’t you take my mother?
That would be fair.
I always wonder what kind
of person could do such a thing.
But now that I see you,
I think I understand.
There’s just nothing inside you. Nothing at all.
You’re pathetic and sad and empty.
Please spare me.
But as much as I hate you…
I just can’t do it.
Katara! Are you okay?
I’m doing fine.
Zuko told me what you did.
Or… what you didn’t do, I guess. I’m proud of you.
I wanted to do it. I wanted to take out
all my anger at him but, I couldn’t.
I don’t know if it’s because I’m too weak to do
it or if it’s because I’m strong enough not to.
You did the right thing. Forgiveness is the
first step you have to take to begin healing.
But I didn’t forgive him.
I’ll never forgive him.
But I am ready to forgive you.
You were right about what
katara needed. Violence wasn’t the answer.
It never is.
Then I have a question for you.
What are you going
to do when you face my father?
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk