Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the fire nation attacked
only the avatar, master of
all four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar.
An airbender named aang.
And although his airbending skills are great, he has
a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe, aang
can save the world.
Ember island is a magical place.
Doesn't you family have a
house on ember island?
We used to come every
summer when we were kids.
That was a long time ago.
Like waves washing away
footprints on the sand,
ember island gives everyone a clean slate.
Ember island reveales a true "you".
Does it seem kinda weird that we're
hiding from a firelord in his own house?
I told you, my father
hasn't come there since
mine family was actually happy.
And that was a long time ago.
It's a last place everyone
will think to look for us.
You, guys, are not gonna believe this!
There is a play about us.
We were just in town
when found this poster.
What? How is that possible?
Listen to this:
"The boy in the iceberg" is a new production
from acclaimed playwriter pu wang ten.
He scattered the globe gathering
information on the avatar.
From the icy south pole
to the heart of ba sing se.
The sources include singing nomads,
pirates, prisoners of war
and a surprisingly knowledgable
merchant of cabbage.
Brought you by the critically-acclaimed
ember island players.
My mother used to take me to see them.
They butchered "love amongst
the dragons" every year.
Sokka do you really think
it's a good idea for us
to attend a play about ourselves?
Come on! A day in a theater?
It's the kind of wacky,
time-wasting nonsense
I've been missing!
Hey, ehm...
I wanted to sit there.
Just sit next to me.
What's the big deal?
I was just a... I wanted to...
Okay...
Why are we sitting in a nose-bleed section?
My feet can't see a thing from up here!
Don't worry,
I'll tell your feet what's happening.
Sokka,
my only brother!
We constantly roam these
icy south pole seas
and yet never do we find anything...
Fulfilling.
All I want is fullfiling in my stomach
- I'm starving!..
Is food the only thing on your mind?
Well, I kinda try to get it out of my mind
and into in my nouth
- I'm starving!..
This is pathetic!..
My jokes are way better than this!
I think he's got your paint!
Everyday the world awaits
a beacon to guide us.
Yet none appears.
Still, we cannot give up hope
- for hope is all we have!
We must never relinquish it
it, even to our dying breath...
Well, that's just silly.
I don't sound like that.
Oh, man this writer is a genius!
It appears to be someone frozen in ice...
Perhaps for a hundred years.
But who?
Who is the boy in the iceberg?
Waterbend! Hiya!..
Who are you, frozen boy?
I am the avatar, silly!
And I am here to spread is joy and fun!
Wait, is that a woman playing me?
An airbender...
My heart is so full of hope,
so it makes me tearbend!
My stomach is so empty,
so it's making me tearbend!
I need meat!
But wait,
is that a platter of meaty-dumpling?
Oh, where, where?
Did I mention that I am
an incurable prankster?
I don't do that!
That's not what I am like!
And I am not a woman!
Oh, they nailed you, twinkletoes!
Prince zuko, you must try this cake.
I don't have to time to stuff my face.
- I must capture the avatar
and regain mine honour!
Maybe while you do that,
maybe I'll capture another slice?
You're sickening me!
They make me look totally
stiff and humorless.
Actually I think that
this actor is pretty spot-on.
How could you say that?..
Let's forget about the
avatar and get massages!
How could you say that?..
Hey, look. I think I found something.
It's flying rabbit-monkey!
I think I'll name it - momo!
Hi, everybody! I luv u!
Does this dress make my butt look fat?
Riddles and challenges must you face,
if you're ever to leave this place!
Why did you had to steal
that waterbending scroll?
It just gave me so much hope!
The avatar is mine!
Wait, who's coming?
I am the blue spirit,
scourge of the fire nation
to save the avatar!
My hero!
Don't cry, baby!
Jet will wipe out this nasty town for you!
Oh, jet you're so-o ba-ad.
Look, it's the great divide
- the biggest canyon in the earth kingdom!
Eh, let's keep flying!
Don't go yue,
you're the only woman who's
ever taking my mind out of food!
Wait, did you ate pickle-fish at dinner?
Goodbye, sokka.
I have important moon
duties to take care of.
And yes.
And yes I did had pickle-fish...
You never told that you
made out with the moon spirit.
Shh!.. I am trying to watch.
The avatar is back to save the day!
Yay!...
So far, this intermission
is the best part of the play.
Apparently the playwriter thinks I'm an idiot
who tells bad jokes about meat all the time.
Yeah, you tell bad jokes
about plenty of other topics.
I know.
At least this sokka actor
kinda looks like you.
But that woman playing avatar
doesn't resemble me at all.
I don't know. You are more in touch
with your feminine side than most guys.
Relax, aang,
they're not accurate portrayals.
It's not like I am a preachy cry-baby
who can't resist giving emotional
speeches about hope all the time.
Yeah, that's not you at all.
Listen, friends.
It's obvious that this
playwriter did his research.
I know it must hurt.
What are you seeing up there
on that stage is the truth.
Well, here we are in the earth kingdom.
I better have a look around to see
if I can find an earthbending teacher
this is it.
This is must be where I come in.
I flew all over town
but couldn't find a single
earthbending master.
Here it comes.
You can't find an earthbending
master in the sky,
you have to look underground.
Who're you?
My name is toph.
Because it sounds like 'tough'.
And that's just what I am.
Wait a minute - I sound like
a guy,
a really buff guy.
Well, toph, what you here
up there is the truth.
It hurts, doesn't it?
Are you kidding me?
I wouldn't have casted it any other way!
At least it's not a flying bulb lady.
So,
you're blind?
I can see you doing that.
I see everything that you see.
Except I don't see like you do.
I release a sonic wave from my mouth.
There,
I've got a pretty good look at you.
Zuko, it's time we had a talk.
About your hair!
It's going too far!
Maybe it's best if we split up.
Azula, my sister, what are you doing here?
You caught me,
wait, what's that?
I think it's your honour!
Where?
She escaped,
but how?
If she continues drilling.
This wall will come down for sure.
Yes, continue drilling.
The city of ba sing se
can't hide no longer.
Oh, jet, what have they do to you?
Must. Server. Earth. King.
Must. Destroy!
Did jet just ... die?
You know it was really unclear.
I have to admit, prince zuko.
I really find you attractive.
You don't have to make fun of me.
I mean it.
I had eyes at you, since
the day you first captured me.
Wait! I thought you were the avatar's girl.
The avatar, why, he's
like a little brother to me!
I certainly don't think
of him in a romantic way.
Besides, how can he ever find out about...
This!
Oh, you're getting up.
Can you get me some fire-flakes?
Oh, and fire-gummies.
Well, my brother.
What it's going to be?
Your nation,
or life of treachury?
Choose treachury - it's more fun!
No way!
I hate you, Uncle!
You smell!
And I hate you for all time!
You didn't really said that, did you?
I might as well have.
Avatar state, yip-yip!
No, if my lightning can help it!
The avatar is no more!
It seems everytime there is a big
battle you, guys, barely make it out alive.
I mean, you guys, lose a lot.
You wanted to talk, suki.
Didn't azula take you captive?
That's right - she did.
Are you're trying to get on mine bad side?
I am just saying.
Does anyone know where aang is?
You left to get me fire-
gummies, like ten minutes ago.
I am still waiting!
I am gonna check outside.
Are you allright?
No, I am not!
I hate this play!
I know it's upsetting.
But it sounds like you're overreacting.
Overreacting?
If hadn't blocked my chakra I would
probably been in a avatar state right now!
Suki!
What are the chance that
you can get me backstage?
I got some jokes I want
to give to the actor 'me'.
I am an elite warrior, who's trained
many years in a art of stealth.
I can get you backtsage.
Jeez, everyone been so
upset about their characters.
Even you seem down more than usual.
And that's saying something.
You've got a muscly version of yourself
taking down a ten bad guys at once,
making sassy remarks.
Yeah, that's pretty great.
But for me,
it takes all the mistakes
I made in my life,
and shoves them back in my face.
Mine Uncle.
His always been on mine side,
even when things were bad.
He was there for me.
He taught me so much.
And how do I repay him?
With a knife in his back!
It's my greatest regret.
And I may never get to redeem myself.
You have redeemed yourself to your Uncle.
You don't realise it, but you already have.
How do you know?
Because I once had a long
conversation with the guy,
and all he would talk about was you.
Really?
Yeah,
and it was kind of annoying.
Sorry.
But it was also very sweet.
All your Uncle wanted,
was for you to find your own path,
and see the light.
Now you're here with us.
He'd be proud.
What was that for?
That's how I show affection.
Your zuko costume is pretty good.
But the scar is on the wrong side.
The scar is not on the wrong side!
He's coming this way.
Can I help you?
Actually, I think I can help you.
I am a big sokka fan, but I don't
think you represent him
just as well as you could be.
Oh, no - another fan with ideas...
Just hear me out.
Here is something I think
real sokka would say:
"What does the cabbage merchant
use to fix his cabbages?"
A cabbage patch!
That's actually pretty good,
let me see those.
Rocky relationship?..
Not bad!
Also, don't be afraid to
make up some phrases.
Especially before an attack.
Something like ...
Fliyng kick-a-pow!
Who are you, anyway?
I'm just a guy who likes comedy.
Katara,
did you really mean what you said in there?
Where?
What are you talking about?
On stage.
When you said I was just like a
brother to you.
And you don't have feelings for me.
I didn't say that.
Actor said that.
Bit it's true, isn't it?
We kissed at the invasion.
And I thought we're gonna be together.
But we're not.
Aang,
I don't know.
Why don't you know?
Because we're in the middle of the war.
And we have other things to worry about.
This isn't the right time.
Well, when is the right time?
Aang, I'm sorry, but
right now I'm just a little confused.
I just said I'm confused.
I'm going inside.
Argh, I'm such an idiot.
Here is what you missed.
We went to the fire nation,
and you got better,
katara was a painted lady,
and I got a sword, and
I think combustion man died.
Oh, look - the invasion is about to start.
I just wanted to let you know, aang,
that I'll always love you...
Like a brother.
I wouldn't wanted any other way.
Hey, toph.
Would you say you and aang have a
"rocky relationship"?
I told him to that!
I hope everyone's ready for the invasion.
Slop-a-pow!
We finally made it to the royal palace.
But noone's home.
Actually I am home.
And I want to join you!
I guess we have no choice.
I guess that's it. The play's
caught up to the present now.
Wait, the play is not over.
It is over... unless...
This is the future!
With the energy harnesses from that comet.
Noone will be able to stop
the fire nation!
Father, zuko and the
avatar are at the palace!
They are trying to stop you!
You take care of zuko,
I shall face the avatar
myself.
Aang,
you fight the firelord,
I'll hold her off!
You are no longer my brother!
You are an enemy.
No-o, I am the rightful heir to the throne!
Will see.
Honour!!!
So, you have mastered all four elements?
Yeah, and now you're going down!
No, it is you who are going down.
You see you are too late...
the comet is already here,
and I am unstoppable!
No-o-o-o!
It is over, father.
We've done it.
Yes,
we have done it!
The dream of mine father
and mine father's father
have now been realised.
A world... is... mine...
That wasn't a good play.
All say.
No kidding.
Horrible.
You said it.
But the effects were decent.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk