Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long Ago, The four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elments, could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
Previously on Avatar...
What happened generations ago,
can be resolved now.
Born in you is the power to
restore balance to the world.
You see you are too late,
the comet is already here
and I'm unstoppable!
You were right about what Katara needed,
violence wasn't the answer.
It never is.
Then I have a question for you:
What are you going to do
when you face my father?
More ferocious!
Imagine striking through
your opponent's heart!
I'm trying!
Now, let me hear you
roar like a tiger-dillo!
That sounded pathetic!
I said "roar!"
Who wants a nice cool
glass of watermelon juice?
Oh, me, me, me!
Hey! Your lesson
is not over yet!
Get back here!
Come on, Zuko. Just take a break.
What's the big deal?
Fine!
If you want to lounge around like
a bunch of snails all day,
then go ahead!
Maybe Zuko's right.
Sitting around the house
made us pretty lazy.
But I know just the thing to change that:
Beach Party!
It's you!
We kissed at the invasion.
But I've been working on
my sandbending.
You're gonna love this.
You even made a little
Earth King and Bosco.
Try to top that, Sokka!
Is that a blubbering blob-monster?
No! It's Suki!
Suki, we'll all understand if you
break up with him over this.
I think it's sweet.
But it doesn't even look like...
What are you doing?
Teaching you a lesson!
What happened?
Zuko's gone crazy!
I made a sand sculpture
of Suki and he destroyed it!
Oh, and he's attacking Aang.
Get a grip before I blast
you off this roof!
Go ahead and do it!
Enough!
What's wrong with you?
You could've hurt Aang!
What's wrong with me? What's
wrong with all of you!?
How can you sit around
having beach parties
when Sozin's Comet is
only three days away?
Why are you all looking
at me like I'm crazy?
About Sozin's Comet...
I was actually gonna wait to
fight the Fire Lord
until after it came.
- After?
- I'm not ready.
I need more time to master firebending.
And, frankly, your earthbending
still could use some work too.
So, you all knew Aang
was gonna wait?
Honestly, if Aang tries to fight
the Firelord right now,
he's gonna lose. No offense.
The whole point of fighting
the Firelord before the comet
was to stop the Fire Nation
from winning the war.
But they pretty much won the war
when they took Ba Sing Se.
Things can't get any worse.
You're wrong.
It's about to get worse than
you can even imagine.
The day before the eclipse,
my father asked me to attend
an important war meeting.
It was what I dreamed about and
wanted for so many years.
My father had finally accepted me back.
Welcome, Prince Zuko.
We waited for you.
General Shinu, your report.
Thank you, sir.
Ba Sing Se is still under
our control, however,
Earthbender rebellions have prevented
us from achieving
achieving a total victory in the Earth Kingdom.
What is your recommendation?
Our army is spead too thin,
but once the eclipse is over
and the invasion defeated,
we should transfer more domestic
forces into the Earth Kingdom.
Prince Zuko, you've been among the
Earth Kingdom commoners,
do you think that adding more troops
will stop these rebellions?
The people of the Earth Kingdom
are proud and strong.
They can endure anything,
as long as they have hope.
Yes, you're right.
We need to destroy their hope.
Well, that's not exactly what I...
I think you should take
their precious hope,
and the rest of their land, and
burn it all to the ground.
Yes, yes, you're right, Azula.
Sozin's Comet is almost upon us.
And on that day, it will lend us the
strength and power of a hundred suns.
No bender will stand a chance against us.
What are you
suggesting, sir?
When the comet last came, my
grandfather, Fire Lord Sozin,
used it to wipe out the air nomads.
Now, I will use its power to end
the Earth Kingdom,
permanently.
From our airships, we will
rain fire over their lands.
The fire that will
destroy everything!
And out of the ashes,
a new world will be born.
A world in which all the
lands will be Fire Nation
and I am the supreme ruler
of everything!
I wanted to speak out
against this horrifying plan,
but ashamed to say
that I didn't.
My whole life I struggled to gain
my father's love and acceptance.
But once I had it,
I realized I lost myself
getting there.
I forgotten who I was.
I can't believe this.
I always knew the Firelord
was a bad guy,
but his plan is just pure evil!
What am I gonna do?
I know you're scared.
And I know you're not
ready to save the world.
But if you don't defeat the Firelord
before the comet comes,
there won't be a world
to save anymore.
Why didn't you tell me about
your dad's crazy plan sooner?
I didn't think I had to.
I assumed you were still gonna
fight him before the comet.
No one told me you
decided to wait.
This is bad, this is
really, really bad!
Aang, you don't have
to do this alone.
Yeah! If we all have to fight
the Firelord together,
we got a shot at
taking him down!
Alright! Team
Avatar is Back!
Air, Water,
Earth, Fire,
Fan, and Sword!
Fighting the Firelord is gonna be the
hardest thing we've ever done together.
But I wouldn't wanna do it
any other way.
- Yeah!
- Alright!
Get over here, Zuko.
Being part of the group also means
being part of the group hugs.
There's one technique you need
to know before facing my father.
How to redirect lightning.
If you let the energy in your body
flow, lightning will follow it,
and you turn your opponent's
energy against them.
- That's like waterbending.
- Exactly.
My uncle invented
this technique himself
by studying waterbenders.
So...have you ever redirected
lightning before?
Once.
Against my father.
What did it feel like?
Exilirating.
But terrifying.
You feel so powerful holding that
much energy in your body,
but you know if you make
the wrong move, it's over.
Well, not over-over, I mean...
There is always Katara and
a little spirit water action,
am I right?
Actually, I used it all
up after Azula shot you.
You'll have to take the Firelord's
life, before he takes yours.
Yeah, I'll just do that.
Gather around, Team Avatar.
In order to take out the Firelord,
or in this case, the Melonlord,
our timing has to be perfect.
First, Suki and I will
draw his fire.
Then, Katara and Zuko charge in
with some liquidy hot offence,
and while the Melonlord
is distracted,
Aang swoopes in and BAM!
He delivers the final blow.
Ehm, what about me?
For now, you're the
Melonlord's forces.
So I get to chuck flaming
rock at all of you?
Whatever makes the training
field more realistic.
Sweetness!
Watch it, Toph!
I'm no Toph,
I AM MELONLORD!
Now, Aang!
What are you waiting for?
Take him out!
I can't.
What's wrong with you?
If this was the real deal, you'd
be shot full of lighting right now.
I'm sorry. But it just
doesn't feel right.
I didn't feel like myself.
There. That's that how it's done.
I have a surprise
for everyone!
I knew it! You did have a
secret thing with Haru!
Ah, no.
I was looking for cooking pots in
the attic and I found this.
Look at baby Zuko!
Isn't he cute?
Oh lighten up, I'm
just teasing.
That's not me.
It's my father.
But he looks so sweet
and innocent.
That sweet little kid grew
up to be a monster.
And the worst father in
the history of fathers.
But he's still a
human being.
You're going to defend him?
No, I agree with you.
Firelord Ozai is
a horrible person,
and the world will probably
be better off without him,
but there's got to
be another way.
Like what?
I don't know.
Maybe we can make some big pots
of glue and then I can use
gluebending to stick his arms and legs
together so he can't bend anymore!
Yeah, then you can show
him his baby pictures
and all these happy memories
will make him good again!
Do you really think
that will work?
No!
This goes against everything
I learned from the monks.
I can't just go around wiping
out people I don't like.
Sure you can.
You're the Avatar!
If it's in the name of
keeping balance,
I'm sure the universe
will forgive you.
This isn't a joke, Sokka!
None of you understands
the position I'm in!
- Aang, we do understand. It's just..
- Just what, Katara?
- What?
- We're trying to help!
Then why don't you figure out a way
for me to defeat the Firelord
without taking his life,
I'd love to hear it!
Aang, don't walk
away from this.
Let him go.
He needs time to sort
it out by himself.
Hey, Momo. I don't suppose
you know what I should do.
I didn't think so.
Okay, that's everything.
No it's not, where's Aang?
Aang?
- Aang?
- Come on, lazy bones, let's go!
He left his staff.
It's so strange.
Aang's not in the house,
let's check the beach.
Look! There's
his footprints.
The trail ends here.
So, he went for a midnight
swim and never came back?
- Maybe he was captured.
- I don't think so.
I don't think so.
I bet he ran away again.
He left his glider and Appa.
Then what do you think
happened, oh, sloozy one?
It's pretty obvious.
Aang mysteriously disappears
before an important battle.
He's definitely in a
spirit world journey.
But if he was, wouldn't
his body still be here?
Oh, yeah, forgot about that.
Then he's gotta be somewhere
on Ember Island,
let's split up and look for him.
I'm going with Zuko.
What? Everyone else went on a
life-changing field-trip with Zuko.
Now it's my turn!
Aang! Aang! Aang!
Aang! Aang!
Avatar State, Yip Yip!
And when I was 9,
I ran away again.
I know I should complain.
My parents gave me
everything I ever asked for.
But they never gave me the one
thing that I really wanted.
Their love.
You know what I mean?
Look, I know you had a rough childhood,
but we should really focus
on finding Aang.
This is the worst
field trip ever.
Judging by the looks
on your faces,
I'm guessing you guys
didn't find Aang either.
No, it's like he
just... disappeared.
Hey, wait a minute,
has anyone noticed that
Momo is missing too?
Oh, no! I knew it was
only a matter of time!
Appa ate Momo!
Momo! I'm coming for you, buddy!
Sokka, Appa didn't eat Momo.
He's probably with Aang.
That's just what Appa
wants you to think.
Get out of the bison's
mouth, Sokka.
We have a real problem here.
Aang is nowhere to be found and
the comet is only two days away.
What should we do, Zuko?
I don't know.
Why are you all
looking at me?
Well, you are kind of the
expert on tracking Aang.
Yeah, if anyone's got experience
hunting the Avatar,
it's you.
Zuko, I don't want to tell
you how to do your job,
but why are we heading
to the Earth Kingdom?
There's no way Aang's there.
Just trust me.
Come on, slowpokes,
faster!
Sorry I'm late, father.
Good palanquin bearers are
so hard to come by these days.
So, is everything ready
for our departure?
There's been a change
in plans, Azula.
What?
I've decided to lead the
fleet of airships
to Ba Sing Se alone.
You will remain here,
in the Fire Nation.
But, I thought we were
going to do this together?
My decision is final.
You, you can't treat
me like this!
You can't treat me like Zuko!
Azula, silence yourself.
But it was my idea to burn
everything to the ground!
I deserve to be by your side!
Azula!
Listen to me. I need you here to
watch over the homeland.
It's a very important job that
I can only entrust to you.
Really?
And for your loyalty,
I've decided to declare you
the new Firelord.
Firelord Azula?
It does seem appropriate...
But, what about you?
Firelord Ozai is no more.
Just as the world will
be reborn in fire,
I shall be reborn as the supreme
ruler of the world.
From this moment on,
I wll be known as
The Phoenix King!
And the reason you brought us to the
Seedy Earth Kindom Tavern is what now?
June.
Oh yeah, this weird bounty
hunter with a big mole.
Mole? Her skin is flawless.
No, she has this giant mole-creature
she rides around on.
Shirshu.
It's the only animal who can track
Aang's scent anywhere in the world.
It's the one shot we
have at finding him.
I don't know who this
June lady is,
but I like her!
Hey, Momo...I just had
the strangest dream.
Wait.
Where are we?