Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the fire nation attacked
only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar.
An airbender named aang.
And although his airbending skills are great, he has
a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe, aang
can save the world.
You have mastered all four elements?
Yeah, and now you're going down!
No, it is you who are going down.
The comet is already here,
and I am unstoppable!
The avatar state is defence mechanism,
desinged to empower you with a skills
and knowledge of all the past avatars
the glow
is the combination of all your past lives,
focusing their energy through your body.
I can feel a lot of energy
twisted up around there.
Let me just see if I can...
What happened generations ago
can be resolved now…
by you.
Born in you, along with all this strife,
is the power to restore
balance to the world.
To the world.
After I leave here today,
I’m going to free Uncle
iroh from his prison
and I’m going to beg for his forgiveness.
But I’ve come to an even
more important decision.
I’m going to join the avatar.
And I’m going to help him defeat you.
Where is my Uncle??
He busted himself out.
Sokka!
It's you!
We kissed at the invasion.
And I thought we're gonna be together.
But we're not.
Aang,
I don't know.
You miscalculated.
I love zuko more than I fear you.
No, you miscalculated, you
should have feared me more!
You were right about what katara needed.
Violence wasn't the answer.
It never is.
Then I have a question for you.
What are gonna do when you face my father?
More ferocious!
Imagine striking through
you opponents heart!
I'm trying.
Now let me hear you roar like tiger-dillo!
That sounded pathetic.
I said, roar!
Who wants a nice cool
glass of watermelon juice?
Uh, oh, me-me, me!
Hey, your lesson is not over yet!
Get back here.
Come on, zuko,
just take a break.
What's the big deal?
Fine.
If you want to lounge around
like a bunch of snails all day
then go ahead!
Maybe zuko's right?
Sitting around the house
made us pretty lazy.
But I know just a thing to change that:
Beach party!
Check out my appa sand-sculpture.
Not, bad boldy.
But I've been working on my sandbending.
You're gonna love this.
Wow!
You even made a little
earth king and bosco.
Trying to top that, sokka?
Ta-da!
Is that a...
Blubbering blob-monster?..
No, it's suki!
Suki, we will all understand if
you'll break with him up over this.
I think it's sweet.
But it doesn't even look like..
A-a-ah!
What are you doing?
Teaching you a lesson!
What happened?
Zuko's gone crazy:
I've made a sand sculpture of suki
and he destroyed it!
Oh, and he is attacking aang.
Get a grip before I'll
blast you off this roof!
Go ahead and do it!
Enough!
What's wrong with you?
You could have hurt aang.
What's wrong with me?
What's wrong with all of you?
How can you sit around having beach parties
when sozin's comet is only three days away?
Why you all look at me like I'm crazy?
About sozin's comet...
I was actually gonna wait to fight
firelord until after it came.
After?
I am not ready.
I need more time to master firebending.
And, frankly,
your earthbending can
still use some umpf too.
So,
you all knew aang was gonna wait?
Honestly,
if aang tries to fight the firelord right
now... he'gonna lose.
No offence.
The whole point of fighting
the firelord before the
comet was to stop the fire
nation from winning the war.
But they pretty much won the
war when took ba sing se.
Things can't get any worse.
You're wrong.
It's about to get worse
that you can even imagine.
The day before the eclipse
my father asked me to attend
an important war meeting.
It was what I dreamed about
and wanted for so many years.
My father has finally accepted me back.
Welcome prince zuko.
We waited for you.
General shinu, your report.
Thank you, sir.
Ba sing se is still under our control,
however, earthbending rebellions have prevented us
from achieving a total victory in the earth kingdom.
What is your recommendation?
Our army is spread too thin,
but once the eclipse is over
and the invasion defeated
we should transfer more domestic
forces into the earth kingdom.
Mmm, prince zuko,
you've been among the
earth kingdom commoners,
do you think that adding more
troops will stop these rebellions?
The people of the earth
kingdom are proud and strong.
They can endure anything
as long as they have hope.
Yes, you're right.
We need to destroy their hope.
Well, that's not exactly what I...
I think you should take their precious hope
and the rest of their land and
burn it all to the ground.
Yes, yes, you're right azula.
Sozin's comet is almost upon us.
And on that day it will lend
us with the strength and
power of hundred suns.
No bender will stand a chance against us.
What are suggesting, sir?
When the comet last came,
mine grandfather, firelord sozin,
used it to wipe out the air nomads.
Now, I will use it its power
to end the earth kingdom!
Permanently.
From our airships we will
rain fire over their lands.
The fire that will destroy everything.
And out of the ashes, a
new world will be born.
A world in which all the
lands will be fire nation,
and I am the supreme ruler of everything!
I wanted to speak out against
this horrifying plan
but ashamed to say I didn't.
My whole life I struggled
to gain mine father love and acceptance.
But once I had it.
I realize I lost myslef getting there.
I forgotten who I was.
I can't believe this.
I always knew the firelord was a bad guy.
His plan is just a pure evil.
What am I gonna do?
I know you're scared.
And I know you're not
ready to save the world.
But if you don't defeat the
firelord before the comet comes...
there won't be a world to save anymore.
Why didn't you told me about
your crazy dad's plan sooner?
I didn't think I had to.
I assumed you are still gonna
fight him before the comet.
Noone told you decided to wait.
This is bad.
This is really, really bad.
Aang,
you don't have to do this alone.
Yeah, if we all have to fight
the firelord together,
we're gonna shot it and take him down.
All right!
Team avatar is back!
Air.
Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Fan and sword.
Fighting the firelord is
gonna be the hardest thing
we've ever done together.
But I wouldn't wanna do it any other way.
Yeah.
All right.
Get over here, zuko.
Being part of the group,
also means being part of the groups hugs.
There is one technique you need
to know before facing my father.
How to redirect lightning.
If you let the energy in your body flow,
lightning will follow it.
And you turn your opponents
energy against them.
That's like waterbending.
Exactly.
Mine Uncle invented this technique himself
by studying waterbenders.
So, have you ever
redirected lighting before?
Once.
Against mine father.
What was it feel like?
Exilirating.
But terifying.
You feel so powerful holding that
much of energy in your body,
but you know if you make the wrong move:
It's over.
Well, not over-over, I mean,
there is always katara and a little
spirit water action, amirite?
Actually I
used it all up, after azula shot you.
Oh.
You'll have to take firelord's life,
before he takes yours.
Yeah,
I'll just do that.
Gather around, team avatar.
In order to take out the firelord.
Or... in this case... the melonlord.
Timing has to be perfect.
First, suki and I will draw his fire.
Then katara and zuko charge in
with some liquidy hot offence,
and while the melonlord is distracted
aang snoopes in and
ba-am!... He delivers the final blow.
Ehm, what about me?
For now... you're the melonlord's forces.
So I get to chuck flaming
rock at all of you?
Whatever makes the training
field more realistic.
Sweetness.
Mua-ha-ha-ha!
Watch it, toph!
I'm no toph,
I am melonlord!
Mua-ha-ha-ha!
Now, aang.
What are you wating for?
Take him out!
I can't.
What's wrong with you?
If this was the real deal... you'd
be shotful of lighting right now.
I'm sorry... but it just
doesn't feel right.
I didn't feel like myself.
There. That's how it's done.
I have a surprise for everyone!
I knew it!
You did have a secret thing with haru!
Ehm... no.
I was looking for cooking pots in the attic
and I found this.
Look at baby zuko!
Isn't he cute?
Oh, lighten up... I'm just teasing.
That's not me.
It's mine father.
But he looks so sweet and innocent.
That sweet little kid
grew up to be a monster.
And a worst father in
the history of fathers.
But he's still a human being.
You're going to defend him?
No, I agree with you.
Firelord ozai is a horrible person.
And a world will probably
be better off without him,
but there's got to be another way.
Like what?
I don't know.
Maybe we can make some big
pots of glue and then I can
use gluebending to stick
his arms and legs together
so he can't bend anymore.
Yeah,
then you can show him his baby pictures
and all this happy memories
will make him good again.
Do you really think that will work?
No!
This goes against everything
I learned from the monks.
I can't just go around wiping
out people I don't like.
Sure, you can.
You're the avatar.
If it's in the name of keeping balance, I'm
pretty sure the universe will forgive you.
This isn't a joke, sokka!
None of you understands
the position I'm in!
Aang, we do understand. It's just..
Just what, katara, what?
We're trying to help.
So when you figure out the way
for me to beat the firelord
without taking his life,
I'd love to hear it!
Aang, don't walk away from this.
Let him go.
He needs time to sort it out by himself.
Hey, momo.
I don't suppose you know what I should do.
I didn't think so.
Ok, that's everything.
No, it's not.
Where's aang?
Aang?
Come on, lazy bones, let's go!
He left his staff.
It's so strange.
Aang's not in a house.
Let's check the beach.
Look!
There is his footprints.
The trail ends here.
So,
he went for midnight swimming
and never came back?
Maybe he was captured...
I don't think so.
There's no sign of a struggle.
I bet he ran away again.
He left his glider and appa.
Then what do you think happened
to him, oh, sloozy one?
It's pretty obvious:
Aang misterously disappears
before an important battle?
He's definitely in a spirit world journey.
But if he was,
wouldn't his body still be here?
Oh yeah, forgot about that.
Then he's gotta be
somewhere on ember island.
Let's split up and look for him.
I'm going with zuko!
What?
Everyone else went on a
life-changing field-trip with zuko?
Now, it's mine turn.
Aang, aang, aang, aang,
aang, aang, aang, aang!
Avatar state, yip-yip!
And when I was nine,
I ran away again.
Aha.
I know I shouldn't complain.
My parents gave me
everything I ever asked for.
But they never gave one
thing that I really wanted.
Their love.
You know what I mean?
Look,
I know you had a rough childhood.
But we should really focus on finding aang.
This is the worst field trip ever.
Judging by the looks on your faces,
I'm guessing you guys
didn't find aang either.
No.
It's like he just
disappeared.
Hey, wait a minute.
Has anyone noticed that
momo is missing too?
Oh, no!
I knew it was only a matter of time!
Appa ate momo!
Momo, I'm coming for you, buddy!
Appa didn't eat momo.
He's probably with aang.
That's just what appa wants you to think.
Get out of the bison's mouth, sokka.
We have a real problem here.
Aang, is nowhere to be found and
a comet is only two days away.
What should we do, zuko?
I don't know.
Why are you all looking at me?
Well, you are kind of the
expert on tracking aang.
Yeah, if anyone's got
experience hunting the avatar,
it's you.
Zuko, I don't want to tell
you how to do your job,
but why we are heading
to the earth kingdom?
There's no way aang's there.
Just trust me.
Come on, slowpokes, faster!
Sorry, I'm late father.
Good palanquine bearers are so
hard to come by these days.
So, is everything ready for our departure?
There's been a change in plans, azula.
What?
I've decided to lead the fleet
of airships to ba sing se alone.
You will remain here, in the fire nation.
But, I thought we were
going to do this together?
My decision is final.
You...
You can't treat me like this.
You can't treat me like zuko!
Azula, silence yourself.
But it was mine idea to burn
everything to the ground.
I deserved to be by your side.
Azula!
Listen to me,
I need you here to watch over the homeland.
It's a very important job that
I can only entrust to you.
Really?
And for your loyalty,
I've decided to declare
you the new firelord.
Firelord azula?
It does seems appropriate.
But, what about you?
Firelord ozai is no more.
Just as the world will be reborn in fire,
I shall be reborn as the
supreme ruler of the world.
From this moment on, I will be known as
the phoenix king!
And the reason you brought us
to the seedy earth kingdom
tavern is what now?
Jun.
Oh, yeah, this weird bounty
hunter with a big mole.
Mole,
her skin is flawless.
No she has this giant mole-creature,
she rides around on.
Shirshu.
It's the only animal who can track
aang's scent anywhere in the world.
It's the one shot we have to finding him.
I don't know who this jun lady is,
but I like her!
Hey, momo.
I just had a strangest dream.
Wait.
Where are we?
Hey, I remember her,
she helped you attack us.
Yep.
Back in the good old days.
Oh, great, it's prince pouty.
Where is your creepy granpa?
He is my Uncle!
And he is not here!
I see you worked things
up with your girlfriend.
- She is not mine girlfriend!
- I am not his girlfriend!
Ok, ok....Sheesh.
I was only teasing.
So what do you want?
I need your help finding the avatar.
Hm...Doesn't sound too fun.
Does the end of the world
sound like more fun?
Nyla!
Who is my little...Uumm...Snufly-wafly?
No! Careful there!
Ok,
so who's got something with
the avatar's scent on it?
I have aang's staff.
Well, what does that mean?
It means your friend is gone!
We know he is gone!
That's why we are trying to find him!
No, I mean he is gone gone.
He doesn't exist!
Where are we, momo?
Maybe I am in the spirit world?
But, wait, you can see me!
We can both be in the spirit world.
Nope,
my bending works.
Maybe if we climb to the top of the island,
we can figure it out where we are.
What do you mean aang doesn't exist?
Do you mean he is...
You know...Dead?
Nope, we could find him if he were dead.
Oh...lt's a real headscratcher.
See ya.
Helpful...Real helpful.
Wait. I have another idea.
There is only one other
person in this world,
who can help us face the firelord.
I'll be right back with the smell sample.
You saved your Uncle's sweaty sandal?
I think it's kinda sweet.
Let's do this.
Hey, wait up!
We are going to ba sing se?
Your Uncle is somewhere beyong the wall.
Nyla is getting twitchy,
so it can't be too far.
Good luck.
It's been a long day.
Let's camp and start our
search again at dawn.
It's a hexagon.
It doesn't seem like normal rock.
It's not made of earth.
This is so strange.
I wish some help right now,
I wish I had roku.
I do have roku!
You're right, aang.
All the past avatars,
all their experience and wisdom
is available to you,
if you look deep inside yourself.
So, where am I, roku?
What is this place?
I....Don't know, aang.
But I see that you are lost
in more ways that one right now.
I am.
I need to figure it out what to
do when I face the firelord.
Well, look who is here?
Everyone expects me to
take firelord's life.
But I just don't know if I can do that.
In my life,
I tried to be disciplined
and show restraint.
But it backfired,
when fire lord sozin took advantage
of mine restraint and mercy.
If had been more decisive,
and acted sooner,
I could have stopped sozin
and stopped the war before it started.
I offer you this wisdom, aang.
You must be decisive.
What's going on?
We're surrounded by old people?
Not just any old people,
these are great masters
and friends of ours.
Pakku.
It is respectful to bow to an old master,
but how about a hug,
for your new grandfather?
That's so exciting!
You and gran gran must be so happy
to finding each other again.
I made her a new betrothal
necklace and everything.
Welcome to the family, granp-granp.
You can still just call me pakku.
How about...
Gran-pakku?
No.
And this was aang's first
firebending teacher.
Jeong-jeong.
Master piandao.
Hello, sokka.
So wait,
how do you all know each other?
All owl people know each other,
don't you know that?
We all are part of the same
ancient secret society.
A group that transcends the
divisions of the four nations.
The order of the white lotus.
That's the one.
The white lotus was always been about
philosophy, and beauty, and truth.
But about a month ago,
a call went out that we were all
needed for something important.
It came from our grand lotus, your Uncle.
Iroh of the fire nation.
Well, that's who we are looking for.
Then we will take you to him.
Wait,
someone is missing from your group,
someone very important...
Where is momo?
He is gone,
and so is aang.
Oh well, so long as they have each other
I am sure we have nothing to worry about.
Let's go!
Avatar kyoshi,
I need your wisdom.
In my day,
chin the conqueror threatened to
throw the world out of balance.
I stopped him,
and the world entered a great era of peace.
But you really didn't kill chin.
Technically, he fell to his own doom
because he was too stubborn
to get out of the way.
Personally, I don't really
see the difference,
but I assure you...
I would have done whatever it took
to stop chin.
I offer you this wisdom, aang.
Only justice will bring peace.
I knew I shouldn't have ask kyoshi.
So, bumi,
how did you end up escaping
your imprisonment in omashu?
Escape?
I didn't escape.
Everybody else escaped.
There I was back in a ...
Moment. I didn't know what or when,
bit I knew I'd know it when I knew it.
An eclipse.
That'll do it.
What do you think you're doing?
Taking back my city.
You've got no fire power
and it's payback time!
Wow,
you took back your whole
city all by yourself.
So what about you, guys?
Did you do anything interesting
on the day of the eclipse?
Nah.
No, not really.
I need to look deep inside myself.
I am avatar kuruk.
When I was young,
I was always a
"go with the flow" kind of avatar.
People seemed to work
out their own problems,
and there was peace and
good times in the world.
But then, I lost the woman I loved to koh,
the face stealer.
It was mine fault.
If I had been more
attentive and more active,
I could have saved her.
Aang,
you must actively shape your own destiny,
and the destiny of the world.
Well, here we are.
Welcome to owl people camp.
Where?
Where is he?
Your Uncle is in there, prince zuko.
Are you okay?
No, I am not okay.
My Uncle hates me, I know it.
He loved me and supported
me in every way he could.
And I still turned against him.
How can I even face him?
Zuko,
you're sorry for what you did, right?
More sorry than I've been about
anything in my entire life.
Then he'll forgive you.
He will.
Uncle,
all these past avatars,
they keep telling me I'm
gonna have to do it.
They don't get it.
You're right,
maybe an air nomad avatar
will understand where I'm coming from.
I know you can't really talk,
pretending you can just helps me think.
I am going to pretend I
didn't pretend to hear that.
I am avatar yangchen, young airbender.
Avatar yangchen,
the monks always taught me
that all life is sacred,
even the life of the tiniest
spider-fly caught in its own web.
Yes,
all life is sacred.
I know, I am even a vegeterian.
I've always tried to solve my
problems by being quick or clever,
and I've only had to use
violence for necessary defence.
And I've certainly never
used it to take a life.
Avatar aang,
I know that you're a gentle spirit.
And the monks have taught you well,
but this isn't about you,
this is about the world.
But the monks taught me,
that I have to detach
myself from the world,
so my spirit could be free.
Many great and wise air nomads
have detached themselves
and achieved spiritual enlightenment.
But the avatar can never do it,
because your sole duty is to the world.
Here is my wisdom for you.
Selfless duty calls you to
sacrifice your own spiritual needs
and do what ever it takes
to protect the world.
I quess I don't have a choice, momo,
I have to kill the fire lord.
Uncle,
I know you have mixed
fellings about seeing me.
But I want you to know,
I am so,
so sorry, Uncle.
I am so sorry and ashamed of what I did.
I don't know how I can
ever make it up for you.
But I...
How can you forgive me so easily?
I thought you will be furious with me.
I was never angry with you.
I was sad,
because I was afraid you lost your way.
I did lose my way.
But you found it again,
and you did it by yourself.
And I am so
happy you found your way here.
It wasn't that hard, Uncle.
You have a pretty strong scent.
Wait,
is it just me
or those mounts getting bigger?
There are not getting larger,
they are getting closer.
The whole island is moving.
It's amazing, momo.
The biggest animal in the world.
I've got to swim around and find its face.
Uncle,
you are the only person
other then the avatar
who can possibly defeat the fatherlord.
You mean the firelord?
That's what I just said.
We need you to come with us.
No, zuko.
It won't turn out well.
You can beat him.
And we will be there to help.
Even if I did defeat ozai
and I don't know that I could.
It will be the wrong way to end a war.
History will see it as just
more senseless violence,
a brother killing a brother to grab power.
The only way for this war to end peacefully
is for the avatar
to defeat the firelord.
And then,
then would you come and take your
rightful place on the throne?
No.
Someone new must take the throne.
An idealist with pure heart
and unquestionable honour.
It has to be you, prince zuko.
Unquestionable honour?
But I've have made so many mistakes.
Yes, you have.
You struggled, you suffered,
but you have always followed you own path.
You restored your own honour,
and only you can restore the honour
of the fire nation.
I'll try, Uncle.
Well, what if aang doesn't come back?
Sozin's comet is arriving
and our destinies are upon us.
Aang will face the firelord.
When I was a boy,
I had a vision, that I'll one day
take ba sing se.
Only now do I see that
my destiny is to take it back
from the fire nation,
so the earth kindom can be free again.
That's why you gathered the
members of the white lotus.
Yes.
Zuko,
you must return to the fire nation,
so that when the firelord fall,
you can assume the throne
and restore peace
and order.
But azula will be there,
waiting for you.
I can handle azula.
Not alone.
You'll need help.
You're right.
Katara,
how would you like to help
me put azula in her place?
It would be my pleasure.
What about us?
What's our destiny today?
What do you think it is?
I think that
if we don't know where aang is,
we need to do everything we can
to stop the airship fleet.
And that means, when aang
does face the firelord,
we will be right there if he need us.
Nothing runs faster over
land or swims quicker
than a giant eel-hound.
The airship base is on the small island
just off the earth kindom shore.
You should be able to intercept the
fleet within the day's journey.
Thank you, master.
So if I'm gonna be the firelord
after the the war over,
what are you going to do?
After I reconquer ba sing se,
I am going to reconquer my tea shop
and I am going to play pai sho every day.
Goodbye, general iroh.
Goodbye, everyone.
Today destiny is our friend,
I know it.
A lion-turtle.
Maybe you can help me.
Everyone,
even my own past lifes
are expecting me to end someone's live.
But I don't know if I can do it.
The true mind can weather
all the lies and illusions
without being lost.
The true heart can tough
the poison of hatred
without being harmed.
Since beginningless time
darkness thrives in the void
but always yields
to purifying light.
Wait for him.
He will come.
It's time for this world to end in fire
and for a new world to
be born from the ashes.
Zuko, don't worry,
we can take azula.
I'm not worried about her,
I'm worried about aang,
what if he doesn't have the
guts to take out my father?
What if he loses?
Aang won't lose.
He's gonna come back.
He has to.
What am I holding?
A cherry-pit, princess.
Correct.
And what day is this?
It's the day of your coronation.
Yea, it is.
So please, tell me why on the
most important day of my life
you decided to leave a pit in my cherry?
It wasn't a decision, it was a just
small mistake.
Small?
Do you realize what could have happened
if I didn't have sensed the pit in time?
I suppose, you could have choked?
Yes,
then you understand the
severity of your crime.
I understand, princess.
Please, forgive me.
Oh, very well,
since it is a special day,
I will show mercy.
You are banished.
Leave this palace immediately.
What are you all looking at?
I have two feet, that need scrubbing.
And make sure you get inbetween the toes.
I won't have as first day as firelord
marked by the poor foot hygiene.
It's weird to say,
but the comet actually looks beautiful.
Too bad the firelord is about
to use it to destroy the world.
We're too late!
The fleet's already taking off!
Then we're taking off, too.
Where is the closest airship?
It's right there...
A-a-h!
You sent for us, princess?
Is everything all right?
Actually everything is not all right.
Do you know how long it
took you to get here?
E-e-eh, few minutes a guess?
Five, to be precise.
In which time an assasin
could have smugged in,
done away with me,
and went on his merry way.
My apoligies, princess.
Is this how you plan to
treat your new firelord?
With retardiness and disloyalty?
Dai Lee would never betray you.
And I'm sure that's just what
you told long feng before
you turned against him and joined me.
You're all banished.
But...
Bye,
please send in the next
group on your way out.
That's how it's done.
Good work, toph.
Time to take control of the ship.
Take the wheel.
That's a great idea.
Let the blind girl steer the giant airship.
I was talking to suki.
That would make a lot more sense.
What are we gonna do with
the rest of the crew?
Take us down closer to the water.
I've got an idea.
Attention, crew, this is
your captain speaking.
Everyone please report to
the bomb bay immediately,
for hot cakes and sweet cream.
We have a very special
birthday to celebrate.
Hey.
I'm quin Lee.
I work up, in the communications.
Oh, hi.
I work down, in the engine room.
That's probably we never met before.
Big airship, you know.
Yep.
So, do you know whose birthday it is?
I can't believe that captain
remembered my birthday!
He really does care!
Happy Birthday.
Firelord ozai,
here we come.
Azula, we heard what happened.
Why have you banished all your servants?
Or your dai Lee agents?
And the imperial firebenders?
None of the mcould be trusted.
Sooner or later they all
would have betray me.
Just like mai and ty Lee did.
Azula, we are concerned about
you and your well-being,
mine father asked you to come
here, and talk to me didn't he?
He thinks I can't handle the
responsiblity of being firelord.
But I will be the greatest leader
in the fire nation history.
I'm sure you will.
But considering everything
that happened today,
perhaps it's best for you to
postpone your coronation.
What?
Which one of you just said that?
What a shame.
There's only one way to resolve this.
You two must duel each other.
I order you to fight in a agni kai.
But..
We're not firebenders.
All right, fine.
Lo, you're banished.
Li. You can stay.
But,
I'm Lee.
So who is banished?
Ba sing se,
the order of the white lotus is here.
Here, to set you free.
Only once every hundred years,
can a firebender epxerience
this kind of power.
All right hair, it's
time to face your doom.
What a shame,
you always had such a beatiful hair.
What are you doing here?
I didn't want to miss mine
daughter's coronation.
Don't pretend to act proud.
I know what you're really think of me.
You think I'm a monster.
I think you're confused.
All your life you used
fear to control people.
Like your friends, mai and ty Lee.
But what choice do I have?
Trust is for fools.
Fear is the only reliable way.
Even you fear me.
No,
I love you, azula.
I do.
We're not gonna catch up to him in time.
No.
Momo,
time for you to go.
What just happened?
It's aang!
He's back!
After a generations of
firelords failed to find you,
now the universe
delivers you to me as a
act of providence.
Please listen to me.
We don't have to fight.
You have the power to end it here
and stop what you're doing.
You are right.
I do have the power/
I have all the power in the world!
Go, aang! Airbending slice!
Shouldn't we be helping him?
The firelord is aang's fight,
we need to stay focused
in stopping that fleet,
for burning down the earth kingdom.
And how do we do that, captain boomerang?
I can't see outside of this
honking side of metal.?
Airship slice!
Wow...
That's a lot of fire, isn't it?
That's gonna be a rough ride.
We need to get on the top
of this thing, fast.
Then what?
Watch each other's back,
and if we would make it that far...
I'll let you know.
Suki!
I'm okay!
Just finish the mission.
No.
Sokka I think we gotta
jump!
By decree of phoenix king ozai,
I now crown you firelord...
What are you waiting for?
Do it!
Sorry.
But you're not gonna become firelord today.
I am.
You're hilarious.
And you're going down.
Wait.
You want to be firelord?
Fine, let's settle this.
Just you and me, brother,
the showdown that was always meant to be...
agni kai!
You're on.
What are you doing?
She's playing you.
She know she can't take out us both,
so she's trying to separate us.
I know.
But I can take her this time.
Even you admitted to your
Uncle that would need help facing azula.
There's something off about her.
I can't explain it, but she is slipping.
And this way,
noone else has to get hurt.
I'm sorry it has to end this way, brother.
No, you're not.
No lightning today?
Afraid I'll redirect it?
Oh, I'll show you lightning!
No-o-o-o!
Zuko!
You're weak!
Just like the rest of your people!
Fated not deserve to exist in this world,
in mine world!
Prepare to join them.
Prepare to..
Die!
Come on out, avatar!
You can't hide in there forever!
Toph, metallbend the rudder, so it's change
in the turnining position.
The ship will spiral and
slam into the others.
Got it.
Have I ever mentioned how sweet it is,
that you invented metallbending?
You can stand to mention it more.
My leg.
Hang on, toph.
Aye-aye, captain.
Bye... space sword!
I don't think boomerang
is coming back, toph.
It's looks like this is the end.
How did that happened?
Did boomerang come back?
No,
suki did.
Come on out, little boy.
You're about to be...
I would really rather our family physician
look after little zuzu,
if you don't mind.
Zuzu, you don't look so good.
There you are, filthy peasant.
Thank you, katara.
I think I am the one who
should be thanking you.
Firelord ozai.
You and your forefathers
have devastated the balance of this world.
And now, you shall
pay the ultimate price.
No.
I am not going to end like this.
Even with all power in the world,
you are still weak...
In the era before the avatar,
we bent not the elements,
but the energy within ourselves.
To bend another's energy,
your own spirit
must be unbendable,
or you will be corrupted
and destroyed.
What?
What did you do to me?
I took away your firebending.
You can't use it to hurt or
threaten anyone else ever again.
You did it!
You should have seen yourself!
It was amazing!
You were all like...
And the fire lord was all like ...
So did you...
You know...
Finished the job?
I'm still alive...
I've learn another way to
defeat him and restore balance.
I took his bending away.
Wow, who taught you that?
A giant lion-turtle.
You have the craziest
adventures when you disappear.
Well, look at you, buster.
Now that your firebending is gone,
I guess we should call you
the "loser lord".
I am the phoenix king...
Oh, sorry,
didn't mean to offend you phoenix
king of getting his butt-whooped.
Ye-eah, or how about "king of the
guys who...
Don't win"?
Leave the nicknames to us, honey.
You need some help with that?
Mai. You're ok.
They let you out of prison?
My Uncle pulled some strings.
And it doesn't hurt when a new
fire lord is your boyfriend.
So is this mean you don't hate me anymore?
I think it means
I actually kind of like you.
But don't ever
break up with me again.
Dad!
I heard what you two did.
I am the proudest father in the world.
And your mother would be proud too.
There is my favorite warriors.
I have to admit, I kinda
have missed the face paint.
So how is it feel to be
back in uniform again?
It feels great!
Careful, suki!
Ty Lee is pretending to be
a kyoshi warrior again.
It's okay.
She is one of us now.
Yeah, the girls and I
really bonded in prison
and after a few chi-blocking lessons,
they said I can join their group.
We are gonna be best friends forever.
I can't believe the year ago mine
purpose in life was hunting you down.
And now,
and now... we're friends.
Yeah.
We are friends.
I can't believe a year ago I was
still frozen in block of ice.
The world so different now.
And it's gonna be even more different.
We'll rebuild it together.
Please,
the real hero is the avatar.
Today,
this war is finally over.
I promised my Uncle that I will
restore the honour of the fire nation
and I will.
The road ahead of us is challenging,
a hundred years of fighting
has left the world scarred and divided.
But with the avatar's help,
but we can get a back on the right path.
And begin a new era
of love and peace.
All hail firelord zuko!
I should count myself lucky...
the new firelord
has graced me with his presence
in mine lonely prison cell.
You should count yourself lucky that
the avatar has spared your life.
Banishing me was the best
thing you could have done for mine life.
It put me on the right path.
Perhaps your time in here
can do the same for you.
Why are you really here?
Because you are gonna tell me something.
Where...
Is...
My mother?..
Zuko, stop moving!
I'm trying to capture the moment.
I wanna to do a painting.
So we will always remember
a good times together.
That's very thoughtful of you, sokka.
Wait, why did you gave me momo's ears?
Those are your hair loopies.
At least you don't look like a porcupine.
My hair is not that spiky.
I look like a man.
And why did you painted me firebending?
I thought it look more exciting that way.
Oh, you think you could
do a better job, momo?
Hey, mine belly is not that big anymore...
I really trimmed down.
Well, I think you all look perfect!
Thanks for watching the entire seasons using
my fixed subtitles. I hope you enjoyed the show! :-)
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk