Chapter 4 - "Songs of the Dark Lantern"
[Wind rushing, pastoral music playing]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[Train whistle blows]
[Pastoral music playing]
[wind whistling]
Stop! No!
[Shouts]
Oh, no!
The beast is upon me!
[Duck quacks]
- Shh!
- Greg, is there a beast out there?
Mmm...
I found a duck. Do you
know how to make eggs
from a duck? I'm hungry.
- What about the beast?
- The beast is upon me!
I didn't see any beast.
That driver is nuts.
Mmm, nuts.
- Whew! Well, that's good.
- Good?!
That crazy driver's
taking us way off course!
- Really?
- Yeah, who knows where we are
by now with that guy acting all bananas.
Ooh, banana nut duck bread.
[Lightning strikes]
[Whinnies]
[all shout, ducks squawking]
- Whoa-ah!
- Well, finally some good luck.
Let's go to this creepy tavern
and ask for some directions.
But...
[lightning strikes]
[Sign creaking]
[Neighing, crying]
But it's creepy.
Why don't you guys go ask for
directions, and I'll just wait out ...
no, wait, I-I don't want
to be out here by myself.
How about you guys ...
- Just go to the tavern!
- Okay!
- But you ask for directions.
- Fine, yeah, I'll do everything.
Greg: I'm hungry.
- [Grunts] Go on!
- I-It's stuck. Oh.
[Dog sputtering]
E-Excuse me, there.
Excuse me. Hmm?
[Whistling]
[down-tempo music playing]
[Indistinct talking]
[whistling continues]
[Down-tempo music continues]
You. Wait. Here.
- I'll get some food.
- Well, at least it has music.
Well, hey, there, peach pot.
Whatcha doing around ...
- hey, what's that bird you got there?
- It's a ...
I am Beatrice!
These two sweet kids and I got
a bit lost in the ... Aah!
[Gasps]
No birds allowed in my tavern!
No birds allowed in your ...
It's a bad omen when a bluebird enters
through your door. It's bad luck!
Lady, bluebirds are good luck!
We bring joy and
happiness to the ... aah!
Good luck, bad luck ...
I don't need any of it!
Curse you, lady! Curse you!
You'll die someday, and I'll
laugh ... laugh! [laughs]
- Ohh!
- Forget this. I'm out of here.
- Wirt, you get directions.
- W-Wait, no.
- I-I don't want to ...
- Just do it!
Who are you two anyway,
bringing bad luck to my tavern?
I'm Wirt, and this is Gregory.
[Snorts]
And that's a horse!
That's great, but who are you?
I'm... Wirt. I'm ...
I'm just a-a guy, I-I guess.
Um, w-what do you mean?
- Well, he's the butcher...
- I'm the butcher.
- ...the baker...
- Yeah!
...the midwife...
[Coughs]
...the master and apprentice...
the tailor.
[Moaning]
and I'm the tavern keeper.
Who are you?!
I am hungry!
I-I-I don't know.
I don't really like labels.
I'm just sort of,
like, myself, you know?
- Maybe he's simple.
- No, I-I'm just [sighs]
I'm just lost. See,
w-we're trying to get to ...
- I'm the highwayman.
- Okay, good to know.
- Well, so, you see ...
- # I'm the highwayman #
♪ I make ends meet ♪
♪ just like any man ♪
♪ I work with my hands ♪
♪ if you cross my path ♪
[Mid-Tempo music playing]
# I'll knock you out #
♪ Drag you off the road ♪
♪ steal your shoes from off your feet ♪
♪ I'm the highwayman ♪
♪ And I make
ends mee-e-e-e-t ♪
[cheers and applause]
[Sighs]
[cheers and applause continue]
[Sighs] Hey.
[Crunching]
Are you wearing lipstick?
[Smacks lips, snorting]
♪ La la la la ♪
Hmm? Who's out there?
♪ Chop the wood to light the fire ♪
What kind of person
goes out chopping trees
in the middle of a
thunderstorm at night?
- # Light that fiery fire #
- What kind of a person
talks to a horse?
[Neighs, laughs]
Ooh Ah.
[Both grunting]
[Laughing]
Hmm.
[Sighs]
[Laughing]
- Excuse me?
- Huh?
I was wondering if you knew the way ...
uh, I mean, I-I'm ...
- her name is Adelaide, and ...
- Oh, it's a girl you're after, eh?
No! I-I mean, yes, but ...
[Laughs]
Oh, you're not the witless
simple-minded fool
everybody takes you for.
- Everyone thinks I'm ...
- You're the young lover.
- What? Young lover? No, uh ...
- If you really want to get
- with this Adelaide gal...
- I-I don't. I-I mean, I-I ...
well, here's what you do.
[mid-tempo music playing]
♪ Write a loving letter, boy ♪
♪ that swoops and sweeps and curls ♪
♪ calligrapher's just the thing
to help you win your girl ♪
♪ then you'll need to dress up smart ♪
♪ the tailor's here by chance ♪
♪ He'll stitch your
trousers, hole your belt ♪
♪ in fine couture of France ♪
♪ your shoes, my goodness,
how they're worn, ♪
♪ but you're too young to know ♪
♪ Nothing courts a woman's scorn
more than scuffs on the toe ♪
♪ The cobbler can attend to that ♪
♪ Meanwhile, you must have cake ♪
♪ The baker and patissier
need work for goodness sake ♪
♪ high, dee, diddly,
um-de-dum-de-day ♪
♪ What a merry time we'll
have upon your wedding day ♪
- What?
- # High, dee, diddly, #
♪ um-de-dum-de-day ♪
♪ there's work for all when little
boys get married ♪ [laughter]
No, no, no, no. y-you guys,
I-I-I'm not getting
married. I'm just trying to find ...
♪ That pointy cone upon your head ♪
- Oh, no, please.
- # You can't be wearing that #
[mid-tempo music continues in distance]
[Thunder rumbling]
Mm. [Sighs]
If I have to be outside,
then those jokers do, too.
Oh, hey, Beatrice!
Do you want some food, too?
No. How's Wirt doing
getting directions?
Mm, pretty good.
♪ High, dee, diddly,
um-de-dum-de-day ♪
♪ What a merry time we'll
have upon your wedding day ♪
[Sighs]
# High, dee, diddly #
What about that woodsman?
I bet he knows these woods
better than anybody, huh? [Sighs]
All right, horse, good riddance!
[Neighs, laughs]
[All cheering]
Lover! Lover!
No, y-you guys, Adelaide
- isn't ... I-I'm just ...
- Young lover, sing us your love song!
- Love song?
- Yeah, lover! Sing us your love song!
No, I-I-I don't have a ...
- All: [chanting] Sing, lover, sing!
- No.
- All: Sing, lover, sing!
- Aah! Ohh!
All: Sing, lover, sing!
Sing, lover, sing!
- Sing, lover, sing!
- Sing, boy, sing!
[Vocalizing nervously]
♪ My name is Wirt, and his name ♪
♪ is Greg ♪
♪ we're related 'cause my mom ♪
♪ Remarried and then gave
birth to him with my stepdad ♪
[Mid-tempo music playing]
[sighs]
♪ We're not from around here ♪
♪ can you all give me ♪
♪ Some directions today? ♪
♪ So we can be on our ♪
[breathing heavily]
# wa-a-a-y #
- This ain't no love song. [Sniffling]
- It's a metaphor. [Crying]
- Keep it together, tailor.
- Hey!
- Uh, yes?
- I know what you are!
- You're a pilgrim!
- What? What, like the ...
the guys who eat turkey
and cranberry sauce?
- No, you're a pilgrim!
- A pilgrim?
You're a traveler
on a sacred journey.
You're the master
of your own destiny.
- The hero of your own story!
- A pilgrim.
Tell us your feats, pilgrim!
What other challenges
- have you overcome?
- Regale us with your travels, pilgrim!
One time, Wirt fell on a gorilla.
[all cheering]
And helped me find this frog.
[All cheering]
- More! Tell us more!
- Tell us more!
Let the cat out of the bag!
We want to hear it!
And, oh, uh, I met this
helpful woodsman who told us
which direction to go to avoid beast.
- All: [gasp] The beast!
- The beast.
- Oh, goodness.
- Oh, you guys have heard of
- the beast, too?
- We all know the beast, pilgrim.
♪ He lurks out there in the Unknown ♪
♪ seeking those who are far from home ♪
♪ hoping never to let you return ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ ooh-ooh, better beware ♪
♪ ooh-ooh,
the beast is out there ♪
♪ ooh-ooh, better be wise
and don't believe his lies ♪ [vocalizing]
♪ for once your will begins to spoil ♪
♪ he'll turn you to a tree of oil ♪
♪ and use you in his
lantern for to burn ♪
[Vocalizing]
[Blows]
Wait, wait, wait! Lantern?
The woodsman was the guy with
the weird lantern, not the beast.
Pilgrim, he who carries the
dark lantern must be the beast.
What?
No, the woodsman's a good guy.
He warned us of the beast and
told us which direction
- to go to avoid him.
- And now you're more
- lost than ever, huh?
- Yeah, but...
Oh, yeah, hey, can you
give us some directions?
Our friend Beatrice is trying
to take us to Adelaide
of the pasture, the
good woman of the woods.
- She can help us get home.
- You don't need directions, pilgrim.
- You follow that compass
inside your heart.  - Uh...
- No, I think we need directions.
- Aah!
- [Gasps] Beatrice!
- Go save your friend and get
yourself home!
[All cheering, shouting]
- Pilgrim!
- You got it!
Uh... Okay.
Never say die, never say die!
[All cheering]
Oh, boy, I guess
I'm really doing this.
Horse, I'm just gonna pretend
like I can ride you, all right?
[Grunts]
[Neighing]
Beatrice!
[Creature howling in distance]
Beatrice?
[Wind whistling]
- Another one of those trees.
- Halt!
[Gasps]
It's you!
- Hey, Mr. Woodsman!
- I told you to leave these woods!
[Gasps]
Beatrice!
You're turning her
into an edelwood tree!
[gasps]
You were the beast all along!
[Blows]
Huh?!
[Whinnying]
Whoa! Huh?!
- What is this?
- Greg, get Beatrice!
[Grunting]
What are you doing?!
Boys, the beast is upon you!
Agh!
Oh!
[Gasps]
[Neighing]
[Sighs]
- Beatrice, you all right?
- Yeah, I just ... I saw a weird shadow
and then stupidly flew
into a tree and got knocked out.
Oh, well, we're all right now.
Wirt was amazing!
He sang a song, rode a horse,
and saved you from the axe guy!
He's the pilgrim!
That's all well and good,
but you were supposed
- to get directions.
- I did.
We just got directions from
Fred before you woke up.
- Who?
- Oh, uh, Beatrice, meet Fred the horse.
- Nice to horse your acquaintance.
- You can talk?!
[Neighs, laughs]
Man: It seems you're
running out of oil, woodsman.
Why not let me take
the lantern for awhile?
Begone, beast!
I've fought you for the lantern
before, and I'll fight you again!
No need for violence,
woodsman, but be sure
to keep it lit, or your daughter's flame
will go out... forever.
Now, what direction
did those children go?
You leave those children be!
[Laughing evilly]
- Beast!
- # La la la la #
♪ Chop the wood to light the fire ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~