Episode 5 - "Mad Love"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Yes, tea! That's my trade!
- Quincy Endicott's health tea.
- Your tea sounds good.
Ugh. Never touch the stuff myself.
- Bleh. Me either.
- Ha ha! Yes!
It's all for the money! Yes,
the money takes my mind off
my troubles ... the deep
soul-crushing loneliness.
Yes, the more money I make, the
bigger my mansion gets,
the more lost I feel.
Why, this house is so big,
I sometimes don't even
know where or who I am!
Yeah, well, I'm glad your
nephews here were able to pay a visit.
- Yeah, yeah!
- Yes, what a ... what a
pleasure it is to have company ...
a perfect pleasure.
A perfect pleasure, lads!
A per... yes, yes. Yeah, yeah.
- Ha ha! Yeah! Ha ha!
- # Perfect pleasure, Heather...#
Um, Beatrice, w-why
are you pretending I'm
- this guy's nephew?
- We need money.
- You're scamming him?
- I was thinking more like
- flat-out stealing from him.
- What? No way.
Why not?
We already stole a horse.
- Hey, guys.
- No, we didn't.
Fred's a talking horse.
He can do whatever he wants.
I want to steal.
- What?! You guys are bonkers.
- If we're going to Adelaide's,
- we need two cents.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, you guys do
what you ... two cents?
- Only two cents?
- Yeah, we need two pennies
to take the ferry
to Adelaide's pasture.
Ha ha! Come everyone!
Let us retire to the parlor
and enjoy my unnecessary
excess of wealth and luxury.
Well, maybe he just has some
loose change somewhere he
wouldn't mind us taking.
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-Hmm.
- Hmm.
Behold, nephew, the majesty of wealth!
Ooh!
What was that?! Uh ...
What's wrong unkie Endicott?
Your forehead is all sweaty.
M-My nerves. My ...
my ... my ner...
my nerves are a bust these days.
How come?
Uh, yes, yes. Maybe
it would be ... be good to ...
to talk to someone. Well, y...
Actually, it all began one day
when I was exploring
my exceedingly large and
labyrinthine manor here.
I happened upon a section of
the house I didn't even recall building.
Isn't that funny?
Must've been the old wing.
But it was lit in a rather sort
of eer... eerie ... eerie light.
And I pressed on, and then I-I
saw the painting of the most
beautiful woman I've ever seen,
and that's when things
took a rather strange turn.
From that day on, I was obsessed
with the woman in the portrait.
She con...
consumed my every thought.
I'd fallen in love ...
... with a ghost.
Ohhhh.
- It's too big. Get a grip.
- Oh, I must sound crazy,
mustn't I?
Perhaps it's time for you all
to leave my treasure-filled home.
- No!
- Yeah, unkie!
- I want to see the ghost!
- Ohh, how I long to see her
- just once again, as well, yes.
- To the painting!
Yes. Yes.
- Ooh, boy! Ghost hunt!
- Fred, go with them.
- Buy me some time.
- While I'm at it, I'll steal
other stuff, too.
We're supposed to just be
- looking for loose change.
- That's what I'm ...
Oops. That's what I'm doing.
Well, let's try not
to break any more ...
- Gah!
- Oh, hey.
Hey, you didn't check the armoire.
Endicott's back. Hide!
- Is that the portrait?
- No.
Look, w-w-why don't I-I
just tell you when we
- reach the portrait.
- Okay, what's the matter, unkie?
You seem tense.
You know me well, nephew.
Yes, the truth is
- I'm frightened.
- Of a ghost?
- Ghosts are just floaty things.
- Oh, no, no, not afraid
of the ghost.
I mean I'm afraid what ...
What ... what if there is no ghost?
What if I'm on the ... on the ...
on the ... on the brink of ...
hmm ... madness.
Maybe the doctors were right.
Come along, boys!
Back to the parlor.
The parlor?
What would anyone go
the parlor for?
There's nobody in the parlor ...
certainly nobody after your money.
Yeah, no giving up now, old man.
- It's got to be a ghost!
- But h-how can you
- be so certain?
- 'Cause I really, really want
- to see a ghost ... really bad.
- Oh.
- Whew.
- Okay, I think they're gone.
- Beatrice? You there?
- Bah! Yes, smart guy.
Start searching for change.
Uh, I can't see anything in here.
Well, I-I don't think
these coats have pockets.
Check the lining. Maybe
somebody sewed money
- into the fabric.
- Nope.
- Do people even do that?
- I've done it on my clothes.
You wear clothes?
Like a little bird vest
or something?
- Or little bows?
- When I was a human, fool.
You used to be human?
Did I know that?
- I-I don't think I knew that.
- Jiminy Cricket!
Let's just find some coins, all right?
Open the door.
It's stuck. Well,
guess we have to spend
- some quality time together.
- Help!
The greenhouse.
This is where I grow my
camellia for testing new teas.
Perhaps we should savor the ...
the quiet tranquility of this ...
this place.
Ghost!
I can't do it!
Uncle Endicott, it's
just a funny chicken.
Yes, o-one of my
prize-winning roasting peacocks.
Yes, with all this love
in my brain, I, uh, forgot
to feed them.
It's almost as though
- I've lost my mind.
- We can look for that after we
find our ghost. Heave-ho!
Yes, yes. Heave-ho.
Into the abyss...
never to return.
Um, anyone want
to go back to the parlor?
- Hey. Are you still there?
- Yes, Wirt. I'm still here.
- So, how did you become a bluebird?
- Hey, what's that?
- Don't change the subject.
- Hmm.
There's a breeze coming
- out of here.
- Oh, yeah.
- Whoa!
- What?!
A secret entrance!
So, about your dark secret.
Hey, how about you tell me
your dark secrets instead, huh?
My secrets are too secret.
Hey, look. Light.
Whoa. Now who's
avoiding the question?
- You.
- Fine.
I threw a rock at a bluebird,
and it cursed me and my family,
and now we're all bluebirds.
Happy? Now you go.
Whoa. Y-Your whole family?
- Yeah.
- Is that why you're going
- to Adelaide's ... to fix things?
- That was the plan, but ...
Yeah, that was the plan.
- It'll all work out.
- All I know is I am never
going back till I can
make them human again.
I'd do pretty much anything.
All right.
My turn, huh? Okay.
Well, it's weird to admit it,
but, well, I-I have this
- crush on this girl.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's all.
- That's all?
And I think about her a lot,
and I play clarinet.
- Wirt! You got to be kidding me.
- And I secretly whisper
poetry to myself in my room at night.
Wirt, that stuff's not weird.
Those are just ...
well, the poetry thing is weird.
But those are just character traits.
- You played clarinet?
- Sort of.
- What else do you do?
- I don't know.
Uh ... hey. Does this
room look different to you?
- Uh, how so?
- It's like French-rococo style.
That doesn't really seem in
line with Endicott's
- Georgian sensibilities.
- How ... what?
Who on Earth am I talking to right now?
Should I not know that sort of stuff?
Endicott probably just built
it without thinking, right?
Or ... whoa. Yeah.
W-What if the ghost he was
talking about was actually...
This is the room where ...
the room where I first saw her.
- Whoa! Just a bedroom?
- Just a bedroom, my nephew?
This is the chamber of mine own
true love, and here she stands,
hovering above us
- like the blinding sun.
- Hmm. No ghost?
- No ghost? Then I am... mad.
- Don't be mad.
Hey. What's this suspicious
- mess over here?
- It looks like there was
a struggle ... a violent struggle.
What are you implying,
my equine friend?
Nothing, nothing. I'm just ...
Endicott is a crazed lunatic
who did away with the
lady of the house and is now
- pretending to own the place!
- What?!
Who do you think you are,
making accusa... I see it now.
You're after my money.
Do you know what I did
for this money ... t-the things
these filthy hands have done
- to make this money?!
- I'll never steal again,
I swear. I'll get an honest job.
- And what say you, nephew?
- Uh, I'm confused.
Well, then ...
She comes for me!
Wait, unkie! Face your fears!
Mr. Endicott? Are you all right?
Psst! Ghost.
What do you want with me, spirit?
Spirit? But you're the ghost.
My lady, I assure you
I am flesh and blood and I ...
I welcome you to my home.
Your home? Good
sir, you're in my home.
- Impossible!
- Look here. You see?
This is my camellia
garden for my tea company.
Margueritte Grey?!
Why, with all due respect,
- madam, this is my tea garden.
- Quincy Endicott?!
Your guys' mansions are so
huge they're actually connected.
So you ... you mean that
beautiful ghost
- was really just...
- That dashing specter was really just...
My business competitor?
Well, Greg, my boy, I can't
thank you enough for
helping me to face my fears.
You're a ... you're a
sweet boy with good sense.
Take this penny and start your fortune.
And here's one from me, as well.
Hey, nice.
Now we can ride the ferry.
Well, everybody, I think
it's time we head to
Adelaide of the pasture,
the good woman of the woods.
Uh, what about you, Fred?
Are you coming with us?
No, thanks. I've got
a real job now as
- an official tea horse.
- Well, then I guess that's it.
- Off you go, the lot of you.
- Goodbye.
And don't forget to
buy Endicott brand tea.
Hey, Wirt.
You did good back there.
- Yeah?
- You got a lot more going
for you than I thought. Huh?
Greg! Our pennies!
Why did you do that?!
'Cause uncle Endicott
pegged me all wrong ...
I've got no "cents,"
no "cents" at all.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~