Chapter 6 - "Lullaby in Frogland"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Yeah! Whoo!
Ahh.
What a nice way to spend
our last day ... going to
Adelaide's house.
Our journey is finally over.
Pretty soon I'll be back home.
I won't have to worry
about that Woodsman
or that beast or whatever,
and you won't have
to put up with us anymore.
Bet you're pretty happy,
- huh, Beatrice?
- Huh? Oh. Yeah. Sure.
You all right? You
sound uncharacteristically wistful.
- What? Sorry. Just thinking.
- Hmm.
* Oh, we're going to the pasture
to meet Adelaide and ask her *
* if she has a way to send
us back where we came from *
* I don't know who she is or how
she is or when, what, why she is *
* But as for where she is,
she is where we will go *
* to Adelaide, to Adelaide *
* Come on and join the Adelaide parade *
* Adelaide, to Adelaide *
* we're going to
Adelaide's house today *
Boy. Finally going home.
Hey, what's with Beatrice?
I don't know. What's
with George Washington
being naked?
- What?
- All the other frogs are dressed up nice.
He's an outcast, and he's cold.
- Feel these cold feet.
- No.
He's supposed to be
cold, Greg. He's a frog.
- But he's our frog!
- Well, he's not my frog ...
or she's not my frog.
We don't really know its gender.
Come on, George.
You're a manly frog,
and you need some socks.
Huh?
Uh-oh.
It looks like we're in trouble.
It's 'cause the president is nude!
It's probably 'cause you snuck on
- without paying.
- Oh, yeah.
But that's because Greg
threw all our money away.
Take him, not me!
Sorry!
Tadpoles! Your babies!
Ahh.
Good day, gentle...
Good day, gentlemen.
We ... I ... must be
going now to join the band.
- Wirt, drum me!
- Okay.
Ow! Ow, ow!
Are we good?
- Whew! I think so.
- Wirt, sometimes you got
to face your problems.
Turn yourself in and get
- kicked off this boat.
- I don't think today's a good
- day to get arrested by frogs.
- Hmm. Well...
- Hey! What's going on?
- Don't push me!
Oof! Oof! Oof!
Okay, everybody.
- Act natural.
- Drum me! Drum me!
- I said, "act natural."
- It is natural! I'm a drum!
Wirt, drum me!
- Drum me in the face!
- Okay! Okay! Shh!
Don't draw attention to us!
Whoa!
- Whoa!
- No bassoon player.
Uh-oh.
Dog, those frogs
really love the bassoon!
Huh?
- Hmm.
- Oh, no.
Beatrice, I'm too young
to go to frog jail.
Hey, why don't you play the bassoon?
That'll get us kicked
off this boat for sure.
No, Greg's right.
You should play it.
Go ahead. You'll do fine.
- You play instruments, right?
- Yeah, but bassoon and
clarinet are way different.
I don't have the embouchure
for bassoon. I mean,
the lower and middle
ranges have some
similarities in terms of ...
- Wirt, you can do it.
- Seriously, nobody wants
- to hear me play.
- I do!
I do!
Uh...
- Wirt?
- Yeah. Here we go.
Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
* At night when
the lake is a mirror *
- Huh?
- Whoa!
* And the moon rides
the waves to the shore *
* a single soul sets his voice singing *
* content to be slightly forlorn *
* a song rises over the lilies *
* wah-ooh, wah-ooh *
* sweeps high to
clear over the reeds *
* and over the bullrushes swaying *
* to pluck at a pair of heartstrings *
Hey, Beatrice, thanks for
supporting my bassooning.
- Yeah. You're actually good.
- The best part is we're still
- on track to get to Adelaide's.
- Yep. That's great.
- You don't seem thrilled.
- Well, I just ...
I don't want you to ...
never mind. Never mind.
* carries their memory on *
- Shh!
- Uh...
* Over the treetops and mountains *
* over the blackened ravines *
- Ohh!  - # Then softly it falls
by a house near a stream #
* and over the garden wall *
* To thee *
I knew you were special.
What are they doing?
Looks like they're...
hibernating in the mud.
So, where's Adelaide's
house? Is it close?
It's ... hmm.
We should probably just go
tomorrow, I think. We
don't want to bother her
- too late, you know?
- What are we supposed to do ...
just sit around in the
mud with these frogs?
I call that mud over there!
Yeah!
- So, then what?
- Well, then I went to go talk
to Sara ... I mean, like really
talk to her, you know ...
- put all my cards on the table, you know?
- Yeah.
And then Jason Funderberker
comes out of nowhere
and whisks her away!
Ugh! Jason Funderberker ...
that guy.
Plus Greg was around.
He would have embarrassed
- me even more.
- Well, Wirt, sounds like
- you're a real loser back home.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
I mean compared to how you are here.
Here you're like a
hero and stuff, right?
Am I?
Well, I don't know if I'd say,
- "hero," but ...
- Do you think that I could
be a hero, too? Huh?
You done good, Mr. President.
You done good.
If I was you, I wouldn't
even want to go home.
Yeah, but I-I can't stay here forever.
- Why not?
- Hmm? Why not?
Because ... because
I-I can't just ... maybe it is
- better to stay here.
- Great. Then it's agreed.
We're not going to Adelaide's.
Good night, Wirt.
Oh, what?
Oh. Good night, Beatrice.
Beatrice.
- Greg, wake up!
- Huh?
- Beatrice took off!
- What?
- Come on!
- Mmm.
- Come on, Greg!
- I'm coming.
Close the flue.
That fresh air does simply
gruesome things to my
tender, delicate skin.
- Adelaide, we need to talk.
- Did you bring me what I asked for?
I found two brothers lost in the woods,
but I can't give them to you, Adelaide.
- They need to go home.
- Nonsense!
I'll give them a wonderful home here.
- That's what you said, but ...
- Can't you see I'm sick
and helpless?
Ah-choo!
I'm all alone in the world.
- I want a child servant.
- Servant?
I thought you just wanted
some yard work done.
Our arrangement was for you
to bring me a child servant and
then I give you the scissors...
to snip, snip, snip your
family's wings away to
make them human again.
What if I became your servant?
Ha! I need a big, strong child!
You can turn me into
a human, can't you?
- Oh, yes ... scissors!
- Yeah. Yeah.
So, give me the scissors.
I'll go help my family.
- Wirt!
- Close the door!
- I'll catch my death of cold!
- What's going on?
- You shouldn't be here.
- Adelaide?
Welcome home, children.
Huh?
- Beatrice, wh-what ...
- I...
- But I thought we were friends.
- Now they're mine.
And once I fill their heads with wool,
they'll become just like
little sheep and follow
- my every command.
- All along, you've been
- leading us to this crazy lady?
- I do as he commands ...
the voice of the night,
the beast of eternal darkness.
What are you doing?!
Ohh! The night air is poisonous!
Breathe it in, lady.
Wirt, Greg, let's go!
- The deadly... air!
- Whoa! Geez!
- She wasn't kidding!
- It's fresh!
- Ohhhhhh!
- Huh?
Wirt? Greg?
Greg! Wirt!
It wasn't what it looked like!
I was just ... please come back!
Ohh.
- Hmm.
- Wirt, what about Beatrice?
Hmm.
I shouldn't have trusted anyone.
Huh?
Benjamin Franklin!
Hurry it up, Greg.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~