Africa.
In the four years of making this series,
we've been to some astonishing places
and seen animals behaving in ways
that have never been filmed before.
But Africa has another story to tell.
The wildlife of this continent has seen
more changes in the last 50 years
than it has in the last two million.
Changing landscapes and changing climate.
Today's animals are facing
unprecedented challenges
whilst, around them,
Africa's human population
is growing at nearly
double the global rate.
There is an increasing urgency
to understand
and, crucially, to conserve
the wildlife of this great continent.
Today, there is a new generation
of naturalists and scientists
who're fighting to save the wild places
and the animals that live in them.
One, two, three!
This is the greatest
wildlife continent on the planet.
And what happens here
is relevant to us all.
So, what is the future of wild Africa?
This animal has become the world's
number one target for poachers.
Its kind has been hunted
almost to the point of extinction.
It's now so rare that this individual
is watched over day and night.
This is the black rhinoceros.
And black rhinoceros are
notorious for being rather grumpy
and suddenly charging.
But he is in great danger...
because he has, on his nose...
that horn...
which is worth its weight in gold.
The demand for rhino horn has rocketed.
There has been a 3,000% increase in poaching
just in the last five years.
Today, powdered rhino horn
can fetch up to $65,000 a kilo.
Rhinos are a lucrative target
for organised crime.
In Chinese medicine, it's believed that
rhino horn can reduce fever.
And some Vietnamese sell it
as a cure for everything,
from cancer to hangovers.
It's made of keratin,
the same substance as hair and nail
and it has no clinically proven
medicinal value.
But it has made every black rhino
in Africa a target.
They've all been killed
in Uganda and Rwanda,
and there are only
around 600 left here, in Kenya.
But these are not poachers.
These are protectors.
And that protection is overseen
by rhino expert Dr. Matthew Mutinda,
one of the Kenya Wildlife Services' top vets.
Black rhinos are critically endangered.
And that is what we at Lewa Wildlife
Conservancy, we're trying to do.
Save the animal, provide a safe
and secure sanctuary,
where the animal can breed
and live freely.
There aren't many true wild rhinos left in Africa.
Most, like these,
in Lewa Wildlife Conservancy
are under armed guard.
This young female has reached the age
when Matthew must do some health checks,
including taking blood samples.
This will help deter
poachers and traffickers,
as DNA in illegally traded rhino horn
can be tracked back to its origin.
If you have to do
anaesthesia in the wild,
you will expect some degree of risk.
This female has reacted
badly to the anaesthetic.
She's not breathing. It's a rare
and extremely serious situation.
He knows that the next few minutes are crucial.
And when an animal is this big,
there's only one way to get the heart
going again when you're out in the bush.
Thanks to Matthew's quick thinking,
they can hear that she's breathing again.
They've got to get her back on her feet.
Not surprisingly, she's disorientated.
Mission accomplished.
It's been an ordeal,
but now this rhino can be tracked
and protected for the rest of her life.
Within minutes, she's grazing peacefully
again, with her mother.
It may seem heartless
to treat an animal like that,
but we have to keep tabs on them
and be able to identify individuals.
They're in great danger.
Even now, on average, one rhino is
killed by poachers every day in Africa.
There are so few black rhino
left in Kenya
that we're getting to know
each individual.
But this is still a creature
that can surprise us.
Previously, it was widely believed
that black rhinos
were largely solitary creatures.
Here, in the Kalahari,
a starlight camera reveals
that they may be much more sociable
than many thought.
This waterhole gathering
is an enchanting window into the past.
Early explorers reported seeing
a rhino behind every bush.
Before the invention of the gun
there were probably
hundreds of thousands of rhinos
across the continent.
The people protecting rhinos in Africa
are striving to ensure that we'll
still be able to witness
wonderful scenes like this
in 50 years' time.
Right across Africa,
conservationists have realised
that if we want to save our big animals,
then now is the time.
The human population of the continent
has just exceeded one billion,
and many wild animals are being hunted
commercially for food.
Some legally.
But many illegally.
Wildlife meat is often sold
as goat or beef.
The amount is astonishing.
Millions of tonnes are eaten
across Africa every year.
At this rate, some species are almost
certainly heading for extinction.
But commercial hunting
is not just affecting the grazers.
As the prey decreases,
it's affecting the predators, too.
Fifty years ago, there were about
half a million lions in Africa.
Today, there are less than 30,000.
But in one particular part of Africa,
things are improving
in a quite extraordinary way.
These hunters have become
part of a new and unlikely alliance.
In recent years, hungry lions have
increasingly been killing livestock.
One group of traditional Maasai have
reacted in a very untraditional way.
The Maasai are cattle herders
who don't eat wild animals.
But when lions attack their herds,
they've always retaliated.
Maasai and lions are ancient adversaries.
A lion hunt is still a rite of passage
for young Maasai warriors
like Olubi Lairumbe.
For me and any Maasai,
killing a lion is the ultimate fulfilment
of a truly accomplished Maasai.
Nothing compares to that.
There is nobody who knows
more about living alongside lions
than the Maasai themselves.
I met Olubi and some of
the other warriors in his village
to find out about their relationship
with the local pride.
How many lions are there around here?
Around here there are about a hundred.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
So they all have names?
Every single lion has a name.
A Maasai name.
And when you see a lion,
do you know how it's going to behave?
It depends on the lion.
For a Maasai warrior,
lions are nothing to be scared of.
If I saw a lion...
A lion would be likely to attack me.
Only if you threaten it.
Hmm, well,
I hope the next lion knows that.
Olubi killed his first
lion when he was just 17,
after it attacked his cattle.
Unfortunately,
the lion turned out to be pregnant.
And that led to a remarkable turnaround.
The Maasai respect all living things.
And I began to feel guilty
about the lion that I had killed.
In the end, I came to admire the lions.
Olubi had a dramatic change of heart.
He turned his back on hundreds of years
of Maasai tradition.
Along with some other warriors,
Olubi became a lion guardian.
Instead of hunting lions,
Olubi would be protecting them.
He teamed up with Stephanie Dolrenry,
who helped pioneer the project.
Just by respecting their traditions
and also bringing in
their ecological knowledge,
it's been hugely successful.
They know their areas,
they know how to track lions,
they've been doing it
for generation after generation.
They know how to track them,
they know how to hunt them,
they know how to find them.
This is only a small-scale project.
But with lion numbers
as low as they are,
they need all the help they can get.
Olubi is tracking radio-collared lions.
He's able to warn villagers
to move their cattle
when the pride is in the area.
And so they're avoiding conflict.
No lions have been killed
in the immediate area
since the project began.
By combining the science,
both ancient and contemporary,
they're beginning to make
a real difference.
There's so much to be learned.
I feel I bring in modern technology,
modern knowledge,
and, in return, they teach us
about the environment,
and how things have changed
in their environment.
And it's a really neat exchange...
You can't say the biologists
are the teachers
or the guardians are the teachers.
We're both teachers
and we're both students.
And I think that's...
That blend is amazing.
Critically,
at the heart of this project
is a huge attitude change
by these Maasai warriors.
An animal that was once
their sworn enemy, they now protect.
And their willingness to share knowledge
with other communities
means that projects like this could be
repeated in other parts of Africa.
Traditionally, when a warrior killed
a lion, he took the name of the lion.
Now, it's the other way round.
Now the lion takes the name
of the warrior who protects it.
The scheme is a huge success.
There are about 100 lions involved
in this scheme in this neighbourhood.
This is 21st century
conservation in action.
Perhaps the biggest threat to wildlife
is the competition for space
with the rapidly growing
human population.
The Virunga volcanoes straddle
the borders of Rwanda, Uganda
and the Democratic Republic of Congo.
The rich volcanic soils
are extremely fertile.
It's one of the most intensively
cultivated areas in Africa.
But the farmers also share this region
with one of our closest relatives.
This is home to the last 800 or so
wild mountain gorillas left on Earth.
We know a great deal
about these animals.
They've been closely studied
for 50 years.
One strong silverback male
keeps everyone in order.
And gorilla family life
is mostly peaceful.
Until a few generations ago,
mountain gorillas,
hidden in the seclusion
of their forests,
were seldom seen by human beings.
But their habitat was steadily
being carved away.
And now these gorillas are marooned
on the volcanic slopes
in a sea of farmland.
The fact that gorillas now
regularly come into contact with people
not only means an increased
threat of poaching,
but also of disease.
Gorillas have little or no resistance
to the bugs that we carry.
Numbers here once dropped to around 250.
They were facing extinction.
Action had to be taken.
The boundaries of the national park
were strictly enforced,
halting the encroachment of farmland.
And it was decided
that the only solution
was to intensively manage
the remaining gorillas.
Teams of scientists
constantly monitor them.
Their forests are patrolled
to cut poachers' snares.
And vets watch their health closely.
This is funded mostly
through ecotourism
and donations from all over the world.
Mountain gorillas are now
back from the brink.
This level of human intervention
might not be ideal, but it's working.
Every year there are
a few more mountain gorillas
and possibly just
a little more optimism.
Intensive management
within a protected area
may represent the only future
for many African species.
But for some animals
that is simply not possible.
What happens if the animal
you're trying to protect
is not suited to park life?
Elephants require vast amounts
of space to roam.
They have a range
of up to 1,300 square miles.
Given the chance,
they will even move between countries
in search of the best food,
particularly if conditions get rough.
This was the scene in
Amboseli National Park in 2009.
The park is home to nearly
one and a half thousand elephants.
And this was the worst drought
for half a century.
60% of zebras and 95% of wildebeest
were wiped out.
The seasonal rains had failed
for the last two years.
And the elephants that lived here
were slowly starving.
The park created to protect them
is now surrounded by farmland.
The elephants had little choice
of where else to go.
Caught up in this catastrophe
were three sisters.
They are the frontline
for elephant protection in the park.
And they know these animals
better than anyone else.
Nora Njiraini,
and Katito and Soila Sayialel.
All the elephants have been given names.
They're a family to us.
Hello, Anastasia.
The sisters have been following these elephants
for over 25 years,
trying to ensure their safety,
particularly at times when life
is tough for these animals.
It really was terrible.
There was nothing, actually, to feed on.
We even went and asked
the old Maasai men
whether they have ever
experienced such a drought.
The only time it was close
to what was then, was in 1961.
In 2009,
we lost quite a number of elephants.
I think we lost about 400 elephants.
And it started with the young ones.
Elephants usually escape drought
by moving into other less affected areas.
But Africa's human population
is growing at double the global rate.
And traditional migration routes
have been cut
by the developments
of towns, cities, farmland and roads,
leaving these elephants stuck.
This young calf is starving,
and there is nothing they can do to help.
For the sisters,
who know each elephant personally,
this is a terrible moment.
It is something
that we feel in our hearts.
You can imagine
the kind of feelings that we get.
You know, knowing those elephants
and seeing something like that happen,
it really touches us.
It was a tough year for all
the young elephants in the region.
We lost all the calves
who were born that year.
All of them. We lost them.
There was nothing the sisters
could do to save the baby.
But they were determined
to save any elephants they could,
especially mothers who could breed again.
They found this female
stuck in the mud, exhausted,
in a dried-up lakebed.
The elephant that got stuck
in the mud was Qualida.
Poor thing, you know,
she was there for quite a long time.
The Maasai reported it to us,
and we had to combine efforts with
the Kenya Wildlife Services people.
Weighing about three tonnes,
Qualida is just too heavy
to shift by hand.
She's weakening fast.
So the next morning,
heavy machinery is brought in.
After two days stuck in the mud,
Qualida is exhausted.
But she is up on her feet again.
The rains did return to Amboseli,
and, thanks in part to the work
of those dedicated three women,
elephant numbers
are now beginning to rise again.
There's no doubt
that this was an extremely severe event.
But is it an isolated incident
or a developing pattern?
Especially with global warming,
we actually don't know
what's going to happen,
but we just have to cross fingers
and hope for a better future.
Given the opportunity,
the numbers of elephants
in East Africa will recover.
Especially if they are given
the freedom to range widely,
and so avoid the harshest conditions.
One solution to help elephants
find the space they need
is to link parks together
and provide safe routes between them.
Elephants are great travellers,
and here, in this part of Kenya,
they regularly moved from the lowlands
up the side of the mountains
to feed in the forests up there.
But then, the human population of Kenya grew,
and roads like this one were constructed.
Penning the elephants
down in the lowlands
where they created havoc
amongst the farms.
Not only that, there were dangers
of collisions on the road.
And then someone suggested
building an underpass.
Within 24 hours of it being completed,
one elephant had passed through,
and now all the elephants use that route
to go up the mountain,
often at night, to feed.
Simple ideas like this underpass
are a lifeline for these elephants.
Especially in times of drought.
Africa's climate is certainly changing.
Some parts of the continent
have become three and a half degrees
centigrade hotter
in the past 20 years.
At the summit of Africa's
most famous mountain, Kilimanjaro,
80 percent of its permanent ice fields
have disappeared.
Soon, it will be free of ice altogether.
All over Africa
the mountainous regions are often
the first indicators of climate change.
Here, in the Ethiopian Highlands,
live very unusual-looking creatures.
Gelada baboons.
Climate change refugees.
Although this region of Ethiopia
lies in the tropics,
up at 4,000 metres,
it doesn't feel like it.
Unlike most African animals,
geladas are adapted
to life in the cold.
They used to be one of Africa's
most successful primates,
found all over the continent.
At one stage, there were
six different species.
Now there is only one.
With the warming climate,
their grazing is becoming
more and more scarce,
restricted to cooler and higher places.
These geladas are being forced
higher into the mountains.
Soon there will be nowhere left to go.
This is a species living on the edge.
Even though they're isolated
on the mountain tops,
they're not immune to our influence.
As a result of changing climate,
these gelada baboons
may soon be gone from our planet.
Africa is the world's hottest continent.
And there is no doubt,
it's getting warmer.
The Sahara is the largest
hot desert in the world.
Very little can survive
in these harsh conditions.
Along the desert edge, life clings on
in the face of encroaching sands.
But for how long?
Alongside the wildlife,
22 million people struggle to make a living
on these desert margins.
Can anything be done to stop the sand
overwhelming this fragile land?
One idea is to build
a green wall of trees
across 11 countries.
The project has already started,
in Senegal,
but, like all big ideas,
it has big problems.
Getting 11 countries
to work together is not easy,
and simply irrigating
a 5,000-mile-long belt of trees
is an ambitious task.
But, all over Africa,
people are recognising
how important it is to have trees
as part of their local landscape.
This group of volunteers has planted
nearly 100 million saplings.
And they're just one of countless
similar groups and individuals,
taking it upon themselves
to reforest their own part
of this great continent.
Trees are essential
for the future of the continent,
and indeed to the rest of the planet.
This is the Congo basin.
It's one of the most biologically
important forests on Earth,
and it's not just because
of the concentration
of plants and animals that live here.
It's because it's also one
of the powerhouses
behind the planet's wind and rain.
Each hectare of trees releases as vapour
almost 190,000 litres of water a year.
This water passes into the atmosphere,
to be transported
around the entire globe.
That means the heart
of the world's weather
lies in tropical forests.
Unfortunately, there's an almost
insatiable demand in Europe and China,
for hardwood from these very forests.
And that is having an enormous impact.
As more tropical forest is felled,
some scientists are
seeing a correlation
with changing storm patterns
across Europe and America.
And it's likely to become more extreme.
Staggeringly,
50 percent of the Congo basin forest
has been allocated for logging.
The future of Africa's forests
has never been more critical for us all.
But the consequences of global warming
aren't limited to the land.
Africa is almost completely
surrounded by oceans.
Here, on the east coast,
there are animals feeling
the change in climate
in a most surprising way.
This is a young female green turtle.
During her lifetime,
she will travel thousands of miles
through the ocean, looking for food.
Turtles return to the same beach
from which they hatched
to lay their own eggs.
The eggs are buried in the sand,
and the hatchlings will emerge
after about two months.
Now, there's a strange thing.
about turtle eggs,
and that is the temperature
at which the eggs are kept
will determine the sex
of most of the hatchlings.
If the sand temperature is high,
they will be female.
If it's low, they will be male.
So global warming
could have a crucial effect
on turtle populations.
And this young female
may find it very difficult,
in years to come,
to find a male with which to mate.
But a local conservation group
recognised that the odds are stacking up
against these little turtles.
There's not much they can do
about climate change,
but they have got together
with the local fishermen
to try and improve
the turtles' chances of survival.
Every turtle counts.
So each time one is found injured
or accidentally caught in the nets,
it's brought to Kahindi Changawa
and his team.
So we began with only
16 fishermen altogether, in 1998,
and now we have hundreds
of fishermen working with us.
Grazing by turtles
is essential for the health
of the beds of seagrass.
And these are the home
of shrimps and lobsters,
and that, of course,
helps fishermen, too.
The project has a turtle
rehabilitation centre,
and for the last two years,
it's become home to Shella.
She had an accident with a boat,
was hit from behind.
She lost three ribs
and her spine was, as well, damaged.
It's now in the process
of healing back together.
Shella's injuries have affected her buoyancy.
She's healed well,
and to encourage her
to exercise her flippers properly,
she has, every day,
a little trip to the seaside.
So we usually take Shella
for a sea bath on daily basis,
and the whole reason why
we're doing that,
we're trying to give her
enough room to get exercises.
And she gets an opportunity
to eat her natural food.
We believe that it keeps her fit,
and the other thing is she gets
to use her rear flippers quite often.
For Kahindi, it's one
of the rewards for all his hard work.
It's really, really enjoyable.
Very few people have the privilege,
like I do,
swimming with the turtles,
and having that fun.
I do enjoy what I'm doing.
Shella certainly did get stronger,
but the hope that someday
she might swim out in the open
was not to be fulfilled.
Unaccountably, she became weaker
and eventually died.
This kind of work will
inevitably have setbacks.
But there are always
new turtles to be cared for.
Is she healthy?
Yeah, this one is healthy.
I mean, she has a few bruises,
could be from the fishing gear.
Um, like these ones here.
Oh, yeah, but otherwise healthy?
Otherwise, the turtle
is obviously really healthy.
Shall we let her go?
Since 1998, till now,
we've released over 8,200 turtles.
It fills me...
feel proud and privileged.
We've done lots of work
with the community,
on changing their attitudes
and their behaviours and everything.
So I guess...
our job as an organisation
is really successful.
A young turtle like that
could lay 6,000 or 7,000 eggs
in her lifetime.
So the survival of just one
could have huge consequences.
Saving just one individual
requires huge effort,
and of course, saving a species
requires even more.
But these heroic efforts are only
ever going to be a partial solution.
Every individual animal is part
of a much bigger story,
part of an interconnected web
of plants, animals,
and the landscape itself,
that make up an entire ecosystem.
Saving ecosystems is the key
to Africa's wild future.
Gorongosa in Mozambique,
is a modern-day Jurassic Park.
It's ruled by some
of the world's biggest crocodiles.
Some of these monsters
are six metres long
and close to 50 years old.
Somehow, they managed to escape
a civil war lasting nearly 20 years,
which swept through Gorongosa.
95% of all the other large animals
were wiped out.
But 50 years ago
the scene was very different.
This was a thriving tourist attraction,
a wild paradise.
Visitors flocked from around the world,
drawn by the vast range
and abundance of the wildlife.
The most popular spot for tourists
was an old restaurant,
a lookout post for the local lions.
The restaurant has long gone.
Along with the lions.
Gorongosa looked empty
and beyond rescue.
But not to everyone.
A brave and ambitious project began
to try and restore the park
to its former richness and splendour.
The first stage
is to find out which animals,
as well as crocodiles, are still here.
So the team is mapping and counting all
the big animals they see in the park.
But it soon became clear that these
big animals were only part of the story.
Perhaps even more important
might be the little ones
hidden underfoot.
It's understanding these creatures
that is attracting
some of the best minds
in the scientific world.
You were going to show me something?
Yeah, something new.
Professor Ed Wilson
is a world expert on biodiversity.
And at a mere 83,
he's still pursuing his passion -
ants.
You see, there's a big nest of...
I think they're Myrmicarias.
Wow! Let me just get one specimen.
If you look down at your feet,
you may see them,
walking by here and there, an ant,
a little beetle...
What I like to call
the little things that run the earth.
It's the rich diversity
of insect life here
that gives Gorongosa
the prospect of a future.
These creatures form
the basis of life in the park.
This is so much fun.
These little invertebrate creatures,
the creatures that do most of the work,
turn most of the energy,
save most of the material,
and allow us to re-insert big animals
with some confidence.
Have you got it in the vial yet?
Yeah, I got three of them.
Oh, good.
Professor Wilson was one of the first scientists
to explore this area,
together with local wildlife biologist
Tonga Torcida.
That's a good one.
If you could gather them all up,
all these little invertebrate creatures,
and weigh them,
they would weigh...
far more than all of the big animals
put together,
even in a fully restored park.
It's these little creatures,
together with the plants and trees,
that still make this place
a viable option
for re-introducing bigger animals.
I can't be sure that's a new species
but, you know, this is the kind
of thing that might be.
This park came...
that close to vanishing.
And I'm happy to report
it is coming back.
And this is one of the great stories.
It's inspirational, I think.
And it's a fine shining example
of what to do with all our parks,
even those that have been damaged
by human activity.
But there's another reason
why Gorongosa is important
for the future of Africa,
and perhaps for us all.
So it is here, in this park,
that people come to see...
not just the big animals
that thrill us,
but they will see Earth
as it looked and felt
before the coming of humanity.
Saving big animals is important,
but to do that with any real success,
we have to start understanding
and preserving the plants and insects
that support an ecosystem.
It's this that will allow
the large animals to thrive.
Gorongosa is a real success story.
The government and the management team
have pledged themselves to a plan
to restore the land to what it was.
While it can never be exactly
the same as it was before the war,
it can still become a rich
and thriving ecosystem.
The scale of the challenge
across Africa is enormous.
After all, it's a huge continent.
The United Kingdom, China,
the United States of America,
India, Japan and most
of the rest of Europe
would all fit within its borders.
Africa still retains 45 percent
of the Earth's uncultivated land.
It's still the greatest wilderness
on Earth.
And that is why it's important.
Human beings have lived
alongside wildlife here
longer than anywhere else.
But now, in the 21st century,
animal numbers are at a critical level.
Like it or not,
this generation is responsible
for handing on the world's wildlife
to the next.
Come on...
That means taking care of the animals
and lands where they live,
so there is still space
for us all to coexist.
Nobody knows...
what the future has in store
for this little calf.
Or, indeed,
how the changes that inevitably
are going to take place in Africa
will affect the rest of the world
and this little animal.
But one thing is certain -
what happens here
is more important
than it has ever been,
and that the relationship
of the rest of the world
to this great continent
and the creatures that live in it
is more important than ever before.
On whichever part of the planet we live,
we all have a part to play
in what sort of future
this wild continent has.
Africa, the final shoot.
It's one of our most ambitious trips,
with lots of locations to visit
and many technical hurdles to overcome.
Five, take one.
To the west, a vast rainforest
the size of India.
Helicopters enable us to go
to extraordinary landscapes.
We're heading off
to do the very first piece to camera,
the opening of the whole Africa series
with David.
Well, how do you like
the view from my office?
And attempt air-to-air filming.
Standby, David, and action!
I'm flying over the Great Rift Valley
in East Africa.
But perhaps the most ambitious task for this shoot
is the filming with black rhinoceros.
They have a reputation
for being aggressive
and, with poor eyesight,
they're likely to charge objects
or people they don't recognise.
But the plight of the rhino
is such an important story
that we want to get as
close to them as possible.
We also want to meet the people
who are working to protect them.
So our team have come to assess
the viability of filming up-close
with a rhino called Elvis,
who's been reared by humans.
He should be safer than a wild rhino,
but there's still a risk he could be
unpredictable with strangers.
Wildlife ranger Tonga Casio
has bought up Elvis by hand
and knows that tickling him gently
with a stick keeps him calm.
But if anything were to go seriously wrong,
there would be little he could do
against the one-tonne Elvis.
And this fact hasn't escaped
cameraman Mike Fox.
He knows we're here.
We're here on his terms.
If he decided to bat us all
into the next world, he would do.
Director Kate Broome checks with Tonga
that it's safe for the crew to get closer.
Normally we have to stay in the Land Rovers.
He's saying it's okay to go in.
This is such an extraordinary opportunity,
to be this close to a black rhino.
The trial goes well with Elvis.
And the stage is set for future filming.
What I'm saying...
Several weeks later,
the team are back.
And this time I've joined them.
But Elvis's mood has changed.
He seems more wilful.
Now, I've stood by many wild animals
in my time,
but I'm not as fast on my pins
as I used to be.
We don't want to test Elvis's patience,
so we get on with filming.
A horn that is worth its weight in gold.
And one way...
of protecting him...
would be...
to cut that horn off the nose.
How is it?
Looks great.
The team check that they have what they need,
and Elvis lets us know
that he's had enough.
Just watch out everybody. Yeah.
- Okay.
- Right then.
But, actually,
it's a positive sign
that Elvis is not as friendly this time.
Tonga and his colleagues want Elvis
to live more like a wild rhino
and develop a wariness of humans,
that may offer him some protection
from poachers.
Good luck to you, Elvis.
Whilst filming, we are lucky enough
to have a very well-equipped camp.
It's in the bush and there's no escaping
the wild animals.
One of the great, wonderful things
about camping out
in the middle of the open
is the animals.
But it could also be one of
the dangerous, stroke, annoying things.
Absolutely.
In the annoying category - vervet monkeys.
Vervet monkeys have stolen
my Ferrero Rocher,
and one of my glow sticks
from our medical supplies.
Um, so if we see a luminous-faced monkey
in the night, um,
I'll identify the naughty one
that's been stealing our stuff.
And they leave little, uh,
presents for us
when they've been in,
just as a calling card.
But camp manager Andres
finds more worrying animal signs.
Well, the lions were quite close, um,
just behind the tents.
And some must have come in,
and I don't know, uh...
You can see a few scratches.
I think maybe he was wanting to look
at himself in the mirror.
Lions in camp are worrying enough,
but there I was reading my book,
when...
- Uh, uh...
- Whoa!
A Cape buffalo arrives.
The most grumpy and dangerous
of the big five African animals.
Mike, stay in your tent.
Should we get David to get in the tent?
Buffalo usually move in herds,
so there's something odd about him.
It may be that it was brought up
as a calf, and is humanised,
or it may be that he's an outcast
from the herd, in some way,
and that he's rather grumpy
and fed up with life.
Uh, but I think it's just hot,
and he's just trotting around
and wondering where he might
get a drink and a decent sandwich.
Because I feel the same way
myself actually.
The team's filming has coincided
with the newest arrival
at Lewa.
A baby rhino in need of 24-hour care.
This little chap was born blind
and is guided everywhere by his keepers.
They took him away from his mother
a few weeks ago
because she couldn't protect him any more.
He's very vulnerable, so he would have
been killed by predators.
It's like filling up a petrol tank.
Every rhino is precious.
And so it seems a fitting end
for the final scene of the series.
No one knows what the future holds
for this little creature.
Nor, indeed,
what changes will take place
in the great continent
on which he lives.
David, I found that...
Gosh, there's ants.
They're everywhere, yeah, hang on.
Ants! Ants attack.
I just found that
extraordinarily moving, actually.
- What I said was all right?
- Yes.
You sure?
And how you did it... I just...
It made me cry.
I'm afraid so.
David Attenborough has made me cry.
But just as we think we're finishing,
someone won't let us go.
Hello, little friend.
He starts to squeak.
And we're able to have a little chat.
Think about it.
He's got a black world, doesn't he?
And, uh, he's got smell.
And he's got sound, so...
He's more likely to be responding to sound
if he hasn't got the vision.
And yet, just inquisitive, I suppose.
You coming back?
There is hope for this little fellow.
He's due to have an operation
on his eyes,
which may mean that, as an adult,
he could be returned to the wild.
Just like Elvis.
I do hope he gets a cataract operation.
It'd be marvellous if he did.
Well, what an enchanting creature.