Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Lulu, sweet thing.
l miss her.
l hate the rain.
lt makes me all sentimental.
You're probably wondering
what an old robot like myself is doing...
having all these feelings.
Well, l'll tell you...
but we gotta go back,
way back to the beginning.
Aku's beginning.
Ages ago, Aku slowly rose to power
and enslaved the world.
But he wasn't fast enough.
He needed an army.
A robot army.
Aku's evil scientists began to build.
The first models were crude.
But as time progressed,
the scientists got better.
Much better.
We were the X-models.
Lean, mean, and all machine.
Except me.
See, one of the scientists...
installed an experimental
emotion chip inside of me.
Why?
He was funny that way.
Emotions are bad news
for somebody in my profession.
l began to have feelings.
l started to understand
right from wrong...
and what l did was very wrong.
l became the best.
The emotions helped.
ln a bad scrape,
the other X-models couldn't care.
l cared.
l got angry. lt wasn't pretty.
But then, l met Lulu, sweet thing.
l retired.
The last X-model left.
l was lucky, too, because those scientists
made a new breed of robots.
Bugbots or something like that.
l didn't care, though.
Me and Lulu had a good thing.
Music.
We love music.
Lulu, sweet thing.
Time passed, but...
it made no difference to us
until Lulu disappeared.
Seems like Aku
got himself a little problem.
A problem that won't go away.
A samurai problem.
l wanted nothing to do with it...
but that funny scientist
informed Aku of my emotions.
They'd got Lulu.
Sweet thing.
l had no choice.
l came out of retirement.
Tracking the Samurai wasn't difficult.
The new bug, beetlebots, or whatever,
were no match.
The Samurai's good, real good.
l've never seen such talent.
l'm not sure
if l even have a chance.
But l gotta try...
for Lulu, sweet thing.
Well, that brings us
back to the beginning.
The Samurai is shacked up
in that old robot factory.
Kind of ironic, huh?
As soon as the rain stops,
l'll go in and get him.
For Lulu, sweet thing.
l hate the rain.
Lulu... Take care of Lulu...
Sweet thing.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "