Long ago, in a distant land...
I, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
OK, so you want
a little off of the top?
Yes, sir, it's no problem.
Well, we don't get many people
up in these parts, kind of slow, you know...
but l will make you look sharp.
Yes, sir!
You are in good hands with Tonino
'cause l'm the best!
l've been cutting hair all of my life.
No matter how big or small,
l cut them all.
Mamma mia!
lt's Jujunga,
the aboriginal bounty hunter.
His blowgun has captured
the most elusive prey.
A tattooed terror!
What is he doin' this far north?
Must be on some kind of hunt.
Certainly ain't here for the night life!
So, as l was saying...
lt's l and Am,
the infamous twins...
bounty hunter legends.
Their techniques are so cunning...
their abilities so in tune...
it's rumored
that they share the same mind.
That reminds me, back in the old days...
how l used to hang around
the barber shop...
with all of the customers...
some with nice, black, thick hair,
you know, like all of...
Sorry! Zabaglione!
lt's The Gentleman.
He's a nice fella but deadly.
This bounty hunter dueled with many...
but none could escape his skill.
The knives are his weapon of choice.
Look at him so stylish, oh, so fancy!
Great hair!
What's this?
l never seen this one before.
Curious.
A strange fella. l wonder...
Oh, my!
You...you...you're...
Boris, biggest, baddest
bounty hunter of all!
Da!
What is up here?
lt seems there is a problem
you cannot deny.
We are all here
for the same samurai.
lndeed we are,
but l see no reason to discuss this...
in the most frigid
of temperatures.
l suggest that we confer
on this delicate matter...
inside this nearby
vacant structure.
Da! lt is cold.
lt seems we have amassed
quite a committee.
But only one of us
can claim this bounty.
lt seems that
the one who goes first...
will have the best chance
of collecting everything.
l have come here before everyone.
l will go first.
He has no chance
against the power of Jujunga.
As the Samurai approaches...
l shall sit by the roadside playing the flute.
He will pause a moment
and listen to the beautiful sounds...
slowly being lulled
into false security.
At the moment he's
at his most vulnerable...
my trap is sprung.
My flute is really a blowgun...
with darts dipped
in the most lethal of poisons.
This bounty will be mine!
You will fail.
Your plan is flawed.
How? lt has never failed me before.
lt cannot be defeated.
The Samurai's senses are too acute.
He will hear you take a breath
before you fire...
and easily avoid your dart completely.
You wouldn't stand a chance!
The Gentleman reluctantly must agree
with our mysterious friend.
You lack a certain style,
a savoir-faire...
that is required
for this particular bounty.
Whereas l, on the other hand, have
all the wit and panache necessary...
to take on such a worthy adversary.
For l shall meet
my most studious of samurais...
out on the field of honor..
in a duel,
a duel of epic proportions.
lt is true the Samurai has great skills...
that no one can deny...
but on this day, my friends...
it is The Gentleman who will prevail...
for my talents are far superior...
and my strategy
is as sound as l am elegant.
Yes, l will take advantage
of his intense concentration...
and split his focus...
forcing him to choose
between life and death.
My cloak acting
as shield and decoy...
for the coup de grâce.
Now, l'm not one to brag...
but l must say that my blades
fly faster than any bullet.
He will not be able
to escape them.
l assure you, indeed...
this bounty will be mine.
lt is definitely the end for you.
Pardon me?
He is too disciplined
to fall for your tricks.
Your decoy alone
is not strong enough.
A stylish plan it sounds, indeed.
But he is right.
An attack like that will not succeed.
- Listen to our plan.
- And you will see.
- lt is ''l''.
- And ''Am'' who will claim this bounty.
As the Samurai enters the town...
we will wait for the final showdown.
Concealed we will be.
Our surprise he will never see.
l will attack from the rear...
and Am from the sun will appear.
A thousand bombs
will fall from the sky.
ln his confusion,
the Samurai will surely die.
You're on the right track,
but the two of you can never defeat Jack.
Jack is cunning and hard to restrain.
By leaving him a sword
he stays in the game.
Enough with this kiddie talk.
Boris is best.
Bounty belongs to Boris.
Little man is coming.
l do not wait.
He will attack with sword.
lt breaks against my belly.
Then l break him!
Break him! Break him!
Break him!
That's how Boris gets the bounty!
Any questions?!
Have you always been this stupid?
Yes!
What? What? No...
You've underestimated your opponent.
You have no idea
what you're up against.
You will all run headlong into death!
What?!
Your skills are most impressive...
and your talents certainly
seem to match your wisdom.
lf you would be so inclined,
kind sir, to reveal yourself to us.
A woman?!
Oh, my!
l am Princess Mira
of the Andaluvians.
l've heard of her.
She's powerful.
ls she the one
who captured that guy...
on that planet...
- Yes.
- Oh, my!
Well, she is good.
l have more power and skill
than all of you.
lt seems her tongue
bites as hard as her stick.
But even l cannot defeat
the Samurai on my own.
- What's that?
- The only way to defeat him...
is to join forces
and attack him together, all at once!
A wise and powerful plan
this would be.
But who is the one
to claim the bounty?
- l am!
- No woman will!
Silence!
l must claim this bounty.
But not for the money.
For freedom.
The freedom of my people
and my kingdom.
Aku has enslaved my nation
for many years...
plundering our wealth
and resources.
l will collect this bounty,
and for payment...
l will ask for my people to be freed,
and my kingdom restored.
ln return for your help,
l will pay you the sum of the bounty...
plus tenfold!
My, my!
That is much money.
Her land has priceless resources.
- Priceless?
- So it seems.
- lt seems to me.
- That Boris does agree.
Da! Much money, please!
- You'll get it.
- l better.
- You will.
You will.
OK, what is plan?
This is what we'll do.
This is the plan.
Well, it certainly seems to be
a wise and prudent plan, my dear.
lt is good.
Plan OK.
Boris would have had better plan.
Da.
Good. Let's get to work!
Am, you head up the road
and hide in the trees.
Watch for the Samurai
and alert us when he comes.
The rest of us dig.
l hate taking orders from woman.
Hey, you, country boy man...
how about you and me team up
and collect bounty, no?
The Gentleman
never goes back on his word.
Besides, our present course
of action is, in fact...
the most lucrative
for all parties involved.
You must be crazy, sir.
Simple answer, da or no?
Keep digging!
OK.
He's coming.
Positions!
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "