Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
l'm just trying to find your lost brain!
Like, l'm not Samurai Jack.
All right, then. All aboard!
- lt's calm.
- Aye, sir.
- Dead calm.
- l don't like it.
- Aye, sir.
Refreshments!
Like, somebody call the weatherman!
That was sudden.
- Keep your wits about you, men.
- Aye, sir.
Sounds like someone's stepping on a cat.
Sounds like someone's
stepping on a lot of cats.
- Beautiful.
- Aye, captain.
- Music...go!
Have you all lost your brains?!
Lovely.
Well, now.
You don't see that every day.
Tribute.
Yeah. Keep walking, zombie boy.
So, you're the cause of all this racket!
Nice thing you got going here...
turning people into mindless zombies...
with a sound that can gag a yak!
" One seems to resist "
" Are you not affected by our song? "
" Don't you love us? "
" Adore us? "
You're all tone-deaf!
A banshee can at least carry a tune!
The sound of breaking glass
has more rhythm!
l've heard pigs squeal better than you!
You call this singing?!
Now, my wife, she can sing!
Her angelic voice floats
such melodious and heavenly tunes...
it makes angels weep.
The sun rises just to hear
her morning melodies.
Even the sweetest of birds
can learn a thing or two...
from my precious bonnie lass.
But you! You cough out wilted notes
not fit for a whistle!
So, what did you do to me friend here?!
" Oh, yes "
" He was most troublesome "
" Trying to free our slaves "
" Until we sang the song
that robbed him of his mind "
" And set him out
to wander the world as a fool "
" For ever "
" While keeping his treasure as a prize "
That's it!
She-dogs must pay!
You robbed your last brain...
you deadly wailing
tune-screeching women!
All right, all right.
Now look.
l don't want to hurt you.
Snap out of it!
lt's the music
that's making you crazy!
lt's making me crazy it's so bad with...
lf it's music you want...
get a load of me pipes!
l remember now.
We sure showed them, eh, buddy?
l am forever in your debt.
Don't mention it.
So, how you been?
- Like, totally cool.
- What?!
So, there you were...
shivering like
a gold-dean hootin' daddy...
No? Really?
..and out comes the beast...
and you're screaming
like a wimpy man, and then...
How embarrassing!
And then you faint dead away.
With a little whimper at the end.
Where do you think you're going?!
You ungrateful guinea-wolf taddies!
Come back here!
We saved you
from a fate worse than death!
You could at least give us a lift,
you milk-drinkin' silpit!
Well, my toonie bloot!
Sorry-faced, plookie...
curly breeked stoogies!
Can you believe that?
We missed the boat.
- Laddie, we're in luck!
- How fortunate!
l shall do the honors
of rowing us back.
Nope, l'll row! Least l can do.
My friend,
you have done so much already.
l am forever in your debt.
Allow me to honor your deeds.
l shall row back.
Nice try. l'm driving.
But l am afraid l must insist.
No. l insist.
- l must row.
- l'm rowing!
- l must row!
This will not do.
We must decide through contest!
Well, what do you have in mind?
A test of strength perhaps.
Oh, no! l remember last time.
- You cheated.
- l do not cheat.
Perhaps not,
but you sure don't play by the rules.
Here, take a stone,
so you can't pull no wily tricks.
The man who throws it
the farthest wins.
Very well.
Good luck.
All right. Best two out of three, then.
Feat of speed!
First man round the island
crosses this line rows.
On the count of three.
Ready?
Three!
l...got another one...for you.
That branch.
- Jump good.
- Yeah, yeah.
All right!
Give me your hand, laddie.
We'll wrestle for it!
Thumb-wrestle.
One.
Two.
Three!
No!
- One, two, three.
- All right.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "