Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Will these visions never cease?
l see you.
l see inside of you.
A gentle soul.
A compassionate heart.
A warrior's spirit.
A selfless service.
Yes.
lt is in your nature to sacrifice all
for what is right.
Forever giving.
You are a hero.
Well, l...
- But what replenishes you?
- Well...
What is your quest, young servant?
What brings you
through such bitter lands?
My destiny.
But it continues to be elusive.
And so, l journey on.
You have suffered for far too long.
Who are you?
- Why...
- To aid you in your cause.
l have come to give you nourishment,
to provide for you.
- But l...
- You are tired, weary of battle.
Like a weight upon your shoulders,
your quest offers you no peace.
Well, yes, but...
Stay a moment where it is peaceful.
Rejuvenate your senses
and regain your strengths.
There is water to drink and food to eat.
Be at peace, young servant.
Be at peace.
l am...
l thank you but l do not think l can...
ls it not true that even the gods
must rest from time to time?
lt is true.
And you are not a god.
No.
Then why deny yourself?
lt serves no purpose.
Fear not.
Your destiny will still be there for you,
even after you've rested.
Well, maybe for just a moment.
l am weary from travel.
- l should go.
- Stay. You must not leave, not yet.
Stay. Rest.
No, l must go!
No! You will stay!
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "