Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Not again after all these years.
Your Highness,
l'm afraid the city guard...
is no match
for these Squoomian gunships.
Contact Admiral Lantana!
We must recall our fleet
from the Pydian System.
Sire, the Deep Space Antenna Array
has been destroyed!
Radio contact with the Star Navy
has been severed.
Blast those Squoomian devils!
We have no sign of them for a decade,
yet they re-surface...
just when our defenses
are most compromised.
Captain, begin evacuation!
My children, come.
Verbina, Astor, you two
must get word to Admiral Lantana...
on errand
deep within the Pydian System.
You must bring back our navy.
You are our only hope.
You can count on us, mother.
We will not fail our people.
Chitron 6, make ready the ship.
- Oh, my! Yes, sir!
- Wing well, my children. Wing well.
We're clearing Chrysalis ionosphere.
Chitron, calculate jump vector
for the Pydian System.
Triangulating...
and entered now, Your Majesty.
Oh, my!
Your Majesties' sensors detect...
Squoomians!
Three vessels bearing 1 mark 08.
Shields down to 35% !
Mulch! We're totally outgunned.
We can't take any more hits!
Astor, we've got to shake them.
l know. l know.
l bet l could lose them in The Ring.
Oh, my!
We lost one of 'em.
Great, Astor, but don't get cocky.
- Watch out!
- Hang on!
- Nice work, brother!
- Stunning flightsmanship indeed!
Thanks. Now, Verbina,
we should be clear for that hyperjump.
lgnition ready.
Deploying hypervibe wings.
Prepare to jump in three, two, one.
- No! Come on, come on!
- Now what?
One of those hits severed the vibrodrive
uplink to the starboard hyperwing.
A relatively simple fix, but we will have
to set down before l can effect repairs.
Where in the silk
are we gonna land around here?
Chitron, what about...
the third planet
in this yellow star system?
A largely nickel-based planet,
molten core, solid crust...
with a generous amount
of surface moisture.
No fog layer, no dewsphere.
lt's just a wet rock?
l'm afraid it's not very hospitable...
but atmosphere and temperature
are compatible.
lt'll have to do. Set course.
So glad to see you conscious again,
Your Majesties.
- We'll be all right.
- The ship?
l regret l was unable
to initiate a proper landing...
but l did get to the helm in time
to keep the nose up, if you will.
Good job, Chitron. We should...
l feel like l weigh a ton.
Yes. The planet's gravity
is much heavier than our own.
You two should rest, save your strength.
l'll have that wing relinked as quickly as...
Oh, my! l detect natives
approaching our position.
We can't fly, Astor.
This gravity is just too strong.
Greetings, fellow Chitron units.
l am Chitron 6 in service
to the royal house of Chrysalis.
lt seems my masters and l...
..and we'll be on our way
as soon as it's repaired.
You will see Aku.
l've got a bad feeling about this.
Yes, chamberlain.
What pitiable persons
have you brought...
before my all-enshrouding Akuness?
Trespassers
who invaded the Wasteland shore...
without proper clearance
and tariffs, my lord.
Well, what have you
to say for yourselves?
Great lord Aku, l am Verbina,
Princess of Alepidopterans.
My brother Prince Astor,
and our assistant Chitron 6.
Salutations, o most majestic one!
l must say, it's an honor.
We humbly beg
your forgiveness for our trespass.
We meant no offense
and certainly no conspiracy.
We are on an urgent mission,
for our homeworld, Chrysalis...
is under attack.
Our ancient enemies,
the vile Squoomians...
have returned from the depths
to lay siege on our capital!
As the palace burned,
our parents sent us into space...
with orders to recall our star navy
and bring them home...
to repel this heinous attack.
But our ship was damaged
and forced us to land.
Again, we appeal to you,
most wise and powerful one.
We ask only time enough...
to repair our ship,
so that we may depart...
and trouble you no more,
o gracious Aku.
Such a sad story!
Whatever can l do
to put an end to this tragic tale?
l know!
Chamberlain,
have their ship confiscated!
Captain, throw them in irons
and take them into the mines...
where they can live
miserably ever after!
You can't do that!
These are royal heirs
to the throne of Chrysalis! You can't just...
Chitron!
l certainly can!
l am Aku, this world is Aku,
and everything in it is Aku!
Now, shoo these moths away.
You beast! You devil! Villain!
Strange.
l thought l sensed a presence.
Take him!
Aren't you a little short
for a demonic minion?
The uniform.
l am called Jack,
and l'm here to rescue you.
Quickly. We must reach your ship
before Aku's drones.
Pull up, pull up, pull up!
Please slow down!
You don't know
how to fly this thing, do you?
l like to walk.
Do you even know
where our ship is?
Yes. l heard you crash,
and when l saw you captured...
l followed,
thinking you might need some help.
Good.
Then you navigate, and l'll drive.
- Your Majesties.
- Yes, Jack. Come...
Hello? Prince-- Ver--ina,
can --ou --ear me?
Yes, Jack. What is it?
Verbina, l ca--not hear --ou!
Do you read --e?
Jack, don't keep pushing the button.
Let go of the button to listen,
push down the button to talk!
How are the repairs going?
Slow.
Your gravity doesn't help much.
But we'll do it.
We're almost there.
Good work.
Now it is my turn.
Wing link reconnected.
Main power on-line.
- All systems are go.
- We're clear for launch.
Oh, my silk. Look outside!
Jack, the repairs are done. Hurry!
Good, princess.
Make your escape now.
l will keep the drones at bay.
We can't leave you!
Jack, the top hatch is open. Hurry!
The drones would swarm the ship
before l could get inside. Now, go!
Go!
Jack!
Jack? Can we help him somehow?
With the ship's artificial gravity back on...
l feel strong enough
to take those drones myself.
Maybe we can.
lf we recalibrate the gravity generator
to full negative...
and reroute it through
the transmission dish...
We could extend
the ship's force field out...
far enough
to encapsulate the drone horde...
Negating the gravity
within the entire bubble!
Jack, we did it.
Look. We really did it!
Oh, thank you, Jack.
Thank you!
Yes, thank you, Jack.
You risked your life to help us,
yet we are strangers.
How can we possibly
show our gratitude?
- Save your home.
- What?!
We are not such strangers, l think.
Our stories are much alike.
For l, too, was a prince...
given charge to save my land.
But l...
l could not let your story end like mine.
With Aku!
Your story's not over yet.
Go to your people.
There is no time to lose.
Yes, Your Majesty.
- Wing well, Jack.
- We won't forget you!
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "