Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Peaches.
- Well, you know, l like some carrots.
- How about some turnips?
Right! Carrots, turnips, what else?
A nice bit of onion.
Now, hold on a minute,
onions makes his breath reek.
And how is that different
from any other day?
That's true.
Your breath always reeks.
Righty-oh, onions it is!
Right, let's see.
With all these vegetables,
l might like a pinch of spice.
Now, hold on.
When you say a pinch of spice,
it better just be a pinch!
Yeah! Last time you spiced
the bloody heck out of it!
My mouth was burning for two days!
What are you, a bunch of nancies?!
l'm just saying,
this is a nice piece of meat...
and l'd like to taste
the natural flavors coming through!
All right, all right. Nancies.
Blimey, he's stealing our dinner.
Yes, OK.
Please, l understand,
but you must be quiet.
Please, please be quiet.
Right, come on,
l think l heard him over this way.
Blimey, l swear l heard him over here.
Now to find your parents.
There, there, little one.
The fire will keep us warm tonight.
My mother used to tell me a story
when l could not sleep.
Would you like to hear it?
OK.
Long, long ago,
in the land of my ancestors...
there lived
an old woodcutter and his wife.
They loved each other very much.
Yet they were often sad,
for they had no children.
But one day,
the king of heaven smiled upon them...
and sent a gift.
As the old woman
was washing some clothes by the river...
a huge peach came floating downstream.
She took it home with her.
And when her husband returned home
from chopping wood that evening...
she presented
the giant peach for supper.
''l have never seen such a marvelous fruit,''
exclaimed the old man.
''Let us taste it right away!''
But just before they could slice it,
the peach popped open...
and there stood
a beautiful baby boy.
The old couple were shocked,
to say the least.
''Don't worry,'' said the boy.
''l have been sent from heaven
to be your son.''
The couple were overjoyed,
and named their new son...
Momotaro,
which means ''peach boy''.
They loved him
with all their hearts.
And Momotaro grew
into a fine, strong boy.
One day, Peach Boy
went to his parents.
''Mother, father,'' he said...
''you have been so kind to me,
l want to repay you.''
He told them
he wanted to travel to Ogre lsland...
and rid the country of the terrible ogres
that robbed and pillaged the land.
The old couple worried
for Momotaro's safety...
but they knew he was a special boy.
Along his travels...
Momotaro came across a hungry dog,
who meant to bite him.
But he gave the dog
one of the dumplings...
his mother had packed for him instead.
''l am going to fight the ogres
on Ogre lsland,'' said Momotaro.
''Then l will help you,''
said the grateful dog.
Soon they met an angry monkey,
who threw sticks at them.
Momotaro threw a dumpling
back at the monkey.
The monkey's mood quickly changed.
And when he learned
of where they were going...
the monkey vowed
to help them fight the ogres, too.
As the three left the forest,
they met a vigilant pheasant.
The pheasant turned out
to be fond of dumplings...
but not fond of ogres at all...
and decided to join Momotaro
on his mission.
When the band of adventurers
reached the sea...
they went to work building a boat...
and soon set sail for Ogre lsland.
Momotaro and his friends came ashore...
and found an ominous fortress...
full of terrible ogres of all kinds.
The gate was well-guarded,
but Peach Boy devised a plan.
''Pheasant flew over the walls
and attacked the guards!''
The ogres swung at him,
but the quick Pheasant dodged their blows.
With the guards distracted,
Monkey climbed the wall...
and unlocked the gate,
so that Momotaro and Spotted Dog...
could charge in
and take the ogres by surprise.
lt was a terrible battle.
Pheasant pecked the ogres' heads.
Dog bit at them.
Monkey clawed their faces.
And Momotaro swung at them
with his father's ax.
At last, the ogres surrendered.
They bowed before Momotaro in defeat...
and gave him all the treasure
they had stolen...
promising to never do
wicked deeds again.
The four friends heaped
the treasure onto their boat...
and sailed home to give it back
to the people of Peach Boy's land.
The woodcutter and his wife were
overjoyed to see their son return safely.
And with Momotaro home,
he and his family lived very, very happily.
Yes, yes, little one.
l, too, am hungry.
But l know not where to find breakfast
for one such as you.
My goodness,
what a hungry little fellow.
Are you feeling better with a full belly?
Yes. Me, too.
We'd best get on the road then, my friend.
Are you ready to travel?
You look ready.
Very strong, and ready to go.
Yes, you do.
Let us go.
You are a cagey rascal, yes.
But now that l have got you,
l am not letting go of you.
Oh, no, l am not.
Please do not cry. lt is all right.
Samurai Jack, prepare yourself...
for you are my bounty.
Wait! Look!
Look over here.
We must find your parents.
Please, no, do not get sick.
Please, do not get sick.
Do not worry, my little friend.
My mother made this for me
when l was not feeling well.
A little water and herbs
will do wonders for one's spirit.
Here, this will make you feel better.
Please, you must.
Perhaps some food.
Would you like some food?
Perhaps this will give you some strength.
You must have something.
What? What?
What would you like?
- What?
- Momo.
Well, well.
What do we have here?
lt's the skinny bloke who stole our dinner.
Don't worry, little baby.
We won't harm you.
At least not until supper time.
68, 43, 7 1!
l'm gonna stomp your bones!
Go get him!
l got it! l got it! l got it!
My baby! My baby!
Thank you, kind sir.
l thought l'd never see
my precious again.
There, there, baby.
Mama's got you now.
Precious? What...what is it?
What...
What have you done to my baby?!
l am afraid your son has seen
many things on our travels...
and has now achieved sakai...
the spirit of the samurai.
Momotaro!
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "