Long ago, in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
Master of Darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil!
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law!
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku!
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Got to get back "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "
Destroy him.
No, l will not fight you today.
l don't feel good.
Father?
Mother?
Not too smart, is it?
Going out into a blizzard
with just a funny robe and sandals?
You could catch your death
out there or worse.
The storm should pass by tomorrow.
You can rest here till then.
Here. This will give you
your strength back.
Thank you.
You are very kind.
lt's OK.
Just be careful next time.
That weather out there is no joke.
We've been mining up here
for the last five years.
We've managed to mine
these three priceless stones.
One more, we can retire
and leave this blasted mountain.
Will you stop with the showing off?!
Pretty soon, the whole mountain's
gonna know about those.
No need to worry, my friends.
Your secret is safe with me.
l owe you both my life.
What's with your hand there?
l don't know.
lt will not come off.
You better get some rest.
You sure you don't need anything?
No. Thank you.
l will be fine.
Brave kid.
Not too smart, but brave.
lt is still very cold.
Help!
Help...
Help.
- Can l help you?
- Boy, am l glad to see you!
l thought l'd never get out of here.
There l was, just checking out the view,
and it is beautiful, mind you...
when suddenly the floor
started to give way beneath me.
Luckily, this rope...
- Are you OK?
- l'm fine. How are you doing?
l am sorry.
Must have slipped.
No problem.
Don't even worry about it.
But if you could pull me up soon,
that would be good, too.
And why should l?
What's in it for me?
l'll give you anything you want,
just don't drop me, please!
Drop you? l will save you.
OK, so what do you want?
l do not want anything.
Except everything you've got.
l will accept nothing
for only doing what is right.
You're gonna pay,
or l shall drop you.
No, do not worry.
l will pull you up.
Come on!
Give me some money.
Please, we must hurry
before the rope breaks.
You know, never mind.
l think l'm just going
to stay here for a while and...
check out the view some more.
- Are you certain?
- Yeah.
Very well,
if that is what you desire.
But it's pretty stupid,
if you ask me.
l think...
you owe me an apology.
l said...
l'm gonna give you
until the count of three.
One.
Two.
Three.
l feel so...
l feel...
stronger!
No! No!
This cannot be happening.
Oh, yes, it can.
Must keep control.
Yeah! Got to get a grip.
Need help. The monks! l...
l'd better find those accursed monks!
Must find...
Yes?
- l am Jack.
- Oh, yes.
We have been awaiting
your arrival for many days.
The master was worried
an ill fate had befallen you.
Please, this way.
Master Ning...
l am sorry to disturb
your meditation...
but Jack, he has arrived.
Yes, the Wandering Samurai.
We were worried about you.
We began to wonder
if your quest had ended.
But we are glad
you are with us now.
Again, we extend our invitation.
We believe the Pool of Convergence
may be of use to you.
All factors of time and existence
converge here...
and form
an interdimensional nexus...
which we gaze into to study...
the infinite facets of reality.
We have never attempted
a physical journey...
but with proper conditioning
you would be able...
to step into this crossroads
and find your way home.
You seem weary, brother Jack.
Come! The purity of our spring
will refresh you.
Come, come.
Tell us of your quest.
What is it you seek?
l...
l seek...
l seek to foil the Samurai...
to destroy his dream
of returning home...
and to destroy
all who stand in my way!
Brothers, the pool!
Yes, slaughtering pathetic whelps...
is the perfect way
to loosen up...
before l really...
desecrate things.
Forgive me.
Be strong, my son.
You are gravely ill.
Aku's very essence
is creeping through your veins...
possessing your body,
poisoning your mind.
lt means to devour your spirit.
Please...help me.
l beg you.
We are doing what we can
to stave the illness of the flesh...
but we can only slow the sickness.
You have been infected
by pure evil...
which can only be purged
by the light of good...
the good within you.
l cannot.
You must help me.
l am sorry.
This is a sickness
only you can truly cure.
No...No...
You must. You...
You worthless, wrinkled grub!
l'll have you for dinner, you worm!
l'll eat every last monk
in this hole.
l'll devour you all...
just as l have consumed the Samurai!
Cannot fight it.
Not alone.
Cannot do it alone.
You are not alone, my son.
We are always
with you here.
Here, in your heart...
the place we will make
our stand against this evil.
But l was not there for you.
Nonsense.
Aku's victories are not your failures.
The struggle against Aku is arduous...
and none have fought
more bravely than you, my son.
You have won many victories...
rekindling hope in the hearts
of those you have protected.
Each sends their blessing.
Each blessing
a stone to fortify this land.
Your castle is strong, my son.
Your allies are many.
Wield what lies within...
and reclaim what is yours.
Break the siege of darkness.
Master Ning...
how can you forgive one
who has raised his sword against you...
and defiled your sanctuary so?
Although the Pool of Convergence
is destroyed...
the nexus still exists.
ln time, we will reconstruct the gateway.
As for you...
had you not defeated
the demon within...
it surely would have destroyed us all.
We owe you our lives.
My son, all debts are paid.
All but one.
l said, get off your fat tochis
and get the ladder, you lazy bum.
Don't yell at me!
l didn't steal the gems.
l think you better come out here.
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, back to the past,
Samurai Jack "
" Watch out! "
" Got to get back, Samurai Jack "