Get off of me.
- ♪ Fa la la la la ♪
- Jesus.
♪ Don we now our gay apparel ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la, la la la ♪
♪ Troll the ancient Yule tide carol ♪
♪ Fa la la la la... ♪
- ♪ Fa la la la la, la la la, la la la ♪
- Take a look behind us.
Following us.
- ♪ ...and join the chorus ♪
- Crap.
- ♪ Fa la la la la, la la la, la la la ♪
Oh, my God.
Hey... Hey.
Hey.
What's the plan? Are you just...
Where are we going?
What?
Is that...
You speak with sign language?
Are you kidding me?
How are we supposed...
Chained to a deaf guy.
Jesus.
We need to cut this.
We were headed north, towards Watab.
Maybe 40 minutes on the bus.
Maybe longer.
I think I fell asleep.
A river nearby...
The Mississippi, I'm guessing.
Hey.
Hey!
We need a plan.
A plan!
I knew a Helga once.
All she do... Talk, talk, talk.
Whoo-ee! Good shooting, son!
I think I got him.
Ray...
I thought I could tough it out
but I guess I'm a wimp.
Baby, please.
Baby...
Tell me you brought the getaway money.
Baby?
It's just... It happened so fast.
Ray, we need that money.
I know.
I'm going.
Ray...
You want me to go?
No. I'm fine.
I got it.
Put your back in it.
Oh. It's okay.
Get down. Get down. Get down.
No!
Okay. Okay. Okay...
One, two, three.
You bitch!
No. No way.
No. No.
You want shoes?
What?
Shoes.
No.
Just whiskey.
Make it a double.
And one for my friend.
Yeah. Just this much.
Sherry.
Shartis?
Huh?
"Job sat on his dung heap,
covered in boils."
- Mister, it's been a long day.
- Ah!
They're all long.
That's the nature of existence.
Life is suffering.
I think you're beginning
to understand that.
Hmm?
Amen.
Can I show you something?
Aw...
Ray is the cat.
What?
His name... I call him Ray.
I know, I know. That's not
really a cat's name,
but when I looked at him,
that was the name that stuck.
But this is how it is, I think.
Are you familiar with Ghuilgul?
It's Hebrew.
It's a word that describes
how an old soul
attaches itself to a new body.
Ray?
Is that you?
Unfortunately, some souls
cannot find a body to enter.
And they become lost.
Rabbi Nachman believed
the Jewish victims
of the massacre of Uman
were lost souls.
1768 in Ukraine,
untold thousands killed by the Cossack.
Women and children...
Their bodies dumped in a hole
and forgotten.
When Rabbi Nachman first visited Uman,
he saw the mass grave,
and he called it...
a garden.
He told his followers
that he wanted to be buried there.
The master of the field.
His soul, he said, would bind
and comfort theirs.
Have you been to this place before?
The bowling alley?
Is that what you see?
Oh...
Cheers.
Hits the spot.
We all end up here eventually.
To be weighed and judged.
As it is now for you and your friend.
You know, some thought that
he should have stayed behind,
but I convinced him that
he was on a better path now.
And you...
What about me?
I don't...
"Who will rise for me
against the wicked?"
Who will take a stand against evildoers?
You need a ride?
- Uh...
- There's a car out front.
It's a green Volkswagen Beetle.
This is the universe at its most ironic.
Don't worry. Its sins
have been swept clean.
You and your friend should take it.
The keys are under the mat.
I...
- Thank you.
- Oh, don't thank me.
Simply deliver a message
when the time comes.
A message?
- To who?
- To the wicked.
Tell them...
"Though thou exalt thyself
like the eagle,
"though thou make thy nest
among the stars,
"thence will I bring thee down,
"sayeth the Lord."
"Though thou exalt thyself..."
It's okay. It's okay.
You'll remember.
Ray...
I'm afraid you have to leave the cat.
It's okay.
Don't worry.
Hey, do me a favor, will you?
Mmm.
When the Gophers play,
put a little beer in a bowl
and put it in front of the game.
Napkins.
And some vodka.
Yuri...
You are Yuri Gurka,
Cossack of the plains.
Grandchild of the Wolves' Hundred.
I have a message for you
from Helga Albrecht
and the Rabbi Nachman.
Socks.
Great.
I... I needed socks.
- Thanks.
- Don't thank us, thank Santa.
I should, um, go check on the ragout.
Let me help you.
Are you having a good Christmas?
Oh... You know...
Kinda weird.
I know, we'll figure it out.
Hmm.
Burgle.
Oh, jeez.
- Sir.
- Not now.
Gloria Burgle. Eden Valley police.
You had one of mine
on the bus. Nikki Swango?
We're still doing a head count.
There's some dead from the crash,
- others from the assault.
- Assault?
We count three sets of
boot prints on the approach.
We got a stolen crotch rocket
in the trees.
Plus some kind of homemade ramp
we think caused the upend.
You saw the vehicle on the way in?
The yellow deal flipped on its top?
Couple of bystanders probably
slowed to do the Christian thing,
then recognized the debacle
for what it was.
Second vehicle, panel van maybe,
chases them for 2 miles,
runs them off the road,
finishes the couple execution style.
Jeez.
If I could just get
a look inside the bus,
my suspect, well, she's real memorable.
- A woman, you said?
- Yeah.
No women on the bus,
I can tell you that.
Anything I can...
That patch on your coat,
does it say "US Marshal"?
- No, sir.
- Well then,
we'll call you
when we find out, either way.
- Either?
- Dead or Alive.
Yeah, is he home?
We got a meeting.
What the heck?
Sy, come in.
We're just having lunch, mind you.
Where's Emmit?
I tried calling yesterday, but...
He's resting. He's upstairs.
All this bother with his brother,
he's very upset.
I know, I was there.
So, if he's...
Can you get him?
Like I told your man,
the police asked us
to come down to the precinct,
give a statement.
Yeah. That's all taken care of.
- What? When?
- Just come and take a seat.
Please.
In fact, there's some very good news.
- Good news?
- Yes.
Today, you are $5 million richer
than you were yesterday.
- What?
- Year-end bonuses.
We already...
Round two. There is a round three,
but I thought it better to hold it
till the next fiscal year.
Sweet potato?
Uh... No.
I'm... I'm not very hungry.
No, no. It would be a shame
to let it all go to waste.
Think of all them starving children.
No?
What about some tea then, eh?
Fancy a nice cuppa?
Sure. Good Christ.
- Sugar?
- No. I...
That's fine.
It was me mum's recipe,
the secret of which
she smuggled beneath her bosom
all the way from Wales to Bristol.
- It's a little bitter.
- Yeah.
Well, try some more, I think
you'll find it smooths out nicely.
Right, well, I'll tell
the big man you stopped by,
and don't worry about all this
trouble with the police.
I think you'll find these things
have a way of clearing themselves up.
Okay, well, just...
I feel like I should
at least check on him.
- Make sure he's...
- No, he's resting now.
Little bit of the old snore and drool.
He took a pill, I think,
maybe two. Or three.
As soon as he's wakeys,
I'll have him give you a ring-a-ding.
Copacetic?
- Five million?
- Bye-bye, Mr. Feltz.
Anderson said he couldn't wait,
said you should call to reschedule.
You okay there, chief?
I just...
Give me a minute.
Jeez.
I'm okay.
Well, that's not right.
Oh, Jeez. Call 911!
Make a hole, guys.
Stay with us.
Almost there.
Running fast.
Almost there. Come on.
Stay with us.
Three, two, one, lift.
- No.
- How's he doing?
Spoke to Mr. Feltz's doctor last week.
He says they're still stumped.
Some kind of toxic shock, sounds like.
What kind of toxic, is my question.
Toxic as in toxin? As in poison?
Like that Russian fella.
I already spoke to your boss.
Both of you.
- This is harassment.
- We're on our lunch break.
Heard it was shepherd's
pie day in the cafeteria.
And here you are.
How's business?
Private company like yours,
it's hard for us to tell.
Newspaper said you've been buying up
a lot of new properties though.
Expanding?
- Wasn't that your brother's car?
- Um, I...
I must have parked somewhere else.
I had to take a taxi.
I think my car was stolen.
- Stolen? Do you want me to...
- No, no.
I'm just being silly, probably.
Just forgot where I parked.
Madeline!
Jeez! We've got the intercom.
What the shit is this?
It's... I don't know.
Saw 'em when I came in this morning.
- Thought maybe you redecorated...
- I want...
- They have logs at the front desk, yeah?
- Yes.
The comings and goings and... cameras!
- Mr. Stussy, you're hurting me.
- Oh, sorry.
You know, maybe Mr. Varga...
He does that thing sometimes.
- Maybe...
- I bet that's it, Maddy.
Probably he told me and I forgot.
I'm sorry about your arm.
No, it's... You were surprised, is all.
After what happened to Sy...
Your darn brother.
You want me to call him?
My brother?
No. Mr. Varga.
No. No.
See if you can find out what
happened to the old pictures.
Make sure they don't throw them out.
That's him.
Mr. Stussy...
- He's alive.
- Who?
Ray.
Somehow he...
I can feel him watching me.
Your dead brother? How interesting.
Listen. I think we should...
I think we need more men.
What kind of men? Short men?
Melancholy?
I'm not kidding.
What if they're... A new move.
Setting me up...
They?
Ray and the girl.
She's still out there according to...
well, the cops and the newspapers.
And you said yourself,
your man never came back so...
Canada.
What?
If the girl is alive... If...
Then she did what any smart person
wanted for murder would do
and then she ran away to Canada.
Ray's car was parked in my spot.
The Corvette.
At the hospital.
You were at the hospital?
And now I'm standing in my office.
- And all the pictures are...
- Emmit?
Emmit, are you listening?
Yes.
You won.
I won? What did I win?
Life.
Sit tight.
Meemo will be over presently
to take you home.
There's some papers to sign.
You're selling a shopping mall.
I own a shopping mall?
What?
Help!
He has a what?
And you were here the whole time?
It's me.
It's my fault.
Did he sign the papers?
Emmit, we've talked about this.
If you don't sign the papers,
we don't make the money.
No. No more papers.
No more signing.
Something's going on here.
A hand reaching out
from beyond the grave.
Things I've done.
Transgressions.
And now, death.
Creeping close.
Step by step.
A father dead on a driveway.
An older brother taking
advantage of a younger...
Mi amore...
Sit.
You know how I describe you
when I meet with my bankers
and hedge fund managers?
A hero.
Clear of mind.
A man of singular purpose.
But even heroes have setbacks.
A messy divorce, death of a loved one
or a beloved business partner.
Sy's not dead.
- Yet...
- What?
What?
Look, my point is that
you have to remember
that even heroes can lose sight
of what's real from time to time.
Try these.
- What? What are they?
- A mild sedative.
Something to stop the engines racing.
Now...
I want you to picture an island.
Tropical island, somewhere warm.
South Pacific, perhaps. Can you see it?
Yeah.
Now I want you to imagine
that on this island,
one day in September, 1945,
a blizzard of paper fell from the sky.
Leaflets, dropped in their hundreds
by the allied forces
to tell the Japanese soldiers
stationed there
that the war was over.
The emperor has surrendered.
But down below,
one man refused to believe.
Lieutenant Hiroo Onoda.
A man of honor, values...
And as the rest of the world
went about its business,
1946, 47, 50, 64, 71...
As peace was made,
in a cold war fort
Hiroo Onoda battled on,
a tireless soldier
of the emperor's imperial army,
and the last man to die for an ideal.
He was just a boy.
He used to follow me around
after school.
"Emmit, play with me.
Emmit, watch this."
Is the Bible a children's book?
What we're doing here,
the sober affairs of men...
These are feats of great strength,
of cunning and fortitude.
Not child's play.
Not the best you can do.
Nobody remembers the second man
to climb Mount Everest.
That's it.
Sleep now.
Everything will be clearer
in the morning.
Well, that's it for me then.
- Gotta pay the sitter.
- Okay, Chief.
Told you. Can't call me that anymore.
I'm a Deputy now, same as you.
I'll run the rest of these
tomorrow. Which, you know...
Serving eviction notices
doesn't give you
a sense of hope and purpose, what will?
You know what?
Throw this in the "Outgoing"
for the morning?
My name's Emmit Stussy.
I want to confess.