You stole my Jesus fish, didn't you?
Yeah, that's right.
If she is allowed
to infiltrate this world...
...then George Costanza
as you know him ceases to exist.
You see, right now,
I have relationship George.
But there is also
independent George.
That's the George you know.
The George you grew up with.
Movie George. Coffee shop George.
Liar George. Bawdy George.
- I love that George.
- Me too.
And he's dying, Jerry.
If relationship George
walks through this door...
...he will kill independent George.
A George divided against itself
cannot stand!
Would you like some bread, Jerry?
No. No thanks, I'm just not hungry.
Then at least drink your beer.
Twist-off.
You have a little something
on your face.
She had man hands.
- He's a re-gifter.
- She's a two-face.
She's got the jimmy legs.
- She's a virgin.
- He's poor.
She's got everything I've always
wanted in another human being.
Except for the walking.
She eats her peas one at a time.
She just took credit for my salad.
He's a male bimbo. He's a mimbo.
- She's one of these low talkers.
- He's a high talker.
- Bit of a close talker.
- She can't hear very well.
- She's bald?
- She's bald!
He's a bad breaker-upper.
She went out with Newman.
He's like a Svengali.
- She's too tan.
- She's too good.
She wasn't my type.
She just dislikes me so much.
It's irresistible.
How could I do this?
How can I move back in
with those people? Tell me.
They're insane. You know that.
Hey, my parents
are just as crazy as yours.
- I'm paying.
- Dad, I'm paying.
- Get out of here.
- You're not paying.
Now, Jerry, please
do not do this to your father.
I can't get it open.
Yay, Jerry got it open.
How can you compare your parents
to my parents?
I told everybody about it.
Everybody knows.
I stopped short.
It's Frank Costanza,
Mr. Steinbrenner's here...
...George is dead, call me back.
Georgie, I'm a divorcée.
You're not a divorcée.
You're just separated.
You're a " separatée."
- Well, I'm out there, George.
- You're not out there.
- I am too.
You can't be, because I am out there.
And if I see you out there...
...there's not enough voltage
in this world...
...to electroshock me
back into coherence.
This is delicious, Mrs. Ross.
Let me understand.
You got the hen, the chicken
and the rooster.
The rooster goes with the chicken.
So who's having sex with the hen?
- We'll talk about it another time.
- But you see my point?
You only hear of a hen,
a rooster and a chicken.
- Something's missing.
- Something's missing, all right.
They're all chickens.
The rooster has sex with all of them.
That's perverse.
Hello, and welcome
to Movie Phone.
If you know the name of the movie
you'd like to see, press one.
Come on, come on.
Using your touch-tone keypad...
...please enter the first three letters
of the movie title now.
You've selected Agent Zero.
If that's correct, press one.
What?
You've selected Brown-Eyed Girl.
If this is correct, press one.
Why don't you just tell me
the name of the movie you selected?
That couple is breaking up.
They're breaking up?
- How do you know?
- She reads lips.
Oh, my God.
I-I just had a great idea.
She could come to the party tomorrow
and read Gwen's lips for me.
What?
We bring her to the party...
...and she tells me
what Gwen is saying about me.
She's not a novelty act, George...
...that you hire out
for weddings and bar mitzvahs.
Look, it's a skill, just like juggling.
She'll probably enjoy showing it off.
I don't know, George.
I'm not sure about this.
Would you ask her? Just ask her.
- If she says no, case closed.
- All right.
Laura, George was wondering-
Sure. I'll do it.
Hey, there.
One mulligatawny, and...
- What is that? Is that lima bean?
- Yes.
Never been a big fan.
You know what?
Has anyone ever told you...
...you look exactly like Al Pacino?
You know, Scent of a Woman.
Very good. Very good.
You know something?
- No soup for you!
- What?
Come back, one year.
Kramer, I've been
reviewing your work.
Quite frankly, it stinks.
Well, I...
I've been having trouble
at home, and...
I mean, you know, I'll work harder.
Nights, weekends,
whatever it takes.
No. No, I don't think
that's going to do it.
These reports you handed in,
it's almost as if...
...you have
no business training at all.
I don't know
what this is supposed to be.
Well, I'm just trying to get ahead.
Well, I'm sorry. There's just no way
that we could keep you on.
I don't even really work here.
That's what makes this so difficult.
I will never understand people.
They're the worst.
Why do they call it Ovaltine?
The mug is round.
The jar is round.
They should call it "Roundtine."
That's gold, Jerry. Gold.
Stop.
Well, you ladies look lovely tonight.
Good night, honey.
Good night.
Come on, Uncle Leo, I've seen
the way women look at you.
When's the last time you looked
in the mirror? You're an Adonis.
You're the only one I know
who's got the good stuff.
And I need it bad. I feel like
I've got bugs crawling up my skin.
- Now, you gotta help me out.
- Not on my watch!
I won't have you turning my office
into a den of iniquity.
- Get your fix somewhere else!
- Hey! Hey!
Go on, cretin!
Look at you, you're disgusting.
If a woman
can take your presence...
...for more than 10 seconds, you
should hang onto her like grim death.
Which is not far off, by the way.
Tim, do you think you should be
making jokes like that?
Why not? I'm Jewish, remember?
- I know, but-
- Jerry.
It's our sense of humor that sustained
us as a people for 3000 years.
- Five thousand.
- Five thousand. Even better.
Okay.
Crissy, give me a shtickl of flouride.
What do you think, I've never
ridden in a Cadillac before?
Believe me, I have ridden
in a Cadillac hundreds of times.
Thousands.
You put the balm on?
Who told you to put the balm on?
I didn't tell you to.
Why'd you put the balm on?
Where did you get
that balm, anyway?
- The Maestro.
- The who?
Jerry.
Tonight you in for a real treat.
I'm personally
gonna prepare the dinner...
...for you and my Audrey.
Hey, Cedric, Bob.
This guy won't wear a ribbon.
Who? Who doesn't want
to wear the ribbon?
Hello, Jerry. May I come in?
Perhaps there's more to Newman
than meets the eye.
No, there's less.
Hello, Mrs. Seinfeld.
Hello, Newman.
Excellent.
I've looked into his eyes.
He's pure evil.
All right. All right.
All right, you go ahead.
You go ahead, you keep it secret.
But you remember this.
When you control the mail,
you control information.
Oh, the humanity!
Believe it or not,
George isn't at home
Please leave a message
At the beep
I must be out,
Or I'd pick up the phone
Where could I be?
Believe it or not, I'm not home
It's funny, George.
You don't know how you're
feeling about something...
...until a person like you comes along
and articulates it so perfectly.
Articulate?
What?
- Live.
- Live?
- Oh, right, right, right, right, right.
No. No. No. No. No.
Oh, yeah!
All right. All right. All right!
- George, Marla.
- Marla.
- George.
- Jerry, Stacy.
- Jerry.
- George, Stacy.
- Stacy.
- George.
- Jerry.
Marla. Stacy.
- Newman.
- Jerry.
- Elaine.
- George.
- Newman.
- Jerry.
- Kramer.
- Whatley.
- Newman.
- Jambalaya.
Are we finished?
Done.
- So you're still master of your domain?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
But I will tell you this.
I am going over to her apartment...
...and I'm telling her
to put those shades down.
Wait, wait. What did you just say?
I can't take it anymore.
She's driving me crazy.
I can't sleep, I can't leave the house.
I'm climbing the walls.
I'm dating a virgin,
I'm in this contest.
Something's gotta give.
He took it out.
He what?
He took...
...it out.
What are you doing to yourself?
I can't stop.
Alex thinks I'm naturally hairless.
What? You can't keep this up.
Don't you know
what's gonna happen?
Every time you shave it, it's gonna
come in thicker and fuller and darker.
Oh, that's an old wives' tale.
Is it? Look at this.
- What-? What is that?
- Jerry, look at it!
Look at it!
Could it be because you
don't want him to know...
...you have a friend
who pees in the shower?
- No, that's not it.
- Oh, I think it is.
- That's exactly what it is!
- Why couldn't you wait?
I was there! I saw a drain!
Since when is a drain a toilet?
It's all pipes! What's the difference?
Different pipes
go to different places.
I'll call a plumber right now!
Could we just drop
all the pee-pipe stuff here?
Okay!
What is that?
I think it's the horse.
Oh, my God.
Hey, how's everything?
You need anything?
I can't - I can't take this.
We can't breathe back here.
Rusty!
So we're gonna make the post office
pay for my new stereo now?
It's a write-off for them.
- How is it a write-off?
- They just write it off.
Write it off what?
Jerry, all these big companies,
they write off everything.
You don't even know
what a write-off is.
- Do you?
- No, I don't.
But they do.
And they're the ones writing it off.
I like sports.
I could do something in sports.
In what capacity?
You know, like the general manager
of a baseball team.
Yeah, well,
that can be tough to get.
Well, it doesn't even have to be
the general manager.
Maybe I could be, like, an announcer.
Like a color man.
You know how I always make those
interesting comments during the game.
Yeah.
Yeah, you make good comments.
So, what about that?
Well, you know, they tend to
give those jobs to ex-ballplayers...
...and people that are,
you know, in broadcasting.
- Well, that's really not fair.
- I know.
And I'll tell you another thing,
Cosmo Kramer.
The kissing thing is over.
There's no more kissing.
And I don't care
what the consequences are.
Kramer, what the hell is going-?
Jerry, come on, man.
- Are you in?
- What, are you kidding?
You see those ladies
I got showing?
You think they're scared?
Oh, man, you're killing me.
Oh, forget it.
Julia's still laughing.
Okay.
There's no point in going.
Julia's laughing.
- No I'm not.
- Okay, can we go?
- No. She's laughing. Right now.
- Yes. Yes. We can go.
Go ahead, waste the film.
Waste everyone's time.
Okay, here we go. All right.
And action.
Kasha?
Hello.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
You telling me there's
not one condo available...
...in all of Del Bofa-
Del- Del Boca Vista?
That's right.
In all of Del- Del- Del Vista-
Del- Del Boca Visto?
- In all of Del Besta Bicko?
- That's right.
In all of Del Visto Becko?
- Hey.
- You ought to come over.
Tonight's pipe night.
No, thanks.
Come on.
What happened to your face?
It looks like an old catcher's mitt.
It's-It's all that s-
Come on.
What did you expect?
- What?
- Your teeth are all brown.
No.
Look away, I'm hideous.
See you.
- Okay, where's my boy?
- Oh, my God.
My George isn't clever enough
to hatch a scheme like this.
You got that right.
What the hell does that mean?
What the hell does that-?
Come on. Okay. Let's go, let's go.
That means whatever the hell
you want it to mean.
You're saying
you want a piece of me?
You saying you want a piece of me?
You want a piece of me?
You got it!