To see this movie
we gotta get moving.
Let's roll.
Come on, people. Previews.
Oh, hello.
Nine years.
Seems like a long time,
doesn't it? It is.
And we've packed a lot in,
the four of us.
It seems like every week
a whole new set of problems...
...would just crop up out of nowhere.
Except for summer...
...where nothing seemed to happen
for months at a time.
Anyway, the point is,
over the last nine years-
- We're gonna miss the movie!
- I'm coming!
- Previews, Jerry!
- Just go already!
Over the last nine years,
we've had a lot of experiences.
And I'll tell you, when you stop
and add them all up...
...that's what you realize.
Watch this.
- Jerry!
- Shut up!
What is this?
Do you ever get the feeling like you
had a haircut, but you didn't have one?
I'm all itchy back here.
- What?
- What are we doing?
- What in God's name are we doing?
- What?
What- What kind of
lives are these?
We're like children. We're not men.
No, we're not. We're not men.
We're pathetic, you know that?
Like I don't know that I'm pathetic.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry, I thought
this was the baby's room.
I'm really sorry.
I was in the pool!
Since when do you smoke?
I've always smoked.
I've never seen you smoke.
Oh, yeah, well. Big smoker.
I gave it up for a while,
but it was too tough.
You know, I don't got the willpower.
I don't like this one bit.
Well, I can't stop now.
I'm addicted.
They got a hold on me.
Well, you are gonna have to quit.
Oh, God.
That's why I'm different.
I can sense the slightest
human suffering.
Are you sensing anything
right now?
Mrs. Enright!
Do you have a woman?
- No.
- Do you have any prospects?
No.
You got anything on the horizon?
Do you have any conceivable reason
for even getting up in the morning?
I like to get the Daily News.
How come
I didn't get a Christmas card?
Everybody else got one.
Jerry got one. Kramer got one.
I thought we were good friends.
I don't get a Christmas card.
I don't get it.
Want a Christmas card?
All right, here.
Here's your Christmas card.
Every group has someone
that they all make fun of.
Like us, with Elaine.
You're bald!
No, I'm not.
I was bald.
Elaine.
- Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
- No!
No! No! No, Elaine!
I don't like this thing!
And here's what I'm doing with it!
Stop!
Stella.
Stella!
- Elaine, you don't like the movie?
- I hate it!
Oh, go to hell!
- Are you a liar?
- Are you?
- Get your finger out of my face.
- I was here first.
- I don't care.
- Get it out.
Get it out.
Hey, hey, hey. All right.
Hey, hey. Come on. Stop it.
Come on. Break it up.
Hey, hey!
What's the matter with you?
Now, don't you two see
that you're in love with each other?
Kramer goes to a fantasy camp.
His whole life is a fantasy camp.
People should plunk down $2,000
to live like him for a week.
Do nothing.
Fall ass-backwards into money.
Mooch food off your neighbors...
...and have sex without dating.
That's a fantasy camp.
Well, looks like
you've adjusted to the boxers.
Well, I wouldn't go as far as that.
- You went back to the Jockeys?
- Wrong again.
Oh, no.
What? What?
Don't you see
what's going on here?
No boxers, no Jockeys.
The only thing between him and us
is a thin layer of gabardine.
I'm out there, Jerry,
and I'm loving every minute of it.
A facecloth for your-
Hey!
Ladies and gentlemen, it's our
good friend, George Costanza.
What a surprise.
Kramer, he's just a dentist.
Yeah, and you're an anti-dentite.
I am not an anti-dentite.
You're a rabid anti-dentite.
Next thing, you're saying
they should have their own schools.
- They do have their own schools.
- Yeah!
What kind of a person are you?
I think I'm pretty much like you.
Only successful.
No! No!
Anyway, I wanted to talk to you
about Dr. Whatley.
I have a suspicion
that he's converted to Judaism...
...purely for the jokes.
And this offends you
as a Jewish person?
No, it offends me as a comedian.
Would you be interested in
switching over...
- ... to TMI long distance service?
- Oh, gee, I can't talk right now.
Give me your home number
and I'll call you later.
Well, I'm sorry,
we're not allowed to do that.
I guess you don't want
people calling you at home.
- No.
- Well, now you know how I feel.
Hey, buddy.
I'm on no sleep. No sleep!
You don't know what it's like in there.
All night long, things are creaking
and cracking.
And that red light
is burning my brain.
- You look a little stressed.
- Oh, I'm stressed.
Jerry. Kill me.
Kill me now. I'm begging you.
Well, what, kind of like this?
What- What are you doing?
Jerry!
Jerry.
Elaine. What are you doing here?
Oh, my God.
What percentage of people
would you say are good-looking?
- 25 percent.
- 25 percent?
No way. It's, like, four to six percent.
It's a 20-to-1 shot.
- You're way off.
- Way off?
Have you been to the motor vehicle
bureau? It's a leper colony there.
So basically what you're saying is...
...95 percent of the population
is undatable?
Undatable!
Then how are all these people
getting together?
Alcohol.
What about you?
Did people make fun of your name?
Are you kidding?
What do you expect...
...when your name rhymes
with a part of the female anatomy?
Oh, Jerry.
Oh, you.
Love is a spice with many tastes.
A dizzying array
of textures and moments.
All right, let's go.
I'll give you half an hour.
- What?
- Come on.
- Are you serious?
- Look, Jerry.
We have to have sex
to save the friendship.
Sex to save the friendship.
Well, if we have to, we have to.
What's going on?
It was a pleasure
doing business with you.
But I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to get going.
"Get going"?
But we haven't really, you know...
Eight dollars? Eight dollars?
What are you doing?
You're robbing me?
I wasted my whole morning
on you for $8?
- Wait a second, what are you doing?
- I'm taking your clothes.
No, no, no! That's my only suit!
It cost me $350.
I got it at Moe Ginsburg!
- Bye, George.
- Wait, you can't just leave me here.
Will I see you again?
You just tell him
that you're my boyfriend...
...and that we're in love, okay?
Can you do that?
- Yeah, yeah. I'm your boyfriend. Yeah.
- Okay.
Have we been intimate?
Yeah. Yeah, we've been intimate.
All right, how often do we do it?
Kramer, how is that important?
Do you really think
he's gonna ask that?
Elaine, he's a psychiatrist.
They're interested in stuff like that.
All right, all right.
We do it five times a week.
- Okay?
- Oh, baby.
Oh, man.
So we're fooling around there,
you know.
It's getting a little passionate
and she starts with the dirty talking.
All right. All right.
Hold on. Time out.
- What did she say?
- Typical things.
What's typical? Give me typical.
Give me some typical.
She says...
George.
What are you doing?
You know.
Pleasuring you.
It feels like aliens
poking at my body.
- So you think you're spongeworthy?
- Yes, I think I'm spongeworthy.
I think I'm very spongeworthy.
Run down your case for me again.
Well, we've gone out several times.
We obviously have a good rapport.
I eat well. I exercise.
Blood tests, immaculate.
- Do something about your sideburns?
- Yeah, I told you. I'm gonna.
- All right, let's go.
- Okay.
I might tell her that I love her.
Well, that's a big move,
Georgie boy.
Are you confident
in the "I love you" return?
Fifty-fifty.
Because if you don't
get that return...
...that's a pretty big matzo ball
hanging out there.
Well, I just gotta say it once.
Everybody else gets to say it.
Why can't I say it?
What, you've never said it?
Once, to a dog.
He licked himself and left the room.
How is it that a man like you...
...so bald and so quirky and funny...
...how is it you're not taken?
Well, Marisa...
...see, the thing is...
...I'm sort of engaged.
I'm not married. I'm not allowed
to go out with somebody else?
- Depends.
- Depends on what?
- On many factors.
- Like what?
Well, how long
you've been seeing her.
What's your phone call frequency?
- Are you on a daily?
- No.
Semi-daily.
Four or five times a week.
Do you have to ask her out
or is the date implied?
Implied.
She got anything
in your medicine cabinet?
Might be some moisturizer.
Let me ask you this.
Is there any Tampax in your house?
Yeah.
Well, I'll tell you what you got here.
- You got yourself a girlfriend.
- Oh, no, no, no.
I mean, what are you thinking about,
Jerry? Marriage? Family?
- Well...
- They're prisons.
Man-made prisons.
You're doing time.
You get up in the morning,
she's there.
You go to sleep at night,
It's like you gotta ask permission to-
To use the bathroom.
"Is it all right
if I use the bathroom now?"
- Really?
- Yeah.
And you can forget about
watching TV while you're eating.
Because it's dinnertime.
- And you know what you do at dinner?
- What?
You talk about your day.
"How was your day today?"
"Did you have a good day
or a bad day?"
"Well, what kind of day was it?"
"Well, I don't know, how about you?"
- I'm glad we had this talk.
- You have no idea.
Do I have to break up with her
in person?
Can't I do it over the phone?
I have no stomach for these things.
You should just do it like a Band-Aid.
One motion, right off.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
You're acting weird.
Is anything wrong?
No.
Are you breaking up with me?
Are we going out?
You're breaking up with me,
aren't you?
- Do you want me to break up?
- If that's what you want.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Okay, fine. Break up with me.
- All right. We're broken up.
Can we still be friends?
Listen to this.
Marcy comes over and she tells me...
...that her ex-boyfriend
was over late last night...
...and, " yada, yada, yada,
I'm really tired today."
What do you think
she was tired from?
Well, obviously the yada, yada.
You don't think
she'd yada, yada sex?
I've yada, yada'd sex.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I met this lawyer,
we went out to dinner.
I had the lobster bisque.
We went back to my place.
Yada, yada, yada,
I never heard from him again.
But you yada, yada'd
over the best part.
No, I mentioned the bisque.
Allison spoke to me...
...and she wanted me
to speak to you.
So Allison and I think that
the best thing to do is just...
...make a clean break.
Can't we discuss this?
We just don't think you're ready
for a serious relationship.
I didn't even know
you wanted to get serious.
So, what am I in this for?
You know, I'm getting to a point
in my life...
...where I need something more
than just...
...a good time.
Kramer, please.
You didn't have make-up sex?
How could you not have make-up sex?
That's the best feature
of the heavy relationship.
I missed out on the make-up sex.
The only sex you're gonna have
better than make-up sex...
...is if you're sent to prison
and you have a conjugal visit.
Yeah, conjugal visit sex.
That is happening.
David, I'm going to hell.
The worst place in the world.
With devils and those caves,
and the ragged clothing.
And the heat. My God, the heat.
I mean, what do you think
about all that?
It's gonna be rough.
You should be trying to save me.
Don't boss me.
This is why you're going to hell.
I am not going to hell.
And if you think I'm going to hell,
you should care that I'm going to hell.
Even though I am not.