Erstwhile on Fargo...
So you think this is the one
killed all those people
over in Bemidji?
Could be.
I mean, you're saying this is
all some... some big coincidence
that suddenly
we got four victims
in 24 hours, yourself included?
My wife is dead,
and you're harassing me.
Just leave
poor Lester alone, will ya?
Found this on my windshield
last week.
You got bronzer
on your blackmail note.
I'm taking over.
I ran his plates,
and it turns out
that the car was registered
to one of your victims.
30 milligrams.
Don't take two of these
and think you're gonna nap...
it's basically speed.
It's like a nightmare.
I told you.
I know a guy.
You know a guy.
A guy?
Better be some guy, Stavros.
For this...
we gave up everything.
Gave up?
What did we have?
Debts, screaming phone calls,
bill collectors at the door.
At least it was warm.
Shit.
What?
Out of gas.
You bought gas.
$5.00.
It was all I had.
Idiot!
The boy's gonna freeze!
We can't stay here.
I know.
I'll think of something.
Think of what?
Gasoline?
Yeah, from your brain into...
Would you shut up?
I got to think.
Oh, hey!
Here!
Hey!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
slow down.
Hey! No, no, stop!
Stop!
Wait!
Hey!
Come on, come on!
Oh!
All right.
Lord, let me get through this.
Let us find gas
and a...
and a warm bed.
Let us prosper even in the...
in the smallest of ways,
and I'll be your humble servant
for the rest of my days.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
My God.
Thank you, God.
All right.
I can't believe
he wouldn't stop...
A family vehicle,
a baby in a car.
Who doesn't stop
for a baby in a car?
God is real.
We're gonna freeze to death
because a man that hasn't
showered since the '70s
couldn't be bothered
to apply the brakes.
God is real.
Well...
there's nothing here.
No wildlife in your pipes.
Water heater's clean.
I'm not sure how you got
blood in your shower.
Are you sure it wasn't rust?
'Cause...
Listen to me.
It's not like
a band-aid fell out, okay?
It was buckets,
literally buckets of blood.
Whoa.
Making a horror film, huh?
And with the dead dog
you mentioned too... uffda.
Sounds like a bad day.
Did you see any signs
of tampering?
Tam... tampering?
Yeah.
Screws loosened recently
or holes that blood
could've been injected.
Injected?
What the heck are you
thinking happened here?
Nothing.
Thanks for your time.
Yeah.
You know, I, uh... I seen
your commercials on TV...
July in January.
You got any, like,
gift certificates?
- The wife, she...
- Get the hell out of here.
Sure, okay.
Yeah.
Uh, say...
you ever read the Bible?
What?
The Bi... Bible...
you know, The Big Book.
All that blood
made me think of it,
you know, Moses and the like.
"And God sent a plague
of blood upon the land."
Better get right with the Lord.
- You know what I'm...
- What'd you say?
Nothing.
Say it again.
Well, no...
What did you say to me?
- Say it again!
- Boss, let him go.
What did you say?
Boss, he's just a damn plumber.
Let him go.
Jeez.
He's crazy.
You're crazy!
Jeez.
Car 39, this is Dispatch.
Come in.
Ah, hold your horses.
Car 39, this is Dispatch.
Come in.
Yeah, this is 3-9.
Over.
Car 39, need you to follow up
on a report...
murdered canine
at 1301 Bird Lane.
Over.
Is that a... Can you call it
a murder if it's a...
Anyhoo, that's Animal
Control's purview.
Yeah, Joe's sick.
Was supposed
to respond yesterday.
Claimant's super PO'd.
Over.
Jeez, come on,
that guy is always sick.
What's he got, the cancer?
Over.
Yeah, leukemia.
Jeez, that is...
that's awful.
Okay, well, uh...
3-9,
car 3-9 responding.
Over and out.
1-2-5.
1-2-7.
Okay.
Oh, jeez.
It's him.
Oh!
Freeze!
Don't...
Put your hands
where I can see...
where I can see 'em.
I'm just on a call.
Drop... drop it.
Yeah, just as soon as I finish.
This is Duluth.
Package requested.
Frank Peterson.
Okay, all good.
See?
Put it down.
It's a new phone.
Now!
Okay.
Okay, um...
uh, turn around and put
your hands on your head.
What... what's this
all about, Officer?
You know what this is about.
Okay, um...
put your, uh... your left hand
around your, uh...
the back of your...
Yeah.
Okay.
Now the other one.
Slowly.
Am I under arrest?
You're handcuffed.
Of course you're under arrest.
On what charge?
It... um...
We'll figure that out
at the station.
Okay.
All right.
Back... back to the car.
Dang it.
All right, uh, butt first.
Watch your head.
You're making a mistake.
Be quiet.
I said quiet!
That's what you're gonna say
a couple hours from now...
"You're making a mistake."
Got one.
What was he, mean to a cat?
Murder and car thievery,
all right?
This fella's wanted for
the triple homicide in Bemidji.
Oh, now, hold on a sec.
It's like I told
this young fella.
This is a boondoggle,
plain and simple.
Save it, Cochise.
Now, I'm gonna ink
your right hand
and press each finger
individually against a book.
If you try anything,
I can't promise your fingers
won't get broke.
Okay, message received,
young fella.
You won't get
no pushback from me.
What the heck?
Son of a...
Molly, call on two.
Yeah, Solverson.
Yeah, hey, it's Gus.
I got him.
Who's this, then?
Uh, yeah, Gus Grimly,
from over Duluth.
You know, we had
the milkshakes the other...
Oh, yeah, hey.
How's it going?
Yeah, uh, real good.
Um, so, uh, I was
on patrol earlier,
responding to a 613, and, uh...
What's that, then?
A-a dead dog,
foul play suspected.
And I see this fella,
and he's standing by a van.
And it was him.
Him who?
The fella
from Mr. Nygaard's car.
The driver?
Yeah, yeah.
The, um...
the one I let go.
But there he was.
I mean, you know, just standing
there making a call on his, uh...
So... so... what did you...
I stopped and arrested him,
of course.
Arrested him?
Yeah.
For the murders.
I'm looking at the guy
right now.
The Lieutenant's gonna
have a chat with him.
I thought you might want to...
Yeah, yep.
Okay, I'm getting in my car.
- Great.
- Yeah.
Uh, I'll be there
just as soon as I...
Okay, then. Yeah, I'll tell
the Lieutenant to wait for you.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- You're welcome.
- Yeah, okay.
So we've been putting in
a lot of hours on the Chief,
but the weather service
is tracking a big storm.
Okay, they're looking
at Wednesday night,
Thursday early AM...
high winds, blizzard,
the whole shebang.
So, if you want to make
extra money plowing,
see Cindy.
Same goes for traffic duty,
et cetera.
I don't want this impacting
everyday doings.
So don't sign up
unless your workload
is cleared.
Chief, they got him.
Who?
Duluth PD.
No, who'd they get?
Oh, yeah, uh, fella driving
Lester's stolen car.
Deputy pulled him in
an hour ago.
How come they called you?
Pardon?
Well, you're not even
on the case.
How come they called you?
I just...
Well, the other day
a deputy drove down from Duluth,
and, you know, he and I...
he and I talked is all.
Well, that's irregular.
They should talk
to the officer in charge.
Yeah, yeah, so I's thinking
I'd drive up there,
you know, talk to the suspect,
on account of, you know,
I think he's the fella
put the naked guy in the trunk.
Nah, should be me.
You said he was driving
Lester's car.
That's my case.
Plus, Vern takes precedence.
Okay, but, Chief... Knutson,
you're in charge till I get back.
Okeydokey, Chief.
Ten-four.
Got to pick up a few things.
You could have waited
in the car.
No, Kitty said I should...
I mean, I want to be here
for you, so...
Oh, jeez.
They just...
they leave it like that?
All the blood?
Yeah, it's, uh...
you know, they gi... they give you
a number to call, a service.
Lester, I...
I got to...
Jeez.
Oh, yeah... oh, my...
oh, yeah.
Ah, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, God.
Oh.
What's...
Ow!
God damn it!
Christ!
Oh, my God.
There, that's...
Hello?
Was it worth it?
Who's this?
The Widow Hess...
her husband nice and cozy
in the ground,
insurance money on the way,
every night she puts
her kitty in your face.
Guy like you, Lester,
small town, small time,
I think you won the lottery.
But I think that
you need to ask yourself...
was it worth it?
Worth what?
Your life.
- Freshen you up?
- No, we're good. Just the check, please.
Everything okay?
He's just not very hungry.
Thanks.
For Christ sakes, man!
Seriously?
I'm not looking at you!
I'm not looking at you.
You got two minutes.
Okeydokey.
Thanks a lot, sir.
Sir?
Are you Don Chumph?
Uh... yeah.
There's a phone call for you.
- A what now?
- Telephone.
You can take it
right here at the counter.
Hello?
Do they have 'em?
Who is this?
Well, let's figure
this out together.
Who knows you're
at the pet store right now?
My mom.
Do I sound like your mom?
- Uh, no.
- Hold on.
Does your mom know why you're
at the pet store right now?
She thinks I'm getting a cat.
Okay, I don't have time
for this.
Do they have 'em, yes or no?
Yeah, but only a hundred.
Okay, well, there are three
other pet stores in the city,
so hit 'em all.
I'm in jail.
I'll be out in a few hours.
Wait. What?
Time's up.
Okay, two hours.
Come get me.
And this is the deputy
who effected the arrest.
Yeah, nice work there.
He give you much of a fight?
Uh, no, sir.
Bill Oswalt's the Chief
over Bemidji.
Ah.
Molly come?
Who?
Deputy over in my office.
Sounds like your man's
got a thing for her.
Lock that shit down, Grimly.
This is a murder case.
Yes, sir.
So we got a name on the guy?
Yes, sir, driver's license
says Frank Peterson
and an address up in Baudette.
Peterson, eh?
I knew a Jay Peterson once.
Had a dwarf arm.
What about evidence?
Sir?
Yeah, proof of his connection
to the crime.
You say you stopped him
driving Lester's car.
Yes, sir, but I didn't know
that it was stolen.
Why I let him go.
Yeah, but you pulled prints
from the impounded vehicle?
No, sir.
Tech said it was wiped clean.
Yeah.
Well, we got a photo,
though, right?
I mean, dashboard camera
from the car stop?
You know, proof he's our guy.
No, sir, my camera
hasn't worked for weeks.
But Molly's got a picture.
It's in the file.
She showed me.
Yeah.
- She did?
- Yeah.
There.
Yeah, this fella.
It's kind of hard
to see, though.
It's grainy.
You sure this is our guy?
Yeah... yeah, no.
That's our guy.
I-I'm positive.
Yeah, I'm Lieutenant Schmidt.
This is Bill Oswalt,
Chief over Bemidji.
Yeah, Frank Peterson.
I'm the minister
up in Baudette.
Go, Bears.
Minister?
Yeah, Baudette Lutheran,
six years now...
Frank Peterson.
Before that, Aberdeen.
So, you know, I'm not used
to having a firearm
stuck in my face,
which I know the Lord
tests you in all kinds of ways,
but, oh, partner,
that's a heart-stopper.
Cut the shit.
You were pulled over
Tuesday night
driving a stolen car.
No, sir.
I think I'd remember that.
Plus, Tuesday's bingo night
at the church.
We had a full house.
Florence Nightgarden won
the entire pot,
if I'm not mistaken.
And we can check on that?
Oh, sure, yes, sir.
You could call Florence herself.
Or Jim Avery...
he's our alderman.
Deputy Grimly...
Oh, that's the fella,
Deputy Grimly.
Pulled his pistol,
pointed it right at me.
Thought I was gonna have
a heart attack.
But, you know, after he told me
about those homicides
over Bemidji,
I thought, "Frank, I mean,
you can't blame the guy"
for being a little jumpy,
a horror show like that."
That son of a bitch.
So you're saying you weren't
in Bemidji last week?
If I show your picture around,
no one would recognize you?
Me?
No, sir.
I have a cousin lived
in Bemidji back in the '90s,
out near Leech Lake,
but he moved to Anchorage
in '03.
I said, "What, Minnesota's
not could enough for you?"
We had a good laugh about that.
Also, you're saying you weren't
pulled over for speeding?
No, sir.
I'm a cautious driver
by nature,
on account of my eyesight.
Glaucoma, they say it is.
Only in the one eye,
but you can't be too careful.
That's what I tell
my parishioners.
- Deputy Grimly...
- Forgiveness...
that's the heart
of the Good Book.
Turn the other cheek,
second chances, Amen.
So, no, I don't hold a grudge
against the Deputy,
though I'm lucky I had
my nitroglycerine pills with me,
I tell you, uffda.
Okay, well, sit tight.
We're gonna make some calls,
check your story.
Oh, you just... just pick a name
out of the phone book.
Everybody up there knows me.
Yeah.
So, uh, looks like a call
was placed to your motel
from the victim's house the
night Pearl Nygaard was killed.
You said that on the phone.
Right.
So, uh, you remember any seedy
types checking in last week?
Possible with a head injury?
I thought on it
on the way over.
There was a fella
checked in around then,
had a bump on his head.
Gave me guff when I asked him
if he had any pets.
Oh, yeah?
Was it, uh, this fella maybe?
Yeah.
That's him.
You don't sound
too happy about it.
Well, he just wasn't
very nice is all.
Brought my book like you asked.
Fella paid cash, I think.
But I make everyone put
their name in the ledger.
There ya go.
Okay.
Yeah.
"Lorne Malvo."
Say, uh...
you remember
finding anything odd
when you cleaned his room?
What do you mean odd?
Like out of the ordinary,
memorable, I guess.
Well, he had some tokens
from over the Lucky Penny.
You don't say.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
All right, then, well,
it looks like he's
a pretty well respected member
of the community up there.
We just had to call and verify.
Thanks for your time.
- Grimly.
- Where you been?
I've been trying
to call you all day.
Thought you were coming.
Yeah, I tried.
Are you in the room?
Yeah, they just talked to him.
Why not you?
Me?
No, I do Animal Control mostly.
Listen, I got a name
for the suspect...
Lorne Malvo.
He used it
to check into a motel.
Lorne Malvo, huh?
Oh, they're... they're coming out.
I'll call you back.
Sorry again for
the confusion, Pastor.
Oh, just glad nobody got hurt.
You're letting him go?
Desk duty, two weeks.
- Now, just a...
- Three weeks.
For Pete...
You're making a mistake.
Grimly, with me, now.
You pointed your service weapon
at a civilian...
no, a damn minister
on a public street.
No evidence, no fingerprints,
nothing.
What about the picture?
Oh, that Zapruder film
in the file?
Hell, son,
that could be a photo
of my mama, for all I know.
No, it's him.
I know it's him.
Negatory.
We checked his story.
- It tracks.
- He's lying!
You have a blessed day.
How can you do that?
What's that, son?
Just... just lie like that.
I sure hope
you catch that fella
killed all those people.
I'll be praying on it.
Lorne Malvo.
Did you know the human eye
can see more shades of green
than any other color?
What?
I said, "Did you know
that the human eye"
can see more shades of green
than any other color?"
My question for you is, why?
No, no, no,
just h-hold on.
When you figure out
the answer to my question,
then you'll have
the answer to yours.
Where are they?
In the back.
Can't you hear?
It's driving me crazy.
Yeah?
Yeah, Mr. Nygaard?
This is Dave
from Duluth Impound.
Oh, oh, yeah, I'm gonna pick
her up probably Friday.
No, sir, I'm supposed to tell
you your car's not ready yet.
What do you mean?
It's, uh... well,
forensic team's looking at it.
- Forensic?
- Yes, sir.
Just routine, but I can't
release the car to you
till they release it to me,
so I'll just call you
when it's done, okay?
- Bye, now.
- Hey, Lester.
Aah!
I'm in a meeting.
Chazz?
Oh, I said,
"I'm in a meeting."
Chazz, it's Lester.
Look, I think I might be
in a bit of trouble here.
When are you not in...
What kind of trouble?
Well, uh, I'm...
I'm in the trunk of a car.
What?
A car.
In... in... in the trunk.
You're in the trunk
of your car?
No!
N-not my car.
It's... it's these two fellas.
You see, the thing...
I think I may have
been kidnapped, is the thing.
What?
Yeah, they got me,
uh, in the trunk.
I'm not... don't really
know where we're going.
Did you say you got kidnapped?
Lester, where are you?
I'll call the cops.
No, no, no, no.
Don't... don't...
don't call the...
Yeah, I'm just, uh...
I'm pranking you.
What?
Yeah, remember
how we used to...
you know,
practical jokes and all?
Well, uh, you're it.
You're an asshole.
Come on.
There you go.
Come on, let's go.
You're gonna say it.
"I, Lester Nygaard..."
I, Lester Nygaard...
Louder.
Louder!
- I, Lester Nygaard...
- "Killed!"
No, no, you see,
I did not kill...
Lester, you're gonna say it
- one way or the other, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- All right?
"Killed Sam Hess."
That's not true.
I didn't kill him.
Yes, you did.
No, I didn't.
Okay, then who was it?
The man.
Who's the man?
Who?
Who's him?
Who...
who is him?
It was the guy.
Was... What... Who?
What guy?
I need...
- Hi, I need...
- Is this your car, sir?
What?
- Is this your car?
- No, no.
I need a ride back to town.
- I'm not a taxi service, sir.
- What?
I said we're not
a taxi service.
Please, I just...
I just need...
Just give me a damn ride.
Oh.
Heck, sir.
Well, now I got to arrest you.
Well, good, good.
Let's go.
Oh, jeez.
Thanks.
Okay.
Yeah, this is car 3108.
I'm coming in with a 3-1-3.
Copy, 3108.
Yeah, guy punched me.
Knock, for Christ's sake!
How many times?
Not now.
Not now!
Look, I want to talk about mom.
I said, "Not now."
Dad, you're not
being very nice.
"Nice"?
You think you go down
to a car dealership,
buy a car with nice?
You think the girls
at titty bar care about nice?
It's kill or be killed, son.
Are you crying?
No.
No, don't.
Kill or be killed.
Dad, what's happening?
We demand one
million in unmarked bills.
We'll call tomorrow
at 10:00 AM
with the drop instructions.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Remember, God is watching.
Is that him?
God is real.
Bartender,
- I tend...
- Hmm.
To have a, uh, beer
and then a little tequila guy.
Looks like you already
had a few.
Well, then they're working,
right?
What are you looking at?
You know,
I'll tell you something.
I will put your eye out.
I was about to send
a search party.
Yeah, sorry.
Cindy said Bill's
on his way back.
What happened?
Well, they, uh...
they let him go, Malvo.
Yeah, he had an alibi,
it checked out,
but it's him.
How do you know?
'Cause I said the name
Lorne Malvo,
and he stopped,
and he looked at me real funny.
And then he said, like,
a riddle.
What's that about a riddle?
Like, um, how come
the human eye can see
more shades of green
than any other color?
'Cause of predators.
Uh...
Used to be,
we were monkeys, right?
And in the woods,
in the jungle,
everything's green.
So, in order to not
get eaten by panthers
and bears and the like,
we had to be able to see them,
you know, in the grass
and trees and such.
Predators.
So what do we do now?
Lester.
Oh, okay.
Can I get, uh, like,
a phone call?
And a...
Oh, a chicken pot pie?
Sleep it off, rummies.
♪ All over this country ♪
♪ Have you ever ♪
♪ mistreated anybody ♪
♪ In order ♪
♪ to advance yourself? ♪
♪ If you have, ♪
♪ it's coming up again ♪
♪ Say it loud ♪
♪ It's coming up again ♪