You see, I mean, to me Janice, art, you know - art as...an
art, must by its very nature be self-indulgent, right.
I mean as I said to, David Hockney once, 'The inherent
element in all artistic projects
should not be one of contemporary
mass appeal
but rather one of personal symbolism.'
Don't you agree Janice?
I dunno Rodney.
Oh well, um, you know that's why I like talking to you,
you're one of the few people who seems to understand me.
My brother Don paints you
know.
- Really?
- Yeah, for the council.
No, that is cosmic Janice.
No really - no that is cosmic that.
That's probably why we have the same appreciation
and understanding of true art.
I mean, we have an affinity, an aesthetic bond, we are kindred
spirits, Janice, seekers of beauty in a broken ugly world.
- Janice?
- Yes Rodney.
- Get yer bra off.
- I can't.
Well of course you can, you
must live and be free!
- I can't Rodney, I'm not wearing one!
- Oh, well.
It ain't half dark in here innit.
Oh put him down Janice, put him down, you don't know
where he's been...Oh well, what we got going on here.
Oh I'll have to drop off that - thanks. Here, look,
we don't want all this rubbish on do we, eh?
That's better. Oi Janice, mind
his bruises won't you.
What bruises?
He's covered in 'em, it's where the girls keep on pushing him
away with 10ft barge poles. Oh dear, oh dear, that's better.
You're in are you Del?
Yes, yes, I'm in Rodders. Hope you've been behaving yourself,
remember what I told you, not to do it on your own doorstep?
We've just been sitting here
discussing art that's all.
D'you like art Del?
Oh yeah, Del used to be a
cultural adviser to the Chelsea Shed!
Yes, I like art Janice. I like art, I'm a Renaissance man myself.
I like them picture where the eyes follow you round the room.
Last week, down the pie and eel shop, Del shook
the international  art world to it's very foundations by stating,
quite openly, that
Michaelangelo was a wally-brain.
Well he was a wally-brain weren't he? It took him 12
years to paint one ceiling.
That wouldn't do your brother
Donald any good would it Janice, eh?
Well he's on bonus.
I do not believe this, I'm
gonna wake up in a minute!
Here, look, I'll tell you another thing while we're on
about it an' all.
You know some of these artists you know,
they're a bit sick if you ask me.
What are you on about now?
Well look, take a look at this right. Now this is a statuette
of the world-famous Venus de Milo, right?
Now who but the sick of mind would do a
sculpture of a disabled person? Am I right Janice?
- It's a bit sick innit!
- There you are.
It weren't like that originally!
No, no, no, this is the product of a
twisted imagination this Rodney.
Yeah here, talking of twisted imaginations are you
still looking for a job?
What in this country?
There's three million
unemployed, what chance has Rodney got?
Well, with his big brother looking after him he's got
every chance in the world.
Now take one of your purple hearts
Rodney because I've got a surprise for you.
I have managed to secure you for a
position with a newly formed security company!
Now they did want a man with previous
experience and, as your last job was a milk monitor,
I did have a bit of trouble persuading them but,
however, I have managed to swing it for you.
Are you putting me up Del?
No, definitely, I've got a job
for you Rodney!
Hey that's great Del!
Yeah, it's alright, you'll
start off as a trainee NSO.
No.
Oh yes and who knows my son you know - you know,
use your old filbert, keep your nose clean,
a couple of years' time you could you could end up as a,
well - I don't know - a senior NSO.
- Oh I will Del, I won't let you down son.
- What's an NSO.?
Oh don't be gauche Janice.
What's an NSO.?
They don't know they're born
some of them do they?
That's right! Tell her what an
NSO is Del.
An NSO Janice is a Nocturnal
Security Officer.
Yeah see it's a nocturnal security officer. That don't
'arf sound like a night watchman Del!
It's nothing like a nightwatch- man! I mean yeah, yeah, you
will have to work at night.
And will some of my duties
include 'watching'?
No they won't, no I mean all you'll have to do is,
you'll just have to - you know,
you just have to well...
keep an eye out.
What is the name of this
recently formed security company then?
Oh well, you wouldn't have
heard of 'em.
Try me Del. Come on, let's
have it.
It's called...Trotter Watch!
Trotter Watch, that's you
innit? I'm working for you, ain't I?
Yeah, you see the way I see it Rodney is that crime is a
growth industry so I'm getting in while the going's good.
It's a nice regular job - got
a uniform - good wages.
How good?
We'll talk about that later.
First of all let us try on your uniform eh?
Yeah come on, slip into. There it is.
Oh look at that, colour suits you don't it, eh?
Yes look at that fit, oh yeah,
deja vu, it's like made to measure innit?
Yeah for someone else!
Oh well the sleeves and that - well he'll grow into them.
Don't worry about that, hey, let's have a look - that's it.
- TW.
- That's right, stands for Trotter Watch.
Could also stand for Traffic
Warden though.
Well - yes it could,
Traffic warden yeah.
This is a traffic warden's
uniform innit?
It is not a traffic warden's
uniform!
You've got me done up as a
bloody traffic warden!
Look it is once and for all not a traffic warden's uniform!
Now just trust me will you...Put your cap on.
I look like a traffic warden. I look like a traffic warden
who hasn't been well!
No you don't, you look stunning Rodders. Oh yeah, look at that,
you're emitting authority all over the place.
I'm not doing it Del. I don't
want the job.
Oh no, come on Rodney, you've got to do it,
you can't let me down, I gave then your word.
Gave who my word?
The people down at the Tyler Street bus and coach garage.
That's where you're gonna be based.
No I'm definitely not doing it
Del.
Oh alright, yeah okay. Well of course if you're scared!
You could admit it, come on. Allemagne dix points,
Janice'll understand if yer
bottle has gone.
Me scared? You must be joking!
Ah, that's the spirit, now I want you down there tomorrow
night nine o' clock. I'm a stickler for punctuality right.
Right then, I'm going to bed.
By the way, excuse me a minute Janice,
Your bondage robes
there're in the garage - alright?
And Grandad has washed your whip and he's put
it in the airing cupboard. I don't think it's shrunk.
Well I'll leave you two love birds alone.
And shall I just say 'Buenos Aires'. its.
Janice he was only...
You rotten git Del!
Well I'll leave it in your
capable hands then Rodders.
Yeah cheers Del...you realise this job's gonna
mess up my love-life don't you!
Yeah, that's why I'm giving you
every second Sunday off, ain't I?
Yeah but Janice is hardly gonna
be happy with that is she?
I mean while I'm down here at nights she could be
going out with someone else.
Now don't worry about that.What d'you think I'm all
dressed up for like this,eh?
I'm taking Janice out for
a meal.
You're taking Janice out?
Of course I am, for your sake, otherwise
she might be going out with somebody else!
- Yeah, cheers Del. But if she's...
- Why are you wearing plimsoles?
What?
I said, why are you wearing plimsoles, don't you think they
mar the overall symmetry of the uniform somewhat?
- I can run faster in these...
- You what?
I mean give chase you know...
pursue and detain sort of!
No, nothing happens round here.
It's as quiet as a grave.
Well I'll see you in the morning then Rodders,
take care now!
Yeah, don't worry about me Del, I'll be alright.
Ah, here you are Grandad, there you go. Look at that.
Look at that, eh? It's beautiful innit? Beautiful.
It's gonna earn our fortunes this is Grandad!
Come on Rodney it's ten to nine.
I used to be a security officer
you know, before the war.
Blimey, do you mean to say that somebody
actually trusted you with their property?
It's like trusting a piranha fish
with yer finger - or worse.
Oh yeah, it was a big warehouse over Kilburn way,
stocked everything from bedroom suites to kiddies' toys.
Well, there was this fella used to work there,
he used to arrive every morning in a big Wolseley car,
he wore a camel-hair overcoat, kid gloves and he always
carried a brand-new leather attache case
and he smoked expensive cigars. Well, call it
intuition if you like, but I was suspicious of him.
- Yeah, why?
- Well he was only a sweeper-up!
Cor, how do you do it Holmes?
Anyhow, one night he was leaving I stopped him and
I searched his attache case. It was empty.
Still, unperturbed by this minor
hiccup in my investigation.
I stopped him and searched his attache case
every night for a whole year. Then he left.
I wonder why?
I don't remember. I think he claimed someone
was victimizing him. No unions in them days see.
No, well that is it - innit, eh?
Anyway, a couple of weeks after he left the auditors come.
D' you know what they discovered?
We was missing 348 attache
cases!
What do you mean you had been
searching stolen gear?
Yeah and I got done for it. Finger-prints.  There's a moral
to that story Del Boy but for the life of me I can't find it.
I don't think I'm even gonna
bother to look either Grandad.
Hello the son of the bride of
Dracula. Here he is.
- What time is it?
- The time is nearly nine o' clock.
Nine? I'm gonna be late if I
don't get a move on.
No, no, it's alright. There's no hurry, go on, sit down.
Take it easy, that's it, go on.
Let me get you a cup of
tea, alright?
- Oh yeah.
- Here you go then.
Are you still taking my part
with Janice?
Yes, don't worry, I won't let
you down.
Oh cheers Del...How am I doing?
Very well, very well. Yes one
more steak meal could crack it.
Yeah? I haven't done this well
with a girl for a long time.
You're like me Rodney, I never
ever found it easy to get girlfriends.
I wonder why.
Here it's still light out. It's
broad daylight!
Yeah, of course it would be wouldn't it, nine o' clock in
the morning, what do you expect?
Nine o' clock in the morning? I thought it would be
nine at night. I've only been in bed 20 minutes!
What d'you wake me for?
Sit down. Sit down. It's alright, alright,
don't exaggerate, 20 minutes.
Listen, I want to discuss something
very important with you see.
What could be that important,
eh? I haven't got Janice into trouble, have we?
Don't be silly, least I hope not. I want to talk to you see.
No, listen now,
this night security job of yours is
merely a tiny part of my immaculate scheme.
What immaculate scheme?
The Tourist Trade Rodney. The Tourist Trade. Did you realise
that over 2,000 are pouring into London every day?
And I happen to know, despite the fact that tourism
has never been so high, the coach party trade is falling off.
Now, why you may ask, is that Del? Well, since you ask,
I will tell you Rodney.
The reason is yer average tourist gets fed up,
don't he, of seeing the old places.
Like the Houses of Parliament, Buck House, the National Gallery.
Once you've seen one Rubens, you've seen them all.
Now this is where a dynamic person like
me steps in.
Wake up while your brother's
being dynamic!
So, go on.
Yeah, right, you see out there Rodney, out there is a new
vibrant exciting London waiting to be discovered.
- Is there?
- Yeah of course there is. Ethnic London.
Ethnic London?
Yeah, yes, you know all those romantic
places that you've heard about in fairy tales.
You know the Lee Valley Viaduct, the glow of
Lower Edmonton at dusk,
the excitement of a walk about in Croydon, yeah,
look what I've had printed.
Oh I don't believe this. Trotter's Ethnic Tours.
What's all this squiggly stuff and the Chinese?
The squiggly stuff - the squiggly - that is Arabic
and the Chinese is Japanese.
It's a well-known fact that 90 per cent of all foreign tourists
come from abroad, so we've got to speak the lingo, ain't we?
We?
French I like it. Already you're picking up the lingo.
It's what I call enthusiasm Rodney.
I weren't speaking French Del,
I meant what do you mean 'we'?
We, us - you know, us - here you know -
'cos it's a family enterprise innit.
Grandad, he'll sell the programmes, I shall be the courier
and you, Rodney, you have got the best job of all
'cos you will drive the bus, hold tight everybody
Rodney's coming, eh? It'll be another wage Rodney.
I've already got a wage Del.
Yeah but you can't afford to
live on what I pay you, can you!
I don't know Del, how much you
paying me?
Well not a lot, not a lot. You see I can't afford to.
See, well I, I done a deal with the bus garage,
what happened was I provided them with a
nightwatchm...a nocturnal security operative, see,
and they provided me with an open- topped bus.
That saves the exchange of any cash.
- You know, stops any paperwork and...
- And income tax?
Income tax yeah. Well, come on, what about it Rodney,
a lot of work and effort's gone into this enterprise.
I mean, Grandad, he was up town this morning
at the crack of dawn
distributing all those leaflets to every hotel,
boarding house and hostel he could find.
Grandad, he believes in this
scheme, don't you Grandad?
Ethnic tours, it's the most stupidest thing
I've ever heard of.
See.
Del you can't expect me to work all night then, in the
morning, drive a bus load of tourists round ethnic London?
I've got to sleep Del.
My whole body is crying out for sleep.
Yeah, yeah, I'll tell you what I'll do, I'll get you some
assistance at the garage then you can have a kip,
- I'll get you an ex-police dog.
- An ex-police dog?
- Yeah, now do you fancy some breakfast?
- I wouldn't say no.
Good, great, come on then, off you go,
there you go -  in there.
While you're in there make me
a bacon sandwich, alright?
Where are you gonna get an ex-
police dog from?
- I'll get him - I'll get him Nero.
- Who's Nero?
Nero, Janice's corgi!
We clearly stated on our leaflets nine o' clock was
departure time. Here we are eleven-thirty , no sign of 'em!
I've told you before no one
will turn up.
Yes they will, soon as the word spreads about a bit,
they'll be here in droves.
No the only thing that worries me is, is a 59-seater bus
gonna be big enough?
Perhaps we should have
had two, you know maybe three.
- A tandem would be too big.
- Leave it out will you.
I'll bet not one single tourist
arrives.
- I'll bet you, 50 quid they do.
- Right, 50 quid, you're on.
- Right then.
- Alright.
- Right.
Shut up you two will yer. I didn't get a wink of sleep
last night taking that rotten dog for walkies...
and what 'ave yer. That's a funny kind of police dog
that Del, it saw a cat and run a mile.
Ah well, cats aren't Nero's strong point. But show him a
burglar and it becomes a tower of strength.
Where's all the tourists then? I thought we'd be having
an ethnic look round Chingford by now.
Don't worry, they'll be here.
Shut up you...
How much you charging them for
his tour then?
- 17 quid each.
- 17 pounds for a walk-about in Croydon?
Well that includes lunch don't it.
Traditional British flare...
...doner kebab, something like that.
A doner kebab. For 17 nicker
I'd want Donna Summer.
You would wouldn't you, you tight wad.
No, these tourists, they don't mind splashing out,
providing they're getting value for money.
Now look at that, they'll snap these souvenirs
of Olde London up they will.
That's a snip that is at a fiver a go,
almost alabaster, you know.
You're going to sell 'em models of a Greek statue
now housed in the Louvre gallery Paris
for souvenirs of Olde London? It's
the Venus de Milo, Del.
No, that is Boadicea that is
innit?
Boadicea rode round in a chariot with big swords
sticking out the wheels.
Alright, so she fell off her
chariot.
You're just trying to rip 'em
off, aren't you?
Au contraire Rodney, au contraire.
No, I don't want to leave them potless.
I want them to have some money in their
pockets, at least enough for us to have a tip.
As a courier what do you actually know about these
places you intend to drag 'em to?
Know? Nothing, which means twice as much as they know.
Don't worry, I shall bluff 'em Rodney.
I shall use the old spiel. If there're questions
that I find a bit dodgy to answer,
I shall just say I can't understand their English.
Don't worry, it'll be a doddle.
I mean, today I shall take 'em down Shoreditch
and show 'em the house where Sherlock Holmes was born.
Sherlock Holmes was fictional.
Was he? Oh well, I'll just say his house
was blown up during the war.
Tomorrow I shall take
them to the summit of Mount Pleasant.
The summit of Mount Pleasant!
What's the matter with you Grandad,
can't you stand heights or something.
Mount Pleasant hasn't got a summit.
All it's got is a big post office sorting depot.
Well that's ethnic innit, eh? We can give 'em
a guided tour of the depot,
you know show 'em the workers getting the most
from our post. I should stay awake if I was you.
They'll be here in their
hundreds in a minute.
I'll take 'em over to North London, you know, show 'em
where Jack the Ripper was buried.
Nobody knows where Jack the Ripper was buried.
Then they cannot prove me wrong, can they?
Shall we give 'em another five minutes then go Del
Yeah, alright. Take the bus back to the garage
then you can begin your night shift, alright?
I want you back first thing in the morning though.
And don't forget to take Nero out so that he can do his
business, alright?
A pint of lager Rodney, they'd sold right out of Pina Coladas
Del, so I got you a Mackeson instead.
Oh that's good thinking yes,
thank you Grandad.
What are you going to do if the tourists start asking
about the history of the places.
I mean, say one of them wants to know how the
Elephant and Castle got it's name.
Well I'll just say...er, once upon a time Richard the
Lionheart or Coeur de Lion as the French used to call him -
which he did not like one little bit - see where a
little bit of intimate knowledge goes a long way
in impressing people. Well, I'll say that he had a castle
situated roughly near the roundabout.
And what about the 'elephant'
bit?
I'll say er, Hannibal and his elephants lay siege to the
castle and Bob's yer uncle.
But Hannibal crossed the Alps.
I know, on his way to the castles, and the natives who
had never seen an elephant, they were sorely afraid.
And that is how it became known in
that area as the Elephant and Castle.
If they'd never seen an elephant before how did they
know it was an elephant?
For Gawd sake Grandad, a elephant's a bloody elephant,
innit? I mean you can't odds that!
I mean, you can't look at an elephant and say, I know we'll
call this place the Cow and Castle, you can't do that can you?
But you're not telling them
the truth are you?
The truth? The truth, you're so naive, Rodders. The truth
is only relative to what you can earn from a lie! Einstein.
I'll tell you one truth that you won't earn a brass
farthing out of. No one's gonna turn up.
They will turn up. They've got to...
This time next year we'll be millionaires.
You said that this time last
year!
You're eating, ain't yer?
No. I wanted to do this for years
Rodney. I always thought if we could make a success of it,
that eventually we would go legit. You know, we would
register the name Trotters Independent Traders
as a proper McCoy company. I have this dream
where you and I own this skyscraper office block
on the South Bank. And we're standing on the balcony
in a penthouse suite with a couple of sorts,
Gabrielle, Bianca,
bra-less but with class
- here did you know your Janice doesn't wear a bra.
- Yeah, I know.
Oh you know. Anyway we're in our penthouse full of rubber
plants and pine tongue and groove -
and we're sipping red drinks. And above us on top
of this skyscraper in 50ft neon high lettering
are the initials of Trotters Independent
Traders! Good innit, eh?
Triffic Del.
They've got to come. My dream starts the way
every success starts, with a big rip-off.
Del. Grandad's right, no-ones
gonna turn up.
Yes they will, you wait and
see.
I think that dream of yours
contains a subliminal message.
Yeah, you what?
A sort of subconscious truth. You see this skyscraper
belonging to Trotters Independent Traders right!
And on the roof is the company's initials and you're
standing on the penthouse balcony?
Well don't you see what the dream's trying to tell you? As
you're standing on that balcony with your red drink -
just above your head, in 50ft- high neon lettering,
is the word 'TIT'.
Come on, let's call it a day.
You owe me 50 quid on that bet!
Alright you old pessimist!
- What about our wages then Del?
- Oh yeah, I meant to talk to you about that!
I thought that was going to be the big one Rodney. I thought
I was gonna become the Freddie Laker of the highways.
It was a nice try Del.
Yeah, I don't understand it though,
I just don't understand it.
Grandad distributed a thousand leaflets, a thousand.
You'd have thought that one, just one punter
might have been interested.
Still, as dear old Mum used to say
'Its better to know you've lost
than not to know you've won'.
Dear old Mum, she used to say some
bloody stupid things...
I'm gonna chuck this down the
chute.
Well that weren't too bad was it Rodney?
I've had two days away from the housework,
a nice little drink and I've won meself a 50 quid bet.
Very nice, very nice indeed... Where's Del Boy?
Oh he's just gone to chuck
that sign down the dust chute.
The dust chute? Oh my Gawd!
Grandad! Come here, you senile
old parasite.
It wasn't me Del, it was me
brain!
It was your - I'll brain you if I catch up with you.
Come here. Get him! Oi!
Subtitles by NVL