It seems like whenever people
call you in for a meeting...
...it's all about sitting down. "I would
really like to sit down with you."
"I think we need
to sit down and talk."
"Why don't you come in
and we'll sit down?"
Sometimes sitting doesn't work.
People get mad at the sitting.
"You know, we've been sitting here
for I don't know how long.
How much longer
are we just gonna sit here?"
I'll tell you what I think we should do.
I think we should all sleep on it.
Maybe we're not
getting down low enough.
Maybe if we all lie down,
then our brains will work.
I can't eat this without ketchup.
Would it kill her to check up on us?
Would that be a terrible thing?
"How's everything? You need
anything? What can I do for you?"
- I know what you mean.
- Do you?
It's like going out with someone
and not hearing back.
- Same thing.
- Not really, but it's something.
Ask the people behind you.
Excuse me.
Are you using your ketchup?
What do you think?
You wanna give him the ketchup?
It's up to you.
You know what? I don't think so.
I'm gonna need it from time to time.
You wanna go to the movies?
What for?
To see a movie.
- I've been to the movies.
- Not this movie.
They're all the same.
You go, you sit,
you eat popcorn, you watch.
I'm sick of it.
- Did you take a shower today?
- Yeah.
That's the kind of mood I'm in
when I haven't showered.
When is it gonna be
my turn, Jerry?
When do I get my 15 minutes?
- I want my 15 minutes.
- Oh, quit complaining.
- You have your health.
- Health's not good enough.
I want more than health.
Health's not doing it for me
anymore. I'm sick of health.
All right, we're done.
You can have it now.
Oh, very gracious.
- Nice day.
- Yeah.
What is that?
- Hey, Jo Jo.
- Hey, hey.
Hey.
- All right, thanks for the ride, Kramer.
- No, thank you.
- So, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Come on, let's go to the beach.
- Are you crazy?
- No, it's a beautiful day.
- Have a good time.
Yeah, there's something
in the air today.
Can you feel it?
There's something in the air.
You know you're turning
into Burt Lancaster?
Yeah, there's something
in the air.
Oh, I forgot to call Jill.
Jill. Hi, it's Elaine.
How is your father?
Is everything okay?
What?
I can't hear you so good.
There's a lot of static.
Wha-?
I'm gonna call you back.
Jill's father is in the hospital, and you
call to ask about him on a cell phone?
- What? No good?
- Faux pas.
- Faux pas?
- Big, hefty, stinking...
- ...faux pas.
- Why?
You can't make a health inquiry
on a cell phone.
It's like saying, "I don't wanna
take up my important time at home.
I'll get it out of the way
on the street."
And the street cell phone call
is the lowest phone call you can make.
It's an act of total disregard.
It's selfish.
- It's dismissive.
- It's pompous.
Why don't you think
before you do something?
Here's a thought.
Bye-bye.
Too much?
Boy, I'm really surprised
at Elaine.
You know,
that whole phone business.
She should know
better than that.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What?
Where do you think
this relationship is?
If you are thinking of instituting
an open door urination policy...
...let me disabuse you
of that notion right now, my friend.
- You're so uptight.
- Yeah, I'm uptight.
Let's all just have
a big pee party.
Hey, everybody, grab a bucket.
We're going up to Jerry's.
It's a pee party.
Jerry, this is Elizabeth Clark...
...calling from
James Kimbrough's office at NBC.
Could you please
give us a call? Thanks.
Hello. Hi.
This is Jerry Seinfeld...
...calling for James Kimbrough.
Hello?
Hi.
Really?
No problem. Definitely.
Okay. Bye-bye.
- That was James Kimbrough.
- Who's he?
He is the new president of NBC.
He wants to sit down with us
and talk about Jerry.
- Our show, Jerry?
- Right.
Jerry? Oh, my God...
- ... he wants to talk about Jerry?
- Yeah.
- When?
- Today, like right now.
Right now?
- Jerry?
- Jerry.
- He wants to talk about Jerry?
- He wants to talk about Jerry.
- Jerry.
- Can I go like this?
- Sure.
No sports jacket? I don't need one?
Writers wear sports jackets.
- Forget it.
- I won't feel like a writer.
- You're not a writer.
- Right.
Water.
Need some water.
Water here.
Okay, now, listen. I don't want any
scenes in here like the last time.
- Don't worry. No scenes.
- Don't blow this.
I will not blow this.
If he says he doesn't want it to be
a show about nothing, don't go nuts.
- It doesn't have to be.
- He might not want nothing.
Something, nothing.
I could care less.
He might want a show
about everything.
Anything. Everything. Something.
Nothing. Who the hell cares?
- Put me down. I'm down.
- All right.
Mr. Kimbrough
is ready to see you.
- Magic time.
- What?
Mr. Kimbrough.
- Hey, Jerry.
- Hello.
Hey, hey, hey.
- How you been?
- Good. You remember George.
- George, good to see you.
- Hello, Stu.
You remember Jay Crespi.
Jay Crespi.
I'm gonna forget Jay Crespi, huh?
- This is James Kimbrough.
- Nice to meet you.
- Thanks for coming in.
- Kimbrough.
- Don't spell.
- K-I-M-B-R-O-U-G-H.
- That's right.
- Yeah. It's a talent I have.
Why don't we sit down?
I'm glad you're here.
Some day out there, huh?
Did you ever see
weather like that?
It's crisp.
It's Crespi-crisp.
Shut up, George.
Can I get you anything?
What do we have
in the fruit department?
Pineapple.
That's a dangerous fruit.
It's like a weapon, that thing.
Got spikes on the end.
Get killed from one of those things.
Anyway, let me tell you
why I called.
When I took over here, I reviewed
what was in development...
...and it was pretty much
same old.
Been there, done that.
Right. I was looking for something
different. Something that would have...
- ...people talking at the water coolers.
- Water coolers?
We call it a water-cooler show.
Because the next day, people gather
around the water coolers...
...to talk about it, right?
I would think people would talk about it
at the coffee machines.
Well, it's probably just easier
to say water-cooler show...
...than coffee-machine show.
It's really not accurate.
Nobody drinks from a water cooler
anymore, they use bottles.
But I think Mr. Kimbrough
makes a good point.
Anyway, Stu here started telling me
about a show, Jerry...
...that he developed
five years ago.
I have always loved it.
He said it was a show
about nothing.
So I saw the pilot,
and I've gotta tell you...
...I flipped out.
He totally flipped out.
What I wanna do is put it on the air.
Thirteen episode commitment.
Start it off on Wednesday night,
build an audience.
This show needs time to grow.
I love that Kramer guy.
He's a little off-the-wall.
- Oh, yeah, off-the-wall.
- Kramer.
And Elaine, I wouldn't mind seeing
something happening between you.
- Definitely.
- I tell you, I-
I really don't think
so-called relationship humor...
...is what this show's all about.
Or we can not do the show
altogether. How about that?
Or we could get them together.
Jill. Hi, it's Elaine.
Yeah, well,
I'm calling from my home.
Indoors.
Well- Well, I was just calling
to see how your fath-
I'm sorry, I'm getting another call.
Hang on just a second.
- Hello.
- Hi, Elaine, it's me.
- I'm on the other line.
- This is an emergency.
Get off the phone.
I'm sorry, Jill.
I'm gonna have to take this call.
Jerry, what's the emergency?
Jerry's back on, the TV show.
George and I
are moving to California.
That's the emergency?
- Did you hear what I said?
- I was on the other line talking to Jill.
Jill? Well,
why didn't you say so?
You said it was an emergency.
So now she's lost
a phone face-off?
That's even worse than
your cell phone walk-and-talk.
Congratulations.
They're doing the show.
They should have
put that show on five years ago.
Bunch of idiots at that network.
Can I tell you something, Jerry?
It's all crap on TV.
The only thing I watch
is Xena: The Warrior Princess.
She must be about 6'6".
She's not 6'6".
- Jerry, you ever watch that?
- Yeah, it's pretty good.
They picked up the show?
I'm moving to California.
Oh, baby doll, this kid's going places.
I told you.
The NBC guy liked it?
- Of course he liked it.
- He told you he liked it?
He wouldn't put it on
if he didn't like it.
Well, what are you doing?
- I'm writing.
- You know how to write?
Without the writing, you have nothing.
You make them look good.
Since when do you know
how to write?
- I never saw you write anything.
- Ma.
I don't know how you're gonna
write all those shows.
And where are you gonna
get all the ideas?
Would you leave him alone?
You'll shatter his confidence.
I don't need any ideas.
It's a show about nothing.
Nothing, please.
I'll tell you the truth.
The whole thing
sounds pretty stupid to me.
NBC is letting me
use their private jet?
And I can go anywhere I want?
That is fantastic.
Thanks. Yeah.
Great. Okay, bye.
Oh, hey.
Hey. How was the beach?
You missed it, buddy.
Lot of femeninas.
Some major femeninas.
Had a little meeting today
at NBC.
What are you doing?
You know, I went swimming.
I can't get this water out of my ear.
So do you remember five years ago,
we did that pilot, Jerry?
Well, the new guy at NBC
wants to do it.
They're putting it on the air. They're
giving us a 13 episode commitment.
George and I
are moving to California.
You're moving to California?
Yeah, but only for a while.
Yeah, but, Jerry,
what happens if the show's a hit?
You could be out there for years.
You might never come back.
- No, I'll be back.
- Jerry, it's L.A.
Nobody leaves.
She's a seductress,
she's a siren, she's a virgin...
...she's a whore.
And my agent said as a bonus
I can use their private jet.
So we'll all go somewhere,
the four of us.
One big fling before George
and I go to California.
A fling.
- So we can go anywhere we want?
- Go anywhere.
- Why are they doing this?
- I think they wanna make it up to us...
...because they let this
sit on their shelf for years.
This is all very exciting.
So where we going?
Well, I say Japan.
- Why Japan?
- Oh, geishas.
You know,
they cater to your every whim.
They're shy at first, but they're
quite skilled at conversation.
They can discuss anything, from
world affairs to the fine art of fishing.
Or baking.
I got it.
How about Russia?
Russia. It's so bleak.
It's not bleak.
- It's springtime.
- It's still bleak.
You can't be bleak in spring.
You can be bleak in spring.
If you're bleak, you're bleak.
What about Switzerland?
Switzerland.
The von Trapp family, huh?
It's a bit hilly. No?
You're not gonna do any walking.
What if I wanna
walk around a little?
So then you'll walk down the hill
and we'll pick you up.
- What if I'm at the bottom?
- You know what, forget it.
All right, come on.
Come on now, people.
Let's face it. We're not all
gonna agree on anything.
Why don't we just
all go to Paris?
I'll go to Paris.
- Me too.
- Yeah.
- So that's it. It's settled.
We're going to Paris.
Yeah!
Hey. NBC limo is downstairs.
I'm just gonna call Jill
one more time before we go.
Elaine, you can't make a call
like that on your way out.
You can't rush that conversation.
Well, I can't call from the limo.
Can I call from the plane?
First you make
a cell phone walk-and-talk...
...then she loses
a call waiting face-off...
...now you're talking about
a plane call?
All right, I'll just have
to call her from Paris.
Hello, Jerry.
Hello, Newman. What gives?
I was speaking earlier
with Kramer...
...and he mentioned something
about a private jet to Paris.
Yeah, that's right.
Well, I hear it's quite beautiful
there this time of year...
...and you know
I'm one-quarter French.
- Really?
- Oh, yes.
In fact, I still have family there.
This probably
won't interest you...
...but I have a cousin there
who's suffering very badly.
She's lost all use
of her muscles.
She can only communicate
by blinking.
I would so love to see her.
Bring a ray of sunshine
into her tragic life.
But, alas, I can't afford it.
For I am, as you know,
but a simple postal worker.
- That's a shame.
- Take me! Take me!
Oh, forget it.
Pull yourself together.
You're making me sick.
Be a man.
All right.
But hear me and hear me well.
The day will come. Oh, yes.
Mark my words, Seinfeld.
Your day of reckoning
is coming.
When an evil wind will blow
through your little play world...
...and wipe that smug smile
off your face.
And I'll be there,
in all my glory, watching.
Watching as it all
comes crumbling down.
- Jerry?
- Yeah.
I'm Captain Maddox.
This is my copilot, Kurt Adams.
- Ready to go to Paris?
- All set.
- We'll just grab the bags.
- Don't worry about that.
- We'll take care of them for you.
- Just keeps getting better and better.
Not bad.
The only way to fly.
This is it?
I'm sorry, I have to say,
I'm a little disappointed.
I thought it would be a lot nicer.
You're complaining
about a private jet?
You think this is the plane
that Ted Danson gets?
Ted Danson is not even
on the network anymore.
I bet when they gave him a plane,
it was a lot nicer than this.
Will you shut up?
You are ruining the whole trip.
This is a real piece of junk.
I don't even feel safe
on this thing.
- I have a good mind to write a letter-
- You're not writing any letters.
- Will you turn around?
- Why?
You are annoying me
sitting like that.
It's effeminate.
- It's effeminate to sit like this?
- Yes.
I think it's a little effeminate.
How is this effeminate?
I don't know. It just is.
- What are you doing?
- You still got water in your ear?
I can't get rid of it.
Maybe it leaked inside my brain.
Kramer, stop that. It's not safe
to be jumping on a plane.
I gotta get it out.
I can't take this anymore.
Kramer, don't be
fooling around up here.
- Kramer!
- Hey, get the hell out of here.
What is that?
Oh, my God.
- What is that noise?
- Kramer, what the hell did you do?
I lost my balance.
Oh, my God.
What's going on?
- Kramer!
- It was an accident!
I told you to stop
with the hopping!
Oh, my God,
we're going down.
We're gonna die.
Just when I was doing great.
I told you God wouldn't let me
be successful.
Is this it? Is this how it ends?
It can't. It can't end like this.
I'm ready. I'm ready.
Glory hallelujah.
- Jerry? Jerry, can you hear me?
- Yeah.
- There's something I have to tell you.
- What? What is it?
- I cheated in the contest.
- What?
- The contest, I cheated.
- Why?
Because I'm a cheater!
I had to tell you.
Great, I won.
- Jerry, I gotta tell you something too.
- Yeah.
Elaine, I've got something
I wanna say to you.
- No, no. Me first.
- All right.
Jerry, I've always-
Hey, what's going on?
We're straightening out.
- We're straightening out.
- Yeah!
Well, again,
sorry about that little mishap.
Once we get everything checked,
shouldn't be any more problems.
- Where are we?
- Latham, Massachusetts.
Why don't you take a cab into town,
get yourself something to eat?
I got your beeper number,
I'll beep you as soon as we're ready.
- Okay.
- Yeah, okay.
We'll see you later.
Well, what are we gonna do
about Paris?
I mean, are we actually
gonna get back on this plane?
I say we go back to New York
and take a regular flight.
I'm not getting on
a regular plane now.
I'm all psyched up
to go on a private jet.
No way I'm getting on
a regular plane.
Well, I'm sure that they would
fly us first class.
First class
doesn't make it anymore.
You get on the phone with Kimbrough
and tell him to get another plane here.
But this time, the good one.
The Ted Danson plane.
- All right, I'll feel him out.
- Yeah, just tell him to hurry it up.
Nice day.
Another one.
All right, fatso,
out of the car.
I'm gonna capture this.
- Come on.
- I'm getting out. Give me a minute.
- Give me your wallet.
- Don't shoot.
Well, there goes the money
for the lipo.
See, the great thing about
robbing a fat guy is...
...it's an easy getaway,
you know?
They can't really chase you.
He's actually doing him a favor.
It's less money for him
to buy food.
I want your wallet. Come on.
Come on, come on!
That's a shame.
All right, I'm gonna call NBC.
Officer, he's stealing my car.
Officer, I was carjacked.
- I was held up at gunpoint.
- I understand.
Okay. Thanks anyway.
They can't get another plane.
What's wrong with the plane we got?
They're checking it out.
- No, no, no.
- Forget that.
- Forget it.
- We're not getting on there.
Come on, let's get something
to eat here in Sticksville.
- All right. Hold it right there.
- What?
- You're under arrest.
- Under arrest? What for?
Article 223-7
of the Latham County Penal Code.
What? No, no,
we didn't do anything.
That's exactly right.
The law requires you to help
or assist anyone in danger...
...as long as it's reasonable
to do so.
I never heard of that.
It's new. It's called
the Good Samaritan Law.
- Let's go.
- Well-
A Good Samaritan law?
Are they crazy?
- Why would we help somebody?
- I know.
That's what nuns
and Red Cross workers are for.
The Samaritans
were an ancient tribe.
Very helpful to people.
All right.
Excuse me. Hi.
Could you tell me
what kind of law this is?
Well, they just passed it
last year.
And it's modeled
after the French law.
I heard about it
after Princess Diana was killed...
...and those photographers
were standing around.
- Oh, yeah.
You're the first ones
to be arrested on it...
...probably in the whole country.
All right,
so, what's the penalty?
Let's pay the fine
and get the hell out of here.
Well, it's not that easy. See, the law
calls for a maximum fine of $85,000...
...and as much as
five years in prison.
- What?
- Oh, no, no, no.
We have to be in California
next week.
We're starting a TV show.
California?
Oh, gosh, I don't think so.
My guess is
you're gonna be prosecuted.
Better get yourselves
a good lawyer.
Who told you to put the cheese on?
Did I tell you?
- I didn't tell you to put it on.
- Jerry Seinfeld on the phone.
You people with the cheese.
It never ends.
Hello.
Good Samaritan Law?
I never heard of it.
You don't have to help anybody.
That's what this country's about.
That's deplorable,
unfathomable, improbable.
Hold on. Susie.
Cancel my appointment
with Dr. Byson.
And pack a bag for me.
I wanna get to Latham,
Massachusetts right away.
So they got Jackie Chiles, huh?
And you know what that means.
This whole place
is gonna be swarming with media.
By the time this thing is over...
...you're not gonna be able
to find a hotel room in this town.
The whole country
is going to be watching this.
Now, we gotta do
whatever it takes to win it.
No matter what the cost.
And a big issue in this trial
is going to be character.
Find out everything
about these people.
And I mean everything.
It's pretty good chow, huh?
It would kill him
to check up on us?
No. Drops off the meals
and that's it.
I realize we're prisoners,
but we're still entitled to ketchup.
I guess we could have
called for help.
But then we would have missed
the whole thing.
I still had it on video.
We could have watched it later.
Yeah, he's right.
I forgot about the video.
Oh, sure, video.
What is that?
Plane's ready.
I'm Geraldo Rivera.
We'll be talking about...
...what most of you have probably
been discussing in your homes...
...and around the water coolers
in your offices.
I'm speaking of the controversial
Good Samaritan trial...
...that gets underway Thursday
in Latham, Massachusetts.
Now, before we meet our panel,
let's go to Latham live...
...where Jane Wells
is standing by. Jane.
Yes, good evening, Geraldo.
What's the mood?
What's going on tonight?
Well, Latham
is fairly quiet tonight...
...considering the media circus that
has descended upon this quaint town.
And what about the defendants,
the so-called New York Four?
How are they holding up?
Well, I did speak
with one of the deputies...
...who has some contact with them,
and he told me, quote:
"There's no love lost
with that group."
Anything else, Jane?
There also seems to be some friction
between Mr. Seinfeld and Ms. Benes.
The rumor is that they once dated,
and it's possible that ended badly.
Well, who knows, maybe this trial
will bring them closer together.
Maybe they'll even end up
getting married.
I hope you packed enough.
This trial could last for weeks.
What's all that?
- Cereal.
- You're packing cereal?
I'm bringing it for Jerry.
- You got enough for a life sentence.
- He likes it.
He misses that
more than anything.
So bring a snack pack.
Poor Georgie.
Was it our fault
this happened to him?
Did we do something wrong?
Maybe it was our fault.
Maybe it was your fault.
It wasn't my fault,
I can tell you that.
Oh, so it was my fault
but not yours.
You were the one
who smothered him.
- I did not smother him.
- You smothered.
He couldn't get any air. He couldn't
breathe. He was suffocating!
Sure. And you were always in Korea
with your religious chachkas.
I had to make a living!
This is excellent, huh?
Don't worry, I didn't use too much milk,
because I know we gotta make it last.
You know, I've had to reduce
my milk level.
I've always filled to three-quarters,
sometimes to the top of the cereal.
Now to conserve,
I can't even see the milk anymore.
- It's a big adjustment.
- I bet.