It's one of the hardest things
I've ever had to do.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Jackie.
- Is everybody ready?
Didn't I tell you I wanted you
to wear the cardigan?
- Makes me look older.
- Look older?
You think this is a game?
That what you think this is?
I'm trying to give you a moral
compass. You have none.
You're gonna walk
into that courtroom...
...and they'll see a mean,
nasty, evil George Costanza.
I want them to see Perry Como.
No one's gonna convict Perry Como.
Perry Como helps out a fat tub
who's getting robbed.
You think it's funny?
No.
You damn right it isn't.
You better not be laughing
in that courtroom, funnyman.
If you start getting all smart-alecky,
making wisecracks, acting a fool...
...you're gonna find yourself in here
for a long, long time.
I don't like that tie.
Susie, get one of my ties
from my briefcase.
How do I look, Jackie?
Oh, you looking good.
You look strong.
You one fine-looking,
sexy lady.
Thank you, Jackie.
What about me, Jackie?
Kramer, you always look good.
You got respect for yourself.
You're genuine.
The jury's gonna pick up on that.
Here.
- This one?
- That's right.
- Do I have to?
- Jackie says put it on, Jerry.
All rise.
Fourth District County Court, Latham,
Massachusetts is now in session.
The Honorable Judge
Arthur Vandelay presiding.
Vandelay?
- The judge's name is Vandelay?
- Vanda who?
- Jerry, did you hear that?
- Yeah. Yeah.
I think that's a good sign.
Is the district attorney
ready to proceed?
We are, Your Honor.
Mr. Hoyt.
Ladies and gentlemen,
last year our city council...
...by a vote of 12-to-2,
passed a Good Samaritan law.
Now, essentially,
we made it a crime...
...to ignore a fellow
human being in trouble.
Now, this group
from New York...
...not only ignored,
but as we will prove...
...they actually mocked the victim
as he was being robbed at gunpoint.
I can guarantee you one other thing,
ladies and gentlemen...
...this is not the first time
they have behaved in this manner.
On the contrary.
They have quite a record
of mocking and maligning.
This is a history of selfishness,
self-absorption...
...immaturity and greed.
And you will see
how everyone...
...who has come into contact
with these four individuals...
...has been abused, wronged...
...deceived and betrayed.
This time...
...they have gone too far.
...they are going to be
held accountable.
This time...
...they are the ones who will pay.
Mr. Chiles?
I am shocked and chagrined.
Mortified and stupefied.
This trial is outrageous.
It is a waste of the taxpayers'
time and money.
It is a travesty of justice
that these four people...
...have been incarcerated
while the real perpetrator...
...is walking around laughing.
Lying and laughing.
Laughing and lying.
Do you know what
these four people were?
They were innocent bystanders.
Now, you just think
about that term.
Innocent bystanders.
That's exactly what they were.
We know they were bystanders,
nobody's disputing that.
So how can a bystander be guilty?
No such thing.
Have you ever heard
of a guilty bystander?
No. Because you cannot be
a bystander and be guilty.
Bystanders are,
by definition, innocent.
That is the nature
of bystanding.
But, no.
They wanna change
nature here.
They wanna create
a whole new animal.
The guilty bystander.
But don't you let them do it.
Only you can stop them.
Thank you.
That was wonderful. Thank you.
Is the prosecution ready
to present its first witness?
We are, Your Honor.
Call Officer Matt Vogel
to the stand.
Call Matt Vogel.
- So they were just standing there?
- Yes.
Did one of them have
a video camera?
Yes.
With the court's permission,
we would like to play back that video...
...and enter it into evidence
as Exhibit A.
Proceed.
- Come on.
- Okay, I'm getting out.
Well, there goes the money
for the lipo.
See, the great thing about robbing
a fat guy is it's an easy getaway.
They can't really chase you.
Come on, come on.
He's actually doing him a favor.
It's less money
for him to buy food.
So they just stood there
and did nothing?
Yeah. Nothing. Nothing.
No further questions.
Hey, great plane.
Thanks a lot.
Piece of junk.
You know,
you almost got us killed.
Call Mabel Choate to the stand.
Call Mabel Choate.
Your Honor, I most strenuously
and vigorously object to this witness.
She was not present
at the incident.
Her testimony is irrelevant,
irrational and inconsequential.
The prosecution has gone to great
lengths and considerable cost...
...to find these character witnesses.
It is imperative that we establish
this is not merely an isolated incident.
It's part of a pattern
of antisocial behavior...
...that's been going on for years.
- Objection overruled.
- Thank you.
I'll hear the witness.
Now, Mrs. Choate,
would you please tell the court...
...what happened
the evening of January 4th?
Well, I was in Schnitzer's Bakery
when I got accosted by that man.
Let the record show
that she's pointing at Mr. Seinfeld.
What did he want?
My marble rye.
Your marble rye?
I got the last one.
He kept persisting,
and I said no.
- Then you left the bakery.
- Right.
But it didn't end there,
did it, Mrs. Choate?
Oh, no.
- Give me that rye.
- Stop it. Let go.
I want that rye, lady.
Help. Someone, help.
Shut up, you old bag.
Stop, thief. Please, stop him.
Stop him, he's got my marble rye.
No further questions.
I call Marla Penny to the stand.
Call Marla Penny.
The virgin.
What was your connection
to the defendants?
I dated Mr. Seinfeld for several weeks
in the autumn of 1992.
Then on October 28th, there was
an abrupt end to that relationship.
Tell us what happened.
Well, it's rather difficult
to talk about.
It's all right. Take your time.
Well, I became aware of a-
A what?
- A...
- Yes?
A contest.
- A contest?
- Yes.
What was the nature
of the contest?
Oh, please, I can't.
It's okay.
The four of them...
- ...made a wager to see if they could-
- Yes?
To see who could
go the longest...
...without gratifying themselves.
- Boy, this is an outrage.
- For the love of God.
It was horrible. Horrible.
Call Donald Sanger to the stand.
Who the hell is that?
Come on, Donald.
You're doing fine.
- The Bubble Boy.
- Bubble Boy?
That's right, the Bubble Boy.
What's a Bubble Boy?
He's a boy who lives in a bubble.
What the hell
are you all looking at?
Would you please tell the court
about the incident...
...that occurred in your house,
October 7th, 1992?
Well, Jerry Seinfeld was supposed
to come to my house...
...but his friend Costanza
showed up instead.
So I challenged him
to a game of Trivial Pursuit.
Who invaded Spain
in the eighth century?
That's a joke. The Moors.
Oh, no.
I'm so sorry, it's the Moops.
The correct answer
is the Moops.
Moops? Let me see that.
That's not Moops, you jerk.
It's Moors. It's a misprint.
I'm sorry. The card says Moops.
It doesn't matter. It's Moors.
There's no Moops.
- It's Moops.
- Moors.
Moops.
Help, someone.
There's no Moops, you idiot.
Stop it. Let go of him.
Donald. Stop it.
No. Donald, stop it.
- It was Moops.
- Moors.
So Mr. Costanza parked in
a handicapped spot, and as a result...
...you got in an accident
and your wheelchair was destroyed?
- That's right.
- And then Mr. Kramer...
...gave you a used wheelchair?
That's right.
So you were the doctor on duty
the night Susan Ross died?
Yes, that's right.
It was May 16th, 1996.
I'll never forget it.
So you broke the news
to Mr. Costanza?
Would you tell the court, please,
what his reaction was.
I would describe it...
...as restrained jubilation.
- Murderer!
- He killed our daughter.
He knew those envelopes
were toxic!
Order in this court.
Call Sidra Holland to the stand.
Look at this one. She's fine.
She's a 12.
You dated her?
So you met Jerry Seinfeld
in a health club...
- ...sometime in 1993?
- Yes.
- You met Ms. Benes in the same club?
- Yes, that's true.
Would you describe
the circumstances of that meeting?
We were in the sauna,
making chitchat.
You know,
I've seen you around the club.
My name's Sidra. This is Marcy.
Oh, hi.
- I'm Elaine.
- Hi.
So she pretended to trip...
...and she fell into your breasts.
Yes.
Why would she do that?
Because he sent her in there
to find out if they were real.
- State your name.
- Bookman. Joe Bookman.
- And what's your occupation?
- I'm a library cop.
What's a library cop do?
We chase down
library delinquents.
Anyone in this room
ever delinquent?
Yeah, he was. Right over there.
Seinfeld.
- How long was his book overdue?
- Twenty-five years.
We don't call them delinquent
after that long.
- What do you call them?
- Criminals.
So you and Mr. Costanza
were dating.
- Yes.
- And then what happened?
Well, I invited him to attend
my son's birthday party and...
Fire!
At the time, I was employed
as a security guard...
...in the parking garage
at the Garden Valley Shopping Mall.
Okay, let's go.
Why would I
unless I was in danger?
- I know it's against the law.
- I don't know.
Because I could get uromysitisis
poisoning and die, that's why.
Uromysitisis.
I wonder if they're having any trouble
controlling themselves now.
Perhaps these two hooligans would
like to have a pee party right here!
Objection, Your Honor.
This is completely inappropriate.
My client's medical condition
is not on trial.
May I refer you
to the Disability Act of 1990.
Sit down, Mr. Chiles.
All right, detective,
then what happened?
We got a tip that a lot
of prostitutes had been...
...turning tricks in the parking lot.
- You just cost me some money.
- Hey, cool it, lady.
Cool it.
Cool it, lady. Cool it.
Police officers. Freeze right there.
So Cosmo Kramer was, in fact...
...a pimp.
So you asked Mr. Seinfeld
if he would wear your puffy shirt...
...on the Today show?
Excuse me?
Excuse me, Your Honor.
What is the point of this testimony?
This woman's a low talker.
I can't hear a word.
So either get some other kind of
microphone up there or let's move on.
Call George Steinbrenner
to the stand.
Call George Steinbrenner.
So George Costanza came
to work for you in May of 1994?
That's right. He was a good kid.
A lovely boy.
Shared his calzone with me.
That was a heck of a sandwich.
Yes, sir, that was
a good sandwich, sir.
- Had one little problem though.
- What was that?
He was a communist.
Pink as they come.
Like a big, juicy steak.
How could you give $12 million
to Hideki Irabu?
Order.
Cockfighting?
Cockfighting.
Sponges. And I don't mean
the kind you clean your tub with.
They're for sex.
She said she needed
a whole case of them.
She exposed her nipple.
- How did she try to kill you?
- She tried to smother me with a pillow.
Call Yev Kassem to the stand.
- Call Yev Kassem.
- Who?
The Soup Nazi.
Soup Nazi?
You people have a little pet name
for everybody.
State your name.
- Yev Kassem.
- Could you spell that, please?
No. Next question.
- How do you know the defendants?
- They used to come to my restaurant.
Medium turkey chili.
Medium crab bisque.
- I didn't get any bread.
- Just forget it. Let it go.
Excuse me. I think you forgot
my bread.
- You want bread?
- Yes, please.
Three dollars.
- What?
- No soup for you.
But the idiot clowns
did not know how to order.
I banned that one,
the woman, for a year.
Then one day...
...she came back.
Five cups chopped
porcine mushrooms...
...half a cup of olive oil...
...three pounds celery...
That's my recipe
for wild mushroom.
You're through, Soup Nazi.
Pack it up.
No more soup for you.
Next!
She published my recipes.
I had to close the store
and move to Argentina.
She ruined my business.
His soup's
not all that good anyway.
What did you say?
The state calls Mr. Babu Bhatt
to the stand.
- How did they find Babu?
- I thought he was deported.
You've come a long way
to be here today, haven't you?
Yes. All the way from Pakistan.
And what's your connection
to the defendants?
I owned a restaurant.
Seinfeld told me to change
the menu to Pakistani.
But nobody came.
There were no people.
And then what happened?
Then he got me an apartment
in his building...
...but they mixed up the mail...
...and I never got
my immigration renewal papers.
So they deported me.
It's all his fault.
Him and the woman.
But they did not care.
They're totally indifferent.
All they do is mock me.
Just like they did the fat fellow.
All the time mocking,
mocking, mocking.
All the time.
Now it is Babu's turn to mock.
Finally, I will have some justice.
Send them away. Send them all away.
Lock them up forever.
They're not human.
They're very bad.
Very, very, very bad.
Hi, I'm Geraldo Rivera, and welcome
to this special edition of Rivera Live.
Arguments in the Good Samaritan
trial ended today...
...the jury has been in deliberation
for four and a half hours now.
Let's go live to Jane Wells,
who is in Latham, Massachusetts...
...covering this trial for us. Jane.
Just a few minutes ago,
the jury asked to see the videotape.
That's the one where they are
overheard making sarcastic remarks...
...during the robbery.
Yes, it's a very incriminating
piece of evidence.
But I must tell you,
Geraldo...
...this courtroom and everyone
who's attended this trial...
...is still reeling from the endless
parade of witnesses...
...who've come forth
so enthusiastically...
...to testify against these
four seemingly ordinary people.
One had the feeling that if Judge
Vandelay didn't put a stop to it...
...it could have
gone on for months.
Jane, whose testimony
do you think resonated...
...most strongly with this jury?
That is so hard to say.
Certainly, there's the doctor
with the poison invitations.
The Bubble Boy was an extremely
sympathetic and tragic figure.
And that bizarre contest certainly
didn't sit well with this small-town jury.
There's the woman they sold
the defective wheelchair to.
The deported
Pakistani restaurateur.
Geraldo, it just went
on and on and on into the night.
And so we wait.
Do they make you wear uniforms
in prison?
I think so.
It's not that bright orange one, is it?
I hope it's not that one...
...because I cannot wear orange.
Will you stop worrying?
Jackie's gonna get us off.
He never loses.
How about when he asked that cop
if a black man...
...had ever been to his house.
Did you see the look on his face?
Sorry to bother you, judge.
How did you get in here?
Please. If he's found guilty...
...please be kind to him.
He's a good boy.
This is highly irregular.
Well, maybe there's something
I can do for you.
What do you mean?
You know.
Oh, Jackie. You're so articulate.
We got plenty of time too.
This jury could be out for days.
Hello.
Damn.
They're ready.
Hey, Elaine. What was it you were
about to say to me on the plane...
...when it was going down?
I've always loved...
...United Airlines.
I think it's gonna be okay.
That girl just smiled at me.
Maybe because she knows
you're going to jail.
What?
All rise.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury...
...have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
Will the defendants please rise?
And how do you find with respect
to the charge of criminal indifference?
We find the defendants...
...guilty.
Oh, no!
Order in this court.
Order! Order in this court!
I will clear this room.
I do not know how...
...or under what circumstances
the four of you found each other.
But your callous indifference
and utter disregard...
...for everything
that is good and decent...
...has rocked the very foundation
upon which our society is built.
I can think of nothing
more fitting...
...than for the four of you
to spend a year...
...removed from society...
...so that you can contemplate...
...the manner in which
you have conducted yourselves.
I know I will.
This court is adjourned.
You had to hop.
You had to hop on the plane!
Puddy.
- Don't wait for me.
- All right.
We gotta get out of here.
We wanna beat the traffic.
Come on, Jackie. Let's go.
What?
Oh, and by the way...
...they're real,
and they're spectacular.
Well, it's only a year.
That's not so bad.
We'll be out in a year.
And then we'll be back.
Could be fun.
Don't have to worry about your meals
or what you're gonna do Saturdays.
And they do shows.
Yeah, we could put on a show.
Maybe Bye Bye Birdie
or My Fair Lady.
Yeah, Elaine,
you could be Liza Doolittle.
Why don't you just
blow it out your a-?
If I call Jill from prison, you think that
would make up for the other ones?
- Sure.
- Because you only get one call.
The prison call is like
the king of calls.
I think that would be
a very nice gesture.
I got it.
It's out.
Not that bad, huh?
Oh, boy, what a relief.
See, now, to me, that button
is in the worst possible spot.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
The second button
is the key button.
It literally makes
or breaks the shirt.
Look at it. It's too high.
It's in no man's land.
Haven't we had
this conversation before?
You think?
I think we have.
Yeah, maybe we have.
So, what is the deal
with the yard?
When I was a kid, my mother
wanted me to play in the yard...
...but she didn't have to worry
about my neighbor...
...sticking a shiv in my thigh.
What's with the lockdown?
Why do we have to be locked in cells?
Are we that bad that we have
to be sent to prison in prison?
You would think the weightlifting
and the sodomy is enough.
- So anyone from Cellblock D?
- I am.
I'll talk slower.
I'm kidding. I love Cellblock D.
My friend George
is in Cellblock D.
- What are you in for, sir?
- Murder one.
Murder one.
Watch out, everybody.
Better be nice to you.
I'm only kidding, sir. Lighten up.
- How about you?
- Grand theft auto.
Grand theft auto.
Don't steal any of my jokes.
You suck. I'm gonna cut you.
I don't knock the license plate
out of your hand.
All right, Seinfeld,
that's it. Let's go. Come on.
All right.
Hey, you've been great.
See you in the cafeteria.