Without a doubt, this will
be one of the best museum exhibitions
Gotham City has ever seen.
You can be quite the humanitarian
on occasion, Bruce.
It's commendable. It's inspiring.
- It's deductible.
- The Scroll of Osiris.
Pity only half of it exists.
It's the oldest Egyptian document
known to man.
Yeah.
Oops!
I gotta go meet Tammy at Charday's.
Hmm. Such a pity.
Now, let's have a look at you.
Ubu?
You could've been
my successor, Detective.
Instead, you will suffer the fate
of all mortal flesh.
Snake venom?
From an Egyptian cobra.
Extremely deadly.
- You're certain it was Ra's Al Ghul?
- None other.
But I thought he died
in the Pit months ago.
So did I.
That piece of papyrus is obviously
very important to him.
- I have to find out why.
- Where are you off to now?
Just in case the stockholders ask.
Gibraltar. There's someone
I've been meaning to look up.
Beloved?
My father? Alive?
It was dear old dad, no mistake.
No, he would have found me.
He would have told me he was alive.
I know the face of my most
powerful enemy, Talia.
He took quite a risk
stealing that scroll from me.
Why does he want it so badly?
It's part of a map.
My father has the other half.
As long as I can remember
he's been obsessed with finding...
Finding what?
The tomb of the ancient
queen Thoth Khepera.
It lies somewhere
in the Canyon of Tombs.
Many who've sought it have vanished.
And why does Ra's seek it?
I don't know.
You must believe me.
I have to go after him, Talia.
Will you help me?
You are so like him,
making me choose between the two of you.
Oh, beloved, why has he forsaken me?
Does he think I've betrayed him?
I can't pretend to know
what Ra's thinks, Talia.
The only thing he and I have ever
agreed upon is our feelings towards you.
My father used to have
a hidden sanctuary in Cairo.
- Perhaps he still uses it.
- It's worth a try.
Artifacts from the king's tomb.
- Every one's a valuable treasure.
- In here.
- This place looks familiar.
- Guaranteed authentic.
How may I help you?
We're just browsing.
You could find no finer place
than this establishment
in which to obtain wondrous bargains.
This, for example,
a priceless relic
from the Seventh Dynasty.
The only one of its kind.
Another time, perhaps.
Hmm.
This is the place. I'm sure of it.
There's a secret entrance
to a lower level,
but I don't remember where.
This might help us.
An ultrasound imager.
Eureka.
This part of the store
is closed to customers.
- We make a good team.
- That we do.
The completed scroll?
Yes,
and a translation made by Ra's.
Did you really think
I would be foolish enough
not to have this sanctum
under observation?
Father! You really are alive.
Yes, Talia, I am alive.
No thanks, I regret to say, are due you
for my current state of health.
No, Father, you can't believe that.
I only tried to save the man I love.
You've got a serious
priority problem, Ra's.
What can be in that tomb that's more
valuable than the love of your daughter?
Power, Detective.
The power once held by almighty
Thoth Khepera, queen of two continents.
You surprise me, Ra's.
The world's oldest chauvinist
chasing after a woman?
Thoth Khepera
was not simply a woman, Detective,
nor merely a ruler.
Through her flowed
the power of the gods.
With no more than a gesture,
she controlled
the force of life and death,
and with it she kept a nation
under her thumb for 1,000 years.
You sound like a bad
Saturday afternoon serial, Ra's.
- This is sheer nonsense.
- No, Detective.
I know there is a power there
to be tapped.
My 600 years of life
are proof of that power.
Farewell, Detective.
Farewell, Talia.
It is said that one finds immortality
in one's offspring.
Alas, I know that to be a lie.
The air won't last much longer.
It's not the end
I would've chosen, beloved,
but if we must die,
I am glad we're together.
We're not licked yet.
Cover your ears, Talia, and pray.
Talia, I'll do whatever I have to
to stop him.
You must know that.
I do. And though it breaks my heart,
I will do what I must as well.
No sign of Ra's.
Looks like we beat him here.
- How did you know where to find it?
- I saw the scroll's translation.
For only a moment.
I'm a quick study.
The queen's sarcophagus.
It's not what it seems, Detective.
Father!
That chest contains
more than a mummy's corpse.
Remember, Thoth Khepera was immortal.
Her subjects deified her,
named her after the ancient gods
of infinite knowledge and eternal life.
And in a few short moments
I will be privy to those same secrets
of life and death.
No.
No!
Who are you?
I am Thoth Khepera.
Those who have joined me
share their knowledge with me.
We are legion.
I am called Ra's Al Ghul.
I have searched for you
for over 500 years.
Tell me your secret.
Grant me the powers of the gods
that legend says you possessed.
That knowledge can be yours
if you join us.
Come forward, Ra's Al Ghul.
Come and know the mysteries
of life and death.
Father.
No!
None may defile me and live.
Talia!
Run!
Keep going and don't look back.
I'll do what I can to stop that thing.
Infidel!
Daughter.
Father.
My apologies to you, daughter.
Though I had abandoned you in my heart,
obviously, you have not done the same.
- What will you do now?
- Take them back to the authorities.
Your father has much to answer for.
I am truly sorry, beloved,
but he is my father.
Please dismount.
Another time, Detective.
Yes, another time.