Hey!
Who's in here?
This is the fourth
identical poisoning this month.
We've kept the victims alive so far,
but we're not even sure
what kind of poison it is.
Why don't you ask the woman who made it?
Poison Ivy.
She was our first guess,
but we ruled her out.
- You mean she's still in Arkham?
- No.
She completed her rehabilitation
six months ago.
The board gave her a clean bill.
And now, wealthy bachelors are being
struck down by an unknown toxin.
Sounds like Ivy's MO to me.
I don't think she's interested
in single men anymore.
Hmm?
You haven't heard?
Not only did Pamela Isley
clean herself up,
she also got married.
Hi. Come on in.
Thank you, Ms. Isley.
My pleasure, Commissioner,
though it's Carlyle now.
Mrs. Pamela Lillian Carlyle.
This is my husband, Steven.
Hello, Commissioner.
Nice to see you again.
Dr. Carlyle is our liaison
between the board at Arkham
and the police department.
You also teach classes
on criminal psychology at Gotham State.
I've read some of your works.
They were very impressive.
Thank you.
But I get the feeling
this isn't a social call.
Someone is poisoning and robbing
wealthy young men.
As painful as it sounds,
all clues point to your wife.
- That's outrageous! Pamela hasn't...
- Darling, please.
Batman, I don't doubt
that I was your first,
and probably only suspect.
Over the years, you and I
have had a rather intense relationship.
But that's all in the past, believe me.
I look back on what I was,
and I shudder.
Locked away in Arkham
with the obsessed and the insane
and me just as lost as any of them.
And then I met Steven.
His love and guidance
brought me into the light again.
Mom, Dad,
the Batmobile's outside!
It is, it is! We saw it!
Whoa!
Cool. Batman's really here!
Mommy, you didn't tell us
you know Batman.
That was a long time ago, sweetie.
These are my boys, Chris and Kelly.
- Hi.
- Can we ride in your car?
Come on, guys.
Let's leave Mom alone for a minute.
Bye, Batman.
I never thought about
having kids before.
I can't.
Nature's little tradeoff
for my hyper immune system.
And yet, when I met Steven's boys,
something inside me just melted.
I guess there really does come a time
when a woman wants
something more in her life.
At least this woman does.
Steven doesn't care about my past.
He and the boys accept me
for who I am now.
I don't know who has been duplicating
my old crimes,
but I can assure you, gentlemen,
Poison Ivy is dead.
Don't tell me the great Dick Grayson
is spending the night in for a change?
Hey, we got finals coming up.
But what about those cheerleaders
I always see chasing you around?
Can't they help you pass calculus?
- That's not the reason I asked you over.
- Oh, no?
No. I just thought it would be fun
to get together
and study and talk and, um...
And?
Hello?
It's me.
Oh, hi.
I wasn't expecting to hear
from you tonight.
I'd better go.
Uh...
Do you have company?
Not anymore.
Sorry.
I need you to check on a teacher
there at GSU. Steven Carlyle.
I was in his class last year. Nice guy.
- He's not in trouble, is he?
- Possibly.
See what you can find on him.
Family history,
places he's worked, anything.
Right. I'll check back with you later.
Cindy?
I'm so sorry.
It's all my fault.
If only I hadn't left him.
It's all right.
I had just gone back to my room
when I heard a loud crash.
I ran down here, and Dick was gone.
And you saw no one
leaving the dorm?
No.
I don't think Dick
is the only victim, Mr. Wayne.
You mean they kidnapped him
to get at me.
It fits the pattern. Wealthy single men,
all targets of robberies.
Only, in your case, you have something
more valuable to hold for ransom.
My ward.
Keep driving, or your neck gets
a new air hole.
What do you want?
I do the talking.
Bring five million in cash to the docks
tomorrow midnight.
Come alone, or the kid is history.
Nod if you understand.
Smart boy.
I expect
there's no other option?
The money's not important.
Getting Dick back is.
Agreed, Master Bruce.
But even so, didn't the kidnapper
leave some clue for Batman to follow?
Just my torn shirt.
I'll have to fall back on my instincts.
And right now, they're saying
Ivy's fairy tale lifestyle
isn't everything it seems.
Wait for me, guys.
Bye, honey. Love you.
What's she doing now, sir?
Buying squash.
I've been keeping tabs
on her all morning.
And so far, she's done
nothing more incriminating
than return an overdue video.
Even paid the late fee.
Could it be Poison Ivy truly
has reformed?
I want to believe it. Why can't I?
The greenhouse checks out too.
Nothing but plants and flowers.
Sir?
Later.
- Can we watch cartoons?
- After your homework.
This is a dead end.
I haven't found anything that...
There are laws against spying on people.
There are laws against
poisoning them too.
Look around, Batman.
I've got a nice house, a little garden
and a family that loves me.
Why would I jeopardize that?
For the first time in my life,
I'm happy.
I'm beginning to think you're right.
Batman?
Good luck.
You too, Mrs. Carlyle.
Wayne,
kick the case over here.
Let me see the boy.
The money. Now!
Send out the boy.
You hear me?
I hear you.
Goodbye, Mr. Wayne.
Time to hit the drink.
I guess I should be grateful that thing
used a fist on me and not poison.
Right. But we're still in the dark
as to who's behind this.
You don't think it's the plant lady?
All she wants is to be left alone
with her husband and sons.
- Sons?
- Carlyle's two boys, Chris and Kelly.
I know Chris and Kelly.
I was in Carlyle's class when his ex
brought them to visit last year.
I thought Carlyle had custody.
No. And here's another shocker for you.
Chris and Kelly are girls.
Hmm.
No sign of Ivy.
What's that?
Insurance.
Plastic?
Just a happy little homemaker, huh?
- Dr. Carlyle?
- Help me.
She's insane. Has to be stopped.
- You don't know what she's done.
- Mommy.
Mommy.
No.
It... It isn't possible.
- Mommy.
I was her doctor in Arkham.
She said she wanted to reform.
I trusted her, let her get too close.
One little kiss, and dear Steven
was my slave.
He was useful in signing
my release papers,
and for supplying certain raw materials
for my experiments
but the marriage was, well, a fake.
And these mutations?
Our children, Batman.
Plant-based life forms
enhanced with Steven's DNA.
They're not truly human.
In fact, their life spans are somewhat
like certain rare flowers
that blossom and die in a few days.
I see.
At first it looks like a child.
Then it resembles Dr. Carlyle.
- And in its final phase...
- In its final phase,
before it burns itself out...
The creature becomes my willing enforcer
and bodyguard.
Thief and kidnapper
is more like it.
It costs money to raise a family.
- You haven't changed a bit.
- Yes, I have.
I meant it when I said I wanted
a family that loves me.
I just wanted it on my terms.
Lady, you're nuts.
Well, that's your opinion.
Probably the last one
you'll ever have, too.
Kids?
That water I fed them
contained a super active growth formula.
True, it cuts their life span down
to just a few minutes,
but that's more time than you've got.
This way, Doc.
Great. She gave her little family
the formula too.
Stay with Carlyle!
Anyone else want their weeds whacked?
Come on.
My darlings!
Weed killer.
I figured what you were up to
involved plants
so I pumped your water tanks
with herbicide.
What was the tip-off, Batman?
Steven's kids?
You couldn't replicate them as girls,
not with Carlyle's DNA.
So, you took your chance with boys.
But Ivy could replicate herself.
What?
Guess you weren't the only one
with an escape plan, huh, Batman?
Most of the stolen property
was still in the lab
along with Ivy's toxin formulas.
Well, at least we have Ivy's toxins
to form an antidote.
I'm just sorry she got away.
Me too, Robin. But I don't think
we'll see her again anytime soon.
Ivy lost everything she had.
Everything she said she ever wanted.
For what it's worth,
I believed her when she told me
for the first time in her life,
she was happy.