Don't bother trying, Croc.
Those cuffs are stacked
polycarbon alloy.
Not even you can break them.
So they finally declared old Croc sane
and responsible for his crimes.
Took them long enough.
I hear they're giving him
his own cellblock upstate.
Your tax dollars at work.
Wake me if he busts out.
That would be a story.
You know, there's something the brains
back at the joint didn't think about.
Yeah, what's that?
Crocodiles got the strongest jaws
of any animal around.
Get back!
- What was that?
- Did you hear that?
Oh, man. Did he get loose?
I'm not going near that thing.
Batman? Come on.
Can't you do any better than that?
You want a piece of me?
Think you can take the champ?
You're pumped full of sedative, Croc.
You won't get far.
Farther than you.
No.
- Looks like he's been hurt.
- See his chains?
The poor guy.
It's okay. We'll take care of you.
Oh, judgment,
thou art fled to brutish beasts.
And men have lost their reason.
Bring him, good Goliath.
Huh?
Rise and shine.
- Please try and drink some.
- Yes, it's good for you.
Ah, now, that's better, isn't it?
Sorry, we haven't been introduced.
Richard. At your service.
Like Richard III,
I too am rudely stamped.
You have to forgive our dramatic friend.
He's nuts about Shakespeare.
These two sylvan nymphs
are May and June.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Ditto.
And you've met Billy.
You're the one that pulled me
out of the drink, ain't you? I owe you.
And I'm Goliath. I helped haul you in.
So I'll buy you a medal.
No need to be shy.
We're all family here.
It must have been fate
that led you to us.
Yeah. What's a freak show
doing in the middle of nowhere?
You're one to talk, lizard lips.
June, he's a guest.
Our circus days are over.
We used the money we earned to buy
this farm so we could live in peace.
This is a sanctuary,
not only for us but for all our kind.
If you're willing to join in the work,
you too are welcome here.
Is that a fact?
- Hey.
- You did it!
- Bravo. Well done.
- I told you he was strong.
So tell us, friend,
from whence do you hail?
See, I was part of this freak show,
same as you,
only they kept me chained
like an animal. Day and night.
Forced me to live in a tank.
Made me do tricks.
- How awful.
- Jerks.
Yeah. They fed me
fish heads and stale bread.
When I tried to get away, they worked me
over pretty good, put me in chains.
Don't worry. Nobody will find you here.
Haven't seen a soul since we moved in.
That's good, real good.
Ah!
And they say the city's dangerous.
No, I don't mind
sleeping out on the straw.
- Go ahead and take my bedroom.
- Don't put yourself out for me.
The cot's too small anyway.
And tomorrow we'll go
swimming, right, Croc?
There's the coolest grottos along
the river. It's like another world.
Yeah, sure, kid.
Too bad I forgot my bathing suit.
That's right. Our new friend here
is going to need additional raiment.
- He means clothes.
- Yeah? You guys got money?
Just a small nest egg left over
from the purchase of this mill.
Fifty thousand.
Thank you, Goliath.
It's not something we like to broadcast.
Fifty grand?
A guy could go to town on that.
Croc?
- What you doing?
- Looking for a blanket. I'm cold.
I'll find you one.
I got it, shorty.
You know, Croc,
I know you feel a little funny
being here, but it's great.
It really is. No one stares at you,
laughing, making you feel bad.
You can be yourself.
Yeah, great. Whatever.
Huh?
Calm down. I won't hurt you.
I'm looking for someone.
Half man, half crocodile.
- He's in there, isn't he?
- No. Stay away.
He's one of us.
Croc, run!
- I don't want to hurt you.
- Don't worry. You won't.
You.
Richard, help!
Quickly. Quickly. In there.
Ha! Who's the freak now, Bats?
- Who is he?
- A nutcase in a mask.
- He's the one who put me in the tank.
- Don't listen to him.
His name's Killer Croc. He's dangerous.
Quiet! Don't think you're
gonna fool my friends, do you?
They know my story. I'm one of them.
Yes. And his chains speak more
eloquently than any words of yours.
Listen to me. He's an escaped convict,
a cold-blooded killer.
I said shut up!
What he said, it's not true, is it?
You're being square with us,
aren't you, Croc?
'Course I am. I ain't the one who
attacked big boy in his sleep, am I?
What are we gonna do?
Get rid of him.
What do you mean?
If he gets loose, he'll bring 'em all
down on us. No one's safe.
The bat's gotta go.
It's your last hunt, Bats.
And now you're the prey.
Croc, no. Don't do this.
- You can't.
- It's not right.
I can and I will.
No killing.
Why, you dirty...
Stay out of this!
This is between me and the bat.
- But you can't kill him.
- He's still a human being.
- Who are you calling human?
- Oh, Croc.
Alas, I fear that the chameleon
has shown his true colors.
I think you should leave, my friend.
We've had enough of these shenanigans.
Well, kid, looks like we're gonna
have to postpone that little swim.
Watch out!
Hey!
The bigger they are, eh, Bats?
The evil that men do...
Stuff the Shakespeare.
You're lucky you're still around
to recite it.
You I'm not done with yet.
All right.
Hey!
Lookie here, Bats.
Got a couple of souvenirs.
One for you too.
Don't want you talking about me
when I'm gone.
Give it up, Bats. You can't take me.
I got the high ground. I got the gun.
I know a way in.
Huh?
Hyah!
You're guano, bat.
What?
Show's over, folks.
Okay, guys. All set.
Why, Croc?
Why did you turn on us like that?
We could have helped you.
We could have done something.
You said you can be yourself
out here, remember?
Well, I guess that's what I was doing.
Being myself.