You know what I like about people?
They stack so well.
Let me get
this for you.
Want the paper?
No.
This is too much.
It's not half enough.
Thanks for opening
up for me.
Anytime day or night.
You know that.
In a town where everyone is so
carefully reinventing themselves,
what I like about Freddy is that
he doesn't even pretend to change.
Oh, I'm late.
Every Tuesday I sit down with the
Speaker and the Majority Leader
to discuss the week's agenda. Well,
discuss is probably the wrong word.
They talk while I
sit quietly and imagine
their lightly-salted
faces frying in a skillet.
Vasquez must be
shitting herself.
Shitting herself while
Walker is shitting himself
then shoveling his
shit on her shit.
Bob, I'm planning
on eating.
Do we have a back-up
on the docket?
You're on that,
right, Frank?
I'm working
with my staff...
The Republicans are gonna
ram this up our ass.
I would if
I was them.
Well, even if we
squeak it through the House,
watch them mangle
it in the Senate.
Or filibuster it.
Well, sure, if it
looks anything like this.
I don't know why Walker's trying
to tackle a charging elephant.
It's madness.
Congressman,
sorry to interrupt,
but I saw you
sitting over here and...
Remy. Gentlemen,
this is Remy Danton.
Remy, this is Speaker
Birch, and Congressman...
I'm well aware.
Mr. Speaker, Congressman.
Remy just made
partner at Glendon Hill.
Glendon Hill? Great team over there.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
When was the last time
they added a partner?
It's been a while.
Well, they know a winner
when they see one.
Remy was the best press
secretary I ever had.
Why'd you
let him go?
I didn't.
They stole him away.
What accounts
do you have?
SanCorp Industries
is my main one.
I run that account now.
Anyhow, I'll let you get back to it.
Sorry again to interrupt.
No problem. Very nice
to meet you both.
Christ, these lobbyists keep
getting younger and younger.
He's probably making more
than all of us combined.
Gentlemen, this one's on me. I'm
gonna track down that check.
Glendon Hill fronts
SanCorp Industries.
SanCorp is deep
into natural gas.
I don't give a hoot
about natural gas.
But I have 67 deputy whips and
they all need cash to win races.
SanCorp helps me
purchase loyalty
and in return,
they expect mine.
It's degrading, I know. But
when the tit's that big,
everybody gets in line.
Tell them I'm
on top of it.
I need more than that.
You are well aware that
I do not drop the ball
on things
like this, Remy.
Promises, Frank.
The Secretary of State,
Argentina, the offshore
drilling accounts...
Talk to me when I've
solved the problem.
Don't waste my time when
I'm working on solving it.
When there's billions on the
line, you can't not call me back
and I can't not show up.
Fine. Thank you
for your diligence.
Eight figures to you
and the D triple C.
Six million to build that
library of yours, in your name.
I know.
Don't make them throw money at
your challenger next cycle.
You've made your point.
Have I?
I hope so.
Such a waste of talent.
He chose money over power.
In this town, a mistake
nearly everyone makes.
Money is the McMansion
in Sarasota
that starts falling
apart after 10 years.
Power is the old stone building
that stands for centuries.
I cannot respect someone who
doesn't see the difference.
What am I looking at?
The Williams Register.
Williams...
College. September '78.
And why am
I looking at it?
The editorial.
Not that interesting.
Michael Kern went to Williams.
Check out the masthead.
And then there's this.
It's thin.
The guy's a unicorn.
He pisses rainbows.
You think we can get traction with this?
I think you could.
Linda Vasquez
is on the phone.
I'm surprised it
took her this long.
It's only six
past 9:00.
Which means she read the
Herald three hours ago
and spent the past
two and a half
getting reamed
by the President.
Tell her I'm on my way.
You were supposed to keep Donald in line.
You assured me...
Twenty-five years he's been
pushing this particular agenda.
We got between the mother bear and her cub.
It's a setback, that's all.
On our first day
in office.
Linda, I've worked
with four presidents.
Setbacks are a dime a dozen
with a bill of this size.
Frank, if you can't
control this...
I don't take well to being
micromanaged, Linda.
You want to do my job for
me and run the White House?
Good luck. I won't
stand in your way.
Okay, Frank. Fine.
This is yours now.
If this thing can't make it to the
floor in the first hundred days,
then I'll let you
explain to the President
why he lied to
the American people.
I'm gonna get
back to work.
Please do.
We really should be doing this on
a Friday instead of a Wednesday.
Because if we do it on a Friday,
people have the weekend.
Fine, we'll
do it on Friday.
Is all
the paperwork ready?
Some of the more senior people are trickier.
There's severance and...
But we shouldn't run into
any legal issues. No, no.
We use at-will employment
contracts across the board.
We'll get started
first thing Friday.
I want all of the exit
interviews done by lunch.
Claire, I just can't help but
think that this is a mistake.
We've discussed this already, Evelyn.
I know, I know.
But I just have to say it
for the sake of my conscience.
I think that you
are dismantling
what we have built over
the past 10 years and I...
And I think the way
you're handling this is...
Is cruel.
It's not easy, Evelyn.
But it's necessary.
You have always asked me
to be honest with you.
That's how we
work together.
I disagree with
something, I say it.
Well, I disagree 100%.
Please, Claire,
don't do this.
I respect your
opinion, Evelyn.
And I appreciate you
sharing it with me.
But I'm not going
to change my mind.
Friday, then.
If that's what you want.
This is major reform.
A complete overhaul.
That would
usually take months.
Well, we only have
days, not months.
But think about the process.
We can't just...
When I asked my
colleagues, your bosses,
who are the smartest
minds in education,
out of hundreds,
we arrived at you.
The six of you
in this room.
Now I realize it
is a difficult task.
But we have the opportunity
to make history here.
And I want all of us
to make it together.
So, good luck.
We're counting on you.
Page one.
These bullet points reflect the key
planks at the center of our bill.
Get comfy. This is your home until
we have a presentable first draft.
Donald, what a morning.
I have no idea
how they got this.
I specifically told my staff
to destroy everything.
I can't imagine... It doesn't
matter how it happened.
We can't make it un-happen.
So now we have to adapt.
Don't they realize that
this is a first draft?
All we have here really
is a perception problem.
We don't get
a second chance
at a first impression,
Donald. You know that.
Now, look,
I'm on your side.
But Linda is furious.
What's she saying?
They want
to point fingers.
At me?
I told her we
cannot do that.
I mean, you are
vital to this process.
I'm up to here
with them, Donald.
For lying, for turning
their back on you.
You know, I'm of a mind
to say "screw it."
I'll fall on this grenade
myself just to piss them off.
Get me John King at CNN.
Wait, Frank. This
is not your fault.
No, we have to protect
your reputation.
But you're the man that needs to
get the bill through the House.
I will. Hang on. I will assign
it to one of my deputies
and quietly manage it. And I'll
help guide you through the process.
I am not comfortable with this.
Well, then, what do
you suggest we do?
What a martyr craves more than
anything is a sword to fall on.
So, you sharpen the blade, hold
it at just the right angle,
and then, three,
two, one...
It should be me.
It was my bill.
No, impossible.
Donald, education has
been your life's work.
The truth is my heart
is not in this fight.
You know me. I'm not a wheeler-dealer.
I can put my mind to policy,
but I'm no good at
this brand of politics.
Well, if not you,
then who?
It should be you, Frank.
You're formidable.
People respect you.
They will follow your lead. Let
me be on the sidelines for this.
Well, I could only consider
that as an option if I knew
that I could still
come to you for counsel.
Of course.
Whatever you need.
Part of me is glad
this got leaked.
Well, it would've been
better if it hadn't
but at least people
know where I stand.
Thank you, Donald.
Happy to do it, Frank.
He has no idea we got
six kids in the next room
already working on
a new draft. Stamper!
But why dampen his mood by telling him?
We just gave him a great gift.
The chance to
fulfill his destiny.
Write up
a statement for Blythe.
Stepping aside, fresh ideas,
et cetera, et cetera.
Make it dignified.
He's a good man.
And bring me that
Williams editorial.
After careful thought and
discussion with my staff,
I am relinquishing my management
of the Education Reform Act.
I hope to remain a part of the
process, but I won't be working...
Why did
you leak the draft?
I'm not exactly sure
how it got leaked
but it does represent...
It came from your
office though, correct?
We wrote it...
Who will be
managing the bill now?
Frank Underwood.
Was that your choice?
Or did the administration...
I feel very confident placing the
bill in Frank's capable hands.
Ms. Barnes.
How very
Deep Throat of you.
Well, I can't help you dispatch a president.
How about a senator?
The editorial on
the Camp David Accords.
"It is the opinion
of this newspaper
"that President
Carter demand Israel
"withdraw all
its citizens from
"the Gaza Strip
and West Bank..."
"Which it has illegally
occupied since 1967."
"Illegally occupied."
That's quite an incendiary
quote, don't you think?
For an administration
that says
the Middle East is its top
foreign policy priority.
Michael Kern?
Did he personally
write the editorial?
He was the editor.
But did he
write it himself?
Then there's no story.
I'm saying it's
a question worth asking.
And if he denies
involvement?
He will. Let him.
This is a man trying to be
confirmed as Secretary of State.
Everything is a story.
There's no direct link.
I can't get this
past Hammerschmidt.
Remember this moment
when you resisted me.
When you said the words,
"Then there is no story."
Get a good night's
sleep, Ms. Barnes.
You have a big
day tomorrow.
Francis?
What is this?
What does
it look like?
But the basement is mine.
I know.
It's not for me.
So who's it for?
For you.
There's a gym
in the Capitol.
Which you never use.
Because I'm a tad
busy running the country.
But not at home.
So now you have no excuse.
I want it out.
Give it a try first.
Is this your subtle way of
saying that I'm out of shape?
No. It's my way of suggesting
you could be in better shape.
That sounds both passive-aggressive
and condescending.
Just plain
aggressive and true.
Don't wait up for me.
Are you going running now?
Yes, because I couldn't this morning.
I had an early meeting.
Use the monstrosity.
It's freezing out.
You break it in.
It looks positively
medieval, doesn't it?
Trying to turn
my only sanctuary
into a fitness dungeon.
I won't have it.
It's a stretch.
We're not misleading anyone.
He was the editor.
Did you call for comment?
I tried three times.
The press secretary said he'd
get back to me, he didn't.
What about research?
You couldn't find anything
to echo the editorial?
No quotes?
No op-ed pieces?
Don't you think if something
like that existed
someone would have
printed it by now?
Nobody else
has this, Lucas.
I don't think
there's a story here.
I'm not saying
there's a story.
All I'm saying is that there's a
question that needs to be answered.
This is a nominee
for Secretary of State.
We have an editorial
on Palestine and Israel.
Which he didn't write.
Which we don't
know he didn't write.
Exactly.
We don't have
to print it.
I could just scan the thing, stick
it on a site and tweet the link.
But if I did that,
some other paper might...
Whoa, whoa.
Don't be a bitch.
I'll talk to Tom.
That's all I was asking.
We simply can't
afford to allow...
I got a guy,
he's almost perfect.
He's a libertarian drug fiend
marinating in a mobile home.
I didn't agree with President
Reagan on many things.
But there was some merit to the
notion of trickle-down economics.
And I feel there is much merit to
the idea of trickle-down diplomacy.
Those are my lines. Vasquez
must have given them to him.
...solve the stalemate
between Israel and Palestine,
that success will trickle down to a
hundred other diplomatic dilemmas
between Muslims,
Jews, Christians...
I'm glad you brought
up Israel and Palestine,
because just before
we came on the air,
I received an advance copy of
an article that's going to be
in tomorrow's Washington Herald.
It's front page.
And it was
written by Zoe Barnes.
And in it she quotes
an editorial that ran
in the Williams
College Register
when you were editor,
back in September 1978,
which called
the Israeli presence
in the Gaza Strip
and West Bank, quote,
"An illegal occupation."
May I see that?
Sure.
Did you write those words,
"Illegal occupation"?
No.
I have no memory
of this.
But you were
the editor of the paper.
Yes.
So it couldn't have gone out
without your approval.
No, of course not.
But my staff...
Somebody else usually wrote the...
And then we'd vote...
Well, did you
vote for it?
Honestly, George, I can't remember.
It was 35 years ago...
So you're not sure whether or
not you supported these words.
I can tell you without
a shadow of a doubt,
I did not write
these words.
But were they in line with
your thinking at the time?
This is ludicrous.
It's ludicrous.
That's all we need,
him laughing.
Nancy, get me
Dennis Mendel at the ADL.
The Middle East is a vital
American interest. Yes.
What you think about
the Middle East is relevant.
You can look at
my voting record.
Every single vote has been
in defense of Israel.
So when did your
views change?
What I'm saying to you is...
What's important now, George,
is how I have voted while I have
represented the great state of Colorado.
I understand
that's your position.
But a lot of other people are
going to look at it and think
what you thought then
is relevant as well.
Let me ask you this, have you ever
changed our views since college?
Certainly. But I'm not the
nominee for Secretary of State.
Even if I did have
this viewpoint...
It's golden.
It's a bull's-eye.
What were you
saying when you came in?
So...
I found a guy who was on the college
editorial staff when Kern was there.
This burn-out still pumping
mimeograph manifestos
out of a trailer park
in the Berkshires.
But you're not planning
on talking to him. Uh-uh.
Peter Russo.
Good.
Sounds like
a perfect match.
Dennis.
Any chance you're
watching Stephanopoulos?
You look sexy when
you're improving
the lives of hardworking
Pennsylvanians.
Is it the improving lives, or is
it these fetching sweat pants?
Why don't you move that
computer out of the way,
let me see
what that looks like?
Yeah, it's better
with the laptop.
Fuck off.
You're not paying
enough attention to me.
I pay attention to you
all day at the office.
Hey, you know, I don't think I've ever
seen you brush your teeth before.
Sure you have.
No, I don't think so.
I mean, I know
that you do brush.
But I don't think I've ever
actually witnessed it before.
Well, here it is
in all its glory.
Is that my toothbrush?
I don't know, is it?
Yes, it is.
You left it here.
Peter, gross.
Come on. We've exchanged
plenty of fluids by now.
No, no, no, no.
No. Toothpaste!
It's not toothpaste.
I'm rabid!
No!
Go get it.
I have to take this.
This is Russo.
Yeah. Right now,
it's 12:53.
Okay, okay, okay.
I have to go.
Is everything okay?
It's work stuff.
What kind of work stuff?
Congressman Wilensky.
He wants to go over the tax
incentive stuff we sent him.
Peter, it's 1:00
in the morning.
Hey, Peter!
I have meetings tomorrow.
I have a committee hearing...
Congress will
survive without you.
Address. Directions. There's
an e-ticket in your name.
Your flight leaves at 6:30. You
should head to the airport.
This is coming
from Frank?
No. This is coming
from no one.
You have the flu and
you're calling in sick.
What's that?
What's what?
Is that a hickey?
Are you whoring
around again?
No. I have a girlfriend.
You mean your
little office romance.
What do you
know about that?
When it comes to your life,
Peter, and what I know about it,
you should assume that there's
no such thing as a secret.
Stay in touch.
You call me on my cell,
never at the office.
Good luck.
Knock 'em dead, tiger.
How are we?
Over-tired, under-caffeinated,
but we're making progress.
Less than a week to go.
Yeah, we'll do our best.
You what?
We'll get it done.
And somebody open a window.
It's rancid in here.
That is what happens when six people
don't shower for half a week.
Anything you need,
other than deodorant?
Yeah, this performance
standards thing.
The teachers unions are gonna...
Leave it in.
But we could dilute it a bit...
I'll handle the unions.
What else, anything?
Conjugal visits?
I'll get back to work.
Nancy, what do
I have next?
Constituent calls from 2:10 to
2:35, fundraising until 3:50,
deputy caucus at 4:00.
The call list?
It's on your desk. My
briefing for the caucus?
Next to the call list.
Have you been in
the conference room?
Have it steam-cleaned
over the weekend.
In the meantime, get those poor
kids some Febreze or something.
It's like a petting zoo.
You gotta see this.
But were they in line with
your thinking at the time?
We do not consider
the issue of
Israel and Palestine
a laughing matter.
And he calls Israel "illegal"? Well,
he's an anti-Semite and he is wrong.
We would have grave, grave concerns
about appointing such a man
our next Secretary of State.
It's too easy.
Roy. Hi, my name is Peter Russo.
Congressman Russo.
I'd like to just
speak to you for just...
Sir? Either you're lying,
and you can fuck off,
or you're telling the truth, and
you can absolutely fuck off.
I saw your web site.
I'm a fan.
And I brought
you something.
Babe, put some clothes on.
What?
We got a guest.
So?
Hey.
Put some clothes on.
Ice or no ice?
No ice.
Good, 'cause we
don't have any.
Fuck. Echo! I told
you to put the...
It's okay.
I'll keep your secret
if you keep mine.
A congressman,
you say?
Right now, I'm just
a drinking companion.
Well all right, companion,
have yourself a drink.
Come on in.
$10,000.
What will
that get me?
I mean, I'm kinky,
but I don't know
if I'm the girl
you're looking for.
You're definitely the girl
that I'm looking for.
Excuse me.
All I want for that
money is your silence.
My what?
The guy you were
with the other night,
the one who was arrested.
Do you know who he was?
You mean
the congressman?
There was
no congressman.
There was no arrest.
None of that exists.
All that exists is the money sitting
right there in front of you.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Good.
Open your mouth.
Last little bit's for me.
You're scolding me.
Am I?
You are. Silently.
Is it the rowing machine?
You tell me.
It's the rowing machine.
You haven't used it.
How do you know
I haven't?
Francis.
You know I don't
like to be managed.
I'm not trying
to manage you.
I just don't want to
outlive you by 25 years.
I must walk three miles a
day around that Capitol.
I'm constantly
on my feet.
And do you know how many
calories the brain burns?
I'm not worried
about your brain.
It's your heart
we're talking about.
Use the machine.
She's right. I should take
better care of myself.
But it's the principle.
I won't be a slave
to anybody or anything
you can order
with a toll-free number.
We share the wealth
in this republic.
I thought the whole
editorial team pitched in.
Sometimes.
Not that time, though.
But he must've
written some of it.
No, that was all me.
What if people
thought he wrote it.
Fuck that,
he's a fraud.
No, he's worse than a fraud,
he's a fucking farce.
And I'll tell you
something.
He used to be even more
of a maniac than I am.
Chemicals?
No, politics.
We had some
nights, man.
Long conversations.
Dangerous fucking notions.
Like what?
You name it.
OPEC, Pinochet, the
fucking Food Stamp Act,
then the motherland
sang her mating call.
♪ Oh, say can you... ♪
Next thing, he's
cramming for the bar
at Bryn Mawr and
snapping on a flag pin.
Does Bryn Mawr
have a law school?
My point is, he started goose-stepping
in the marionette parade.
Left, right, red, blue,
Democrat, Republican.
They're all dangling
from the same strings.
Take a sledge hammer to the whole
fucking Punch and Judy show,
that's what's required.
Thought you
were a patriot.
Fuck yeah,
one of the few.
So what's wrong
with public service?
Public service?
Come on, man.
You gotta get a grip
on who your masters are.
The IMF, the World Bank, the
Rockefeller Trilateral Commission.
You bank roll their
fucking death squads.
It's called FEMA, it's called
Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.
NATO, border control.
You think Katrina
was incompetence?
That was highly
orchestrated negligence.
Look at Waco, Amnesty
International, the ACLU.
Smoke screens, all of them.
Blood on their hands.
Well, exactly.
You want me to
lie to the people.
I want you to spare the
people another hypocrite.
What's in it for you?
Poetic justice.
Come on,
you're one of them.
Can a corporate sell-out
roll a joint like this?
If I wanted to do
this thing,
how might I go
about that, precisely?
How did it go?
There were a few tears here
and there and some anger,
but nothing unexpected.
I'm going to need you to
leave us today too, Evelyn.
I'm sorry.
I just can't have any doubt
about the direction I'm taking.
You just had me fire 18 people.
I know.
I sat across from
them in this room,
and I had to tell each
and every one... I know.
I am 59 years old.
Nobody hires anybody my age.
I will write you any kind
of recommendation...
To do what?
Bag groceries?
Come on, what am I supposed
to tell my daughter?
I'm sorry,
Evelyn, I truly...
No, you're not.
You don't give a fuck.
Eighteen people, Claire.
Nineteen if
you count me.
I have to...
I have to call
my daughter.
I know today has been tough.
A lot of your
colleagues have left,
and I owe you
an explanation.
Many of those who
left us today helped
build the CWI
from the ground up,
and I'm grateful to them.
But it is time
for us to evolve,
and to accomplish this,
we had to make hard choices
and bring in new people.
That's what today was about.
You have any questions,
my door is always open.
I'm all good for
National and Metro.
We've got space for
Political if we need it.
Janine? Anything new
on Michael Kern?
The White House
is dodging.
You can't get
anyone on record?
Not just me. They're shutting all
of us down in the briefings.
No one is giving an inch,
even on background.
In the meantime, I'm
working on a feature about
the administration's
foreign policy agenda,
how it shifted from the start of the
campaign, increased DOD spending...
We see you, Zoe.
I can link Kern directly
to the Williams editorial.
What? I've got a guy
named Roy Kapeniak,
who was on the editorial
staff when Kern was there.
Hey, Twitter-twat. WTF?
Wait, wait, wait.
Roy what?
Kapeniak.
A classmate of Kern's.
I have him on record saying Kern
wrote every word of the editorial.
Let's move this into
my office. Zoe, Lucas.
Janine!
Let me once and for all
say this definitively.
I didn't author
that editorial.
Not a single sentence,
word, comma or period.
If memory serves me, it was
Mr. Kapeniak who wrote it.
Why on earth he's trying to
claim that I did is beyond me.
Let me further say that I am a strong
supporter of the state of Israel.
As the most stable country in the
region and our strongest ally...
It's Frank Underwood
for Cathy.
...in any peace process.
Because without the stability of
Israel, there can be no Palestine.
CNN, right now.
"Without Israel there
can be no Palestine"?
I've got it on.
I would remind Senator Kern
that there was a Palestine
long before
there was an Israel.
His comments are not only
ignorant, they are racist.
Get ready, Cathy. Things are
about to move very quickly.
Okay, I'm ready.
Hey. I...
Peter.
Not now.
Stop! Hey, hey,
where have you been?
God, you're fucking high.
No, I...
Yes, you are,
look at your eyes.
Please, just lay off.
You promised me
it wouldn't be like this.
Cancel whatever I have
for the rest of the day.
Kern is out.
They're tossing him?
Technically, he'll
withdraw himself, but yes.
Can I say, "A source close
to the White House"?
No. You let this story
play out on its own time.
They'll announce
in the morning.
I'm sorry, if not that, what
story are we talking about?
Catherine Durant.
As soon as Kern withdraws,
you say she'll
be the replacement.
Is that true?
It will be after
you write it.
Roy Kapeniak was you.
You might very well think that.
I couldn't possibly comment.
You found him.
You had him call me...
Kapeniak and Kern were
appetizers, Ms. Barnes.
Catherine Durant
is the meal.
Say that name. "Catherine
Durant." Say it over and over.
Tomorrow afternoon,
write it down.
Then watch that name
come out of the mouth
of the President of
the United States.
This is where
we get to create.
Don't miss your train, Ms. Barnes.
It's the last one tonight.
Zoe Barnes of the Washington
Herald now reporting,
quoting a source
close to the President,
as saying that
Senator Catherine Durant
will likely be the new nominee
for Secretary of State
after Michael Kern's
withdrawal earlier this week.
The White House has remained
silent on whether the President
will tap Durant
for the nomination,
but a national
Zogby poll shows
wide support for
Durant across party lines.
...has served 10 years on the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee,
made numerous diplomatic
missions to South America...
...place our faith
in her, knowing that
we have a responsible,
experienced,
brilliant woman representing
our interests abroad.
...middle of the road, team
player, strong on defense.
And if there's
a woman that can work
with the Joint Chiefs,
she's the one.
Durant is the way to go,
it's a no-brainer.
The President should stop this
pageant and simply make the call.
Why are we still talking about if
they're going to nominate Durant?
Why don't they
just do it already
so we can all stop
talking about ifs
and start talking
about when and what
and how Durant's going
to shape our foreign policy.
So, history?
History.
I'm very impressed, Frank.
Good. With your go-ahead,
I'll start the mark-up.
Have Birch and
Rasmussen seen this?
Not yet, I wanted you to be
the first to have a look.
I'll schedule a time for you
to fill in the President.
Oh, no, no, no. That is your turf, Linda.
You should do that.
Thank you, Frank. My pleasure.
Thank you.
I so apologize
for everything...
No, no, no.
That's not necessary.
Now for
the real meeting.
So, what is happening
with Michael Kern?
It's a total nightmare.
Do you know who you're
going to tap next?
Frank, we still need
you in the House...
No, no, no.
I wouldn't dream of it.
We've got
our education bill.
I was just curious.
Somehow, the rumor
is flying around that
we're going to
nominate Catherine Durant.
I'm sure you've noticed.
Is the rumor true?
Well, we weren't
considering her at first,
but the President asked
me to have her vetted,
in case we
want to go that route.
Interesting.
What do you think?
Well, she wouldn't
be my first choice...
Who would be
your first choice?
She campaigned hard against
us in the primaries.
That's my reservation.
But you'd show yourself
above party politics,
and I know she'd work
all the harder for it.
Decent experience.
Respect across the aisle...
So you think we can
seriously consider her?
It's not the worst idea
in the world.
Where are you
getting this shit?
What?
Your stories.
I was just...
Who are you fucking?
Nobody.
Oh, come on.
You're a Metro scrub,
and now look at you.
You'd have to be fucking
somebody important.
I'm just doing my job,
Janine. Excuse me.
All right.
One sec. Okay.
Is this your
first remote?
Yeah, it's my first time.
Right into the camera.
Don't shift in your seat,
and there's no reason
to speak above a conversational
volume, the mic will pick you up.
You all ready?
Yeah.
All right,
don't forget to breathe.
Five, four, three...
We'd like to welcome Zoe Barnes
from the Washington Herald.
Zoe, thank you
for joining us.
I am very glad to be here.
Thank you for having me.
You broke the education
bill, the Kern editorial
and now Durant.
I'm just thrilled to be
reporting news that matters.
And it's truly
been a team effort.
Everyone at
the Herald pitched in.
But yes,
a lot of firsts.
First national story,
first...
Thank you.
Calling it a night.
See you tomorrow, sir.
But yes,
a lot of firsts.
First national story,
first front page by-line,
first TV interview...
I would wave to my mom, but the camera
man said not to shift in my seat.
What a roller coaster.
It really is too bad.
Kern is a good man.
And now Catherine Durant.
Yes. Right place,
right time, I suppose.
We like her,
don't we?
Very much.
The question is does she like
SanCorp as much as we like her?
I would say that
that is a very good bet.
But then again,
I'm not a betting man.
No, you always
like a sure thing.
When it avails itself.
Goodnight, Remy.
Goodnight, Frank.
See you around.
Hopefully less
and less now.
Oh, no, I charged the wrong thing.
What did you have again?
Medium decaf latte.
Med, latt, dec...
I don't know how to
get it to go back.
This one
and this one.
This one?
No. Let me do it.
I'll have to ask you
to stay back, Congressman.
What's going on?
Some guy was trying
to get into the building.
When we said no, he started
tearing his clothes off.
Nobody can hear you.
Nobody cares about you.
Nothing will
come of this.
Why don't you let these nice
gentlemen take you home?
Cover him up.
It's cold out here.
You heard the congressman.
Cover him up.
Francis?