It's there
for leverage,
so that we can lock down
performance standards.
You don't toss
around their right
to collective bargaining
like a poker chip.
If we don't,
they won't budge.
Has Marty Spinella
seen this?
Not in the version
I showed him.
So you lied to his face? No.
I revised the parameters
of my promise.
Which is lying.
Which is politics.
The sort you're
well-versed in, Bob.
Here's some
politics for you.
I allow this to
go to the floor,
I get murdered
next election.
This is coming
from the President.
Last time I checked, I was
still a Democrat, Frank,
and you were, too. Are you
telling me the President isn't?
Because he's acting a hell
of a lot like a Republican.
I thought Bob
was on our team.
Just sit him down with the President.
Ten minutes.
We won't touch
collective bargaining.
Are you interested
in my advice on this,
or you just want me to
deliver the message?
I'm always interested
in your advice, Frank.
Birch is right. You're going
to burn a lot of bridges.
The President should
at least sit down with him
and let him
make his case.
You tell Bob I'm happy to schedule
a meeting with the President
once he's set a date to put
this bill on the floor.
The President
can fuck himself.
This is the platform.
It's what he ran on.
I don't give a shit what he ran on.
He can't steamroll the House.
And don't forget, you work
for me, Frank, not him.
If he wants something
on the floor,
he's gonna have to
talk to me directly.
I know you take a lot of
pride in your manhood, Bob,
and it's impressive,
but as big as it is, Linda can
still shut the door on it.
Tell Vasquez
the bill is dead.
That's not the first time
he's pulled that stunt on me.
Probably should
have held my tongue,
but I just couldn't resist the
chance to see him shrivel.
Good morning.
Frank.
Mr. President.
Linda.
Let's strike the anti-collective
bargaining provision from the bill.
Linda and I have
talked it over,
and I think
she's right on this.
Tell Bob he can come by
tomorrow afternoon.
Sir, respectfully,
I do not think
you should give
him the satisfaction.
Well, give me a reason.
Makes us appear weak.
This is an opportunity for you
to establish your supremacy.
We should seize it.
But without
Birch's cooperation,
we're fighting
an uphill battle
before we even get the bill to the floor.
Frank, we discussed this.
Sir, if you
give in now,
Birch will walk all over you
for the next four years.
I can get this bill on the House floor as is.
I promise you.
All right, Frank.
Show me what you can do.
Thank you,
Mr. President.
That was her trying to
take credit for my idea.
Advice she wouldn't take
from me. Unacceptable.
I will not allow
her to sell my goods
when she cuts me
out of the profits.
I specifically told
her no interviews.
She disobeyed me,
not just once.
At least eight
times in the past month.
She stays, Tom.
She has no respect for
my authority, Margaret.
I said she stays.
There are rules. There's
a way of doing things.
If I have a reporter
who won't listen...
Two freshmen girls are moving
into their dorm room together.
One of them's from Georgia, one
of them's from Connecticut.
Girl from Connecticut's helping
her mother put up curtains.
Girl from Georgia turns to them and says, "Hi.
Where y'all from?"
Girl from Connecticut says,
"We're from a place
"where we know not to end a
sentence with a preposition."
Girl from Georgia says,
"Beg my pardon.
"Where y'all from...
"Cunt?"
You heard that one before?
A version of it.
With softer language.
Tom, we don't need people
who follow the rules.
We need people
with personality.
We want Zoe's face,
her energy.
We want to get her on
TV as much as possible.
It helps us cut
through the noise.
See what I'm saying?
I hear you, Margaret.
Thank you, Tom.
Thank you.
Come in.
Oh, I thought...
I wanted to say
hi to Evelyn.
Evelyn?
This was her office.
I don't think she
works here anymore.
Oh.
Gillian Cole.
I came on board
a couple weeks ago.
Gillian. WorldWell.
Yeah. I've heard great things.
Remy Danton.
You work with Claire?
In a way.
Hello, Remy.
Claire.
I see you've
met Gillian.
Yes, just now.
She's doing fantastic work
for us, as you can see.
Red is completed wells,
green, potential sites,
yellow, approved sites, and blue
are the filtration centers.
Nice. So you
liking it here?
Yeah. My staff
and I are loving it.
Claire's opened
a lot of doors for us.
Sounds like Claire.
Shall we head
to my office?
Gillian, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
What happened?
Things got complicated.
SanCorp was in
a difficult situation.
I would have thought you'd step
up when things were difficult,
not hold the
donation hostage.
Well, things are
less complicated now.
The donation is
back on the table.
I had to fire
half my staff.
Now you can
hire them back.
SanCorp is prepared to double
its initial commitment.
$1.5 million,
lump sum, this quarter.
Why? Public relations.
Same as before.
And what do they
want from Francis?
Things are square with Frank.
We're only talking about the CWI.
But why double it?
Because I said
they should.
The more they give,
the more you can do.
The more you can do,
the better they look.
And that's why they hired Glendon
Hill, to make them look good.
And they also hired you to
get traction in Congress.
Not in this case.
We want a long-term
partnership, Claire.
This is an investment
in the future.
We're not attaching strings.
I'll think about it.
They'd really love to
move quickly on this.
I said I'll
think about it.
Madeleine, you have to email me this shit.
I need it in writing.
And with more than
an hour's notice.
Yeah, I know that, but you have
to understand we have a plan.
We have a way that we do
this, and when you...
Okay.
Fine.
Yeah. Yeah. Bye.
Madeleine has decided to have a
spur-of-the-moment trip to Orlando
with her latest
eHarmony catch.
No heads-up, no warning.
The kids?
They get out of
school at 2:30.
I can do the
Shipbuilder's meeting.
You sure? Yeah, it's just
their public affairs team.
I'll brief you, and then you
can call them tomorrow.
Go get your kids.
Mmm.
Hey.
Remy came by this morning.
To the office.
What does he want?
The donation's
back on the table.
They've doubled
it to $1.5 million.
You said no, right?
I didn't.
He doesn't want anything
from you, Francis.
Come on, Claire.
You know better than that.
I specifically asked.
Maybe not right now, but look, I
invented this guy, all right?
It's a slippery slope.
Think of what I can
do with this money.
I can hire back
the people I let go.
I can help
accelerate the funding
for the projects that
Gillian has brought in.
Let's find another
way to raise the money.
But it's right
there at my feet.
Claire, I have too much
on my plate right now.
I can't have SanCorp breathing
down my neck again.
I can't have Remy...
Look, it is Remy.
He knows me too well.
It's dangerous.
Look at the
bigger picture here.
I'm asking.
No. You're not.
Claire.
I'll tell you
what I told him.
Which was?
I'll think about it.
I know there's
been some tension,
and I'm probably more
to blame than you are.
But I'd like to
put that behind us.
Zoe, you're going to be our new
White House correspondent.
What about Janine?
I promoted her to
Midwest Bureau Chief.
She's okay with that? She wants
to give up the White House?
It's the decision
I've made.
It's just that Janine
has so much experience.
I thought you'd be
more excited about this.
I'm sorry. I just thought you brought
me in here to... I don't know.
To fire you.
Maybe.
Water under the bridge.
We're starting over.
So are you ready
to take this on?
Can I think about it?
People usually don't
have to think about it
when they're offered
the White House, Zoe.
Just a day or two.
Janine is booked for a
flight to Chicago on Friday.
I'll let you know before then.
I just need to...
Thank you.
Thank you, Tom.
David Rasmussen is
the majority leader,
which means he's
one step above me
and one below Birch, which is akin
to being between a very hungry wolf
and a very
quarrelsome sheep.
Let's see if he stays with
the herd or joins the pack.
David. You mind
if I join you?
Please. A salad, huh?
Yes. I'm trying to take
better care of myself.
Good man. Diet?
Diet, exercise,
everything.
You ought to take better
care of yourself, too.
Well, then they should stop
serving such good pizza.
I'm not talking
about the food.
I'm talking about Birch.
You are never
going to be Speaker
unless you do
something about it.
I'm very satisfied
where I am.
Oh, come on.
For the time being, yeah.
Time being never.
The only way
you become Speaker
is if Birch loses his
district or retires,
neither of which
is going to happen
before you and
I have dentures.
I'm not happy where this
conversation is going, Frank.
If you want it, and I know
you do, there's a way.
Okay. Right.
I can't...
All you need is a simple majority.
218 votes.
We're going to get at
least 205 out of the GOP,
and after that, all you
need is 13 Democrats.
You and I make two.
Are you out
of your mind?
Just consider it
for a moment.
You want to collude
with the Republicans?
I don't want to, but I would if you
become Speaker in the process.
Never been done before.
There's a first
time for everything.
This is ridiculous.
The Republicans
would love a chance
to knock Bob
down a peg or two.
And you want
to help them?
I want to help us.
Bob will not play ball
with the White House.
Now, you're a reasonable
man, David, and he's not.
You know what I am?
I'm a discreet man.
You're lucky for that.
I'm not going to
mention this to Bob,
but if you ever
bring it up again,
I won't have a choice.
Looks like he
opted for the herd.
Claire. I'd like to put an
order for the water filters
and the well-digging equipment
for the South Sudan project.
Can we talk
about the budget?
How much?
$200,000.
For one project?
I know it's a lot,
but it'll be our flagship
project in Africa,
and we would be the first organization
there to work on this scale.
I'd like to go over
the specifics first.
I have the budget
right here.
Let me just grab my messages,
and then I'll come in to you.
Okay. I'll be
in my office.
Any calls
while I was out?
They're on the desk,
and this came by messenger.
Adam. It's Claire.
Yes. I know. It has.
No reason. I was just
thinking about you.
You're right. It is a lie.
I do have a reason.
I need to use you.
The White House is where news goes to die.
Everything's canned.
These perfectly
prepared statements...
It's a prestigious
job, Zoe.
Used to be, when I was in ninth grade.
Now it's a graveyard.
The only halfway
interesting thing they do
is throw a big dinner
party once a year
where they pat
themselves on the back
and rub shoulders
with movie stars.
Who needs that?
Every day since
you started here,
you've begged me to move you
up, and now suddenly...
My goal in life is not to
climb up The Herald's ladder
one rung at a time until
I've got my own stationery.
Some of us value a career
at a paper like this.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
for that to come off...
Well, it did, and you skipped
a few rungs, by the way.
Do what you
want to do, Zoe,
but if you want me to
be your cheerleader
and say, "Yeah, turn
it down," I won't.
I would have killed for that
job when I first started here.
Put Fichner in the
"leaning yes" column.
Don't you think
he's a neutral?
He hates Birch.
Yeah, but he owes Birch for the
Ways and Means appointment.
Put him in "neutral."
Who else?
Ramirez as a neutral?
Oh, this list
is so shaky.
Any one of them
leaks it to Bob...
No, what we need
is one name.
One person who
can deliver 12.
The Black Caucus.
Womack.
What can we offer him?
What does he need?
Let me pull up his file.
Here we go.
McCuddin Airforce base employs
3,000 people in his district.
It's on the DOD's
chopping block this year.
Who do we know on
the BRAC commission?
That's dangerous.
The trail leads back to us trying
to influence the DOD or the BRAC.
No, no, no. What we do is
we close another base.
We leave enough money
in the DOD's budget
to keep Womack's
base off the list.
What we need...
Is someone we own.
Dad, I'm hungry.
Coming, buddy.
Here we go.
With cheese.
Without cheese.
Umm, Dad?
Yeah.
That looks
pretty disgusting.
Yeah, it looks disgusting.
It's not how it looks,
it's how it tastes.
And a fork
would be nice.
Shit. Okay. Hold on.
Hello.
Good evening,
Mr. Russo.
There's a Mr. Underwood
here to see you.
Uh...
Okay. Send him up.
Hi, there.
Hi.
This is Kevin,
this is Sarah.
Hi. I'm Frank.
Nice to meet you both.
Do you work with Dad?
I do.
Congressman Underwood
is Daddy's boss.
I thought you
didn't have a boss.
Everybody has a boss,
sweetheart, even Congressmen.
Why don't you take your dinner
and go into the bedroom?
But I wanted to watch TV.
Go now.
Cute kids. Yeah, I like them.
Can I get you a drink?
No, I won't
be here long.
Yeah. Have a seat.
Thank you.
Is that a PS Vita?
Uh...
Which games
does he have?
All of them.
I have a console at home.
I play sometimes to relax. I ought
to get one of these for the car.
So, Peter, we need to close the
shipyard in your district.
The BRAC hearing is tomorrow. You
won't put up your usual fight.
You have zero
testimony to add.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can, Peter.
I spent months
on that testimony.
I lobbied the commission.
My entire office...
I'm sure you've
done splendid work,
but unfortunately, it
can't come to fruition.
Why?
Politics.
There's forces bigger than
either of us at play here.
It's 12,000 jobs.
I know.
It's a shame.
Keeping that shipyard open
is what got me elected.
Those people
are my friends.
I'm not here to
debate this, Peter.
The base will close.
The only question is, will
you make it a swift death
or a painful one?
No way. I won't
sit on my hands.
I sympathize that this is
gonna be difficult for you.
And I don't
know how yet,
but I will make it
up to you, Peter.
I'm a powerful friend
to have right now,
perhaps your
only friend,
so don't defy me.
Love of family.
Most politicians are permanently
chained to that slogan.
Family values.
But when you cozy up to
hookers and I find out,
I will make that
hypocrisy hurt.
Did you get the
present I sent you?
You wouldn't really
call it a present.
Well, more of a
gentle reminder, maybe.
More heavy-handed than
gentle, which surprised me.
It's not really
your style, Francis.
But, yes. I got it.
I like that one.
I do, too.
But the first
one's better.
You think?
Something special tomorrow?
Adam Galloway's coming
down from New York.
What for?
Because I need some
of his photographs
for the silent auction
at the gala next month.
You speak to Remy yet?
I haven't.
If you want to look inviting,
wear the black one.
Hello.
Oh...
Okay. Great. Thanks.
Adam?
How is it the world
keeps spinning
and you manage to
stay ahead of it?
David's on board
with this?
It was his idea.
Then why
isn't he here?
Well, we have to be careful
until it's a done deal.
I don't know, Frank.
Think about it, Terry.
You could become the first
African-American majority leader
in the United States
Congress.
Let's make
some history.
You don't care
about history.
You just wanted me because
I can round up the votes.
I need the votes, and I
do care about history,
but most importantly, Terry,
you know how to lead.
You're the head of the
Black Caucus for a reason.
So David becomes speaker,
I become majority leader...
And I stay on as Whip.
Why don't you want majority
leader for yourself?
I'm satisfied where I am.
Maybe one day, when you become
Speaker, you'll bump me up.
This is the sort of thing
that there's no turning back.
I can throw a
cherry on top.
McCuddin stays open.
How?
You don't want
to know how.
You just want the headline when you
keep 3,000 jobs in your district.
12 votes?
12 votes.
I can get you 10,
probably 11.
It's so refreshing
to work with someone
who will throw a saddle
on a gift horse
rather than look
it in the mouth.
That's nice.
Wow.
I found her in
a village outside Amravati.
Her name was Tyala.
She died three weeks
after I took that picture.
Oh, that's awful.
You can have
them all if you like.
I love your hair short.
You have plans tonight?
No.
Is Frank
expecting you home?
I'm sure he'll
be home late.
Get dinner with me.
What time is your train?
I don't book
round-trip tickets.
It's going to be a while
before I can leave.
What time will
you be done?
Probably around 8:00.
I'll pick a place,
let you know.
Ah, David.
How are you, Joe?
I'm behind you.
Let's do this.
Do what?
Keep your cards close.
I like that.
Hi. Yeah.
This is room 1214.
I'd like a bottle of
the Weinbach, please.
Yeah. Actually, could you
make that two bottles?
Thank you.
Sit down. You're
making me nervous.
You still smoke?
From time to time, yes.
I quit. These are
an illusion.
You want?
Sure.
What?
Not now.
Okay.
I should go.
I just...
assumed...
I know.
We can't start
this again.
When I end something,
I end it.
So why'd you have me come all
the way down from New York?
It was a mistake.
I'm sorry, Adam. I should've
kept it business.
Side of you
I like the least.
There are no
mistakes, Claire.
Hi.
Hello.
More wine?
Mmm-hmm.
How was your day?
Good.
Adam well?
He is.
We just had dinner.
Hmm.
I emailed Remy
on the way home.
I told him I'm not
taking the money.
Thank you. I appreciate
that this was not easy.
Well, we don't
like easy, do we?
All the evidence
would suggest it.
Is it all right
if the Holburns
come over for
dinner Wednesday night?
I want Felicity to buy
some tables for the gala.
Yeah, of course.
I'm going to need Congressmen
and senators there.
You need to
call in favors.
Done.
Not a few, a lot.
I'll start making
calls in the morning.
Adam donated
10 photographs.
That was generous
of him.
He's staying
at the Mandarin.
And you?
Here.
But the Proving
Ground's importance
stems far beyond its
strategic geographic value.
APG's research and development
of military materiel
is central to our nation's
counter-terrorism efforts.
The base houses research laboratories
for preventative medicine
as well as a wide variety of training
grounds for military personnel.
APG is also a job creator.
It provides $400 million
in payroll annually,
and nearly $500 million
in contracts.
Thank you for the opportunity
to testify before you today.
Any questions for the
Congresswoman from Maryland?
No.
Those in favor of removing
the Aberdeen Proving Ground
from the list of closures?
Aye.
So noted and removed.
Okay, we'll next consider the
Philadelphia Naval Shipyard.
Would the congressman from
Pennsylvania's first district
like to offer testimony?
I have no testimony to offer.
Yeah, but the difference
that we're gonna make...
Uh, Terry, let me
call you right back.
Terry Womack?
Possibly.
I've had three members of
the Black Caucus tell me
they're backing my
play for the speakership.
Interesting.
I have a sense
you've been disseminating
some misinformation.
No. I'm afraid it's you
who are misinformed, David.
You don't have three members backing you.
You have 10.
I made it very clear I didn't
want any part of this.
Yes, you made it
crystal clear.
Then why are you
telling people?
Because they don't know
you made it crystal clear.
I have to go to
Bob with this.
He'll think you
organized a coup,
got cold feet, and are
making me the scapegoat.
David, if I pick up
this phone right now
and leak this story,
Bob will have no
choice but to drop you,
even if he believes
your version of events.
You wanna take a seat?
Ah, Freddy?
Yeah, Frank?
You better make
it a half order.
I got a big
dinner tonight.
Sure thing.
Slaw? Uh-huh. You got it.
Always.
Here you go.
So, what's the latest?
You know, Frank.
Same old shit.
Almost got killed
last weekend.
Here?
No.
State fair
down in Virginia.
Me and my brother hauling
this smoker down there,
and this fucking minivan
had a fridge strapped on top.
A fridge strapped on
top of a minivan, Frank.
That's stupid. Well, that
fridge slipped loose.
Boom! Right in front of us. I had to
swerve to the left. Barely missed it.
But now that smoker
is fishtailing,
almost hit a hatchback
in the next lane.
Swerved to the right.
Barely missed that, too.
Jesus.
Oh, man, it was real.
But, you know, that's
why God gave us reflexes.
So we can move
the fuck out of the way
when a fridge
come out of nowhere.
How are them ribs?
You know
how they are.
You know I like
to hear it.
Perfection, Freddy.
Perfection.
You go on ahead, Frank.
Thank you, Freddy.
Well, this is a surprise.
You usually text.
Where are you?
On the other side
of the tracks
trying to find
the meaning of life.
Find anything for me?
You mean anything
newsworthy?
I actually didn't
call to badger you.
Yes, you did, but that's
part of your charm.
No. I wanted to
tell you that
I've been promoted to White
House correspondent.
I'll have to travel with the
press corps, be at briefings,
but I can work
around all that.
If you need me. It
won't change anything.
Oh, on the contrary.
This changes everything.
No. I can
be flexible.
I'm not interested in
someone who's flexible,
I'm interested in
someone who's available.
So you think I
should turn it down?
That's entirely
up to you.
Well, I mean,
it's not official yet.
I could... Oh, look,
I've got to go,
but call me, you know, if you
find yourself available again.
You see, Freddy believes that if
a fridge falls off a minivan,
you better swerve
out of its way.
I believe it's the fridge's
job to swerve out of mine.
Hey, Janine...
Keep walking, Zoe. I really don't
want to talk to you right now.
It's not like I
asked him for it.
He just called me
into his office, and...
Oh, please. You've been
gunning for my job
since the day you bounced in here
with a lollipop in your mouth.
Congratulations.
I'll send you a bottle of
champagne from the Middle West,
wherever the
fuck that is.
I'm gonna turn it down.
You don't have to leave.
Are you trying to rub
this in or something?
Please believe me. You should
be in the White House.
I don't want it.
I never did.
I was hoping we could
go see Tom together.
I want him to
know that we both...
Get the fuck
out of my face.
I'm asking. For real.
I don't want the job.
Then you're an even bigger
idiot than I thought you were.
Go. Before I get violent.
Peter?
Hello?
Hi. My name is Christina.
I work with your dad.
He's not here.
Where'd he go?
I don't know. He said he'd
be back in a little while.
When was that?
When he dropped us
home from school.
He left his phone here.
Are you Dad's
girlfriend?
No. No. I work
for your dad.
Then why do you have the
keys to his apartment?
Will you
make us Pop-Tarts?
It was just
sublime, Claire.
- Thank you.
- I don't think I'll eat for a week.
Does that mean no
room for dessert?
I'd love to,
but none for me.
Why don't you and
I head downstairs
for a little brandy
and some cigars?
Cubans?
You don't think I smoke
anything legal, do you?
Dessert for you?
No. No, thanks.
But I will take a refill of
this Chardonnay, though.
Of course. This is almost out.
I'll grab another.
I hate how they just hit you
like that with no warning.
You get night
sweats, too?
I, umm...
This is very
new to me.
Does Frank know?
I haven't...
We haven't... No.
I'm sorry. We don't have
to talk about this.
No. It's fine.
I'm just...
It's fine.
I feel better now.
Could I have a little bit more?
Sure.
Just say when.
Charles is driving
tonight, so...
And when.
Cheers.
So, you mentioned, when
you invited me, the CWI.
You're having a gala and
launching some new...
Yes, that's right.
We just brought on this
brilliant young woman
who's going to help us
expand our efforts overseas.
Claire, I will save
you the trouble.
Charles and I would be
delighted to contribute.
Well, that's very generous
of you, Felicity.
Well, you were such a darling, getting
us tickets to the Jefferson Ball.
Oh, that was nothing.
It wasn't nothing.
It was...
People in this town don't go out of
their way to be nice to each other.
Fourteen years Charles and
I have been here, and...
Anyway, um...
I'm grateful to
have a friend.
How much
do you need?
Christina, what the fuck
are you doing here?
Shh! They're sleeping.
Peter.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, kiddo.
Would you take your
brother downstairs?
I'll be there
in a second.
Okay.
Bye, Dad.
Bye.
Bye?
Where they going?
I'm taking them to
their grandmother's.
I was able to get ahold of
Madeleine, and I told her...
Fuck. You didn't
tell her?
No, I didn't.
But I should have.
I told her that you had
to travel for work,
which is the last time
I ever lie for you.
Look...
What happened, Peter?
I'm sorry about
the BRAC hearing.
Fuck the BRAC hearing.
What about your kids?
After I drop
them off, I'm done.
I am no longer your girlfriend.
I no longer work for you.
No. Hey, Christina...
I don't want to hear it, Peter.
There's no excuse this time.
I don't have
much time, Frank.
I'll make it short.
The President?
No. The speakership.
David's making a play.
What? He came to me for support.
My first thought was
to tell you right away,
but then my second thought was
to ignore my first thought,
because we have
the votes, Bob.
If there had been a party revolt,
I would've known about it.
We don't need the whole party to revolt.
We need 13...
Thirteen Democrats, plus the
other side of the aisle.
Are you out
of your mind?
People have been asking
me that a lot lately.
I'm inclined to
start saying yes.
Who are they, the 13?
David and I are two,
Terry Womack,
and 10 members of the Black
Caucus make another 11.
Is the President
behind this?
No. He doesn't
have a clue.
This was David's
plan executed by me.
But there is
an out for you, Bob.
I can sway Womack
either way
as long as you make him
the next majority leader.
And...
The Education Bill.
Now we're on
the same page.
I can't do that.
You know I can't.
You're the Speaker, Bob. You
can do anything you'd like.
And I have to say,
appointing the first
African-American
majority leader,
why, that isn't
a bad legacy to have.
I'm sorry.
I changed my mind.
I thought
about it, and...
Thinking about it was what
those two days were for.
And then I thought about it
some more, and I realized I...
Jesus Christ, you're
fucking unbelievable.
Look, Tom, I
appreciate the fact
that you took
a chance on me, but...
No, I don't think you do. I don't
think you appreciate anything.
I think you're an ungrateful,
self-entitled little...
Little what?
Little what, Tom?
Say it.
Cunt. You're a cunt.
What are you doing?
Don't you dare...
You don't even
know what I'm typing.
Get out, Zoe. Just a second.
I'm almost done.
Get out.
You're fired.
Whatever you have to
tell yourself, Tom.
Get out!
So should I
press send?
I think I should.
Call me whatever you want,
but you should remember,
these days,
when you're talking to one
person, you're talking to 1,000.
Well, you'll say you
wanted to spend more time
focusing on
your home district.
You'll say Womack is the right
man to fill your shoes.
You won't make waves.
You won't do interviews.
You'll suck it up
and be a team player.
This was Frank's idea.
I told you he was gonna
try to blame me on it.
Ask around.
Talk to Womack.
I did. He said
you came to him.
He's fucking lying, Bob!
I would never...
Shut up, David.
Do you understand how you're to
behave when we make the announcement?
And if I don't
play along?
Then the DCCC will pour
everything it's got
into your primary opponent's
campaign next cycle.
We'll cleave you from the herd and
watch you die in the wilderness.
Tell us now, David.
If you think
it's best, Robert.
And just think,
he could have been a wolf.
You made yourself
available.
I quit.
Fuck that place.
It was a prison.
I'm free now.
Congratulations.
Where are you?
In a car.
So am I.
Where you headed?
Home.
So am I.
To your home or mine?
Is that an invitation?
It's whatever
you want it to be.
You sound tipsy.
I am.
I just spent
the last two hours
drinking Long
Island Iced Teas.
What's your address?
Do your parents know
you live like this?
No. They
haven't visited.
Are you cared for?
How do you mean?
Do you have a man
who cares for you?
An older man.
No.
But you've been with
older men before?
Yes.
Then you know
they hurt you,
and after
they discard you.
You can't hurt me.
Take your heels off.