Meadow, do you have a tampon?
I'm spotting and the dispenser is out.
You had an examination?
It's the middle of the month.
This never happens to me.
Here.
Imagine having your portrait
in a museum.
She's a rich merchant's wife.
It's how Rubens made money.
You talk the talk, Miss Art History.
I've never seen these grades from you.
Well, you take Intro to Semiotics.
If you spent less time
in Jackie's car...
Please.
That is so over.
Just like that? What happened?
Are you crying?
What's the matter?
I don't know. Just look at it.
“Jusepe de Ribera. The Mystical
Marriage of Saint Catherine."
That's the baby Jesus.
She's marrying a baby?
Good luck.
We all do.
- What?
- I shouldn't be sarcastic.
Just look at her.
The little baby's
hand against her cheek.
She's so at peace.
A beautiful, innocent,
gorgeous little baby.
Come on, let's go eat.
Tony!
Come on.
I'm sorry about what happened.
- You won't return my calls.
- Go fuck yourself.
Tony.
We have something too special
to just... over one argument.
One argument? You threw a fucking
dinner at my head, Gloria.
If you were a guy,
you know where you'd be.
But you were late.
You kept me waiting three hours...
What about the present?
You threw it into the Barnegat Bay.
All right, I...
I'm having a bad couple of weeks.
Shit with my family and other crap.
I was trying to act in control
and not dwell on it. It's no excuse.
- We can't talk about your problems?
- I didn't wanna bother you.
Well, I had a lot on my plate.
Can I see you later?
I'm late for my appointment.
Me and this broad, we're like...
leather and lace.
A burning ring of fire.
Whatever.
Amour fou.
As the French call it.
- Crazy love, all-consuming.
- That's it.
We push each other's buttons.
- Most people don't push your buttons.
- That's not true.
Now, I know you think I'm like a hard,
cold, captain-of-industry type.
That's not all there is.
I don't know.
She gets freaky.
Is she a full-blown
loop-do-loo or what?
- As you know, I cannot...
- Discuss another patient.
If I duke you a five?
I'm not charging you.
Last month you overpaid.
- You gave me good tips.
- I won't have it.
- Don't offer it again.
- All right. Jesus.
- Back to Gloria.
- She never wants money.
And you like this?
She's, you know, very
independent-minded. That I do like.
- You see her as independent, strong.
- She's not?
We're talking about your perceptions.
She made her own way in the world.
Irina was such
a helpless, fucking baby.
But Gloria knows a lot,
about a lot of shit.
Buddhism, and the movies...
She went to Morocco all by herself.
And those eyes.
Those dark, black eyes.
When she stares at you, it's like...
Like a Spanish princess
in one of those paintings. A Goya.
- Those eyes are deep.
- Complicated.
- Complicated? I said deep.
- You said dark.
Whenever I bring her up,
you get this weird puss.
You ask if she seems happy.
Like she's not.
Or if she reminds me of somebody.
Like you don't like it.
Amo-fo, or whatever you call it.
You've told me what you see in Gloria.
What does she see in you?
Oh, please, huh?
What does she see in me?
With all the faggots and crybabies
around. Whatever else I am, I'm not...
I'm more of...
Well, you know, like I said...
Captain-of-industry type.
- You're a tough guy.
- Oh, come on.
You can say it.
You embarrass me with that.
Does Gloria know
what you do for a living?
You mentioned fire.
Can we say that certain kinds
of people are drawn to fire?
Looking for an inevitable result,
like a moth to a flame?
And this is Gloria?
And I'm the flame?
Why would anybody hit you,
of all people, with a side of beef?
She's complicated.
I said complicated. Dark, you said.
No, I said her eyes are dark.
Nice. Not bad.
Since we're kicking up...
we were hoping you could,
you know...
watch our back?
350 buys you "Hello."
Watching your back...
That's gonna require
a little more initiative on your part.
Oh, look at the face.
What's he got to be frowning about?
Tell me, Romeo.
Now that you moved home...
you gonna be humping Tony
Soprano's girl on our couch?
Fuck her.
And Tony's stay-in-school shit. He
could have reached out to Rutgers.
He should break the dean's legs
because you won't read.
Now go ahead.
I gotta make some calls.
You did good.
Keep coming by.
Go. Go.
I knew a Moroccan guy once.
He hit and ran me. I tracked him down.
I never forget a face.
Jesus Christ!
That's the oldest joke in the book.
Hello?
No, you have the wrong number.
What?
I thought it might be my sister.
That family shit
you were telling me about?
It's okay if you don't wanna talk
about it. Really.
She said I can never see
my niece and nephew again.
- Right before Christmas.
- We had a new Santa at our party.
- Wasn't good.
- I love those children.
So much.
She said I turned them
against their dad. I didn't.
Not that he doesn't deserve it.
Fucking crackhead sack of shit.
Hannah and Seamus go to this
alternative, private...
elementary school in Santa Monica.
- Where it's all about self-esteem.
- I hate that shit.
I ask Hannah, she's a third-grader,
"Will you be in the Christmas play?"
And she says,
"We call it the Winter Festival."
So I go, "Whatever."
I don't say anything.
"We can't say Christmas.
We call Christmas 'the C-word."'
And I fucking flipped out.
- What did Seamus say?
- What the fuck does he know? He's 10.
So my sister gets mad
because her husband...
teaches there, except he's
on leave for drug abuse treatment.
And one thing led to another and...
She said I always had it in for John.
- And she forbid me to see them again.
- He smokes crack?
Without those two kids...
Maybe we'll all get lucky.
The way these trucks go by out here?
- Maybe I'll get plastered on a grill.
- What?
I'm just kidding. It never rains.
I think they're gonna fire me
over at Globe.
Fucking Arnie Mills sexually harasses
me and then dares me to sue.
Anyway-
Fuck them.
- You like this song?
- It's okay.
- I love this song.
- Yeah?
Guys, if you're gonna smoke,
take it outside.
Fuck's the matter?
Speak English?
- Who are you?
- The owner is a dear friend.
- That should be enough for you.
- Fuck him too.
- What you fucking say?
- Chill! Relax!
Jackie. What are you doing?
It's under control.
Go find a fucking Taco Bell
before I cap your asses.
Get the fuck out of here.
- Oh, shit. Take this.
- Fuck, no. He's a made guy.
He'll flip when he sees this shit.
Roy's his aunt's cousin.
- What's up?
- Hey, Christopher.
- What the fuck happened?
- Ask your buddy.
Spics disrespected the place.
I had to straighten them out.
- Had to straighten them out. How many?
- Three.
- Goddamn fucking craziness.
- You all right?
Twenty years I'm collecting these.
What the fuck, it's only glass.
Have a seat.
- How's business? Making money?
- Doing all right.
- Why, got something?
- My favorite. A truck. Cigarettes.
Sounds good.
But we're kind of with Ralphie now.
Besides, wouldn't Tony go ballistic?
Unless they're paying you...
nobody can tell anybody
how to earn a living.
- Finally. Thank you.
- Ralphie, huh?
Well, if you ever think about
jumping ship, you know my number.
I need the paperwork
on the preowned C5.
- Mrs. Soprano?
- Yes?
The courtesy Van's stuck in traffic.
It should only be maybe 20 minutes.
Well, you know,
maybe I'll just call a cab.
Jerry, I'll give her a lift.
I'm going out anyway.
- Gloria Trillo.
- Carmela Soprano. You don't mind?
Give me a minute,
let me grab a demo.
This is sweet of you.
Don't believe it.
Everybody is a potential sale.
- So, what do you do?
- I'm a homemaker.
Oh.
You must make a very nice home
to drive a Benz.
- So you're married?
- Yes.
- Kids?
- Two. You?
No. To both.
Boys? Girls?
One boy, one girl.
The boy is still in high school
and my daughter's in college.
She's not too far away though.
She's in New York City.
- She's at Columbia.
- School of Broadcasting?
The university. It's in the Ivy
League, one of the top schools.
- I know. I was just kidding.
- Oh.
Right.
Boy, these kids today.
They got the world
by the you-know-what.
Yeah, tell me about it.
At least your daughter doesn't
need a man for success.
Thank God.
- That's a beautiful ring.
- Thank you.
- What does your husband do?
- He's in a few businesses.
- Sounds mysterious.
- No, no, it's not, really.
My daughter calls us bourgeois.
Thank you so much.
- No problem. It was nice to meet you.
- You too.
- Nice house.
- Thank you.
I tell you, the thing I like
about Moltisanti?
He'll even tell Tony Soprano
to go fuck himself.
The guy's fearless.
Who's fearless?
Chris Moltisanti.
Where's my mother?
She's an early riser.
What about Moltisanti?
We were saying he's young
to be made. That kind of shit.
He wanted it
so he stepped up and took it.
Like your dad and Tony Soprano.
Know how they made their names?
- How?
- We got any marshmallows?
Come on, what about my father?
When we was kids,
we had our own little crew.
Me, your dad, buon'anima,
Tony, Silvio Dante.
We'd do Mickey Mouse scores,
you know, moving pot...
swag. Bullshit stuff.
We thought we were
like the sixth family.
But who knew we was even alive?
Till one fucking night.
And I gotta give your father credit.
He had balls as big
as an Irish broad's ass.
There was this old...
old mustache named...
Feech Lamanna.
What Feech meant,
who the fuck knows?
But he was made on the other side,
so he was an original.
He was an O.G.
Whatever.
He had this Saturday night
card game...
and your father sees a chance
to rise to the A-league.
Connected or not, him,
me and Tony were gonna rob him.
We thought your father lost a marble.
- But he said, "Fuck it."
- Balls.
What happened?
They took it down and
walked away with 20 large.
Jesus Christ.
What do you mean, "they"?
You didn't go?
I'm still sick over it.
I caught the clap from some
hippie broad I was fucking.
My dick was dripping
like a busted pipe.
Anyways, the rest is history.
Your father and Tony was on the
fast track to being made, and I...
was still a little shit here,
like the two of you.
And of course I, whatever...
But that was a few years later.
- They get away with it?
- What could Feech do?
There was a sit-down.
And the right people
got some of their money back...
but the point was made.
Your father and Tony were rising stars
to be respected.
Cocksuckers.
All right, kiddies.
That's enough for tonight.
Oh, Jackie.
Rinse those plates before you put
them in the dishwasher. It clogs.
We can't help but be amazed
at the instincts they possess.
To protect all manner of livestock.
To be protective of us.
What can we do to protect them?
Nurture their defenses...
musing the natural body
defense system in Pedigree.
What is wrong with me?
Pedigree.
Cut it out.
Are you drunk?
- How about right here?
- You would, wouldn't you? Huh?
Does my car look slanted?
Oh, shit.
I have a flat.
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ.
So creepy.
Why?
I don't know.
What?
- You know who did this, don't you?
- What?
I saw that look.
At least don't lie to me.
- What do I know about your tires?
- Fine.
Thanks for your help.
One time.
My ex-girlfriend, she got a little
jealous and she slashed my tires.
That thought went through
my mind just then.
- It couldn't have been her.
- The cunt that called?
- My car's fucked!
- You work for a dealer.
- You think I get free tires?
- So I'll pay for it!
Why offer if you didn't
have a guilty conscience?
About what?
I don't know. Tell me.
This is fucking bullshit.
I'm going home.
- Who else would do it?
- Kids, maybe.
- Ruin a great evening over this!
- Kids!
Maybe your brother-in-law.
Maybe Mr. Globe, since you're
America's sweetheart this week.
Where the fuck do you get off?
This immigrant, alcoholic,
probably HIV-laden slut...
Whoa with that!
Slashes my tires and you
call my life into question?
She wouldn't do it!
I slapped the piss out of her.
Oh. Did you?
Did you really hit her?
I don't know.
She's a poor, confused kid
from an underdeveloped country.
Even if she did do this.
I'll make some calls.
I'll have new Michelins in an hour.
What are these'? 8541185'? What'?
Jesus Christ.
All right, 17's!
Gene Pontecorvo's got a card game.
We could take it down now.
Are you crazy? He's with Ralph.
Essentially, that's Ralph's game.
Even better. Fuck him
and his rinse-your-dishes shit.
Know what?
I think he's a secret fag.
I don't know.
Maybe take Carlo. He's got a shotgun.
We wear masks.
We go in.
We're out in like two minutes.
- What if they find out it's us?
- We want them to.
Not right away,
but like Ralph said.
When they do, you know
it's gonna get squashed.
My old man was Jackie Aprile.
The worse that'll happen,
we give some back.
We pull this off...
we're like free agents.
We dictate the terms, not them.
Because we show balls.
Come on, call Carlo.
Fuck. There's no signal.
I'd have to be pretty stupid
to write a book about killing...
Use that phone.
Oh, yeah, this one.
Come on, hurry up, call Carlo.
- They show my favorite part yet?
- I think it's coming up.
The answer's no.
- Dude, move over. Give me some room.
- Fuck you, it's my house.
Here it comes.
Yeah.
Like a cigarette, Nick?
- You two know each other?
- No.
I saw a psychiatrist. That's why
Father lntintola said we should talk.
He said you were getting
a doctorate in psychiatry.
Psychology-
The psychiatrist told me my
whole life is a lie, and he's right.
And now I think I'm sick.
And if I die, I will never
be with God in eternity.
- You're ill?
- I think I have ovarian cancer.
- What does the doctor say?
- I haven't seen one.
I'm afraid.
- Why do you think you are ill?
- I'm spotting. Lower back pain.
My hormones are all over the place.
My cousin Kathy died from it.
God doesn't punish people
for mistakes that they've made.
He loves you more than you know.
Have you thought, with your symptoms,
you might be with child?
I know, that's another...
Would you be more comfortable
if we set this sacrament aside...
and stepped into my office?
The psychiatrist said
I should leave my husband.
When he said that, it seemed so right.
You made a sacred vow.
Divorce is out of the question.
Unless...
Is he abusive, your husband?
Not to me. But he is unfaithful.
He's a good man basically, but...
I talked to Father lntintola
years ago, and here I am.
- Do you love your husband?
- I do.
I love my husband.
And I love God.
But my life is financed by crime.
His crime.
Fifty thousand dollars
to my daughter's college.
The psychiatrist says
it's all blood money.
Now, to maybe bring another child
into this?
God understands that we all live
in the middle of tensions.
You say your husband has good in him.
What you have to do is learn to live
on what the good part earns.
The what?
There is a point inside yourself.
An inner boundary beyond which
you feel culpable.
You've got to come to an awareness
of where that line is.
And forego those things
which lay without it.
- The Church has changed so much.
- It's a complex world.
Learn to live on the good part.
Forego those things that lay without it.
I think I can do that, Father.
I'll try.
And go see an ob-gyn.
This mad-cow disease.
It's terrible the English government
didn't tell people.
Maybe they didn't wanna
create a stampede.
Oh, by the way...
guess which former medical student
no longer dates the Queen of Mean.
You're kidding.
- Jackie Jr. and Meadow are finished?
- Frankly, I am delighted.
Kevin told Angie Bonpensiero
that Jackie was smoking marijuana.
- And was caught cheating at Rutgers.
- Gee, that bad?
That black kid would've been better.
He's got a 4.0 and he's moving
to India for the U.N.
- I told you.
- That's my fault.
She wasted three months
with Jackie Jr.
- Hello.
- Mrs. Soprano!
- Gloria Trillo, Globe Motors.
- Hi, how are you?
I hope this is a good time.
The new E-320 just came in.
You might wanna take a look.
No, I don't think so.
I still have another year on my lease.
Maybe your husband will treat you.
Maybe I will.
Thank you for calling.
Okay, bye. Hope to see you!
Bye-bye.
Well, what a nice woman.
Who?
Just some saleswoman
from Globe Motors.
What?
She wants me to try the new wagon.
I'm not interested, but she was nice.
She took me home
while they serviced the wagon.
I should hold onto it another year,
don't you think?
Another year.
Yeah.
I was just wondering
if we could switch days off.
- Give me a minute.
- We could switch...
I got a customer coming in, all right?
Tony.
Are you out of your fucking mind,
talking to my wife?
I was upset about your ex-girlfriend.
I thought you should see my version.
I'm sorry, all right?
You drove her home. What the fuck?
Then you look right into my eyes
and don't tell me?
It's normal to be curious about
someone you love's significant others.
- It's not. It's fucking twisted.
- It is not.
I don't wanna argue.
You're upset.
I know it's on the margins
for someone like you...
and it'll never happen again.
No shit.
You can tell your shrink
you ruined eight relationships.
- What do you mean?
- It's fucking over.
Tony!
You see, Tuesday I can take my kid
to hear Raffi.
Left ovary.
Right ovary.
Just tell me right out.
Don't mince words.
I didn't like people
knowing my personal life.
Where is this asshole now?
What did he have, one song?
- What?
- We should do what we gotta do.
- Call Carlo.
- Who the fuck was Feech Lamanna?
You know what? Don't come.
You wanna spend your life with
your head up your ass, be my guest.
- How's your calamari salad?
- He's not using the right olive oil.
- You haven't said two words, Carmela.
- Sorry.
- I came from Dr. Rotelli's.
- Everything all right?
I've never been better.
Just a thyroid thing.
- Thank God.
- I thought I was pregnant.
Bite your tongue. At our age?
With the kids growing up and all...
I want a grandchild. Terry
and her husband are trying, but...
Speaking of kids, I am sick
about Jackie and Meadow.
I ask, he tells me
to mind my own business.
- So does she.
- They broke up?
Is Meadow okay?
She's so different than I was.
It rolls off her back.
- No weight loss or sleepless nights.
- Not like what we go through.
Because we married them.
It's not just us.
The president of the United States...
His wife put up with the
blowjobs and the stained dress.
Hillary Clinton? I can't stand her.
We could all take a page
from her book.
To be publicly humiliated
and go around smiling?
That is so false. I would dig a hole,
climb into it and not come out.
All I know is, she stuck by him,
put up with the bullshit...
and she set up
her own little thing.
She took all that negative shit
he gave her and spun it into gold.
You gotta give her credit.
Well, that's true, isn't it?
She's a role model for all of us.
No, the case is still pending.
They could try me on mail and wire
fraud, but they want a major RICO.
Tony. Line two.
- Who is it?
- It's a woman. I think she's crying.
Let me get back to you.
Hello.
Tony.
I don't know, I don't know,
I don't...
I can't understand you.
I can't take it anymore.
Stay...
I don't know... l don't know why.
I don't know why.
Tony-
Tony.
- Thanks for coming.
- All right.
- You want something to drink?
- No.
I'm sorry. There's no one else
I can talk to.
What about him?
- Laugh if you want. He helps.
- He's a Captain Marvel.
I just want it to be the way it was.
- I love you.
- Stop it.
- I'm sorry.
- Quit crying. I can't stand it.
- I wanna be with you.
- That's not gonna happen.
I know.
My life's a trip to nowhere.
You bring it on yourself.
You're a beautiful, talented woman.
But you...
- You push a man away.
- That's not gonna happen again.
The other night with the tires.
I'm a grown man. I've had other women.
- You think I lived in a freezer?
- Fine.
I'll sit back like a mute while you
screw every woman out there.
See, there's that tone again.
Look.
It's over.
I mean, we had our mo-fo,
or whatever.
And it was great.
And now it's time to put it to bed.
You think you can treat me like
some stupid goombah housewife?
You think I'll let some fucker
shit over me...
just because he buys me
some ridiculous, gaudy ring?
Where the fuck do you get off?
You don't care.
Think you're the only one with
problems? My life's a fucking picnic?
Poor you.
You got a dream life compared to mine.
Nobody cares if I'm alive or dead!
I didn't just meet you.
- I've known you my whole life.
- That's right.
Take a dump wherever you please
and walk away.
My mother was just like you.
A bottomless black hole.
The mother now.
I surrender.
Burn me at the stake.
You know what?
You're fucking crazy.
- All I ever asked for was kindness.
- Come here.
Listen to me, and listen good.
No more calls, no more nothing.
You see me, cross the street.
You're dangerous,
and I don't want you in my life.
DOD'!
I'll call your wife!
What did you say?
I'll go to Columbia.
I'll tell your daughter.
Come on!
Come here.
Now, you listen to me.
Go near my wife or my family,
and I'll kill you.
Understand? I'll kill you.
Kill me. Kill me, you cocksu...
You fucking bitch!
Kill me. Kill me. Kill me.
Kill me.
Kill me, kill me,
kill me, kill me...
Kill me.
All right, this is it.
I don't care if God comes by,
don't move the car.
- You do the talking.
- Me?
- Eugene will know me.
- Don't worry.
When they see this,
nobody will have to say a word.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
- You sure you wanna do this?
- Why?
Don't you?
Fuck it, let's go down the shore.
Let's do it before the crank
wears off.
- Ace high flush.
- Flush talks.
Anybody want a drink?
Nobody fucking move!
Take it easy, all right?
- Shit.
- Shut up!
Empty your pockets.
All of you!
- Come on!
- Very bad, boys. Very bad.
This is a low-level game.
All you'll get is practice.
- You hear what he said? Shut up!
- Take it easy.
You know who you're robbing?
- Give me your watch.
- Leave while you look good.
Just give it to him.
Victory has a hundred fathers,
but defeat is an orphan.
Shut up! Stop fucking looking at me!
Come on, hurry up!
Let's get out of here!
If you can keep your head
while those around you can't...
- Where the fuck is he?
- Shit.
Shit, come on!
- Get the fuck out!
- What are you doing? This is my...
Jackie!
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Hey, cocksucker.
Chris, please.
We didn't know you were in there.
We're with Ralphie.
Please?
If you're one of many men
with erectile dysfunction...
you know it's no laughing matter.
You might not know treatment
is covered by most medical plans...
Dr. Freid. I'm sorry. Your service
said it was an emergency.
Hello.
Jesus Christ.
Not again, Tony.
I can't keep doing this.
I'm in the middle of a comm...
Can't he go to the emergency room?
I thought he had a green card.
You'll make him hit an artery!
Relax, let the sedative do its job.
Be glad they didn't hit
nothing important.
- This prick is really a doctor?
- Close. I'm a prick doctor. Get it?
Maybe he can give you a bulge.
Doc, see if you can remove
this ladies' underwear.
Ah!
It'll be all right.
Little motherfucker.
He's going, bigtime.
- Sure it was Jackie Jr.?
- I'll do him tonight.
- No, you're not.
- Why?
- Because I said so.
- I don't gotta explain.
- Because he's Jackie Aprile's kid?
You're not gonna let this go.
You can't!
He shot at me, tried to kill Furio.
We're made!
Everyone you whack,
you risk exposure.
The feds ask for major murder
for Christmas.
- You're a fucking hypocrite.
- What did you say?
You preach this wise-guy shit...
meanwhile we're the only ones
who play by the rules.
I loved you.
What happens, I decide.
You don't love me, that hurts,
but too bad.
Because you don't gotta love me.
But you will respect me.
Ralph Cifaretto's here.
What'd we say?
- Ton.
- How you doing?
- It's terrible, huh?
- Yeah.
Ro's going nuts. She knows
he hangs around with Dino.
- Any word from her son?
- No, no.
All right, come on.
This kid.
- He did a terrible thing.
- Terrible.
- Your fucking card game.
- I know you're close to the family.
No, I feel for you.
You're living under the same roof.
And it was my card game.
But what happened to Sunshine...
is a disgrace.
But to tell you the truth, Tony...
I wanna give the kid a pass.
Yeah?
It's just me though.
I know you got bigger concerns.
You're the boss, and...
I'll make sure your orders are done.
I think you should go
with your instincts on this, Ralph.
You do?
But Furio took a hit. Chris.
These are made men.
I'll make sure they respect
your decision.
Because I'm sure
you'll do the right thing.
That's why I made you captain.
This is Rosalie's kid.
That's why I'll understand if you give
him a pass. Everybody else will too.
Who cares about shit they don't
have the balls to say to your face?
Kid disrespected you.
But they don't have
to live with your commitments.
But, hey, the decision
goes the other way?
The one thing you cannot do, Ralph,
you cannot do...
is blame yourself.
You took this kid under your wing.
You schooled him as best you could.
Didn't you?
Jack spoiled him.
I think this is yours.
The stupid kid was carrying it around
during the holidays.
She wanted me to fucking kill her.
Like suicide by cop.
So she set me up?
She saw me as only a fucking hammer?
She loved you.
She looked so good too,
that day in your office.
Just another Irina
with a college degree.
Ask yourself.
How did you recognize in Gloria,
under her layers of sophistication...
this deeply wounded, angry being
that would let you replicate...
your relationship
with your mother?
I don't wanna fuck my mother.
You're never gonna convince me.
Not fuck.
Try to please her.
Try to win her love.
Forty fucking years old.
We need to repeat what's familiar,
even if it's bad for us.
Gloria's need for drama.
The selfishness.
The incessant self-regard.
At one time...
in your mother's hands,
it passed for love.
All right, look. You're her doctor.
You tell me.
Do I gotta worry about this broad?
She says she's gonna
tell Carmela about us.
I honestly can't predict.
We should deal with...
why are you so attracted
to dangerous relationships?
Why do you put your marriage
in such danger?
- Maybe I'm looking for a way out.
- Anthony.
- You'll never leave your wife.
- Bullshit. There's a limit.
She might leave you,
but you'll never leave her.
Despite your mothering...
you made one good decision
in your life vis-a-vis women.
You won't throw that over.
Your own selfishness is too strong
to let that happen.
All right. All right.
Actually, in spite of everything
you're a very conventional man.
I said all right.
We have to stop now.
- Got pep, I'll give it that.
- Zero to 60 in under seven seconds.
What's the matter, you don't like me?
I'm not back, they call the cops,
standard operating procedure.
Here's standard operating procedure.
Stay away from Tony Soprano.
Shut the fuck up and listen.
It's over, capisce?
Over and done.
You call or go anywhere near him
or his family...
and they'll be scraping your
nipples off these leather seats.
And here's the point to remember.
My face is the last one you'll see.
Not Tony's.
We understand each other?
It won't be cinematic.
Any word, anything?
He probably went down to Florida.
Ro, I'm sure he's fine.
Ro, come on.
Sit down.
Look.
- This will be hard for you to hear.
- Jesus Christ!
No, it's okay. It's okay, it's just...
he has a very serious drug problem.
What?
It's coke.
He may owe some money to dealers.
- Oh, my God.
- I didn't wanna tell you.
Look, we're doing everything we can.
We're gonna find him.
We'll get him help.
We'll get him to rehab.
Let's just hope he's not too far gone.
Something smells good.
Lemon snaps for the
bake sale at church.
You look good.
I went to step today.
Is that why you don't have these
looney-tune moods when you exercise?
Where's your ring?
I had to get it sized.
It's a little big.
Hi, it's me. I'll be home
in about twenty minutes.
Yeah, I picked up the stuffed shells.
No, the Celantano's,
you just gotta heat them up.