? Game of Thrones 6x04 ?
Book of the Stranger
Original Air Date on May
Sync, corrected by elderman
BluRay resync by TooN
www.addic7ed.com
Where you gonna go?
South.
What are you gonna do?
Get warm.
I was with you
at Hardhome.
We saw
what's out there.
We know
it's coming here.
How can you
leave us now?
I did everything I could.
You know that.
You swore a vow.
Aye, I pledged my life
to the Night's Watch.
- I gave my life.
- For all nights to come.
They killed me, Edd!
My own brothers.
You want me
to stay here after that?
Riders approaching!
Open the gate!
This is good soup.
Do you remember those kidney pies
Old Nan used to make?
- With the peas and onions?
- Mmm.
We never should
have left Winterfell.
Don't you wish we could
go back to the day we left?
I want to scream at myself,
"Don't go, you idiot."
How could we know?
I spent a lot of time thinking about
what an ass I was to you.
I wish I could
change everything.
We were children.
I was awful,
just admit it.
You were
occasionally awful.
I'm sure I can't
have been great fun.
Always sulking in the corner
while the rest of you played.
- Can you forgive me?
- There's nothing to forgive.
- Forgive me.
- All right.
All right,
I forgive you.
You'd think after
thousands of years,
the Night's Watch would have learned
how to make a good ale.
Where will you go?
Where will we go?
If I don't watch over you,
Father's ghost will come
back and murder me.
Where will we go?
I can't stay here,
not after what happened.
There's only one place
we can go.
Home.
Should we tell the Boltons
to pack up and leave?
We'll take it back
from them.
I don't have an army.
How many wildlings
did you save?
They didn't come here
to serve me.
They owe you
their lives.
You think they'll be safe here if
Roose Bolton remains Warden of the North?
- Sansa.
- Winterfell is our home.
It's ours and Arya's
and Bran's and Rickon's.
Wherever they are,
it belongs to our family.
We have to fight for it.
I'm tired of fighting.
It's all I've done
since I left home.
I've killed brothers
of the Night's Watch.
I've killed wildlings.
I've killed men that I admire.
I hanged a boy
younger than Bran.
I fought and I lost.
If we don't take back the North,
we'll never be safe.
I want you to help me.
But I'll do it myself
if I have to.
My lady.
Ser Davos.
Will you stay here
at Castle Black?
I will do
as Jon Snow commands.
You serve Jon Snow now?
He's the prince
that was promised.
Forgive me, my lady, I thought
that was Stannis.
What happened
down there?
There was a battle.
Stannis was defeated.
And Shireen?
What happened
to the princess?
I saw what happened.
I saw Stannis' forces
defeated in the field.
My lady,
I'm Ser Davos Seaworth.
We've met before.
I was Kingsguard
to Renly Baratheon.
Before Renly was assassinated
with bloodmagic.
That's in the past now.
Yes, it's in the past.
It doesn't mean
I forget.
Or forgive.
He admitted it,
you know.
Who did?
Stannis.
Just before
I executed him.
The Defender of the Vale!
Uncle Petyr!
My lord.
Come and see.
I missed your name day.
Go on.
A falcon!
A gyrfalcon.
The greatest and rarest
of birds.
Last time
I saw you, Baelish,
you told me you were taking
Sansa Stark home with you to the Fingers.
Indeed I was.
And yet not long ago,
we received reports
that she has been married to
Ramsay Bolton in Winterfell.
On our way to the Fingers,
we were set upon by a large
force of Bolton men.
Seemed to know exactly when
we were traveling and exactly
whom we were transporting.
Do you take me
for a fool?
Tell me, Lord Royce,
how many people knew
of my travel plans with Sansa Stark?
I shared my intentions
with you
and no one else.
Slander a man
in his own home,
you might find yourself
crossing swords with him.
Your home is the Vale.
The Lord of the Vale stands before us.
And only his judgment
concerns me.
Shall we throw him
through the Moon Door?
My lord.
My lord, I have always been
faithful to House Arryn.
To your father, to your mother,
and now to you.
Do you believe him,
Uncle Petyr?
Lord Royce has served
the Vale well.
He's enjoyed a distinguished
military career.
If we could trust
his absolute loyalty,
he would make a capable commander
in the wars to come.
You can trust my absolute loyalty,
my lord.
I think he deserves one more chance.
What do you say?
Fine.
I bring good news.
My friends in the North
tell me Sansa has escaped Winterfell.
I expect she's headed
to Castle Black
where her brother serves
as Lord Commander.
But she won't be safe there,
not with the Boltons after her.
She's my cousin.
We should help her.
That was my instinct
as well.
Our lord has spoken.
Gather the Knights
of the Vale.
The time has come
to join the fray.
You invite the enemy
into our city?
I did.
As a clever man
once told me,
"We make peace with our enemies,
not our friends."
I don't make peace
with the queen's enemies.
I kill
the queen's enemies.
Yes, that's
the military approach.
And how has that worked
here in Meereen?
I represent
the diplomatic approach.
Our queen tried to make
peace with the Masters
and they tried
to murder her.
We enter these negotiations
with open eyes.
Trust me. My own recent
experience with slavery
has taught me the horrors
of that institution.
How many days
were you a slave?
Long enough to know.
Not long enough
to understand.
I bought this dwarf
for a single gold honor.
And somehow you've risen
to the top of the
Great Pyramid of Meereen.
It's most impressive.
And now you speak
for the Good Masters of Astapor.
Here's to reversals
of fortune.
We came here
to meet the queen
and instead we're greeted
by a dwarf and a eunuch.
Let's make this simple, shall we?
Tell me what you want.
We want you to leave
Slaver's Bay.
Take your dragons
and your mercenaries and go.
Queen Daenerys won't stay
in Meereen forever.
Her path takes
her westward.
When we last met,
I offered her ships
so she could return to Westeros
where she belongs. She refused them.
She refused them because
hundreds of thousands
of men, women, and children
still lived in chains.
As they have
since the dawn of time.
- Not anymore.
- You think you're a free man now?
You still follow orders.
Just because your master
has silver hair and tits
doesn't mean
she's not a master.
Friends, friends,
friends, please.
There have always been
those with wealth and power
and those with nothing.
That is the way of the world.
I'm not here to change
the way of the world.
Slavery is the way
of our world.
You don't need slaves
to make money.
There haven't been slaves in Westeros
for hundreds of years
and I grew up richer
than any of you.
But our queen recognizes
that she erred
by abolishing slavery
without providing
a new system to replace it.
So here
is the queen's proposal.
Slavery will never
return to Meereen,
but she will give
the other cities of Slaver's Bay
time to adjust
to the new order.
What does that mean?
Instead of abolishing
slavery overnight,
we will give you seven years
to end the practice.
Slaveholders
will be compensated
for their losses,
of course, at fair prices.
In exchange,
you will cut off
your support for
the Sons of the Harpy.
We do not support
Fine, fine, but you will
cut it off all the same.
I do hope you accept,
my friends.
You will not receive
a better offer.
Let us sail
on the tide of freedom
instead of being
drowned by it.
And as a parting gift
to our honored guests...
Give freedom a chance.
See if it doesn't taste every bit as good
as what came before.
My friends!
Large sorry...
...you wait so fat time.
Perhaps I should
translate for you.
We speak
the Common Tongue.
- Excellent.
- You met with the slavers today.
I did.
Our brothers and sisters
died fighting this scum.
Now you invite them
to our city and drink wine with them.
I imagine
this room was built
so the rulers could
intimidate the ruled.
But I am not your ruler.
I'm not
the Breaker of Chains.
I'm not the Unburnt.
And I am certainly not
the Mother of Dragons.
You are a stranger here.
So why do you represent
Meereen in these talks with our enemies?
Because our queen
chose me as her advisor.
Until she returns
from her travels--
When does she return?
Soon.
You have my word.
We don't know you. We don't trust you.
We know Torgo Nudho.
We fight with him
against the Masters. We trust him.
And that is exactly why Grey Worm
took part in these negotiations.
As commander of the Unsullied,
he knows how to defeat the slavers
and he knows when
it is time to make peace.
You have made peace
with the slavers?
We offered terms.
And you, Grey Worm?
You want to drink wine with these men?
The men who tore us from our mothers' arms
and sold us at auction like cattle?
I am a soldier, not a politician.
But if there is a chance for peace --
a just peace --
we should take it.
Missandei,
you know what these men are.
How can you trust them?
I do not trust them.
I will never trust them.
But as a wise man once said,
"We make peace with our
enemies, not our friends."
- Do not use me for your lies.
- Those men respect you.
They respect me
because they know who I am.
- They know I am loyal.
- As do I.
I am loyal to my queen,
not you.
If you betray her work,
you are my enemy.
I am not betraying her work.
I am trying to save her city.
You promised the slavers
they could keep slavery.
For a short time.
Seven years is not a short time
for a slave.
You're right.
Slavery is a horror
that should be ended at once.
War is a horror that should be ended
at once.
I can't do both today.
You are wrong
to trust these men.
I don't trust the Masters.
I trust their self-interest.
They're trustworthy
if they're convinced
that working with me
is in their self-interest.
You don't know them.
You don't understand them.
We are not human
in their eyes.
They look at me
and see a weapon.
They look at her
and see a whore.
They look at me and they see
a misshapen little beast.
Their contempt
is their weakness.
They'll underestimate us every time
and we will use that to our advantage.
You will not use them.
They will use you.
That is what they do.
You all right?
Why don't you sit
and catch your breath?
I'm fine.
I don't think you
could ride the dragon.
20 years ago, maybe.
- What?
- Our queen.
She's wild, you know.
Don't let her size fool you.
It's hard enough for me
and I'm a young man.
You, I don't think
your heart could take it.
Must make you angry
that our queen chose me.
Makes me sad.
You'll disappoint her before long.
- She'll move on.
- We'll all disappoint her before long.
We need each other right now.
After we're done needing each other--
Oh, I don't want to fight you,
Jorah the Andal.
What do I have to gain?
If I win, I'm the shit
who killed an old man.
If I lose, I'm the shit
who was killed by an old man.
You didn't get much
discipline as a child, did you?
None.
The road running
through the Horse Gate,
they call that
the godsway.
Eastern Market,
Western Market.
When Khal Drogo died,
she was supposed to come here
and join the Dosh Khaleen,
the widows
of the dead khals.
That's where they
would have taken her,
the Temple
of the Dosh Khaleen.
What are you doing?
It's forbidden to carry weapons
in the sacred city.
Isn't it forbidden to sneak into
their city and steal their khaleesi?
If they spot us
and we're unarmed,
we'll say we're traders heading
for the Western Market.
But if they see
weapons...
You're asking a dog
to hand over his teeth.
There's 100,000
of them down there.
We can't fight our way out.
We wait till dark,
and then we'll find her.
Uh...
I'm very attached
to this knife.
Don't worry.
It didn't touch you.
You know what happens?
I know what happens.
I'll do it myself.
I should have been
born a Dothraki.
Come on.
My friends...
We wandered off from the
Western Market and got lost.
Could you show us the way back?
What do you sell?
Wine.
Come down to my stall tomorrow,
I'll give you a cask of the Arbor's finest.
You're not merchants.
Get the others.
Told you, I'm very attached
to this knife.
You all right?
If they find a body
with a stab wound,
the whole city
will be looking for us.
Huh.
Some of them don't think Dothraki
should breed with foreigners.
They are stupid old women. They don't realize
that we have always diluted our blood.
This one is Lhazareen.
Her Khal found her hiding in a well
after he burned her village.
How old were you?
Twelve.
A year later, she bore her Khal a daughter.
How did he show his happiness?
He broke my ribs.
We are not queens here, but the khals
depend on us for our wisdom.
Our lives have meaning.
That is more than most have.
When the khals meet
for the Khalar Vezhven tomorrow night,
I hope they let you live out your days with us.
The other possibilities are not so pleasant.
I need to make water.
You can't run from Dothraki.
You know this.
I will never run from Dothraki.
Go, show her.
I needed fresh air.
The old women stink.
They do stink.
You must have been very young
when your Khal died.
Sixteen.
Too bad he didn't die sooner.
Yes, too bad.
Is it true you have three dragons?
Mm-hmm.
And they breathe fire?
They do.
Would you like to see them one day?
I am Dosh Khaleen.
I can never leave Vaes Dothrak, until I rise
as smoke from the pyre on the day I die.
- No, don't hurt her.
- She'll give us away.
We have to go now.
We will never get out
of Vaes Dothrak alive.
All we can do is try.
No.
We can do more than that.
And you're going
to help me.
And you...
Have faith in me, Khaleesi.
Do not betray me.
If I were to let you leave right now,
where would you go?
-  What would you seek out?
I'd go to my brother,
my husband, my family.
Of course, but for you,
that means seeking out money,
finery, power.
Seeking out your family
means seeking out sin.
I'm not maligning you.
I sought
those things out, too.
To the exclusion
of all else.
My father was a cobbler.
He died when I was young
and I took over his shop.
He was a simple man
and he made simple shoes.
But I found that the more work
I put into my shoes,
the more people
wanted them.
Fine leather,
ornamentation,
detailing,
and time.
Time most of all.
Dozens of hours
spent on a single pair.
Quality takes time.
Yes.
I imagine
you've worn a year
of someone's life
on your back.
The highborn liked to cover
their feet with my time
and they paid well
for the privilege.
I used their money
to buy a taste
of their lives for myself.
Each time I indulged,
I felt myself ascending
to something better.
And one day you walked
through a graveyard
and realized it was
all for nothing
and set out on the path
to righteousness.
Book of the Stranger,
verse 25.
You know
"The Seven-Pointed Star."
Septa Unella reads it to me.
At me.
Yes, yes, she does enjoy
reading at people.
You're close.
But it wasn't
a graveyard.
It was a feast.
I bought old fine wine
and young pretty girls
and invited my friends
to come and share it all.
We passed around the wine,
passed around the women,
and soon we fell
into a stupor.
I woke before dawn.
I could barely stand.
Everyone else was asleep on
the couches or on the floor,
lying in heaps next
to their fine clothes.
The truth of their bodies
laid bare.
I could smell them
beneath the incense
and the perfume
and the fine food that had
already started to turn.
And I saw it
with perfect clarity.
I saw what my sins were.
The gold I had, the wine I drank,
the women I used,
my ceaseless struggle
to maintain my position.
It was all part
of a story.
A story I was telling
myself about who I was.
A collection of lies
that would disappear
in the light.
The people I was trying
to climb away from,
the beggars
in the street,
the poor,
they were closer
to the truth than I ever was.
So what did you do?
I left to go
and find them.
I didn't even
put on my shoes.
I walked out the door
and never went back.
Come, let's go
and see him.
- Who?
- Your brother.
Loras.
Listen to me.
You need to stay strong.
I can't stay strong.
I never was strong.
You are strong.
You are the future
of our house,
the future
of our family.
- I don't care about that.
- Shh!
Shh.
Have you--
have you told them that?
That you don't care?
I just want it to stop.
Help me.
They want me
to help you.
They want me to help
tear you down.
That's why he's letting me see you.
I know it is.
And if either of us give in to
what they want, then they win.
Let them win.
Just make it stop.
Please.
All right.
And now, how to avert disaster
with our current predicament.
This High Sparrow.
I have dealt with fanatics
of every description, Your Grace.
Not setting them off,
that's the most important thing.
You are beset with enemies
both within and without.
What are you doing here?
I am advising the king
on our current predicament.
Leave.
I am a member
of the small council.
The king--
Is this a small
council meeting?
Obviously not.
I'm here to lend my wisdom
and my support.
Thank you for your counsel,
Grand Maester.
That will be all
for now.
Your Grace.
Since I've missed
the past several small council meetings,
I wanted to speak to you
about a few things.
I've been thinking
about the High Sparrow.
As have we all,
unfortunately.
We need to be careful
in dealing with such a man.
To prevent things from
escalating any further.
We have to be careful
not to antagonize him.
He has Margaery.
We can't put her at risk.
- He's dangerous.
- Look at me.
What did they do to me?
To the king's own mother?
It's all right.
It's done.
It's in the past.
And of course
Margaery's safety
is paramount.
You don't like Margaery,
do you?
Whether I like her or not
is completely unimportant.
Margaery is the queen.
Queens must command respect.
Kings even more so.
Not just for their own sake,
but for everyone's.
The High Sparrow has no respect for
kings or queens.
No respect for anything
in this world.
He has no use
for the things of this world.
He wants to knock them down
and replace them with what?
With fantasies.
With beggars
in the street.
With nothing.
Mother...
there's something
I want to tell you.
Something the High
Sparrow told me.
You've spoken with him?
I promised him I wouldn't tell anyone.
If he found out I told--
It would be a breach of confidence which
he would not take lightly
given his constant
prattling about the truth.
I am your mother.
You can always trust me.
The small council meeting has been
postponed on the king's orders.
I would have thought we were
perfectly clear the first time.
You're not welcome.
You once spoke of your
respect for our father
because he understood the necessity
of working with one's rivals.
My dear, you have been stripped of your
dignity and authority,
publically shamed,
and confined to the Red Keep.
What's left to work with?
Cersei is the mother
of the king.
She has the king's ear
and his trust.
And the king has been
speaking regularly
with the High Sparrow
about Queen Margaery and Ser Loras.
The High Sparrow
seized power
knowing full well
we'd bicker amongst ourselves
instead of
seizing it back.
Here we are.
Well done to us.
Now the future
of the Seven Kingdoms
rests in his dirty
peasant hands.
In a few days, he'll have
a trial for me.
But before that, Queen Margaery
will make her walk of atonement.
Yes, Margaery
will repent her sins
before the good people
of the city.
Oh, no.
That cannot happen.
That will not happen.
I agree.
You've got the second largest
army in Westeros.
You'll bring them
into the city,
stop Queen Margaery's
humiliation before it starts,
and take her back
into Crown custody.
The king has ordered me to take
no action against the High Sparrow
or the Faith Militant out of fear
for the queen's safety.
You will take
no action at all.
When the Tyrell armies come,
you will stand down.
Are you expressly
forbidden from standing down?
No, but if the king
should call--
The whole thing will be over before
anyone can call on you to do anything.
When the High Sparrow is in custody
or dead, preferably,
and Margaery's back
at Tommen's side,
do you think the king
will be angry at the outcome?
You hate these fanatics
as much as we do.
You hate what
they've done to your son.
Do you want Lancel back?
Or have you
given him up for good?
Of course
I want him back.
Then stand aside
and let the people
that took him from you be destroyed.
If it doesn't
go as planned,
the sparrows have
many friends in this city.
We'll have civil war.
Many will die.
Many will die
no matter what we do.
Better them than us.
They told me you were home
and I didn't believe it.
"Theon Greyjoy?"
I said.
"He's dead.
He's been dead
a long time."
He let you go?
I escaped.
I can't hear you.
Look at me.
Men died trying
to rescue you.
Good men.
My men.
I'm sorry.
You were my brother.
You were a spoiled little cunt,
but you were my brother
and I risked
everything for you
and you betrayed me.
I know.
I know and I'm sorry.
Stop saying that.
He broke me.
He broke me
into 1,000 pieces.
- I know.
- You don't know.
He sent us
one of those pieces.
That's why
I came for you.
Why did you come here?
Where else could I go?
You heard Father was dead and you thought
you'd claim the crown?
No, no. I only heard he died
after we docked.
You happen to show up
on Pyke right before the kingsmoot?
I didn't know.
You think any ironborn
wants you to be king
after what you've done?
I don't want
to be king.
What do you want?
I should have listened to you.
You're the only one--
That doesn't matter anymore.
Stop crying.
Look at me.
Tell me what you want.
You should rule
the Iron Islands.
Let me help you.
They've cleaned
you up nicely.
You know who I am?
A lord.
Yes.
You've seen my banners?
The flayed man.
Does that worry
you at all?
You eat them after?
No.
Then I've seen worse.
You served the Starks?
Aye.
They put me in chains
and put a sword
at my throat,
so I served them.
The Starks have been
gone for a long time,
but you kept
protecting Rickon.
He'd fetch a good price
to the right buyer.
I served his family
a long time.
Didn't get no wages.
Way I see it,
I'm owed.
Be that as it may,
Rickon's not yours
to sell anymore.
He's mine.
So what use could I possibly
have for you?
I can give you
what you want.
And you're sure
you know what that is?
Same thing
men always want.
And when they really want it,
they give it a bath first.
You're a good talker.
I like that.
You're a much better talker
than Theon Greyjoy.
That so?
I had to work hard
to get him talking.
But he talked.
They all do.
He told me everything.
All about the Stark boys,
who helped them escape,
and how she did it.
Open the gate!
Sorry about the food.
It's not what
we're known for.
That's all right.
There are more important things.
A letter for you,
Lord Commander.
I'm not Lord
Commander anymore.
"To the traitor
and bastard Jon Snow.
You allowed thousands
of wildlings past the Wall.
You have betrayed
your own kind.
the North.
Winterfell is mine, bastard.
Come and see.
Your brother Rickon
is in my dungeon.
His direwolf's skin
is on my floor.
Come and see.
I want my bride back.
Send her to me, bastard,
and I will not trouble you
or your wildling lovers.
Keep her from me
and I will ride north and slaughter
every wildling man, woman,
and babe living under your protection.
You will watch
as I skin them living.
You--"
Go on.
It's just more
of the same.
"You will watch as my soldiers
take turns raping your sister.
You will watch
as my dogs
devour your wild
little brother.
Then I will spoon your eyes from their
sockets and let my dogs do the rest.
Come and see.
Ramsay Bolton, Lord of Winterfell
and Warden of the North."
Lord of Winterfell
and Warden of the North.
His father's dead.
Ramsay killed him.
- And now he has Rickon.
- We don't know that.
Yes, we do.
How many men does
he have in his army?
I heard him say 5,000
once when he was talking
about Stannis's attack.
How many do you have?
That can march and fight?
2,000.
The rest are children
and old people.
You're the son of the last
true Warden of the North.
Northern families are loyal.
They'll fight for you if you ask.
A monster has taken
our home and our brother.
We have to go back
to Winterfell and save them both.
It is forbidden
to spill blood in the sacred city.
to carry weapons in the sacred city.
So we don't spill blood!
Well... there's always a little blood.
Someone crushed his head with a rock.
Aggo belonged to my khalasar.
He served me well.
He got his head smashed in by a rock.
Fuck Aggo.
Bring in Drogo's widow.
Who cares about her? She's a midget.
I like her.
She's paler than milk.
I'd like to know what a khaleesi tastes like.
Good.
You can suck my dick.
She belongs with the Dosh Khaleen.
The Wise Masters of Yunkai want her.
They're offering ten thousand horses
in exchange.
What's worth more,
one pink little girl or ten thousand horses?
Fuck the Wise Masters
in their perfumed asses.
I'll take their horses for myself.
Don't you want to know what I think?
You'd rather be sold into slavery?
Or maybe you'd like to show Rhalko
here what you taste like?
No.
I don't want either of those things.
We don't care what you want.
This is the Temple of the Dosh Khaleen.
You have no voice here,
unless you are Dosh Khaleen.
Which you are not, until we decide you are.
I know where I am. I have been here before.
This is where the Dosh Khaleen pronounced
my child the Stallion Who Mounts the World.
And what happened?
You trusted a sorceress, like a fool.
Your baby is dead because of you.
And so is Khal Drogo.
This is where Drogo promised to take his
khalasar west to where the world ends.
To ride wooden horses across the Black
Salt Sea as no khal has done before.
He promised to kill the men in their iron suits
and tear down their stone houses.
He swore to me
before the Mother of Mountains.
And you were dumb enough to believe him.
And here, now, what great matters
do the Great Khals discuss?
Which little villages you'll raid,
how many girls you'll get to fuck, how
many horses you'll demand in tribute.
You are small men.
None of you are fit to lead the Dothraki.
But I am.
SO I Will.
All right.
No Dosh Khaleen for you.
Instead we'll take turns fucking you.
And then we'll let our bloodriders fuck you.
And if there's anything left of you,
we'll give our horses a turn.
You crazy cunt.
Did you really think we would serve you?
You're not going to serve.
You're going to die.
Sync, corrected by elderman
BluRay resync by TooN
www.addic7ed.com