Tony, hey. I tented the bulbs.
Good.
I've been meaning to ask you...
The Sacrimonis.
I've been doing his yard
over there a year now.
And?
I guess what I'm asking is,
how much longer do I have
to keep doing this on the arm?
It was OK when we were getting you
out of your Feech La Manna problem,
but suddenly, short fucking memory?
I appreciate that, but...
You're a selfish prick, Sal.
Her husband's in jail. This is
when Mrs Sacrimoni needs you the most.
The federal prosecutors and myself
have been told to clear our calendars.
So trial is upon us.
And the feds have reached
a complete accounting of your worth.
"The vintage Wurlitzer"?
They go through my fucking sock drawer?
They shot a video the day of your arrest.
They even tracked down the 180 grand
under your father's name.
They estimate your net worth at five million.
While Ginny lives on scraps.
Between your cash and portfolios
with Fidelity and Vanguard,
your 401 K and severance parachute
from Essany Scaffolding,
condo in Deal Beach at 450,
Maserati, Ginny's Yukon,
and the house and contents
at a million two.
Is this all part of your plan, Ron?
Make me so depressed that I hang myself?
It's my obligation to raise the idea
again of cooperating.
Flip?
Let me explain something
to you again, Ron, but differently.
Being a rat, where I'm coming from,
is like asking a person where you're
coming from to become a fucking Nazi.
I don't wanna hear that shit again.
Good.
Because I don't represent turncoats.
Cos it would kill your practice.
What happened to my stuffed pork loin?
You ever hear of knocking?
I ordered it special.
You had them send it up to Carmela?
You get what you pay for.
Jag skojar, hon liknar dig bara.
Jag fattar inte varför du inte kan erkänna
att du skyller din skottskada på oss.
You never miss a chance to shit on him.
I'm joking. She looks like you, that's all.
Why can't you admit
that you blame us that you got shot?
Unfortunately, I have only myself to blame.
Unfortunately? So obviously
you'd like to blame somebody.
I have only myself to blame.
You don't blame me for the shooting?
You fucking blame me for something!
- Jan, the baby.
- Marrying the boss's sister,
usually it's a step up.
But you keep your goddamn foot on our necks.
You punish Bobby because he's my husband.
- Will you stop?
- To be his age and not to be a captain?
Now I see what this little visit's all about.
He works so hard for you,
and what does he get?
Merciless ridicule.
About his weight, his model railroading...
- He's a grown man!
- But it's OK for Neil Young.
He owns Lionel!
Domenica! Take care of your things.
I don't know where it comes from,
all your anger, your hate for me.
I'm your sister.
I know I'm not perfect.
I know I annoy people.
I think about you
lying in that hospital bed...
I cried for you. I sat with you.
I know it.
And I appreciated it.
But we both know,
no matter how much help I gave,
you'd still be here fucking complaining.
My God... there's nothing
holding us together but DNA.
I'm asking what else you got
besides slot machines?
That single-deck blackjack? OK, thanks.
I can't believe this.
Is this what you're doing all day?
I knew there was a reason
you wouldn't let me read your book.
- It's research.
- So Rocky Marciano liked the greyhounds?
Cos I found a fucking
trifecta box ticket in my trash!
Hold up. It's complicated shit.
Are you even a sports writer?
We're talking about taking
the next step in this relationship.
I ask you to share my home
and you can't even be straight with me.
- Fuck this. Nice knowing you.
- Jimbo, come on.
I'm not a writer, OK?
I'm not from Scottsdale...
and the car's not my sister's.
I'm actually from New Jersey.
- I knew it.
- Some shit went down. I had to leave.
My home, my contracting business...
my wife, my kids.
Are you drunk? It's not even 11 o'clock.
You think it's easy? I miss home
so bad my heart's a fucking lump.
I'm barely holding together,
stuck in the sticks,
running out of money and now this?
You think I was looking for you?
A wife and kids. Of course.
- I've been divorced for a few years.
- Where do they think you are?
You can never tell anybody, ever.
I'm not fucking around here.
I was married too, remember?
I was only gonna say, you need some money,
you worked construction,
maybe I can help you get work.
I know some people could always
use a good handyman.
Happy birthday!
- Stop blubbering. It's a party.
- You think we'd let you turn 50 alone?
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
Hi, Sal!
He's such a mope.
The girls come around and that helps.
Allegra's bitchy, but it's painful for her here.
- She thinks I resent her happiness.
- Newlyweds.
She's probably freaked out
that she's not happier.
Ginny, that kitchen... and this room, the light...
Not his decision.
I'm running that shop, not him.
My days are completely full.
- I shouldn't.
- It's your birthday.
I love this place. It reminds me
of the Palladian villas I saw in Italy.
Thank you. Sometimes I forget.
I spend most of my time upstairs.
- Wellbutrin.
- I wish there was a pill.
John in that place? Of course, I can't
say my pain's worse than anybody's.
Yeah. We're both grownups.
I'd rather go with my own instincts.
- Your feet are like fucking icicles.
- Hands too?
Dinner was good.
I found a woodland mountain.
27" peak, clump foliage and snow.
- Bobby.
- I'm listening, OK?
Where are you going?
Rafe's brother's making a music video.
They got dry ice.
Where's your helmet?
Check out the Moe and Joe action.
You know what? Let's do a race.
The Polar Express one. We could trash it.
I can't.
I see the grey cloud
hanging around your head.
Where's Prince Albert? Still sleeping?
Who knows?
I've been very patient with you
because you've been sick.
You were going to talk
to the building inspector.
- My spec house.
- Yeah.
I sent Little Paulie.
Now, he made headway
with the supervisor,
but the other guy,
the inspector, he's a piece of work.
Next I'll get Sil on it.
Gotta pay a visit
to the Montville Building Department.
To what end?
I promised Carm I'd lean on this inspector.
Completely went out of my head.
The guy's name is Ron Senkowski.
Ginny Sack's brother, Anthony.
The lord of the lenses.
Actually we just started carrying these.
The newest Cross pen.
A rollerball.
- You want a classic fountain?
- Nah. Have a seat.
- How's your brother-in-law?
- John's fucking made of steel.
I was told "your ears only".
- That's why he didn't get a pen?
- No...
He's fucking with you, Anthony.
Johnny's a silent partner in this
equipment leasing thing in New Orleans.
Good. FEMA's down there
handing out Krugerrands in buckets.
He said post-Katrina you had some
knowledge of business in the area.
Well, let me say this...
Dick Cheney for President...
of the fucking universe.
On account
of John's liquidity problems,
the asset freeze,
he'd love you to contact these brothers,
the owners, and turn it into cash.
- Me?
- Phil Leotardo shouldn't be involved.
Just know John's asking as a friend.
Obviously there's a finder's fee.
What the hell's this, a siesta?
What? I wasn't sleeping.
I was resting my hips.
I was supposed to have surgery.
Am I early?
- What do you mean?
- Dinner.
I am interviewing
a new contractor for my spec.
Bill DeGillio.
He built the Sacrimoni house.
He did decent workmanship.
Ginny says he works for a price.
- So?
- Your sister loves that house.
She said it reminded her of a villa in Italy.
- Is he coming here now?
- I picked up sandwiches from Italianissimo.
Your father did this house
and it was more than decent workmanship.
Think about replacing him before you rush into
something that could cost a lot more time.
Why do you suddenly care
so much about my dad?
I like that she has these little projects
and charities, what have you.
Makes her happy, keeps her busy.
But...
even in bed she's a million miles away.
Sounds like you want
to encourage her with this house
as long as it doesn't interfere with your life.
Carmela and me...
we came to an understanding
when we reconciled.
I would financially back her spec house
and she would have more
of a don't-ask-don't-tell policy
towards my work and my recreational
life outside of the home.
But you tell me there hasn't been
much recreating since the shooting.
No, and that's OK.
Fucking Janice came to visit me at work.
That doesn't happen often.
Well, she shops for meat there.
We get it free.
By the way, if you ever need a roast
or any specialty kind of cut,
please just ask.
My dad used to drop us off there
when he had to run errands.
We'd go into the back and steal
cigarettes, play house, shit like that.
She was all upset. She said that
I was mean to her and her husband.
- What did you say?
- It doesn't matter, cos she's right.
I love it when I can take a shit on her
and her husband.
What's that about?
When they told me
Uncle Jun' might need diapers,
I thought about Bobby having to change
him... I still get a kick out of it.
It makes Bob seem weak?
Your sister too? These are acts of kindness.
Janice only does acts of Janice. Trust me.
You two have never really gotten along?
Not never. She was my older sister.
I thought she was pretty cool.
And she gave it back to my mother.
That was heroic shit.
Because she defended you.
Please. It was every man for himself.
I remember one time
my parents left her in charge.
Go ahead.
She stood in the hallway
and she tape-recorded...
me and Barb having a fight.
And she held that cassette tape
over my head for a month.
Fucking extortion.
Made me make her bed, get her shit.
- Did she do that to Barbara too?
- That's not the fucking point.
I've been coming here five years
and you still don't understand what it
means to tape somebody in my family?
You still don't fucking get this?
Listen, as far as that thing goes...
the coffee with the chicory?
- What the fuck is that?
- Shit.
I suck at talking like this, John. I'm sorry.
Our friend with the stomach.
- In town or near home?
- Your neighbour.
- AS.
- All right.
Just say, "The thing I asked you to do".
The coffee with the fucking chicory!
- Is he gonna get it for me?
- Yes.
Bad news is he wants ten cups
for himself. Not seven.
All right. Done.
Did you pick up the birthday cake
for Gin with the marzipan flowers?
- The stuff behind the pool?
- No, an actual fucking cake.
It's her birthday.
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming with you.
OK, but stand clear.
- What's going on?
- Pastor heard water running,
went down, basement's flooded.
But the pastor's trapped.
- You get him?
- An arcing wire's hanging.
These assholes skipped a conduit
when they remodelled.
I spent years as a contractor.
Electrical is where I started.
...few minutes. There's nothing to see here.
Way to go, Vince!
What the fuck did I tell you?
- The guy was gonna get cooked.
- You trying to be a big man?
- Back the fuck off!
- What the fuck, Jim?
Boys, calm down.
Let's cut the bullshit, get the water turned off
and pump out the damn basement.
I thought you guys
were morons for doing this shit,
but now I can see it's a fucking rush.
- You should join the department.
- We could use another moron.
It's a commitment, firefighting.
Every day it's there.
You have to have a passion.
I've got bad hips. Supposed to have surgery.
This is all bullshit talk anyway.
You're gonna forget this craphole
the minute you hear from your publisher.
Darts! Five bucks a point. Who's in?
Nah. It's almost midnight.
Where the fuck you guys going?
- Let's play some poker.
- You did great.
Where I come from, the night's just starting.
Good week,
even with the fucking Dolphins.
Night, boss.
Get his joint.
- You know who the fuck I am?
- You beat, nigga.
Come out the bookies?
You a winner or a loser?
You're making a big mistake.
Damn! Three Gs.
You got what you want.
Please don't. I got kids.
Look at his mouth.
Look at his fucking mouth!
- Do him now.
- Jesus, no. Please.
No, please.
What the fuck you doin'?
Why you pull that trigger?
According to John, the retail value
of Bayou Leasing is around six mil.
- Seem about right?
- Between five and six.
Let's do this again.
You're gonna have to find a buyer
and deliver John's half to me
in about 30 days,
give you a chance to get bidders.
- His half?
- Yeah.
I don't think that's up for debate.
Had you controlled your fucking football,
we wouldn't have no silent partner.
That man floated me 50 grand. 50.
Next thing I know he's
buying in for half a fucking million.
Look at him, like they don't
do this shit every day.
You took John's loan. He helped you expand.
Now it's time to cash in.
Mr Soprano, that's what
I've been saying all along.
- You two don't seem like brothers.
- In-laws. He married my little sis.
15 years of womanly company
but I had to come all the way
to New Jersey to get truly fucked.
I'm doing this as a favour to John.
I don't need another headache.
Do we got a problem here?
No, sir. I'm buying a boat.
You fancy yourself a businessman.
Would you sell with all that money
pouring into New Orleans?
John Sacrimoni asked me to.
Well, we're very different people.
- Thanks.
- North belligerents will kindly remain in Utah.
You, shake hands and come out fightin'.
I'll take you.
- Yeah?
- Heard about Bobby Bacala?
Yeah, my sister called
with the breaking news.
That fucking part of Newark.
Even the cops don't go there.
So you heard everything.
Doctor said the slug blew
bits of sidewalk into the eye.
- Yeah, I heard.
- But they're optimistic.
Right, doctors.
It's always good news till it ain't.
Speaking of that, whatever the fuck
happened to you with the prostate?
I've been dealing with some shit.
Cancer, to tell you the truth.
What the fuck, Paulie?
It was early. Maybe I caught a break.
Still encapsulated.
I'm taking a course of radiation
to knock the PSA back into single digits.
Are you all right? The hair and shit?
Knock wood... I must have
done good things in my life.
Yeah.
All right.
The cancer... your ears only.
Absolutely.
You hear about Bobby?
- Yeah.
- Should've seen him.
Put a patch over his eye like Hathaway.
He was really rattled.
It was kind of stupid
to be out there that late.
Cops don't even go there no more.
Anyway, Bobby's vision's fucked.
He could be a candidate
for a cornea transplant.
He should be a candidate
for a brain transplant.
To his credit, all he was thinking about
was straightening out for the week.
Fuck that honour and loyalty shit.
It was a manoeuvre, Carlo,
cos he knew it was his own fucking fault.
What? Don't give me that look.
Including the wife's IRA and his pension...
we'd go for 240 months.
20 years and 90% of his assets?
Makes trial seem like
a risk worth taking.
- Have you seen the evidence?
- You came to us.
My client insists the house is off-limits.
- He wants his wife provided for.
- What do you have in mind?
Again, the shit that has nothing to do with him,
the house, her IRA, the Yukon,
the deed on the daughter's condo.
- And 12 years.
- For conspiracy to commit murder?
Get back to me when you're sober, Ron.
So Eagles absolutely no good here.
Not sure even seven will.
Eagles will go for McNab.
Back pass, he has this...
- It's broken.
- Wanna switch?
No. I'm good.
Carm called. She's still
getting her folks in the car.
Where's Barb and Tom?
I asked them to bring wine.
We'll see how long that takes.
Did you take the Vicodin?
Giants... Fucking blowing 'em out.
As long as they don't beat the spread.
- Where are you going?
- Out.
The Giants are kicking ass here.
- I'm going to watch the Chargers.
- What channel's that on?
Some people buy the satellite package.
Sit down. This is a Giants house.
- I hate the fucking Giants.
- What'd we say about that language?
AJ didn't come to Sunday dinner.
AJ has a job. Do you wanna go get a job?
Go ahead.
But first go get your last report card
and read it to everybody.
No? I thought so.
Go finish your Spanish report before dinner.
Set the table, honey.
My brother-in-law
almost got his fucking eye put out.
Some fucking crackhead animals.
- That is terrible.
- Yeah, it is, but...
it's one thing after another with her family.
You mean the bad luck?
Or do you feel like somehow they deserve it?
I don't know, but...
Fucking Janice attracts drama.
- She creams over the misery.
- Does she remind you of anyone?
When we were growing up,
she had something.
She had beautiful hair
and she was built and...
Guys were always buying me ice cream,
giving me baseball cards,
kissing my ass to get in good with her.
Sounds a little like jealousy.
No guy wants his sister to be the town pump.
You weren't sexually threatened?
Jesus Christ, will you make up
your fucking sick mind?
First it's my mother.
Now I wanna fuck my sister?
It's normal, not sick,
that she functioned as the focus
of your early sexual feelings.
In fact, it was probably mutual.
Jesus Christ.
You describe her as "built".
All those afternoons in your
father's office, "playing house".
Whatever your bond,
what happened between then and now?
She fought it out with my mother
and finally took off first minute she could.
What if you had taken off?
That never would have happened.
I wasn't like that.
- I did what I was told.
- Your father's son.
- Yeah, that's right.
- And all that went with it.
That's right. All the success and the money.
But beyond that, what else did you inherit?
I'll tell you what I inherited. My mother.
Janice got laid. She took off.
She laughed at all this shit.
Then the trip's over and she's back
and she wants her piece.
Well, she gets nothing!
Cos I got the scars! So it's mine!
What are you doing?
Cooking. How was the call?
It was nothing.
It was a laundromat on Webster.
Thought I'd make a little dinner
like we do back home.
We got pasta badan.
Macaroni and potatoes.
Real peasant food.
We got a little salad.
Then pork chops and vinegar peppers.
I fucking miss this shit, I gotta say.
I can see why.
You gotta wait for that.
- What?
- Nothing.
I just realised...
the other night when you cut
the power to the church...
- I was a real dick.
- Yeah.
But it was only because I was worried.
Something could've happened to you.
That's a nice thing.
You don't understand.
Vincent...
I love you.
I love you, johnnycakes.
10:30, gotta be.
Hour and a half, lunch.
The halfway fucking point.
Don't look at your watch. Not yet.
Save it. Treat yourself.
Ten to 11...
maybe five of.
Don't look.
Think of those sandwiches Jim made.
When you've eaten the last bite,
this fucking day is halfway gone.
11:30, has to be.
Look at the angle of the sun.
Maybe even a quarter to 12.
OK, look now.
Fuck me!
Vincent!
Jiggle the toilet after.
Moment of truth?
It's still up to the judge,
but they're gonna recommend 15 years...
and 4.1 million.
You keep the home, the 45k in equity
from the girls' variable life insurance,
and Ginny's IRA
which is worth about 110 grand.
- And?
- That's it. Or go to trial.
15 fucking years.
You're a young man.
In 15 years, you'll be 67.
The golden years. Grandkids.
Do I have to to do the allocution?
You know the allocution is always part of it,
practically the whole point.
I'll take it.
That IRA of Ginny's...
she worked the tie counter at Wanamaker's.
That's where we met.
No Mocha Mix?
I was looking forward to blueberries,
but Mom hasn't shopped.
What are you doing hanging around here?
Finn asked me to see a movie,
but I didn't want to go
and I told him he could go
if he wanted to and he went.
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
Don't give it to me, OK?
I know. I'm sorry. It's just...
he doesn't fucking get it.
I don't know what he's thinking.
He spends more time
at Jeffrey's apartment than with me.
You know who's really good
to talk to about stuff?
Your mother.
This whole year off together,
I've seen such a selfish side.
"I'll come back early."
He said that. He actually said that.
All right, well...
Maybe he thought you wanted him to go.
You did say it.
Yeah, or maybe subconsciously he's done.
We sleep together at Jeffrey's apartment
and Finn sleeps on the floor half the time
and I'm right there for him.
When you're living in sin, you can't expect...
Living in what? Jesus Christ.
You should talk to your mother
about this shit!
Did you go see that guy
at the building department?
I was going to go on Friday
when the schedules are looser.
Well, don't.
Fuck!
Jesus. Are you all right?
Why the fuck are you parked here?
Excuse me? I'm getting my mail.
You're driving like a maniac.
My God. How come your airbag
didn't go off?
- Somebody took it out. They sold it.
- Who would do such a thing?
Look, I'm really sorry. I was in a rush.
- So you admit it was your fault.
- Yeah, absolutely.
Let me get the damages here
and I'll be on my way.
We should file a police report.
You got a phone?
No, seriously.
What do you say, 500 bucks?
Look, I took the worst of it.
And then you call your insurance on me?
No thank you.
I'm not gonna do that. Six?
I don't want an argument here.
My place is just up the drive.
We'll call the police. They'll come right out.
Turn on your hazards.
Let me get my registration.
Motherfucker!
Fucking cocksucking cunt!
Fuck!
- I was just coming to see you.
- I'm on my way home.
- It's just I haven't heard from you.
- The fuckheads from fuckland?
- Yeah.
- It's gonna be too much effort.
John was really counting on this.
And Ginny needs the money,
for Allegra, for the family.
What?
- He changed the terms.
- A bigger piece for his fat mouth?
No, smaller, actually, but it's the house.
He wants you to unload it
to his sister at a reduced price.
Half, actually.
But the New Orleans thing,
he'll knock two per cent off his finder's fee
and he'll make sure those pricks sell.
I guess beggars can't be choosers.
The worst part is
I gotta sell the idea to Ginny somehow.
Gab took me to her Moroccan tile place.
By the way, I don't wanna pester you.
Did Sil make a visit?
Yeah, I meant to tell you.
He didn't have any luck with that inspector.
- Really? You're kidding.
- No. Sorry about that.
- Did he bring him a gift?
- Cash.
So how hard did he lean on the guy?
Carm, Sil knows his business.
I know you're disappointed but,
I gotta say this, just sell it.
You'll get a good price.
30 per cent return on your investment.
So that's it? You just give up?
I don't think I ever heard that before.
The guy said no.
How far do you wanna push this thing?
Those sons of bitches.
All my planning for a fucking year!
And they let people
build those fucking monstrosities!
You wanna go out to dinner tonight at least?
Why not put a runner here
or a large diameter round Oriental?
It could cut down
on the echo and warm it up.
I'd rather we spend where we have to
right now. Window treatments.
Mr Sacrimoni, during the time period
beginning approximately
January 1st 1996 through today,
were you employed by or associated with
the New York faction of an organised
crime family of La Cosa Nostra?
Yes.
Sacrimoni allocuted in federal court,
admitting a ten-year connection
with La Cosa Nostra.
Fucking nauseating!
Could have been worse. He could have flipped.
Are you fucking kidding me?
You don't ever admit the existence of this thing.
He should have stood trial like a man.
I did 20 fucking years.
What?
Johnny Sack pleaded guilty.
It was just on the radio.
He got 15 years.
Fuck!
Hold on. Wait a fucking minute.
- Are you the owner?
- Yeah.
I went in for a half an hour, tops.
Douchebags make that a red zone?
This is a seizure order for assets
belonging to John Sacrimoni.
No. I bought it from his wife.
If she sold it, she violated
a court order freezing his assets.
Of course she sold it.
I paid her fucking 25 grand cash.
It's going to be auctioned in May.
You like it so much, buy it again.
This is insane,
you cocksucking motherfucker!
Keep talking like that.
I'm gonna get a truck out here for you.
To think that piece of shit
was my friend once.
- I hope he dies in there.
- You know how this looks?
I wish I was at the courthouse
to throw acid in his face,
just to distance myself.
Excuse me, Tony?
I've been meaning to ask you...
I was just wondering
about the Sacrimoni place.
- What about it?
- Now that Mr Sacrimoni is guilty,
do you think I could maybe
take him off my route?
- What the fuck did you just say?
- I don't know.
The fucking Lawnmower Man
just said John was guilty.
- He pled guilty, Sal. OK?
- Yeah, OK.
With this government, no trial.
Maybe they stuck tasers on his balls
and beat him with a rubber hose.
- You ever think of that?
- No.
But of course, it makes sense.
Don't besmirch the man, Sal.
- So about the yard...
- Do you believe this fucking guy?
You're done with that.
Come on. Let's go check out these DVDs.
...to take about 35 to 40 of them.
No gain, second and ten...
he's on a roll to the nearest side...
Gets it away and has a completionl
Mead, put the cavatell' in.
- Hey there.
- Hi.
- Where's Christopher?
- AA meeting.
- Tony?
- Yeah.
I just wanted to say thank you.
You're welcome.
No one's ever done something so...
It's OK, Janice. Really.
Sorry.
You got the wine? We're almost ready.
What happened?
No one knows what goes on in my head.
What's the matter? What happened?
She's happy about the house.
Honey, it's OK. It's OK.
- Come on. You OK?
- Yeah.
- You all right?