Hiya, sweetie.
They took the tube out of his throat.
Now he's breathing on his own.
He took a lot of damage to his spleen.
- They might take it out.
- Oh, my God.
- I know.
- Jeez.
I'm so scared.
Hey, listen, listen.
This guy, he's a tough kid.
If anybody can make it through
something like this, it's Christopher.
Look, you got His Holiness.
That's good.
He got shot too and survived.
Look what they did to my son!
My son, those sons of bitches!
Fucking vodka.
When you find him, I want him
to suffer, you hear me, Sil?
I want that motherfucker in agony!
Don't worry.
We'll do the best we can.
Gismonte, with a G.
The kid who died, right?
- What, you never heard of him?
- No.
Him and his friend, Bevilaqua,
ran with Moltisanti.
You never saw him hanging out
with Christopher?
You don't want to help your friend?
Hey.
I thought they were
moving him out of the ICU.
- They think he's getting better.
- We've gotta pray.
Hey, you gotta pray.
We are. Jesus.
I don't know what
I would do, Uncle Rich.
I love him so much.
He's gonna make it.
I don't want that fuck here.
I told him that.
He's full of negative energies.
He said he'd only come back here
if he had something on Matthew.
- Start talking.
- Back the fuck off.
All right. What do you got, Rich?
The word is definitely out
on the street on this Bevilaqua kid.
Tommy Biondi from OTB
came up with a name.
A dealer named Quickie G.
He's been in the Bing a few times.
Or it might have been
this other prick, Fast Fatty.
I'm telling you, this won't take long.
I give Bevilaqua five days before
somebody brings his ass to us...
...to score points.
My brother was in this hospital.
The bill was 75 pages long.
Eight dollars for an aspirin.
You hear about Ralph and Mary Ritaldo?
No, what happened?
Ralphie's had this
Brazilian goomar for years.
- A dancer, right?
- She just gave birth to Ralph's baby.
A C-section.
Hey.
Why don't you try and get some sleep?
Why?
Tomorrow's gonna be
another rough day, that's why.
I don't think I'll sleep tonight.
Will this light bother you?
No.
Good night.
Tony?
I love you, Tony.
I don't want anybody getting hurt.
Not me, not the kids, not you...
I can't do one
of these tearful things...
...till 5:00 in the morning tonight.
I just can't.
Not tonight.
Did you hear about Ralphie Ritaldo?
- What about him?
- The Brazilian he keeps on the side?
Yeah?
She had a baby.
Christopher's in the ICU.
This is on your mind?
Maybe it has to do
with the CK One on your shirt.
- It's over. Months ago.
- Yeah, right.
Yeah, right what? I cut it off!
Listen, Tony, if you're gonna
keep doing what you do...
...then, at the very least,
I want you to get a vasectomy.
- You want me to do what?
- Let's get real, Tony.
You know what a bastard child
would do to this family?
Think about the shame we'd feel.
You're putting us all at risk.
Hey, I had her tested for AIDS.
What do you think I am?
Code Blue, ICU 3.
No! Oh, my God! Chrissy!
No! He's gonna die!
No, he's gonna be okay.
It's not fair!
They said he was gonna get better!
No, let go of me! No!
Yeah?
What?
How is he?
His heart stopped.
They're working
their asses off on him.
All right.
Well, we gotta stay positive, right?
We gotta give him that.
Positive vibes only.
Gentle and merciful Lord Jesus.
I want to speak to You now
with an open heart.
With an honest heart.
Tonight I ask You to take my sins...
...and the sins of my family
into Your merciful heart.
We have chosen this life
in full awareness...
...of the consequences of our sins.
I know that Christopher's life
is in Your hands.
And his fate is Your will.
I ask You humbly to spare him.
And if it is Your will to spare him...
...I ask that You deliver him
from blindness...
...and grant him vision.
And through this vision,
may he see Your love...
...and gain the strength to carry on
in service to Your mercy.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
If I had any reservations,
I'd suggest we move him now.
This is the best trauma unit
in the Tri-State.
- I'm up on all the ratings.
- Oh, thanks, Hesh.
There's no news yet.
Tony, it's Dr. Rubin.
Mr. Moltisanti suffered cardiac
and respiratory arrest...
...due to internal bleeding.
He was resuscitated.
The bleeding was brought under
control. He's in stable condition.
- What was the duration of the arrest?
- About a minute.
- He still intubated?
- They're removing the ventilator now.
What the fuck you two talking about?
The worst is over. But he was
clinically dead for about a minute.
Doctor, can I go see him?
No, he'll be in post-op
for about five hours.
Then he's asked to speak
with Mr. Gualtieri.
- Me?
- He asked for you and Mr. Soprano.
Christopher.
Hey.
I'm sorry, T.
For what?
I know you're mad at me.
What are you talking about?
I'm not mad at you. Nobody is.
I'm going to hell, T.
- You're not going anywhere but home.
- I crossed over to the other side.
You what?
I saw the tunnel...
...and a white light.
- I saw my father in hell.
- Get the fuck outta here.
The bouncer said that I'd be there
too when my time comes.
- What bouncer?
- The Emerald Piper.
That's our hell.
It's an Irish bar where it's
St. Patrick's Day every day forever.
Mikey Palmice and Brendan Filone
were there too.
They were friends.
Those two guys hated each other.
You gotta relax.
You just need some rest.
They're friends now.
They were playing dice with two Roman
soldiers and a bunch of Irish guys.
Doesn't make sense.
And the Irish,
they were winning every roll.
And then Mikey gave me
a message for both of you.
A message.
Yeah.
Yeah, he said:
"Tell Tony and Paulie, 3:00."
Three o'clock?
This fucking morphine drip.
I don't think it's working.
- I don't feel a fucking thing.
- You gotta be careful with that.
- That was all he said?
- Who?
Mikey. Three o'clock?
Yeah.
What was he wearing?
Come on, let's go. He needs his rest.
He had on a gangster suit.
Pinstripe.
Old-fashioned style.
Hey...
That was a dream.
Forget about it. Okay?
I'm gonna take you home soon.
Do they know this kid likes
his chemistry set too much?
He's in pain.
What the fuck else they gonna do?
What time was Mikey hit?
How the fuck do I know?
You were there.
It was in the morning, right?
Eleven, ten?
All right, so I cheat.
I used to cheat.
I'm not getting spayed.
End of subject.
You brought up the vasectomy.
Now you don't want to talk.
You asked me what was going on.
I saw on the news
about a gangland shooting.
Yeah.
Is that your nephew Christopher
that you've spoken of before?
The papers said he was
in critical condition.
It'll be fine.
Have they found the person
that shot him yet?
No. Have you?
I'm not trying to pry
into that part of your life.
I know our deal.
But I've heard you say before
that you love this young man.
Christopher was...
...clinically dead...
...for about a minute.
He thinks he had one of those
near-death experiences.
Says he visited hell...
...and they told him
he'd be back permanent.
Who's "they"?
It's bullshit. It was a dream
combined with the morphine.
He thinks he's going to hell.
He's all fucked up over it.
Do you think he'll go to hell?
No.
He's not the type that deserves hell.
Who do you think does?
The worst people.
The twisted and demented psychos
who kill people for pleasure.
Cannibals, degenerate molesters,
torturers and killers of babies.
The Hitlers, the Pol Pots. They're
the evil fucks that deserve to die.
Not my nephew.
What about you?
What?
Hell?
You been listening to me?
No. For the same reasons.
We're soldiers, you know.
Soldiers don't go to hell.
It's war. Soldiers,
they kill other soldiers.
We're in a situation...
...where everybody involved
knows the stakes.
And if you're gonna
accept those stakes...
...you gotta do certain things.
It's business. We're soldiers.
We follow codes.
Orders.
So does that justify
everything that you do?
Excuse me. When America
opened the floodgates...
...and let all us Italians in,
what do you think they did it for?
Because they were trying
to save us from poverty?
It was because they needed us.
They needed us to build their cities
and subways and to make them richer.
The Carnegies and Rockefellers
needed worker bees. There we were.
But some of us didn't
want to lose who we were.
We wanted to preserve
the important things:
Honor and family and loyalty.
Some of us wanted
a piece of the action.
Now we weren't educated
like the Americans...
...but we had the balls
to take what we wanted.
And those other fucks,
those other, the J.P. Morgans...
...they were crooks and killers too.
But that was the business, right?
The American way.
That might all be true.
But what do poor Italian immigrants
have to do with you...
...and what happens every morning
you step out of bed?
- What the fuck is all this?
- I'm just asking a question.
Oh, so you're taking a stand here now.
You pick here to make a stand?
After all this, telling me nothing's
my fault because of poor parenting...
...you pick now to be
Betsy-fucking-Ross?
My nephew's in the fucking hospital.
He might not get out.
What? Three o'clock again?
Quiet.
My wind chimes?
Sorry, hon.
Just don't wake up my kids, Paulie.
Motherfucker.
Baby...
...you gotta relax your thoughts.
Whatever Christopher saw...
...you can't take it personal.
Christopher's a troubled kid.
Who knows what's in his heart?
Come.
You're right.
I need to relax with this.
Let me help you.
- That is so weird.
- What the fuck you saying?
Three o'clock?
Kenny and I were supposed
to be married at 1:00...
...in the Fontainebleau Room
at the Roman Gardens.
Mikey and Jo-Jo had the
Bella Vista Room booked for 3:00.
The Bella Vista Room
is smaller with no windows.
A week before the wedding, Mikey saw
the Bella Vista Room and flipped out.
He almost killed the events manager.
So Mikey and Jo-Jo
got the Fontainebleau...
...and Kenny and me wound up
with the Bella Vista Room.
At 3:00.
Fuck.
Just trying to tidy up the place.
Go back to sleep.
Tidying up?
How you doing?
I'm doing.
I'll tell you...
...I'm still baffled
by this 3:00 thing, though.
I wish I had more for you,
but that's all he said.
- Let me ask you a question.
- Yeah?
That bouncer that sent you back,
did he have horns on his head?
He was just some big Irish goon
in old-fashioned clothes.
Did anybody there have horns?
Or buds for horns? Those goat bumps?
Paulie, it was fucking hell, okay?
My father said he loses
every hand of cards he plays.
And every midnight, they whack him...
...the same way he was whacked
in life, and it's painful.
Night after night. Does that sound
like fucking heaven to you?
- Was it hot?
- Yeah.
I don't know. What the fuck?
Heat's the first thing you'd notice.
Hell is hot.
That's never been disputed by anybody.
You didn't go to hell.
You went to purgatory, my friend.
I forgot all about purgatory.
Purgatory.
A little detour
on the way to paradise.
- How long you think we stay there?
- Now that's different for everybody.
You add up all your mortal sins
and multiply that number by 50.
Then you add up all your venial sins
and multiply that by 25.
You add them together,
that's your sentence.
I figure I have to do about 6000 years
before I get accepted into heaven.
And 6000 years is nothing
in eternity terms.
I can do that standing on my head.
It's like a couple of days here.
Was I insensitive?
And, perhaps,
did I do it deliberately?
Do I hate him?
How often are you taking the Ativan?
Almost every night.
And when else?
Sunday afternoon I took one.
There's another thing. I...
I've been drinking.
Alone.
I'm glad you're telling me.
Part of it is that I'm afraid.
I've told him my son is at Bard.
Why did you agree
to continue working with him?
We've discussed this, Elliot.
I took him back
because I felt it was...
...a professional and ethical
responsibility to do so.
Jennifer, I'm not challenging
your ability or professionalism...
...or even your ethics.
Then what are you challenging?
What you hope to achieve
with this man.
- What do you hope to achieve with me?
- No, that's a facile analogy.
I'm living in a moral
Never Never Land with this patient.
Not wanting to judge but to treat.
But now I've judged.
I took a position,
goddamn it, and I'm scared.
I feel for you.
You're late.
That go on my record?
It's common courtesy.
I got a life too.
- Yeah, lucky you.
- So, what do you got?
- I think he knows.
- Knows what?
- Or suspects.
- What are you talking about?
He looks at me different. Glances.
"Glances"?
We had sandwiches brought in.
Four with meats, one eggplant and
the other with tomato and mozzarella.
That's six.
There were only five of us.
Tony said he ordered the eggplant,
but I did. He ordered the tomato.
- Maybe he forgot.
- He never forgets.
What's your point?
He let me eat the eggplant.
He took the tomato.
- But there was a moment.
- A glance.
Yeah, a fucking glance!
This is simple.
I'm gonna help you out.
Keep in mind that you're
the one who's different.
You're seeing differently.
You got a new attitude.
I know the man.
He's the one who's different with me.
Odds don't favor it.
Either way, it doesn't matter.
- Yeah, to you.
- I wasn't the one selling heroin.
I wasn't the one pinched for it.
So, what do I do?
What do you do?
You do everything you can do.
Do what you do to a girl that you
want to fuck. Make him love you.
I'll be back first thing
in the morning.
What do you want for breakfast?
- You don't wake up till lunch, Mom.
- Tomorrow I'll get up early.
How about the peppers
and eggs and bread?
- That sounds great, Ma.
- Okay.
- Do you need more time alone, Jo?
- No. I'm ready.
Okay, Chris.
Bye, Ma.
If you want to sleep, it's okay.
I brought a book.
No, I just got up 10 minutes ago.
And the painkillers aren't helping?
No, they're pretty fucking good.
I want to tell you
something, Christopher.
The other night,
when your heart stopped...
...I walked down the hall to a room
and I prayed to Jesus to spare you.
And that if He would spare you,
I asked that He grant you vision.
Sight.
So that you can see the way
to Christ clearly.
Yeah, so?
And He did spare you.
And you saw, Christopher.
You saw something.
Something that none of us
have ever seen.
- So, what did He say to you?
- Who?
Jesus.
I didn't see Jesus.
Tony said you saw Jesus and He took
you to see your father in heaven.
- Then He said it wasn't your time.
- I was in hell.
You what?
My father was in hell and they said
that's where I'd go when it's my time.
Maybe it was purgatory,
but I don't know.
Then you have to look at this
experience as a chance to repent.
To change your heart.
To start to walk in the light of
the Lord. You were blessed by this.
You were blessed with a second chance.
I don't know, Carmela.
Well, I do know.
And I am gonna pray
like I did the other night.
And I'm gonna pray
every day from now on.
It is not too late
for you, Christopher.
If you pray.
Will you pray?
Okay, you just have to follow me.
In the name of the Father...
...the Son...
...and the Holy Spirit.
How was he?
Fine.
Same.
So any news?
No.
So, what, we're not talking now?
I said what I had to say, Tony.
If you can't be honest with me, have
the balls to be honest with yourself.
I got balls. And as long as I do,
they will remain intact.
You don't have faith in me,
it's up to you.
You gotta prove it to yourself first.
Yourself and God.
You're only religious
when it suits you.
What is that supposed to mean?
Come here.
What's it mean?
The pope don't like Trojans yet you
want me cut. Isn't that hypocritical?
Look, I'm thinking of
my family first. That's all.
What's down here is God's creation.
Isn't it a sin to undo His work?
You should know.
You made a living of it.
You're un-fucking-believable,
you know that?
Look what I made that living for.
You had dinner an hour ago. What
the fuck are you doing to yourself!?
Leave him alone.
I'm supposed to get a vasectomy
when this is my heir?
Look at him.
Tony, come back here and apologize!
- You're dragging me to hell!
- What?
- Paulie! Paulie!
You had a nightmare.
Mommy, somebody was screaming.
I'm scared.
I know, honey.
It's okay. It's okay.
Uncle Paulie had a bad dream.
Mommy.
Come here, baby.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's okay, sweetheart.
I'm putting them to bed.
And I'm going home to sleep.
I don't need to keep everyone up.
Come on. Let's go to sleep.
Come talk to me.
- How much can you believe in dreams?
- Wait. Wrong.
Christopher did not have a dream.
A dream, I'd make my peace.
He was dead.
Science said he was dead. Science.
You need to talk to someone
who deals with this professionally.
What kind of thing?
He's in New York, Paulie.
In Nyack.
- His name's Cullen, a psychic.
- Get the fuck outta here.
He's famous for contacting
dead relatives for people.
He contacted my dead friend.
Remember Ronnie with the arm?
He knew about the fingers at the elbow,
and I didn't tell him.
He said, "Johnny is here."
I told him I didn't know any Johnnies.
But then he said, "Well, one arm
is shorter than the other.
Does that mean anything to you?"
Ronnie. It was Ronnie.
Jesus. A fucking creep show.
You got nothing to lose
except the nightmares.
- What's up, yo? Paulie around?
- No.
Sil?
What the fuck? I'm here.
You talk to me. You got something?
You better remember me, man.
Yeah, I will. Now you got something?
All right.
Hacklebarney State Park.
Where the "George Washington
slept here" house is.
Up that road, there's a gray house.
Bevilaqua's there?
Twenty bucks, baby.
Now, are you telling me that's
who you are or that's who he is?
I see.
Right.
The spirit put him on hold.
Do you take the name Gregory?
My father.
I understand now. You're Gregory.
This is your son.
- Is your name Daniel?
- Yes.
Because I got this image
of Daniel in the lion's den.
He says you found his body.
Oh, my God.
He's sorry.
He knows how traumatic that was.
He couldn't take the pain anymore.
Gregory, I'm sorry.
Could you repeat that?
He wants you to know...
...that he was there with you
and that you should move on.
Yes, go ahead.
What's the problem?
- What the hell's the matter?
- No, please, go on.
He can't hurt you. Don't be afraid.
I understand. Yes.
I feel your anger.
- Who the fuck are you talking to?
- Charles.
Yes, yes. You have a son.
- You're with your son?
- What the fuck? I don't got no kids!
Oh, Sonny.
- Pagano?
- Kind spirit, is your name Sonny?
Charles Pagano.
- How the fuck do you know that?
- He says he was your first.
But I feel many more.
- Hey!
- That one's laughing.
Poison ivy?
He wants to know if it still itches.
Who you been talking to?
You're gonna have to leave.
Why? What the fuck are they saying?
Do you really want me to say it?
Fuck you and this bullshit.
Because that's what this is, you know.
Satanic black magic. Sick shit.
I'm asking you to leave, sir.
Fucking queers!
When I made my appointment
I gave the name Ted Hughes.
Did you call him from your house?
I'm not a moron, T.
I knew this might be a scam...
...so I called him from a Pathmark.
There's no denying it.
I'm dragging a bunch
of fucking ghouls around with me.
And Mikey's their fucking ringleader.
Alright.
Paulie, think about it.
You whacked a lot of heavy hitters.
You think they'd join together
and follow that prick?
How can you just sit there?
He warned you about 3:00 too.
I don't believe any of this.
It doesn't mean a fucking thing to me.
T, I was ready to write
the whole thing off...
...until this psychic mentioned
Little Sonny Pagano.
But that? I don't know.
I did this guy over 30 years ago.
How the fuck did he know that?
Did you ask the fucking Ghostbuster
where Matt Bevilaqua is?
We're breaking our ass
trying to find him...
...and you're up there
fucking around in Nyack.
He deals only with the dead.
You eat steak?
The fuck you saying?
In India, you'd go to hell for that.
I'm not in India.
What do I give a fuck?
That's what I'm saying. None of
this shit means a goddamn thing.
I'm not hungry.
You mind if I eat in here?
I'm sorry for talking
to you the way I did.
It's okay.
No, it's not.
I was wrong.
I hope you know I didn't mean it.
I said it because all the anger
and the frustration...
...of the last few days
had built up inside me and exploded.
There's no excuse for that.
I gotta learn to control my emotions
around the people I love.
I think you're the same way.
I think...
...your feelings, you keep inside.
And you and me,
we react without thinking.
So I get mad at you, you know?
I see myself in you.
I couldn't ask for a better son, AJ.
And I mean that.
Thanks.
Want a piece of pizza?
Here.
Pussy's on the phone.
He says it's urgent.
- I been calling you all over.
- I'll be right there.
What's going on?
Nothing.
He's way the fuck out near Morristown.
In Hacklebarney State Park.
Over by that "George Washington
slept here" house?
Yeah.
Give me one.
You don't have to do this.
Furio and me are on it.
I want to do this.
Good.
Cut Furio loose. Three's a crowd.
Why don't you just take it easy?
We want to talk to you. That's all.
It wasn't me. It was Sean.
Just Sean.
You're shaking.
You're gonna fucking kill me
for something I didn't do.
Don't you think we could have
killed you already if we wanted to?
Relax.
We just want to talk to you.
It was Sean. You gotta believe me.
It was Sean. He got nuts.
He said we were pissed on, that we
should get in good with Richie.
But I told him,
"Hey, Rome wasn't built in one day."
Anything. I'll tell you
anything you want to know.
What did Richie say?
It had nothing to do with Richie.
He didn't ask for it.
He got mad when I told him.
Sean did it on spec.
All right.
Come here.
Come here. Come on.
Are you sure nobody else was involved?
Take a minute. Think it over.
It was Sean all the way.
All right.
You're a good kid.
I'm thirsty.
See if we got something to drink.
What can I get you?
You want a Fanta?
Something like that?
Here.
How is that?
You sure you want a diet drink?
You don't want something with sugar?
There's only diet.
It's good.
You finished?
Thank you, T.
That sugarless motherfucker was
the last fucking drink you'll have.
Mommy! Mommy!
Please, Tony. Please!
Twenty-three years
of donations...
...and this guy sees
this hanging over me?
You shouldn't have seen a psychic.
It's divination, the devil...
...and completely unsanctioned
by the Church.
Psychics are heretics and thieves
who practice witchcraft.
There's no validity
to anything he told you.
- Your problem's a spiritual matter.
- Maybe.
But irregardless, I should've
had immunity to all of this shit.
I should have been covered
by my donations.
When the organ needed a reed job,
who was there?
When the priests and altar boys needed
new whites, who picked up the tab?
You should've come to me first.
This wouldn't have happened.
But don't worry, Paul.
I'm here. I can help you.
It's too late.
You been slacking off on me.
You left me unprotected.
I'm cutting you off for good.
You ain't never gonna see
another dime from me.
A rich man and a poor man
got the same anniversary.
They always meet on Madison Avenue,
shopping for their wives.
Poor man asks,
"What'd you buy your wife?"
Rich man says, "I got her a huge
diamond ring and a brand-new Benz."
Poor man says,
"Why'd you get her both?"
Rich man says:
"If she don't like
the diamond ring...
...she can bring it back in the Benz
and still be happy."
Rich man says to the poor,
"What'd you get your wife?"
He says, "I got her a pair
of slippers and a dildo."
Rich man says,
"Why'd you get her both?"
Poor man says, "She don't like the
slippers she can go fuck herself."
- Can I get another Heineken?
- Sure.
Remember when you first
brought me here?
Yeah, I remember.
Popped my cherry that night.
Yeah. It seems like old times.
Puss...
...you believe in God?
Yeah, I do, Ton. Absolutely.
Works in very mysterious ways,
His wonders to perform. But no doubt:
He's been very good to me.
- Salute.
Hi.
Hey.
How you doing?
Fine.
You?
Good.
Yeah?
I've been thinking.
What?
I'll do it.
You'll do what?
Snip-snip.
I don't want you to do it, Tony.
No, you want me to do it.
And now I want to do it.
So...
...we'll do it.
I started thinking.
Meadow is leaving soon.
I may want to have another baby.
Maybe.
What, are you trying
to drive me fucking crazy?
What's behind all this?
Ralphie Ritaldo with his goomar,
the vasectomy, no vasectomy, now this.
What? Now you don't want me cut?
Tony.
All I want is you.
That's all I have ever wanted.
And I want you to be true
and to be mine.
I want you to not cheat.
- I will be true, Carm, from now...
- No, Tony, please.
Well, if you're not gonna
believe me, then fine.
But what can I do?
I don't know.
No.
What can I do?
Prove it to me.