Two guys...
A Russian and some...
Some kind of oriental.
Drove a late model Cadillac.
I didn't get the license.
Ahh.
You ready?
Oh, you betcha.
Come on.
This is a true story.
A 150-year-old bank
with $60 billion in
assets collapses overnight.
Its stock price drops
93% in eight hours.
One day, it's solvent,
the next, it's worthless.
Perception of reality becomes reality.
Another true story.
The First World War was
started by a sandwich.
On June 28th, 1914,
Gavrilo Princip, one
of seven conspirators,
failed to blow up the
Archduke of Austria
with a hand grenade.
Demoralized, Gavrilo stopped for lunch
at Schiller's delicatessen
on Franz Joseph Street in Sarajevo.
But as he was eating,
the Archduke's driver, lost,
pulled up outside the
restaurant and stopped.
Fate had delivered
Gavrilo's target to him
and he would not miss twice.
One last story, also true.
Here men from the Planet Earth
first set foot upon the moon.
July 1969 A.D.
I guess you're about
the only person around
that doesn't have TV
coverage of the scene.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
Cut!
Wait.
What?
It was a sound stage in New Mexico.
That's not...
That never happened.
"Let each man say what he deems truth
and let truth itself
be commended unto God."
Emmit, are you gonna...
The point is, Stussy Lots Ltd.
Are in the process of securing
$50 million in new loans.
Now, we're gonna use that
money to buy 16 more lots,
after paying some healthy bonuses
to the partners, of course.
You're talking about
doubling the size of the
company in six months?
- Three months.
- It's a lot of debt.
And just to line our
pockets? Shouldn't we...
I'm just sayin', a more
cautious approach. Why not?
Because the shallow end of the pool
is where the turds float.
Emmit?
No one ever got anywhere
staying home, Sy.
What does that mean?
It means, we're either doing this,
or we're not doing it.
Whether you step off the
board with one foot or two,
you still end up in the water.
Okay. But what about the IRS?
You said yourself, he's sitting
in the conference room right now,
going over the books.
Some books, not "the" books.
What the heck does that mean?
Let's just say for testimonial purposes,
it's better that you don't know.
Oh, you think the IRS
won't... This is what they do.
Catch cheats.
Middle managers and movie stars,
people who park their money
in a Denver Wells Fargo
under their mother-in-law's maiden name.
But I assure you,
the IRS could not
unravel an intricate web
of shell companies and
loan-outs with secret accounts
in Monaco, Luxembourg,
and the Cook Islands,
if you gave them the account numbers.
What?
I'm beginning to think that
finance is more of a hobby with you.
Just how are we supposed to...
It's already done.
I've even seeded in the odd
100K as an act of good faith.
Emmit, you wanna...
Your problem, Mr. Feltz, is you think
you started a parking lot company.
You started a bank.
This is a true story.
When I'm done with you,
they'll be sponging you off the floor.
Yeah? You'll be in the poor house
making soup out of your dirty socks.
Bigger the bank, the safer the banker.
So, the IRS?
Leave the IRS to me.
Section 41C of the US tax code
affords my client the right
to licensed representation
in the face of any IRS inquiry.
As counsel, I'm filing here
with you an official protest
to this baseless and cockeyed inquiry,
and demand you withdraw immediately
and file by mail
the statutory-required 30-day notice
listing the exact documents you require
and personnel you wish to interview.
Until that time, we demand
you vacate our offices.
Immediately.
Third fella.
Could be the head honcho.
No.
Why not?
Baby, trust me.
I want payback, maybe
even more than you.
But we gotta wait.
Babe, shouldn't we...
I'm worried you've
got internal injuries.
I'm fine.
I'm just saying, drop
in to the emergency room,
let 'em take a look.
You said yourself, the
cops are looking for me.
And these fellas, the villains,
probably watching the hospital.
I don't like it.
He's into something, your brother.
I got the sense from his lawyer, Feltz,
that it may be involuntary.
Meaning, against his will.
So, you sayin'...
What are you sayin'?
Some shady dealings.
Guys like your brother, fat cats,
making secret moves,
looking for quick returns.
What do they care if
a wad is legit or not?
Didn't you say he was having
money trouble a while back?
In the crash, yeah.
Business like theirs, real estate,
with the mortgage collapse.
He never said so, Emmit,
but I think he was worried.
So, what does he do?
He goes to the bank, tries to borrow.
But we know from the
news, they're not lending.
A loan shark?
On that level they
call 'em something else.
Private equity.
But a shark in a suit is still a shark.
We got any more aspirin?
Those fellas are lucky you held me back.
No one puts a finger on my woman
- and gets away with it.
- Easy, baby.
You'll get your chance.
But first, we gotta know the play.
Yeah.
Right this way.
Mr. Stussy, these ladies
are here to see you.
Oh, yeah?
Gloria Burgle.
Hi. Winnie Lopez.
- Would you like to sit down?
- Yeah, thanks.
What's this about?
I'm, uh, chief of Eden Valley.
- Out near Paynesville.
- Right.
And, uh, Officer Lopez
is from here in St. Cloud.
I was in the other night
talking to your Mr. Feltz
about a traffic skirmish
involving a company car.
Well, I'm... Sure. I mean,
Sy's the man to help you there.
I don't know how I could, uh...
Moshi-moshi.
I'm sorry, I couldn't
help but overhearin', uh...
This sounds like my area of expertise,
if you like to talk in my office?
That's... I got it.
Don't trouble yourself.
There's no trouble. I
know how busy you are.
So, what are we talking about here?
I didn't get your name?
True.
This is Mister, uh...
I'm an associate of Mr. Stussy's
is all you need to know for now.
Associate in what capacity?
Ladies shoes.
We'll come back to that.
Mr. Stussy, have you seen
your brother recently?
- My...
- Raymond.
No, I know his name. I just...
I thought this was
about a traffic accident.
In a way.
Well, it either is,
or it isn't, isn't it?
Turns out the traffic
accident I was in for previous
- is connected to a homicide.
- We think.
A homicide?
Yes, sir, that's my case.
Uh, victim ran a grocery
store in Eden Valley
about 30 miles south
of here, Ennis Stussy.
I read that in The
Tribune, the old fella.
What'd he die with, again?
His mouth and nose were glued shut.
Christmas.
Also, the house was ransacked
in search of what, we're not yet sure.
But, as of yesterday,
we pinned the crime
on an ex-convict named Maurice LeFay.
This is from hard evidence,
fingerprints and the like.
Turns out your brother
was his parole officer.
- Ray?
- Yes, sir.
And that got us wondering,
especially since Mr. Stussy, Raymond,
his car got rammed
into by another vehicle
registered to your company and...
Allegedly, words exchanged between Ray
and a yet-to-be-identified
member of your team.
- My team?
- Yes, sir.
And we thought it curious
the house being targeted
and searched as it was
that he shared the same last
name as you and your brother.
The same first initial.
Lived in towns with similar names.
What are they...
Is there some kind of
feud between you and Ray?
A feud? No.
'Cause we had your
brother into the station,
asked him the same
question, and he said...
Well, I mean...
Okay, we had our
differences over the years.
Who hasn't?
Brothers and all, but
nothing like a feud.
May I?
What exactly is the
connection, in your mind,
between Emmit's alleged
brother and the victim?
His alleged?
Are you suggesting
somehow Ray Stussy isn't...
It's your story, Detective.
I'm merely looking for clarification.
Chief, not detective.
My apologies.
My point is,
all this sounds like mere surmise.
Two brothers, a traffic skirmish,
a dead man in another county.
Mere what?
All named Stussy.
You see, in 1932 there were, what,
24 Hitlers in a German phone book.
Now, are you suggesting
that they were all responsible
for the Final Solution?
Twenty-four, exactly?
Sir, was there some kind of disagreement
over money between you and your brother?
Or if not money,
something he wanted back?
- Reason we ask is...
- Mmm-mmm.
You're saying...
My brother was trying to rob me?
All right. Look.
I'd like to thank you
for bringing all this to our attention.
And to assure you that
if anything fruitful comes to mind,
any details that you
might find illuminating,
then we'll make sure
to bring them to your
attention, all right?
Are we leaving?
Yes, you are. Come on.
If you think of anything.
Thanks. Thank you.
So, Eden Valley, is it a nice town?
We got a Tastee Freez and a Dairy Queen.
Will wonders never cease? Come on.
Seems like your brother's
got a backbone after all.
There is a police station
in Eden Valley with no computers.
I'd like to take a look at a case file.
One or two?
Just Yuri.
I think keep a low profile.
Now, the victim's name is...
Stussy. Same as our benefactor.
- Quiet or loud?
- Quiet.
I'm trying to contain
something, not expand it.
Stay the course for me?
Put an ear to this
Goldfarb meeting tonight?
They're on for 6:00.
Now...
I want you to find the brother,
this Ray character, and his bitch.
Execute?
Got anything back there?
Nope, it's all locked up back here.
Come back tomorrow.
Hon?
Heat's on. We better blow.
Okay, come on.
Ray, slow up.
Sorry, babe. We should
get off the street.
I know a motel where they take cash.
Good boy.
- All right?
- Yeah.
- Okay?
- Uh-huh.
I think I'm gonna
need you to round me up
some more aspirin, babe.
Maybe a cold compress.
Thought I could tough it
out, but I guess I'm a wimp.
Baby, please.
That beating that you took...
I swear to God, if those
guys were here, I...
Cash only, remember.
For the aspirin. They can
track the cards, the cops.
I know. I just gotta...
I, uh, used my last
20 for the room. So...
What about the sack from the bank?
There's still a few
thousand in that, right?
Ray.
Tell me you brought the getaway money.
It's just that we...
It happened so fast.
Ray, we need that money.
I know.
I mean, if it were just
the underworld types,
but with the law enforcement
on our ass, we're...
- I know, I'm going.
- You want me to go?
No, I'm fine.
Ray.
I got it.
You win.
I'm done.
Whatever you want, just tell me.
I co-signed the mortgage,
you think I don't have a key?
Came for my money.
The Dalmatian at the bank.
You poured her in the trash, the dog.
I got it for Grace when she was seven.
Laverne. She didn't live that long.
Car got her, but we'd grown attached.
I was looking for my stamp.
You know, I was thinking
about her on the way over.
I can't think of a single
person doesn't like me.
Except you.
That's what they say to your face.
No. Ray, I'm a fair man.
I treat people honestly.
- Help 'em when they're down.
- Them you help.
When did I not help you, kid?
Everything you asked.
Co-signing the mortgage,
repairs for the car.
I'm not less than you.
Some child that needs...
Ray, come on.
We've done this already.
Been doing it for 20 years. Enough.
It's finished, okay?
Words said in anger, crimes committed...
We've both done things.
It's a certain madness, I think.
Brotherhood.
Buttons you push in
me, that I push in you.
Grudges...
But I don't want that anymore.
So...
I'm giving you the stamp.
Well, you're not giving it to me.
No. I am.
You can't give me what
was mine from the start.
Okay.
No, that's...
Take it.
It's yours.
I said take it.
I don't want it.
Take the damn stamp.
Stop!
Take it!
Don't. Don't.
Jesus.
Emmit.
Ray.
Raymond?
Mr. Stussy.
Do you know what Lenin
said about Beethoven's
Piano Sonata Number 23?
Vladimir Ilyich Ulyanov.
Not the bloody walrus.
He said, "I know nothing
that is greater than the Appassionata,
but I cannot listen too often.
It affects one's nerves,
and makes one
want to say kind, stupid things,
and stroke the heads of those
who, living in such a foul hell,
can create such beauty.
Better to beat the person
unmercifully over the head."
Where are you, Mr. Stussy?
There's been an accident.
Things of consequence
rarely happen by accident.
Can you come?
Give me the address and
I'll leave immediately.
I'm at Ray's.
Did anyone see you?
I'm so rarely seen,
maybe I don't even exist.
What's he doing here?
You called for help.
This is what help looks like.
I wanted to find his
pulse, but I was afraid.
Afraid you'd leave fingerprints?
Where else might we
find your fingerprints?
Uh, I came in that door.
So, the knob, inside and out.
That frame, the glass.
Bury the body, missing person?
No.
Collect the frame and the stamp,
and leave the glass.
Is there someplace you're
supposed to be right now?
Uh, what time is it?
A meeting, a dinner.
Which is it, a meeting or a dinner?
Uh, dinner.
With whom?
- Sy.
- Which restaurant?
Uh, it's in my phone.
Never mind, never mind.
Listen, this is important.
If the restaurant has a back door,
go to the bathroom
and wash your face and
hands in very cold water,
then go to the table.
That way, if any witnesses see you,
they won't be able to time your arrival.
Do you understand?
Yeah, but...
Emmit.
Look at me.
- Are you listening?
- Yeah.
Your brother
was killed by his ex-convict girlfriend.
He'd been abusing her, you see?
Beating her in places you don't show.
And tonight she'd had
enough, so she cut his throat.
And watched him bleed.
Now,
the police will contact you tonight
to inform you of his death.
Be upset, not too upset.
Volunteer nothing, you
haven't seen him for days,
you haven't spoken to him.
I called him on his cell.
- When?
- Yesterday.
Right. Well, there'll
be a record of that.
Did you speak for long?
Just a few minutes.
All right. Well, it's just a quick call,
just to catch up, innit?
Be vague.
I didn't mean to...
No one ever does.
Walk him to his car, out in the back.
Make sure you're not seen.
Nothing like a feud.
Will wonders never cease?
Go figure. It's a pretty common name.
- There's jealousy there.
- Ladies shoes.
Screw it.
St. Cloud Metro, this
is Eden Valley One.
Go ahead, Eden Valley.
Yeah, I'm trying to get a
message to Officer Lopez.
Tell her I'm heading
back to the PO's domicile.
Have her meet me there.
Will do.