[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICH IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[trumpet playing]
(male narrator, off)
JOEY CROWN, MUSICIAN
WITH AN ODD, INTENSE FACE,
WHOSE LIFE IS A QUEST
FOR IMPOSSIBLE THINGS.
LIKE FLOWERS IN CONCRETE,
OR LIKE TRYING TO PLUCK
A NOTE OF MUSIC OUT
OF THE AIR
AND PUT IT UNDER
GLASS TO TREASURE.
[music stops,
applause]
HI, JOEY!
HI, BARON!
LISTEN, I, UH--
I BROUGHT ALONG
MY BABY,
I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT NEED
SOMEBODY WITH A HORN.
UH, NOT TONIGHT, JOEY.
THE LAST TIME YOU
PLAYED TRUMPET FOR ME,
YOU LOUSED IT UP.
I HAD TO SHARE
YOU WITH A BOTTLE.
A BOTTLE? ME?
I FORGOT WHAT
THE STUFF TASTES LIKE.
SIX, SEVEN MONTHS,
I'M WAY UP ON
THE WAGON.
SURE, JOEY, SURE.
WHAT AM I?
SOME KIND
OF KOOK?
LOOK, BARON, I KNOW
WHAT THAT STUFF
DOES TO ME, BUT--
I AIN'T AN OLD MAN.
ME AND THE HORN,
WE GOT A LOT OF
YEARS LEFT.
I COULD BE A
NUMBER ONE BOY.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
CHUCK IT AWAY ON
SOME BUM HAB IT?
LISTEN, I--
IT'S A PRETTY
MELLOW HORN.
I GOT SOME NICE
MUSIC IN HERE.
YOU KNOW YOURSELF,
WHEN I PICK IT UP
AND I BLOW IT,
I CAN MAKE 'EM CRY!
WHAT DO
YOU SAY, BARON?
DON'T DO IT.
FOR OLD TIMES,
JOEY, HUH?
FOR OLD TIMES
WHEN YOU HAD IT.
A MAGIC HORN.
HARRY JAMES
AND MAX KAMINSKY,
AND BUTTERFIELD,
A LITTLE B IT OF
ALL OF 'EM, BABY!
YOU TRADED IT OFF
FOR SOME BAD HOOCH
AND YOU GOT TOOK.
YOU GOT THE CRUMMY
END OF THE STICK!
WHY, JOEY, WHY?
BECAUSE I'M SAD,
BECAUSE I'M NOTHING,
BECAUSE I'LL LIVE AND DIE
IN A CRUMMY ONE-ROOMER
WITH DIRTY WALLS
AND CRACKED PIPES.
I'LL NEVER EVEN
HAVE A GIRL.
I'LL NEVER BE ANYBODY.
HALF OF ME
IS THIS HORN.
I CAN'T EVEN
TALK TO PEOPLE, BARON,
'CAUSE THIS HORN,
THAT'S HALF MY LANGUAGE.
BUT WHEN I'M DRUNK, BARON,
OH, WHEN I'M DRUNK, BOY,
I DON'T SEE
THE DIRTY WALLS
OR THE CRACKED PIPES,
I DON'T KNOW
THE CLOCK'S GOING,
THAT THE HOU RS
ARE GOING BY,
'CAUSE THEN I'M GABRIEL.
OH, I'M--I'M GABRIEL
WITH A GOLDEN HORN.
AND WHEN I PUT IT
TO MY LIPS, IT--
COMES OUT JEWELS.
IT COMES OUT A SYMPHONY--
COMES OUT THE SMELL OF--
OF FRESH FLOWERS IN SUMMER.
COMES OUT BEAUTY.
BEAUTY.
WHEN I'M DRUNK, BARON.
ONLY WHEN I'M DRUNK.
JUST PLAIN ORDINARY NOTHING.
OH, MAN, I'M--
I'M TIRED
OF HANGING AROUND.
[melancholy melody]
[high squeaky note]
[repeats melody]
(male narrator)
JOEY CROWN, MUSICIAN
WITH AN ODD, INTENSE FACE,
WHO IN A MOMENT
WILL TRY TO LEAVE
THE EARTH
AND DISCOVER
THE MIDDLE GROUND,
THE PLACE WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
BACK AGAIN, HUH, JOEY?
HI, NATE.
THIS TIME
I'M SELLING IT.
EIGHT AND A HALF.
EIGHT AND A
HALF--? ALRIGHT.
EIGHT AND A HALF.
SIGN IT.
I GOT ENOUGH
INSTRUMENTS NOW TO
EQUIP SOUSA'S BAND.
I NEED ANOTHER BUGLE
LIKE I NEED MY
TAXES RAISED.
[cash register rings]
DON'T WORRY,
I AIN'T GETTIN'
THAT PRICE SO FAST.
I GOT AN OVERHEAD
TOO, YOU KNOW!
GUYS LIKE YOU, YOU
DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT.
WHAT KIND
OF RESPONSIBILITIES
SOMEBODY LIKE YOU GOT, HM?
NOTHIN', NOTHIN' AT ALL.
YEAH.
NOTHIN'.
NOTHIN' AT ALL.
NO RESPONSIBILITIES.
NO NOTHING.
[truck horn blares]
LOOK, OFFICER,
I ASSURE YOU,
I'M NOT WHAT YOU
WOULD CALL DRUNK,
YOU SEE.
YOU CAN ASK
OFFICER FLAHERTY WHO'S
USUALLY ON THIS BEAT.
WHY, HE'LL TELL YOU
I'M NOT
THE KIND OF GUY
THAT RUNS AROUND--
EXCUSE ME, BUDDY,
YOU HAPPEN TO
HAVE A--?
EXCUSE ME, PAL,
YOU HAPPEN TO
HAVE A MATCH?
I SAID YOU HAPPEN
TO HAVE A MATCH.
MOVIES BETTER
THAN EVER?
LOOK, LADY,
[unintelligible],
BUT, YOU SEE,
I KNOW THE GIRL THAT
USUALLY WORKS HERE, GRACIE.
I WAS GONNA TELL
HER WHAT HAPPENED TO ME.
THIS BIG TRUCK
AND I, WE TANGLED,
AND THE FIRST THING
I KNEW I WAS--
LOOK, AT LEAST YOU CAN
BE A LITTLE COURTEOUS,
I MEAN--
LOOK AT ME!
NOW, LOOK.
NOW, LISTEN.
SOMEBODY'S TRYING
TO PULL A GAG.
TO SHAKE ME UP.
NOW, LOOK, MISS.
PLEASE, SOMETHING'S
GOING ON, SOMEBODY
TRYING TO PULL--
LOOK, FELLOW,
YOU HAPPEN TO
HAVE A LIGHT?
[relieved]
OH.
I'M DEAD.
THAT'S IT.
I'M JUST PLAIN
OLD DECEASED.
HEY, I'M A GHOST.
YOU KNOW, THAT TRUCK
MADE IT AFTER ALL.
I'M HAUNTING YOU.
I'M A GH--BOOJIE, BOOJIE!
WELL, AT LAST.
FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN THE VERY SHORT
LIFE OF JOEY CROWN--
HE WAS SUCCESSFUL
AT SOMETHING.
CHARLIE'S OFF, HUH?
YOU DON'T HEAR
ME EITHER, DO YOU?
NOBODY HEAR ME?
ANYBODY SEE ME?
I USED TO COME
IN HERE A LOT.
OF COURSE, I DON'T
RECOGNIZE ANY OF
YOU PEOPLE.
NONE OF YOU OF
COURSE WOULDA
NOTICED ME.
I MEAN, UH--YOU DON'T
HEAR ME EITHER, DO YOU?
I'M NOT THE KIND
OF GUY YOU WOULD NOTICE.
WELL, CHARLIE,
EVERY NOW AND THEN
HE USED TO GIVE
ME A DRINK ON
THE HOUSE.
HE WAS A NICE GUY, CHARLIE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
HE DID ONE TIME?
YOU KNOW WHAT HE DID?
CHARLIE WENT OUT AND--
AND BOUGHT AN OLD
TOM MY DORSEY RECORD
FROM WAY BACK--
WHEN I WAS
PLAYI NG WITH HIM--
AND ON THIS
RECORD THERE WAS A--
THERE WAS
A LONG SINGER
WITH ME ON THE HORN.
OLD CHARLIE GOES
AND ORDERS IT.
LIKE A BIG
SURPRISE FOR ME.
PUTS IT
ON THE JUKE.
[tsk]
WOULD YOU
BELIEVE IT?
A NICE THING
LIKE THAT FROM
OLD CHARLIE.
WHEN I WAS ALIVE.
[fast trumpet
band music]
[thud]
[perfect trumpet music]
HEY, DON'T STOP,
IT'S--IT'S COMING
OUT BEAUTIFUL.
THANKS.
THAT'S ALRIGHT.
YOU SAID THANKS.
THANKS.
YOU HEAR ME?
I HEAR YOU.
YOU SEE ME?
VERY CLEARLY.
OH, YOU'RE A
GHOST TOO, HUH?
[chuckIes]
NOT REALLY.
I AM. I
STEPPED IN FRONT
OF A RATHER LARGE
VEHICLE THIS MORNING,
I [unintelligible],
BELIEVE ME.
YOU WANNA BLOW THIS
A WHILE, JOEY?
YEAH.
YEAH, I'D LIKE TO.
YOU MIND?
WHATEVER YOU LIKE.
JOEY? YOU
CALLED ME JOEY.
JOEY CROWN,
THAT'S THE NAME,
ISN'T IT?
YEAH, THAT'S
MY NAME BUT--
WE AIN'T NEVER
BEEN INTRODUCED.
NOT FORMALLY
BUT I KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
YOU PLAY
A NICE TRUMPET.
I KNOW,
I'M AN EXPERT
ON TRUMPETS.
YOU AIN'T NO SLOUCH
ON IT, THAT'S
FOR SURE.
WELL, GO AHEAD.
OKAY.
[previous melancholy tune]
[previousIy squeaky
high note, perfect]
HOW COME
YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
YOU SAY YOU'RE
NOT A GHOST,
YOU'RE NOT DEAD.
NO, I'M NOT DEAD.
NEITHER ARE YOU, JOEY.
I'M NOT?
BY NO MEANS.
BUT--WHAT ABOUT
THE PEOPLE IN
THE BAR?
THE GIRL IN
THE TICKET BOOTH
AND THE PEOPLE
IN THE STREETS?
THEY ARE DEAD.
THEY'RE THE GHOSTS, THEY
JUST DON'T KNOW IT,
THAT'S ALL.
SOMETIMES TO MAKE IT EASIER,
WE HAVE TO WORK IT
THAT WAY.
WE LET THEM GO ON IN
A LIFE THAT THEY'RE
FAMILIAR WITH.
THEY NEVER KNOW
FOR A LONG WHILE.
BUT THAT'S WHY
THEY COULDN'T HEAR YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT'S ALIVE.
BUT LIKE I SAID,
I STEPPED OFF
A CURB--
THAT YOU DID.
RIGHT NOW YOU'RE IN
A KIND OF A LIMBO, JOEY.
YOU'RE NEITHER
HERE NOR THERE.
YOU'RE IN THE MIDDLE.
BETWEEN THE TWO.
THE REAL
AND THE SHADOW.
WHICH DO YOU
PREFER, JOEY?
WHICH DO I PREFER?
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
I ALWAYS FELT
I WAS GETTING
DEALT FROM THE BOTTOM.
OR MAYBE, MAYBE
I JUST FORGOT HOW
MUCH THERE WAS FOR ME.
AND MAYBE I
FORGOT ABOUT--
ABOUT THE MUSIC THAT
I COULD MAKE ON
THIS HORN.
AND HOW NICE
IT SOUNDED.
AND GOING
INTO CHARLIE'S--
AND TALKING
TO PEOPLE--
AND MAYBE GOING TO
A MOVIE NOW AND
THEN, HUH?
YOU KNOW, I NEVER WON
A BEAUTY CONTEST BUT--
YOU KNOW, I HAD FRIENDS,
I MEAN, I HAD GOOD ONES.
GOOD ONES.
YEAH, SOMEWHERE ALONG
THE LINE I JUST FORGOT
ALL THE GOOD THINGS.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
I JUST FORGOT.
YOU'VE GOT
A CHOICE,
YOU KNOW.
A CHOICE?
THERE'S STILL TIME.
WELL, IF I'VE
GOT A CHOICE,
I MEAN, IF I'VE
GOT A CHOICE--
THEN I WANNA GO BACK.
UNDERSTAND? I
WANNA GO BACK!
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GO BACK.
BUT JOEY,
NO MORE STEPPING
OFF CURBS.
TAKE WHAT YOU GET
AND YOU LIVE
WITH IT.
SOMETIMES IT'S
SWEET FROSTING,
NICE GRAVY.
SOMETIMES IT'S SOUR, IT
GOES DOWN HARD, BUT YOU
LIVE WITH IT.
YEAH, IT'S A NICE
TALENT YOU GOT.
TO MAKE MUSIC,
TO MOVE PEOPLE.
MAKE 'EM WANNA LAUGH,
MAKE 'EM WANNA CRY.
THEY CAN TAP THEIR FEET.
MAKE 'EM WANNA DANCE.
THAT'S AN EXCEPTIONAL
TALENT, JOEY.
DON'T WASTE IT.
SEE YOU AROUND, JOEY.
HEY!
HEY, MISTER!
WHAT IS IT, JOEY?
I DIDN'T GET
YOUR NAME!
HOW'S THAT?
YOU R NAME!
I DIDN'T GET
MY NAME?
CALL ME GABE.
GABE?
GABE!
SHORT FOR GABRIEL.
GOODBYE, JOEY.
[distant trumpet playing]
[truck horn blares]
[tires screech]
[thud]
[woman screams]
[murmurs]
(driver)
I DIDN'T
SEE YOU, PAL.
YOU STEPPED
RIGHT OUT IN
FRONT OF ME.
LUCKY I ONLY
GRAZED YOU.
OH, THAT'S OKAY,
NO HARM DONE.
YEAH, NOW LOOK.
I AIN'T HAD
AN ACCIDENT
FOR 14 YEARS,
AND I'D BE OBLIGED
TO YOU IF YOU, UH--
WELL, YOU KNOW,
NO DOCTORS, NO
INSURANCE COMPANIES,
NOTHING LIKE
THAT, HUH?
BE A NICE
GUY, HUH, PAL?
[thud and engine
revvs, becomes distant]
[trumpet playing pleasantly]
YOU PLAY
IT BEAUTIFULLY.
THANKS.
I GAVE IT UP
THIS MORNING BUT--
I'M TAKING HER BACK.
THE BUGLE AND ME,
TILL DEATH DO
US PART.
I'M NEW HERE.
I'VE--I'VE NEVER EVEN
BEEN IN NEW YORK BEFORE.
I JUST MOVED IN.
MY NAME IS NAN.
HI. I'M JOEY.
JOEY CROWN.
WILL YOU--PLAY
SOME MORE?
SURE.
I'LL PLAY
WHATEVER YOU LIKE
FOR AS LONG
AS YOU LIKE.
YOU KNOW, YOU
MAY LIKE IT HERE.
IT'S NOT A BAD TOWN.
OH, I'M SURE
IT ISN'T.
MAYBE--
MAYBE YOU COULD
SHOW ME SOME
OF IT.
ME?
SURE. I'D LOVE TO. I--
WELL, I COULD SHOW
YOU THE BATTERY AND--
I COULD SHOW YOU
CENTRAL PARK,
I COULD SHOW
YOU 52ND. STREET!
WE COULD GO IN AND
LISTEN TO SOME GOOD
JAZZ! AND, UH--
(male narrator)
JOEY CROWN,
WHO MAKES MUSIC.
AND WHO DISCOVERED
SOMETHING ABOUT LIFE
THAT IT CAN BE
RICH AND REWARDING
AND FULL OF BEAUTY.
JUST LIKE
THE MUSIC HE PLAYED.
IF A PERSON WOULD
ONLY PAUSE TO LOOK
AND TO LISTEN.
JOEY CROWN, WHO GOT
HIS CLUE IN THE
TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male announcer)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK,
YOU'LL MEET
THE OCCUPANT
OF THIS DESK
WHOSE NAME IS
JAMES B.W. BEVIS,
A WARM AND WINNING
TWENTIETH CENTURY ODDBALL
ABOUT A MILE AND A
HALF FROM THE NORM.
HE LIKES THINGS LIKE
ZITHER MUSIC, LITTLE KIDS,
AND STUFF LIKE THIS.
ORSON BEAN
STARS NEXT WEEK ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
AS M R. BEVIS.
AND HENRY JONES
PLAYS HIS GUARDIAN ANGEL.
HE'S THIS KIND
OF ODDBALL.
[curtain music]
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH
STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE
SAME STATIONS.