[eerie music]
(narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[snoring]
IN THIS CORNER OF THE
UNIVERSE A PRIZEFIGHTER
NAMED BOLIE JACKSON.
ONE HUNDRED AND
EIGHTY-THREE POUNDS, AND
AN HOUR AND A HALF AWAY
FROM A COMEBACK
AT ST. NICK'S ARENA.
MR. BOLIE JACKSON,
WHO BY THE STANDARDS
OF HIS PROFESSION
IS AN AGING,
OVER-THE-HILL
RELIC OF WHAT WAS,
AND WHO NOW SEES A REFLECTION
OF A MAN WHO HAS LEFT TOO MANY
PIECES OF HIS YOUTH
IN TOO MANY STADIUMS
FOR TOO MANY YEARS
BEFORE TOO MANY
SCREAMING PEOPLE.
MR. BOLIE JACKSON,
WHO M IGHT DO WELL TO LOOK
FOR SOME GENTLE MAGIC
IN THE HARD-SURFACED GLASS
THAT STARES BACK AT HIM.
[crack]
FEELING GOOD, BOLI E?
FEELING SHARP?
TAKE THE TIG ER
TONIGHT, HUH, BOLI E?
I'M GONNA TAKE THE TIG ER,
HENRY. I'LL GIVE HIM A
LEFT THEN A RIGHT.
AND I'M GOING TO THE
STOMACH, THEN PICK HIM
U P BY THE TAI L
AND THROW HIM RIGHT UP
INTO THE N I NTHROW.
YOU'RE LOOKING
GOOD, BOLI E. YOU'RE
LOOKING SHARP.
YOU GONNA WATCH?
YOU FOOLING?
I'LL YELL SO LOU D
YOU'LL HEAR ME
ALL THE WAY TO
ST. N ICK'S.
[Iaughs]
YOU KNOW,
A FIGHTER DON'T NEED
A SCRAPBOOK, HENRY.
ANYONE KNOW
WHAT HE'S DONE,
WHERE HE'S FOUGHT,
YOUREAD IT
IN HIS FACE.
HE'S GOT THE WHOLE
STORY CUT INTO
HIS FLESH.
ST. LOU IS, 1 949.
GUY NAMED
SAI LOR LEVITT.
REAL FAST BOY.
HERE, AND THIS,
M EMORIAL STADI U M,
SYRACUSE, NEW YORK.
ITALIAN BOY.
FOUGHT LIKE
HENRY ARMSTRONG.
ALL HAN DS AND ARMS.
JUST LIKE A WIN DM I LL,
ALL OVER YOU.
FIRST TIME I EVER
GOT MY NOSE BROKE
TWICE IN ONE FIGHT.
AND THEN MOVE
SOUTH, HENRY.
M IAM I, FLORI DA.
THAT BOY GOT ME UP
AGAINST THE RING POST.
HE DID THIS
WITH HIS LACES.
TIRED OLD MAN.
TIRED OLD MAN
TRYING TO CATCH A BUS
AND THE BUS IS
ALREADY GON E.
LEFT A COUPLE
OF YEARS AGO.
ARMS H EAVY.
LEGS LIKE RU BBER.
SHORT OF WIN D.
ONE EYE ALMOST GON E.
THERE I GO,
RU N NING DOWN
THE STREET
TRYING TO CATCH
THAT BUS TO GLORY.
BOLI E, YOU ARE
GOING TO CATCH
THE TIG ER TONIGHT.
I'M GONNA MAKE A WISH.
I'M GONNA MAKE
A BIG, TALL WISH.
AND YOU AIN'T GON NA
GET H U RT NONE EITHER.
YOU HEAR, BOLI E?
YOU BEEN H U RT
ENOUGH ALREADY. AND
YOU'RE MY FRI EN D, BOLI E.
YOU'RE MY GOOD
AND CLOSE FRIEND.
YOU HAVE QU ITE A
BOY THERE, FRANCES.
YOU GOT QU ITE A BOY.
TALKS LIKE A LITTLE
OLD MAN, YOU KNOW?
I'M HIS GOOD AND CLOSE
FRI EN D. THAT'S WHAT
HE TELLS ME.
REAL, REAL I NTENSE.
I'M HIS GOOD AND
CLOSE FRI EN D.
WELL, YOU'RE GOOD
TO HIM, BOLI E.
REAL GOOD.
TAKING HIM TO BALL
GAM ES ALL THE TIME
AND TAKING
HIM FOR WALKS.
TAKE CARE OF
YOURSELF, BOLI E.
DON'T GET H U RT NON E.
I'LL WORK HARD
TRYING NOT TO.
[footsteps]
I'M GONNA MAKE
A WISH, BOLI E.
I'M GONNA MAKE A WISH
NOTHING HAPPENS TO YOU.
SO DON'T YOU
BE AFRAI D, BOLI E.
UNDERSTAND?
DON'T YOU BE AFRAI D.
OH, GO ON.
BOLI E, THAT BOY'S
GOT YOU IN A SH RIN E.
WHO? A SCARED OLD MAN WHO
DON'T REMEMBER NOTHING
EXCEPT HOW TO BLEED?
I DON'T F IT
NO SH RIN ES, FRANCES.
BUT YOU TELL
HIM, FRANCES,
YOU TELL HIM
HOW MUCH I'M OBLIGED
TO HIM FOR HIS WISH.
HE'S ALL THE
TIME WISHING.
WHY, JUST THE
OTHER NIGHT H E--
WHAT?
OH, I NEEDED $1 5
FOR THE RENT.
HENRY SAID HE WAS
GONNA MAKE THE BIG,
TALL WISH.
THAT'S THE BIGG EST WISH.
THE BIG, TALL WISH.
HE DON'T WASTE THAT
ON JUST ANYTHING.
THAT'S WHAT HE CALLS
THE MOST IMPORTANT KIND.
THAT WAS LAST FRI DAY.
AND A WOMAN I DID SOME
N U RSING FOR ON THE ISLAND
SENT ME A CHECK.
A CHECK FOR $1 5.
LITTLE BOYS.
LITTLE BOYS WITH
THEIR H EADS FU LL
U P WITH DREAMS.
AND WHEN DO THEY
F IN D OUT, FRANCES?
WHEN DO THEY
SU DDEN LY F IN D OUT
THAT THERE
AIN'T ANY MAG IC?
WHEN DOES SOMEBODY PUSH
THEIR FACE DOWN ON THE
SIDEWALK AND SAY TO 'EM,
"HEY, LITTLE BOY,
IT'S CONCRETE.
THAT'S WHAT THE WORLD
IS MADE OUT OF, CONCRETE."
WHEN DO THEY
F IN D OUT THAT YOU
CAN WISH YOUR LIFE AWAY?
GOOD LUCK
TONIGHT, BOLI E.
SURE, FRANCES.
WE'LL BE
WAITING FOR YOU.
TELL HIM I'LL
SEE HIM LATER.
HEY, BOLI E.
GOOD LUCK, BABY.
YOU CAN TAKE HIM.
TAKE HIM FOR ME.
BEST OF LUCK, BOLI E.
WE'LL BE WATCHING.
TRY IT, BOLI E.
FEELS OKAY?
FEELS GOOD, JOE. THANKS.
HE'S ALL READY.
BUTT IT OUT,
WILL YOU, THOMAS?
I WANNA BREATH E.
YOU H I RED ME
FOR THE NIGHT,
BOLI E BABY.
IT'S A PACKAG E DEAL.
ME AND THE CIGAR.
I SAID BUTT IT OUT.
[crowd yelling]
FE ISTY LITTLE OLD MAN.
THE OLDER THEY GET,
THE LOU DER THEY TALK
AND THE MORE THEY WANT.
AND THE LESS CHANCE
THEY GOT TO GET IT.
HOW DID I GET
YOU TONIGHT?
OH, I'M A
BARGAI N, BOLI E.
I'M A EXPERT
ON HAS-BEENS.
I SEEN YOUR BOYS.
CATCH ES, AREN'T THEY?
G UARANTEED TWO
ROU N DS EACH.
SHOVEL THEM I N,
SHOVEL THEM OUT.
SEW THEM TOGETHER
FOR THE NEXT TIME.
[chuckIes]
WELL, THAT'S
THE ONLY WAY
TO DO IT, CHAM P.
A MONTH OR SO FROM NOW
MAYBE I'LL SIGN YOU
AT THE BACK DOOR.
WHY NOT?
YOU'RE LONG
GON E, BOLI E.
YOU'VE HAD IT.
WAIT TILL AFTER TONIGHT.
YOU'LL WANNA GET
IN THE STABLE, TOO.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS GUARANTEE TWO ROU N DS.
TWO, THREE
PRELI MS EVERY MONTH.
WHY, YOU CAN DO THAT
STANDING ON YOUR H EAD.
CAN'T YOU?
I THOUGHT THE SM ELL
CAME WITH THE CIGAR.
YOU WEAR IT ALL OVER YOU.
YOU STIN K, THOMAS.
YOU TELL 'EM, CHAM P.
YOU TELL 'EM.
[man knocking]
JACKSON, TEN M INUTES.
HE'LL BE THERE.
WHAT ABOUT TONIGHT?
WHAT DO I WATCH OUT FOR?
I'VE ONLY SEEN THIS BOY
FIGHT ONCE. THAT WAS A
COUPLE OF YEARS AGO.
I AIN'T NEVER SEEN HIM.
YOU WATCH ED HIM FIGHT. YOU'VE
SEEN HIM FIGHT SIX, SEVEN
TIMES IN THE PAST YEAR.
YOU P I ECE
OF GARBAG E, YOU.
YOU'RE BETTING
ON HIM, AREN'T YOU?
IT AIN'T ENOUGH
HE SELLS FLESH
BY THE POU N D.
HE COMES IN HERE FOR A DIRTY
$20. SU PPOSED TO H ELP ME
AND BETS ON THE OTHER GUY.
I MAY BE A BUM UPSTAIRS
IN ANOTHER TEN MINUTES
BUT NOW I'M GONNA FIGHT
A BEAUTIFUL FIRST ROU N D.
YOU TOUCH ME AND
I'LL HAVE YOU UP
FOR TEN YEARS.
I SWEAR TO YOU, BOLI E,
I'LL F IX YOUR WAGON GOOD.
LAY OFF ME, YOU CU N NING FREAK!
LET ME LOOK
AT THAT. S IT DOWN.
WASN'T ENOUGH
SPOTTING 'EM ALL
THOSE YEARS, BOLI E?
WASN'T ENOUGH HOW YOU
GOTTA GO IN THE RING
WITH FOUR BUSTED KN UCKLES?
OKAY, JACKSON, YOU'RE ON.
WELL?
WELL, NOTHING.
LET'S DO IT.
OH, POOR LITTLE
HENRY TEM PLE.
I'VE GIVEN HIM
TWO STRI KES ON
ALL HIS MAG IC.
TWO STRI KES.
WHOSE?
NOTHING.
THERE AIN'T NO SUCH--
[groaning]
THERE AIN'T NO
SUCH THING AS MAG IC.
[people yelling]
[punching]
(announcer)
THERE'S ANOTHER LEFT.
ANOTHER RIGHT.
JACKSON'S KNEES ARE
WOBBLING. HE'S HURT.
BOLIE JACKSON IS
DEFINITELY HURT.
CONSIGLIO MOVES IN ON HIM.
[people cheer]
HE JABS HIM
TO THE RIGHT.
JACKSON IS DOWN.
BOLIE, BOLIE, BOLIE.
ON E, TWO, THREE,
FOU R, FIVE, SIX,
SEVEN, EIGHT,
[no audio]
N IN E.
[silence]
TEN.
[audience yelling]
YOU DONE DAN DY, BOLI E.
HEY, JOE,
YOU WERE WRONG.
JUST BRU ISED,
I GU ESS, HUH?
G EE, IT H U RT LIKE ANYTHING
BUT SOMEBODY SAID I
GOT HIM WITH IT.
COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
BROKEN AFTER ALL.
WHO SAID IT WAS?
YOU SAID.
J EEZ, FELT
LIKE IT, TOO.
COULD FEEL THE KN UCKLES
COMING RIGHT UP TO
THE BAN DAG ES.
I COULD HAVE SWORN
IT WAS BROKE.
AND THEN WHEN H E
KNOCKED ME DOWN--
WHAT? WHEN HE WHAT?
WHEN HE KNOCKED
ME DOWN, JOE.
WHEN HE KNOCKED ME DOWN.
I DON'T EVEN
REMEMBER GETTING UP.
THE NEXT THING I KNEW,
THERE HE WAS AT MY FEET.
WE MUST HAVE BEEN IN
DIFFERENT ARENAS TOGETHER.
YOU DIDN'T GET
KNOCKED DOWN, BOLI E.
YOU WAS NEVER
OFF YOUR FEET.
I WASN'T?
NO. YOU CARRI ED THIS
ONE ALL THE WAY, BABY.
[chuckIes]
JOE! I WASN'T
OFF MY FEET?
I DIDN'T GO DOWN?
READ ABOUT IT
IN THE PAPERS.
GOOD NIGHT, OLD-TIMER.
I'M PROU D OF YOU.
BEAUTIFUL, BOLI E,
BEAUTIFUL.
YOU WERE
JUST GREAT, MAN.
JUST WON DERFU L.
YOU WE GREAT, BOLI E,
WE'VE SEEN YOU ON
TELEVIS ION.
THAT WAS A RIGHT.
THAT WAS THE REAL RIGHT.
HEY, WHAT DO YOU
SAY, HENRY TEM PLE?
YOU ARE A TIG ER, BOLI E.
YOU ARE A REAL TIG ER.
DID IT LOOK OKAY?
JUST LIKE A CHAM P.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
THAT BOY MUST HAVE
H IT ME SO HARD
IT KNOCKED ALL THE
H U RT RIGHT OUT OF ME.
I DON'T REMEMBER
A DOGGONE THING, HENRY.
I MUST HAVE REALLY
BEEN PU NCHY FOR
A SECON D
'CAUSE I THOUGHT
HE HAD ME ON MY BACK.
AND THERE I WAS,
LYING THERE,
LOOKING UP
AT THE REF WAVING
HIS ARM DOWN ON ME,
STARING AT THE LIGHT,
BLIN KING MY EYES.
THERE MUST HAVE BEEN
SOME KIND OF A DREAM
OR SOMETHING 'CAUSE--
HENRY?
HENRY, IN EVER
WENT DOWN.
I WAS NEVER
OFF MY FEET.
HENRY, IN EVER
WENT DOWN.
HENRY, WAS I?
WAS I ON MY BACK
AND ON MY WAY OUT?
NOBODY REMEMBERS IT.
NOBODY AT ALL
EXCEPT ME.
I THOUGHT IT HAPPENED,
BUT IT DIDN'T.
I THOUGHT I WAS
LYING THERE ON MY
BACK, BEING COU NTED OUT,
AND EVERYBODY
TELLS ME THAT--
BOLI E, I MADE
THE BIG WISH THEN.
I WISHED YOU WAS
NEVER KNOCKED DOWN.
I JUST SHUT MY EYES,
AND I, I WISH ED REAL HARD.
IT WAS MAG IC, BOLI E.
WE HAD TO HAVE
MAGIC THEN.
HAD TO, BOLIE. NOTHING
LEFT FOR US THEN. HAD
TO MAKE A WISH.
THERE AIN'T NO MAG IC
OR WISHING OR NOTHING
LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE TOO BIG TO HAVE N UTSY
THOUGHTS. YOU'RE TOO BIG TO
BELIEVE IN FAIRY TALES.
IF YOU WISH HARD
ENOUGH, BOLI E,
IT'LL COME TRU E.
IF YOU WISH
HARD ENOUGH--
SOMEBODY GOTTA
KNOCK IT OUT OF YOU.
SOMEBODY GOTTA TAKE YOU
BY THE HAIR AND RU B YOUR
FACE INTO THE WORLD
TILL YOU GET THE TASTE AND
FEEL OF THE WAY THINGS
ARE, DON'T THEY?
LISTEN, KI D, I'VE BEEN
WISHING ALL MY LIFE.
YOU UNDERSTAND, HENRY?
I GOT A GUT ACH E
FROM WISHING,
AND ALL I GOT
TO SHOW FOR IT IS
A FACE FU LL OF SCARS
AND A H EAD FU LL
OF-OF MEMORI ES
OF ALL THE H U RT
AND M ISERY
I'VE HAD TO LIVE
AND SLEEP WITH ALL
MY MISERABLE LIFE.
CRAZY KI D, YOU TRYING
TO TELL ME YOU WISH ED
ME INTO A KNOCKOUT?
YOU TRYING TO TELL ME IT
WAS MAGIC THAT MADE ME
GET UP OFF MY BACK?
YOU'RE A LITTLE
KOOK, HENRY. THAT'S
WHAT YOU ARE.
HOW DID I EVER GET M IXED
U P WITH YOU? I AIN'T
GOT ENOUGH TROU BLE.
I GOT M IXED UP
WITH SOME DOPEY KI D--
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE,
BOLI E, IT WON'T BE TRU E.
THAT'S THE WAY MAGIC WORKS.
LISTEN. LISTEN, BOY.
THERE AIN'T NO MAG IC.
NO MAG IC, HENRY.
I HAD THAT FIGHT
COMING AND GOING.
I HAD IT IN MY POCKET.
I WAS THE NUMBER ONE OUT
THERE. IT WAS ME WHO DONE
IT. ME, BOLI E JACKSON.
H ITTI N' AND
SLUGG I N' AND WIN N I N'.
WIN N I N'!
HENRY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE.
I'M TOO OLD.
AND I'M TOO
H U RT TO BELIEVE.
I CAN'T, BOY.
I JUST CAN'T.
NOW, HENRY, THERE AIN'T
NO SUCH THING AS MAG IC.
GOD H ELP US BOTH.
I WISH THERE WERE.
BOLI E, YOU'VE
GOT TO BELIEVE.
I CAN'T, BOY.
YOU'VE GOT
TO BELIEVE.
I CAN'T.
PLEASE, BELIEVE.
YOU'VE GOT
TO BELIEVE, BOLIE.
TEN.
[audience yelling]
[audience cheers]
YOU SHOU LD'VE
STOOD IN BED.
HOW COME YOU
DI DN'T USE YOUR RIGHT?
HE'S IN BED, BOLI E.
CAN I SEE HIM?
SURE. I EXPECT
HE'S WAITING FOR YOU.
BOLI E?
I'M REAL SORRY.
AH, I PULLED
A ROCK, HENRY.
I TH REW A PU NCH
BEFORE I SHOU LD HAVE.
H IT A WALL.
BUSTED MY KN UCKLES.
I WENT IN WITH HALF
MY ARTILLERY GON E.
YOU LOOKED LIKE
A TIG ER EVEN SO.
A REAL TIG ER.
I WAS PROU D
OF YOU, BOLI E.
I WAS REAL PROU D.
BOLI E?
NOW YOU GO TO SLEEP.
TOMORROW WE'LL GO
TO A HOCKEY GAM E,
AND WE'LL GET
SOME HOT DOGS
IN THE PARK MAYBE.
SURE THING, BOLI E.
THAT WILL BE N ICE.
BOLI E?
I AIN'T GONNA MAKE
NO MORE WISH ES, BOLI E.
I'M TOO OLD FOR WISH ES.
AND THERE AIN'T
NO SUCH THING AS
MAG IC, IS THERE?
I GU ESS NOT, HENRY.
OR MAYBE--
MAYBE THERE IS MAG IC,
AND MAYBE THERE'S
WISH ES, TOO.
I GU ESS THE
TROU BLE IS--
I GU ESS THE TROU BLE IS
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH PEOPLE
AROUND TO BELIEVE.
GOOD NIGHT, BOY.
GOOD NIGHT, BOLI E.
(narrator)
MR. BOLIE JACKSON,
1 83 POUNDS,
WHO LEFT A SECOND
CHANCE LYING IN A HEAP
ON A ROSIN-SPATTERED
CANVAS AT ST. NICK'S ARENA.
MR. BOLIE JACKSON,
WHO SHARES THE MOST
COMMON AILMENT OF ALL MEN.
THE STRANGE AND PERVERSE
DISINCLINATION TO BELIEVE
IN A M IRACLE,
THE KIND OF M IRACLE
TO COME FROM THE M IND
OF A LITTLE BOY.
PERHAPS ONLY TO BE FOUND
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR OF
TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
G REETINGS FROM
THE LOW-RENT DISTRICT.
NEXT WEEK WE FOLLOW THE
FORTU N ES AND M ISFORTU N ES
OF MR. LARRY BLYDEN,
WHO PLAYS THE ROLE
OF ONE ROCKY VALENTIN E
AN ITIN ERANT SECON D-STORY
MAN WHO'S SHOT TO DEATH IN
AN ALLEY ONE NIGHT
AND GOES TO
HIS JUST REWARDS.
THIS LITTLE ITEM
HERE BEING ONE OF THEM.
THIS ONE YOU CAN WATCH
WITH THE TONG U E IN
YOUR CH EEK.
IT'S CALLED A NICE PLA CE
TO VISIT, NEXT WEEK ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[eerie music]
(male presenter)
KIMBERLY-CLARK
INVITES YOU TO
WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THE SAME STATIONS.