[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[machinery clanking]
(announcer)
THE BLASTING AREA WILL
BE CLEARED BY 0200.
REPEAT. THE BLASTING
AREA WILL BE CLEARED
BY 0200.
IT'S AN ODD WAY
TO SPEND THE LAST
NIGHT, ISN'T IT?
ODD?
WELL, THE LAST NIGHT
ON EARTH YOU DON'T SPEN D
LOOKING AT YOUR TRANSPORTATION.
LAST NIGHT ON
EARTH, YOU SPEND
ENJOYING EARTH.
YOU WALK ITS STREETS,
GO IN ITS BARS, DANCE
WITH ITS WOM EN.
THAT'S GOING
TO BE OUR WORLD
FOR A LONG TIME, SAM.
AND YET WE STAND OUT HERE
WATCHING HER JUST THREE
HOURS BEFORE WE TAKE OFF.
MARCUSSON?
MM?
ARE YOU AFRAI D?
I DON'T THINK SO.
ARE YOU?
I AM.
VERY.
IT'S DIFFERENT
WITH YOU.
YOU'RE TRAINED FOR IT.
IT'S NOT THE
SAME WITH ME.
I'M A SCI ENTIST,
A B IOLOG IST.
MY WORLD IS ONE
OF BOOKS AND SLI DES
AND M ICROSCOPES.
I'M BEING SENT UP
THERE BECAUSE THEY
NEED MY MIND.
AND IT'S A P ITY
THEY CAN'T J UST
SEND THAT.
LEAVE THE BODY BACK HERE
WHERE IT BELONGS. J UST
SEND THE MIND.
OH, I AM FRIGHTEN ED.
I'M FRIGHTEN ED OF WHAT
WE'LL F IN D UP THERE.
WELL, THAT'S THE ONE
THING YOU SHOU LDN'T
BE FRIGHTEN ED OF.
THE U N KNOWN, SURE.
TH E-THE LON ELIN ESS,
THE S I LENCE.
THAT SHOULD
SCARE ANYBODY.
BUT I'VE GOT
A PH I LOSOPHY
ABOUT PEOPLE.
I MEAN, ALL
PEOPLE, SAM.
THEY'RE THE
SAME ALL OVER.
WELL, I'M SURE
THAT WHEN GOD
MADE HUMAN BEINGS,
HE DEVELOPED THEM
FROM A F IXED FORM U LA.
THEY'D BE THE SAM E
HERE ON EARTH
AS IN THE FURTHEST
REACHES OF SPACE.
PEOPLE ON MARS?
WHEREVER THEY'RE ABLE
TO EXIST, THEY'D
BE THE SAM E.
(narrator)
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A SPECIE
OF FLIMSY LITTLE
TWO-LEGGED ANIMAL
WITH EXTREMELY SMALL
HEADS WHOSE NAME IS MAN.
WARREN MARCUSSON, AGE 35.
SAMUEL A. CONRAD, AGE 31.
HEY, LET'S GET
READY, SAM. WE'VE ONLY
GOT A COUPLE OF HOURS.
THEY'RE TAKING
A HIGHWAY INTO SPACE.
MAN UNSHACKLING HIMSELF
AND SENDING HIS TINY,
GROPING FINGERS UP
INTO THE UNKNOWN.
THEIR DESTINATION IS MARS,
AND IN JUST A MOMENT
WE'LL LAND THERE WITH THEM.
[groans]
MARCUSSON?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
MARCUSSON, WHAT THE--
MARCUSSON.
ANY LAN DING,
YOU CAN WALK
AWAY FROM, REMEMBER?
WHAT ABOUT THE SH I P?
[groans]
THE AIR PRESSURE
SEEMS TO BE HOLDING UP.
I GOT THE LIGHTS RU N NING.
I HAVEN'T HAD TIME
TO CHECK ANYTHING ELSE.
YOU-YOU, UH,
REST FOR A WHILE.
THERE'S PLENTY OF TIME.
PLENTY OF TIME?
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL SEE.
[moans]
[clanking]
SAM?
SAM!
HEY.
HOW LONG DID I SLEEP?
OH, A COUPLE
OF HOURS. YOU
NEEDED IT.
CONRAD. WELL, LET'S
PLANT THE FLAG.
YOU TAKE IT EASY.
THERE'S PLENTY
OF TIME.
WE'VE COME
35 M I LLION M I LES!
SO? ANOTH ER
FEW HOURS WON'T
MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE.
[clanking]
YOU WON'T BE
ABLE TO OPEN IT.
THE HYDRAU LIC'S OUT.
PUT HER ON THE
AUXI LIARY, THEN.
WE CAN OPEN IT.
NO, WE CAN'T.
I'LL F IX IT.
I'LL PUT H ER
ON THE AUXI LIARY.
THEN WE CAN OPEN HER UP.
THAT'S WHAT I'LL DO NOW.
I'LL OPEN HER UP.
MARCUSSON.
YOU HAVE TO
TAKE IT EASY.
OPEN THE DOOR, CON RAD.
I'VE ALREADY
TOLD YOU, THAT DOOR--
YOU'RE A LIAR!
YOU CAN OPEN
THE DOOR.
WHY, SAM?
WHY WON'T YOU
OPEN THE DOOR?
I DON'T WANT
TO OPEN IT.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE.
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO THE
ENQU I RING SCI ENTIF IC
MIND, CON RAD?
I THOUGHT YOU
BROUGHT THAT ALONG.
WHY DID YOU COME
ALONG ANYWAY?
LOOK, I WANT OUT.
I WANT YOU TO OPEN
THE DOOR.
YOU CAN LOCK IT
BEH IN D ME. J UST
H ELP ME UP.
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
PLEASE, H ELP ME UP.
SAM.
I'M BUSTED UP I NSIDE.
I THINK I'M
BLEEDING IN THERE.
LISTEN, SAM, I DON'T
WANNA DIE IN HERE.
I WANNA SEE
WHAT I'M DYING FOR.
TAKE ME OUT,
WILL YOU? TAKE ME OUT.
MARC, PLEASE. PLEASE!
DON'T-DON'T
BE AFRAI D, SAM. I
GOT A STRANG E H U NCH.
IF THERE'S
ANYBODY OUT THERE,
THEY'LL H ELP YOU.
AS LONG AS THEY'VE
GOT MINDS AND HEARTS,
THAT MEANS THEY'VE GOT SOU LS.
THAT MAKES THEM PEOPLE,
AND PEOPLE ARE ALIKE.
THEY'RE BOUND
TO BE ALIKE.
FOR GOD'S SAKE!
DON'T LEAVE
ME ALON E, MARC.
DON'T LEAVE ME ALONE!
[clanking]
YOU SAID WHATEVER
IS OUT THERE IS
JUST LIKE US.
WELL, I DON'T
KNOW THAT!
I DON'T WANNA KNOW.
I DON'T WANNA KNOW,
I DON'T WANT TO KNOW!
[rumbling]
YOU'RE PEOPLE.
YOU'RE JUST LIKE I AM.
FACE, BODY.
EVERYTHING.
YOU'RE JUST LIKE I AM!
OH, UH--
FORGIVE ME.
U H, DON'T BE
FRIGHTEN ED.
MY NAME IS-IS,
U H, SAM CON RAD.
U H, SAM U EL CON RAD.
THAT NAME, UNDERSTAND?
MY FRI END AND I,
WE CAME HERE FROM
THE EARTH.
LOOK, I'LL SHOW YOU.
U H, THIS IS
THE EARTH, SEE?
WE ARE THE THIRD
PLANET FROM THE SUN.
THIS IS YOU.
WHERE I COME FROM,
THIS PLAN ET IS
CALLED MARS.
THE OTHER ONE IS DEAD.
DON'T BE ALARMED,
MR. CONRAD. WE DON'T
INTEND TO HARM YOU EITHER.
WE'VE BEEN WONDERING WHEN YOU
PLANNED TO COME OUT. WE'VE
BEEN WAITING FOR HOURS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
MY LANGUAGE?
WE DON'T, MR. CON RAD.
AS YOU'LL NO DOU BT SOON
REALIZE, YOU ARE SPEAKING
OUR LANGUAGE.
YOUR LANGUAGE?
UNCONSCIOUS TRANSFERENCE.
YOU'D CALL IT HYPNOSIS
OF A SORT.
BUT YOU MUST BE TIRED.
WE'LL PREPARE A PLACE
FOR YOU TO REST.
I'M APPRECIATIVE,
I REALLY AM.
YOU'LL FORGIVE ME.
MY STARING, I MEAN.
I JUST CAN'T GET OVER IT.
I MEAN, YOU'RE
HUMAN BEINGS,
JUST LIKE I AM.
PEOPLE.
MARCUSSON SAID
YOU WOULD BE.
MARCUSSON.
MR. CONRAD?
WE'LL BU RY YOUR
FRI END FOR YOU.
LATER ON YOU CAN TELL US
WHAT KIND OF MARKER
YOU'D LIKE.
WE'LL REPAIR YOUR
SH I P FOR YOU, TOO.
THANK YOU.
YOU WERE RIGHT,
OLD FRI EN D.
THEY ARE PEOPLE.
JUST LIKE US.
I WISH YOU LIVED
TO SEE THAT.
THERE ARE SO
MANY QU ESTIONS
I WANT TO ASK YOU.
SO MANY THINGS I
WANT TO KNOW ABOUT
YOUR CIVI LIZATION.
YOUR SOCIAL STRUCTU RE,
THE WAY YOU LIVE.
YOUR SCI ENCE.
OH, A H U N DRED QU ESTIONS.
A THOUSAND QU ESTIONS.
WE'LL ANSWER ALL YOUR
QU ESTIONS, MR. CON RAD.
BUT FIRST, YOU M UST
REST HERE FOR A WHILE
WHILE WE PREPARE A
PLACE FOR YOU, A PLACE
YOU'LL FEEL FAMILIAR IN.
WE'LL BE BACK SOON.
MISS?
YOU DO HAVE A
NAM E, DON'T YOU?
I'M CALLED TEENYA.
WELL, UH, TEENYA,
WILL YOU TELL
THE OTH ERS HOW VERY
APPRECIATIVE I AM?
I-I WAS SO FRIGHTEN ED,
SO M ISERABLY FRIGHTEN ED.
DON'T BE FRIGHTEN ED,
MR. CON RAD. NO ONE
WILL H U RT YOU.
NO ONE WILL HURT YOU.
YOU MUST BELIEVE THAT.
THANK YOU, TEENYA.
THANK YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU
LATER, MR. CON RAD.
GOOD MORNING.
DID YOUREST
WELL, MR. CON RAD?
LONG AND WELL. MAY I
SEE YOUR CITY NOW AND
THE REST OF YOUR PEOPLE?
VERY SOON. FIRST,
FIRST WE HAVE A
SURPRISE FOR YOU.
A VERY PLEASANT
SURPRISE.
REALLY?
WOULD YOU
ACCOM PANY US, PLEASE?
OF COURSE.
WHERE ARE
WE GOING?
THAT'S THE SURPRISE,
MR. CON RAD.
ARE YOU COMING?
YES, I WILL COME.
IS-IS THIS A MARTIAN
HOUSE? IS THIS THE WAY
YOU LIVE?
OH, NO, OU RS ARE CONSIDERABLY
DIFFERENT. WE BU I LT THIS
DU RING THE NIGHT
BECAUSE WE ASSU MED
THIS IS THE WAY
YOU PEOPLE LIVE.
OH, IT'S A
PERFECT REPLICA.
PERFECT.
[chuckIing]
A TELEVIS ION SET.
THE FU RN ITU RE,
DRAPES, EVERYTHING!
BUT HOW COULD YOU
BU I LD IT SO QU ICKLY? HOW
COULD YOU POSS I BLY KNOW?
FROM YOUR MIND.
YOU THINK VERY
CLEARLY, MR. CON RAD.
VERY CLEARLY, IN DEED.
VERY STRONG IMPRESS ION.
WOULD YOU CARE TO SEE
THE REST OF THE HOUSE?
U H-HUH.
IT'S FABU LOUS.
IT'S REALLY FABU LOUS!
WE WANTED YOU TO FEEL
AT HOM E, MR. CON RAD.
DO YOU?
DO YOU FEEL AT HOME?
IT'S U N BELI EVABLE.
THANK YOU.
WE WERE WON DERING
IF YOU'D MIND REMAINING
HERE FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
YOU EXPRESSED AN I NTEREST
IN SEEING OUR CITY,
M EETING OUR PEOPLE.
WE'LL GO OUT
AND ARRANG E THAT.
THAT'S WON DERFU L.
YOU WANT ME TO STAY HERE?
DO YOU MIND?
U H, I'D BE DELIGHTED.
GOOD. FOR A
LITTLE WHILE THEN.
ENJOY YOURSELF,
MR. CON RAD. ENJOY
YOUR HOUSE.
LET ME SHOW YOU OUT.
AFTER ALL, IT'S MY HOUSE.
TEENYA?
I WILL SEE YOU
AGAIN, WON'T I?
OF COURSE YOU
WI LL, MR. CON RAD.
IF IT'S AN I LLUS ION,
A GUY CAN LIVE WITH IT.
THAT'S THE BEST
SCOTCH I EVER DRAN K.
HEY! YOU LOCKED ME IN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH
YOU, PEOPLE?
[shouting]
I'M LOCKED IN!
WHAT'S WRONG?
[gasping]
THERE AREN'T
ANY WIN DOWS.
THERE AREN'T ANY
WIN DOWS ANYWHERE!
[buzz of conversation]
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
WHY?
WHY HAVE YOU
LOCKED ME IN HERE?
WHY ARE YOU LOOKING
AT ME LIKE THAT?
MARCUSSON!
MARCUSSON, YOU WERE RIGHT.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
PEOPLE ARE ALIKE.
PEOPLE ARE
ALIKE EVERYWHERE.
(narrator)
SPECIE OF ANIMAL
BROUGHT BACK ALIVE.
INTERESTING SIM ILARITY AND
PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS
TO HUMAN BEINGS,
IN HEAD, TRUNK, ARMS,
LEGS, HANDS, FEET.
VERY TINY,
UNDEVELOPED BRAIN.
COMES FROM PRIM ITIVE
PLANET NAMED EARTH.
CALLS HIMSELF
SAMUEL CONRAD.
AND HE WILL REMAIN
HERE IN HIS CAGE WITH
THE RUNNING WATER
AND THE ELECTRICITY
AND THE CENTRAL HEAT
AS LONG AS HE LIVES.
SAMUEL CONRAD HAS
FOUND THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
THIS MAY LOOK
LIKE SOME KIND OF
KOOKY GREEN HOUSE.
ACTUALLY, IT HAPPENS TO BE
A CONVEYANCE, A MODE OF
TRAVEL, TIME TRAVEL.
AND NEXT WEEK,
YOU'LL SEE ALBERT SALM I
TAKE AN EXTEN DED JOU RN EY
FROM 1 880 TO 1 960.
I HOPE THEN NEXT WEEK
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO TAKE
ANOTHER WALK WITH US
INTO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male voice)
HEY, WHERE DID
EVERYBODY GO?
[eerie music]
KIMBERLY-CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THE SAME STATIONS.