[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT ACT ONE,
SCENE ONE OF A NIGHTMARE,
ONE NOT RESTRICTED
TO WITCHING HOURS
AND DARK,
RAIN-SWEPT NIGHTS.
PROFESSOR WALTER JAMESON,
POPULAR BEYOND WORDS,
WHO TALKS OF THE PAST
AS IF IT WERE THE PRESENT,
WHO CONJURES UP THE DEAD
AS IF THEY WERE ALIVE.
THE U N ION SOLDI ERS
BU RN ED ATLANTA,
BUT I ASSURE YOU, THEY
TOOK NO PLEASURE
IN THEIR WORK.
THEY WERE FORCED TO IT
BY A MAN THEY HATED MORE
THAN THEY COULD EVER HATE
THE REBELS.
AN UG LY, SU LLEN,
U N BELI EVABLY BRUTAL MAN
NAM ED WI LLIAM
TECU MSEH SH ERMAN.
TO GIVE YOU A
MORE COMPREHENSIVE
IDEA OF THIS GREAT HERO,
LET ME READ YOU
A FEW EXTRACTS FROM
THE DIARY OF MAJOR SKELTON.
THE DATE IS TU ESDAY,
SEPTEM BER 1 1, 1 864.
"THE CITY WAS OU RS.
"THERE WAS NO NEED
TO DESTROY AUG HT,
"SAVE THAT WHICH
COULD BE OF USE IN
THE FIGHT AGAINST US.
"BUT SH ERMAN WAS
DRU N K WITH VICTORY.
"HE HIMSELF STARTED
THE AWFU L F I RES.
"THE F I RES THAT DESTROYED
THAT GREAT CITADEL OF
G RACE AND BEAUTY."
(narrator)
IN THE VIEW OF THIS MAN,
PROFESSOR SAMUEL KITTRIDGE,
WALTER JAMESON HAS
ACCESS TO KNOWLEDGE
THAT COULDN'T COME OUT
OF A VOLUME OF HISTORY,
BUT RATHER FROM A
BOOK ON BLACK MAGIC.
WHICHIS TO SAY THAT THIS
NIGHTMARE BEGINS AT NOON.
VERY VIVI D, WALTER.
YOU HAD ME ON THE
EDG E OF MY SEAT.
THANK YOU, SAM.
I BEG IN TO SEE WHY
THESE LECTU RES OF
YOURS ARE SO POPU LAR.
IS THAT WHY
YOU SAT I N?
WELL, PARTIALLY. TELL ME
SOMETHING. WHO IS THIS
MAJOR SKELTON?
OH, JUST A LAWYER
WRAPPED INTO A M IST.
U H, WHAT REG I MENT?
H U N DRED AND TWENTY
THIRD IN FANTRY.
I MUST SAY,
THE STORY OF HIS IS
A FASCI NATING DOCU MENT.
MAY I SEE IT?
I, UH, I DON'T
SU PPOSE I COULD
BORROW IT.
I NEVER LEND BOOKS TO
ABSENT-MINDED PROFESSORS.
REMEMBER THE LAST TIME?
YES. YOU'RE RIGHT.
ANYTHING WRONG, SAM?
NO. COULD YOU COME
FOR DIN N ER TONIGHT?
WHOSE I NVITATION?
YOURS OR SUSAN NA'S?
M IN E THIS TIME.
SAY, 7 :00?
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD.
[crickets chirping]
REALLY, DARLING,
M UST YOU ALWAYS
BE ON TIME?
ALWAYS.
PLEASE. REMEMBER,
YOU'RE A Ph. D.
NOT YET, I'M NOT. THERE'S
A LITTLE MATTER OF AN
EXAM INATION. REMEMBER?
A TECHNICALITY.
ANYWAY, YOU'RE
GONNA BE A HOUSEWIFE.
THE DEVIL SHE IS.
I'M GIVING YOU
MY DAUG HTER'S
HAN D, NOT HER BRAI N.
SHE'S GON NA
GET THAT Ph. D.--
IF I HAVE TO SPAN K
H ER. I KNOW.
DON'T TELL ME
YOU'RE THE COOK
AGAIN TONIGHT.
IN DEED, AND WHY NOT?
WELL, I THINK IT'S
TIME THAT I TRI ED
SUSAN NA'S COOKING.
DON'T WORRY, YOU WI LL.
I'M SURE. WELL,
SHALL WE S IT DOWN?
MY LADY.
I TAKE IT BACK, SAM.
SHE'LL NEVER BE
THE COOK YOU ARE.
[chuckIes]
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING, YOUNG LADY?
I'LL DO THE DISH ES LATER.
IT'S NOT THE DISH ES
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S BOOKS AND
STU DY. UPSTAIRS.
BESIDES, WALTER AND
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO DISCUSS.
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO TREAT ME THIS
WAY, ARE YOU?
WORSE. WHO KNOWS?
YOU MAY HAVE
TO SU PPORT US.
YOU OUGHTA BE ASHAM ED
OF YOURSELF, SAM.
SUSAN NA'S ALMOST
30 YEARS OLD.
AND I'M ALMOST 70.
M M-H M.
MY MOVE, ISN'T IT?
YES.
WHAT'S THAT FOR?
LOOK AT THEM.
EXTRAORDINARY, ISN'T IT?
THEY LOOK VERY
MUCH ALIKE.
TWELVE YEARS AGO,
THOSE TWO HAN DS.
TIME MARCH ES ON.
FOR SOME OF US.
WALTER, TELL ME
SOMETHING, WILL YOU?
OF COURSE.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
FORTY-FOU R.
I SEEM TO RECALL THAT WH EN
YOU APPLI ED FOR A POST
ON THE U N IVERS ITY STAFF,
YOU LISTED
YOUR AG E AS 39.
THAT WAS,
LET ME SEE, 1 947,
WHICH WOULD
MAKE YOU 5 1.
COME ON, SAM.
ALL RIGHT, I'M 5 1.
TOO OLD FOR SUSAN NA?
IS THAT IT?
IN A SENSE.
WALTER, IN 1 947,
I WAS 58.
I HAD MOST OF MY HAIR,
ALL MY TEETH AND
HARDLY A WRIN KLE.
LOOK AT ME NOW.
IN 1 2 SHORT YEARS,
I'VE TURN ED INTO
AN OLD MAN,
WHILE YOU HAVEN'T
AG ED AT ALL.
IT HAPPENS THAT
WAY SOMETIME.
I KNOW, BUT WHY?
DON'T ASK ME, SAM.
YOU'RE THE CH EM IST.
I TEACH H ISTORY.
YES, AND YOU
TEACH IT VERY WELL.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THE STU DENTS SAY?
THEY SAY IT'S ALMOST AS THOUGH
YOU'D LIVED TH ROUG H THE PERIOD
YOU WERE DISCUSSING.
I TRY TO MAKE
IT I NTERESTING.
FAKE IT, YOU MEAN?
YOU COULD CALL IT THAT.
YES, THAT'S
WHAT I THOUGHT.
BUT SOMEHOW, THAT
DI DN'T SEEM LIKE YOU.
YOU'RE SUCH
A PRECISE SORT.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT THERE?
A BOOK OF PHOTOG RAPHS
TAKEN BY A FELLOW
NAM ED MATH EW BRADY
DU RING THE TIME
OF THE CIVI L WAR.
WELL, WHAT IS IT?
YOU LOOK AS THOUGH
YOU'VE SEEN A GHOST.
MAYBE I HAVE.
WALTER WAS-WAS YOUR
G RAN DFATHER IN THE CIVI L
WAR, BY ANY CHANCE?
NO.
THEN I'D SAY WE
HAVE SOMETHING OF
A MYSTERY HERE.
HOW SO?
YOU MADE ME CU RIOUS
ABOUT THIS MAJOR
SKELTON TODAY.
I THOUGHT IT WOULD
BE I NTERESTING TO SEE
WHAT HE LOOKED LIKE,
SO I WENT TH ROUG HMY
BRADY PICTURES, NOT REALLY
EXPECTING TO F IN D ANYTHING.
THESE ARE THREE OF
SH ERMAN'S STAFF OFFICERS.
THE ONE SEATED AT
THE TABLE ISIDENTIF I ED
AS MAJOR H UG H SKELTON.
THAT PICTURE WAS TAKEN
ALMOST 1 00 YEARS AGO.
YOU SHOU LDN'T HAVE KEPT
THAT RING, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A DEAD GIVEAWAY.
WHAT ARE YOU
GETTING AT, SAM?
OH, COME, WALTER.
YOU KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT I'M GETTING AT.
OH, YOU'RE JOKING. J UST
BECAUSE I HAPPEN TO LOOK
LIKE SOMEBODY IN A PHOTOG RAPH.
AND HAPPEN
TO BE WEARING
THE SAME RING
AND HAPPEN TO HAVE
THE SAME MOLE ON THE
LEFT SIDE OF YOUR FACE.
WALTER, YOU AND I
HAVE BEEN VERY CLOSE
FOR 1 2 YEARS.
TELL ME THE TRUTH. YOU--
YOU ARE THAT MAN I N--
IN THE PHOTOG RAPH,
AREN'T YOU?
YES.
[sighs]
I'VE SUSPECTED
A LONG TIME.
BUT IT SEEM ED FANTASTIC.
M M, IT IS.
YES.
HOW OLD ARE
YOU, WALTER?
YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE ME.
I CAN BELIEVE
ANYTHING NOW.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S SAY THAT
I'M OLD ENOUGH TO HAVE KNOWN
THIS GENTLEMAN PERSONALLY.
PLATO?
BUT THAT WAS OVER
2,000 YEARS AGO!
I KNEW YOU
WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME.
NO, NO, IT'S--IT
ISN'T THAT, IT'S--
TWO THOUSAND YEARS.
HOW, WALTER? HOW?
IN H EAVEN'S NAME,
THIS IS WHAT MAN KIND
HAS BEEN DREAMING OF.
SAM.
TELL ME THE SECRET.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
THE SECRET, SAM,
BECAUSE I DON'T
KNOW IT MYSELF.
I WAS LIKE YOU, SAM.
AFRAI D OF DEATH.
AND WHEN I THOUGHT OF ALL
THE THINGS THERE WERE TO KNOW
IN THE MISERABLE
FEW YEARS THAT A
MAN HAD TO KNOW THEM,
IT SEEM ED SENSELESS.
AT NIGHT, EVERY NIGHT
I DREAM ED, AS YOU DREAM,
OF IMMORTALITY.
ONLY IF A MAN
LIVED FOREVER,
I THOUGHT,
COULD THERE
BE ANY PO I NT
IN LIVING AT ALL?
I TALKED TO PRI ESTS,
PH I LOSOPH ERS.
THEN ONE DAY
I MET AN ALCH EM IST.
TOLD HIM THESE THINGS.
HE SAID THAT HE COULD
G RANT MY WISH.
ONLY, OF COURSE,
IT WOULD COST A
G REAT DEAL OF MONEY.
I WAS DESPERATE, I PAI D HIM
HIS MONEY AND SU BM ITTED
TO HIS EXPERI MENTS.
I REMEMBER VERY
LITTLE ABOUT IT.
I LAY IN A COMA
FOR MANY WEEKS,
AND WHEN I REVIVED,
I WAS ALON E.
THE ALCH EM IST
HAD DISAPPEARED.
GO ON.
THERE'S REALLY
VERY LITTLE MORE
TO TELL.
I THOUGHT, OF COURSE,
THAT THE EXPERI MENT
HAD FAI LED
BECAUSE I DIDN'T FEEL
ANY DIFFERENTLY.
BUT THEN
I SAW MY WIFE AND
MY CH I LDREN AGING.
MY FRIENDS DYING.
THIS WAS SOMETHING THAT
I HADN'T CONSIDERED,
YOU SEE?
BUT SURELY THERE--
THERE'S SOME ANSWER
TO THAT PROBLEM.
IS THERE?
THINK ABOUT IT.
I TELL YOU THAT
SOM EHOW I CAN STOP
YOU FROM AGING.
WHERE DO YOU WANT
TO STOP, AT 30?
THEN YOU WATCH EVERYON E
AROUND YOU GROW OLD.
AT 70?
DO YOU WANT
TO LIVE FOREVER
THE WAY YOU ARE NOW?
OLD, S ICK?
IT'S BETTER
THAN DYING.
NO, YOU'RE WRONG, SAM.
I WAS WRONG.
IT'S... DEATH
THAT GIVES THIS
WORLD ITS PO I NT.
WE LOVE A ROSE BECAUSE WE
KNOW IT'LL SOON BE GON E.
WHO EVER LOVED A STON E?
I'M NOT A ROSE.
I'M NOT A STON E.
I'M A MAN!
VERY OLD AND
VERY FRIGHTEN ED.
OF WHAT, DEATH?
YES, OF DEATH.
YOU'RE A FOOL, SAM.
I WANT TO DIE.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU?
BECAUSE I'M A COWARD.
YOU?
I HAVEN'T CHANG ED.
I'M THE SAME MAN I WAS.
I WAS A COWARD THEN,
I'M A COWARD NOW.
I'M TIRED OF LIVING.
IN MY DESK I HAVE
A REVOLVER, SAM.
AND EVERY NIGHT I TAKE IT
OUT AND PRAY FOR THE COU RAG E
TO PULL THE TRIGG ER. I CAN'T.
YOU MEAN TO SAY THAT
YOU'VE SU RVIVED
OVER 2,000 YEARS
WITHOUT AN ACCIDENT,
WITHOUT BEING WOU N DED?
SOME PEOPLE ARE
LUCKY THAT WAY.
THEY GO TH ROUG H
LIFE WITHOUT EVER
BREAKING A BON E
OR SEEING THE I NSIDE
OF A HOSP ITAL.
OH, I'VE BEEN
CLOSE TO DEATH,
MANY TIMES,
BUT NEVER
CLOSE ENOUGH.
THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT?
I THOUGHT IF A MAN
LIVED FOREVER, H E'D
G ROW WISER.
BUT THAT ISN'T
TRU E, IS IT?
YOU JUST GO ON
LIVING. THAT'S ALL.
IT MUST BE LON ELY.
I SU PPOSE YOU'VE BEEN
MARRI ED SEVERAL TIMES.
YES.
HOW LONG WITH EACH
WOMAN, WALTER?
TEN YEARS?
F I FTEEN YEARS?
I SEE.
SAM, I TRI ED TO RESIGN SIX
MONTHS AGO. YOU TALKED ME OUT
OF IT. DO YOUREMEMBER THAT?
YES.
I KNEW SUSANNA
WAS FALLING IN
LOVE WITH ME,
AND I KNEW WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN. IT'S
HAPPENED BEFORE.
A FEW YEARS
OF HAPP IN ESS
AND THEN--
I TRI ED TO WARN H ER.
I DID EVERYTHING IN MY
POWER TO DISCOU RAG E H ER.
EXCEPT TELL
HER THE TRUTH.
HOW COULD I DO THAT?
SH E'D HAVE THOUGHT
I WAS MAD.
THEN WHY DIDN'T
YOU LEAVE?
BECAUSE BY THEN
IT WAS TOO LATE.
I WAS IN LOVE WITH H ER.
I NEED H ER.
EVERYTHING IS
AGAINST IT. ALL MY
REASON AND EXPERI ENCE.
BUT THAT DOESN'T
MATTER NOW. IT
DOESN'T MATTER.
IT DOES TO ME, WALTER.
I CAN'T LET YOU MARRY
MY DAUG HTER.
(Susanna)
AND WHY NOT?
WELL, COME ON.
YOUR FATHER SEEMS
TO THINK I'M TOO OLD
FOR YOU, DARLING.
THAT'S THE S I LLI EST
THING I EVER HEARD OF.
GOOD.
THEN YOU'LL
MARRY ME TONIGHT.
I THINK YOU MEAN IT.
I DO. YOU GO
U PSTAIRS, PACK YOUR
PRETTI EST THINGS.
I'LL PICK YOU UP
IN 1 5 MINUTES.
BUT--
GO.
I'LL TELL H ER.
SHE WON'T
BELIEVE YOU.
NOBODY WOULD.
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
IT YOURSELF BY
TOMORROW MORNING.
(Woman)
HELLO, TOMMY.
WHO ARE YOU?
DON'T YOU
RECOG N IZE ME, TOM MY?
LOOK HARD.
LOOK INTO MY EYES.
YOU CALLED THEM THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL YOU'D EVER SEEN
ONCE, A LONG TIME AGO.
I'M AFRAI D YOU'RE
MAKING A M ISTAKE.
NO, TOMMY.
MY NAME IS JAMESON.
PROFESSOR WALTER JAMESON.
DON'T PRETEND.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
AND WHO AM I?
YOU'RE TOM BOWEN,
MY H USBAN D.
YOUR H USBAN D?
MY DEAR WOMAN,
PERHAPS IF YOU'LL TELL ME
WHO YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
OH, STOP IT.
I SAW THE PICTURE
IN THE N EWSPAPER
AN NOU NCING
YOUR ENGAG EM ENT.
I HAD TO COME
TO SEE IF IT WAS TRU E.
IT IS.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
I ONLY KNOW IT'S HAPPENED.
I'VE GROWN OLD,
AND YOU HAVEN'T.
NOW YOU'RE GOING TO
MARRY SOMEONE ELSE
AND LEAVE H ER,
THE WAY YOU LEFT ME.
OH, LAU RETTE.
LAU RETTE.
I CAN'T LET YOU
MARRY H ER, TOM MY.
YOU'RE M IN E.
[yeIIs]
LAU RETTE.
TOM MY, IT'S WRONG.
YOU CAN'T GO ON
H U RTING PEOPLE.
[gunshot]
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
WALTER?
HELLO, SAM.
I THOUGHT I HEARD--
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[weakIy]
I DON'T KNOW.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
E ITHER WAY, YOU'RE--
YOU'LL BE RID OF ME.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
[grunts]
I MEAN--
I'VE COME TO
MY SENSES...AT LAST.
TELL SUSAN NA THAT--
OH, NO, STAY AWAY.
YOU'RE H U RT.
I'LL CALL A DOCTOR.
NO.
YOUR HAN D.
IT'S HAPPENING.
AT LAST.
WALTER, WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
OH, MY GOD.
[weak voice]
NOTHING LASTS
FOREVER, THANK GOD.
[groans]
[quick, shaIIow breathing]
[pained wheezing]
DAD! WALTER!
GO HOME, SUSANNA.
THAT SOUND WAS A
SHOT! WALTER'S HURT!
PLEASE, SUSANNA, GO HOME!
[tussling]
WALTER?
H E'S-HE'S GON E.
WHERE?
I DON'T KNOW,
MY DEAR, I--
HIS CLOTH ES?
DAD?
WHAT IS THAT
ON THE FLOOR?
DUST.
ONLY DUST.
(narrator)
LAST STOP ON
A LONG JOURNEY,
AS YET ANOTHER HUMAN
BEING RETURNS TO THE
VAST NOTHINGNESS
THAT IS THE BEGINNING
AND INTO THE DUST
THAT IS ALWAYS THE END.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, AN
EXCU RS ION TO MARS
WITH RODDY MCDOWALL
AND PAU L COM I.
TWO MEN TRYING
TO PROVE A PO I NT.
A S IMPLE PROPOS ITION
THAT MEN ARE ALIKE ALL OVER.
AND ON MARS THEY DISCOVER
THAT THIS IS JUST WH ISTLING
IN THE DARK.
PEOPLE ARE NOT ALIKE. AND
NEXT WEEK ON THE TWILIGHT
ZONE YOU'LL SEE WHY.
I HOPE YOU'LL BE
WITH US. THANK YOU
AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
(male presenter)
BE SURE TO SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS,
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE STATIONS.
THE TWILIGHT ZONE IS
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY THE NEWEST
COFFEE SENSATION
ON THE MODERN SCENE.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA COFFEE.