[eerie music]
(male narrator)
YOU ARE ABOUT TO ENTER
ANOTHER DIMENSION,
A DIMENSION NOT ONLY
OF SIGHT AND SOUND,
BUT OF M IND.
A JOURNEY
INTO A WONDROUS LAND
OF IMAGINATION.
YOUR NEXT STOP,
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[pleasant music
over PTA]
[elevator bell dinging]
MAY I SHOW
YOU SOMETHING?
NO.
NO, THAT'S...
NOT WHAT
I'M LOOKING FOR.
[elevator bell dinging]
(elevator operator)
GOING UP, MA'AM.
U M, HOUSEWARES?
THAT WOULD BE
THE MEZZAN IN E, MA'AM.
WHAT IN PARTICU LAR
WERE YOU LOOKING FOR?
U H, THIM BLES.
GOLD THIM BLES.
YOU HAD THEM
ADVERTISED.
THAT WOULD BE
SPECIALTI ES, MA'AM.
THE N I NTH FLOOR.
I'M NOT ACCUSTOM ED
TO SUCH SERVICE.
MA'AM?
THERE WERE A WHOLE
LOT OF PEOPLE
WAITING FOR
THE ELEVATOR.
I SEEM TO HAVE
A PRIVATE ON E.
WELL, THIS
IS AN EXPRESS
ELEVATOR, MA'AM--
TO THE N I NTH FLOOR.
THE OTH ERS ARE ALL
LOCALS THIS TIME
OF DAY.
(male narrator)
EXPRESS ELEVATOR
TO THE NINTH FLOOR
OF A DEPARTMENT STORE,
CARRYING MISS MARSHA WHITE
ON A MOST PROSAIC, ORDINARY,
RUN-OF-THE-M ILL ERRAND.
N I NTH FLOOR.
THERE MUST BE
SOME M ISTAKE.
THERE'S NOTHING HERE.
(male narrator)
MISS MARSHA WHITE,
ON THE NINTH FLOOR,
SPECIALTIES DEPARTMENT,
LOOKING FOR A GOLD THIMBLE.
THE ODDS ARE
THAT SHE'LL FIND IT.
[buzz for eIevator]
BUT THERE ARE
EVEN BETTER ODDS THAT
SHE'LL FIND SOMETHING ELSE
BECAUSE THIS ISN'T
JUST A DEPARTMENT STORE.
THIS HAPPENS TO BE--
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(female voice)
WAS SOMEONE
HELPING YOU?
CAN I SHOW
YOU SOMETHING?
OH, WHY, YES.
I WAS LOOKING FOR
A GOLD THIM BLE--
A GI FT FOR MY MOTH ER.
A GOLD THIM BLE.
I THINK WE HAVE
SOMETHING YOU'D LIKE.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
[cIick]
HOW ABOUT THIS?
IT'S 1 4-KARAT GOLD
AND QU ITE DISTI NCTIVE-
LOOKING, I THINK.
DON'T YOU?
U H, YES.
YES, I THINK
THIS WILL DO.
THIS IS A CHARG E?
IS THIS
A CHARG E, MISS?
U H, I BEG YOUR PARDON.
A CHARG E?
NO. NO, I'LL PAY FOR IT.
YOU WANT IT
G I FT WRAPPED.
YES, PLEASE.
NO, ON SECON D THOUGHT,
I'LL WRAP IT MYSELF.
MISS--
THAT'S 22.80 PLUS TAX.
$25 EVEN.
[cIick]
NOW THAT'S ODD.
WHAT IS, MARSHA?
WELL, YOU HAVEN'T
ANY MERCHAN DISE
HERE AT ALL,
EXCEPT THE THIM BLE,
EXCEPT THE VERY
THING I NEEDED.
THE WHOLE FLOOR,
IT LOOKS SO EM PTY AND--
YOU CALLED ME MARSHA.
DID I? I'M SORRY.
THAT WAS FORWARD OF ME.
I APOLOG IZE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW MY NAME?
I'VE PROBABLY
SEEN YOU
AROUND THE STORE.
NO, YOU HAVEN'T.
I'VE NEVER SEEN YOU.
NOW, LOOK, I DON'T
WANNA MAKE A BIG
THING OUT OF THIS
BUT WHAT KIND OF
A PLACE IS THIS?
ALL I WANT IS
ONE SMALL ITEM,
A GOLD THIM BLE.
I COME UP ON A FLOOR
THAT HASN'T
A SING LE THING
EXCEPT WHAT
I'M LOOKING FOR.
YOU MAY BE
MORE SOPH ISTICATED,
BUT THIS I CALL ODD.
PLEASE COME AGAIN.
ANY TIME.
THANK YOU.
MISS WH ITE?
ARE YOU HAPPY?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
AM I WHAT?
AM I HAPPY?
FORGIVE ME, BUT THAT'S
REALLY NONE OF YOUR BUS IN ESS.
REALLY? IT'S NON E
OF MY BUS IN ESS.
ALL RIGHT,
MISS WH ITE,
SU IT YOURSELF.
IT'S NONE OF
MY BUS IN ESS.
(operator eIevator)
GOING DOWN.
WELL, DID YOU F IN D WHAT
YOU WERE LOOKING FOR?
AS A MATTER
OF FACT, I DID.
ALSO AS A MATTER
OF FACT, IT WAS THE
ONLY THING FOR SALE
ON THAT FLOOR.
SOMEBODY OUGHT TO CALL
AN EFF ICI ENCY EXPERT,
ONE ENTI RE FLOOR
DEVOTED TO THE SALE
OF A SING LE
GOLD THIM BLE?
AN EXTREM ELY
ODDBALL SALESLADY
SOMEBODY OUGHT
TO LOOK INTO.
THIS IS SCRATCH ED.
WELL, I DIDN'T
NOTICE THAT BEFORE.
I CAN'T SEND THIS
TO MY MOTH ER.
IT'S SCRATCH ED,
AND IT'S DENTED TOO.
LOOK. LOOK HERE.
COM PLAINTS, THIRD FLOOR.
LOOK AT THIS THING!
IT'S SCRATCH ED
AND IT LOOKS AS I F
SOMEBODY STEPPED
ON IT.
THIRD FLOOR, COM PLAINTS.
[Strauss waltz playing
over P.A. system]
WELL, I DISTI NCTLY
TOLD HER THAT ALL
THE GOLD THIM BLES
THAT WE HAVE
ARE IN GI FTS.
AND THAT IF THE ITEM
WERE DAMAG ED,
WE WOULD CERTAIN LY
MAKE IT GOOD
E ITHER BY REPLACEM ENT
OR REFU N D.
I DISTI NCTLY TOLD
HER THAT, MR. SLOAN.
THEN WHAT IS
THE PROBLEM,
MR. ARM BRUSTER?
THE CUSTOM ER CLAI MS
THAT SHE DIDN'T GET
THE ITEM IN GI FTS,
THAT SHE GOT IT
IN ANOTHER DEPARTM ENT.
MR. ARM BRUST--
JUST TELL H ER
TO TAKE IT BACK
TO THE DEPARTM ENT
WHERE SHE PU RCHASED
THE ITEM.
THAT'S J UST
THE PO I NT.
SHE HAS SOME I DIOTIC STORY
ABOUT HAVING PU RCHASED
A GOLD THIM BLE
ON THE N I NTH FLOOR.
[dry inward laugh]
NINTH FLOOR.
MR. ARMBRUSTER,
I TRUST YOU
IN FORM ED THE LADY
THAT THIS STORE
HAS NO N I NTH FLOOR.
I HAVE TRI ED DESPERATELY,
I REALLY MEAN DESPERATELY
TO ACQUAI NT HER WITH
THIS FACT
BUT SHE STILL I NS ISTS
THAT SHE WAS TAKEN
TO THE N I NTH FLOOR
AND WAITED ON
BY A RATHER ODD WOMAN.
AN ODD WOMAN YET.
H M.
A PERSONALITY TRAIT
THAT SHE WOULD BE
PARTICU LARLY
KNOWLEDG EABLE ABOUT.
WELL, ANYWAY, THIS WOMAN
WHO ALLEG EDLY WAITED
ON H ER--
N EVER MIND, ARM BRUSTER.
I'LL TALK TO H ER.
YES, YES,
WELL, SH E'S
WAITING RIGHT
OUTSIDE, S I R.
[elevator bell dinging]
MISS WH ITE, THIS
IS OUR MANAG ER,
MR. SLOAN.
PERHAPS I
CAN H ELP YOU,
MISS WH ITE.
PERHAPS YOU CAN.
THIS THIM BLE--
IT'S DENTED
AND SCRATCH ED.
WELL, IT MOST
ASSUREDLY IS.
NOW, WHY DON'T
YOU TAKE IT BACK
TO THE GI FT
DEPARTM ENT AND--
I JUST EXPLAIN ED IT,
I DID NOT PU RCHASE THIS
IN THE GI FT DEPARTM ENT.
I WAS TAKEN
U P TO THE
N I NTH FLOOR.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES
IT SO DI FF ICU LT
TO UNDERSTAND.
YOU SEE, WE DON'T
HAVE A N I NTH FLOOR.
I WAS TAKEN TO
THE N I NTH FLOOR.
I WAS WAITED ON
BY A VERY ODD WOMAN.
I PAI D CASH.
YOUR RECE I PT?
MY RECE I PT?
I DIDN'T GET
A RECE I PT
BUT I PAI D CASH.
I GAVE HER A
20-DOLLAR B I LL AND
A 5-DOLLAR B I LL.
SHE GAVE ME
THIS THIM BLE
AND I--!
THERE SHE IS!
THERE'S THE WOMAN
WHO WAITED ON ME. MISS?
MISS, I WON DER
IF YOU'D--
WELL, WELL,
HOW IS SH E?
SHE'LL BE ALL RIGHT,
MR. ARM BRUSTER.
SHE WAS JUST FRIGHTEN ED,
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT ABOUT THIS
DELUS ION OF H ERS?
I DON'T KNOW, I
DI DN'T TALK TO H ER.
BUT SHE'S RESTING NOW.
I THINK, MAYBE
EVEN GONE TO SLEEP.
H M M. WELL,
TELL H ER
WE'RE CLOSING.
TELL HER TO COME
BACK TOMORROW
AND WE'LL GET H ER
A REPLACEM ENT
OR REFU N D OR
ANYTHING ELSE SHE WANTS.
MISS PETTIG REW,
WE'RE CLOSING UP NOW.
WHAT I'D LIKE
TO GIVE HER IS
A BUS TICKET.
A ON E-WAY
BUS TICKET
TO ANY
DEPARTM ENT STORE
WEST OF CLEVELAN D.
PREFERABLY CH ICAGO
OR LOS ANGELES
OR HONOLU LU.
MISS PETTIG REW,
DID YOU HEAR ME?
WE'RE CLOSING UP NOW!
(male voice)
MISS KIEVERS.
YOU HAVE
A CUSTOMER.
HURRY, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, I'M COMING.
[gasp]
[buzzes]
SOMEBODY?
PLEASE, I'M
LOCKED IN HERE.
U H, ANYONE?
I NEED SOME HELP.
ANYONE?
PLEASE?
[gasps]
[Ioud thud]
[Ioud gasp]
(woman)
MARSHA.
(woman No.2)
(man)
MARSHA?
(woman No.3)
MARSHA.
(man No.2)
WHO DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE
FOOLING, MARSHA?
(woman No. 3)
COME ON, DEAR.
CLIMB OFF IT.
(man No. 2)
YOUREMEMBER, MARSHA.
(woman No. 2)
YOU KNOW WHO
YOU ARE.
MARSHA?
YOUREMEMBER, MARSHA.
CLI M B OFF IT.
COME ON, DEAR.
[all call out Marsha
one after another]
[all repeat at once]
[sobbing]
OH, NO!
[sobbing uncontrollably]
NOW, MARSHA, DEAR.
YOU'LL FORGIVE
AN OBSERVATION
BUT YOU'RE ACTING
LIKE A SILLY CH I LD.
COME NOW, MARSHA.
THINK NOW.
CONCENTRATE.
REMEMBER NOW?
ALL OF US WILL TRY
AND H ELP YOU.
WE'LL H ELP YOU CONCENTRATE.
REMEMBER NOW?
COMING BACK TO YOU?
THAT'S ODD.
THAT'S REALLY ODD,
BUT SU DDEN LY, I
SEEM TO--
REMEMBER. COMING
BACK NOW, IS IT?
I'M A MAN N EQU IN.
THAT'S WHAT I AM,
AND IT WAS MY TURN--
YOUR TURN
TO LEAVE US
FOR A MONTH.
BECOMING MUCH CLEARER
NOW, ISN'T IT?
YOU LEFT US FOR A MONTH
AND YOU LIVED
WITH THE OUTSIDERS.
BUT YOU WERE DU E
BACK YESTERDAY
AND YOU
DI DN'T SHOW UP.
YOU KNOW, MARSHA,
THAT'S VERY SELF ISH.
ALL OF US WAIT OUR TURN
AND WE S IMPLY DO NOT
OVERSTAY IT.
NOW. IT WAS MY TURN
STARTING LAST NIGHT.
I'M ONE DAY
DELAYED ALREADY.
BUT OF COURSE.
OF COURSE,
I'M SORRY.
I FORGOT.
WHEN YOU'RE ON THE OUTSIDE,
EVERYTHING SEEMS SO NORMAL.
AS I F--
AS I F
WHAT, MARSHA?
AS IF WE WERE
LIKE THE OTH ERS.
LIKE THE OUTSIDERS.
LIKE THE REAL PEOPLE.
WELL, NO SERIOUS
HARM DONE.
WELL, I'LL
SEE YOU ALL
IN A MONTH.
TAKE GOOD CARE
OF YOURSELVES.
(femaIe voice)
HAVE A BALL.
AND YOU'LL
ALL MISS ME?
(aII)
OH, YES!
AND YOU WON'T TEAR
THE PLACE APART?
AND YOU'LL ALL BE HERE
WHEN I GET BACK?
(many)
BYE.
(severaI)
DID YOU ENJOY
YOURSELF, MARSHA?
WAS IT FU N?
EVER SO MUCH FU N.
[pleasant music
over PTA]
GOOD MORNING, DEAR.
WE'RE EXPECTING $1 00
OUT OF YOU TODAY.
[elevator bell dinging]
KEEP YOUR POWDER
DRY, DARLING.
WELL, IT WILL SELL.
[cIears throat]
MORNING.
MORNING, LADI ES.
HERE, HERE,
BREAK IT UP.
BACK TO YOUR
POSTS, GIRLS.
IT'S 9 :00!
REALLY.
[elevator bell dinging]
[tsk]
(male narrator)
MARSHA WHITE IN HER
NORMAL AND NATURAL STATE.
A WOODEN LADY
WITH A PAINTED FACE
WHO, ONE MONTH
OUT OF THE YEAR,
TAKES ON
THE CHARACTERISTICS
OF SOMEONE AS NORMAL
AND AS FLESH AND BLOOD
AS YOU AND I.
BUT IT MAKES YOU WONDER,
DOESN'T IT?
JUST HOW NORMAL ARE WE?
JUST WHO ARE THE PEOPLE
WE NOD OUR HELLOS TO
AS WE PASS ON THE STREET?
A RATHER GOOD QUESTION TO ASK
PARTICULARLY IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male announcer)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
THIS LOCKER
AND LIN I MENT EM PORI U M
HOUSES A MAJOR LEAG U E
BASEBALL TEAM KNOWN
AS THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS,
ALL OF WHICH BY
WAY OF I NTRODUCTION
IN NEXT WEEK'S SHOW,
A WILD AND WOOLLY
YARN ABOUT THE GREAT
AM ERICAN PASTIME.
IT'S CALLED "TH E
MIGHTY CASEY" AND IT'S
ALL ABOUT A LEFT-HAN DER
WHO P ITCH ES
LIKE NOTHING HUMAN,
S IMPLY BECAUSE HE ISN'T.
MR. JACK WARDEN TAKES
US INTO THE STADI U M
NEXT WEEK FOR N IN E
FAST IN NINGS ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[eerie music]
BE SURE TO SEE
THE FUN-FILLED
FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS.
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS
OVER MOST OF
THESE STATIONS.