[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
A COMMONPLACE,
IF SOMEWHAT GRIM,
UNSOCIAL EVENT
KNOWN AS A
"NECKTIE PARTY."
THE GUEST OF DISHONOR,
A COWBOY NAMED JOE CASWELL,
JUST A MOMENT
AWAY FROM A ROPE,
A SHORT DANCE SEVERAL
FEET OFF THE GROUND.
AND THEN THE DARK
ETERNITY OF ALL EVIL MEN.
MR. JOE CASWELL,
WHO WHEN THE GOOD LORD
PASSED OUT A CONSCIENCE,
A HEART OF FEELING
FOR FELLOW MEN,
MUST HAVE BEEN
OUT FOR A BEER
AND MISSED OUT.
MR. JOE CASWELL
IN THE LAST
QUIET MOMENT
OF A VIOLENT LIFE.
REVEREN D.
NO NEED, I AIN'T
INTERESTED IN PRAYERS.
AND YOUR IMMORTAL
SOU L, CASWELL?
ARE YOU
INTERESTED IN THAT?
IT'S MY MORTAL N ECK
THAT CONCERNS ME NOW.
AND IT'S GONNA BE YOUR
PLEASURE TO SEE THAT IT'S
STRETCH ED A COUPLE FEET.
S I NCE THAT BOOK
AIN'T GOING TO H ELP,
MIGHT AS LEAVE
MAKE IT SHORT AND
GET IT OVER WITH.
J U DG E?
YOU GOT ANYTHING
TO SAY? IT'S YOUR
RIGHT, YOU KNOW.
THAT'S MY RIGHT,
IS IT, J U DG E?
THE YOU NG FELLOW I PUT
A HOLE IN HAD TOO MUCH
MOUTH, NOT ENOUGH BRAI NS.
I'D I NVITE HIM OUT
AGAIN TOMORROW IF I HAD
IT TO DO ALL OVER AGAIN.
YOU SHOT MY SON
IN THE BACK, CASWELL.
AND THAT'S A LONG COU NTRY
M I LE FROM AN I NVITATION
TO A SHOWDOWN.
NOW, THAT'S ALL
YOU GOT TO SAY,
I GOT THIS TO ADD.
I'D LIKE IT
TO TAKE AWHILE.
I'D LIKE YOU TO
FEEL IT, CASWELL.
THE MORE YOU KICK, THE
MORE J USTICE IF IG U RE
THERE IS IN THE WORLD.
WELL, I'LL DO A
J IG FOR YOU, PAPPY,
JUST LIKE A PU PPET.
HOW ABOUT IT,
CAN'T WE GET IT
OVER WITH?
I CAN TELL YOU THIS, CASWELL.
YOU'RE AN EVI L PERSON.
YOU'RE A DISEASE.
AND WHEN WE HANG YOU,
IT'S A SERVICE.
ALL RIGHT, GET ON
WITH THE JOB.
OH, MY DEAR GOD.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
TRY TO RELAX.
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I'LL EXPLAIN TO YOU
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
[raspy voice]
WHERE AM I?
YOU'RE A LONG
WAY FROM HOM E,
OLD FRI EN D.
A VERY LONG WAY.
[raspy voice]
WHERE?
YOU'RE IN NEW YORK CITY,
EIGHTY YEARS FROM
THE LAST MOM ENT OF
YOUR RECOLLECTION.
HOW? HOW?
[gasping]
BY THIS. THIS IS
A TIME MACHINE.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU
I NVOLVES PRI NCI PLES WHICH
YOU WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
FOR THE MOM ENT,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOUR PAST WAS,
BUT YOU'VE GOT A MOST
DISTING U ISH ED FUTU RE.
YOU'RE THE FIRST
TIME TRAVELER IN
THE H ISTORY OF MAN.
AND I'M GOING
TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO A WHOLE NEW WORLD.
AND YOU'RE GON NA
TELL ME ABOUT
AN OLD ON E.
(scientist)
AT 8: 1 5 THE SUBJECT
APPEARED DESPERATELY TIRED,
SO I PUT HIM TO BED.
AFTER TWO HOURS
I'VE DISCOVERED
THE FOLLOWING :
HIS NAME IS
JOSEPH CASWELL.
HE TELLS ME HE WAS A
TRAI L BOSS ON A CATTLE RANCH
IN THE TERRITORY OF MONTANA.
HIS LAST MOM ENT
OF RECOLLECTION
WAS NOVEM BER 1 4, 1 880.
HE SAYS HE WAS
RI DING H ERD WH EN
SU DDEN LY HE BLACKED OUT.
HE AWOKE TO F IN D
HIMSELF ON THE COT
OF MY LABORATORY.
HE FELT NO
SENSATIONS AND--
ONLY IN THE LAST FEW MOM ENTS
DID HE SEEM TO HAVE ANY GRASP
OF WHAT HAS OCCU RRED.
THERE'S ONE
DISTU RBING PO I NT.
THERE ARE THE MARKS OF
A ROPE ETCH ED DEEPLY
INTO HIS N ECK.
HE HAS NO
EXPLANATION FOR THIS.
AND I HAVE ONE
OTHER OBSERVATION
HARDLY SCI ENTIF IC.
I DON'T LIKE HIS LOOKS.
I DON'T LIKE THE
EYES OR THE FACE
OR THE EXPRESS ION.
I GET A FEELING
OF DISQU I ET, I--
I GET A FEELING THAT
I'VE TAKEN A 1 9TH
CENTURY PRI M ITIVE
AND PLACED HIM IN
A 20TH CENTURY J U NG LE.
AND H EAVEN
H ELP WHOEVER
G ETS IN HIS WAY.
[door opens]
THAT'S F I RE RIGHT
OUT OF THE AIR.
I THOUGHT YOU
WERE TIRED.
I AM.
THERE'S PLENTY
OF TIME TO SLEEP.
AND PLENTY OF
TIME FOR THAT.
NOW I WANNA LOOK AT
THAT WORLD OUT THERE.
I WANNA SEE IF THERE ARE
THINGS OUT THERE LIKE
YOU DESCRI BED TO ME.
CARRIAG ES WITHOUT
HORSES AND BU I LDINGS--
THEY'RE OUT
THERE, CASWELL.
THINGS THAT YOU'VE
N EVER SEEN BEFORE.
THINGS YOU
CAN'T I MAG IN E.
[engines humming,
horns honking]
[sirens wailing
and engines throbbing]
BUT SOME THINGS
DON'T CHANG E.
IDEAS, CONCEPTS,
THINGS LIKE
RIGHT AND WRONG.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
ONCE THERE WAS A DEPUTY
SH ERI FF IN DODG E CITY.
TRI ED TO BEAT THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THEM INTO MY BACK
WITH A WET ROPE.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
RIGHT AND WRONG.
AND WHAT ABOUT
J USTICE, CASWELL?
WHAT ABOUT J USTICE?
AM I SU PPOSED TO
KNOW ABOUT J USTICE?
MORE THAN MOST
M EN, PROBABLY.
RIGHT AND WRONG,
THEY CAN TRY TO
BEAT INTO YOU.
BUT J USTICE, CASWELL,
THIS CAME AT THE EN D
OF A ROPE, DIDN'T IT?
THAT'S WHERE YOU WERE
WHEN I REACHED
BACK INTO TIME.
YOU WERE AT THE EN D
OF A ROPE, WEREN'T
YOU, CASWELL?
SIX OR EIGHT FEET OFF
THE GROU N D, AND I GOT TO YOU
IN THAT FRACTION OF A MOM ENT
BEFORE YOUR
N ECK WAS BROKEN.
WHEN YOU'RE DANG LING
AT THE END OF A ROPE
IT DON'T MATTER
WH ETHER YOU'RE
ONE FOOT OFF THE
G ROU N D OR ONE H U N DRED.
YOU KI LLED SOMEON E.
A WHOLE TERRITORY FU LL.
I STOPPED
COUNTING AFTER 20.
WELL?
I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO SEND YOU BACK.
BACK?
BACK TO WHERE
YOU BELONG.
BACK TO THAT VERY
MOM ENT, IF I CAN.
AND THAT'S SU PPOSED
TO BE J USTICE, HUH?
I DIED ONCE
ALREADY, MISTER.
I BEEN TO H ELL.
NOW I'M BACK.
AND THOSE 20 MEN THAT
YOU KI LLED, CASWELL?
THEY DIED WITH
NO DISCOM FORT?
MISTER, Y-YOU'RE
JUST TALKING WORDS.
J USTICE, RIGHT
AND WRONG.
THEY SOU N D GOOD IN
THIS NICE WARM ROOM
WITH A N ICE
FU LL STOMACH,
JUST A FEW FEET AWAY
FROM A SOFT BED.
THEY SOU N D NICE AND
THEY GO DOWN EASY!
BUT YOU JUST TRY 'EM
ON AN ICE-COLD MESA
WHERE ANOTHER MAN'S BREAD
OR ANOTHER MAN'S JACKET
STANDS BETWEEN YOU
AND STAYING ALIVE.
YOU GET IN THIS MACHINE
OF YOURS AND YOU GO
BACK TO WHERE I WAS,
AND YOU TALK ABOUT
YOUR LAW AND YOUR
ORDER AND YOUR J USTICE.
THEY'RE GONNA
SOUND DIFFERENT!
MISTER, I KNOW
YOUR KIND.
YOUR CLEAN-FACED, YOUR
JOH N NY-COM E-LATELY DAN DIES.
YOU COME OUT IN YOUR
WARM TRAI NS ROLLING OVER
THE GRAVES OF MEN LIKE ME!
I JUST HATE
YOUR KIND!
[tape recorder rewinding]
[over tape recorder]
AND I HAVE ONE OTHER
OBSERVATION HARDLY SCIENTIFIC.
I DON'T LIKE
HIS LOOKS.
I DON'T LIKE THE
EYES OR THE FACE
OR THE EXPRESSION.
I GET A FEELING
THAT I'VE TAKEN A
1 9TH CENTURY PRIM ITIVE
AND PLACED HIM IN
A 20TH CENTURY JUNGLE.
AND HEAVEN
HELP WHOEVER
GETS IN HIS WAY.
[car horn honking]
[horns honking]
[horn honking]
[tires screeching]
[ringing]
[ringing continues]
(operator)
THERE IS OVERTIME.
PLEASE DEPOSIT 25 CENTS.
HELLO? HELLO?
THERE IS OVERTIME.
PLEASE DEPOSIT 25 CENTS.
[swing music playing]
WHAT'LL IT BE?
[swing playing
on jukebox]
[music stops]
EXPENS IVE EVENING FOR
YOU, PAL. THAT'S
GONNA COST.
HEAR ME?
THERE'S SO MUCH NO ISE.
LOOK, BUDDY, IF YOU
DON'T PAY FOR IT,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO.
SO LET'S HAVE
NO TROU BLE, HUH?
IF YOU GOT ANY--
U H, EASY, PAL, EASY.
JUST BRING ME
ONE OF THOSE.
WELL?
NOTHING, PAL,
NO ARG U MENT.
WHAT IS THAT?
WHERE DOES THE
MUSIC COME FROM?
THAT THING? THAT'S
A JUKEBOX, JUST A
PLAIN OLD JUKEBOX.
YOU BEEN IN STI R, BUDDY?
NO, IT'S, IT'S J UST
THAT I NEED SOME SLEEP.
AND THOSE, THOSE THINGS
THAT ARE RU N NING AROUND!
THINGS?
THOSE-THOSE CARRIAG ES
WITHOUT HORSES,
AN D-AND THE LIGHTS
GOING ON AND OFF.
AND THE NO ISE,
IT'S-IT'S LIKE
TH U N DER ALL THE TIME.
BUDDY, WHY DON'T
YOU GO HOME AND
SACK DOWN, HUH?
AND GET A GOOD
NIGHT'S SLEEP.
TAKE A COUPLE OF BOTTLES
WITH YOU. THAT'S WHAT
YOU NEED IS SLEEP.
HERE, TAKE THESE
HOME WITH YOU.
WELL, DON'T-DON'T
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
IT'S A WIN DOW.
HERE, WE'LL-WE'LL GIVE
YOU A DEMONSTRATION, HUH?
ALL RIGHT, HOM BRE,
YOU GOT YOUR
CHANCE TO DRAW.
NOW, YOU BETTER
MAKE YOUR MOVE.
ALL RIGHT, COWBOY,
YOU GOTTA PAY FOR THIS.
POLICE! POLICE!
POLICE!
[car horn honking]
[horns honking]
[brakes screeching]
[woman screams]
[whistle blowing]
[people yelling]
[siren blaring]
[panting]
MISTER, YOU--
MAN, YOU--
H ELP ME, PLEASE!
H ELP ME!
I THOUGHT THE
PLACE WAS EM PTY.
JUST MOVE AWAY
FROM THE DESK, COWBOY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHAT DO I WANT?
WHAT DO YOU WANT,
BU FFALO B I LL?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
WHATEVER IS AROUND LOOSE.
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU GOT HERE BEFORE ME.
SAVED ME A LITTLE
TROU BLE. THANKS.
BUT I'M HERE NOW.
YOU KNOW, I
USUALLY GO TO
BED THIS EARLY.
SO WITH THE PLACE
BEING DARK, IF IG U RED
I'D BE ALL ALON E.
YOU CHECKED
THE DESK, DID YOU?
I GU ESS HE DON'T KEEP
MUCH CASH AROUND HERE.
IF IG U RED MAYBE
A KEY TO A DRAWER
OR SOMETHING.
SEE? I EXPECT HE'S GOT
A WALL SAFE OR SOMETHING
AROUND HERE, DON'T YOU?
HEY, COWBOY, I
ASKED YOU A QU ESTION.
DON'T YOU F IG U RE
HE'S GOT A WALL SAFE OR
SOMETHING AROUND HERE?
[groans]
[electronic whirring]
[electronic beeping]
[whirring increases in pitch]
[muffled]
HEY! H ELP!
H ELP, SOMEBODY!
H ELP ME GET OUT!
H ELP, H ELP.
H ELP ME. SOMEBODY!
H ELP ME! H ELP ME!
CUT HIM DOWN,
HURRY UP. CUT HIM DOWN.
THAT AIN'T
JOE CASWELL.
THAT AIN'T THE
GUY WE HANG ED.
LOOK AT HIS CLOTH ES.
WHAT KIND OF CLOTH ES
ARE THEY?
WHO IS IT?
THIS IS NOT
CASWELL, REVEREN D.
IT'S A STRANG ER.
WHAT KIND OF
DEVIL'S WORK IS THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW I F
IT IS DEVIL'S WORK.
DID WE HANG AN
IN NOCENT MAN, THEN?
I HOPE NOT.
I PRAY TO GOD NOT.
(narrator)
THIS IS NOVEMBER 1 880,
THE AFTERMATH OF
A NECKTIE PARTY.
THE VICTIM'S NAME,
PAUL JOHNSON, A M INOR
LEAGUE CRIM INAL
AND THE TAKER OF
ANOTHER HUMAN LIFE.
NO COMMENT ON HIS
DEATH SAVE THIS.
JUSTICE CAN SPAN YEARS.
RETRIBUTION IS NOT
SUBJECT TO A CALENDAR.
TONIGHT'S CASE IN POINT
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
THE MAN WHO LIVES
IN THIS TEN EM ENT
IS AN AGING FIGHTER
NAM ED BOLI E JACKSON.
OVER THE H I LL AT AG E 36.
FROM LEAVING TOO MUCH OF
HIMSELF IN TOO MANY ARENAS
FOR TOO MANY YEARS
BEFORE TOO MANY
SCREAMING PEOPLE.
AND NEXT WEEK HE LOOKS
FOR A M I RACLE, AND H E
F IN DS IT IN A LITTLE BOY.
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE
NEXT WEEK, THE BIG
TALL WISH.
SOMETHING VERY,
VERY SPECIAL.
I HOPE WE'LL
SEE YOU THEN.
[eerie music]
BE SURE TO THE SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS,
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE STATIONS.