[eerie music]
(narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
PORTRAIT OF
A MAN AT WORK.
THE ONLY WORK HE'S
EVER DONE. THE ONLY
WORK HE KNOWS.
HIS NAME IS
HENRY FRANCIS VALENTINE,
BUT HE CALLS HIMSELF ROCKY
BECAUSE THAT'S THE WAY
HIS LIFE HAS BEEN.
ROCKY AND PERILOUS
AND UPHILL AT A DEAD
RUN ALL THE WAY.
HE'S TIRED NOW, TIRED
OF RUNNING OR WANTING
OF WAITING FOR THE
BREAKS THAT COME TO
OTHERS BUT NEVER TO HIM.
NEVER TO ROCKY VALENTINE.
[Police sirens approaching]
[gunshots]
STOP! STOP
OR I'LL SHOOT!
NOT THIS TIME,
YOU LOUSY SCREW.
[gunshots]
(narrator)
A SCARED,
ANGRY LITTLE MAN.
HE THINKS IT'S
ALL OVER NOW,
BUT HE'S WRONG.
FOR ROCKY VALENTINE,
IT'S JUST THE BEGINNING.
MR. VALENTIN E.
MR. VALENTIN E!
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS P I P.
CAN I H ELP YOU?
HOW DO YOU
KNOW MY NAME?
IT'S MY JOB TO KNOW
EVERYTHING ABOUT YOU.
ARE YOU A COP?
OH, NO, NO, I'M A--
I'M YOUR GUIDE,
AS IT WERE.
[chuckIes]
G U I DE, EH?
I NEED LIKE
A HOLE IN THE H EAD.
WHOA.
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU HAD A SLIGHT ACCIDENT.
BUT DON'T WORRY. YOU'LL BE
AS F IT AS A NEW F I DDLE SOON.
I'M SURE YOU'D LIKE TO CHANG E
OUT OF THOSE RU M PLED CLOTH ES,
EH, MR. VALENTIN E?
HOLD IT A MINUTE.
I WANNA KNOW HOW
YOU KNOW MY NAME.
I'VE ALREADY
TOLD YOU.
YOU TOLD ME NOTHING.
LET ME CLU E YOU, FATSO.
I DON'T LIKE GAM ES.
OH, THAT ISN'T TRU E,
MR. VALENTIN E.
WHY-WHY, YOU LIKE
ROU LETTE, BLACKJACK,
POKER, CRAPS,
AND BETWEEN THE AG ES
OF SEVEN AND TEN
YOU WERE QU ITE FON D
OF M U M BLETY-PEG.
WHAT ARE YOU
AFTER, ANYWAY?
ONLY ONE THING,
MR. VALENTIN E.
YOUR COM FORT.
MY JOB IS TO SEE TO IT
THAT YOU GET WHAT YOU
WANT, WHATEVER IT MAY BE.
YEAH? IN
EXCHANG E FOR WHAT?
NOTHING AT ALL,
MR. VALENTIN E.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY FREE.
DON'T PUT ME ON, FATSO.
NOTHING'S FREE. NOTHING!
ANYTHING I EVER GOT
IN THIS LOUSY WORLD
I HAD TO DRAG OUT OF IT,
SO DON'T PUT ME ON.
NOW, WHAT'S THE P ITCH?
YOU WANT ME TO DO A
JOB FOR YOU, RIGHT?
I'M AFRAI D YOU
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NO? ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE.
GIVE ME YOUR WALLET, CRACKER.
COME ON, COME ON.
I DON'T HAVE A WALLET.
COME ON, SANTA CLAUS.
NO, HON ESTLY. WAIT,
WAIT, MR. VALENTIN E.
IT ISN'T A WALLET
YOU WANT, IS IT?
NO, NO. IT'S MONEY.
THREE H U N DRED,
FIVE H U N DRED.
SEVEN H U N DRED BUCKS.
WILL THAT BE ENOUGH
FOR NOW, THEN?
YOU GOT MORE?
OH, YES, AS MUCH
AS YOU WANT. NOW,
SHALL WE?
HEY, FATS.
NOW, DON'T TRY
ANYTHING FU N NY, HM?
YOU LIKE IT?
YEAH.
YEAH, IT'S SOME
PAD, ALL RIGHT.
WHO'S IT BELONG TO?
SOME PHONY POLITICIAN?
WHY, IT BELONGS TO
YOU, MR. VALENTIN E.
MM-HM.
THAT IS IF, UH,
IF YOU APPROVE.
YEAH, I APPROVE.
OF COURSE,
WE CAN MAKE ANY
CHANG ES YOU WISH.
YOU SEE, I WASN'T TOO SURE
ABOUT THE H I-F I RIGHT
OVER THERE, BUT--
YOU MEAN, ALL THIS GETS
THROWN INTO THE DEAL?
OH, IT'S ALREADY
IN THE DEAL AS YOU
CALL IT, MR. VALENTINE.
LOOK HERE.
YOU SEE?
AH.
THAT IS THE
MASTER BEDROOM.
AH, AH, AH,
AH. AFTER YOU.
THERE.
THE BATH ROOM'S IN THERE. I'M
SURE YOU'D LIKE A CHANG E OF
CLOTHING AND FRESH EN UP A B IT.
YEAH. YEAH, SURE.
BUT FIRST OF ALL,
WHAT'S THE P ITCH?
COME ON, THE P ITCH, THE CATCH
THE GI M M ICK. WHAT DO I GOTTA
DO FOR ALL THIS?
NOTHING, I CAN'T
TELL YOU MORE.
I GET IT. YOU'RE
JUST A GOON, HUH?
YOU WORK FOR
SOMEBODY ELSE, RIGHT?
IN A WAY, YEAH.
WHEN DO I MEET HIM?
THE BIG BOY, YOUR BOSS?
[chuckIing]
I REALLY COULDN'T SAY.
ALL RIGHT, GOON.
I CAN WAIT.
ANY PARTICU LAR COLOR
OR STYLE, S I R?
NO, YOU PICK IT.
OH, I COULD HARDLY
PRESU ME TO DO THAT!
HOWEVER, BEARING IN MIND
THAT YOU FAVOR A NICE CHECK,
I THOUGHT PERHAPS--
YEAH, THAT'LL DO.
YEAH. WE HAVE QU ITE
A WI DE SELECTION
OF TI ES HERE,
AND I BELIEVE THAT YELLOW
IS YOUR FAVORITE COLOR.
[chuckIes]
WHAT'S THE
MATTER WITH YOU?
YOU GOT NO TASTE?
NOW, THAT'S A TI E, SEE?
HEY. HUH?
[Iaughs]
IT F ITS.
[Iaughing]
OF COURSE.
YES, VERY IMPRESS IVE, S I R.
YEAH, WELL, I'LL SAY THIS,
YOUR GUY KNOWS CLOTH ES.
MR. VALENTIN E.
WHERE DID THAT
COME FROM?
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT BE A LITTLE
H U NG RY, SO I JUST ORDERED UP
SOMETHING FOR YOU.
U H-U H. YOU EAT IT.
OH, BUT I DON'T EAT.
I HAVEN'T EATEN I N--
IT MUST BE TWO
OR THREE CENTU RI ES.
ANYTHING WRONG WITH IT?
NO.
THEN EAT IT.
BUT I CAN'T.
I'VE FORGOTTEN HOW.
I GET IT.
GIVE A GUY SOME N EW
CLOTH ES AND A BATH
AND THEN PO ISON HIM, HUH?
PRETTY SMART, PRETTY
SMART, FATSO,
BUT NOT SMART ENOUGH!
A BU LLETPROOF VEST, HUH?
LET'S SEE HOW YOUR
H EAD HOLDS UP.
MR. VALENTIN E, PLEASE.
I COULDN'T HAVE MISSED,
NOT AT THIS RANG E.
MAYBE--
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM?
THIS WASN'T HERE BEFORE.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
WHERE AM I?
MR. VALENTIN E, DO YOU
REMEMBER WHEN WE MET
EARLI ER TODAY?
I TOLD YOU I WAS,
IN A SENSE, YOUR GU I DE,
AND YOU SAID
YOU NEEDED A GU I DE
LIKE A HOLE IN THE H EAD?
AS A MATTER OF STRICT FACT,
YOU HAD A HOLE IN THE H EAD,
ONLY A SHORT TIME BEFORE.
A BU LLET HOLE.
OH, YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
THE COPS, THEY--
THEN IMUST--
I MUST BE DEAD.
M M-H M.
WELL, IF I'M DEAD,
TH EN-THEN ALL OF THIS,
THE JO I NT,
TH E-THE CLOTH ES,
TH E-THE BOOZE.
THEN IMUST
BE IN H EAVEN.
YEAH, THAT'S IT. THAT'S
IT, I'M IN H EAVEN, RIGHT?
YOU'RE MY GUARDIAN
ANGEL OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
SOMETHING LIKE
THAT, YEAH.
ANYTHING I WANT, EH?
ANYTHING, ANYTHING.
YEAH, BIG TALK, FATSO.
I WANNA SEE A LITTLE
ACTION NOW.
RIGHT NOW I WANT
A M I LLION BUCKS
IN FIVE "G" NOTES.
AN D, UH, AND A CH ICK
THAT WON'T QU IT.
I MEAN, I MEAN,
JUST LIKE STACKED,
LIKE, LIKE, LIKE,
LIKE, BEAUTIFUL, HUH?
WELL?
AS FOR THE M ILLION,
LOOK IN THAT DRAWER.
THERE?
M M-H M M.
A M I LLION.
A M I LLION BUCKS!
[Iaughs]
HEY, BUT WHAT
ABOUT, UH, UH?
[lively dance
music playing]
NOW I KNOW
I'M IN H EAVEN.
WILL THERE BE
ANYTHING ELSE, S I R?
YEAH, THERE WILL BE,
FATS. THERE WILL BE,
JUST STICK AROUND.
H IYA, DOLL.
OOO-HOO-HOO!
YEE! OOO-HOO-HOO!
YEE!
[Iaughs]
(croupier)
PLACE YOUR BETS,
LADI ES AND GENTLEM EN.
NO MORE BETS, PLEASE.
THIRTY-THREE BLACK.
HEY, HOW ABOUT THAT.
I WIN AGAIN. HEY, FATS,
COME HERE, COME HERE.
PUT YOUR MONEY
ON THE TABLE, FATS.
RIGHT THERE, NUMBER 1 4 RED.
ROCKY IS HOT TONIGHT.
AM I RIGHT, DOLLS?
I'M AFRAI D
I DON'T HAVE
ANY MONEY, S I R.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY?
WHAT DO THEY PAY YOU, IN
HALOS OR SOMETHING?
PLACE YOUR BETS, LADIES
AND GENTLEMEN. PLACE
YOUR BETS.
[Iaughs]
NO MORE BETS, LADI ES AND
G ENTLEM EN, NO MORE BETS.
FOURTEEN RED.
WHOO-HOO!
[shouting joyfuIIy]
THAT MAKES WHAT, WHAT,
HUH? 40 GRAND IN AN HOUR.
HOW ABOUT IT?
IS ROCKY HOT OR
IS ROCKY HOT?
ROCKY'S HOT.
GO TRADE THIS IN FOR GOLD,
BABY. AND I TELL YOU I'M
GONNA BUY AND SELL THIS JO I NT.
HERE, GO GET THEM.
HEY, HEY, HEY, BABY.
THERE'S 40 GRAND IN THERE
AND I COU NT REAL GOOD.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
ALL RIGHT. AH.
I GOT THIS TABLE SPOOKED.
LET'S GO SEE WHAT'S SHAKING
WITH THE CU BES, HUH?
PLACE YOUR BETS,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
HERE, BABY, GO
GET ME SOME J U ICE.
WHOO-HOO!
HEY, LOOK AT THIS!
LOOK AT THIS!
THERE MUST BE 600 BUCKS
HERE, HUH? HOW ABOUT
THAT, FATS?
HERE YOU ARE, SWEETHEART.
GO BUY YOURSELF A DRESS
FOR FREE.
A PRESENT
FROM ROCKY.
[Iaughs]
NEED A CAR, S I R?
YES, A BIG CONVERTI BLE.
BE CAREFU L ON THE
WAY, YOU KI D.
YES, S I R.
SOMETHING BOTHER YOU,
MR. VALENTIN E?
YEAH, HIM.
LOUSY SCREW.
THlNKS HE'S [inaudible]
JUST 'CAUSE HE'S GOT
A COUPLE ON INCHES ON ME.
OH, DEAR, THAT WAS
IN DISCREET OF ME.
BETTER?
YEAH!
HEY, SCREW,
COME HERE.
YOU GOT YOUR HAT ON,
CROOKED TROOPER.
[Iaughs]
READY, S I R.
COME ON, GET I N, GIRLS.
[grunts]
HERE YOU ARE, KI D.
KEEP THE CHANG E.
ALL RIGHT NOW, LET'S
OPEN THIS BABY UP AND
SEE WHAT SHE CAN DO.
[women squeal]
[Iaughs]
ALL RIGHT, GIRLS.
HERE WE GO, HERE WE GO.
INTO THE CRACKER BOX.
ON E, TWO, THREE.
IT'S MAGIC TIME.
HEY, FATS, I WANT YOU
TO GET RID OF THAT H EAP
I'VE BEEN DRIVING.
IT GOES FAST ENOUGH.
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
YEAH, THE
ASHTRAYS ARE FU LL.
HEY, GIRLS, COULD YOU
WAIT IN HERE FOR A MINUTE?
I WANNA TALK TO FATS
FOR A MINUTE, ALL RIGHT?
IN WE GO.
HEY, FATS, HOW ABOUT
TOMORROW WE LOOK UP
SOME OF MY OLD BU DDI ES?
LIKE MATT GORMAN
OR F IN K M ITCH ELL,
S I LKY ARMSTRONG, HUH?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
THEY DIDN'T MAKE IT?
OH, IT'S NOT THAT,
MR. VALENTIN E. IT'S, UH--
IT'S RATHER DI FF ICU LT
TO EXPLAIN, REALLY.
ALL OF THIS,
ALL IT'S YOUR
OWN PRIVATE DOMAI N.
IT WAS MADE ESPECIALLY
FOR YOU ALON E.
OH, WHAT ABOUT THEM?
YOU MEAN THEY'RE PROPS
LIKE IN A MOVIE?
IN A SENSE, YES. EVERYTHING
HERE IS, EXCEPT OF COURSE,
YOU AND ME.
U H-HUH. LOOK, S IT DOWN
FOR A MINUTE, FATSO. I
WANNA ASK YOU SOMETHING.
IT'S BEEN KIND OF
BUGGING ME ANYWAY.
I MEAN,
HOW COME THEY
LET ME IN HERE, HUH?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS ONLY
FOR SCHOOLTEACH ERS
AND LIKE THAT.
OH, WE HAVE SOME
SCHOOLTEACH ERS HERE.
THERE M UST'VE BEEN
SOMETHING REAL GOOD
I DONE SOMETIME,
SOMETHING THAT MADE UP
FOR EVERYTHING ELSE, HUH?
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
BUT, UH, BUT WHAT?
WHEN DID I EVER
DO ANYTHING GOOD?
U H, WELL, LISTEN, HOW
DO IF IN D ABOUT
TH IS, HUH?
WELL, WE HAVE A HALL
OF RECORDS HERE. WOULD YOU
LIKE ME TO TAKE YOU THERE?
IS IT OPEN
AT THIS HOUR?
IT'S ALMOST LIGHT.
IT'S ALWAYS OPEN.
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO.
[Iaughs]
HEY, DOLLS, DON'T
GO AWAY, WILL YA?
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I JUST WANNA
GET SOMETHING
CLEARED UP WITH FATS.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
AH.
"HENRY FRANCIS VALENTIN E."
[chuckIes]
"BORN 1 923,
BROOKLYN, NEW YORK.
AG E OF SIX,
SLAUGHTERED SMALL DOG."
WELL, WHY NOT?
HE BIT ME.
"AG E OF SEVEN,
STOLE 1 4 TOYS
FROM DI ME STORE.
AG E OF EIGHT,
ORGAN IZED STREET
GANG, THE ANGELS."
HOW ABOUT THAT, HUH?
THAT'S WHAT WE CALLED
OU RSELVES, THE ANGELS.
THERE WAS A
G REAT LITTLE BU NCH.
"AG E OF N IN E, BROKE
INTO B ICYCLE STORE."
W-WHAT IS THIS ANYWAY?
YOUR RECORD.
YOU DON'T THINK
THERE'S BEEN SOME
M ISTAKE, DO YOU?
NOT LIKELY.
I CAN'T F IG U RE IT. BUT I F
IT DON'T BOTHER HIM, I AIN'T
GONNA LET IT BOTHER ME.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO
DO NOW, MR. VALENTIN E?
U H. GEE,
I DON'T KNOW.
FOOL AROUND
WITH THE DOLLS.
SHOOT SOME MORE
CRAPS, MAYBE.
I DON'T KNOW.
IF YOU NEED ME FOR ANYTHING,
MR. VALENTIN E, J UST
DIAL P-I-P.
YEAH.
TH I RTEEN BLACK,
LADI ES AND GENTLEM EN.
TH I RTEEN BLACK.
THANKS.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR CH I P, S I R?
MAI L 'EM TO ME.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
STRAIG HT FLUSH.
ROYAL FLUSH.
YOU WIN AGAIN,
MR. VALENTIN E.
YEAH, I KNOW.
THAT'S ALL I EVER DO
IN THIS N UTTY JO I NT
IS WI N, WI N, WI N.
IS THERE ANYTHING
ELSE I CAN DO FOR YOU?
YEAH, GET OUT OF HERE,
WI LL, YA? I'M S ICK OF
LOOKING AT YOU.
COME ON, OUT, OUT.
YOU, TOO. COME ON,
OUT, OUT. LET'S GO.
COME ON, GET OUT.
COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON! KEEP MOVING.
STEP IT UP.
COME ON, COME ON.
OUT, OUT, OUT.
DU M B BROADS.
WHO NEEDS THEM?
[chuckIing]
HEY.
YES, MR. VALENTIN E?
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
WILL YOU STOP
CREEPING AROUND?
ANYTHING YOU SAY, S I R.
ANYTHING I SAY.
KNOCK IT OFF, WILL YOU?
WHY, IS
SOMETHING WRONG?
NO, NOTHING'S WRONG.
EVERYTHING IS JUST PEACHY!
I'VE BEEN IN THIS DU M P
FOR A MONTH AND I CAN'T
STAND IT ANYMORE!
BUT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL SPELL
IT OUT FOR YOU, FATS.
I'M BORED, BORED!
THERE'S NO
EXCITEM ENT AROUND
HERE. NO KICKS!
YEAH, BUT THE GAMBLING.
I THOUGHT YOU ENJOYED THAT.
I DO, BUT WHEN YOU
WIN EVERY TIME,
THAT AIN'T GAMBLING,
THAT'S CHARITY.
I COULD ARRANG E FOR YOU
TO LOSE OCCAS IONALLY I F
YOU'D LIKE. WOULD THAT H ELP?
IT MIGHT.
NO, NO, IT'S NO GOOD.
IT AIN'T THE SAM E.
I WOULD KNOW.
AH, PERHAPS YOU MISS
YOUR OLD VOCATION.
IS THAT IT?
NOW YOU'RE GETTING IT.
THERE'S A BAN K
AT THE CORN ER
THAT YOU COULD ROB.
OR WOULD YOU PREFER
A J EWELRY STORE?
NO, BAN K'S OKAY.
F IN E, F IN E. AS TO
THE GETAWAY CAR,
WE HAVE QU ITE A LARGE
VARI ETY TO CHOOSE FROM.
SOMETHING I NCONSP ICUOUS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
IS THERE A CHANCE
THAT I COULD GET CAUG HT?
OF COURSE, IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU'D LIKE. LET ME J UST
MAKE A NOTE OF IT.
COME ON, S IT DOWN,
FATS, S IT DOWN.
NOW, LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO EXPLAIN THIS,
BUT IT JUST AIN'T
THE SAME THING.
WHAT'S THE KICK KNOCKING
OFF A BAN K IF EVERYBODY
KNOWS ABOUT IT, HUH?
AND THE DAM ES. I--
I NEVER THOUGHT
I WOULD GET BORED WITH
BEAUTIFUL DAM ES, BUT--
LOOK, I WOULDN'T
EXPECT AN ANGEL TO
U N DERSTAND THIS, SEE?
BUT-BUT BEING A BIG
GUY WITH A CH ICK,
IT DON'T MEAN ANYTHING
IF IT'S ALL SET UP
IN ADVANCE.
AND I MEAN, EVERYTHING
IS GREAT HERE, SEE?
REALLY GREAT.
IT'S JUST THE WAY
I ALWAYS I MAG IN ED IT
EXCEPT THAT, THAT--
JUST BETWEEN
YOU AND ME, FATS,
I DON'T THINK
I BELONG HERE.
I DON'T THINK IF IT IN.
OH, NONSENSE,
OF COURSE YOU DO.
NO, I MEAN IT,
I MEAN IT. J UST
SOMEBODY M UST'VE GOOFED.
IF I GOTTA STAY
HERE ANOTHER DAY
I'M GONNA GO N UTS!
LOOK, LOOK,
I DON'T BELONG
IN H EAVEN, SEE?
I WANNA GO TO
THE OTHER PLACE.
H EAVEN?
WHATEVER GAVE YOU THE IDEA
YOU WERE IN H EAVEN,
MR. VALENTIN E?
THIS IS THE OTHER PLACE!
[Iaughs maniacaIIy]
(narrator)
A SCARED, ANGRY LITTLE MAN
WHO NEVER GOT A BREAK.
NOW HE HAS EVERYTHING
HE'S EVER WANTED,
AND HE'S GOING
TO HAVE TO LIVE
WITH IT FOR ETERNITY
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR OF
TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, YOU'LL SPEN D
A FEW RATHER U N FORG ETTABLE
HOURS IN THIS LIVING ROOM
WATCHING MISS JANICE RU LE
AND MR. SH EPPERD STRU DWICK
PARTAKE OF A DRAMATIC
DELICACY THAT IT IS ONE
PART N U RSERY RHYM E,
ONE PART TERROR.
THIS IS DESIGN ED FOR THOSE
OF YOU WHO ARE GETTING
TOO MUCH SLEEP.
NEXT WEEK ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
NIGHTMARE AS A CHILD.
I HOPE WE'LL SEE YOU THEN.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
BE SURE TO SEE
THE FUN-FILLED
FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS,
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE STATIONS.
THE TWILIGHT ZONE IS
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY THE NEWEST
COFFEE SENSATION
ON THE MODERN SCENE.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA COFFEE.
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY THE COFFEE
WITH THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
AROMA, FLAVOR,
BUT NOT CAFFEINE.
NEW AROMA-ROAST
SANKA COFFEE.
AND THE PERFECT COFFEE
ON THE MODERN SCENE,
BRAND NEW
AROMA-ROAST SANKA.
GIVES YOU THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
RICH, RARE AROMA,
HARDY FULL-BODIED
FLAVOR AND NO CAFFEINE.
YES, THE RICHEST AROMA,
THE HARDIEST FLAVOR.
ALL THE BEST
OF THE COFFEE BEAN.
AND GREATEST OF ALL,
YOU CAN DRINK ALL
YOU WANT.
NEW AROMA-ROAST SANKA IS
STILL 97% CAFFEINE FREE.
SANKA COFFEE,
AROMA, FLAVOR,
BUT NO CAFFEINE.
SQU EEZE THE PACKAG E.
GO AHEAD.