[blows]
I just ate a bag of cheese boodles
without using my hands.
Lazy Tuesday, you are
delivering in a big way.
[chuckles] Yeah, it's
nice to finally have a day
where nothing interesting
happens whatsoever.
[muffled roar]
[screaming]
Everyone get down!
Don't let it taste human flesh.
- What is it?
- Can we keep it?
Kill it, kill it!
Patience.
[growling, screeching]
And... gotcha!
Great. Now get it outta here.
Smells like if death could barf.
Grunkle Ford, do you
need any help with that?
I've read all about these
creatures in your journal,
- and I think I know...
- No! I'm sorry, Dipper.
On the dark, weird road I travel,
I'm afraid you cannot follow.
Well, call me for dinner.
[beeps]
Maybe next time then?
Or not.
- Or never.
- Oh, Dipper, don't take it so hard.
No, do take it hard.
Take it hard and serious.
My brother is a
dangerous know-it-all
and the stuff he's
messing with is even worse.
Do yourself a favor and stay
away from him, you hear me?
But Grunkle Stan, all summer long,
I've wanted to know who the
author of the journal was.
Now the guy lives in our basement,
and I can't even talk to him.
Don't worry about
what's on the basement.
- You belong up here with me and Mabel.
- Yeah!
Besides, the season finale
of Duck-tective is airing this Friday.
That's all the mystery
you need this week.
Come on, quack with us, Dipper.
Quack, quack, quack.
[chuckles] Yeah.
[both quacking]
[quacking continues]
Quack, quack, quack!
Why isn't he quacking?
[title music]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
2x13 - Dungeons, Dungeons,
and More Dungeons
Dear Mom and Dad,
we've been in Gravity
Falls for a few months,
and so much has happened.
Just yesterday, gravity
reversed itself, almost destroyed
the universe, and totally
wrecking the whole town.
Well, they say it was an earthquake,
but you know what I think?
I think I'm gonna have to start serving
pineapple right-side up cake.
[laughs] Am I right?
Am I right?
Let the rebuilding of the town begin.
Wrecking ball, start wrecking things.
[laughs]
But the coolest part of
the summer was
Grunkle Stan's twin brother
came out of this portal thingy.
Now we have two grunkles
for the price of one.
And they are adorable together.
"We love each other so much!"
[kissing sounds]
Mabel, you'll never guess what
I found at the store today.
Dogs. Dogs with hats!
No. It's my favorite
fantasy-talking, level-counting,
statistics and graph-paper
involving game of all time:
Dungeons, Dungeons,
and More Dungeons!
- You wanna play it with me?
- Well, I do like unicorns,
and that hot elf looks promising.
- How do you play?
- The rules are simple.
First, you roll a 38-sided
die to determine the level
of each player's statistical
analysis power orb.
These orbs relate
directly to the amount of
power quadrants that your
tem has dominion over,
which is inverse to the anti-quadrants
in your quadrant satchel.
- And then we ride unicorns?
- Yes! [gasps]
And no.
First, we make a graph.
[groans]
This is like Homework the Game.
Come on, Mabel. I need at
least two people to play.
Oh, wow, would you look at that?
Two people!
Hey, Soos, up for a little
game of D & D & More D?
Sorry, Dipper, I don't go in for
that pen-and-paper kinda stuff.
- I'm more of an FCLORP-er.
- A what?
FCLORP.
Foam & Cardboard Legitimate
Outdoor Role Playing.
It is where a passionate
brethren of craftsmen
bring their dreams to magical reality.
- Let yon priestess go, Elf Mage.
- Never, Paladin Radmaster.
Fireball, fireball, fireball.
I'm a fortress.
Well, thanks anyways, Soos.
Say, is this that game
that's mostly math and writing
and isn't anything like
the picture on the box?
Yes, it is! You wanna
play with me, Grunkle Stan?
Ha! Look, kid, I prefer to
do my dice rolling in Vegas.
Besides, only a game designed by nerds
would have "Charisma"
as a fantasy power.
Check this out:
"When facing yon adversaries,
- shield thyself under an elfan buttress."
- Ha ha, say it again.
Buttress.
[both laughing]
Hey, laugh all you want.
You guys just aren't smart
enough to understand it.
[chuckles]
Sorry, dude, but it is kinda nerdy.
Well, I'm off to lay
siege to a goblin fortress.
To my grandma's backyard!
[sighs]
Oh, nice, you rolled a 17.
[bleats]
And this is sad.
Maybe I should start
obsessing over Wendy again.
[crunching]
Hey, give it back.
Come on, Gompers. Let go.
Oh, man, my 38-sided die!
[screams]
- Dipper, stop!
- Great-uncle Ford.
What did I say about coming down here?
My work is far too dangerous
for a single living soul
to spend even one second...
Wait. Is that a 38-sided die
from Dungeons, Dungeons,
And More Dungeons?
Yeah.
You know that game?
With pen and paper, shield and sword...
[both] ...our quest
shall be our sweet reward!
[laughing]
This is my favorite game
in the whole multi-verse.
I can't believe they still make it.
They do, and I've been looking all day
for someone to play with me.
My boy, do you know what this means?
We must stop everything
I've been working on at once,
and play!
That's going to leave a mark.
Okay, I think we've got
everything we need to watch
the season finale of
Duck-tective tomorrow.
I even made mouth ramps
so we can pour food
into our mouths without taking
our eyes off the screen.
[chewing loudly]
And I recreated the main character
out of spare taxidermy parts.
Quack, quack, I'm the Duck Detective.
Who stole my bread loaf?
[both laughing]
That is so messed up.
- Dipper would love that.
- Yeah, where is the little squirt anyway?
I haven't seen him all afternoon.
Alright, you enter the chamber.
Princess Unattainabelle beckons you.
But wait, it's a trap!
[gasps]
An illusion cast by
Probabilitor the Annoying.
You know his weakness, right?
[both] Prime statistical
anomalies over 37
but not exceeding 51.
Yes! In your face,
you cardboard wizard.
Hmm, the old boy looks a bit
different the did back in my day.
Yeah, they change the
art every few years.
Thankfully, you missed the period
when the creators of the game
tried to make it "cooler."
Man, this game is boring.
You dare challenge Probabilitizzle?
♪ Put the cat back
and roll the dice ♪
♪ Don't step to the wizard
'cause the wizard... ♪
_
...updated for the nine double-deuce!
- Available wherever dope games are sold.
- Peace!
[shudders] Must've been
dark times, those '90s.
Yeesh. Sounds like a good time to
be stuck between dimensions.
Great-uncle Ford, I've
been meaning to ask you.
Where were you before you
came out of that machine,
and what have you been doing down here?
Are you working on something
behind that curtain?
Dipper, it's best if you and the family
stay away from that subject.
Honestly, I'm not sure any of
you could handle the real answer.
- But I could handle it.
- Ah-ah!
But I can show you a little something
I brought back with me.
- An infinity-sided die.
- Whoa!
That's so cool... and impossible.
These things are outlawed
in 9,000 dimensions.
You wanna know why?
Look at those symbols.
Infinite sides means infinite outcomes.
If I rolled it, anything could happen.
Our faces could melt into jelly.
The world could turn into an egg.
Or you could just roll an eight.
Who knows?
That's why I have to keep it in
this protective cheap plastic case.
Now, back to the game.
You've got Probabilitor on the ropes.
[Dipper] Oh, man.
Then if I have a Dragon here,
and then a plus-three fire...
Dipper, are you gonna go to sleep?
You've been saying dork words for hours.
Sorry, Mabel.
I gotta finish this dungeon.
It's gonna totally stump
Great-uncle Ford tomorrow.
I can't wait to see
the look on his face!
You're, uh, spending a lot of
time with old Fordsie lately, huh?
You have no idea.
I knew the author must be cool,
but he's better than I imagined!
And he doesn't make
fun of me all the time,
- the way you and Grunkle Stan do.
- Give him time.
Hi-oh!
[chuckles]
Nah, you got me.
You got me.
Thanks for coming
over to watch tonight's
Duck-tective finale, Grenda.
Of course. I'm so invested in
the life of these characters.
Hey, hey, look at you.
Someone's all dressed up.
It's a big night. I think
we all remember where
we were when we learned
Duck-tective was shot.
[clock strikes]
[gasps] Viewing positions, everyone!
[all gasp]
Ahh! Graph paper.
Kill it, kill it!
Dipper, could you maybe
move this to another room?
No dice.
We ran out of room in the basement
and we're going for a world record.
Now dice!
Thirty-two!
- Yes! 7,000 points damage.
- You got me.
Ohh! Why with this?
Wanna break a record, Ford?
You already got it for
world's nerdiest old man.
Hey, at least I'm not all
keyed up to watch a kids' show.
I'll have you know that
Duck-tective has a big mystery
element, and a lot of humor
that goes over kids' heads.
I don't get a lot of it, but I
like animals in human situation.
Grunkle Stan, it
starts in a few minutes.
Move that and pay the price.
Oh, what, 50 magical dwarf dollars?
Don't mock our fantastical
monetary system!
I'll mock all I want.
It's my TV room.
It's my house! You...
[sighs] Listen, Stanley,
did it ever occur to you
that if you joined us, you
might actually have fun?
What? Now you listen to me.
As long as I live, I will never...
- Grunkle Stan, wait!
- ever...
- Stanley!
- play your smarty-pants nerd game.
No!
Mortals of Dimension
46 Apostrophe Backflash.
Kneel before me and...
Snivel.
I am Probabilitor,
the greatest wizard in all mathology,
- give or take an error of 0.4.
- Uh. Is this normal?
Have you come to send us
on the quest of a lifetime,
because we're the smartest
players you've ever met?
You are the smartest
players I've ever met.
That's why I'm going to eat your
brains, to gain your intelligence.
It's what I do.
- It's his thing.
- What?!
Seize them!
Your math is no match
for my gun, you idiot.
Math ray!
I'm not here to play games.
Now to the forest for the ultimate game.
So the room's free now.
Who wants to watch Duck-tective?
[squeaks]
Nobody?
More couch for Grenda.
Oh, no.
That crazy wizard is gonna eat
our brother's brain.
We have to stop him!
Maybe let him get a couple of
bites in Ford's brain first.
Even things out, smartness-wise.
- Grunkle Stan!
- All right, all right.
I guess if we have no other choice,
we'll go on a... [sighs]
epic wizard quest.
[cheering]
Everyone grab a weapon.
Nice.
We're coming for you, Dipper.
And Great-uncle Ford.
And possibly that hot elf,
if he's got anything to do with this.
[laughing]
With each brain I eat,
I shall increase my enchant-elligence.
If my hands were free,
I'd break every part of your face.
The time has come.
Hot elf, ready the brain-cooking pot.
Uh, yes, Probabilitor.
[slap]
We must be getting close.
These fairy bites are
getting more frequent.
Hey, look, listen.
Halt!
You interlopers are trespassing
on the ancient forest
of Probabilitor the Wizard.
If ye wish to pass,
first ye must complete
seven unworldly quests,
- each more difficult than the last...
- No!
Is he... dead?
He's magic, sweetie.
I'm sure he's fine.
There's no cops in the forest.
We take this to our graves.
[laughing]
- What do we do, what do we do?
- Stop thinking, Dipper.
The more wrinkled your brain gets,
the more he'll wanna eat it.
And now, a little math problem.
When I subtract your
brain from your skull,
add salt and divide your family,
what's the remainder?
[Mabel] Your butt!
What? My butt isn't part
of this particular equation.
[all roaring]
Drat! How did you make
it past my one guard?!
Very well. There's only one
way your family can save you.
You must defeat me
in Dungeons, Dungeons,
And More Dungeons,
[echoing] real life edition!
[maniacal laughter]
- What? Oh, come on.
- I choose my characters versus...
[gasping]
yours.
Oh, my ears.
They're so pointy.
There better be something
protective under this tunic.
- Oh, no, there isn't.
- Seriously?
Can't we just, like,
arm wrestle or something?
Come on, this game is a lot of fun.
I had my mom pack me a lunch.
Ew, apple slices?
I'll eat you last.
Just make with the rules, ugly.
The game is a battle royale.
We help our characters by casting spells
determined by rolls of the dice.
If you win, I go back
to my own dimension.
But if I win, I eat their brains.
Hey, I'm not sure this is such a good...
- Deal!
- Oh, boy.
Let the game begin!
Attack!
[war cry]
What do we do?
What are our moves?
There are no moves.
You make them up.
- What? Really?
- Yes. I tried to tell you.
This game involves math, but
also risk and imagination.
- Risk!
- Imagination?!
Grunkle Stan, make something up.
It's just like lying.
I cast... uh...
[groans]
shield of shielding.
- Ha! We're doin' it.
- Shield of shielding reversal spell.
I cast giggle time bouncy boots.
[laughing]
Fat flame-y sword.
Super-hot flame-y sword!
[gasps]
No!
Drat you. You'll never outrun my...
Ogre-nado.
It is what it sounds like!
I cast Centaur-taur!
Yah!
[neighs]
Mabel, I am so confused
and so proud right now.
[cheering]
- Yes!
- Ha ha! Yes!
Ha ha ha, yes!
I was saving the worst for last.
- Oh, no.
- The Impossi-beast.
Hey, I thought they
banned this character.
Think again.
I'm playing the controversial
1991-1992 edition.
- I'll think of some weapons.
- You don't understand.
This is the most powerful
monster in the game.
He can only be defeated
by rolling a perfect 38.
But the odds of that are...
Hey, long odds are what you want
when you're a world-class gambler.
All right, Stan, you can do this.
Papa needs a new pair of...
twins!
- No!!
- Sorry, nerd wizard.
All of your smarts are
no match for dumb luck.
I cast Death Muffins!
[both] Yes!
[laughs]
The game is, like, over.
Excelsi-whatever.
No!
I'm returning to my own realm.
I'm turning into pure math.
What are the odds?!
Grunkle Stan, that was amazing.
How did you know that you would win?
Hey, a gambler never
reveals his secrets.
Man, that was fun for ages eight to 80.
Or a million or however
old you guys are.
You know, I'm sorry for
making fun of your game, kiddo.
Sure, it might be too
nerdy for me, but it's just
the right amount of nerdy
for you and my brother.
And if you two wanna hang out
sometimes, I won't get in your way.
Actually, after all that,
I could use a little mindless fun.
Guys, we can watch the second
showing of Duck-tective!
It's not too late.
[squeaks]
_
I just don't understand who shot you.
The only person clever
enough to defeat Duck-tective
is... [gasps]
Duck-tective. Ugh.
_
He had a twin brother all along?
That's the big twist
we were waiting for?
- What a rip-off!
- I predicted that, like, a year ago.
- This will be here if you ever need it.
- Really?
Even though I got us into
the whole game-playing mess?
Ah, we both got carried away.
I guess we'd both gone for
a while without a friend.
Dipper, can I tell you something?
You asked me earlier
what I was working on.
Well...
I dismantled the portal.
An inter-dimensional
gateway is too dangerous
for the world it feeds into.
That's why I was mad
at Stan for using it.
He saved me, but as I feared,
the instability of the
machine created this.
An inter-dimensional rift.
I've contained it for now,
but it's incredibly dangerous.
Dipper, I don't want you
to tell anyone about this.
Not Stan, not even your sister.
- Do you understand?
- Oh, of course.
In my time, I've made
many powerful enemies.
But I trust you with this secret.
Now get yourself to bed.
I have much research to do.
- Good night, Great-uncle Ford.
- Good night, Dipper.
Guys, do you ever think
maybe we're doin' this
'cause our lives aren't special enough?
That we use fantasy
as an escape to avoid
the self-improvement we all need?
That maybe we should just go out
and grow with people?
- Fortresses can't speak, darling.
- I'm a fortress. [screams]
Does anyone wanna rescue him?
- Ah, I'm tired.
- I'm fine. I'm good.
- Well, too bad for him.
- Long day...
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~