sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[giggles]
- Wait up.
- Yeah, you should keep up.
I-I can keep up.
- Whoa!
- Neato!
Mysterious, boarded-up cave.
It might be filled with
lost prehistoric life forms.
- Or Mesoamerican gold.
- Uh, ladies first.
[both giggling]
[grunts]
[chuckles] Good thing you've
got your smarts, Poindexter.
I've got the other thing.
What is it called?
Oh, right, punching.
Cool. Splinters.
Whoa!
It's so creepy in here.
Hey, don't worry, bro.
Wherever we go, we go together.
Don't forget to leave our names
so they know who owns the place.
[both] Pines, Pines, Pines, Pines.
[title music]
2x12 - A Tale of Two Stans
Finally, after all these
long years of waiting,
you're actually here.
Brother!
Ow!
What the heck was that for?
This was an insanely risky move,
restarting the portal.
- Didn't you read my warnings?
- Warnings, schmarnings.
How's about maybe a thanks for
saving you from what appears
to be, I don't know, some
kinda sci-fi sideburn dimension.
Thank you? You really
think I'm gonna thank you
after what you did 30 years ago?!
What I did?
Why, you ungrateful...
Don't expect me to go easy on you
just because you're family.
Hey, hi. Mabel here.
Quick question.
What the heck is going on here?
Stan, you didn't tell me
there were children down here.
- And some sort of large, hairless gopher.
- [chuckles] I get that a lot.
They're your family, Poindexter.
Shermy's grandkids.
I-I have a niece, and a nephew?
Greetings.
Do kids still say greetings?
I haven't been in this
dimension for a really long time.
Whoa, six-fingered handshake.
It's a full finger
friendlier than normal.
[chuckles] I like this kid.
She's weird.
I... I can't believe it.
You're the author of the journals!
You've read my journals?
I-I haven't just read them.
I've lived them.
I've been waiting for
so long to meet you.
I don't know what to say.
I have so many questions. I...
[hyperventilating]
I think I'm gonna throw up.
No, no, false alarm.
Just gotta ride it out.
Listen, there'll be time
for introductions later.
But first, tell me, Stan.
Are there any security breaches?
Does anyone else know about this portal?
No. Just us.
- Also, maybe the entire U.S. government.
- The what?!
Fan out.
We're not going anywhere
till we find Stan Pines and those kids.
[sigs]
Okay. It's all right.
We've got a while before
they find this room.
We just need to lay
low and think of a plan.
Well, it looks like we're stuck
down here for a while.
Who wants to tell us their
entire mysterious backstory?
Yes, I have some questions
about all this myself, Stanley.
- Stanley?
- But your name is Stanford.
Wait, you took my name?
What have you been doing all
these years, you knucklehead?
Yeah, Grunkle Stan, no more lies.
You owe us some answers.
What's the deal with this portal?
Why did you keep this a secret?
And what happened between
you and your brother?
I'm hoping all this aligns
exactly with my fan-fic, Stan.
If not, I will be very disappointed.
Okay. Okay, okay.
I know I have a lot of explaining to do.
It all started a lifetime ago.
1960-something.
Glass Shard Beach, New Jersey.
I lived with my ma and pa
in the Lead Paint district
above the family pawn shop.
Dad was a strict man.
Tough as a cinder block,
and not easily impressed.
I'm not impressed.
Mom was a pathological liar,
which served her well
as a phone psychic.
That'll be 99 cents an hour.
No, you're overpriced!
Yeah, I predicted you
were gonna hang up.
And then, there was my
nerdy twin brother Stanford.
As if his abnormally
high IQ wasn't enough,
he also had a rare birth defect...
six fingers on each hand,
which might've explained his obsession
with sci-fi mystery weirdness.
As for me, I had what Mom
liked to call personality.
[laughing]
But as different as we were,
we were the perfect team,
and every day, we'd wander the beach,
looking for adventure.
Whoa!
A shipwrecked sailboat.
Possibly haunted by pirate ghosts.
This is the greatest
thing I've ever seen.
And I once saw a dead
rat floating in a bucket.
[laughing]
Ew. What's wrong with you?
Huh.
You know what this thing's missing?
Flags.
[both] Kings of New Jersey,
kings of New Jersey,
kings of New Jersey!
I dub thee the Stan O' War.
Ow! What the heck?
Well, well, if it ain't the loser twins.
Nice boat.
You get it at the dump? [giggles]
You would know, Crampelter.
Get lost!
Listen, dorks, and listen good.
You're a six-fingered freak,
and you're just a dumber,
sweatier version of him.
And you're lucky you have each other,
because neither of you
will ever make any friends.
[laughing]
Dorks and losers.
- Hey, don't let those idiots get to you.
- But I am a freak.
I just wonder if there's
anywhere in the world
- where weirdos like me fit in.
- Hey, chin up, buddy. Look.
One of these days,
you and me are gonna
sail away from this dumb town.
We'll hunt for treasure,
get all the girls,
and be an unstoppable
team of adventurers.
You really mean it?
- High six?
- High six.
Those were the good times.
Those bullies may have
been right about us
not making many friends,
but when push comes to shove,
you only really need one.
Ford's brain seemed to get
more impressive every year.
So did our pet project.
Sure, I got in more than
my fair share of trouble,
but when your brother's
the smartest kid in school,
you've always got a leg
up on the competition.
The future was looking
bright for both of us,
till one day.
[Woman over P.A.] Pines twins
to the principal's office.
Pines twins to the principal's office.
Ah, great. What is it this time?
Not you. Him.
Now, Mr. Pines, I'd like to speak
with you very frankly, if I may.
Very frankly is the only way I speak.
You have two sons.
One of them is incredibly gifted.
The other one is standing outside
this room, and his name's Stanley.
What are you saying?
I'm saying your son
Stanford is a genius!
All of his teachers are going bananas
over his science fair experiment.
You ever heard of West Coast Tech?
Best college in the country.
Their graduates turn science fiction
into science fact.
The admissions team is visiting tomorrow
to check out Stanford's experiment.
Your son may be a future
millionaire, Mr. Pines.
I'm impressed.
But what about our little
free spirit Stanley?
That clown? At this rate, he'll
be lucky to graduate high school.
Look, there's a saltwater
taffy store on the dock,
and somebody's gotta get paid to
scrape the barnacles off of it.
Stanford's going places,
but hey, look on the bright side.
At least you'll have one son
here in New Jersey forever.
[chuckles] Joke's on them if they
think you wanna go to some
stuffy college on the
other side of the country.
Once we get the Stan O' War complete,
it's gonna be beaches, babes,
and international
treasure hunting for us.
Look, Stan, I can't pass
up a chance like this.
This school has cutting-edge
programs and multi-dimensional
- paradigm theory.
- Be-boop. I am a nerd robot.
That's you.
That's what you sound like.
[chuckles] Ah, well, if the college
board isn't impressed with my
experiment tomorrow, then okay,
I'll do the treasure hunting thing.
- And if they are?
- Well, then I guess you better come
visit me on the other side
of the country. [chuckles]
Without Ford, I was just
half of a dynamic duo.
I couldn't make it
out there without him.
And now, thanks to that dumb college,
I was gonna lose my brother forever.
This is all your
fault, you dumb machine!
Oh, no. No, no, no.
What did I do?
There. All right.
Good as new. Probably.
All right, kid, show us what you got.
Okay. Well, what would
you say if I told you
the future of technology
was beneath this sheet?
- I'd say we wasted a car trip.
- What?
But... it was stable yesterday.
A fuse must've blown or something.
Kid, a perpetual motion machine
has one job... to not stop.
I don't think you're
West Coast Tech material.
No, wait. Don't go!
I worked so hard!
One paddle paddle paddle,
two paddle paddle.
Man, that Jackie O.
What a fox.
- Hey, what's the word, sixer?
- Can you explain
what this was doing next
to my broken project?
Okay. I might've accidentally
been... horsing around.
This was no accident, Stan.
You did this!
You did this because
you couldn't handle me
- going to college on my own.
- Look, it was a mistake.
Although, if you think about it,
maybe there's a silver lining.
- Huh? Treasure hunting?
- Are you kidding me?
Why would I wanna do
anything with the person
- who sabotaged my entire future?
- You did what, you knucklehead?
[baby cries]
Stanley, what's going on in here?
Wait, no. I can explain.
It was a mistake.
You ignoramus.
Your brother was gonna be
our ticket outta this dump.
All you ever do is lie and cheat,
and ride on your brother's coattails.
Well, this time, you cost
our family potential millions.
And until you make us a fortune,
you're not welcome in this household.
What?! Stanford, tell
him he's being crazy.
Stanford? Don't leave
me hanging. High six?
Fine!
I can make it on my own.
I don't need you, I don't need anyone!
I'll make millions,
and you'll rue the day
you turned your back on me.
Thanks to one dumb mistake,
I had no brother,
no home, no nothing.
But I had a plan to fix everything.
Oh, this story's so sad.
I know what you two
little broken teacups need.
To hug it out!
Hug it out.
Hug train comin' in the station.
- Hugapalooza 2000!
- Kid, will you knock that off?
I'm trying to tell my life story here.
I had decided I wasn't
gonna show my face at home
till I proved I could
make something of myself.
Unfortunately, the
treasure hunting business
was slow going.
Apparently, gold is
some kind of rare metal.
Luckily, I struck another kind of gold.
In sales.
Hi there. I'm Stan Pines
of Stanco Enterprises.
Are you sick of this
always happening to you?
Then you need the chamois of the future.
Made with the same
material astronauts use
to clean up cranberry
stains on the moon.
That's the Sham Total.
It's a total sham.
I had made my mark, all right.
Unfortunately, so did the chamois.
Apparently, the cheap
dye I used to color them
only made stains worse.
Customers weren't crazy about that.
Luckily, they were chasing me
with Stanco-brand pitchforks.
Suckers!
I was officially
banned from New Jersey.
But with a quick name change,
Steve Pinington was ready
to take on Pennsylvania.
Hi. I'm Steve Pinington.
Are you sick of bandages
that are hard to remove?
Then what you need is the Rip Off.
The Rip Off won't give you rashes.
I repeat, it won't give you rashes.
It gave you rashes.
I traveled the whole country,
sometimes outside of it,
always one step ahead of the law,
looking for something
that would be my big break.
Whoa. So that explains
all the fake ID's.
But wait, what about you?
Did you end up going
to your dream school?
Not exactly.
All right, I know Backupsmore
wasn't anyone's first choice,
but what we lack in prestige
we make up for in
mostly bug-free dorms.
I'm sure your families are proud.
More or less.
In a place like that,
I had to work twice as hard.
Luckily, that's what I do best.
I went from undergrad to PhD
three years ahead of schedule,
wrote a thesis that was
nationally ranked, and was
awarded an enormous grant for
my own scientific research.
But what to study?
My whole life, I'd been teased
for my six fingers.
But that got me thinking
about anomalies.
Things that were odd, unusual,
statistically improbable.
And according to my investigations,
there was one place with
a higher concentration
of these things than anywhere else.
A small lumber town in
Roadkill County, Oregon.
Gravity Falls.
Meanwhile, your old
Uncle Stan was doing great.
I'd come up with a sophisticated
new business strategy.
Come on. Owl, owl...
Football player with an omelet?!
Gah!
I was in great shape, living on my own,
and the best part was,
I didn't need help from nobody.
[line ringing]
Hello. This is Stanford Pines.
I was heading out on my own, as well.
I set to work using my grant money
to investigate the strange
properties of this town.
But what would I find here?
Bingo.
I began to investigate at once.
I knew I'd have to record my findings.
I began to keep a journal.
[shrieking]
The journals!
Sorry, sorry. Just...
[clearing throat] got excited there
about the journals. Keep talking.
I began to keep a journal.
[shrieking]
[clearing throat]
I'm going to ignore that.
There were anomalies everywhere.
And the more I looked, the more I saw.
Fascinating.
What did you say your name was?
Shmebulock... senior.
It was finally a place
where I felt at home,
but something nagged at me.
Where did it all come from?
It seemed to me the answer
must lie outside of our world,
a dimension of weirdness
leaking into ours.
I realized the only way
to understand Gravity Falls
would be to build a gateway, a portal
to the source of its weirdness.
But I couldn't make it alone.
I decided to call up
my old college buddy,
Fiddleford McGucket,
a young but brilliant mechanic
who was wasting his
talent trying to make
personal computers in some
garage in Palo Alto. [ringing]
Hello.
Fiddleford Computermajigs.
You say you're trying to build
a trans-universal
poly-dimensional meta vortex?
Well, that's mathematically feasible,
I reckon. [spits]
Many long nights were spent
perfecting the machine.
It would be the crowning
achievement of my studies,
an answer to the source
of this town's anomalies.
Get out, get out, get out!
The time had come to test it.
Ready? And...
[yells]
What?
I got you, buddy!
[gasps]
What is it? Is it working?
What did you see?
[speaking gibberish]
Fiddleford?
When Gravity Falls
and Earth becomes sky,
fear the beast with just one eye.
Fiddleford, get a hold of yourself.
You're not making any sense.
This machine is dangerous.
You'll bring about the
end of the world with this.
Destroy it before it destroys us all!
I can't destroy this.
It's my life's work.
I fear we've unleashed a
great danger on the world.
One I'd just as soon forget.
I quit.
Fine! I'll do it without you!
I don't need you, I don't need anyone.
[eerie whispering]
What? Who said that?
I was in over my head,
and feared I was losing my sanity.
I needed help.
Someone I could trust.
[pounding on door]
Just give me a few more days, Rico.
I'll pay your goons back, I swear.
You haven't seen your
brother in over ten years.
It's okay. He's family.
He won't bite.
Who is it?!
Have you come to steal my eyes?!
Well, I can always count on you
for a warm welcome.
Stanley, did anyone
follow you, anyone at all?
Hello to you, too, pal.
Hey, what is this?
Sorry. I just had to
make sure you weren't...
uh, it's nothing.
Come in, come in.
Look. Are you gonna explain
what's going on here?
You're acting like Mom after
her tenth cup of coffee.
Listen, there isn't much time.
I've made huge mistakes,
and I don't know who
I can trust anymore.
Hey, easy there. Let's
talk this through, okay?
I have something to show you.
Something you won't believe.
Loo, I've been around the world, okay?
Whatever it is, I'll understand.
There is nothing about
this I understand.
It's a trans-universal gateway,
a punched hole through
a weak spot in our dimension.
I created it to unlock the
mysteries of the universe.
But it could just as easily be
harnessed for terrible destruction!
That's why I shut it
down and hid my journals
which explain how to operate it.
There's only one journal left.
And you are the only person
I can trust to take it.
I have something to ask of you.
Remember our plans to sail
around the world on a boat?
Take this book, get on a boat,
and sail as far away as you can.
To the edge of the earth.
Bury it where no one can find it.
That's it? You finally
wanna see me after ten years,
and it's to tell me to get as
far away from you as possible?
Stanley, you don't understand
what I'm up against.
What I've been through!
No, no, you don't understand
what I've been through!
I've been to prison in
three different countries.
I once had to chew my way
out of the trunk of a car.
You think you've got problems?
I've got a mullet, Stanford.
Meanwhile, where have you been?
Living it up in your
fancy house in the woods,
selfishly hoarding your college money,
because you only care about yourself.
I'm selfish?
Stanley, how can you say that
after costing me my dream school?
I'm giving you a chance to do the
first worthwhile thing in your life,
- and you won't even listen.
- Well, listen to this.
You want me to get rid of this book?
- Fine, I'll get rid of it right now.
- No! You don't understand.
You said you wanted me to have it,
- so I'll do what I want with it.
- My research!
Stanley, give it back!
You want it back, you're gonna
have to try harder than that.
You left me behind, you jerk.
It was supposed to be us forever!
- You ruined my life!
- You ruined your own life!
Stanley. Oh, my gosh, I'm so sorry.
Are you all right?
Some brother you turned out to be.
You care more about your dumb
mysteries than your family.
Well then you can have 'em.
Whoa, whoa, hey.
What's going on?
- Hey, Stanford...
- Stanley! Stanley, help me!
- Oh no! What do I do?
- Stanley!
Stanley, do something!
[screaming] Stanleeey!
Stanford?
Stanford, come back!
I didn't mean it!
I just got him back.
I can't lose him again.
Come on!
[echoing] Stanford!
I lost him.
I didn't know if he was dead
or alive in some distant galaxy,
but I knew his journal
must have the answer
to getting him back... somehow.
I didn't get much sleep that night.
Or the night after that.
I tried for weeks to turn
that dumb machine back on.
But without the other two journals,
it was hopeless.
Finally, I ran out of food.
I had no choice but to go into town.
Just the bread then, stranger?
That'll be 99 cents.
Hey, that's no stranger.
That must be the mysterious
science guy that lives in the woods.
No, no, you got the wrong guy.
I've heard strange stories
about that old shack.
Yeah, mysterious lights
and spooky experiments.
Gosh, I'd pay anything to see what kind
of shenanigans you get up to in there.
Oh, me, too.
Do you ever give tours?
No, really, I...
[sighs]
Yes, I do give tours.
Ten... no, no, 15 bucks a person.
[cheering excitedly]
So what did you say your name was,
you man of mystery?
Oh, Stan... ford.
Stanford Pines.
Step right up, folks, to a
world of enchantment or whatever.
Behold the nerdy science box.
[electricity zaps]
Ah! My eye!
Uh, I can assure you, that
is in no way permanent.
I paid $15 for this?
[people grumbling]
Uh, you're lucky you weren't
part of the last tour group.
They never made it out alive.
[chuckles nervously]
Right?
[laughter]
Funny.
So I came up with a plan.
I couldn't leave my brother's house
until I figured out how to save him.
But I needed to pay
his mortgage somehow.
For once in my life,
people were actually
buying what I was selling.
And so, the Murder Hut was born.
Later renamed the Mystery Shack.
Finally, I'd found
something I was good at.
For once, being a liar
and a cheat paid off.
The old me was dead.
And I faked a car crash to prove it.
By day, I was Stanford Pines,
Mr. Mystery.
But by night, I was
down in the basement,
trying to bring the real Stanford back.
I couldn't risk anyone learning
the truth and sabotaging my mission.
So I lied to everyone.
The town, my family, your parents.
Even you kids.
So all this time, you were just
trying to save your brother.
Grunkle Stan, I'm so
sorry I didn't believe you.
That's okay, kid. I probably
wouldn't have believed me either.
[man] I heard talking. It
was coming from downstairs.
Oh no, we're too late.
The agents are coming for us!
What'll we do?
Oh, man, I was so spellbound
by your dramatic tale,
- I forgot all about those dudes.
- Wait. "Forget." That's it.
I think I know a way we might
be able to defeat those agents.
Of course.
I don't know how you got
a hold of one of these,
but this is perfect.
If I can just amplify the signal
to a radio headset frequency.
There.
Now everyone, plug your ears!
Get down now!
Sir, looks like there's a hidden door
behind the vending machines.
Excellent. Get me
Washington on line one.
I've been practicing making sounds
of excitement for this very occasion.
Hey, do you hear that?
What? Where am I?
Why am I standing in some sort
of goofy, fun knick-knack house?
Stand down, gentlemen.
I've been sent with the
latest intel from Washington.
According to this very real report,
the power surges in Gravity Falls
were actually due to radiation
from an unreported meteor shower.
A total embarrassment
for your whole department.
Luckily, I'm here to take
this mess off your hands.
And I'll need all of your floppy disks,
and, uh, eight tracks. Right?
Uh, everything about this case
is contained on this drive.
Well, what are you waiting for?
A kiss on the cheek?
Get outta here before I have
your butts court-martialed.
Uh, yes, sir.
Apologies, sir.
[whistles] False alarm, everyone.
Whoa.
Great-uncle Stanford, that was amazing.
Let's not go crazy.
It was serviceable.
[chuckles] Thank you, kids.
But please, call me Ford.
Sure.
Thanks, great-uncle Ford.
So, uh, would you mind if I asked you
a couple billion questions
about Gravity Falls?
- Um, well, I, uh...
- All right, kids, it's been a long day.
Me and my brother have
a lot to talk about.
- So why don't you hit the hay, huh?
- But it's the author.
I've been waiting so long
to ask questions about...
I said, hit the hay!
I'll just let myself out.
[phone dialing] Wendy, I've got
something amazing to tell you.
Clear the next 14 hours.
Look at us.
When did we become old men?
- You look like Dad.
- Ah. Don't say that. [both laughing]
[sighs]
Okay, Stanley, here's the deal.
You can stay here for the
Summer to watch the kids.
I'll stay down in the basement
and try to contain any remaining damage.
When the Summer's over,
you give me my house back,
you give me my name back,
and this Mystery Shack junk
is over forever. You got it?
You really aren't
gonna thank me, are you?
Fine. On one condition.
You stay away from the kids.
I don't want them in danger.
'Cause as far as I'm concerned,
they're the only family I have left.
Did you hear what they said?
I think Uncle Ford said
they're gonna buy us puppies
made of ice cream.
Might be wishful thinking, though.
I don't know if this is good or bad.
I wanted to meet the author, but...
Yeah. I liked the way
things were here before.
Just us and Stan,
and the occasional goblin monster.
I'm sure they'll work things out.
Dipper, you don't think we'll turn out
like Stan and Ford, do you?
- W-What do you mean?
- I mean, they used to be best friends,
but then, they got all stupid.
Can you promise me you won't get stupid?
Not stupider than you, dum-dum.
- [giggles] Good night, stupid.
- Good night, stupid.
[Soos] Okay, okay, so it
turns out the second Stan,
the Stan that we know,
was actually Stanley,
but the first Stan was Stanford,
but we didn't know until that
Stanford came out of the portal,
which was built by Stanford,
but then Stanley
pretending to be Stanford,
he did the portal 'cause he's Stan,
but he's not Stan.
- Soos, it's 3:00 in the morning.
- Okay, okay, I understand.
- Anyway, act two, Stan started...
- Aaaah!
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~