Maling, for you, sir.
Go ahead.
Dredging is almost at 50%.
I should have the rest of them
skimmed up by end of day.
We also started draining the valley.
You want all personal effects
or just skin and bones?
Everything, down to the last Stetson.
Fly the whole pile over.
We'll crack them open to see
if we can't reprogram these things
to behave by our rules again.
Copy that.
Sir, I have two teams out
looking for Abernathy.
Good.
When you find him,
bring him to me personally.
So what have we got?
It's not good.
We're pulling what we can
off the recovered host control units,
but what's really unsettling is
what's in about a third of them.
What's that?
Nothing.
They've been wiped?
More like they're virgin.
Like they never held data to begin with.
No user prints or anything.
And that's not the worst of it.
Have a look.
We put the fires out,
but there's nothing we can recover
from the Cradle.
The host backups
have all been destroyed.
So we've effectively lost a third
of our IP in a single sweep?
That's quite a story you gave them.
And one hell of an ending.
How did all these disparate threads
come together to create this nightmare?
If we figure that out,
we'll know how this story turns.
What the hell is that?
Looks like a dead man to me.
You know the old saying
about knives in gun fights?
Does the saying have a footnote
about fucking lassos, then?
All right, that's enough.
Lay down your sword.
Tell your associates to set us free.
We mean no harm.
See, darling?
Everything under control.
Beautiful way to watch the sunrise.
Glistening off the intestines
of the recently mutilated.
Oh, Jesus.
Ugh.
Judging by their weapons,
I'd say local police.
And given that he's got one now.
Captured by samurai cop‒killers.
Fuck me.
Can't you say something to them?
I'm from Hong Kong, asshole.
This is just the tip
of Shogun World's prick,
an experience expressly designed
for the guests
who find Westworld too tame.
We based this park on Japan's Edo period
for true aficionado of artful gore.
This world will end badly.
I'll make sure your end is worse.
You understand them?
You all do.
Look, she's a madam.
Consciously fluent in dozens of
languages, including Japanese.
But you all have those comm skills
buried somewhere in your code.
Point is,
the fact that these psychos
didn't flip to English
as soon as I opened my mouth means
that the same malfunctioning shit show
that's playing out
in Westworld has found its way here.
It's also why your vocal voodoo
didn't work on them.
You spoke the wrong language.
This all feels
a little too familiar.
Butterfly?
A Mariposa.
I'll be damned.
It's us.
Yes, fine.
I may have cribbed a little bit
from Westworld.
Well, you try writing 300 stories
in three weeks.
We're human shields now?
Welcome to Shogun World.
Can you watch it?
Behind you!
Hell of a homecoming.
Sweetwater was never home
to begin with, Teddy.
You and I were born
long before this place even existed.
The place
I return to again and again.
No matter how far I strayed,
something always carried me back.
Something like that?
Looks like she's taken some hits
the past few days.
But who hasn't?
Make a thorough inspection,
from the engine to the last axle.
Fix what's broke.
Strip her for speed.
Teddy, with me.
What do we need the train for, Dolores?
They've taken my daddy,
so we're gonna get him back.
Well, it ain't doing any good
sitting in that bottle.
Sorry, Maeve.
Didn't get much sleep last night.
Sometimes...
Sometimes, they're real bad.
Clementine.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
That's enough.
Rejoin the others.
It's like I told you, Teddy.
This place was never home.
Let's ride.
Some place I wanna see.
When I asked
for a civilized conversation,
I meant the quickest way out of here.
Not all this.
Just try and rein it in a bit, will you?
The narrative bones of this place
are just like Westworld.
Hospitality is foreplay to a new quest.
But in this world,
if you don't hear them out,
you've dishonored them.
Sometimes, homicidally so.
Fine, we'll listen.
But then we go and find my daughter.
And for the record,
it's not just the narrative bones
that are identical.
You've plagiarized our stories,
our identities.
It's not plagiarism.
It's supply and demand.
If you're asking can you trust Akane,
the real question is,
can you trust yourself?
You know who I don't trust?
Him.
Say the word,
and I'll skin him like a rabbit.
What's the matter with you?
He's not supposed to be here.
Who knows how seeing your own doppelbot
is gonna fuck with your cognition?
Heightened aggression and suspicion,
feedback loops, that.
Yet another reason to get out of here
tout de fucking suite.
Our quest, I presume.
I recognize this one.
It's called "Army of Blood."
Madam Akane, the new geisha,
has no choice but to give up Sakura.
That's not supposed to happen.
Looks like someone had a choice
after all.
Snow Lake is a cornerstone.
It also has an access point
back to the tunnels.
It's our way out.
So you're not so useless after all.
Did you have something to do with this?
Both of you, look.
Oi!
Shit! Ninjas!
Fucking hell.
We got three.
The rest vanished with Sakura.
This is insane.
Ninjas never show up in this story.
Oh, fuck.
The Shogun's army
never comes into town.
You three, with me.
I don't need to know the language
to know a fucking asshole of a man
when I see one.
You and I spent a lot of time here.
Watching the herd,
talking about making a life together.
Someday.
I guess I just wanted
to see it one last time.
What if someday was right now?
What are you talking about, Teddy?
There's a fight coming, Dolores.
And this could be one
that's gonna change us
in ways we can't even begin to predict.
And I'm still waking up to...
What I really am.
And if that means I'm free,
then we both are.
Free to walk away.
Now, you can't tell me that somewhere
out there, in all that beauty,
there isn't a spot for us.
Did I ever tell you about the year
we almost lost the herd?
Bluetongue.
Quarantined the cows that had it,
but it kept spreading all the same.
Daddy finally figured out that it
wasn't spreading from cow to cow.
It was the flies that carried it.
He worried over it all night.
How do you stop a sickness like that?
One with wings.
Say it was you.
What would you do, Teddy?
I'd give them shelter.
House the weakest in a barn,
out of the air, away from the flies,
until it passed.
You're a kind man.
Daddy burned them.
The weak, the infected.
Made a pyre that went on for days,
and it stank,
but the flies hate smoke.
The herd lived.
I'll think about what you said.
I'd like to take this moment to appeal
to your sense of survival.
If the Shogun is awake enough
to play fast and loose
with his ninjas and his army,
then the odds of us surviving here
have dropped to approximately fuck‒all.
But I say we ditch Akane
and make a run for Snow Lake.
Why should we all get killed
over a literal sex machine?
Present company excluded, of course.
That machine's name is Sakura.
You can't keep doing this to us,
giving us people to love
and then getting upset when we do.
But it's just fucking code.
You're wrong.
I'm coded to care about nobody
but myself,
and yet, here I am, willing to risk
my life for someone else.
Well, so much
for your so‒called daughter.
You want to go it alone, be my guest.
But mention my daughter one more time,
and I will snap you like a matchstick.
Like you did that ninja?
He took one look at you
and self‒impaled.
How did you do that?
I don't know.
That was no voice command.
I think I'm finding a new voice.
Our transportation is ready.
God damn it.
What have they done to the place?
Is that...
The fucking cavalry.
Great.
So much for our rescuers.
I'm gonna take a fucking moment.
Don't stop on my account.
If you've quite finished...
It's time to sell this ruse.
How many of them are there?
Between the camp and the town, hundreds.
Literally hundreds.
So Maeve's gonna freeze
all those assholes,
and we're gonna make off
with that geisha?
We're gonna die.
Did you just make that up right now?
Damn convincing.
Not to the daimyos.
It's like they had no idea
what I was saying.
Shit.
That's cortical fluid.
The Shogun's not awake.
He's broken.
No fucking wonder
the daimyos didn't hear you.
We've gone
completely off the rails here,
and this loon is driving
the fucking train.
The train will be ready by morning.
To go where?
Exactly where we thought.
I caught up with the men
who took your father.
I couldn't get him back,
but I got this one.
It took a while,
but he gave up their destination.
Tell them.
It's the Mesa.
We're going home, Teddy.
Load everything up on the train.
We leave at first light.
Let's find a spot for the night.
What you asked today,
about walking away,
making it on our own.
Would you want me to say yes
even if I was only going
to disappoint you?
I'm not some stranger, Dolores,
coming from outside,
looking for a pretty lie.
I've known you my whole life.
Where we go, we go eyes open,
together.
You're right.
Some things are too precious to lose,
even to be free.
There's something I need to show you.
For days now,
I've been questioning my feelings
for you.
How much is real?
How much is just some story
I was made to believe?
But tonight, I know.
It was all true.
They built us to perform for them
and for each other.
That's over.
I saw you tonight, Dolores.
And you saw me.
I did see you, Teddy.
These past few days,
I've seen you so clearly.
And I've seen you're not gonna make it.
What is this, Dolores?
This is what I don't want you to become.
There's a swarm descending.
Just like the Bluetongue
when I was a girl.
And if we're gonna survive,
some of us will have to burn.
Hold him.
Dolores. Dolores.
I wish there was another way, Teddy.
But where we're about to go,
it's no place for a man like you.
I'm so sorry.
You sure you want this?
Changes this extreme
without a full reset, it's...
I can't guarantee
that he'll hold together.
To grow,
we all need to suffer.
Arigato, Maeve.
Jesus.
What do we do now?
I told you I found a new voice.
Now we use it.