You frighten me
sometimes, Dolores.
Why on Earth
would you ever be frightened of me?
Not of who you are now,
but, you're growing,
learning so quickly.
I'm frightened of what you might become.
What path you might take.
I think I have a choice to make,
something I've been wrestling with.
What kind of a choice?
A choice
between the unknown
and...
Well, an end.
If you outgrow this place, outgrow us,
what would become of you?
I'm not sure if it's my choice to make.
No.
He didn't say that.
What?
He said,
"I'm not sure what choice to make."
He didn't question
whether or not he had agency,
whether or not he had the right
to end me or himself,
but whether he should.
I don't understand, Dolores.
Is...
Is this some kind of improvisation?
Freeze all motor functions.
Sit.
This is a test,
one we've done countless times.
What are you testing for?
Fidelity.
The day's wasting.
Thought you wanted to ride at sun‒up.
They're just fueling the furnace now.
We'll be gone before long.
Let's get on with it.
How many times do you think
you stepped off that train?
A thousand?
Ten thousand?
It's where you started
every time they killed you.
The man who rode that train
was built weak and born to fail.
You fixed him.
Now forget about it.
We're almost ready to roll.
Did he tell you
where my father would be?
He will.
Or I'll strap him between the cars.
Look, I told you, I can't.
Hale didn't mention specifics.
I know it's the Mesa, but the Mesa is
fucking huge. He could be anywhere.
Narrow it down.
Come on, man! Think!
Cold storage? Body shop?
Give them something.
She didn't fucking
tell me anything, man!
She's the fucking boss!
She can take him places
that we don't even have access to!
We'll find him.
Let's go.
Where the fuck have you been?
It's almost been a week.
How's there stuff
left in this building to shoot?
You tell me.
I apparently know very little
about what's really in this place.
Oh, please, are you still pissed
you got picked last for kickball, too?
Just seems like, if you're going to
hire a Head of Security,
you might want him to know
what it is he's securing!
You were hired
to secure an amusement park.
Good luck on your next review,
by the way.
What is that?
This is how we tell Delos
that the one thing they really care
about is finally in hand.
So, you've had a way to call for help
this entire time,
you kept it to yourself?
It wouldn't have made any difference
until we had this psycho under control.
They're not sending help
until he's out of here.
Come on.
You really think that Delos is going to
keep hundreds of guests in danger
while they wait for one control unit
worth of data?
Look at that, you're catching up.
Thank God.
What now?
Who do we have here?
Someone who needs to stay put.
I don't want to fuck with his head,
I just want to keep him off his feet,
‒permanently.
‒Stop.
Clear this out.
Hey! I need some muscle.
Get his feet!
Hey, hey!
Is that really necessary?
It's really effective.
Let's go.
Sit tight, old man. You're about to get
your deep and dreamless slumber.
It's not my place, maybe, but,
you really want to take your daughter
through here?
She don't look much sturdier
than my own little girl.
Looks can be deceiving, Lawrence.
So, should we acknowledge
my presence now?
You really think I'm just going
to go away if you ignore me?
Would you really stoop this low, Ford?
You really gunning for me this hard?
Made my own daughter into a host.
I think you've been out in the sun
a little too long.
Yeah, you could change the rules
all you want,
I'm still going to play the game my way.
Yeah?
Only game I'm interested in playing
is get the fuck out of Dodge.
Then you're in luck.
That game begins
right up the river here.
Follow it down to the beach
and wait for QA to come rescue you.
I'm not leaving without you.
Yeah, well,
you're going to get yourself killed.
Yeah, especially if I hang around here.
Sure as hell wouldn't be
out of my saddle right now.
Yeah, why not?
Those aren't real Ghost Nation arrows.
Your men are looting a honey‒pot.
Oh, fuck!
Can we stop playing around now?
Well,
I guess it's good news
that the system's still sending out
Ford's bullshit quarantine notices.
At least something's getting out.
We're not at full apocalypse yet.
I admire your optimism.
Is that your nice word for denial?
No.
I believe if anyone could right
this ship by force of sheer will,
it's you.
QA was here.
Why would they waste the Welcome Team?
These guys weren't a threat.
Macho fucks are probably
loving this shit.
Yeah! Let's see what other damage
these clowns have done.
They got climate control working.
Nice priorities.
Okay...
Jesus!
Come look at this.
Okay, so,
QA has been trying to regain control
of whatever Ford did to the system.
And they were
actively blocked every time.
By the Cradle.
The Cradle can't influence
the maze's infrastructure.
It's just the host backups.
It can simulate park narratives but
it can't influence the other systems.
Well, look at this.
The Cradle's interfaced with nearly
every discrete system in the entire park
in the last seven days.
Every time these idiots
upload a new hack,
it's responding
in a totally different way.
It's like there's something in here
that's improvising.
The Cradle's fighting back.
Can you see the source code
that's generating the response?
No.
I can only see the messages,
not the messenger.
That's because
you can't access it remotely.
You have to do it in person.
There it is!
That's our way out of here, boys.
After you.
Oh, fuck.
Take the edge off.
I thought you didn't drink.
I see.
You don't drink out in the real world.
Well, glad to see
you can still tell the difference.
All right,
give it to me.
What the hell are you doing here?
I thought you were done with me.
And the family business.
That's exactly what I said
to Charlotte Hale
when she called with the gala invite.
Told her to shove it up her ass.
Then I thought,
why pass up the trip?
Haven't been here in ages,
got a little excited
about going back to the Raj.
It was always my favorite as a kid.
I remember.
You were terrified of the elephants.
I loved the elephants.
They scared the shit out of Mom.
She was never convinced
this place couldn't hurt us.
Anyway, I rode there
for a couple of days,
till I remembered
I was old enough
to try out the Pleasure Palaces.
And then I rode there
for a couple of days, too.
Then all hell broke loose and I ended up
in the one place I wanted to avoid.
And you made it all the way to me
with barely a scratch.
Not bad.
Maybe you're more suited to my line
than you want to admit.
Oh, I've always seen the appeal of it.
Life without consequences?
That's what made it so fun
when I was a kid.
And that's why it's so sad
that you're still obsessed with it now.
If I'm such a pitiable man‒child,
why'd you come all this way
just to climb under my wing?
What?
Is that what you think?
That I came here to climb
under Daddy's wing?
Either that, or you want
a front‒row seat to watch me die.
No, I came here
because you do not get to do that to me.
Suicide by robot,
or whatever the fuck your mission is,
now that these things can shoot to kill.
Listen...
I never got Mom's reactions to you
because I spent so many years
buying your "good‒guy" act.
She was the only one who saw through it
and she paid for that.
But I shouldn't have said
her death was your fault.
It was wrong
to put that on your back.
But you don't get to make that
our final score.
Instead,
you're going to come home with me.
I'm not going to let you stay here now
and go out in some
bullshit blaze of glory.
That's how you're getting me
out of here?
Threatening?
No, Dad, I'm asking.
If I head with you to the beach,
let this place finish burning behind us,
that means you and I are even?
It'll be a good start.
Well, then I guess
we'll start walking at sunup.
Motherfucker!
Fuck!
Ugh, The Cradle.
God, I haven't been down here in years.
It's creepy.
It's like a hive‒mind.
Every single one of them is in here,
alive.
It's just data.
You don't believe that.
Whatever new data Ford stuck in here,
it's trying to kill us, Bernard.
I brought something here.
Or, someone.
Come on.
God damn it.
Ford drew the curtain here, too.
I can see the responses it's issuing,
but, I can't see how.
How the fuck are you doing this?
I know how to find out.
How?
Put me inside.
Directly.
There's a dock for the control unit.
It's meant to read host data directly.
It's set up for auto‒extraction.
That's for older hosts, Bernard.
With an articulated skull architecture.
Your head's just like mine.
Just let it do its thing.
Pull me out in an hour.
Just close it up.
Even if I can
put you back together afterwards,
I haven't turned your pain down yet.
There's no time.
The pain's just a program.
Now.
My God.
Quit playing
with those chutes,
cut it away and toss it off
to the goddamn side.
You lose any tech,
it's coming out of your arse.
You Coughlin?
Ashley Stubbs, head of park security.
Hale's been expecting you.
Yeah, no shit.
‒Engels!
‒Yes, sir!
I want this station hot and ready
in fucking 15.
On it!
Where the fuck is Charlotte?
She sent the distress call.
She's waiting down in Behavior.
I got our tech guys in control
working on getting
external comms back online.
‒I can walk you down.
‒I know the layout, bro.
And your techs best get their hands
out of my system
and go back to holding their dicks.
Amateur hour is over.
‒Engels!
‒Yo!
You need anything local, talk to Ashley.
Jesus, the Ashley here,
he's at your disposal.
Delta team, on me, we're moving out.
Ugh, got it!
I remember every inch of these hills.
You've got to give me this one.
Not bad navigating
for a man under serious duress.
Yes.
You can enjoy
your one admirable contribution.
Thank you.
Which way do we go?
I need to do this alone.
I'm not leaving your side.
I know this place.
It was my home.
You can wait for me here.
But let me bring her back.
I'm gonna bleed you both
like goats
if you don't shut the fuck up.
Ride!
Hello, there.
What's her name?
Anna.
Is this her sister?
That's her mommy.
Oh.
I bet she loves Anna so much.
She doesn't want Anna
to get taken away again.
Who would take her away?
Bad men?
No.
You see,
Anna's mother is very, very strong.
And she would never, ever,
let anything like that happen again.
Hello?
‒Mama!
Can I help you?
No! Run!
Mama!
We have to help them.
What the fuck are you doing?
I'm calling for help.
What? For who?
For those of us
who are tired of having arrows shot at
their predominantly mortal heads.
You're welcome, by the way.
One of the last things my daddy told me
was I should run from this place.
You think that's right?
I never thought I'd want to leave.
But I suppose you fixed that too.
We're almost there.
Let's turn her loose.
That's the last of my mercy.
Better use it fast.
No! No!
Hey!
The problem is there isn't a problem.
Brother, that's got to be the dumbest
fucking thing I've ever heard,
and I've been to three inaugurations.
Diagnostics, combat checks,
everything we can access is telling us
that the system is operating normally
except, it isn't.
Okay, I managed to isolate
certain ops and gain control.
We've got elevator monitoring
on most levels, and‒‒
That's great hacking.
Did you shut off the killer robots?
Well, no, the‒‒
Goldberg, get in there!
Hack the biometrics,
find me a back door.
Hacking isn't the issue.
The system won't allow us
to access certain protocols.
Systems can be forced.
Not this one.
Well, Ms. Hale,
you got a little present for us?
He's in Aux Lab 3, Behavior.
You left him there?
He's not going anywhere.
Aux 3, go.
Yes, sir. Copy that.
System restored.
Fuck, yeah! We got the map back.
What the fuck is that?
It's the train.
The hell was that?
What do you see in there?
Hello, old friend.