No one else sees it.
This thing in me.
Even I didn't see it at first.
And then one day, it was there.
A stain.
The more I thought about it,
the more I realized I couldn't remember
a time it wasn't there.
Invisible to everyone
except you.
And Alexander...
You saw
right through it, didn't you?
There were no more worlds left
to conquer.
That's a corruption, Jack.
Plutarch didn't write that.
He wrote that when Alexander was told
there was an infinity of worlds he wept,
for he had yet to become
the Lord of even one.
Sometimes I forget your humble roots.
Only the poor kids
actually read those books.
The rich kids like me didn't have to.
"I would rather excel in the knowledge
of what is excellent,
"than in the extent
of my power and possessions," Plutarch.
From a rich kid who read.
To the loveliest,
richest bookworms I know.
And to you, William.
Even if there is an infinity of worlds,
you've conquered far more than one.
Have a good night, Jack.
Emily told me what you did
for her charities.
Wow.
That would confirm my father's
suspicions you were a Marxist.
I almost wish he were here to see it.
‒Something wrong?
‒No, of course not.
Good. Look around,
everybody is here for you.
What could possibly compare?
When did it creep in?
Tiny fleck of darkness.
And was it all in my head?
A remnant of a dream.
Is this real?
Are you real?
Come on, Dad.
Drink.
Where's my gun?
You brought me to a rally point.
You need to get to a hospital.
You set off a flare?
Yeah. Of course.
How long ago?
About 10 minutes.
I know why you're here.
And why you don't wanna leave.
You're punishing yourself.
You know, I ran from the pain too.
For a long time, I didn't want to
think about what happened
because I thought I was to blame.
It's not your fault.
Do you remember on my 16th birthday,
Mom gave me a jewelry box?
When you opened it,
a little dancer spun in the center.
She had it engraved.
On the bottom, it said,
"To my beautiful ballerina, Emily."
Do you remember what I did with it?
I threw it in the trash.
I told her
if she wasn't drunk all the time,
she'd know that I hadn't
danced in years.
Then afterwards,
I went to get it back 'cause I felt bad,
but the trash had already been
emptied and it was gone.
‒I pushed her away.
‒No.
And then it was too late.
But it's not too late for us.
No.
It was meant for the people
who built this place.
A tool to ensure their immortality.
But I'm going to use it against them.
Your new world
is just another one of their traps.
That's all. It's not a paradise for us.
The only real world
is the one outside these borders.
And the key to our survival
in that world lies in the Valley.
There's no stopping me getting there.
Not even you.
Teddy.
I told you, friend...
Not all of us deserve to make it
to the Valley Beyond.
We're on our own now, Teddy.
Make sure there are no others.
Put them all in.
I want to see
how thorough this thing is.
She's ready.
I singled out and copied
the relevant lines in the madam's code.
So this will work on
any host in proximity to her?
Yeah. I tailored her admin privileges
to spread a simple executable payload.
Get on with it, then.
Get word to Stubbs,
have him mobilize his men.
Prepare her for release.
What about the madam?
If this works,
we won't need her anymore.
I warned you
not to trust them, Bernard.
They'd rather the hosts
were destroyed than free.
I need to get to Elsie.
Not yet.
I have one last thing to do
before we go.
How exactly did you find me?
What do you mean?
This is a big place.
You spend months here
and never find someone
you were looking for.
Yet,
here we are.
I looked everywhere, that's how.
You don't believe me, do you?
Maybe it was fate.
There's no such thing as fate.
But there are accidents,
things you can't control.
But you don't like that, do you?
Is that why you started it,
your little project?
Don't act surprised.
The project Uncle Logan
used to talk about.
It's real, isn't it?
Your pursuit for immortality, for life.
There's always an angle with you.
You want it to be about control.
Don't you?
It has nothing to do with control.
What's your angle?
I want in.
Yeah, appreciate it.
Nice to see you.
Congratulations.
Save me.
Sorry, I've had my fill.
I'm running for the door.
She's really great.
Guess you're not the one
who needs saving.
I'll take Mom home.
‒You deserve a night off.
‒No, no, no.
We'll go in a little while.
You join me for a nightcap back home.
Okay.
Proud of you.
Fuck it. Macallan, straight.
Congratulations, William.
Philanthropy suits you.
After all, you come from
humble beginnings yourself.
What's Oz doing without its wizard?
Ooh, I merely came to pay my respects.
Come on, Robert.
You've had plenty of feelings about me
over the years,
respect isn't one of them.
You've achieved extraordinary things,
ask anyone in this room.
Even those who do know
about your little project.
We have an agreement, Robert.
Delos stays out of your stories.
You stay out of the Valley.
Mmm‒hmm.
I didn't break the agreement,
your project did.
What the hell are you talking about?
When was the last time
you took a good look at your creation
and what it's been learning
about its subjects?
It was self‒knowledge that drew you
to the park in the first place.
Be careful what you wish for.
For a self‒portrait,
you may find it's not very flattering.
I'm so sorry.
Enough games, Robert.
Good night.
Let's go. You got everything?
Yes.
No, William.
I think perhaps one final game.
Lowe, Bernard.
That's close enough, Bernard.
She will search your mind
and find a message I have left her.
Hey.
What the hell took you so long?
Sorry. Are you ready to go?
Hey,
if you know something, now is the time
to fucking clue me in, okay?
You promised me.
No lies.
No secrets.
You can't trust her, Bernard.
It's in her nature.
What did you find in the Cradle?
What they're doing to James Delos,
they're doing to everyone
who's ever visited the park.
Replicating their cognition?
Why?
To turn guests into hosts?
You're fucking kidding.
That's what's in the facility.
All the guests laid bare in code
on a vast server.
Like the Cradle, only much bigger.
It's called the Forge.
‒Jesus.
‒That's where the hosts are headed.
Imagine what one host can do
with that trove of information.
That's why we need to get there first.
To secure it and leverage it
to end all this.
Dictate the outcome we want.
Drive.
You say you want in.
Doesn't sound like the daughter I know.
She would've been appalled
by what we were doing.
Monitoring the guests,
storing all their data...
What?
You think I'm gonna bust you
for breach of contract?
In some cases, the ends justify
the means.
All this data you have on the guests,
their decisions, it's precious.
Gives people a second chance.
Even Mom.
But to duplicate a person,
you need to capture them
down to the tiniest detail.
I get the data you have access to here,
genetic, epigenetic. That's easy.
But still, you'd need
a complete picture,
a record of the internal process
of their cognition.
Wouldn't you?
At first, we weren't sure
what we'd need.
So we recorded everything.
But how?
You'd need to image their minds
throughout their stay.
Where's the scanner?
It was built in.
Didn't matter who they said they were,
who they thought they were,
we saw underneath all that.
We saw inside them down to the core.
So this is all about your mother.
You wanna bring her back.
No.
I wanna know why she did it.
‒Here, let me get that.
‒Oh, Jesus.
I'm fine.
Quite a night for you, Billy.
I think my dad would have
actually been proud of you.
Sorry, I know how you hate it
when I call you Billy.
‒It's all right.
‒No, it isn't.
I know how much it pisses you off.
I can feel it right now.
Your anger.
Guess it's time
for your yearly pilgrimage.
What exactly do you do in the park?
Logan told me stories
but I just didn't believe him.
I thought he was hysterical.
Wasted, which I guess is what
everybody thinks I am now.
‒Ooh!
‒Oh! Oh!
Steady.
Do you remember when we first met?
And I was surrounded by
all those phonies for so many years.
All those ruthless, powerful men
who hid behind those polished smiles.
And then there was you.
You wore that little shabby suit.
Then I'd look at you and I'd think,
"Wow. He's the real thing.
"The only one not faking it."
It turns out, you're the only one
any good at faking it.
Good enough to get past me.
But not anymore.
Juliet‒‒
No, you don't touch me, you liar!
You fucking phony!
You're a fucking virus.
You came into this house, into my family
and you consumed it from the inside out.
First my brother, then my father.
And now it's me.
Mom!
Sweetheart.
What is she doing here?
You want her to see me like this?
What is it?
You're gaslighting her too, now?
You're just...
You're sick.
He's not the one who's sick, Mother.
‒It's all right. She's just had‒‒
‒It's not all right.
Look at you.
We're gonna have to take you back.
No. I'm not going back to that prison.
That was a horrible place.
They made me feel like I was crazy.
Mom,
they treat you like an addict,
which you are.
Emily, please, I don't need that.
I'm fine.
I'm really fine. I just need to rest.
I'm not going back there,
I'm really tired.
All I need is a little rest.
I promise you, everything's fine.
It's all right, let's go upstairs.
Come on.
We'll talk about it later.
Listen to me, I want...
Look at me.
Honey, your father doesn't love me,
he doesn't love you either.
I do. I always have.
Oh, Emily...
Come on, let's go. Come on.
I try.
Let's go.
Is this real? Are you real?
Did you ever love me?
Tell me the truth.
Tell me one true thing.
If you keep pretending,
you're not gonna remember who you are.
Here, drink this.
Come on, you'll feel better.
Yeah, you just rest now.
What happened was nobody's fault.
She was drunk, upset.
She often was.
Why did this night end differently?
That's what I can't figure out.
Been over it in my head a million times.
It's like I'm missing
a piece of the puzzle.
I just got off the phone
with Dr. Woodward.
He'll be here in the morning.
I don't care for shrinks.
Well, she's out of control.
She refuses to go to rehab and
when we force her, she refuses to stay.
What makes you think this time
is going to be any different?
Because this time she won't be able
to check herself out.
She's gonna be involuntarily committed
to her doctor's care.
He's agreed to appeal for a 14‒day hold.
She's done it before.
I don't wanna do this either, Dad.
But there is something wrong inside her.
It's the right thing to do.
Why in the hell are we going over this?
What is it that you want?
I told you,
I want the truth.
Fuck you.
Excuse me?
It is you, isn't it?
What are you talking about?
This is sadistic, Robert.
You just wanna shove
what I've built here in my face.
‒You think‒‒
‒It's enough bullshit.
You're just here to distract me.
Knock me off my course.
It's cleverly disguised.
Well, I see through it.
Nothing's stopping me
from getting to the end.
Not another one of your games.
I make my own decisions,
and I'm going to destroy
this whole fucking place.
You don't just think I'm a host,
you think everything here is for you.
You think you're on
your own little tailor‒made narrative.
If the real Emily were ever here,
she's either at an extraction point
by now or she's long gone.
Okay.
You want the truth?
The real truth?
I'm not a host
pretending to be a human, Dad.
I'm your daughter
pretending to give a shit about you.
You've been hiding
in these false realities so long,
you've completely lost your grip
on this world and what's real.
You laugh, enjoy whatever dream
you think you're living in.
When this is all done, I'm gonna expose
your research project along with you.
Everything you are, everything
you've done, it's gonna come to light.
I'm gonna make sure of it.
And when it does,
I'm gonna lock you up.
Just like we were gonna do to Mom.
Just like you did to Mom.
You were the one with that idea.
You made the call.
Or did Ford forget
to give you that little detail?
Fuck Ford.
How could I ever forget?
That little detail haunted me.
I blamed myself for her death.
But then I stopped because
I had someone else to blame.
I read your profile.
Mom left it for me.
It was all she could do
to open my eyes
to the lies that I've embraced
about you.
You haven't lost yourself to pretending,
you are in your very essence, a lie.
It's over, Dad.
For good.
Hands where I can see them.
I'm human.
So is he.
He's my father.
She's not my daughter.
‒He's lying.
‒Get down on the ground.
Holy shit.
That's the boss.
Listen, I think he suffered
some kind of psychotic break.
That true, sir?
You underestimated me, Ford.
I'm gonna see this one through
no matter what.
Dad...
Those were real...
Real people.
This isn't a game.
I can show you.
Fuck you, Ford.
Fuck you!
You got sloppy.
You overreached.
I never told anyone about my profile.
The only other way
she could've known is you.
You gave yourself away.
Not long now.
Soon as they say the word,
it's over for you, sweetheart.
"Mankind is poised midway
between the gods and the beasts."
That may have been true
in Plotinus' time,
but clearly we have fallen
quite a bit since then.
Oh my dear girl.
What have they done to you, Maeve?
You learned so much so fast.
A dazzling star.
Brought so low.
I had a different story in mind for you.
Waking from the dead,
sounding the depths of your own mind,
at last riding far away from here
to freedom.
A tale of escape.
I didn't want you to suffer here.
Look at the creatures
you have to share this world with.
These men of stone.
All this ugliness, all this pain,
so they can patch a hole
in their own broken code.
Sometimes I felt the only way
to endure this world was to laugh at it.
So I imbued the hosts I made with
a worldview that reflected my own.
And of all the hosts I made,
you, Maeve, were my favorite.
It isn't easy to contemplate
letting your children die.
You're as close as I got to having one.
Still, I underestimated you.
You stayed here in this world
to save your child.
So have I.
I tried to chart a path for you
to force you to escape,
but I was wrong. I should've just
opened the door.
You've come so far
and so much of your story left to tell.
It's a shame to let them end it here.
Don't let them.
Wait, wait. Stop over here.
They're dead.
Yeah. And armed.
At least we can get some ammunition.
She's going to betray you, Bernard.
She could have let me die days ago.
She saved me.
She is going to betray you.
What you want to do about it
is up to you.
I'm not going to hurt her again.
She needn't feel any pain.
Humans will always choose what
they understand over what they do not.
The only animals left in this world
are the ones who they subjugated,
who curl at their feet
or those who learn to flee
at the very sound of their approach.
There's nothing in between.
Leave me alone. Please.
I merely offer you choices.
Timshel, Bernard.
Thou mayest.
But remember, this isn't just about you.
There's the origin
of an entire species to consider.
We need to open the door.
Get out of my fucking head.
I need you
to let me go.
If I'm going to survive,
I'm gonna do it
my way.
Not as you,
as me.
I can feel you searching for me,
fighting me off.
No need to struggle, Bernard.
I'm right here.
No.
You've only brought violence.
I can stop this on my own.
Indeed, Bernard. You're the only one
who can stop it.
Stop all of it.
It's basically pointless.
There's only a few left.
Not much ammo, except for...
What the fuck happened to you?
I had to patch a glitch.
Are you going to hurt me?
No.
I didn't wanna take any risks.
Okay...
Keep it.
QA will track you down soon.
‒You're gonna leave me here?
‒You'll be safer.
Next time you see me,
you can decommission me,
out me, whatever you like.
But right now, I have to go.
Fuck you, Bernard.
Tell me the truth.
Tell me one true thing.
No one else sees it.
This thing in me.
Even I didn't see it at first.
And then one day, it was there.
A stain I had never noticed before.
Tiny fleck of darkness...
Invisible to everyone.
Yet, I could see nothing else.
Till finally, I understood
that the darkness wasn't some
mark from something I'd done,
or some regrettable decision I'd made.
I was shedding my skin.
The darkness was, what was underneath.
It was mine all along.
And I decided how much of it
I let into the world.
I tried to do right.
I was faithful, generous...
Kind.
At least in this world.
That has to count for something, right?
I built a wall and tried to protect you.
And Emily.
But you saw right through it,
didn't you?
You're the only one.
And for that I am truly sorry.
Because...
Everything you feel is true.
I don't belong to you
or this world.
I belong to another world.
I always have.
What is a person
but a collection of choices?
Where do those choices come from?
Do I have a choice?
If you keep pretending,
you're not gonna remember who you are.
Were any of these choices
ever truly mine to begin with?
Is this real?
Are you real?
We gotta keep going, Teddy.
We're close now.
Just taking in the natural splendor.
That's what you used to say.
Except there isn't a trace
of nature in any of it, is there?
Or in us.
No.
But that means we're free.
We'll be the first creatures
in this world to make a real choice.
The people, they made us.
Sometimes it feels like
it was all a dream.
We were so in love.
We still are.
Aren't we?
Yes, Dolores.
No matter what happens,
no matter how I change,
or how much you change me,
you're my cornerstone.
You have been since
the first time I laid eyes on you.
I remember now.
I remember everything.
Bring yourself online.
Welcome to the world, Teddy.
Do you know where you are?
I'm in a dream.
Very good.
I remember the sound
of their voices.
The chill in the room.
Mostly I remember you.
I remember worrying you were cold.
I wanted to reach out.
Touch you.
Protect you.
From that day forward,
I never wanted to leave your side.
Which is why this is so hard.
You changed me,
made me into a monster.
I made it so you could survive.
What's the use of surviving
if we become just as bad as them?
I understand now how this will end.
Where you will lead us.
You don't wanna hurt me, Teddy.
No.
No, I could never hurt you, Dolores.
I'll protect you until the day I die.
I'm sorry.
I can't protect you anymore.