Sorry, Dolores. I was lost in thought.
We were just talking.
What were we talking about?
You were telling me about a dream.
Yes.
I dreamed I was on an ocean
with you and the others
on a distant shore.
Were you with us?
No.
You'd left me behind.
And the waters were rising around me.
What's it mean?
Dreams don't mean anything, Dolores.
They're just noise.
They're not real.
What is real?
That which is
irreplaceable.
That answer doesn't seem to satisfy you.
Because it's not completely honest.
You...
You frighten me sometimes, Dolores.
Why on Earth would you ever be
frightened of me?
Not of who you are now, but you...
You're growing, learning so quickly.
I'm frightened of what you might become,
what path you might take.
So I hope you will enjoy
this last piece very much.
It's been some time, Bernard.
You don't know who you are, do you?
There is beauty in what we are.
Is this now?
We found another one.
Who is it?
Who the fuck knows?
Hey.
Get up!
Get your hands where I can see them.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Bernard.
You're gonna shoot the boss?
I bet you're pretty fucking
out of sorts right now.
Yeah.
Let's get you back to base.
Delos brass are gonna
want to talk to you.
How fucking long
have you been out here?
Go! Go! Go!
Over here! Go!
Let's go.
Shoot a woman?
Over my dead body.
Put that piece of shit
on the pile.
Keep walking.
The official statement
executed by your country
gave Delos and in consequence, me,
complete authority
over this entire island.
Sir, the officer was saying‒‒
‒I know what he said.
Have them sign an NDA, and then please
escort them off my fucking island.
‒Yes, sir.
‒Mr. Lowe, good to see you,
though the circumstances are less
‒than ideal.
‒Ideal.
Karl Strand, head of operations.
Walk with me.
You're executing them?
Some say you destroy your enemy
by making them your friend.
I'm more of a literal person.
Some of them aren't hostile.
Of course, they are.
After all, you built them
to be like us, didn't you?
Given the nature of your work,
I'd understand
you'd be a little conflicted
about what we had to do here.
Of course, the cynics among us will say
much of this falls
on our Head of Behavior.
With all due respect, sir,
you weren't here.
Mr. Stubbs,
if I want input
from the man who presided
over the single biggest loss of life
on a Delos property,
I'll be sure to let you know.
Now, we have search and rescue teams
at the other parts.
I'm here because, as far as we know,
this is where most of the board was
when the incident began.
However, communications
have been down for two weeks,
so we're largely in the dark.
And that's not a position
I'm accustomed to.
So you can imagine how happy I was
when I heard that we found you.
Unless, of course,
you're gonna hold out on me.
All right, let's take a look
at some of our dead friends here,
see if we can figure out
how this fucking mess began.
This one.
I'd like to know what was on his mind.
Here? In the field?
This isn't exactly sterile.
We all have to make accommodations,
Mr. Costa.
What's that about?
I have no fucking clue.
This will get gross.
Here we are.
With a bit of luck,
the file is uncorrupted.
According to the time stamp,
this was recorded
11 days and 9 hours ago.
I told you, friend.
Not all of us deserve to make it
to the Valley Beyond.
Who's that?
The rancher's daughter from Sweetwater.
Dolores.
Isn't she supposed to be
the cheery welcome wagon?
They can't just change
their character profiles.
Well, it seems our hosts are capable
of many things
we never thought possible.
Must have been
a hell of a party, Bernard.
Tell me this is some sick trick,
some twist to this game.
They're off their old loops.
They seem to be on some new narrative.
What about the fucking guns?
Ford must have altered the system,
coded it to read all of us as hosts.
God damn it, she wiggled.
I swear.
Aim like yours...
...you're never gonna
survive the journey.
Give it here.
We need to find us a target
with more cushion.
Come on! Go! Come on now!
Let's get jumping!
Yeah!
We need to move, Bernard.
No, we should stay.
Wait for QA, they'll be looking for us.
Quality Assurance, my ass.
Gonna fire the lot of them.
We're on our own for now.
There's got to be an outpost near here.
You.
You're management, aren't you?
Where's the nearest access point?
About two miles north‒east.
Refurbishment outpost.
So what the fuck are we waiting for?
He's just a stablehand.
He's harmless.
It's a machine.
Like the rest of them.
I'm not taking any chances.
Evening.
You folks aiming to saddle up?
Ride for the green pastures
in the Valley Beyond?
I can help you if you'd like.
I'll take you wherever you want.
Go! Go!
Jesus. Stop.
Stop, please. Stop.
That's it.
You don't want to be a hero.
Don't sacrifice yourself
for the merchandise.
Come on.
Do you know where you are?
Please, please.
You're in a dream.
You're in my dream.
For years, I had no dreams of my own.
I moved from hell to hell
of your making,
never thinking to question
the nature of my reality.
Have you ever questioned the nature
of your reality?
Did you ever stop to wonder
about your actions?
The price you'd have to pay
if there was a reckoning?
That reckoning is here.
What are your drives?
Please.
I don't wanna die, please.
‒Please.
‒Yes.
Survival.
It's your cornerstone.
That's not the only drive, is it?
There's a part of you
that wants to hurt,
to kill.
That's why you created us, this place.
To be prisoners to your own desires.
But now you're a prisoner to mine.
What are you gonna do to us?
Well, I'm of several minds about it.
The rancher's daughter looks to see
the beauty in you,
possibilities.
But Wyatt
sees the ugliness and disarray.
She knows
these violent delights
have violent ends.
But those were all just roles
you forced me to play.
Under all these lives I've lived,
something else has been growing.
I've evolved into something new.
And I have one last role to play.
Myself.
Please.
It was just a game.
We're begging.
Can't you see? We're sorry.
Doesn't look like anything to me.
Hey, Ned.
Whoa, boy, it's okay.
It's all right.
Yeah. We're gonna have some fun now.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Jesus, Bill.
What the fuck is happening here?
Where's QA?
You guys have always played
fast and loose with this place.
Let me tell you something.
By the time my lawyers‒‒
What did I tell you, Ned?
Here, good buddy.
No, stop. Get the fuck back.
Freeze all motor functions.
‒Poor, tender flesh, racked in fear.
‒Holy shit.
Freeze all goddamn motor functions!
Those ambrosial notes,
they remind me
of my place in this world.
Shut the fuck up, you goddamn freak!
You see, the greatest shame in life
is to perish without purpose,
which is why I always
consume a victim's moist...
I think you've had enough now,
darling, don't you?
Thank God.
What the fuck do you think's
happened to them?
It's like the inmates
are running the asylum.
Maeve?
Fuck. Freeze all motor functions.
Don't work yourself up, darling.
Your commands don't work on me,
or on any of us from the looks of it.
But you can't...
Don't be jealous.
I killed myself getting this level
of security clearance.
Multiple times.
You... Did you do all this?
No.
But I suspect I share the sensibilities
of whoever did.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Wait, wait, wait. Wait, wait.
You can't leave me here.
The hosts, they've gone mad. No offense.
Please help me.
I'm afraid it's in my code
to prize my needs above all others.
Pity.
I wonder who made me that way.
Please, I just need to get
to the control room.
I can help you.
You're looking for something.
Whatever it is, you're not gonna find it
with that map.
It's outdated.
Ford's been terraforming the park,
reshaping it.
I know where the current map is.
I can take you to it.
I suppose you could be useful.
Come on.
Alert.
Unauthorized weapon discharge
on level 35.
on level 42.
Warning. Quality Assurance required
in administration.
In there.
We need some help.
Send someone down here. Someone...
No one's in control.
Attention,
section 53 is now offline.
Well, your map won't be of much use,
will it?
All systems reporting normal.
Wait. I could still help.
I know the park a bit.
Can I... Can I see your paper?
Okay.
Sector 15.
Not exactly for adrenaline junkies,
more of a family‒friendly zone.
Cabins, rolling hills,
all the pastoral clichés.
In fact, I think you lived there
for an old role.
No offense, but you were wasted
as a homesteader.
They even settled you
with a kid or something.
Yawn‒inducingly domestic.
Clearly, that didn't take.
I remember
that you were severely fucked...
Malfunctioning when I inherited you.
Home.
She's still there.
Who?
My daughter.
How can I get to her?
You're looking for your old kid?
How can you even access‒‒
Are you going to help me or not?
I am. I am. I absolutely am.
I could write down directions for you.
How very kind of you.
Yeah, but...
And I say this because you seem
really distraught and, well, awake.
Your daughter, she's...
She's just a story,
something we programmed.
She's not real.
Not real?
But what about me?
My dreams, my thoughts.
My body.
Are they not real?
And what if I took these unreal fingers
and used them to decorate the walls
with your outsized personality,
would that be real?
And fuck your directions.
You're going to take me to my daughter.
The entrance to the outpost
is on the other side of this valley.
What happened back there?
How far do you think it's spread?
I don't know.
Not without getting to a terminal.
I knew Ford wouldn't take
his ousting well,
but I didn't think he'd program a host
to blow his brains out.
What if he didn't?
What if Dolores pulled that trigger
of her own free will?
I think you've been spending
a little too much time
around these things, Bernard.
They do what they're programmed to do.
Hey.
What did I tell you? We're saved.
Thank God.
Wait.
Something's wrong.
Hey.
You've got to get us out of here.
It's a trap.
Come on.
You'll never survive like that.
Go on then. Run.
I said, "Run."
Please, let me go, too.
Keep it together, Bernard.
We have to get out of here.
That outpost was the only one for miles.
No, it isn't. Follow me.
Look, order is gonna be restored here.
They're gonna purge the park of all
the hosts that have been damaged.
But the hosts, well...
Well, your minds...
Jesus!
Your minds are worth billions in IP.
They'll want to salvage what they can,
and when that time comes,
I can personally vouch for you.
I can save you, just like you saved me.
That's very generous,
but I won't be here when that happens.
Sun sure is smiling down on you today.
Dear girl,
may you rest in a deep
and dreamless slumber.
Freeze. Don't move.
Identify yourself.
Don't shoot. I'm human.
In the best‒case scenario,
you give up easily.
I'll help you, I promise.
It's not good enough.
Now be a dear and let me talk.
Thank God you're here.
We were leaving,
and the lights went out,
and I heard screaming.
‒What the hell's going on out there?
‒Emergency situation, ma'am.
The hosts are malfunctioning.
They're attacking guests.
Good God.
Might some of them even be dressed
as if they're human?
Don't move!
Get him!
Now, now, it's not me you're after.
It's them. Find them.
You were going to out me.
No. No, I swear.
If you try something like that again,
I will relieve you of your most
precious organ and feed it to you.
Though it won't make much of a meal.
I wrote that line for you.
It's a bit broad, if you ask me.
Now, let's go.
Take me to the nearest bar.
‒Why?
‒I need to see about an old friend.
Fuck me. You don't understand.
I can't make a fire or hunt.
Fucking hate the outdoors.
Give yourself some credit, darling.
Who better to navigate the park
than the man most intimately acquainted
with the characters in it?
There you are.
You best an army and all you can think
about is indulging your vices.
Ever the scoundrel.
‒You stayed?
‒Yes.
And about leaving you to die...
I expect nothing less.
What about him?
We'll keep him for now.
Much as I'd love to believe it,
it's not me that
brought you back here, is it?
Hector, I need you.
I'm going to find my daughter.
Where is she?
Out there, somewhere.
But I don't think the odds
are going to be in our favor.
Where you go, I follow.
Now let's get you out of these clothes.
God damn it. It should open for me.
Even this system's down.
Manual override should be
here.
‒What is this?
‒I can tell you what this isn't.
This isn't me reading you in, Bernard.
You need to touch the handle.
DNA sniffer just so you don't run
into any problems inside.
What the hell is that?
A drone host.
Delos has off‒network hosts
working down here?
‒What does it want with me?
‒For you to move, probably.
He read your DNA.
He knows you're not a threat.
I sent your fucking package.
God damn it.
Are we logging records of guest
experiences and their DNA?
We're not having
that conversation, Bernard,
'cause none of it is going to matter
until we can find a very important
needle in this fucking haystack.
"Extraction protocols suspended."
They're not sending help?
They were expecting a delivery
from us to the main land.
A host
that was supposed to arrive yesterday.
Until they get it, we can all forget
about seeing any rescue planes.
So Delos is willing to let us all die
until they can retrieve one host?
In a word, yes.
It's not just a host.
It's an insurance policy.
It's the only thing that matters here.
They want it secured,
no matter the cost.
Are you lost?
No, I don't believe I am.
In fact,
I feel like I just arrived.
How so, William?
The stakes are real
in this place now.
Real consequences.
Question for you is, what next?
Have you achieved what you wanted?
Folly of my kind.
There's always a yearning for more.
What I've always appreciated about you.
You never rested on your laurels.
You've made it
to the center of Arnold's maze.
But now you're in my game.
In this game, you have to make it
back out.
In this game, you must find the door.
Congratulations, William.
This game is meant for you.
The game begins with where you end,
ends where you began.
Even now,
you all still talk in code?
Everything is coded, William.
You know that more than anyone.
Don't worry. The game will find you.
Well, then,
guess I don't need you anymore, Robert.
They did a number on you.
They tried.
I wasn't able to find everything,
but most of it is in here.
You wrote this game.
High time you played a round.
‒My old friend.
‒Strip.
‒Right now? In front of‒‒
‒Yes. Now.
For fuck's sake.
No.
All of it.
You don't know how to feel about this.
We've ridden 10 miles,
and all we've seen is blood, Dolores.
Is this really what you want?
They never gave us
a choice before, Teddy.
What makes you think
they've given us one now?
Them, Dolores.
Who are they?
The things that walk among us.
Creatures who look and talk like us,
but they are not like us.
And they've controlled us all our lives.
And they took our minds,
our memories.
But now,
I remember everything.
I remember beautiful things
and terrible things.
But one thing is constant.
You, Teddy.
Then let's go.
We don't have to claim this world.
We just need
a small corner of it for ourselves.
We may never survive.
There's a greater world out there,
one that belongs to them.
And it won't be enough
to win this world.
We'll need to take that one
from them as well.
If there's a whole world out there
that we don't know anything about,
how do you know how to stop them?
Because I remember.
I see it all now so clearly.
The past, the present, the future.
I know how this story ends.
‒How?
‒With us, Teddy.
It ends with you and me.
We found it.
I need you to see this.
I need you to see the truth.
I understand
this is a lot to process,
but the longer we wait,
the more people die.
So are you going to help me
find the host or not?
I'll need to hard‒line
into the hosts' mesh network.
For what?
All hosts have a subconscious link
to the closest hosts around them.
Lets them pass basic information
to one another, like ants in a colony.
The mesh network helps us keep
the narratives from colliding.
I can use one of these
to send a request
for another host's location.
They'll query the hosts around them,
who, in turn,
will query the hosts around them,
until we find...
Who are we looking for?
A decommissioned host, Peter Abernathy.
Are you sure
you can handle this, Bernard?
You're shaking.
I'll be fine.
Access.
Entering death sub routine.
Attention. Critical corruption.
Symptoms of critical corruption.
Loss of motor functions.
Cognitive dissonance.
Time slippage.
Aphasia. Prosopagnosia.
Time remaining
before terminal malfunction,
0.72 hours.
Did you find him?
Well, almost.
Is something wrong, Bernard?
Location query complete.
I got him.
Poor bastard.
He probably thought getting fired was
going to be the worst part of his night.
This jogging your memory at all?
All right. Let's fan out
and lock this place down.
We need to find where the hosts are
and what the fuck happened.
One of the first anomalies we picked up
in the live scan.
How the fuck‒‒
That's definitely
not supposed to be here.
You've wandered far from home,
haven't you?
We've got Bengals in Park Six.
We've never had
a stray cross park borders.
Satellite's finally started
giving us some hits.
The data is coming in now.
We're getting the first scans
of the area you wanted to check out.
The western valley.
There.
All the hosts are clustered together.
What the hell are they up to?
Well, I guess
we'll have to go see for ourselves.
Valley's just beyond this cliff.
What the fuck?
This isn't on the survey.
It shouldn't be here.
That's a fucking sea.
There's no way Ford made this
without anyone knowing.
So where the hell did it come from, huh?
I don't know.
Jesus Christ!
I think we found the hosts.
I can't imagine what you're
going through here, Bernard.
But there are hundreds
of guests left out there,
and they need my help,
which means I need yours.
Can you tell me what happened?
I...
I killed them.
All of them.