A.J.
Jesus, Meadow, chill out.
Sukanya, what goes in
must come out.
And these people now being released
from prison are the same ones...
...who were jailed during
the Mafia crackdowns of the 1980s?
Seems like yesterday, doesn't it?
For years, we heard how law enforcement
broke the back of the Mob.
Well, they've served their time.
It's the old never-ending battle
against crime and corruption, Sukanya...
...to quote Superman.
So, what do you think is gonna happen
with this infusion of new blood?
We could be looking at a period
of violent power struggle.
They paint everything the worst,
these news people.
- How long until dinner?
- Any familiar names?
In New York, the only old-style boss
still in place is Carmine Lupertazzi.
He'll soon be rejoined by Angelo Garepe,
his former consigliore.
Also, Philip Leotardo,
long-time Lupertazzi captain.
- Can you help me here? Crush some ice?
- I'll be right there.
New Jersey's a better
case in point, Sukanya.
You've got Michele "Feech" La Manna,
released just this week...
...a man greatly feared
and respected in the '70s.
Amen to that.
Similar situation with Anthony Blundetto,
in that same crime family, the Sopranos.
- Let me see how he looks.
- Once known as Tony B., still is.
Twenty-eight years old
when he went away. A rising star.
Thought to be the central suspect in the
killing of Thomas Gilardi and his driver.
That's the best picture
they could find?
- He was a fox.
- Pipe down. We're trying to watch.
It's my house, Tony.
- What are you watching?
- Go call your brother for dinner.
- Bobby.
- Be nice to have him back, huh?
- Your cousin?
- Miss the shit out of him.
The older you are,
the more you're entitled to eat.
- Hi. Sorry.
- Where the hell you been?
- Your mother didn't send anything?
- She wasn't home.
Her and Aunt Ro
went out to dinner, I think.
Everybody sit.
Now, please.
This is great of you, Aunt Jan,
keeping the Sunday-dinner tradition going.
Can you get the roast out of the oven?
- Canned clam chowder?
- Go sit, goddamn it.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
My wedding ring.
- Go strap on the bag, Ton?
- Yeah.
Would you say this is an interesting point
in the history of the Mafia?
I'd say we're looking at a great year
for crime reporters, Sukanya.
Class of '04?
- Anthony.
- What?
I wanna say hello.
Can you stop a minute?
- How was dinner?
- Fine.
- What did you have?
- Roast beef.
- Did your father pick up his mail?
- No, he didn't come in. He was tired.
He said he just wanted to go to bed.
Listen, I'm trying to practice.
I see you didn't bring the Power Vac in
from the pool house like I asked.
Why does that have to be done? Grandpa
still has to lift it into his truck.
I don't want him to have to drag it
from all the way out back.
It's so nice to have a man
around the house.
You should have
thought about that before.
What did you say?
Go out and get that vacuum, now.
What did I just say? Go.
Mom! Mommy! Oh, my God.
Mommy, help. Mommy?
Mom.
Mommy.
A.J., be quiet, don't move.
Mommy?
Mommy!
- Get Dad's gun.
- It's all the way in the dining room.
Hey, go away! Go!
Hey! Get out of here!
Go!
- How was the olive loaf?
- You know what I like?
- I like the Gulden's Brown Mustard.
- Are you leaving?
Yeah, I got a overseas call
coming at home.
- Finish your sandwich at least first.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Could be the same one
from Willow Drive.
God. The most densely populated state
in the country, and still this.
Gone. He went through your neighbors'
garbage, though, the Kalchiems'.
This has been going on all over.
If my son had been alone...
You're not gonna wanna put
your trash out until close to pickup time.
Now, you hear that?
Also, put ammonia or bleach
in the container and on the lid.
I posted a notice for your neighbors.
If this had been a category two,
injury or serious property damage...
...we could set traps, but not for this.
God.
You should've busted a cap in his ass
with Dad's rifle.
It's illegal to discharge firearms
within the borough limits, son.
- You're gonna call Dad, aren't you?
- No.
A great percentage of them
don't come back.
He does, call us.
Ohh, Ahh...
Do you have bird feed back there?
Duck food. Yes, my husband's.
It's probably what attracted the animal.
See, the corn's gone damp and aromatic.
- Tell your husband to put it inside.
- Right.
Setting up the equipment
is a complicated affair.
Video cameras and built-in recorders.
Then the car that he qualifi...
Hello.
I'm Dr. Lowenstein.
- Go back.
- What?
- Come on.
- You're kidding.
- No, go back. Please.
- Why don't you come in?
- I like Nolte.
- Why did you tell me that story?
I'm sorry. That's the wrong story.
Let's just skip it...
...and I'll try to think of a better one.
What's bothering you?
Global warming, acid rain, national debt.
Never even knew it was going on.
- Look at her nails. Totally real.
- Maybe you weren't paying attention.
Oh, let's face it, Lowenstein,
women are more devious than men.
My therapist was a woman.
Too bad you didn't get
all your talking done with her.
You expect a man
to be a tower of strength.
Then when it turns out he's got a few
weaknesses and some insecurities...
...what do you do? You turn around
and, goddamn it, you betray him.
- You feel that your mother betrayed you?
- Oh, God, I hate this Freudian crap.
It's not your job to listen to my problems.
If you don't mind, I'd like to go.
- You're free to leave anytime you want.
- Good.
- Goddamn shrink. Who was I kidding?
- What are you smiling at?
- I was a champion.
- Nothing. I don't know.
You have this goofy little look
on your face.
Come on.
Until Susan Lowenstein came along.
Her questions making me as dizzy
as her perfume.
- Jennifer Melfi?
- Yes?
So we open the fucking trunk.
This suffocating Russian cocksucker
pops up. He's still alive.
We lead him through the snow.
This asshole's shivering.
I mean, he's wearing fucking pajamas
and slippers in like 8-degree weather.
Hey.
- There he is.
- How you doing?
- Fellas.
- Hey, Ton.
Radio on the way in,
another fucking incident at the airport.
Fucking assholes.
I gotta make a couple calls.
Anyway, he starts running,
the Russian.
Boom! I'm telling you, the top of his head
came off like a fucking bad rug.
What a beating we had give this prick.
- Where is he now, you think?
- Who the fuck cares, right?
- Who the fuck knows?
- Poor bastard.
Never would have happened
if Paulie hadn't initially overreacted...
...but it's one for the books.
What do you mean, overreacted?
You choked him with the lamp,
or we could've got Silvio's scarole...
...without spending the night
in the open.
You let him jab you with the shovel.
Lets his guard down.
We would have caught up to the prick
if you didn't lose your fucking shoe.
Wait, you lost your shoe?
You didn't tell us about that.
- "Chrissy, don't leave me out here."
- You little cocksucker.
I covered your ass with Tony
about that whole thing...
...and never a word of fucking thanks.
Always playing that blood-relation card.
Tony's little favorite.
- Fuck you.
- What?
- Come on!
- Come on.
What the fuck?
That was a good story, damn it.
I'm telling you right now...
...it's finished with us.
- Goodbye, Dr. Melfi.
- See you next week.
- Hello.
- Like the flowers?
And, yeah, before you ask,
I am taking the medication.
How are you, Anthony?
- It's been a long time.
- I'm great, actually. You?
Thank you
for that beautiful arrangement.
I see you haven't lost
your sense of humor.
Well, you gotta have a sense of humor
in life, right? You taught me that.
And how is life?
Good, good.
Well, I'm separated, me and Carmela.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Don't be.
Well, I always thought I saw
some good things there.
Two healthy kids. Other than that...
Look, the reason I called...
...I'd like you to have dinner with me.
Since we're not in therapy no more
and I'm a bachelor again.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Unfortunately, because of our prior
clinical relationship...
...I just can't do it.
- What, eat? You must be a toothpick.
- You know what I mean.
See, I knew you were gonna
say something like that.
I can't, Anthony, I'm sorry.
You know, I waited a respectable period
or whatever before making this call.
Well, then you realize yourself...
...there's something not quite right
about us dating.
No, I'm not undeterred by this.
We will talk again.
Thank you for the flowers.
- And the detergent.
- Of course, what's wrong with me?
- I don't know.
But we'll find out.
Leave it to Dr. Tony.
- What's the matter?
- The bear. Stay there.
Oh, right, lock the door.
What do you think, he's gonna wipe
his feet? He'll smash through the glass.
- Now, where is that guy's card?
- I don't know.
You have reached Fish and Game.
If you know the extension, press it now.
- Unbelievable.
- If not, press 0 for a directory.
Hello?
For hunting and fishing licenses, press 2.
For animal removal...
Did you get a letter
from my cousin in the can?
Yes, Officer Zmuida, hi.
Mrs. Soprano from North Caldwell.
We had the bear in our yard
the other night.
- What the fuck?
- Yes. It came back.
- Is anybody hurt?
- No, thank God.
- Property damage?
- No property damage I could see...
...but I didn't really
wanna go out there.
Oh, one of those eastern black bears?
- We can be up in about an hour.
- Yes. That would be great.
- Okay, we'll be here.
- All right. See you then.
Jesus Christ, when did this happen?
The first time, Sunday night,
and I saw it again just now.
A.J. didn't mention it to you when
you went to the game?
No.
I have to warn the Cusamanos.
They keep Esterhaz
chained up along the side there.
That bear will rip him to pieces.
Cusamanos weren't home.
Got the machine.
Well, I don't see Esterhaz.
Why didn't you call me
when this happened?
I called the cops.
They called Fish and Game.
What are you trying to prove? This isn't
Little House on the Fucking Prairie.
- Those thing are dangerous.
- Well, the ranger, whatever...
...said it was your duck food out there
that attracted it.
- I never heard of that happening before.
- Trapper Joe over here.
- We didn't find a spoor.
- I was just telling the gentleman...
...the animal still doesn't meet
the parameters for a removal.
So when somebody's leg is gone...
Problem is, it hasn't really
threatened anybody.
Sorry.
Whoa, hold on a minute.
You and your pal buy some new
lanyards for your whistles.
Well, we can't accept that.
And we don't have whistles.
Thanks, though.
Ranger Rick's a little light
in the Timberlands, huh?
Everybody's always gay with you.
He's a good-looking guy, that's all.
I already put the ammonia on the cans.
I told you.
Look, I came here
to give you your money...
...but this bear thing, though, I'm...
I'm worried.
You and A.J. here by yourselves.
What can we do? You want coffee?
- Last time it had a weird taste.
- The coffeemaker is shot.
- The heating element's corroded.
- That's not the problem.
You don't need another one of those.
Last month it was the upstairs toilet.
He goes down the street
to Willow Drive too.
Maybe he'll stay down there.
All right, look...
...you and A.J. check yourself
into a hotel until this blows over.
Here's 1200 extra
on top of our agreement.
- I'm not going to a hotel.
- Why not?
- I don't wanna break Anthony's routines.
- He'll get a kick out of it.
It's an adventure.
God knows he loves room service.
Yeah, I'll give him room service,
the end of my foot.
- What's with the attitude?
- Well, he's an asshole, that's what.
- So what? It's his age.
- Yeah, thank you, I know.
But you buy him too much stuff.
I think because you feel guilty
about the separation.
Excuse me. It wasn't my idea.
There is more than one way to ask.
- All right, could we please not?
- Spend $5000 on a set of drums.
SAT tutor, coffeemaker,
I gotta fight you tooth and nail.
All I said was I wanna see statements
from the tutor, or he doesn't get paid.
He's a college kid, Tony.
He's not set up for that.
You worried he's gonna soak you
for an extra pencil?
Oh, rim shot!
What I think, Tony,
is you're trying to make my life now...
...as hard on me financially as possible.
- Oh, it should be easy?
- Unbelievable.
What do think,
you're the only Catholic here?
I'm old school. I don't believe
in this separation shit and divorce.
Even if my wife was going after
some fucking immigrant.
Yet you are modern enough
to use a cell phone to call Italy...
...and every other fucking place
to threaten the guy's life.
Well, that's right. Certain people see him,
he's a dead man.
- He had coffee here, Tony, that's all.
- And now the coffeemaker sucks.
How do you like them apples?
You don't wanna stay at a hotel,
you suit yourself.
This is Anthony.
Could you call me
at 973-555-1299?
Thinking maybe I gotta come back.
You know, for therapy.
- Smells good, Feech.
- Yeah? You want a taste?
No, I'll wait.
No offense, kid, but don't look to me
like you do a lot of waiting.
- Just like his old man, huh?
- Lot of changes since you went away.
Twenty years, Madonna.
You know what the biggest change
for me is? Broads shaving their bushes.
I went over to Silvio's.
Like the Girl Scouts over there.
Think I'll let this simmer a bit.
Must be different in the can now.
Not like the old days. Fucking animals.
It's all about setting a precedent.
First day there, I walk in the mess,
and I'm wearing a puss, a fucking scowl.
I look around...
It's my nephew.
- Right in the middle of my story.
- There he is.
The man, the legend, Feech La Manna.
Hey, my God, look at you,
you big galoot.
What, did you go straight from the joint
to Earl Scheib? Look at this fucking tan.
Yeah.
You close the cellar door
when you came up?
It's like the Bowery Boys in here
with this house arrest.
- You got code words and secret passages.
- He's in the middle of a story.
When isn't he?
It's day one. I'm in the mess.
I look around, and I spot the biggest,
blackest motherfucker that I can find.
Everybody's looking at me.
And I walk right up to him and I say:
"What the fuck are you looking at?"
He says, "What?"
I said, "You heard me, motherfucker.
What the fuck are you looking at?"
And with that, I hit him,
right across the fucking coconut.
He goes down. I'm on top of him.
Everybody's around.
He gets some shots in.
Everybody's going fucking crazy.
The screws, this guy, everybody!
Motherfucker!
From that time on, nobody so much as
looks at me cross-eyed.
Well, welcome home, huh?
- Welcome home.
Reason I wanted to see you, Junior,
Tony too...
...now that I'm out,
I'd like to get back in the game.
- What did you have in mind?
- You know me, I'm an entrepreneur.
Get my shy going. Sports book.
Whatever you say.
Long as you don't
step on anybody's toes.
Me? I'm Fred Astaire.
Now, what's this Feech tells me?
You got a bear up there at the house?
What's it on, fucking CNN?
No, it's just that your wife's up there,
and the kids. Your ex-wife, whatever.
It's just that, wild animals,
they're dangerous. People talk.
What people? Who?
I don't know.
What am I supposed to do? Go up there
personally and set fucking bear traps?
We're separated, for chrissake.
- So where's the dinner at?
- I forget the name. It's in the car.
- Who's gonna be there?
- What, are you on the school paper?
Guys. It's business.
- You got any cash?
- Some.
Hand me my bag.
- That's all you got?
- It's like $400.
I'm low man tonight.
I gotta pay for everybody.
You know, this is fucking ridiculous,
Christopher.
Why should you get stuck all the time?
You should make Paulie pay.
What, I make the rules now?
Guy's a captain.
I know, but when he was in jail...
All I'm saying is,
if you get the extra responsibilities...
...you should get the benefits too.
You're right.
I'll say hello to the guys from you.
Benny, hi. Come on in.
Tony sent me. He says he wants
somebody stationed in the yard.
- He's worried the bear might come back.
- What? No, I don't want this.
Well, we'll switch off,
me and Paulie Germani.
- This is silly. I'm gonna call him.
- Actually, it's not that silly, Mrs. S.
If it was my family, I'd wanna know
there was a male at the house too.
What can you do about it
if it does come back?
Tony said to unlock the closet
and give me the shkupit, he called it.
- Oh, for God's sake.
- I mean, we'll call the Fish and Game too.
It's just... I'll have the weapon in case.
He's just worried about you, that's all.
And Anthony.
Well, okay. I don't know.
- You're very nice to do this.
- Nice got nothing to do with it.
Stay inside. You don't have to sit
out there like A Fistful of Dollars.
Tony said not in the house.
I got my little Sony in the car.
You want to eat?
We were just sitting down.
No, I'm good.
I just stopped at Tio Pepe's.
This frigging olive oil.
The food's drenched.
That's the reason it happened.
As far as fucking bears are concerned,
I say, get rid of them all.
They had their turn,
and now we got ours.
That's why dinosaurs
don't exist no more.
- Wasn't it a meteor?
- They're all meat-eaters.
- Meteor. Meteor.
- Take it easy.
Gentlemen, whenever you're ready.
- All right, are we set?
- Yeah, sure.
- What are you doing? You ready?
- I gotta make a pit stop.
- You forgetting something?
- You get it. I got the last one.
Here, baby.
Have some more cheesecake.
The other thing with bears is, if
you're ever chased by one, run downhill.
- Some reason, they can't do that.
- It's the moss.
They attack when you're
having your period.
No, no, that's jungle cats.
- So can we go?
- Hold your horses.
- What's going on? We ready or what?
- Yeah.
- Fine, I'll get it.
- Give me the fucking thing.
- I said, I'll get it.
- Enough. It's done.
- Eight hundred sixty dollars.
- What?
You heard me.
That's what you owe from last night.
You said you got it. I only got
like 100 bucks on me anyways.
Then get the rest by tonight,
or you start paying points.
- I'm thinking of going for the acupuncture.
- What, your shoulder again?
- Those long drives. It's already tender.
- Next time, we get you out there, Angelo.
After 18 years in the can,
I'm just happy to be outside.
What, they don't have a golf course
at Leavenworth?
Still a smart-ass, this one.
Carmine, you all right?
You barely touched your egg salad.
Too much gherkins.
- Smell that?
- What?
- Burning hair.
- I smell cut grass.
- Any word on your cousin getting out?
- Who's your cousin again?
- Tony Blundetto.
- Oh, yeah. Good guy. Right, right.
He was my best buddy inside.
- So you gonna give him a party?
- Take him home, get him laid.
What's the matter? Carmine?
- Carmine.
- Jesus Christ, Carmine!
- Call an ambulance.
- Is he breathing?
- Get that egg salad out.
- Hurry up!
- Lupertazzi residence.
- Carmine, it's John.
Hey, John boy. How's the weather?
Look, I got some bad news.
Your dad's had a stroke.
- Oh, my God. How bad?
- There's some paralysis.
It's too early to tell.
They're doing all they can.
- My mom there?
- I called her, she's on her way.
- We're over at St. Vincent's.
- Anything, John. Anything he needs.
I'm on the next plane.
Sad, this shit, huh?
Wonder if I could smoke in here.
You know, I haven't forgotten
our arrangement last year.
- You leaving me in the lurch like that.
- It was the right thing to do, John.
- Taking out a boss? Come on.
- Even still.
What do you want, an apology?
A fucking Whitman Sampler? What?
Boy, imagine if his fucking speech
is affected. Poor bastard.
So when you're up at the house,
who comes to visit? Anybody?
Mostly Rosalie Aprile, Sil's wife.
- Who calls on the phone?
- Most of the calls are for Anthony.
So?
Look, the real reason I'm here
is to confront you, in a positive way...
...about taking our relationship
in that other direction.
Why did you have to be underhanded?
I don't find that appealing, frankly.
I was gonna ask you out for coffee
or something, but I didn't think you'd go.
I'll pay for the hour.
That goes without saying.
Forget that.
I was listening to that guy on TV.
Dr. Phil?
And he was talking about
a similar situation.
And he said that you could
if you wanted to.
There's no set rules.
It's basically about malpractice...
...and you probably couldn't get sued.
That's not the point.
Look, I was thinking about
all kinds of moves.
Buy her a piece of jewelry.
Pay the guy to close down the restaurant
where she eats, hire a mandolin player.
This is the place where we've been
most honest with each other.
And that's the way I always liked it.
So that being said,
if you don't like me personally...
...or the cut of my jib
or my face or whatever...
...then the matter will end here,
and I will never ask you again.
You can be honest.
I like you, Anthony.
And, no, you have a very nice face.
- Working on the weight too, by the way.
- Good.
Explain to me, okay, why this is
a matter of such importance to you.
- There are plenty of women out there.
- You're different from what's out there.
Not to mention
being drop-dead beautiful.
My training teaches me
to go fairly quickly to the idea...
...that what you really want
is to come back to therapy.
Jesus Christ almighty.
Come on, will you?
Your marriage of 20-something years
has collapsed.
No doubt there are issues
with your children.
Why can't I do something
that's just for me for a change?
It would be for you.
Well, I want you. And not just
for the smart things you say.
I want... I want your skin.
I want your mouth. I want your eyes.
You project all these qualities onto me.
You don't know me.
This is what happens
between doctor and patient.
Don't do that.
Out of respect for this office.
Forget about the way that Tony Soprano
makes his way in the world.
That's just to feed his children.
There's two Tony Sopranos.
You've never seen the other one.
That's the one I wanna show to you.
- Hi.
- Hey. I wonder if I could use the W.C.
- Of course, come on in.
- Yeah, okay.
- Is it cold out?
- Yeah, a little.
But I got a fleece.
I know him. He'll just keep
coming back and coming back.
I had to let him down easy, I...
- You think it's worth telling the police?
- What?
Jesus, Elliot.
I don't wanna paint in somber tones here,
but the man is a sociopath.
Unpracticed in not getting
what he wants.
And now, since the therapy is kaput,
what use are you to him except for sex?
Thank you, Elliot. Your depth of feeling
is really quite extraordinary here.
All you could come up with was this
weak borscht about professional ethics...
...because you are worried about
how this thug will handle rejection.
You know, at first I did find him
a little sexy.
Dangerous alpha male.
But as year followed year,
the ugliness I saw, I heard...
- You kept him a long time, though.
- There's a mutual sympathy there...
...of some kind, I guess.
Maybe it's just the Italian thing.
- Sil said you were looking for me?
- Sit down.
- This about the Easter baskets?
- I don't even know what that is.
And to tell you the truth,
I don't wanna know.
What's this shit between you and Paulie?
You chiseled him out of a dinner?
- I chiseled him? He said that?
- I asked you a question.
Can I say something
in my own defense?
It's not right
that I have to pay all the time.
I've been paying for fucking years.
Are you done? Good.
You pay till I tell you
you don't have to pay no more.
And don't give me that face.
You know how many tabs, how many
dinners I picked up over the years?
Richie Aprile,
fat fucking Jerry Anastasia.
Those guys killed me at Benihana's.
And forget it, if they want a steak,
I put a new wing on Peter Luger's.
Brandy, cigars, champagne.
Could've bought a fucking plane.
I hear you, Ton,
but that was before inflation.
Whatever.
It's tradition. It's like in ancient times,
the samurais, they had these pages.
Young boys that did their errands,
washed their clothes, shit like that.
It's a sign of respect.
Why don't you cheer up? One day,
some kid will be paying for your dinners.
Atlantic City loves its oldies
on Oldies 98.3.
So the pope says, "Just one more thing.
She gotta have big tits."
Oh, man.
You okay, Ton?
You're being, like, a little quiet.
Yeah, yeah, I'm just...
I'm full, that's all.
Calm before the storm. Get him near
those crap tables, and look out.
Jesus, I'm stuffed. I can't remember
the last time I ate this much.
- Sure youse don't want no dessert?
- Not for me.
No, I'm good.
Thank you. Thanks.
Enjoy it, girls.
I've been enjoying looking at you
the whole night.
- Get some fucking glasses.
- We gotta go.
All right, I'll see you over
at the $100 table.
Yeah. Right.
Ton, you sure you're all right?
You got a big mus on.
It's a fucking broad. Believe that?
- Really? You mean?
- It's the real deal, I think.
No shit, huh?
The thing is, we got this
platonic thing going.
We have had for many years.
She thinks that's what it is,
but it's not.
And no amount of convincing
will change her mind.
- So she was a friend?
- Yeah.
They're wrapping up the lobster
for me to take to Ginny.
- We'll see you over there.
- Yeah.
- Anything else, gentlemen?
- We're good.
My friend here will take
the check, though.
Have a wonderful evening.
Eleven eighty-four. Oh, babe.
I gotta play that number.
I'm gonna go wash up.
I'll tell you, after a meal like that,
what I could use is a nice piece of ass.
Who knows, maybe I'll call down,
have them send one up to the room.
Why don't you just fuck yourself,
save a little money.
- What's your problem?
- Stop trying to bait me.
- You know what my fucking problem is.
- No. Why don't you tell me?
You want me to tell you? Fine.
Steaks, 3-pound lobsters, shrimp fucking
cocktails you made everybody get.
On top of everything else, you send
those skanks a bottle of Cristal?
I was being a gentleman.
You ought to try it some time.
Not to mention the lyonnaise fucking
potatoes you didn't even touch.
- What? I lost my appetite.
- Fuck you.
- Excuse me?
- You fucking heard me.
I'm telling you, I don't give
a fuck anymore who you're related to.
Go ahead, Paulie. Go for it.
Your big fucking moment!
- You little fuck.
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
Was there a problem with the service?
- What are you talking about?
- You left me $16, sir.
- Perhaps you miscounted.
- There's 1200 bucks in there.
That's correct, and the bill was $1184.
Assuming you don't tip on tax
or alcohol, 15 percent...
I'm tapped out.
You think this job is easy?
- I have kids.
- Then go back inside before you get hurt.
- I have a goddamn family to support.
- Fuck off.
Yeah, right. Go piss it away at blackjack,
fucking assholes.
What'd you say?
What do you got to say now?
Chrissy, he's fucked up.
Don't have medicine
they're supposed to take, these assholes?
I don't know.
- He'll say we hit him with a brick.
- Still going, this asshole.
That's my money, Paulie.
- How's he doing?
- I love him so much, and I can't do shit.
We're all praying for him.
You know,
you were another son to him.
- Yeah?
- You get some sleep?
- A little. You know.
- Fucked up, huh?
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm not too worried about the cops.
Nobody knows us down there.
The reason I called,
let's bury the hatchet, you and me.
- All this bullshit with us.
- I know. I know, it's stupid.
Life's too short, Chrissy. You can't
waste it fighting with your friends.
Look what could've happened last night.
One of us could've got hurt,
or even killed, for chrissake.
I know.
You're special to me, you know.
Always have been.
You too, Paulie, to me.
- We'll split the tab.
- I'm sorry, Paulie.
I apologize too, kid.
I'll talk to you later.
When you say that,
you make me feel less than.
Next week, everyone.
Good luck.
- I'm going out of town next week.
- Okay.
- Good night.
- Bye.
Anthony.
- Hello.
- Hey.
A friend of mine had these.
I'll see you next week.
I was saying, a friend had these
and couldn't use them.
I figured, well, maybe we could.
Tickets. Bermuda.
Lodging at the Elbow Beach Hotel.
I turn down
a wonderful dinner invitation...
...and you think I'll go away with you?
Well, the guy couldn't use them,
and he gave them to me.
What do you want me to do,
throw them away?
Come on, I'm breaking out
the big guns here.
You're turning me into half a stalker.
Listen, Anthony, I'm...
I'm not going to go out with you, okay?
And it's not because you're unattractive
or I don't think I'd have a good time.
It's just something
I'm not going to do.
And I would like you
to respect my decision.
And just try to feel that
I know what's right for me.
Okay?
But it's not just
the psychiatric-ethic stuff, is it?
I wanna preserve the option for you that
you could come back to our work...
...if you wish...
...and that we could pick up
where we've left off.
- I don't think you get this. I want you.
- And that's very flattering to me.
- I'm not interested in flattering you.
- I know you're not.
All right, then what is it?
Okay? What is it?
Just help me understand it, okay?
You know, Anthony, during therapy, I...
I never judged you or your behavior.
- It's not the place of a therapist to do so.
- All right, I get all this. Go, go.
In a personal relationship,
I don't think I could sit silent.
About what?
- Our values are just very different.
- You don't like my values?
- Honestly?
- Yeah.
No.
Okay. Like what?
- It's getting late...
- No, no, no.
Come on, it's okay. It's okay.
Well, you're not a truthful person.
You're not respectful of women.
You're not really respectful of people.
- I don't love people?
- Maybe you love them, I don't know.
You take what you want from them
by force or the threat of force.
I couldn't live like that.
I couldn't bear witness to violence or...
Fuck you!
You're a fucking cunt!
Ohh.
- How come Benny's not outside?
- He just got here. He's going out.
Where is he?
He's in your office,
on the phone with his girlfriend.
Hey, Ton, how's it going?
- You can take the night off. I'll spell you.
- No, no, no, Ton, that's all right.
- It's okay, really.
- I'll take over, okay, for tonight.
- Okay, well, night, Mrs. S.
- Good night, Benny. Thank you.
- You want coffee?
- No.