Episode 3 - "Schooltown Follies"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
* Don't know who she is or *
* how she is or when,
what, why she is *
* but as for where she is,
she is where we will go *
* to Adelaide, to Adelaide *
* come on and join *
- # the Adelaide parade #
- No.
* Adelaide, to Adelaide *
* let's go to Adelaide's house *
I need to fix that last part,
but that's the idea.
So, Beatrice, you sing
the high part.
Wirt, you sing the really
- high part.
- What?
- Oh.
- And ...
Nobody is singing anything anymore.
- And, Wirt, keep moving.
- But I-I have to ... ugh.
- All right.
- But we have to do something fun.
You know, we really don't.
We can just keep walking
silently, you know?
And ... ugh.
Wirt, let's go. Come on.
- Sorry, sorry.
- But shouldn't we ...
Greg, don't you want to be
more like your brother ...
- just always doing what you're told...
- Huh?
...just a pathetic pushover
who relies on others
- to make all his decisions?
- Hey! What?
- I'm not a pushover.
- Hold on, Wirt.
- Let me get to my point.
- Fine.
See, Greg?
No willpower whatsoever.
- Hrmph!
- You need to be more like that.
- But that doesn't really sound that fun.
- The world is a miserable
place, Greg. Life isn't fun.
- Then I'll do what I need to do, I guess.
- Thank you.
We'll just focus on getting you
guys to Adelaide's so I can wash
my hands of this whole affair,
and if you could pick up
the pace a bit, that'd be great, okay?
Okay? Hey, where's Greg.
Oh.
Uh, wondered off, I guess.
- Cheese and crackers!
- We need to do our part
to make the world a better place!
Yeah.
Huh? Whoa!
School?!
Not today.
Greg!
Greg! Greg?
Oh.
- Greg?
- Excuse me?
Please, take your seat,
children. You're late.
You know the rules ... "once the
bell has run, class has begun."
Oh, sorry, everybody. Sorry.
No, he doesn't have a brain.
He can't learn anything.
Let's go, Wirt. Come on.
Here, boy.
What? Did you say something?
I can't hear you because I'm too
- busy doing what I'm told.
- What?
What are you ...
- No, no. Let's go.
- Oh, no.
See, I'm a pushover, remember?
- I have to do what she tells me to do.
- Ohh.
Wirt, your brother could
be in trouble somewhere.
Yeah!
Bluebird's have a short life span.
You two are literally killing me
every moment I'm forced
- to spend with you.
- Oh.
Young man, I will not
stand for such nonsense
in my classroom. I got
enough nonsense from that
no good, two-timing,
low-down handsome man of mine.
Oh, Jimmy Brown, why did you
have to leave me so?
And now, with my father
threatening to close the school
and that wild gorilla
on the loose, why, Jimmy, I
just have one thing to say...
* "A" is for the apple
that he gave to me *
* but I found a worm inside *
* "B" is for beloved that I... *
Ouf.
That lady's got some baggage.
What's that?
- Young man, go to the dunce box.
- Oh. Sure, okay.
- No, no.
- Sure.
No, no.
- Aw.
- Now, where were we?
Oh, yes.
* "G" is for the gentleman
I thought he was *
* when he first said hi *
So, my theory is hot dogs
are not actually dogs,
regardless of what they
teach you in school.
But you guys don't go to school, huh?
I'm gonna stick with you guys.
Hey, I got an idea.
Let's play "two old cat."
Do you guys know how to play
"two old cat"?
It's fun. I'll show you.
Here we go.
Here's one old cat.
You found another one!
Wait. No.
I think that cat is too old.
- Rowr.
- Sorry, kitty.
We'll have to find another old cat.
Hey, Jeffrey, I think
there's one behind you!
Gorilla! Run!
# And "Y," yes, why is the
question that's on my mind #
# oh, why? #
- Hey, dunce. This is dreadful!
- Good.
I'm glad you feel that way.
* I remember like ... *
- Huh?
- Gorilla!
Mealtime already?
Well, come along children.
- Huh?
- Mm-hmm.
We don't want to be late
for mealtime.
My father will be visiting today,
and we'll need to
be on our best behavior.
Quick! In here!
Oh, boy! Mealtime!
This is way better than
being chased by a gorilla.
Aw, what's the matter?
Mm. Kind of bland.
- Hey, nobody ordered you to eat yet.
- Yeah, but... Mm.
Hmm.
Ohh.
Hey! I know what to do!
Here, Miss Langtree.
Play something like this.
Oh, like this?
Mm... good enough.
* oh, potatoes and molasses *
* if you want some, oh, just ask us *
* they're warm and soft
like puppies and socks *
* filled with cream
and candy rocks *
* oh, potatoes and molasses *
* they're so much sweeter than
algebra class *
* if your stomach is grumblin' *
* and your mouth starts mumblin' *
* there's only one thing to keep *
* your brain from crumblin' *
* oh, potatoes and molasses *
* if you can't see 'em
put on your glasses *
* they're shiny and large
like a fisherman's barge *
* you know you eat enough
when you start seeing stars *
* oh, potatoes and molasses *
* it's the only thing
left on your task list *
* they're short and stout, *
* They'll make everyone shout *
* for potatoes *
* and molasses *
- # for potatoes and ... #
- That's enough!
- Father.
- Is this what I've been paying for?!
- Hey, we just wanted to have a little fun.
- I didn't invest in this
school for fun.
I thought we were trying to do
important work here, teaching
animals to count and spell.
We are! Oh, please, father,
don't close the school.
- It won't happen again.
- I should say it won't.
- This...
- Pbht!
...this...
...and this are all coming
with me. Now send them to bed!
You heard father.
Off to bed with you.
Mm.
I just wanted to have fun,
change the world, and
make it a better place.
But I just made everything worse.
Okay, Wirt, I'll admit it ...
you seem like a
pushover, but you're not.
- Oh?
- Deep down in your heart,
you're a stubborn jerk. When
are you gonna give this up?
Maybe never.
Maybe I'll never give this up.
Hmm. Yeah!
Wirt's right ... never
give up! Come on, Wirt.
- Let's go save the day.
- Okay, if you say so.
Come on.
So, what's the plan, Greg?
Plan?
Ohh. I don't know.
Ohh!
Who would've thought making a
primer school for
animals was a bad idea?
My life savings, my home ...
everything I had went into that
dear, dear school. And now
I'm forced to sell these
instruments just to keep it open.
All the while that loathsome Jimmy Brown
is off gallivanting who knows where!
Not to mention that wild
gorilla on the loose.
If only something would
go right for a change.
Okay, I think he's asleep.
- Let's go steal his stuff.
- What?
The instruments!
They've been stolen!
Who would do such a thing?!
Huh?
- Here you go.
- Oh, here you go, sonny.
What is this?
It's a benefit
concert for the school.
Ah, isn't it grand ... all
these fine people giving out
of the goodness of their hearts?
Not like my Jimmy Brown.
- Ohh, here we go.
- All he ever did was steal
- my heart away.
- Gorilla!
Young man, do something!
Uh...
Whoa!
- Finally.
- Jimmy?
That's right, darlin'.
I was the gorilla.
- But why did you do it?
- Got a job in the circus so's
I could finally buy
ya that wedding ring.
But when I got stuck in the
dang suit, everybody was too
- doggone scared to help me out.
- Aw, Jimmy.
- Oh!
- Darlin'.
I guess the world really is
as sweet as potatoes and molasses.
* oh, potatoes and molasses *
* if you want some... *
So, want me to tell Greg
it's time to get going?
Nah, let him have his fun.
* filled with cream
and candy and rocks *
- Hey, Wirt.
- Yeah?
- Tie your shoe.
- Hmm? Oh. Mm. Okay.
* ...algebra class *
* if your stomach is grumblin'
and your mouth... *
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~