Chapter 9 - "Into the Unknown"
[wind rushing, pastoral music playing]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[distant train whistle blows]
♪ The angels have gone ♪
♪ the songs have gone silent ♪
♪ you're sinking like a stone ♪
♪ before the tide ♪
♪ the river runs co-o-ld ♪
♪ the fight is over ♪
♪ still the haunted ruins of night ♪
♪ call your name ♪
[gasps]
[inhales deeply, squeals]
[guitar solo, vocalizing]
Mm-hmm.
[Gasps]
Yes.
[Wind rushing]
[Guitar solo, vocalizing Continues]
Into the Unknown.
[Crowd cheering]
[school band playing march]
[Cheering intensifies]
Goodbye!
- Thank you, old lady Daniels.
- Goodbye, Gregory.
And please don't call me
old lady.
Yes, sir, young man.
Hey, Wirt, whatcha doing?
- Nothing.
- I was helping old lady
Daniels rake some leaves
in exchange for candy.
Greg, it's Halloween.
Candy is free.
Old lady Daniels says nothing
in this world is free.
Oh, hey, and look!
I also got this rock.
[Deep voice] Hey, Wirt, want
to learn some rock facts?
[Normal voice] So, you want to
go look for frogs with me like
you said you would awhile ago
and haven't done it yet?
- Nah. Nah, I'm busy.
- Is that bee named Sara?
- W-What?
- Your tape says "for Sara."
Are you gonna give it to
Sara the bee?
I-I want to, but [sighs] I can't.
- Can I see it?
- Yeah. It's just a tape.
Hmm. Yeah.
Okay, I'll give it to her for you.
Oh, Greg!
W-Wait! No, no!
[Sweetly] Oh, look at you.
What are you supposed to be?
It's an elephant costume.
[Trumpeting]
- Pbht! See my trunk?
- [Flatly] Yeah, that's cute.
- I'm an egg.
- Yeah, everybody knows you're
- an egg, Rhondi.
- Shut it, Kathleen.
Whatever.
[Sweetly] So, what are you, Wirt?
Some kind of gnome?
Uh, I d... I don't know.
Well, it's ... See, I was ...
- I thought I'd just, like ...
- Hey, what's this?
- That's Wirt's tape for Sara.
- [Mockingly] Ooh!
Wirt loves Sara!
You want us to give it
- to her for you?
- Uh, it's for a different Sara ...
not the one you're thinking about.
Yeah, Wirt's talking about
mascot Sara ... the one he's been
- looking at all night.
- Wha...?!
[Singsong voice] Ooh!
[Laughs]
Wirt's got a crush on Sara.
[Normal voice] Well, you
better act fast 'cause we
heard Jason Funderberker
is gonna ask her out at
the Halloween party tonight.
- Jason Funderberker?
- Together: Yeah.
Yeah.
[Stammering]
- You okay, Wirt?
- Yeah, everything's ...
- everything's Jason Funderberker.
- Both: What?
Uh, uh, Jason Funderberker,
I-I got to go.
Bye!
[alternative rock music plays]
Is the dove never to
meet the sea for want
- of the odious mountain?
- Hey. So... frog hunt?
- Huh?
- I keep hearing ribbiting around
town, and I think it's
the last frog of the season.
No, I just want to wallow in misery.
Sara and Jason Funderberker. Ugh.
That guy's got his act together.
He's the total package.
- I can't compete.
- You're the total package,
too, Wirt. I bet she'll
really like your tape. [Gasps]
We never got the tape back!
I can't let her hear that tape!
- Why not?
- That tape has got poetry
and clarinet on it, Greg.
Poetry and clarinet!
Sara and Jason
Funderberker are gonna start
dating, and then they'll
hear that tape, and then
they'll just sit and listen
to it and laugh and laugh
- and laugh and laugh.
- Why don't you ask Sara out first?
- That way ...
- No, no! Ugh!
Why did you have to take the tape?
- My life is crumbling all around me!
- Okay, I think
we should put our frog
hunt on hold and go get
that tape back.
- Guys, where's the tape?
- We put it in Sara's jacket for you.
Aah!
You better hurry. She's changing
in the track shack. [laughs]
- Scuse me.
- Oh, no.
The jacket!
[Panting]
Hey!
Are you trying to spy on Sara?
Uh... no.
Run, Greg!
Hey, Sara, be careful, huh?
There's some real
- creeps out there tonight.
- Thanks, Jimmy.
[Film noir music plays] Hey, you
two robbers, you're under arrest.
Nah, I'm just kidding. Happy Halloween.
Hey, stop running in the streets!
Just kidding. Happy Halloween.
There she goes.
Let's get her.
- Yeah, let's get her.
- No, w-we're not gonna
- get her like that.
- What are we doing?
We're just gonna get the tape back.
Oh, yeah.
Let's go in after her.
[Sighs] I can't.
[Electronic music plays]
- I wasn't invited to this party.
- I'll go in.
- You weren't invited either.
- Oh.
Yeah, man, there's lots of
bat-and-ball games besides
baseball ... one old cat, two
old cat, stoolball, roundball...
[music continues, indistinct chatter]
Why are you talking to them?
[Silence]
Aah!
Oh. Hey...Guys.
I don't know what he
said, but I-It wasn't true.
- Oh, hey, Wirt.
- How's it going?
- Hi, Wirt.
- Oh. Uh, yeah.
- Well, see you around, guys.
- I used to be really good
at ballet, but my mom wanted
me to be a wrestler.
- Oh, Wirt. You're here.
- Well, I...
I was just asking if you were here.
Oh, wow.
[Chuckles nervously]
Oh, hey, we're gonna
go to the graveyard.
Oh. Are you gonna...
- do something there?
- Nah, we're just gonna hang
out and drink age-appropriate drinks.
- Like juice?
- Yeah, whatever.
Age-appropriate stuff
that's not illegal.
- Hey, you should come.
- Uh, I don't ...
[Nasally] Hey, Sara.
Are you ready to go?
- Hey, Jason Funderberker.
- Oh, hey, Wirt.
- Let's go, Sara.
- You coming, Wirt?
No, no. You ...
You go have fun with
- Jason Funderberker.
- Okay.
[Suggestively] But if
you want to stop bye
- later or something...
- Mm. Bye, Wirt.
Sayonara, Jason Funderberker.
[Gasps]
- Sara's jacket!
- My jacket. Thanks, Wirt.
- Well, see ya ... hopefully.
- Bye.
[Groans]
Sara: You're limiting the universe
to only things humans could understand.
Well, you're limiting the
universe by limiting the
possibility of human
understanding.
- Oh, yeah. Maybe.
- Sara.
- Yeah?
- Do you believe in... ghosts?
- Why?
- 'Cause there's one right
behind you!
Aw, I'm just kidding.
It's okay, Funderberker.
[Laughter]
Stop! You hit me!
Come on.
[Monstrous croak]
[Gasps]
Wirt, you tricked me!
I didn't know this was a frog
- frog hunt all along.
- It never was a ... [Gasp]
- A witches gathering!
- And so then...
a guy with an axe showed up!
[laughter]
Ugh.
Everybody loves Funderberker.
- What do I do?
- I'll pretend to be a dead
elephant and distract them
while you get the tape.
Please just stay here.
And so she kept getting and closer...
and closer...
[laughter]
- What are you doing?
- Jason. [laughter]
Oh, Jason...
[Growls]
- Go, Greg. Do it.
- Okay.
[Laughter]
Uh... you can let go of
- my hand now.
- Oh... yeah.
[Nasally] You could hold my
hand, Funderberker. I don't care.
[Howling]
Hey, isn't that Wirt's little brother?
Nooooo.
I'm the headless elephant.
[Trumpeting]
[laughter]
- Little guy.
- Is Wirt here, too?
Over there!
[Gasps]
There he is.
[Laughter]
- Wirt, we can see you, man.
- [Sighs] Greg.
What are you doing over there?
Oh. Hey, guys.
Greg! There you are.
Totally wasn't spying on anybody.
I was just looking for ...
[Siren wails]
- What's going on here?
- Huh?
Is this some kind of
witches' gathering?
- You're all under arrest.
- Run!
Hey, hey! I was just kidding.
[Upbeat music plays]
Slow down, kids.
You're gonna trip or something.
- Run, run, run! Run, run, run!
- Where do we go?
That way!
- Greg! Why did you say this way?
- I thought I heard a frog.
[Siren wails]
[Gasps]
- This is private property.
- Uh...
Hey, don't climb up there.
That's dangerous!
Get down here before you hurt yourself!
- Huh?
- It has my name on it.
[Gasps]
Let's go listen to it.
[Laughs]
Nooooooo!
Kids, really, get down from
that wall.
- That's it. That's the end.
- No, darn it. No.
I mean come down this way.
[Both grunt]
[Groans]
Once again, you ruin my life.
- [Music ends] Who? Me?
- Ugh! You and your stupid dad!
You're always prodding me,
trying to get me to join
marching band.
Oh, yeah!
If you join the marching band,
you could hang out with Sara more!
That ship has sailed, Greg,
thanks to you messing that up, too.
[Monstrous croak]
[Gasps]
Hold that thought, Wirt.
- Mm.
- What are you doing now?
[laughs]
We found our lucky frog.
We got to name him for good luck.
[Croaks]
I don't want to have anything
- to do with your or that frog!
- Okay, I'll try to think
of a name myself.
[Train approaching]
- Ugh. I'm leaving.
- Hmm?
Huh?
[Train whistle blowing]
Aah!
[Folk music plays]
♪ There's an old black train
a-comin' ♪
♪ scraping 'long the iron ♪
♪ you don't need no ticket, boy ♪
♪ it'll take you in it's time ♪
[Humming pleasantly]
[wind rushing]
Huh? Where...
Huh?
Oh. You're awake.
Here, eat some dirt.
[Spits]
Uh, Beatrice?
You know my daughter!
[Gasps] Where is she?
I don't know.
[Croaks]
Somebody left you and that
frog on the doorstep.
Beatrice.
But have you seen my brother?
- No, I'm sorry.
- Uh, I gotta go!
You're in no shape to head
into that snowstorm, young man.
- Here, here, eat more dirt.
- Thanks.
Come on, guy.
Let's go find Greg.
At least wait until the
storm dies down a bit.
You'll be no good to your
brother dead.
I was never any good
to him alive, either.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
[Soft music plays]
If you see Beatrice again,
- give her a hug for us.
- Yeah.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~