Chapter 8 - "Babes in the Wood"
[wind rushing, pastoral music playing]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[Frogs croaking]
Home!
Home? Home!
Home! Home?
- Could be around any corner.
- # tra-la-la-la #
♪ tra-la-la-la ♪
[gasps]
Hey, captain, do you hear that singing?
[Croaks]
Not you, skipper.
I'm talking to the captain.
[Croaks]
Captain Wirt, do
you know who's singing?
I don't know much
of anything anymore.
Oh. Did you know
that dinosaurs had
big ears but everyone forgot
'cause dinosaur ears
- don't have bones?
- No. I ... I didn't know that, Greg.
That's 'cause it's not true.
- It's a rock fact!
- # Tra-La-La-La #
The beast. It must
be the beast out there.
The obsidian cricket of our
inevitable twilight
- singing our requiem.
- Hmm. Yeah!
Must be a really fat cricket.
[Thuds]
[Gasps]
[bugle plays]
Look! We've reached land!
Feel the dirt!
Ahh. Smell that tree.
We must be almost there.
- Greg?
- Yes, Wirt?
Can we please stop pretending
we're gonna get home?
- Huh?
- Can we admit we're lost for good?
That this fog is deeper than we
can ever understand?
That we are but wayward leaves,
scattered to the air
by an indifferent wind?
Can we just admit we're never
gonna get back home, Greg?
- Can we do that?
- Wirt, you can do anything if
you set your mind to it.
That's what the old people say.
- Well, then let's do that.
- Yes, sir, captain!
[Bugle plays]
Greg!
You need to stop acting
ridiculous all the time.
- Huh?
- Look, do you even know why
we got lost in the first place?
It's 'cause you were goofing around and
- getting into trouble like you always do.
- Really? It was all my fault?
Yeah, so... it's not my
job to get us home, okay?
- I'm done.
- Are you saying I should
- be the leader?
- I don't care what you do.
But if I'm the leader...
what are you gonna be?
- I'll be asleep.
- Wow.
Well, then I better take a nap, too.
I need to dream up a good
way of leading us home.
Thanks for trusting me, Wirt.
Don't worry.
I won't let you down.
I'll be a good leader.
Good night.
[Breathes deeply]
Star, oh, star, up in
the sky, guide my dreams
with light that shines.
Help me know just what to do
to get Wirt home and also me, too.
And if you don't, I don't care.
I'll pull down your underwear.
[Soft music plays]
♪ Forward, cherubs ♪
♪ hear the song ♪
♪ a child's wishes ♪
♪ call us on ♪
♪ descend! ♪
- # Descend! #
- Psst! Hey!
[Groans]
Huh? Whoa!
♪ The dreams our winged ♪
♪ wind hath made ♪
♪ for only beneath ♪
♪ the veil ♪
[Gasps]
Whoa.
♪ Of sleep ♪
Whoooooa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Wow!
Hey, Greg!
[Gasps]
- Nice to see you!
- Hey, everybody!
- All: Welcome to Cloud City!
- Thank you! Thank you!
My name's Greg.
What are yours?
♪ We're the Cloud City
reception committee ♪
♪ And we are here to welcome thee ♪
[Cheers and applause]
Oh, wow, neat.
♪ And we're the Cloud City ♪
♪ auxiliary reception committee ♪
♪ and we are also here
to welcome thee ♪
Thank you.
♪ And we're the hippopotamus,
giraffe, and monkey ♪
♪ and we are committee
number three ♪
Okay. Are there more?
[Scary music plays]
[Thunder rumbles]
Well, that's enough.
[Cheers and applause]
All: So, what brings
- you to Cloud City?
- Well, I'm supposed to be a
- leader, but I don't know how.
- All: Why don't you lead
- our band in a song?
- Okay.
[up-tempo music plays]
♪ Everything is nice
and fine all the time ♪
♪ the softest clouds and rainbow skies ♪
♪ ain't gonna lie ♪
♪ we always have the most
spectacular time together ♪
♪ everyone is sittin' pretty
on top of the weather ♪
♪ lasso a cloud and
make the flowers grow ♪
♪ tie them in a bow to throw
at the end of the show ♪
♪ our songs are filled with love ♪
♪ the sweetest love ♪
♪ and we can send them down to you ♪
♪ with a little shove ♪
♪ so hitch a ride into the sky ♪
♪ and join our band ♪
♪ bring harps and lutes, kazoos,
trombones and flutes ♪
♪ or just your pots and pans ♪
♪ we can write a little jig
out of the mighty blue ♪
- # and we will be here just for you #
- Whee! Whee!
[off-key note plays]
Hee-hee!
[Muffled notes play]
Ohh!
[Thunder crashes]
All: Oh, nooooo!
The North wind is loose!
[All screaming]
♪ Oh, yeah, the ol' North wind ♪
♪ starts to howl ♪
♪ puffs up and furrows his brow ♪
♪ now, now ♪
♪ you better take cover ♪
♪ lock up those doors ♪
♪ and close the shutters ♪
♪ I say, the ol' North wind ♪
♪ yes, he is ♪
♪ he's gonna fight ♪
♪ he's gonna spin ♪
♪ he's gonna pull back ♪
♪ and blow a little more ♪
♪ until you can't tell
what you came here for ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
- Fire!
- # The ol' North wind #
♪ Yes, indeed ♪
♪ he's gonna breathe and breathe ♪
♪ he's gonna blow ♪
[Thunder crashes]
- # blow till you can't feel no more #
- Wirt? Greg?
Is anyone out there?
[Thunder crashes]
Aah!
[Shuddering]
[Laughing evilly]
[Thunder crashes]
[all gasp]
[Wind howling]
[laughing]
Hey, North wind!
Pbht!
[Grumbles]
I don't like that one bit.
That makes me mad!
[Gasps]
[Grumbling]
Oh, no!
[Crashing, thudding]
[all murmuring]
[Door creaks]
Ha ha!
Hee hee hee hee!
[Cheers and applause]
- Huh?
- Why, hello, Gregory.
- Hello.
- I am the Queen of the Clouds.
- Thank you for saving my city.
- You're welcome.
I shall grant you one wish.
What do you wish
- for most of all?
- Well, I'm supposed to be
the leader, but I don't
know how to get home.
- Do you know?
- Of course.
If you wish, I can
certainly send you home.
Great! Let's go get Wirt.
I'm sorry, Gregory, but
Wirt cannot go with you.
- He is too lost.
- [Gasps] But... anything is
possible if you set
your mind to it, right?
See how the edelwood
grows around him?
The beast has claimed him already.
Oh, I should have
been leading better.
I was goofing off again,
like always, and now
you're stuck here.
Isn't there anything I can do?
I'm sorry, Gregory.
Wirt's fate lies solely
in the beast's hands now.
Then I know what to wish for.
[Whispering]
[Gasps]
Are you sure?
Then it shall be done.
[Ting!]
- Hey. Hey, Wirt?
- Shh! Trying to sleep.
Okay. You sleep.
I'm sorry I got us lost, Wirt.
Will you take care of Ronald for me?
Okay. I have to go now.
- Goodbye, Wirt.
- Man: Yes. Come, Gregory.
- There is much to be done.
- And then you'll show us
- the way home, right?
- Of course.
We made a promise, didn't we?
[chuckles]
Greg. Greg?
Greg? Greg?!
- Where did he go?
- # Tra-La-La-La #
No. No, no, no, no!
Greg?!
[Grunting]
What the heck?
♪ tra-la-la-la ♪
- # 'Tisn't much that I require #
- Greg?!
Greg... What did I do?
Greg! Greg!
Aah! Unh!
[Groans]
[Speaking indistinctly]
[Gasps]
Huh? Greg.
Oof! Aah!
[Groaning]
Woman: Oh! You got him!
Pull! Pull! Is he alive?
- Wirt!
- Wirt! Wirt?
- Gr...eg...?
- Wirt, are you okay?
- Wirt!
- Gr...eg? I-I-I ...
- Where's Greg, Wirt?
- Beatrice?
[Shuddered breathing]
Wirt. Wirt!
[wind howling]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~