Led through the mist
By the milk light of moon
All that was lost
Is revealed
Our long-bygone burdens
Mere echoes of the spring
But where have we come
And where shall we end?
If dreams can't come true
Then why not pretend?
How the gentle wind
Beckons through the leaves
As autumn colors fall
Somewhere lost in the clouded
annals of history
lies a place that a few have seen -
a mysterious place called The Unknown.
Where long-forgotten stories are revealed
to those who travel through the wood.
Annual Gugelheim,
Albert Salami,
Giggly Jumpy Tom,
Thomas Tambourine,
Legs Hans McCollen,
Artichoke, Penguin, Pete, Steve.
But I think the very worst
name for this frog is-
Wait! Wait a second. Uh...
Greg.
Where are we?
- In the woods?
- I mean...
What are we doing out here?
We're walking home.
Greg! I think we're lost.
We should've left a trail or something!
I can leave a trail of candy from my pants.
No.
Though I am lost
My wounded heart resides back home
In pieces
Strung about the graveyard of my lost love.
For only-
Do you hear that?
Yeah.
Do you think it is some kind of deranged lunatic with an axe
waiting out there in the darkness for his next victims?
Greg.
Greg!
Uh.
Greg, you're gonna get us into trouble again!
We should ask him for help.
No. We should not ask him for help.
- But-
- Shush!
- You shush!
- Shhhh-
You shush!
Shoot. You think
we should've asked him for help?
Maybe I can help you?
I mean, you guys are lost, right?
What in the world is going on?
Well, you are slapping yourself,
and I'm answering your question, and-
No, Greg. A bird's brain isn't big enough
for cognisant speech.
Hey, what was that?!
I mean I'm just saying you are weird...
like, not normal.
I mean-
Oh my gosh, stop talking to it, Wirt
IT?
What are you doing here!?
Explain yourselves!
And I'll see you guys later. Bye!
Calm- Calm down mister!
Whatever you do here is your business.
We- We just wanna get home
with all our legs and arms attached.
These woods are no place for children.
Don't you know the Beast is afoot here?!
The Beast? We- we- we don't
know anything about that!
We're just two lost kids trying to get home!
Well... Welcome to The Unknown, boys.
You are more lost than you realize.
I found this homestead abandoned,
repurposed its mill for my needs.
You and your brother
should be safe here while I work.
Candy trail, candy trail. Can-dy trail!
What- what is your work exactly?
Everyone has a torch to burn...
and this here is mine.
I grind the heart of the Eldelwood
trees into oil, to keep this lantern lit.
This is my... lot in life. This is my burden.
This guy sounds loony.
Maybe we should make a break for it.
If we can.
But he must know the woods really well,
so we may need to knock him out first.
Except that may turn out really badly, huh?
Y- yeah. Bad-bad plan..
Forget it.
Okay.
What are you boys whispering about?
Bad plan.
We're talking about running away out of here.
Sh-shush
Sh!
Shu-SH
Leave if you wish, but remember -
The Beast haunts these woods,
ever singing his mournful melody.
In search of lost souls such as yourselves.
No, not to help you
To help us?
I have work to do in the mill.
When I'm finished I'll do what I can to
guide you if you are still here when I return.
Huh! I guess we could just leave...
I don't know. Greg!
What?
Do you think there really
is a beast out there?
Or is that guy just messing with us?
Uh huh.
I mean he could've done away with us by now
if that was his plan.
And he lit that fire. That's pretty nice.
Yeah!
I guess it's possible there is a beast...
Since there was a talking bird, but-
Yeaah.
Sometimes I feel like I'm just
like a boat upon a winding river.
I don't know.
Twisting towards an endless black sea.
Further and further,
drifitng away from where I want to be.
WHO I want to be.
Oh. I didn't know that.
Did you know that if you soak a raisin
in grape juice it turns into a grape?
IT'S A ROCK FACT!
Uhh. You are not helping at all.
Why don't you go play with
your frog or something?
Oh beans! Where is that frog o' mine?
Hold on there a second, brother o' mine.
I'll be back soon for your plan.
Kitty. Kitty!
Now where did that frog named Kitty go?
Whoop!
I tripped on my own candy trail!
That frog is giving me the runaround!
Kitty!
Gross!
Kitty?
Hmm. Is that-
Oh there you are!
Whoop!
Wirt?
Kitty?
You have beautiful eyes!
Yuhh.
Greg?
Uuhhh.
What's happening? Where is your brother?
Holy moley! Hot dog!
It's the Beast!
Stay back, boys!
This creature is known as-
Huh?
Oooh m-
Greg, why did you do that?!
That was your plan, remember?
Knock him out!
No! Bad plan! I told you to forget that plan.
AAAH
Spank. Spank. Spank!
Run run run run run! RUN!
Candy Camouflage!
Run run run run run run...
Greg!
This is amazing, huh?
Am I supposed to throw something?
Oh yeah! Ha ha!
He's eating your candy.
I wonder if he ate my help candy trail
that led to this mill!
Ahh Greg! You led the Beast
right to us with your candy!
Hey! Give me the axe.
You are too little to have it anyway.
Aaah! We- we gotta move out of here!
AH! Uuh. Greg! Give him
the rest of your candy!
Oops.
Hey, Wirt! Look!
Greg?
Wirt, he spitted out that turtle
and now he's my new best friend!
Oh!
Ow.
Hey, where are you going?
Ain't that just the way...
The mill is destroyed!
The oil! All gone!
Bu- but look!
We got the Beast problem solved!
THE DOG?
THAT IS NOT THE BEAST!
The Beast cannot be mollified
like some farmer's pet!
He stalks like the night!
He sings like the four winds!
He's the death of hope!
He steals the children.
And he'll roam the...
You're always messing up, Greg!
Boy! You have it backwards!
You are the elder child!
You are responsible
for you and you brother's actions!
Um- um. I'm sorry.
Maybe I can fix it?
I- I can't fix it.
You must go.
Take your brother North. Look for a town.
Come on, Greg.
Yeah. Thanks.
One last thing...
Beware The Unknown!
Fear the Beast!
And leave these woods...!
If you can.
It is your burden to bear!
Right. Yeah. Got it.
And little one...
You look after that frog.
Give him a proper name.
Okay!
Wirt? I think I thought
of a new name for our frog.
I'm gonna call him Wirt!
That's gonna be really confusing.
No. I'm gonna call you Kitty.
What?!
Maybe I'll start calling you Candypants.
Wow! Yeah!
Good one, Wirt!
Thanks.
I'm talking to Wirt!
I'm not talking to you.
Transcribed by lemonison
Revised by -monstersunderthebed
Thanks for using our subtitles!:)