Ladies and gentlemen...
...Corrado Soprano is not some
harmless old man...
...being persecuted
by the government...
...but a ruthless and calculating
mob boss...
...who controls a vast
criminal enterprise.
Over the past few months,
you've heard from FBI agents...
...who have documented clandestine
meetings at his doctors' offices.
Tales of bid-rigging, sweetheart deals...
...secret payoffs and even murder.
No, Corrado Soprano is not
some harmless old man...
...but a killer who orders up murder
like you and I order up coffee.
All right, so I rewrote it.
"The entire point of Melville's
Billy Budd, it seems to me...
...is to show how mean humans
can be to each other...
...when living in cramped conditions."
Whoa, hold that thought.
Come on in.
So how is your mother's
apartment coming?
Artie's Uncle Zio finished the framing.
But now the Sheetrock,
it's wet on the bottom.
There's a leak maybe in the foundation.
My father is a contractor. If you want,
I can have him take a look at it.
- He is free, I think, tomorrow afternoon.
- That would be a huge relief.
What smells in this house?
Madonna, it's like the smell of heaven.
Homemade scones. My son loves them.
Here, try one.
They are just out of the oven.
Thank you, no.
Well, that's all there is for breakfast
is fat and carbs?
We have a guest.
Could you say hello?
Anyway...
"When Mr. Claggart gets mad at Billy,
it is a surprise...
...because he is always saying
how handsome Billy is.
This does not seem realistic,
because why would an officer care...
...if a sailor was handsome or not?"
- Hey, Tony.
- Hey.
A.J., your father's leaving.
I'll come up in a minute. Go over it.
What is this?
"Ocean Club at Paradise Island."
We leave tomorrow
for three beautiful days.
Tomorrow?
I know it's short notice,
but the deal came through.
It's got a view suite,
first-class plane tickets.
Guy owes me a favor.
- What?
- I don't know.
- A.J., school...
- He's old enough to spoil himself now.
You were so jealous
when I left for Florida...
And my mother's skin condition.
Just the time it'll take to pack.
- To pack.
- I'll wait outside.
With all the shit that's been
going on, the horse and all...
Now, I know you need a break.
Deep down...
...that's probably the reason
you got your hair cut.
You believe that in there? The tickets?
She's always complaining
how we never get away.
So I make it happen,
top-shelf across the board.
All of a sudden, her mother's psoriasis
is like the bubonic fucking plague.
You know what, va fangool.
I don't know why I bother.
- She's probably worried for her mother.
- Fuck that.
They got her on the cortisone.
I know she's my wife and the mother
of my children and all.
But let me tell you something,
she can be a moody bitch.
There he is! Live from Miami Beach!
Hey.
- Where's your pop?
- Clubhouse.
Forgot to put his Desenex.
- So? This shit with Tony?
- Total debacle.
And Pop with his testa dura
is not doing anybody any good.
Anything you can do
to change your father's mind.
I'm gonna try, John.
I came all the way up here for that.
You put your sunblock on?
You know, Dad, Tony Soprano
came to visit me recently.
I bought him dinner, we talked.
I'm not sure I like
that he did that end run.
He's an old-fashioned guy, Pop,
very allegorical.
I don't think it was his intention
to insult anybody.
You distracted me.
I'm taking a mulligan.
I'm afraid that maybe you backed
yourself into a corner, this HUD thing.
Your insistence on the 40 percent.
Remember, Carmine, from the beginning,
I thought 40 was a tad steep.
A real hard-head this Soprano kid.
And the ego!
I tell you, though, when I first met him,
decisive as he is...
...I would have been proud
to call him my own son.
- Maybe there's a compromise here, then.
- There's always a compromise.
He's a bit of a poseur, you ask me.
Tony, he likes to talk the talk.
I don't know.
- What? What'd he say?
- His turf, his appraiser.
- Son of a bitch.
- What, did they resod that green?
No, you gotta give him some slack.
He hasn't really been boss
of a family very long.
Family? I told you.
They're a glorified crew.
Whatever they are, Carmine,
the Sopranos bring in a lot of cash.
I've been close with Tony
for a lot of years.
On reflection,
maybe that's the sticking post.
Tony feels you're friends,
not business associates.
See? What am I always saying?
I hate this fucking shit!
Well, it's a small space, but I guess
that makes it a decorating challenge.
The man in the store says
to put mirrors...
...but Mama thinks it's nose-in-the-air
when people look at themselves.
How about, let's see,
something like this?
That's beautiful.
She's fall in love with that place.
It's so cozy with the pillows, romantic.
Not that your mother would be...
I never thank you for helping me.
That's okay.
You're a very special woman.
Have you thought about flooring yet?
Not really, no.
Speak English, for chrissakes.
Well, if she doesn't go for mirrors...
...we should pick a light-colored
ceramic tile maybe.
All the houses back home have
the tile floors.
Well, then we should go to Colortile,
then. They have everything.
- I would love to go with you there.
- Great, then it's a date, then.
Good, it's a date.
The handicaps are all taken.
What beautiful affairs,
those Knights of Columbus dinners.
Julius La Rosa would sing with
that voice of his. Top dollar they paid.
Now, that's a nice-looking man.
- There's a handicap by the door.
- Quick, Minn.
I remember him
from Arthur Godfrey's program.
He was so mean to him, that man.
- Oh, my God!
- Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
I'm bleeding. I'm bleeding. Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ, lady! Didn't you see me?
Guy checks into one of the rooms, calls
down, says, "I got a leak in the sink."
I said, "Go ahead,
the customer's always right."
Any results from Little Carmine yet?
John Sack wants a sit-down
tomorrow night.
Sweetheart? Another drink.
Well, what do you say, Ton?
Maybe we should take off soon.
- What's your hurry? Hang on a while.
- Stay, I'll get you home.
- No, we should go.
- All right, you two wanna go?
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Come on, I'll walk you out.
Perfect.
Got my drink, a little dancing.
Wanna go upstairs?
That's okay.
Oh, Paulie. Madonna!
For Pete's sake, Nucci, you were fine
for the last two hours.
- All right, let me see.
- She's just a little shaken up.
- We gave her some Tylenol.
- It was such a crash though.
Cookie's in the x-ray with three stitches.
When was the last time
you had your eyes checked?
- My eyesight is fine.
- Listen to the doc.
You shouldn't be driving at your age.
I've been driving
since I was a young girl.
- Horse and buggies don't count.
- Paulie, be nice.
Relax, Ma.
She ain't driving you no more.
Maybe if your mother wasn't talking
in my ear!
We were all chatting.
Everybody says you're moving
into the home anyway.
- What do you need a car for?
- I like my independence.
- And it's none of your business.
- This is my ma we're talking about.
But we have tickets to The Producers.
Don't worry about it.
I'll drive you girls.
Hello?
- Colin, hi.
- Hey, Mrs. Soprano.
Meadow's on campus.
She'll be right back.
- I'm Ellen McDermott, Colin's mother.
- Hi.
I'm gonna get my shoes.
You've seen the apartment before?
I teach school out in Akron,
and I couldn't get here till now.
We thought she's only a sophomore,
why does she need an apartment?
But with those seniors moving out
mid-term, we said a Hail Mary.
No, I have to tell you.
Your daughter is really something.
- His old roommate...
- Thank you. Colin is very sweet also.
Thank you.
But she's going places, that girl.
Poised, mature.
Cooks for these other two.
Plus she volunteers at that law center.
I think that's extraordinary.
Congratulations.
Well, speak of the devil.
- Hi.
- Mom, remember Alex?
- Of course, hi.
Excuse me.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Well, the place is really shaping up.
- I guess.
What's the matter? Finn? I thought
things were going well with you two.
They are. I don't know, I...
I keep waiting for him to say
he loves me, and he hasn't.
Some men have to move
at their own pace, Med.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Whoa, Nelly.
- He'll be all right.
- So, what do you say?
You boys hungry?
- We gotta go.
- The limo's on its way up from Norwalk.
Marty, why don't you chopper them out?
Chopper? That's fucking awesome.
I'll call Doug, see if it's available.
Doug, I got Tony Soprano here.
He was asking if the chopper's available.
I know.
This new fucking girl told him.
About 15K between the five of them.
I know.
Righty-o.
Good news, gentlemen.
Sorry about the mess.
Mr. Soprano? Greg Erwitt.
You got any luggage?
- Just him.
- He's drunk. He's just regurge.
- So Caldwell Airport, right?
- Fuck that, how about Maui?
Just climb on in and buckle up.
- Oh, Jesus! Old Faithful.
- Better here than at 2000 feet.
I gotta take a piss.
Oh, yeah!
What the fuck you doing?
You're standing too close.
- Furio come by?
- He's already 40 minutes late.
Probably worse off than me.
What, did you two go out?
Can I get a cup of coffee?
- Where the fuck is he?
- I don't know.
- Was he out with somebody last night?
- He's a single guy. How should I know?
Anyway, my memory's a little hazy.
I'm going back to bed.
When he gets here, don't wake me.
I'm not home now, leave a message.
- Hello?
- Hey, it's me.
- Meadow, hi.
- You all right?
You don't sound happy
to hear from me.
- Of course I am. What's up?
- Nothing.
I wanted to invite you guys
for dinner Sunday...
...so Dad can see the place
and meet the crew.
- How nice. What brought that on?
- I figure before break.
Finn invited me to go skiing
in Canada next week.
- You want me to make anything?
- Nothing.
I'm doing everything myself.
Maybe wine.
We only drink good wine
when parents come.
- Anyway, I gotta go.
- Okay, bye.
- Hey.
Hi, Sil.
- Nice place.
- Yeah, we open in a few weeks.
Carmine got the chef from Fontanella,
killer wine list.
Look at this. It used to hang
in Fiorello LaGuardia's office.
- Who's that, Carmine in that boat?
- Gin and I are going over next month.
Salute.
Listen, Tony. It's very important
to Carmine that we work something out.
- If it's so important, where is he?
- His son's leaving tomorrow.
He had family obligations.
All right, so, what's the offer?
Forty percent of the HUD take
across the board starting now.
Forty?
I thought Little Carmine said
he was gonna take care of this.
- He did. That's why the concession.
- We were at 40 a week ago.
What's done already is done.
You keep that for yourself.
Forty percent only applies
to future deals.
Let's go.
Carmela!
- Darlene, hi, how are you?
- Great.
I wanted to thank you.
Your husband's friend came
by the office. We got the listing.
- Which friend? Who?
- Furio Gunther?
Is that how you say it?
House just went on the market.
Hi, Penny! How are you?
Yeah, all right. All right.
I'll talk to you later.
Who was that?
Silvio.
Listen to this.
Furio called. The stupid fucking zip
moved back to Italy.
Asshole left a message on the answering
machine at the Bing at 4:30 a.m.
Here, carry this.
- Flower delivery.
- Come on in, I'll be right there.
- Hi, Mrs. Soprano.
- Hi, Finn.
Mr. Soprano, Finn Detrolio.
- Finn the dentist, right?
- Someday.
I'm still waiting to hear
from dental school.
Remind me to talk to you
about this loose filling later.
Hi.
These are beautiful, thank you.
So, what smells so good in there?
Mom's recipe for chicken cacciatore.
You see, I should have known.
You always leave your door open
like that?
- I'm cooking, it's hot.
- I'll protect her, don't worry.
You hear that? Anybody bothers her,
he'll knock their teeth out...
...then he can put them back in too.
These are my roommates,
Colin and Alex.
Hi.
- So you're her roommate too?
- Colin McDermott.
I've heard so much about you.
- So he lives here and you don't?
- Dad.
- I have a place on 118th Street.
- Good.
I'll show you around later.
So, Finn...
...where you from?
My dad was in the Navy.
I was born in Japan, grew up
on a base near the Azores.
So...
...your dad was a sailor?
Surgeon, actually.
- So you've been all over the world.
- Yeah, pretty much.
- Would you like a mushroom?
- No, I don't think so.
- Have one, they're good.
- Maybe later.
I gotta tell you, Mrs. Soprano.
Your daughter absolutely
keeps us alive with her cooking.
Didn't you make macaroni
and cheese once?
Well, I didn't want to brag.
Yo, guys. Come here. Look at this.
So, Finn, Meadow tells me
that you're going skiing.
For four days next week,
a whole bunch of us.
A friend of my dad has a house
in the Laurentians near Montreal.
You can ski right onto the trails.
I saw pictures.
There's this humongous stone fireplace.
Just be careful with all those
accidents you read about.
- Sonny Bono.
- How about you, Alex?
- You ski?
- I used to.
My family had a retreat
near the Pyrenees.
- Pyrenees?
- Alex is descended from Spanish royalty.
- Seriously?
- She's our little princess.
My great-great-grandmother
was a countess.
- Which makes you...
- Technically, I'm an infante de gracia.
But that wouldn't fit
on her driver's license.
Well, you might have told me
you were living with royalty.
Well, my daughter's an Italian princess.
Does that count?
My wife too, for that matter.
- There's more chicken if anyone wants.
- Yeah, I'll take a little more.
- So, A.J., what are you, a junior?
- Next year.
- Did you look at any schools yet?
- Not really. I'll go to Rutgers, I guess.
- Are you passing everything?
- I got a C on a paper I did on Billy Budd.
A C?!
He usually gets D's and F's.
- What's with you today? You okay?
- He worked so hard on it. Why only a C?
I don't know.
- Did you like Billy Budd?
- It was okay.
- My teacher says it's a gay book.
- Mr. Weggler? That is ridiculous.
I've heard that before.
That was written in the 19th century?
- I didn't know they had fags back then.
- A.J.
- No offense.
- I'm not gay.
- You're not?
- No.
I read where they found
gay cave-drawings in Africa.
Really?
Shut up!
This stuff is pervading
our educational system...
...not to mention movies, TV shows.
- What "stuff"?
- This gay nonsense they're teaching.
I am sorry, but Billy Budd
is not a homosexual book.
Actually it is, Mother.
I saw the movie, Meadow,
with Terence Stamp.
He was in Priscilla, Queen of the Desert.
I don't know about that.
But Billy Budd is the story of an innocent
sailor being picked on by an evil boss.
Who is picking on him out
of self-loathing caused by...
...homosexual feelings
in a military context.
- Oh, please!
- Okay.
Actually, Mrs. Soprano...
...there is a passage where
Melville compares Billy...
...to a nude statue of Adam.
- Really?
- I thought you read it.
It's a biblical reference,
does that make it gay?
What's the difference?
I'm saying it's ridiculous how everything
is being sold as homosexual.
Must be a gay book.
Billy Budd's the ship's florist, right?
Leslie Fiedler has written
on gay themes in literature...
...since the early '60s,
Billy Budd in particular.
Well, she doesn't know
what she's talking about.
She's a he, Mother, and he's lectured
at Columbia, as a matter of fact.
Well, maybe he's gay.
You ever thought of that?
They broke the urn.
He sent Little Paulie
to trash Carmine's restaurant?
He works for me.
- What do I know?
- A lot more than me, that's for sure.
Everybody does.
We've been friends a long time, Paulie.
I'm gonna go off the record here.
You know, I probably shouldn't be
telling you this, but since you ask...
I think certain people are starting
to wonder where your heart is.
People who? Tony?
What the fuck's that supposed to mean?
Right there, your attitude lately.
Four months inside, I'm supposed
to skip down the street?
You're only as good as your last
envelope, you know that.
You have any idea what Albert
kicked up last week?
Fuck that fucking parakeet.
I got a relationship with Tony
Albert will never have.
No matter how far he sticks
his tongue up Tony's ass.
All right, fuck this.
Every friendship has its peaks
and valleys.
Right now, me and Tony
are in the valley.
The cycle comes around,
it'll be different.
I'm past worrying I gotta be
the top earner every fucking second.
So there you go then.
Don't give me that smart-alecky shit.
Don't forget, I go back
in this family to Johnny.
Before you, even.
It's your fault anyway.
All this shit started with that Russian
when I had to go pick up your 5 grand.
You know, things might be
a little different, Paulie...
...if you could accept some
responsibility for a change.
You're a wormy cocksucker,
you know that?
I'm just telling you how
you're being fucking perceived!
Just worry about how
you're fucking perceived!
Nobody knows what the future holds,
my friend.
You heard what he did
to the restaurant?
So how do you want to respond?
We gotta break this guy's back.
I haven't wanted to do this.
But it's gotta be.
Call the union.
His mother was coming.
He was so excited, Ro.
- We had a date to go to Colortile.
- A date?
To look at tile
for his mother's apartment.
No phone call, no note.
- I know I sound foolish.
- No, you don't, honey.
When I ran into Darlene at church...
...I felt like somebody punched me
in the stomach.
I almost threw up the sacrament.
- What am I gonna do, Ro?
- What's there to do?
A couple of months
you'll forget all about him.
I don't know if I can.
You don't think Tony said
something to him, do you?
I didn't see what all the fuss was,
particularly for what it cost.
Remember we saw
Man From La Mancha that time?
Richard Kiley stared at Ma
the whole time he was singing...
..."The Impossible Dream."
How I cried.
- Give me Sondheim any day.
- When Salvatore was alive...
...Minn went to the theater every week.
He did well, Salvatore.
- Barber scissors, right?
- Precision cutlery, 46 years.
There you are, sir.
Finally, the doggy bags.
I give these to my son.
Here's for Ma and me.
Parking and gas, I'll take care of.
- I have a hundred I need to break.
- Come on, Ma.
- Shoot, I forgot to cash my check.
- Don't you have direct deposit?
She doesn't have a savings account.
I like to have the money
right in my hands.
- Still keep it under the mattress?
- Never you mind where I keep it.
I need change.
Where's my rolls?
- I don't know, Ma.
- Waiter.
These Parker House rolls,
they belong to my ma.
They do not.
They were for the table.
Wrap these up, will you? Cellophane.
Come on, Ma.
What the fuck is this now?
Can I have your attention, please?
I repeat, can I have
your attention, please?
- Whoa, whoa. What's going on?
- You the foreman?
Dave Fusco. I'm the business agent
for local 87, laborers.
This site is employing a substantial
number of non-union laborers...
...in violation of our master contract.
Come on, what the fuck?
- Frankly, sir, I'm shocked and appalled.
- What, are you fucking kidding?
This site is shut down
until further notice.
- Danny! Hey, how you doing?
- Hey.
We just want you to know how glad
we are a guy like you is on that jury.
That mob thing.
That Junior Soprano trial.
I got that.
- Hey, hey, what are you doing?
- It's a privilege.
Hard-working guy, wife and two kids.
Performing a civic duty
we should all take part in.
We know you'll do the right thing.
- Hello?
- Hey, it's me. What are you doing?
- Nothing, just reading. You all right?
- Yeah, I just wanted to talk to you.
- Did I do something to piss you off?
- What are you talking about?
You were kind of mad
at me the other night.
- Why would I be mad?
- I don't know.
Anyway, the reason I called...
It's kind of near my birthday,
and I was thinking we'd do our tradition.
Go to the plaza for tea
under Eloise's picture.
Really? That's so wonderful.
Are you crying?
I'm just happy. That's so thoughtful.
I was thinking tomorrow, it's the only
day I have before we go to Canada.
Well, I have my nails in the morning, but
I could drive in and meet you after that.
I'm gonna be on the West Side,
can you pick me up?
Sure. I'll take the George
Washington Bridge.
Why, if you're going to Midtown?
- I know how to get to the city, Meadow.
- All right, I'll see you tomorrow.
- How's 1:00?
- That's fine.
On second thought, I'll just
meet you there. I love you.
I love you too.
Well, it happened.
Stubborn old fuck
shut down the Esplanade.
This business agent he owns
was there from the union.
Put on an Emmy-caliber performance.
Let him take his 40-percent bullshit
and run it by the other four bosses.
If you want, we could torch a few
of his cement trucks.
No retaliation, counter-retaliation.
- We just sit tight.
- It's gonna cost us, T.
- That's why Carmine did it.
- It's gonna cost him too.
- I brought these.
- Sorry, I am not wearing the gloves.
Soprano family tradition
notwithstanding.
I didn't think so.
But I'm wearing mine.
- Where'd you park?
- There's a lot over on 57th Street.
Would you like to lecture me
on parking too?
What are you talking about?
Since you're an authority
on driving directions...
- Very funny.
- Not to mention literature.
So it's the Billy Budd thing.
I was merely pointing out to you...
...what serious literary critics
have to say about the book.
These look delicious.
So how is Finn?
When are you leaving for Montreal?
Wednesday. He's gonna pick me up
at home. I have my ski clothes there...
...so I'm gonna stay over
the night before and do laundry.
- Is that a problem?
- No, of course not.
As long as he stays
in the guest room.
He's not staying, Mother.
The way you two hang
on each other...
Well, excuse me, Mrs. Danvers.
What do you have against love?
- Nothing.
- Why are you not happy for me?
Are you jealous? Just because
you and Dad are middle-aged?
Watch it, young lady.
- What am I, a child?
- Actually, yes.
Your apartment in Manhattan
notwithstanding.
- What?
- I'm sure your friend, the princess...
...found us quite amusing.
You wanted me to go...
...to an Ivy League school. These are
the type of people who go there.
There are also people who grew up
without plumbing...
...but you would know
even less about them.
Would you rather I transfer
to Montclair State?
Then maybe I can drop out
like you did.
- I'm sorry.
- I invited you here for a nice time...
...not to belittle me.
Maybe you'll be happier
if I didn't come around.
Except that won't happen, because
you'll need money in about a week.
To hell with not coming around,
I'll just transfer to Northwestern...
...so I can be near Finn when he goes.
Sure, sure.
Carmine, hey. What are you doing here?
I'm a guest. My housekeeper's daughter.
Small world. The groom's dad
is my third cousin.
Beautiful ceremony, huh?
So listen...
...about all this stuff that's going on,
Tony and all.
- What's your name again?
- Paulie Gualtieri. Jersey?
Your father was run over
by a trolley, right?
Johnny talked to you about me, right?
Johnny who? Sack?
Talked to me about what?
- Anything good?
- Just bills.
- So you never told me about your lunch.
- It was horrible, since you ask.
She's threatening to transfer
to Northwestern.
- What brought that on?
- Boyfriend probably, Finn.
Maybe she wants to put some space
between us, I don't know.
- Why would she wanna do that?
- You know, frankly, I don't care.
The way I feel now, if I never
see her again, that would be fine.
- How could you say that?
- Look, Tony.
I don't feel well. My joints ache,
my stomach is all queasy.
- You asked, I told.
- Just making conversation.
- If you don't care, don't bring it up!
- All right, calm down.
I don't have enough on my plate?
One of my key guys disappeared
to Naples, for chrissakes!
- Have you seen my Nordica goggles?
- Yeah, they're in the basement.
I had to solder something
to my computer.
What are you reading?
Death in Venice.
Mr. Weggler assigned it.
Where's Mom?
Bed, I guess.
She seem weird to you lately?
- How?
- Angry, sad?
I guess she's been crying a lot.
- Since when?
- Last week.
I think she's upset about Furio's dad.
- Why? What do you mean?
- He died.
And I think Furio went back
to Italy or something.
- She was going over there a lot.
- To Furio's?
She was helping him decorate.
And she made me go too.
It was really a pain in the ass.
- She took you there? More than once?
- I don't know, a couple, three times.
- Oh, dude. Meeting's over.
- Oh, Jesus.
Who's there?
What are you doing?
Minn! Your door was open.
I brought you something from my ma.
- What are you doing in my house?
- Take it easy.
I didn't know you were home.
Your car was gone.
It's being repaired.
- What are you doing?
- Calling your mother.
I know you.
- You got any coffee?
- My kitchen's all wiped off for the night.
Well, this week then, I'll bring my ma...
...the three of us, we'll go have lunch
over at Pals Cabin.
- You're here to rob me.
- No, no. What are you, crazy?
- Just calm down, okay?
- You're a disgrace to your mother.
Don't set that thing off!
You think I'm here to hurt you?
- You know me since I'm a kid.
- Help!
What are you doing?
Help! Help!
- Help!
- Oh, fuck!
- Minn, wait!
- You were always a little bastard!
- Shut up with that fucking mouth!
Help! Help!
- There's the skip.
- Hey.
For you. I know things
have been slow lately.
- That ought to bring us up to date.
- What'd you do, rob a bank?
Back in business, T.
- What, are you going to track?
- Thinking about it.
Ton, Johnny Sack for you.
- What's that prick want?
- I don't know.
Let me take this.
Hello? Thought we did.
Yeah, all right, I'll meet you.
You say goodbye to your mother?
She went to the market
while I was in the shower.
She loves you, Meadow.
You know that, don't you?
- I know.
- Come here.
Cut her some slack, will you?
She's going through a rough time
right now.
- How come?
- Change of life, maybe.
Her kids are growing up.
We talked about this in counseling,
me and her.
- You guys went to counseling?
- Yeah.
It's part of the therapy
for the panic attacks and all.
You were in therapy?
- You knew that, didn't you?
- Oh, my God.
On some level she may feel...
...unfulfilled.
Switch on Rosie O'Donnell,
that's all these women bitch about.
A little of that's probably my fault,
anyway.
It's an epidemic, right?
- You really think that's it?
- Yeah.
It's probably the beginning
of menopause, like you said.
All right, you go have a good time.
Thanks.
Well, here I am. What is it?
We go back a long way, Tony.
We've come way too far
to let it all go to shit.
With all due respect, you wanna go
down memory lane?
Put it in second gear, huh?
The Esplanade now.
I wish for Carmine's own sake
he'd ease off.
Why don't you tell him that?
He's so easily upset these days,
his teeth.
I'll tell you, that restaurant thing
didn't help.
He hurt my appraiser.
What was I supposed to do?
It's on page four of the boss
manual, John. Jesus.
You're preaching to the choir, Tony.
I mean...
You don't wanna hear how many
of his decisions...
...end up lightening my pockets.
Why you telling me all this, John?
Because at heart I know you're
a pragmatist, as I am.
I'm telling you now.
Carmine won't bend.
- And I just told you, I won't.
- If Carmine's health were bad...
...if something were to happen
to him, God forbid...
...all of this unpleasantness
would just...
- John, Carmine's fine.
- Yes.
He's very healthy.
Thank God.
Call me.
Holy shit.
As soon as we get off this barge,
I never wanna see you again.
- Yes?
- Tonight?
No.
You're home early.
What're you watching?
How to Marry a Millionaire.
Do I have a fever?
Maybe. A little.
- You want some Advil?
- I took some.
I talked to Meadow this morning.
She left for her ski trip.
So?
She's a good kid, Carm.
- She hates my guts, Tony.
- She doesn't hate you.
She's gonna call you.
Come on, you know how that works.
Finn'll go.
She'll forget all about him
in a couple of weeks.
In a few years she'll find
somebody else, settle down.
Maybe she won't, who knows?
She can do whatever she wants.
She's becoming a wonderful woman,
Carm.
A smart, beautiful...
...independent woman that you created.
Isn't that what you dreamed about?
Yes.