Water, earth,
fire, air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his
airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
The only reason
you should be interrupting me
is if you have news about the Avatar.
Well, there is news, Prince Zuko,
but you might not like it.
Don't get too upset.
Uncle, you taught me that
keeping a level head
is a sign of a great leader.
Now, whatever you have to say,
I'm sure I can take it.
Ok, then.
We have no idea where he is.
What?
You really should open a window
in here.
Give me the map!
There have been multiple sightings
of the Avatar,
but he is impossible to track down.
How am I going to find him, Uncle?
He is clearly a master
of evasive maneuvering.
You have no idea
where you're going, do you?
Well, I know it's near water.
I guess
we're getting close, then.
Momo, marbles, please.
Hey, Katara, check out
this airbending trick.
That's great, Aang.
You didn't even look.
That's great.
But I'm not doing it now.
Stop bugging her, airhead.
You need to give girls space
when they do their sewing.
What does me being a girl
have to do with sewing?
Simple.
Girls are better
at fixing pants than guys,
and guys are better at hunting
and fighting and stuff like that.
It's just the natural order of things.
All done with your pants,
and look what a great job I did.
Wait! I was just kidding!
I can't wear these! Katara, please!
Relax, Sokka.
Where we're going,
you won't need any pants.
We just made
a pit stop yesterday.
Shouldn't we get a little more flying
done before we camp out?
He's right. At this rate,
we won't get to the North Pole
until spring.
But Appa's tired already,
aren't you, boy?
I said, "Aren't you, boy?"
Yeah, that was real convincing.
Still, hard to argue
with a 10-ton magical monster.
Look!
That's why we're here... Elephant koi,
and I'm going to ride it.
Katara, you've got to watch me.
Cold!
Woo!
Yeah!
Woo-hoo!
He looks pretty good out there.
Are you kidding?
The fish is doing all the work.
No, Appa!
Don't eat that!
Aw, man.
There's something in the water!
What's wrong?
Aang's in trouble.
- Aang!
- Get out of there!
- Get back here, Aang!
- Come in!
Aah!
What was that thing?
I don't know.
Well, let's not stick around
to find out.
Time to hit the road.
Or we could stay a while.
You three have some
explaining to do.
And if you don't answer
all our questions,
we're throwing you back
in the water with the unagi.
Show yourselves, cowards!
Who are you?
Where are the men who ambushed us?
There were no men. We ambushed you.
Now tell us, who are you
and what are you doing here?
Wait a second.
There's no way a bunch of girls
took us down.
A bunch of girls, huh?
The unagi's going to eat well tonight.
No, don't hurt him! He didn't mean it!
My brother's just an idiot sometimes.
It's my fault.
I'm sorry we came here.
I wanted to ride the elephant koi.
How do we know
you're not Fire Nation spies?
Kyoshi stayed out of the war so far
and we intend to keep it that way.
This island is named for Kyoshi?
I know Kyoshi.
Ha!
How could you possibly know her?
Avatar Kyoshi was born here
400 years ago.
She's been dead for centuries.
I know her because I'm the Avatar.
That's impossible.
The last Avatar was an airbender
who disappeared 100 years ago.
That's me.
Throw the impostor to the unagi.
Aang, do some airbending.
- Wow.
- That's amazing.
It's true.
You are the Avatar.
Now, check this out.
Did you hear the news?
The Avatar's on Kyoshi.
Huh?
The Avatar's on Kyoshi island?
Uncle, ready the rhinos.
He's not getting away from me
this time.
Are you going to finish that?
I was going to save it for later!
All right!
Dessert for breakfast!
These people sure know
how to treat an Avatar.
Mm! Katara, you've got to try these.
Well, maybe just a bite.
Sokka, what's your problem?
Eat!
I'm not hungry.
But you're always hungry.
He's just upset
because a bunch of girls
kicked his butt yesterday.
They snuck up on me!
Right, and then they kicked your butt.
Sneak attacks don't count.
Tie me up with ropes...
I'll show them a thing or two.
I'm not scared of any girls.
Who do they think they are, anyway?
Mm! This is tasty.
What's he so angry about?
It's great here.
They're giving us the royal treatment.
Hey, don't get too comfortable.
It's risky for us to stay
in one place for very long.
I'm sure we'll be fine.
Besides, did you see how happy
I'm making this town?
They're even cleaning up
that statue in my honor.
Well, it's nice to see you excited
about being the Avatar.
I just hope it doesn't
all go to your head.
Come on, you know me better than that.
I'm just a simple monk.
There he is!
There he is! Oh!
Hmm, painting the Avatar.
That's easy enough.
Oh, there's another one.
Well, I'll make an adjustment
here and...
There's more.
I...
Ooh! Heh heh!
I can't believe I got beat up
by a bunch of girls.
Sorry, ladies.
Didn't mean to interrupt
your dance lesson.
I was just looking for somewhere
to get a little workout.
Well, you're in the right place.
Sorry about yesterday.
I didn't know
you were friends with the Avatar.
It's all right.
I mean, normally I'd hold a grudge,
but seeing as you guys are a bunch
of girls, I'll make an exception.
I should hope so.
A big, strong man like you,
we wouldn't stand a chance.
True, but don't feel bad.
After all, I'm the best warrior
in my village.
Wow. Best warrior, huh?
In your whole village?
Maybe you'd be kind enough
to give us a little demonstration.
Oh, well, I mean, I...
Come on, girls,
wouldn't you like him
to show us some moves?
Well, if that's what you want,
I'd be happy to.
All right, you stand over there.
Now, this may be a little tough,
but try to block me.
Ow!
Good.
Of course, I was going easy on you.
Of course.
Let's see if you can handle this!
Ouch!
Oh!
That does it!
Anything else you want to teach us?
There she is, girls,
me in a past life.
You were pretty.
Excuse me for a second, ladies.
Oh, good.
Can you help me carry this
back to the room?
It's a little heavy.
Actually, I can't right now.
What do you mean, you can't?
I promised the girls
I'd give them a ride on Appa.
Why don't you come with us?
It'll be fun.
Watching you show off
for a bunch of girls
does not sound like fun.
Well, neither does
carrying your basket.
It's not my basket.
These supplies are for our trip.
I told you,
we have to leave Kyoshi soon.
I don't want to leave Kyoshi yet.
I can't put my finger on it,
but there's something
I really like about this place.
What's taking you so long, Aangie?
Aangie?
Just a second, Koko.
Simple monk, huh?
I thought you promised
me this Avatar stuff
wouldn't go to your head.
It didn't. You know what I think?
You just don't want to come
because you're jealous.
Jealous? Of what?
Jealous that we're having
so much fun without you.
That's ridiculous.
It is a little ridiculous,
but I understand.
Ugh!
Uh, hey, Suki.
Hoping for another dance lesson?
No, I...
Well, let me explain.
Spit it out. What do you want?
I would be honored
if you would teach me.
Even if I'm a girl?
I'm sorry if I insulted you earlier.
I was wrong.
We normally don't teach outsiders,
let alone boys.
Please make an exception.
I won't let you down.
All right, but you have to follow
all of our traditions.
Of course.
And I mean all of them.
Do I really have to wear this?
It feels a little... Girly.
It's a warrior's uniform.
You should be proud.
The silk thread symbolizes
the brave blood
that flows through our veins.
The gold insignia represents
the honor of the warrior's heart.
Bravery and honor.
Hey, Sokka.
Nice dress.
Katara, remember how
the unagi almost got me yesterday?
Yeah.
Well, I'm going to go ride it now.
It's going to be real dangerous.
Good for you.
You're not going to stop me?
Nope. Have fun.
I will. Great.
I know it's great.
Well, I'm glad you know.
- I'm glad you're glad.
- Good!
Fine!
You're not going to master it
in one day.
Even I'm not that good.
I think I'm starting to get it.
It's not about strength.
Our technique is about using
your opponent's force against them.
Loosen up.
Think of the fan as an extension
of your arm.
Wait for an opening and then...
Hmm.
I fell on purpose
to make you feel better.
I got you!
Admit I got you!
Ok, it was a lucky shot.
Let's see if you can do it again.
What's taking so long?
I'm sure it will be here any second.
Um, what about this?
Not that again.
Boring.
Where's unagi?
It's getting late.
Where are you going?
Don't leave!
Sorry, Aang!
Maybe next time!
Katara, you showed up!
I wanted to make sure you were safe.
You really had me worried.
Back there you acted like
you didn't care.
I'm sorry.
Me, too.
I did let all that attention
go to my head.
I was being a jerk.
Well, get out of the water
before you catch a cold, you big jerk!
On my way!
Hang on, Aang!
Aah!
Aang!
Zuko!
I want the Avatar alive.
Wake up, Aang.
Katara.
Don't ride the unagi.
Not fun.
Not bad.
Fire bandits have landed
on our shores.
Girls, come quickly!
Hey, I'm not a...
Oh, whatever.
Come out, Avatar.
You can't hide from me forever.
Find him.
I guess training's over.
Nice try, Avatar,
but these little girls can't save you.
Hey, over here!
Finally.
Get inside.
Look what I brought to this place.
It's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
These people got their town destroyed
trying to protect me.
Then let's get out of here.
Zuko will leave Kyoshi to follow us.
I know it feels wrong to run,
but I think it's the only way.
I'll call Appa.
There's no time to say good-bye.
What about "I'm sorry"?
For what?
I treated you like a girl
when I should have
treated you like a warrior.
I am a warrior...
But I'm a girl, too.
Now get out of here.
We'll hold them off.
Appa, yip yip!
Back to the ship!
Don't lose sight of them!
I know it's hard,
but you did the right thing.
Zuko would've destroyed
the whole place if we stayed.
They're going to be ok, Aang.
What are you doing?
Thank you, Avatar.
I know, I know,
that was stupid and dangerous.
Yes, it was.