Water, earth,
fire, air...
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his
airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Great. You're back. What's for dinner?
We've got a few options.
First, round nuts and some kind of
oval-shaped nuts.
And some rock-shaped nuts
that might just be rocks.
Dig in.
Seriously, what else you got?
What was that?
It's coming from over there.
Shouldn't we run away from
huge booms, not toward them?
Hyah.
An earthbender.
Let's go meet him.
He looks dangerous,
so we better approach cautiously.
Hello there! I'm Katara.
What's your name?
Ah!
Nice to meet you!
I just wanted to say hi.
Hey, that guy's
got to be running somewhere.
Maybe we're near a village.
And I bet that village has a market.
Which means no nuts for dinner.
Hey! I worked hard to get those nuts.
Yeah, I hate them, too.
Great hat.
I'll trade you some nuts for it.
Hey!
Hi, Mom.
Where have you been, Haru?
You're late!
Get started on your chores.
Hey! You're that kid.
Ah!
Why did you run away before?
Uh... You must have me confused
with some other kid.
No, she doesn't.
We saw you earthbending.
They saw you doing what?
They're crazy, Mom.
I mean, look at how they're dressed.
You know how dangerous that is.
You know what would happen
if they caught you earthbending.
Open up!
Fire Nation. Act natural.
Aah!
What do you want?
I've already paid you this week.
The tax just doubled.
We wouldn't want an accident,
would we?
Fire is sometimes so hard to control.
You can keep the copper ones.
Nice guy.
How long has
the Fire Nation been here?
Five years. Fire Lord Ozai
uses our town's coal mines
to fuel his ships.
They're thugs. They steal from us.
And everyone here
is too much of a coward
to do anything about it.
Quiet, Haru!
Don't talk like that!
But Haru's an earthbender.
He can help.
Earthbending is forbidden.
It's caused nothing
but misery for this village.
He must never use his abilities.
How can you say that?
Haru has a gift.
Asking him not to earthbend
is like asking me not to waterbend.
It's a part of who we are.
You don't understand.
I understand that Haru can help
you fight back.
What can the Fire Nation do to you
that they haven't done already?
They could take Haru away,
like they took his father.
My mom said
you can sleep here tonight.
But you should leave in the morning.
Thanks. I'll make sure
Appa doesn't eat all your hay.
I'm sorry about
what I said earlier.
I didn't know about your father.
That's ok.
It's funny. The way you were talking
back in the store,
it reminded me of him.
Thanks.
My father was very courageous.
When the Fire Nation invaded,
he and the other earthbenders
were outnumbered ten to one.
But they fought back anyway.
He sounds like a great man.
After the attack,
they rounded up my father
and every other earthbender
and took them away.
We haven't seen them since.
So that's why
you hide your earthbending.
Yeah.
The problem is,
the only way I can feel close
to my father now
is when I practice my bending.
He taught me everything I know.
See this necklace?
My mother gave it to me.
It's beautiful.
I lost my mother
in a Fire Nation raid.
This necklace is all
I have left of her.
It's not enough, is it?
No.
Aah! Help!
The mine!
Aah...
Help me!
Ah! It's not working.
We have to get help.
There's no time. Pull harder!
Haru, there's a way you can help him.
I can't.
Please. There's no one around
to see you.
It's the only way!
Ah!
Haru, you did it!
It was so brave of Haru
to use his earthbending
to help that old man.
You must have really inspired him.
I guess so.
Everyone should get some sleep.
We're leaving at dawn.
Dawn? Can't we sleep in for once?
Absolutely not!
This village is crawling
with Fire Nation troops.
If they discover you're here, Aang,
we'll be eating fireballs
for breakfast.
Good night.
I'd rather eat fireballs than nuts.
Ah!
That's him!
That's the earthbender!
Aah!
They took him!
- They took Haru away!
- What?
The old man turned him in
to the Fire Nation.
It's all my fault.
I forced him into earthbending.
Slow down, Katara.
When did this happen?
Haru's mother said
they came for him at midnight.
Then it's too late to track him.
He's long gone.
We don't need to track him.
The Fire Nation is going to
take me right to Haru.
And why would they do that?
Because they're going to arrest me
for earthbending.
I thought you were
crazy at first, Katara,
but this might work.
There are ventilation shafts
throughout these mines.
All Aang has to do is
send an air current
from that vent to this one right here.
The boulder levitates and ta-da...
Fake earthbending.
Aang, did you get all that?
Sure, sure. I got it.
Do you remember your cue?
Yeah, yeah. Just relax.
You're taking all the fun out of this.
By "this" do you mean
intentionally being captured
by an army of ruthless firebenders?
Exactly. That's fun stuff.
Here they come.
Get in your places.
Uh! Get out of my way, pipsqueak.
How dare you call me pipsqueak,
you giant-eared cretin?
What did you call me?
A giant-eared cretin.
Look at those things.
Do herds of animals
use them for shade?
You better back off!
Seriously, back off.
I will not back off!
I bet elephants get together
and make fun of
how large your ears are.
That's it! You're going down.
I'll show you who's boss,
earthbending style.
I said, "earthbending style!"
That lemur. He's earthbending.
No, you idiot. It's the girl.
Oh. Of course.
I'll hold her!
You've got 12 hours
to find Haru.
We'll be right behind you.
Momo, you have some big ears.
She'll be fine, Aang.
Katara knows what she's doing.
Earthbenders,
it is my pleasure to welcome you
aboard my modest shipyard.
I am your warden.
I prefer to think of you
not as prisoners,
but as honored guests.
And I hope you come to think of me
as your humble and caring host.
You will succeed here
if you simply abide...
Hyah!
What kind of guest dishonors his host
by interrupting him?
Take him below.
One week in solitary
will improve his manners.
Simply treat me with the courtesy
I give you
and we'll get along famously.
You will notice, earthbenders,
that this rig is made
entirely of metal.
You are miles away
from any rock or earth.
So, if you have any illusions
about employing
that brutish savagery
that passes for bending
among you people, forget them.
It is impossible.
Good day.
Katara?
Haru!
What are you doing here?
It's my fault you were captured.
I came to rescue you.
So you got yourself arrested?
It was the only way to find you.
You've got guts, Katara.
I'll give you that.
Come on. There's someone
I want you to meet.
Katara, this is my father, Tyro.
Dad, this is Katara.
It's an honor to meet you.
Have some dinner, Katara.
Ew.
It's not as bad as it looks.
Eew!
It's still pretty bad, though.
Tyro, the prisoners are complaining
there aren't enough blankets
to go around.
I'll talk to the guards.
In the meantime, make sure
the elderly are taken care of.
The rest of us will simply have to
hope for warmer weather.
If you don't mind me asking,
what's your escape plan?
Excuse me?
You know, the plan
to get everyone off the rig?
What is it? Mutiny, sabotage?
The plan? The plan is to survive,
wait out this war, hope that one day
some of us can get back home
and forget this ever happened.
How can you say that?
You sound like
you've already given up.
Katara, I admire your courage.
And I envy your youth.
But people's lives are at stake here.
The warden is a ruthless man,
and he won't stand for any rebellion.
I'm sorry, but we're powerless.
We'll see about that.
Earthbenders!
You don't know me, but I know of you.
Every child in my water tribe village
was rocked to sleep
with stories of the brave
Earth Kingdom
and the courageous earthbenders
who guard its borders.
Some of you may think
that the Fire Nation
has made you powerless.
Yes. They have taken away
your ability to bend.
But they can't take away your courage.
And it is your courage
they should truly fear,
because it runs deeper than any mine
you've been forced to dig,
any ocean that keeps you
far from home.
It is the strength of your hearts
that make you who you are,
hearts that will remain unbroken
when all rock and stone
has eroded away.
The time to fight back is now!
I can tell you
the Avatar has returned!
So remember your courage,
earthbenders!
Let us fight for our freedom!
Ah!
Shh.
Your 12 hours are up. Where is Haru?
We've got to get out of here.
I can't.
We don't have much time.
There are guards everywhere.
Get on!
Katara, what's wrong?
I'm not leaving.
I'm not giving up on these people.
What do you mean,
you're not leaving?
We can't abandon these people.
There has to be a way to help them.
Maybe she's right.
What do you say, Sokka?
I say you're both crazy.
Last chance. We need to leave now.
No.
I hate when you get like this.
Come on, we better hide.
Go.
Look!
Tell me exactly what you saw.
Well, sir, it looked like
a flying bison.
What?
It was a giant, flying buffalo, sir,
with an empty saddle.
Which was it, a buffalo or a bison?
I'm not sure what the difference is,
but that's not really the point,
is it, sir?
I'll decide what the point is, fool!
Aah!
You! Wake up the captain!
Search the entire rig!
- Sir.
- What?
That was the captain
you just threw overboard, so...
Then wake up someone
I haven't thrown overboard
and search the rig.
There's something going on here,
and I don't like it.
We don't have much time.
What are we gonna do?
I wish I knew how to make a hurricane.
The warden would run away,
and we would steal his keys.
Wouldn't he just
take his keys with him?
I'm just tossing ideas around.
I tried talking the earthbenders
into fighting back,
but it didn't work.
If there was just a way
to help them help themselves.
For that they need some kind of
earth or some rock,
something they can bend.
But this entire place
is made of metal.
No, it's not. Look at the smoke.
I bet they're burning coal.
In other words...
Earth.
It's almost dawn.
We're running out of time.
You sure this is gonna work?
It should.
These vents reminded me
of our little trick
back at the village.
We're gonna do the same thing,
but on a much bigger scale.
There's a huge deposit of coal
at the base of this island.
And the whole system is ventilated.
Aang closed off
all the vents except one.
When he does his airbending,
the coal only has one place to go...
Right back here.
There's the intruder!
Stay back! I'm warning you!
Katara, stop.
You can't win this fight.
Listen to him well, child.
You're one mistake away
from dying where you stand.
Here's your chance, earthbenders!
Take it!
Your fate is in your own hands!
Foolish girl.
You thought a few inspirational words
and some coal
would change these people?
Look at these blank hopeless faces.
Their spirits were broken
a long time ago.
Oh, but you still believed in them.
How sweet.
They're a waste of your energy,
little girl.
You failed.
Grr.
Hyah!
Show no mercy!
Aah!
For the Earth Kingdom,
attack!
Get to the ship! We'll hold them off!
Do not let them escape!
Guys, throw me some coal!
No, please. I can't swim.
Don't worry. I hear cowards float.
I want to thank you for saving me,
for saving us.
All it took was a little coal.
It wasn't the coal, Katara.
It was you.
Thank you for helping me
find my courage,
Katara of the water tribe.
My family and everyone here
owes you much.
So, I guess you're going home now.
Yes, to take back my village.
To take back all of our villages!
The Fire Nation will regret the day
they set foot on our land!
Come with us.
I can't.
Your mission
is to take back your home.
Ours is to get Aang to the North Pole.
That's him, isn't it? The Avatar.
Katara, thank you for bringing
my father back to me.
I never thought I'd see him again.
I only wish there was some way...
I know.
My mother's necklace! It's gone!