Well, I painted
my apartment again.
I've been living in this
apartment for years and years,
and every time I paint it,
it kind of gets me down.
I look around and think, "Well,
it's a little bit smaller now."
And I realize it's just
the thickness of the paint,
but I'm aware of it.
It just keeps coming in
and coming in.
Every time I paint it,
it's closer and closer.
I don't even know where
the wall outlets are anymore.
I just look for, like, a lump
with two slots in it.
It kind of looks like a pig.
He's trying to push his way
through from the other side.
That's where I plug in.
My idea
of the perfect living room
would be the bridge
on the Starship Enterprise.
You know what I mean?
Big chair, nice screen,
remote control.
That's why Star Trek really was
the ultimate male fantasy...
just hurtling through space
in your living room,
watching TV.
That's why all the aliens
were always dropping in,
because Kirk was the only one
that had the big screen.
They'd come over Friday nights...
Klingon boxing.
Got to be there.
What did you do?
Mousse. I moussed up.
I guess it was just
a matter of time.
You know, I should've done this
years ago.
I mean, I feel like
I've had two lives...
my premousse,
and now I begin my postmousse.
Truthfully, have you ever seen
a better-looking guy?
Looks, it's so subjective.
Oh, I don't mean
to interrupt or anything,
but on Sunday,
my friend is having a brunch
for the New York marathon...
Oh! I keep forgetting
to enter that! Gee!
She lives
right above 1st Avenue.
She says she has
a perfect view of the race,
and she said I could
invite some friends.
Maybe.
No, I'm not going up there!
Harold and Manny.
Boys, boys.
Oh, Jerry.
I slid the rent
under your door, Harold.
Did you get it?
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Jerry,
would you like anything
from Miss Hudwalker's apartment?
I was only joking.
He thinks I'm going to give you
Miss Hudwalker's things.
We have to go up there now
and clean the apartment.
It's a good thing
her rent was overdue.
She'd be rotting
up there for a month.
She died? Mrs. Hudwalker died?
94 years old.
I found her yesterday.
She didn't have a wig on.
It was horrifying.
What's the matter with you?
I'm talking!
So, Jerry, you know anybody
who needs an apartment?
Are you kidding?
Do you know my friend Elaine?
Yeah. I like her.
She always says hello to me.
It's not promised to anyone?
Because she'd take it
in a second.
Well, Manny wanted it
for his brother,
but he got deported.
...deported?
It's un pequeño misunderstanding
con departmento de immigracíon.
What's the difference?
It's true.
So it's okay? I can just
tell her she can have it?
Sure, sure.
She's getting a bargain too.
It's only $400 a month.
Okay.
Okay!
Hey, Harold.
What do you think?
Manny, look.
Kramer put mousse in his hair.
Thanks.
What was that all about?
Oh, nothing important.
What's going on?
What is that look?
What look?
Nothing.
Something's going on here.
I don't know if you should sit
for this or not.
Sitting is good if you faint,
but standing is good
for jumping up and down.
I can't decide.
Jumping up and down?
What are you talking about?
Come on. Cough it up.
Oh, Elaine,
you know the way I am,
rarely ever thinking of myself.
My only concern
is the welfare and happiness
of those close to me.
Sure, it hurts sometimes
to give and give and give...
Would you please?
What would you say...
if I told you that...
Told me what?
I got you an apartment
in this building?
No!
Yes.
Yes!
You didn't!
I did.
You got me an apartment
in the building?
I got you an apartment
in the building.
How did you...
You remember Mrs. Hudwalker,
the 94-year-old woman who lived above me?
No.
She died.
She died?
She died!
And... the rent
is only $400 a month.
Get out!
400 a month? Only 400 a month?
400 a month.
And I'll be right upstairs?
Right upstairs.
Right above you?
Right above me.
Oh! Whoo-hoo! We're neighbors!
I'll be here all the time!
All the time.
We can exchange keys
so we can come in and out.
Oh, this is gonna be great.
All the time.
The problem with talking
is that nobody stops you
from saying the wrong thing.
I think
life would be a lot better
if it was like
you're always making a movie.
You mess up,
somebody just walks on the set
and stops the whole shot.
You know what I mean?
Think of the things
you wish you could take back.
You're out somewhere
with people.
"Gee, you look pregnant.
Are you?"
Cut, cut, cut, cut, cut!
That's not gonna work at all.
Walk out the door. Come back in.
Let's take
this whole scene again.
People, think about
what you're saying.
Thanks.
See you later, Donna.
What happened to you?
You can't believe
what I just did.
What? What did you do?
I could tell you what I did,
but you won't believe it.
It's not believable.
What did you do?
How could I have done that?
Done what?
I told Elaine about
an apartment opening up
in my building.
She's going to move in.
Elaine's moving
into your building?
Yes. Right above me.
Right above you?
You're gonna be neighbors.
I know. Neighbors.
She's right above you?
Right above me.
How could you do that?
Because I'm an idiot.
You may think you're an idiot,
but with all due respect,
I'm a much bigger idiot
than you are.
Please.
Don't insult me, my friend.
Remember who you're talking to.
No one's a bigger idiot than me.
Did you ever ask
an ex-girlfriend
to move into your building?
Did you ever go
to a singles' weekend
in the Poconos?
She's right in my building,
right above me.
Every time I come
in the building,
I'm gonna have to sneak around
like a cat burglar.
You're doomed.
You're gonna have to have
all your sex
at women's apartments.
It'll be like
a permanent road trip.
Forget about
the home-bed advantage.
But I need
Of course.
We all do.
Come in for two minutes
and sit with me.
I was just in there.
It's embarrassing.
Oh, who's gonna know?
They all saw me walk out.
Two minutes.
My sensoring system broke down.
You know that little guy
in your head
who watches everything you say
and makes sure
you don't make a mistake?
He went for a cup of coffee
and, in that second,
ruined my life.
My sensor quit two years ago.
Checked into a clinic,
emotionally exhausted.
So is there any way out
of this Elaine thing?
It's tough.
You know, the water pressure's
terrible in my building,
and she loves a good shower.
I never heard of anyone
turning down an apartment
because of a weak shower spray.
If they were fanatic
about showers, they might.
For that rent,
she'd take a bath
in the toilet tank
if she had to.
Look at this woman
feeding her baby
greasy, disgusting,
coffee-shop
corned beef hash.
Isn't that child abuse?
I'd like to have a kid.
Of course, you have
to have a date first.
Remember my friend Adam
from Detroit?
Yeah, the guy
with the flat head?
He's a cube.
Anyway, he got married
about six months ago.
He told me, ever since he's been
wearing a wedding band,
women have been coming on to him
everywhere he goes.
Yeah, I've heard that
about wedding bands.
I wonder if that's really true.
That'd be an interesting
sociological experiment.
You know, Kramer
has his father's band.
He'd loan it to you.
Hey, thanks a lot.
So I'll give it back
to you in a week.
You know, I don't even know why
you're fooling around
with this ring.
I've been telling you...
get yourself some plugs
or a piece.
I'm not doing that.
Oh, man. You know, you're crazy.
You're a good-looking guy.
Why do you want to walk around
like that for?
No, I'll put a half a can
of mousse in my head, like you.
No.
I told you,
I don't like these sponges.
They're too small.
I want a big sponge!
You can't pick up anything
with these.
There's no absorption.
Boys, boys.
Hi, Jerry.
Hello, Jerry.
Okay.
Your friend can't have
the apartment, Jerry.
What?
Because somebody
offered Manny $5000
for the apartment.
I don't want to do it.
Manny wants to do it.
Because it's true!
Why shouldn't I tell him?
Hey, hey, I understand.
You're businessmen.
Okay, okay...
Oh. Now he says that
if your friend has $5000,
we'll give it to her.
Well, that's a lot of money,
but if that's the way
it's got to be,
that's the way it's got to be.
You know, I used to think
that the universe
is a random, chaotic sequence
of meaningless events...
But I see now
that there is reason and purpose
to all things.
What happened to you?
Religion, my friend.
That's what happened to me.
Because I have just
been informed
that it's going to cost Elaine
the sum of $5000
to get the apartment upstairs.
$5000? She doesn't have $5000.
Of course
she doesn't have $5000.
So she can't get the apartment.
Can't get it.
So she doesn't move in!
No move.
So you see?
It's all part of a divine plan.
And how does the baldness
fit into that plan?
Elaine?
Yeah!
All right.
This is going to require
some great acting now.
I have to pretend
I'm disappointed,
so you're going to see me
really being a phony now.
I hope you can take this.
Maybe you should go
into the other room.
Are you kidding?
I lie every second of the day.
My whole life is a sham.
Because, you know,
I love Elaine.
Of course you do.
But, you know,
not in the building.
Really, I feel terrible
about this.
My intentions were good.
What... What can I do?
Tell me.
No, I'll be seeing you!
♪ Good morning
Good morning ♪
Have you ever gotten up
first thing in the morning
and felt that it's just great
to be alive?
That every breath is a gift
of sweet life from above?
Ooh.
Before I forget,
I have the checks
for the first month,
last month, security deposit.
I have $75 left in my account.
Well...
There's a little bit
of a problem.
Oh, I know.
There's a weak shower spray,
I know,
and I already thought about it...
I am switching to baths.
As Winston Churchill said,
"Why stand when you can sit?"
Maybe I'll get
some rubber duckies.
Uh, no, uh...
Someone offered Harold and Manny
5000 for the apartment.
I'm sure they'd just as soon
give it to you,
but you would have to
come up with that money.
Five thousand dollars?
I don't have $5000.
I know.
How am I going to get $5000?
I have no idea.
Hey! My new neighbor.
Oh, I'm not moving in.
What?
They want $5000 now.
So, okay, uh,
w-what's the problem?
I don't have $5000.
Oh, come on!
You can come up with $5000!
Jerry, you don't have $5000
you can lend her?
Come on.
Yeah, well, I didn't...
I mean...
is that something
you want to borrow?
No, that's too much money
to borrow.
Loan her the money.
You can afford it.
She doesn't want
to borrow the money.
Oh, come on!
She'll pay you back.
What's five grand
between friends?
Oh, of course I'd pay you back.
Yeah, so what's the problem?
Who said there's a problem?
Uh! See? He said
he'll loan you the money.
Well, now, Jerry,
it might take a while
for me to pay you back,
you know.
Maybe a few years.
How do you feel about that?
Ah, it's okay!
He doesn't care.
Well, you know,
money can sometimes
come between friends.
Get out of here.
Let me think about it.
What's to think about?
Well, I don't know.
I don't know. 5000?
Let me just take
one more look at it.
It was all over.
Taken care of.
Done. Finished.
5000... where is she gonna get...?
She doesn't have 5000.
Clean. Goodbye.
She's gone.
Then you come in.
"Why don't you loan her
the 5000?
"What do you care?
You got 5000.
Give her 5000."
Wait a minute.
You didn't want her
in the building?
No, I didn't.
Well, then, what did you
loan her the $5000 for?
Well, uh, look,
maybe she won't take it.
I mean, she did say
that she was going
to think about it.
People don't turn down money.
It's what separates us
from the animals.
Oh, man, well,
I still don't understand
what the problem is,
having her in the building.
Let me explain something to you.
You see...
You're not normal.
You're a great guy.
I love you.
But... you're a pod.
I, on the other hand,
am a human being.
I sometimes feel
awkward, uncomfortable,
even inhibited
in certain situations
with the other human beings.
You wouldn't understand.
Yeah. Because I'm a pod.
I'll take it!
No.
Hi, Elaine.
Oh, hi, Roxanne.
It's nice to be here.
These are my friends.
This is George.
And this is Jerry.
Hi.
Jerry's the one
who got me my new apartment.
So you're Elaine's hero.
Yes, it's my life's work.
There are so few true heroes
left in this world.
Yeah, my wife
couldn't make it today.
She's got some thing
with her mother.
Who knows what's
going on with her?
Don't let anybody kid you.
It's tough.
Well, better load up
on some carbos
before the race.
Oh, the marathon
is great, isn't it?
Oh, yes, particularly
if you're not in it.
I wish we had a view
of the finish line.
Ah, what's to see?
A woman from Norway,
a guy from Kenya,
and 20,000 losers.
Yeah, my wife started
getting on me
about the lawn today.
I tell you,
it's one thing after another.
Is she here?
Uh, no, no, she's working.
What does she do?
She's an entomologist.
Yeah, you know...
bees, flies, gnats.
Yeah. What... What about you?
I work for the director
of Madison Square Garden.
It's great.
I can get free tickets
to any sporting event
in New York.
Wow.
Anyway,
she's a very lucky woman.
Enjoy the race.
But...
Hi, Stan.
Joanne.
Come in.
Jerry, this is Joanne
and this is Stan.
They're in my short story class.
Hi.
How are you?
Hey, Jerry just got me
a great apartment
in his building.
Well, Jerry, it'll be nice
to have a close friend nearby.
Fantastic.
She can pop in
whenever she wants.
She doesn't even need to knock.
It's tremendous.
Any time of day.
I'm in heaven.
Oh, Rita.
Rita, come here.
This is Jerry.
He's the one
who got me the apartment.
Oh, hi.
Bob, this is the guy
who got Elaine her apartment.
I'm sorry, I just
don't see the big deal
about being a matador.
I mean, the bull charges,
you move the cape...
What's so hard?
So, are you really married?
Because I've actually heard
of single guys
who wear wedding bands
to attract women.
You would have to be
a real loser
to try something like that.
That's too bad, because...
I really have a thing
for bald guys with glasses.
Hey, everybody!
Here come the runners!
Oh! Ooh.
So, you and Roxanne
are hitting it off, huh?
Oh, I wouldn't quite say that.
Really?
From a distance, you seemed
to be coming on to her.
Oh, I'm a guy.
It always looks like that.
Because I was thinking...
Are you at all concerned
that living in the same building
will, you know,
cramp our styles?
Nah.
Because I was worried
that there might be a situation
in which one of us
came home with somebody.
It could get
a little uncomfortable.
But as long
as you're okay with it,
it's fine with me.
I've never been able to be
with just one person.
I can, however,
carry on strictly
physical relationships
which can last
for years and years.
It's a shame you're married.
Um... I'm not.
Um, it... it's just
a sociological experiment.
Please.
You have no idea
what an idiot is.
Elaine just gave me
a chance to get out,
and I didn't take it.
This is an idiot.
Is that right?
I just threw away
a lifetime of guilt-free sex
and floor seats
for every sporting event
in Madison Square Garden.
So, please, a little respect,
for I am Costanza,
lord of the idiots.
You're all winners!
But, suddenly,
a new contender has emerged.
George, I didn't sleep at all
last night.
I decided I have to tell her.
I'm just gonna be honest,
that's all.
Yes, I'm nervous.
Are you listening to me?
Just... Just put some soap
on your finger.
It'll slide right off.
Well, then try axle grease.
I'll call you back
after I talk to her.
Well...
It's all taken care of.
Everything's cool.
What? What's cool?
Elaine.
What are you talking about?
I just found a guy
who's willing to pay $10,000
for the apartment.
You what? Get out!
10,000?
Cash!
Who would pay that much?
He's in the music business.
Elaine would never borrow
that much money.
Kramer...
my God, man.
This is beautiful.
I think I'm in the clear here.
Elaine's not moving in.
I don't have to confront her.
She has no idea
I never wanted her to move in.
I'm golden.
Well, occasionally,
I like to help the humans.
Wow, you're right, that is loud.
It's just unbelievable.
They rehearse all the time?
All the time!
I've been up there six times.
They refuse to stop.
I can't live like this.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
I'm headed for a breakdown.
Can't you do something?
I'm not going up.
It stinks up there.
Manny?
I'm not the one who said
they could play
till 11:00.
He makes up his own rules.
Boy, too bad. If I was up there,
you'd never hear
a peep out of me.
I'm as quiet as a mouse.
Hey.
Oh!
I love the one they do
right after this one.
I don't know.
What do you do when a neighbor
is making, like, a lot of noise
at 3:00 in the morning?
I mean, can you
knock on someone's door
and tell 'em to keep it down?
You're really altering
your whole self-image.
I mean, what am I,
Fred Mertz now?
What's happening to me?
Can I do this?
Am I a shusher?
I used to be a shushee.
There's a lot of shushing
going on in movie theaters.
People are always shushing.
Shh. Shh, shh. Shh!
It doesn't work...
Because nobody knows
where a shush is coming from.
They just hear a "shh!"
Was that a shush?
I think somebody shushed me.
Some people you can't shush
in a movie theater.
There's always a certain group
of people talking and talking.
Everyone around them
is shushing them, shushing them.
They won't shush.
They're the unshushables.