He was supposed to have
a breakfast date, right?
I mean, they told me that last night.
- Breakfast? Is that on the sched?
- It isn't,
but the lieutenant told me that he'd be doing
breakfast with someone down at the harbor.
I mean, if he ain't, I could go get this
gassed up at the Fallsway.
I hate this detail, man.
It's soft duty. Lotsa perks.
All this standin' around and wait.
You know?
Hoskins says I do the one year,
I'll make sergeant on the next list.
They told me, career-wise,
you can't do better than drive the mayor.
Shit, if you could make rank the right way,
I'll still be working Western drugs.
All right, fuck this, I'm gonna go look
for the lieutenant.
Anyone comes looking,
I'm back up on the second floor.
Sir?
I understood that the Mayor
might be going to breakfast at the harbor?
With Kweisi.
But that's up in the air, I thought.
Would you happen to know
where Lieutenant Hoskins is?
Sir?
Lieutenant?
Uh...
When you walk through the garden
Watch your back
Well I beg your pardon
Walk the straight and narrow track
If you walk with Jesus
He'll save your soul
Gotta keep the devil down in the hole
He's got fire and the fury
At his command
Well, you don't got to worry
Hold on to Jesus' hand
We'll be safe from Satan
When the thunder rolls
But you gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
Oh yeah, mm
We'll be safe from Satan
Gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
In the hole
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
Keep him in the...
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
Keep him in the...
Down in the hole
You don't look happy, Detective.
We're about to raise some hell.
Maybe too much hell.
A state senator, two councilmen,
the City Development Agency,
all those developers...
Princes of the city.
Lester, tell me the thought
hasn't crossed your mind
that some kinda shit
could blow back on us, man.
Do you know what Theodore Roosevelt
said about hunting grizzly bears?
The thrill is in overcoming your own fear.
What was the thrill for the bear?
I should've run every one of these subpoenas
by my front office.
- That's not procedure.
- Fuck procedure, Lester.
My boss is running two points behind
in the polls with the mayor's support.
How is he gonna do if he pisses off Royce
and starts dropping off incumbent tickets?
Why do you care?
If Demper thinks I fucked him and he wins,
I will be at Central Booking
covering bail reviews.
If he loses to Bond,
a new front office comes in
and maybe they bounce the white girl back
and give the Narcotics Division
to one of their own.
It's Baltimore, Lester.
We're missing a couple of subpoenas.
We are?
Clay Davis and Andy Krawczyk.
I'm holding those till October.
- Oh, the hell you are.
- Lester...
we drop subpoenas on either of those guys
three weeks before the primary,
and all hell breaks loose.
- That's what I'm sayin'!
- Clay Davis
is Royce's deputy campaign chairman,
and the number-two man
at the City Legislative Caucus.
And Krawczyk is his number-one fundraiser!
You're giving me résumés and job titles.
I'm just following the money.
And we will follow it after the polls close.
We can drop a second batch of subpoenas.
There is no reason to do this now and risk...
A year ago, if we had gone
after these records,
City Hall would've stomped on this unit
and the subpoenas.
And a month from now,
after Royce is re-elected,
they'll do us the same way.
But right now,
with the primary coming,
they gotta worry about how they look,
how they behave.
Right now, they gotta worry about scandal.
You told me you wanted to do this a year ago,
but fresh cases got in the way.
You told me that.
Very clever, Lester.
You got it all figured, huh?
Me?
I'm just the police.
I saw the teachers' union
finally endorsed Royce.
You knew they were gonna.
What time's your first appearance?
Today? I meet up with you guys
at the SoWeBo forum.
And tonight, it's me and the kids
next to Tommy
at the Roland Park fundraiser.
Better speed things along.
A kick in the ass sometimes helps.
- B-5?
- No, Daddy, D-5.
You sure you didn't say B-5?
D-5. What did I hit?
Submarine.
Um...
E-6.
Miss.
- Just gimme ten minutes.
- You seen your schedule?
You ain't got ten minutes.
Norman, I got this pretty girl's
aircraft carrier boxed in.
- D-4.
- Ow!
- Hit.
- Tommy, for Christ's sakes.
Is there any way that I can win?
With the numbers what they are,
is there any way?
So if it's just a matter of playing out
the string, then that's what I'm gonna do.
That game's pretty much over, Norman.
But this game, this game right here,
this one could still go either way.
- H-11, sweetheart.
- Miss. D-3.
I fell into a burnin' ring of fire
I went down, down, down
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
I fell into a burnin' ring of fire
I went down, down, down
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire, the ring of fire
So I guess y'all getting what y'all need?
- Brianna keepin' y'all close?
- She come up with it.
Money comin' through
every month like she say.
All right, 'cause I'm standin' tall up in here.
They don't need to worry about me
an' I ain't need to worry about them.
- You a soldier, Bey.
- You know it.
Everything all right with my fishes?
You'd tell me if it wasn't, right?
The fish be fine. I mean, they fish, right?
How I know how they feelin' about shit?
- De'londa...
- They fine, Bey.
- Ask Namond.
- Cleaned the tank an' all, like you say.
Cleaned the filter too.
All right, all right. Check you out, though.
Getting some fuzz up there, huh?
- Mm-hm.
- Yeah, whatever.
I know when I was a kid,
I couldn't wait till I started shaving.
One of the old heads on the corner say,
"Hey, little man, you wanna grow a 'stache?
"Next time you take a piss,
take some of that piss,
- "get it on your fingertips, do like this, here."
- Ugh.
- You do it?
- You damn right I did it.
Shit.
- What's going on with you, though, son?
- Ain't nothing.
- School about to start.
- Mm.
So what about Bodie and his boys?
They treatin' you right?
Yeah, he cool.
Boy, don't lie to your father.
He don't even show up for work
half the damn time.
- Bodie told me.
- I missed a few days. That's all, Dad.
And what money you do make,
you waste on nonsense.
And if you think I'm-a give you a dime
for your school clothes,
you better think again.
- What Bodie got you doin'?
- I'm a runner most days.
Everybody got to start somewhere.
You better listen to your father.
He ain't tell you 'bout that hair, though, huh?
Yeah, he said I gotta get it cut.
I like it this way.
Even the white police from three blocks away
gonna be able to spot you
from every other nigger out there.
They gonna say, "Look at the boy
over there with the pretty-ass ponytail.
"Get him." You think I'm bullshitting.
Either you real out there, or you ain't, Na'.
You see what I'm sayin'?
Hey!
Let me get some.
- Let me get some!
- Hey, you. Over here!
- $100!
- Thanks, mister!
- Thank you, Mr. Marlo!
- Thank you!
That's my money, yo!
Your name gonna ring out, man.
Manuel, tú empiezas enfrente.
Yo hago la parte de atrás.
- A Connie le gusta por atrás.
- No tanto como a ti, maricón.
Boy, you talk that shit better than me
and I been dealin' with
these Mexicans for years now.
I don't think they would call
what I'm speakin' Spanish, man.
Just a dirty word or two here or there.
Yeah, well. Once you can talk to these cats,
the only thing you need then is a truck, man.
Could be runnin' your own crew,
pickin' up fresh clients.
I mean, if we put in together,
we could be coverin' twice the ground,
makin' twice as much.
Nah, man, I got other obligations.
Oh, right.
You set to be the new Angelo Dundee.
I near forgot.
- Chinga a ti, pendejo.
- Chinga a la tuya, hijo de puta.
I thought you already went up to Mondawmin
to get your school shit, man.
Yeah, but not all of it. And my boy,
he need to pay for his own shit
and his little brother too.
The fuck this look like,
a Social Services office?
- Want a check, go the fuck up Rosemont.
- Come on, man, I'll work for it.
Na', I took you on out of respect
for your father, all right,
but I can't go hirin'
the whole damn neighborhood.
You can have my job
until you get enough for you an' Bug.
- Thanks, man.
- Yeah, work for y'all, work for me, yo.
Po-po. Step the fuck off.
Looking for your man Lex.
I see his broom, but I don't see him.
Where's your number two been at?
- I ain't seen him.
- Since when?
I thought we were on better terms.
Or do you want me rolling past
lookin' for Lex every 15 minutes?
He come past, I'll call you.
I will.
If he come past.
I don't know.
They're spinning their wheels.
You know, poor Tony Gray,
pulling 20% of the black vote.
It's embarrassing.
Who knows what the fuck
Carcetti's trying to prove?
But I tell you, at the end of this thing, he's
gonna regret getting on the wrong side of me.
All right, now.
I got what you need, boy.
Clean tees, any sizes.
Lookin' for socks, briefs,
you lookin' for some dice, Zippo, cards,
come on over to the Rollin' Emporium.
You ain't gotta walk to Rite Aid.
Shit, Rite Aid comin' to y'all.
- What can I get you, baby?
- Fresh dice an' a pack of Trojans.
- All righty.
- You got Philly blunts too?
Bubbles got it all, dawg.
I'm the one-stop shop.
- How much is that?
- Six an' a bit.
- Thank you. Thank you kindly.
- A'ight.
Yes, sir, I see what you're lookin' at.
Two a deck, name brand.
- You can't beat that price.
- Yeah, let me get two decks, man,
and a white tee, double-X.
And give me the rest
of them paint cans too, man.
There you go. That's it?
- Yeah, what's that?
- How much the man owe, Sherrod?
- 13.
- Whoa, whoa. He asked for all the cans.
Three cans is 12, plus the other stuff.
It's 19. 19, sir.
You still gettin' off with a deal,
you didn't even have to move your feet.
My bad. 19, like he said.
Thank you very much.
He's an intern, I'm working with him.
But, ma'am, what I'm asking is
when was the last time you saw Lex?
Oh. Excuse me. Curtis.
Mm?
- Two days ago?
- I don't know where he at.
Three days?
- You mind I look around?
- I'd rather you leave my house be.
Well, Ms. Anderson...
your son is in trouble,
and I can tell you're upset.
But the best thing that you can do for him,
the best thing that he can do for himself,
is talk to me.
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
We know he's selling drugs.
And I'm gonna tell you...
I don't know nothin' about that.
But I'm telling you that I don't care
he's selling drugs.
I'm not even gonna bother with that.
I'm here because of a homicide,
and the way it looks right now,
your boy is running from the police
behind that killing.
I don't know where he at.
Ma'am...
Councilman, my people got only
cost-of-living bumps for four years.
Morale is at rock bottom.
All things being equal, you'd be our guy.
We like what we hear.
The polls say it's going to be Royce.
We endorse you now, we're out in the cold.
Bobby, this might be the chance to get in
on the ground floor of something better.
That may be true, Major. But for now, we're
gonna play the cards that we were dealt.
Councilman, if you were me...
I'd cover my ass and endorse Royce,
along with the teachers and the firefighters.
But I'd also tell my membership
not to get carried away.
I mean, it's one thing
for the police union to call out for Royce,
it's another thing entirely for off-duty cops
to be manning the mayor's phone banks
and polling stations.
I don't think any of my officers
will be too aggressive for anybody.
That much I can give you.
Best you could do, Tommy. Royce has got
all those fucks runnin' scared.
Yeah...
best I could do.
Call it a night, Tommy. You got a debate
to prepare for tomorrow.
Yeah.
Debate.
- Nothing matters more at this point.
- Let the truth set you free, Norman.
Nothing matters at all.
Thanks.
Go left.
Back.
Come on, boy, come on now.
Man, you better not be getting tired,
'cause you gonna get put to the test
- on Saturday night.
- I'm ready.
- Hey, Miss Johnson.
- Hey, Justin. Hello, Dennis.
- You're Spider's mother, right?
- Right, Sharon. Sharon Johnson.
- Your boy left here a while ago.
- I ain't looking for him.
He at his grandmother's.
I wanted to ask you something.
You know, my son is crazy about you.
All he talks about is boxing, bein' at the gym,
and what his coach been teachin' him.
Well, Spider's a good kid.
He really studies the sport.
Dennis, I am so grateful
for your interest in Spider,
I want to cook you dinner.
How about tonight?
Well, that is really nice, Sharon.
But the thing is, I got four of my boys
fighting this weekend,
and I got to train 'em really hard
these next few evenings.
You in here every night of the week.
What you do for fun?
Look here, you got to eat, right?
And you can look at me and know
I throw down in the kitchen...
among other places.
Yeah, I tell you what,
you fix me a plate and bring it over here,
I would love that.
That I can do.
He said what?
"Me?
"I'm just the police."
Like butter wouldn't melt in his mouth.
And the thing that I resent most,
that he's not just playing the system,
he's playing me.
Like I'm part of the problem.
You were gonna hold back the paper
for Davis and Krawczyk, right?
Only until the primary was over.
And now you feel guilty about it.
Did he do that thing where he stares at you
over the top of his reading glasses?
You know, with that look that says,
"I'm the father you never had,
"and I don't want to be disappointed
in you ever again."
It's not funny, Cedric!
Those subpoenas went out today!
The front office is gonna go batshit!
But you did it anyway.
I'm sorry, but shit, I'm just glad to see
Lester doing it to somebody other than me.
You holdin' us back, Sherrod.
I made a mistake, man. Why you trippin'?
If I can cut you loose
to handle the money,
we can cover twice the ground,
selling twice the merchandise.
More, what you call it, market share.
Instead I gotta keep your ass close.
You shoulda been promoted
to your own cart by now.
You keep on hittin' your dome
on the glass ceiling.
- Glass what?
- You gotta step up the math skills
if you wanna advance here in this enterprise.
Remember last spring when you tried
to take me to Harlem Park?
They couldn't find my records, Bubs.
They didn't want shit to do with me.
- They put you in a classroom, right?
- The teacher didn't look at me once.
So you rolled out. An' who got hurt
behind that, huh? The teacher or you?
What's four times five plus six times seven?
See? See?
Fuck that shit, son.
I can't wait until school starts.
- You joking, right?
- Nah, seriously, son.
I can't wait to see all them girls,
see which ones got phat
over the summer, you know?
- Guess who I saw last week?
- Who?
Kwaneese Davis.
- Shit, you mean Cute-Ass Kwaneese?
- Uh-huh.
- She phat?
- Got titties too. Mm.
I'm definitely tappin' that pussy,
now, y'all watch.
I'm-a be all up in Kwaneese this year
like this, bangin' that...
Just like you tried to do last year, right?
Fuck you, nigger, I only halfway tried.
So, Michael, who you gettin' with this year?
Stankin' ass... What's her name?
- Tina.
- Tina. Tina Jenkins.
- Don't talk bad about Tina, man.
- I'm not sayin' nothin' bad.
I'm sayin' she be sucking dudes' dicks
in the boys' bathroom and shit.
I heard you, man.
She suck dick even better
than you do, Namond.
Ohhh!
What up?
- What up? What up, see?
- Jab him, man. Jab him.
Chill, chill, chill! Don't rip this shit.
I just bought this throwback.
Yo, Michael, son, if I ain't had this shit on,
I'd have fucked you up. Word up.
You little niggers ain't up to no good, is you?
Yo, what up, Monk?
Look here, first day
of school coming up, right?
Yeah, next week.
So y'all need, like, school clothes and shit?
Here.
Yo, what's this for?
What, you ain't hear me? For new clothes,
whatever else you need to get.
- Thanks, man!
- Damn, 200?
- Yo, thanks, Monk.
- Oh, you need to thank my man Marlo.
He ain't wanna see you little motherfuckers
going raggedy on the first day.
That Marlo?
- Naw, man, no thanks.
- You ain't gotta do nothing for it.
No, thank you, man.
Hey, yo, Mr. Monk?
I'll take his if he don't want it.
- I'll hold his for you...
- Yo, don't press, man.
Don't press.
Fuck is wrong with you, boy?
You too good for my money?
Or is you such a bitch-ass punk you worried
about where my money come from?
Yeah.
Ain't no thing, shorty. We cool.
You can't tell nobody.
Swear to me you won't spread this around.
And he saw you?
Yeah, he saw me.
Carv, I'm fucked in the ass
with a pineapple on this.
- What the hell'd you say?
- "Mr. Mayor,
"that's a strong dick you got,
and I see you know how to use it."
I didn't say shit! And I didn't wait for him
to say anything, either.
Shit, I'm never gonna make rank now.
I'll end up riding the boat
or some shit like McNulty.
This is way beyond my pay grade.
We need to get with someone
who knows politics.
Who do we know like that?
On crime, he knows you're coming,
so he'll set some traps
and lean on stats that say crime is down.
He'll also try to inoculate himself
by making it about you.
Like you're playing the race card
if you talk about drugs or violent crime.
He's hoping you'll back down.
But you come on twice as hard.
"Clarence Royce has not made this city safe."
Hey, Jen, what's up?
- You got a second?
- No, I got time, what is it?
- You forgot the check.
- Oh, no, you're kidding me.
You've got to pay it right away.
No, no, I got the number here, yeah.
No, I'll straighten it out straightaway. Yeah.
Shit.
I forgot to mail the check
to the fuckin' archdiocese.
My kid's gonna get tossed outta St. Albans
if I don't get my shit together.
Tommy. Focus.
He comes at me with race
and some bullshit crime stats.
I ignore the race thing and counter
by noting that homicides are up 15%
even though other violent crime stats
are down 12%.
I point out this does not make sense
unless Royce is cooking the crime stats,
making robberies, rapes
and assaults disappear.
I suggest the mayor is not telling
the truth about crime.
I conclude by declaring that it is
for all of Baltimore, every neighborhood,
that I'm making public safety
the cornerstone of my campaign.
Tomorrow night...
I will kick his ass.
But the next morning,
I still wake up white in a city that ain't.
Sister Theresa? Hey, how you doing?
Yeah, Tommy Carcetti.
Yo, Randy, man, you crack me up, son.
Running behind him talking about,
"I'll take his, Mr. Monk. Give his to me."
Listen, man, I could've used that extra.
I already spent all the clothes money
Miss Anna gave me on stuff to sell at school.
Yo, and plus Marlo wanted us to have it.
He want to show us
who callin' the shots out here.
- Michael, why you ain't take it?
- That ain't me.
- Say what?
- That owin' niggers for shit, man.
- That ain't me.
- I'll take any motherfuckin' money
- if he givin' it away now.
- Why?
Shit, your family
got more money than all of us.
Yeah, but my mom said she cuttin' me off,
she ain't buyin' me school clothes and shit.
You already took my job with Bodie, so...
- Gentlemen.
- Oh, my God.
- Shit!
- Oh.
Whoa.
Donut, you crazy, man.
Yo, Donut. You think you could steal us
one of them camper trucks?
You steal us a camper truck,
we can all go campin' in the woods.
I be scared in the woods.
I don't mean far like that.
I mean like Howard County.
Nah, nah, nah, man. The Ku Klux Klan
live in Howard County. I know that for a fact.
Nigger, my aunt live in Howard County.
Ain't no Ku Klux Klan there.
Nigger, you simple, I swear.
Hey, yo, Donut, drive me away
from these ignorant bitches, man.
You can't tell these niggers nothin'.
Move, motherfucker.
Can you see over the steering wheel?
You think he'll talk to me?
Use my name if you have to.
I had one of his sectors for eight months.
What's wrong with that picture?
Nigger, if there was a black one
in the parking lot, I would've took one.
Yo, knockos, knockos!
760 to K-G-A. I got a bail-out
at Calhoun and Mosher,
six to eight juveniles beating feet north
in the alleys around Calhoun.
10-4. K-G-A to all units...
I love this. Just like old times.
I don't need to chase these fucking
knuckleheads. I know half of 'em.
Shit, I know where they hang.
Besides, you're a little overdressed.
Let's just call this in
and go see the man about your thing.
Yo, yo, man, I ain't do nothin'!
- I ain't do nothin'!
- Then why you runnin'?
- 'Cause you chasin' me.
- Yeah, right. What's your name?
- I ain't do nothin'.
- What's your goddamn name?
- Randy.
- Randy what?
- Wagstaff.
- I know you ain't lying.
Wouldn't nobody make that shit up.
Put your hands against this fucking wall.
What do you know about hoppers
bailing from a stolen car?
Nothin'.
Little motherfucker. You slingin'.
- No. I swear to God.
- Hell you ain't.
How else you got 200 in your pocket?
My foster mother gave me that
to buy school clothes.
- Your foster mother gave you 200 cash?
- Yeah.
Tell her to come down to the Western,
and I'll give it back to her.
Beat feet, motherfucker,
before I lock your little ass up.
Don't be fucking lookin' at me. Move.
This right here is fire.
That said, I'm ready to serve 'em myself
and keep your names off the returns.
I've got my 20.
You two got to live in this department.
Fuck 'em where they live.
Let's go.
The price of steel being what it is,
that's gonna kill us if we can't
pass along the overage.
Mr. Krawczyk? Baltimore City Police.
- What's this?
- A subpoena for records.
You need these right now?
Because I'm kinda up to my ass in stuff today.
Honor it in a timely fashion.
I think that's the legal standard.
- No problem, Detective...
- Shakima Greggs.
You're with the city?
- Which unit?
- Major Crimes.
Senator.
- What the hell is this?
- Subpoena for records.
Sphinx Club?
- Man of the year.
- What kinda bullshit is this?
You people must be out your damn mind.
You were in the Sphinx Club?
My uncle used to tend bar over there.
- Marvin Thompson? Short guy...
- What is your name, Officer?
Detective Sydnor, sir.
Major Crimes?
Shit.
Enjoy your day, sir.
Son, we're gonna see about this.
That's it.
Yankin' that bitch.
Son, that's too much knuckle.
Why the fuck you keep callin' me?
But what I say, though?
He got the message, fool.
- Yo, Monk. Who that, man?
- Andre. Old Face Andre.
Here, let me holler at that dude.
Yo, check this out, man.
I'm gonna show you how you do this
right here, man.
Don't rush me on shit.
I'll get at you when I'm at you.
Yo, remember who you're talking to
before you say another fuckin' word.
Andre, man. Nigger need more maintenance
than both my babies' mamas.
By accident. It was accidental.
And the mayor doesn't say anything?
I think he's pretty mad.
I mean, Major, I only took this detail
to try and make sergeant on this list.
Kid, you made sergeant already.
Shit, if Royce gets re-elected,
you'll be a lieutenant in two years
and a major in four.
You go back down to the hall.
You act like it never happened.
You shut up.
Say nothing to no one.
- But the mayor, he's gonna...
- He's gonna watch and see how you carry it.
And, kid, you're a fucking rock.
When the mayor looks in your face,
he knows he can trust you with this.
And I'll bet in a couple of weeks,
he comes asking, real friendly-like,
"What are you looking
to do with the department? With your career?"
He's interested in you.
But he doesn't mention no blow job,
and neither do you.
Uh-uh. It just lays there like a bad pierogi
on the plate,
both of you pretending it ain't there.
What if he screws me over?
Bounces me to a midnight shift?
He does that, you will talk.
What I wouldn't give
to be in your shoes right now.
Kid, careers have been launched
on a hell of a lot less.
Just shut up and play dumb.
I can do that. No problem.
Thanks, Major.
Thanks for taking the time to meet me on this.
I mean, it's a weight off
my mind talking to you.
- It really is.
- Don't mention it.
Maybe you get a chance
to do me a turn one day
after you make rank, huh?
- All right.
- Yeah.
Oh, boy.
It's all good, Carv.
If some federal motherfucker comes through
the door, I say, "Hey, it's all in the game."
But a city police?
Baltimore City? Hell, no.
Can't be happenin', 'cause I know I have
raised too much goddamn money
for the mayor and his ticket.
Hell, no! Ain't no soul in the world
that fuckin' ungrateful!
- Calm down, Clay.
- Money laundering?
They gonna come talk to me
about money laundering?
In West Baltimore?
Shit. Where do y'all think I'm gonna raise cash
for the whole damn ticket?
From laundromats and shit?
From some tiny-ass Korean groceries?
You think I have time to ask a man
why he givin' me money?
Or where he gets his money from?
I'll take any motherfucker's money
if he givin' it away.
- I don't wanna know.
- I know you don't wanna know.
But I'm scratchin' an' clawin'
to get it done for you, Clarence.
For you and me and the rest of the team.
And who comes through my door
but a Baltimore City police
- lookin' to get up into my shit about it.
- Clay, we didn't know about that.
I'm sorry, I gots to leave up out of here
before I lose my damn mind.
Nobody knew about that.
You want to run a campaign with my money
pillowed under your ass,
you need your people
to back the fuck up, Clarence.
Krawczyk's on line one.
I'll jump on Burrell and Demper both.
- Find out what the hell's going on.
- Wait a minute. Erm...
That new driver, the bald-headed, white kid.
Where did he come in from?
- Hoskins brought him in, I think.
- Hoskins?
He doesn't have a better rabbi
in the department than that?
Why, you want to lose him?
Let me think about it.
Yeah, man, Officer Walker be shady like that.
Police be stealin', yo.
Yo, what I really wanna get
is a bubble Caprice.
I seen a nice one too.
'94 Caprice on 22s. Shit was tight.
You be careful.
They almost caught you today.
- Nigger, they ain't almost caught shit.
- Quiet, y'all.
- Y'all know who I am, right?
- Carver. You a knockos.
Today I'm auto theft.
Fair warning.
If I see any of y'all little hoppers
even smile at a motor vehicle again,
it ain't gonna be no juvenile hearing.
It's gonna be my people settlin' up with y'all
in the alleys. Understand?
- You can't do that, yo.
- Try me, Namond.
Yeah, that's right. I know your name.
I know where you live
and I know where y'all hang.
Damn, yo! Nice ride.
Damn.
- Hey, Bunk.
- Hm?
- You have any luck finding your shooter?
- Naw. He's runnin'.
But at least I know who my shooter is, right?
I just got to find the boy.
- Family won't go for nothin'?
- Nah.
Mother wouldn't say shit.
But it wasn't the usual way a mama lies.
- What do you mean?
- I don't know.
It was a weird vibe, man. I can't explain it.
It was like she was off
somewhere else in her head.
Line four. Communication.
- Who's up?
- I'm up. I'll take it.
No, wait.
If it's yours, you lucky bitch,
then it's a domestic in a house with four wits.
You want the call?
But if I pick up that phone,
do I make it unlucky? Or is it still your call?
Look, you want the call, pick it up.
If you don't, don't.
Homicide. Norris.
Right.
Uh-huh.
I got it.
1400 Lanvale, in the street,
found by the post officer,
no suspects, no witnesses.
Ah, man.
Better to be lucky than to be good.
You wanna work the heavy bag?
Go ahead. Four rounds.
- Hey.
I'm Gail. I made this for you
and the other men
to let you know you're appreciated.
- That's real nice.
- Peach cobbler.
I'm sorry, I forgot whose mother you are.
I don't have any boys.
I just appreciate what you been doing,
you and the other coaches,
volunteering and all.
Well, thank you, that's real nice.
I got three girls. Y'all don't
teach girls, though, do you?
- No, I'm real old-fashioned about that.
- I agree wit' you.
Men should be men
and women should be women.
That's what I think.
Single wound, upper back, no casings,
no witnesses, and nothing on the canvas.
- Dead when you got here?
- Actually not.
He was conscious and coughin' blood
when I pulled up.
- You ask who shot him?
- Yeah, I asked who shot him.
He said it was a guy with a gun.
Yo, why the fuck
you keep calling me?
He got the message, fool.
- Yo, Monk. Who that, man?
- Andre. Old Face Andre.
Let me key that.
- Yo, Monk. Who that, man?
- Andre. Old Face Andre.
Yo, check this out, man.
Don't rush me on shit.
- I'll get at you when I'm at you.
- I'm just saying...
- Old Face Andre.
- Tryin' to re-up with Monk Metcalf.
Yeah, Monk took the call on his cellphone.
But that second voice ranked him.
- Ranked everybody, by the sound of it.
- Marlo Stanfield. On the phone.
The way he shut that call down,
I'd say, yeah, that was him.
But what was all that in the background?
Fireworks?
No, it was regular intervals.
Semi-auto from the sound.
Target practice, maybe.
Either that or a firing squad.
There are no bodies on this guy in months,
but we get him on the phone
and it sounds like a war zone.
Well, at least he gets on a phone
now and then.
- That's something.
- Sounds arrogant, doesn't he?
Like he's the little king of everything.
Ah, youth.
Yo, Bubs.
Thought you asleep.
If you want...
I could go to school some.
I ain't been for a while,
so I don't even know if I can.
But if you want me to go...
ain't no thing.
His Honor was mad?
I can't begin to describe it.
- What's he want from us?
- To block the subpoenas,
but he knows we can't
once those things go out.
What I could promise him
is no more surprises out of our shop.
Is this that cocksucker McNulty?
Not this time. He's been gone
from that unit a year.
My best guess would be Lester Freamon.
- Freamon?
- Lester's got a hell of a game.
Well, we need to sit on the motherfucker.
All that unit needs, Commissioner,
is proper supervision.
Hey, the State of Maryland just lost another
cooperating witness,
and I just found a lot of fucking overtime.
This case went from a who-gives-a-fuck
drug murder to straight-up red ball.
Fuck, I should've picked up that phone.
Hey, Sarge. My boy's a witness.
Drug case pending in part 18.
You know for sure he's killed for that reason?
Don't know shit.
But from the look of the court computer,
this guy's the state's whole case.
Don't put it in the 24
that the guy was a witness.
Trust me, we do not wanna
kick shit in an election year.
Work the case, take the OT,
but bury the witness angle
till we know for sure.
And close the door.
Yeah.
It's Landsman. Homicide.
Is the major in this morning?
Next order of business, class rules.
It helps if the team is constant on these.
Less wiggle room for the children.
- Mrs. Scott?
- Same as last year, double space.
Language Arts.
We grade a lot of papers.
It doesn't make them write any better,
but it saves my eyesight.
Demonstrate it for them.
Some of them think double space
means more space between words.
- I'd have thought by eighth grade...
- Rule of thumb here, Mr. Pryzbylewski,
never assume.
Explain what you want them to do,
have them do it, then explain again.
With time and patience, they'll get it.
- Mrs. Shapiro?
- It's easier to keep track of lab work
if we all use the same heading.
Upper right-hand corner,
above the first blue line,
name, date, and class number, in that order?
Mr. Pryzbylewski, do you have
anything you want addressed?
Can we have them not chew gum?
They won't do it in Ms. Sampson's class,
but in four years,
I have not been able to stop them.
You can try, but first year,
it's best to stick with basics.
In team rules, we can only go
with what we can all enforce.
Also, keep your windows closed.
Makes them drowsy, and drowsy's good.
There's a lot to learn. But for now,
build in lots of activities in your lesson plan,
you can't have enough.
You keep them busy,
you keep them off-guard.
You need soft eyes.
Excuse me?
Yeah, but that doesn't prevent you
from giving more under your wife's name,
your children, if they got
separate accounts, yeah.
Sorry, Richie,
can you hold a moment?
Your buddy from the FOP.
And he says it's important.
Hey, Stan.
I'm a little busy losing an election here.
You remember about six months ago,
you told me to keep an eye
for any witnesses gettin' clipped?
You remember that?
Who's better than me, Tommy?
Hey, Richie, can I call you back?
Thanks.
Anything else you want me to do,
Miss Donnelly?
Uh...
- You live near Duquan Weems, correct?
- Dukie?
- I want you to take this to his house.
- Them clothes won't stay clean long.
Make sure you deliver them just to Duquan,
not any of the adults in the house,
- just Duquan.
- Want me to do it tonight?
That would be great.
And, Crystal, thanks for today.
You're welcome, Miss Donnelly.
- Can I help you?
- Yes, ma'am.
This young man has to be
registered for school.
- Does he attend here?
- He should.
What I mean is, what grade
were you in last year, dear?
He kinda lost his way some time ago.
He's livin' with me now.
- And you are his...
- Uncle. I'm his uncle.
Come into my office.
Thank you. Excuse me.
To your right. To your right.
One, two, one, two.
One, two, yeah.
Yo, look at coach workin' it, yo.
All right!
All right, man, break.
That's what I like to see, baby.
You gotta use that left a little more.
- Yo, man, you finished?
- Got another two minutes.
Fuck that, I got a fight coming up.
You can come back later.
- Man said he got one more round.
- Step aside, young'un.
Naw, man, bag is mine
for four rounds and I only did three.
- Fuck that.
- Yo.
What the fuck you tryin' to prove, huh?
Come on, man, come on.
What's going on, boy?
I got a fight Saturday,
an' the boy won't get off the bag.
What the fuck he on the bag for anyway?
He don't even fight. He don't even spar.
- Spar with your ass any day.
- Come on, then.
Y'all be cool, you hear me?
I ain't putting up with this foolishness.
Come here, Michael.
- I can work the bag now, right?
- Not yet. Just wait.
- You said four rounds.
- Yeah, I know what I said.
You finish up your rounds,
and then Justin gets on.
I don't want hear no more street talk.
We boxin' up in here, we ain't fightin'.
He wanna get in the ring with me,
- we can go.
- Look here, let me tell you something.
You can come here, work out,
use the equipment.
But nobody gets in that ring
unless they're being trained.
You wanna be trained?
I've been watching you hit that bag.
You got a natural right hand,
the way you throw it, the way you land it.
Now, if I was to train you,
we'd have to start with floor work.
'Cause see, if you don't know how to move,
you ain't got no business being in that ring.
So what you think?
I'd train you myself, personally.
Nah, really, I just wanna keep doing
what I been doing.
All right.
Let's see that right. Uh-huh.
Is Dukie here?
What's that? That's for Duquan, right?
I take it to him.
Gimme.
Hey, Crystal.
Miss Donnelly said to give you these.
OK. I'll be right down.
What?
And for either of my opponents to suggest
that downtown development comes
at the expense of our city's neighborhoods,
well, that's just unfair and divisive.
For them to suggest
that my administration
has not been responsive, well...
Economic development
cannot be a Band-Aid.
It is a long-term process
that requires commitment
to retraining our workforce
and, as I said before,
this can only be successful
in a city where people feel safe.
So before we can begin to think
about luring new industries to Baltimore,
we need to think about
how we can make these neighborhoods
and this city safe once again.
Mr. Carcetti may think
it's in his interests to exploit people's fears.
He's been doing it throughout this campaign.
I'm offended by it, personally. But the fact is,
that violent crime is down city-wide,
and our police department
is working hard to keep it that way,
and will continue to do so
under my administration.
Councilman Carcetti,
you have two minutes to respond.
Does anyone in this room really believe
that crime is down in Baltimore?
You calling me a liar, Tommy?
Gentleman, please. No personal interactions.
- Councilman Carcetti.
- Can the mayor honestly tell
the people of Rosemont,
of Belair Edison,
of Highlandtown or Cherry Hill
there's less drug-dealing, less violence?
Any statistics coming
from the police department
cannot be trusted, because under this mayor,
the police are more concerned
with protecting Clarence Royce politically
than fighting crime.
There's no leadership
and morale has never been lower.
I'll change that.
It's business as usual down at City Hall
and as a result, our response to crime
has been characterized time and time again
by wanton indifference.
..32 yards!
What do I mean by business as usual?
What do I mean by wanton indifference?
Well, last night
in West Baltimore, on Lanvale Street,
another citizen was shot and killed.
This victim was a key witness
in a drug case that had yet to come to court.
Courageously, this man had agreed to testify
in two weeks' time in that case.
The police should have been protecting him.
They were not, and he was murdered.
- Oh, shit.
- Why? Because this mayor...
- You're prime-time, Eddie.
- ..would not spend the money to protect him.
Now I have no doubt
that in a moment or two
Clarence Royce will accuse me
of exploiting this man's death
for my own political purpose,
but the truth is, a year ago
I wrote the mayor a letter.
I have copies for anyone who wants one.
I begged him to spend the money
and make witness protection a priority.
He ignored me.
I even teamed up with our legislative leaders,
Delegate Watkins and others,
to get matching funds
for witness protection approved in Annapolis.
And incredibly those matching funds
were never claimed by this administration.
Now to mention this now may be exploitive,
I don't know, I only know it's true,
and on such truths I ask the voters of our city
to consider a change.
Folks, please, hold your applause
until after the round of questions is over.
Mayor Royce?
No more surprises, huh?
I am unaware of the specifics
of the incident
to which Councilman Carcetti is referring,
so I can't answer that directly,
however, I can say
that this city places the highest priority
on protecting those citizens
who come forward to testify,
and we will continue to do so.
Mr. Carcetti states that he wrote a letter
expressing his concerns,
and I'm sure that he did.
I mean, it's easy enough to write letters
when all you have to do is write letters.
But when you are required
to run a city
on limited resources,
and balance priorities,
well, then...well, then you understand
that writing letters
will not solve the problem, oh, no.
Shit, girl.
You know I'm-a roll wit' you.
I need some kinda break.
Mm-hm.
Oh, shit.
Ain't nothin' worse than them bitches
with fucked-up nails at the blackjack table.
You know.
Hold on.
You think my son ain't gonna go up
to that school lookin' like himself?
I don't believe we can get a handle on crime
until we get a handle on the schools.
Because we need to be
thinking about these kids
before the corners take them.
And this means a renewed focus
on our schools...
Oh!