So, Rashad has 82 apples...
and 12 friends...
all of whom are hungry.
And, uh, so he looks carefully at his apples
and sees that seven have worms.
Another 15 have gone rotten.
But he wants to be fair
and distribute all the good apples equally.
- "Distribute"?
- Give out.
- Well, just say that, yo?
- OK.
OK, so how many apples
does each of Rashad's friends get:
A - four, B - five.
C - six or D - seven?
Take your time but do it fast.
Nigger said, "I got my rights,"
so my boy said, "Oh, yeah?
Well, here's a left to go with your right."
He was like, pow!
- Calvin, you done already?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah?
- B - 5.
How did you work that out so fast?
Easy. "B - 5" got the dinks.
- The what?
- If you want, I could show you.
Don't show him, show me.
OK.
You did this with
the earlier math class, right?
So, you, like, got 82 apples...
12 niggers...
and then how many blah, blah, blah...
then you went, like, dinking all round
this one and no other one.
So the answer is "B - 5." Everybody get that?
- Yeah.
- "B - 5," it got all the dinks.
"B - 5," and I'm an Audi 5000.
When you walk through the garden
Watch your back
Well I beg your pardon
Walk the straight and narrow track
If you walk with Jesus
He'll save your soul
Gotta keep the devil down in the hole
He's got fire and the fury
At his command
Well, you don't got to worry
Hold on to Jesus' hand
We'll be safe from Satan
When the thunder rolls
But you gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
Oh yeah, mm
We'll be safe from Satan
Gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
In the hole
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
Keep him in the...
Down in the hole
Keep him in the hole
Keep him in the...
Down in the hole
The priority should be keeping the
H files up to date with all notes transcribed,
the standard office report. Uh...
On our day shift today, you may encounter
Councilman and Democratic
mayoral nominee Thomas Carcetti,
who's been fact-finding
within the department.
So, if you go leaving your facts laying around
and he finds them, that shit's on you.
Uh, lastly, as most of you are already aware,
our CID Commander Raymond Foerster,
after a long bout with cancer,
passed away last night at Johns Hopkins.
Better, uh, eulogies are coming.
So, let me just say
that the man served 39 years
attaining the rank of colonel
without leaving a trail of bitterness
or betrayal.
In this department,
that's not a career, it's a miracle.
Uh, there'll be a detective's wake this evening
followed by viewings on Wednesday
and a burial Mass on Friday.
The family suggests donations
to the colonel's favorite charities.
Addresses will be posted in the coffee room.
All told.
And, Bunk, I just got
your overtime for the week.
Get in to my office and pull your pants down.
No, no, no! Fuck that.
You finish a pot, you make the next one.
OK.
I don't see the right one in here anywhere.
- Sergeant Hauk.
- Yes, sir.
I just got off with Beauford at IAD.
He says a harassment complaint's been filed.
A Jamaican woman says you had her
searched by Amtrak police?
Yeah. Well, you see, in my report,
we had what we thought was reliable info
that she was a drug courier
for Marlo Stanfield.
I mean, we actually scoped Stanfield with her.
What was the info?
The CI's been reliable.
Great track record with us. Long history.
CI 238. Give me his name.
His name? Sir.
Sir! Sir, I've never been comfortable
with, you know,
tossing around names
of informants in squad rooms.
- I feel that it's...
- Name.
Fuzzy Dunlop, sir.
- I might have to meet this character.
- He's kind of leery of meets.
He's been reliable, I promise you.
This one baffled the shit out of me, too.
But he's never been off, never.
You jumped out
on bad information, Sergeant.
You brought in another agency
and brought discredit to this unit - my unit.
In good faith though, sir.
If anything comes of this, I have your report,
and I will bury you with it.
And in case you haven't been paying attention
to the election results,
your rabbi has left the building.
- No tantrums today?
- What's the point?
- They're not gonna suspend us, right?
- Right. What's the point?
So, we're here, like it or not.
If it makes you feel better, you're here
because you beat the system.
You had no interest in class,
and you made it
impossible for everybody else,
and now you're out. You won.
- Yeah!
- You feel like winners?
- Always.
- That's how we did.
Who's we?
- Us.
- No, who are you?
- Players.
- Kingpins?
Nah, that comes later.
Right now, we just corner boys.
- So how long until you're kingpins?
- I'm thinking two, three years.
Two, three years.
Let me ask,
and I want everybody to write this down,
where do you see yourself in ten years?
Come on, pencil and paper.
This isn't schoolwork, this is about y'all.
- She's young but she's good.
- Yeah. Doctoral candidate,
psych department of College Park. Thesis
work is on social alienation and analysis.
- All right, how many wrote "NBA"?
- Yeah, but only for the Lakers.
I want to be a pediatric neurosurgeon
like that one nigger, what's his name?
- Ben Carson.
- Yeah, that dude.
- A black surgeon at Hopkins.
- You need to go to medical school.
Whatever.
- How many wrote "dead"?
- Shit, you saw that coming, huh?
Shame y'all have so little time and you're
wasting it here.
You know where you're going.
- We can't teach you anything about that?
- That's what we've been saying.
- Namond, put away the magazine.
- I ain't reading no magazine.
- Namond.
- What? It ain't even mine.
- It was laying here when I came in.
- Y'all little pissers.
You know, we're giving them a fine education.
"It ain't even mine.
It was just laying here when I came in."
You know this right here,
the whole damn school,
the way they carry themselves,
it's training for the street.
The building's the system, we the cops.
Yeah, you are for sure.
I mean, y'all come here every day
and practice getting over,
try running all different kinda games.
It's practice for the corner, right?
Ain't no real cops. Ain't no real danger.
But y'all are getting something out of this.
- Bet you didn't even know that.
- I'd still rather be out there.
Can I, uh...? Corner boys, huh?
Let me ask y'all something.
You help us home in on this,
and maybe we do a little better job.
- What makes a good corner boy?
- Eyes open.
- Keep the count straight.
- Don't trust nobody.
Uh-huh. If you don't got no respect,
you ain't got nothing.
If you stupid, you get killed.
That's the only way.
This name in black right here got stink on it.
- Eyeball witness, Bunk.
- Go back to the scene with me,
- take a fresh look.
- You're out of line, here, Bunk. You are.
- A lot of names. Too many.
- No, we're good with it.
Listen, you back-seat-driving motherfucker,
the guy picked him out -
Omar-fucking-Little. Why?
Who the fuck cares?
We got a dead female taxpayer,
- and somebody's saying him.
- I don't buy it.
And this ain't the motherfucker
that came up with 62 ways for the peanut.
His name pops up on five
or six cases I know of,
including two of yours,
and you want him back on the street?
But this ain't him.
So someone else is walking on you all.
Bunk, the next body you catch,
I'm going to be crawling all over it,
second-guessing your ass every step,
pulling on every last motherfucking thread.
Yeah. We gonna see how you like it.
Hey, Vern. Hey, Vern, Vern, Vern, Vern.
- Just go back on it with me.
- What?
Shit doesn't play out any differently, I'll give
you a back rub you'll never forget.
You guys don't need to do anything
you wouldn't normally do just cos I'm here.
I wouldn't know what we
normally do around here.
I'm new and inexperienced.
Oh, you're, uh...
Yeah. I am.
I'm just trying to get a feel
for your response to the violence.
I'm not the hall monitor or anything.
- So, this is your day?
- We catch a body, it's different.
- You got my camera?
- I what?
- Licence and registration.
- You do me one, I'll do you.
You got a card or something?
City, huh?
Video camera gotta come back.
Yeah, well, I see what I can find out about it.
But you know cameras -
kind of like pigeons in a storm.
Know what I'm saying?
Sometimes they come back. Sometimes...
But I keep an ear out on it.
Pigeons? Did he just say pigeons?
He's fucking with you. Tell Marimow you used
the camera for the PC at the train station.
Then admit the camera got took.
I already put it down to the CI.
I tell dickhead the truth,
- he takes my stripes on it.
- Come on.
I'm just saying
you weren't suspended that long.
Is it because Tiff dropped it,
or you had to do something
for Miss Donnelly?
- Do something?
- I don't know. Like, promise or something.
No, Tiff dropped it. Ain't nothing past that.
That's good. You know,
the thing with the teachers and cops,
they always come at you
like they got you by the ass.
But keep your mouth shut,
ain't nothing they could do.
So, more times than not, they go away.
Word on that.
It don't even matter. Miss Anna...
she got me on this short leash now.
Can't go out the house unless
she know right where I'm going.
Shit, at least you've got a leash.
We turned and shook
As we had a look
In the room where the dead men lay
So big Jim Dwyer made his last...
What the fuck is that?
Club soda...and lime.
You mincing bitch.
Why not just suck a dick and get it over with?
- That'll get the bad taste out of your mouth.
- Ah.
- Yeah.
- I'm a freeborn man of the USA
I'm a freeborn man of the USA
Almost new.
- Don't want no dead man's hat.
- I'm just fuckin' with you.
Here, let's pray.
Here we lay a couple of New York boys
who came too far south
for their own fuckin' good.
Fucking Yankee proud of it now,
you fuckin' bitches.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
You hungry?
You want some Chinese?
- She didn't...
- No talking.
Keep your eyes on your paper.
Yo, Mr. Prezbo, this say "cars."
- So?
- The stuff we practised was about food.
It's OK. It's just a different object.
Pay attention to the number.
Numbers are messed up, too.
We never did one-thirds.
It's the same operation.
One-fourth, one-fifth, one-third.
It's the same steps, different denominator.
- How do you get one-third of a car?
- It's one-third of all the cars.
Was I talking to you?
You get close enough...
you could take a headshot.
Why?
Cos maybe he vested up.
Word. A chest shot maybe won't do it for you.
Then what? You.
- It's his turn.
- Thug, you on it.
You shoot from a distance,
you can't risk a headshot.
You go for the belly, the dick or the ass area.
Because the vest don't go down that far.
Bam. Take 'em out.
- Then what?
- Walk up,
- finish 'em off.
- With a...?
Headshot.
Damn, y'all coming along full effect.
I hear it. I hear that.
All right, now say he in a car.
Sergeant Thomas Hauk, Baltimore City Police.
Didn't I say City would come running?
- Did.
- I'll check this joker out for you.
See what's what.
One other thing, you're doing OK
running them New York niggers
of the East Side, I know that.
But this thing you got
with disappearing the bodies...
My man is saying if you just
vanishing the bodies like that,
it do kind of defeats its own purpose.
Niggers don't know if they
went back to the Bronx or whatever.
- You feel me?
- Course. I'll tell my people.
No disrespect to your
professionalism or nothing.
We all impressed how you lose
the motherfuckers like that.
We just trying to send a message
to these New York people in full effect.
- You know what I'm saying?
- I'll get back to you on this.
So, Councilman, I understand
you were at CID yesterday.
See anything big downtown?
They messed up the lunch order.
No, I figured I needed
to get closer to the street.
Rolling with the mighty.
Remember, we had a shooting last week
so keep those corner fucks to one window.
Shit, if only we had a van full of you guys.
Dressed like that,
Stevie Wonder make you as police.
Radios out of sight.
Volume up on those boom boxes.
- Ten bucks say we collar up first.
- 20.
Mr. Mayor, in the Eastern we are hungry
motherfuckers - respectfully, I mean.
So, you're saying, you don't ever
give anybody a break?
Anybody?
Nah, nah. Cos if you let him slide for a dollar,
it's a sign that you're weak.
Today's dollar is tomorrow's two.
Same with your crew. Your boy
come up short saying spillage or police,
you let him be, and then he gettin' over
on you, then you a chump.
So, you got to fuck him up!
You gotta...mess him up.
Nah. Nah. Something for real happen,
you do that.
Do it over some bullshit,
all you did was lose a good worker.
- I don't know...
- You gotta fuck that nigger up, man.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa.
Stop talking on top of each other.
This how you communicate out on the street?
All right, it's like this -
your boy come back to you,
- say this happened...
- Then you fuck him up.
I'm gonna let him
make it out of his own cut, too.
If he a good worker, he know what to do.
- Yeah, he got a point.
- He got a point. That's a good one.
If he thinks about it, says it ain't his fault,
then that nigger runnin' game on you.
And then you fuck that nigger up.
- Yeah.
- All right, yeah.
- But why?
- You know it gotta happen, man.
- You know what I'm saying!
- Wait, wait, wait! One voice.
- One voice, y'all. One voice.
- D, you tell him.
There always people watching.
- Watching... you.
- True. Yeah.
What's taking you so long?
There he is now.
- Hurry up, this guy. This guy right here.
- Fuck you, guys.
Yo, man, we need some pills.
You in the right place.
- Get them for us.
- Man, I'm going to work.
Yo, 20 for the pills and ten for you.
- Leave the bike.
- What, you want steal my bike?
What the fuck I want your bike for?
I got a car.
Give me a minute.
$20 might mean nothing to you
but I ain't making that much money.
It's hard money.
Y'all some lazy motherfuckers.
It's round the corner.
We appreciate this.
I love it when they come
to work pumped like this.
Shit!
Come on, man. I'm going to work.
I'm going to work, man!
It's bullshit!
This is some bullshit right here.
For real! For real!
I ain't got no drugs, no shit on me.
I ain't got nothing on me, man.
You taking my bike, too?
I need that. This is bullshit!
- One down.
- ..comin' here, fuckin' with us.
This is fucked up right here, man.
Andre, how you doing?
- This is a friend of mine, Detective Moreland.
- Hey.
You doing OK there or what?
Listen, for my friend, tell me one more time
how the thing went down.
- The boy came in.
- Omar?
- Omar.
He puts the nine on her.
Says to me, "Whatever you got."
Mm-hm.
A nine, huh? Where were you?
- Where you see me at.
- Mm-hm.
Nine wouldn't go through this.
- Why did you come out?
- Cos he said to.
- Trying to save her life.
- Right, I'm saying...
This is like Bank of England glass.
Fort Knox glass.
And who put that up there? Huh?
Guy must have had an elephant gun
or some shit.
I don't know. The boy had a mask on.
A mask, huh?
Like Zorro, huh?
- When did that happen?
- A few weeks back.
- Put in a report?
- It got away from me.
Mm-hm.
Andre,
we're going to need you
to come down to the office
and straighten out a couple of things.
I'm running a business here.
I ain't going nowhere.
Give me a bottle of Mylanta. Please.
His whole story is fucked, and here's why.
First, it don't make any sense.
The shooter took out the woman
and left him breathing to talk to you.
He should be dead, too.
Second, that's a drug depot in there.
The glass, reinforced steel,
camera, low inventory.
And, third, he's shining us on
about that big-ass .50-cal hole
because I know who put it there
and he knows.
And if he were to say,
"Oh, that? That's Omar's previous.
"Ripping off a re-up in here,"
which is what happened, he be fucked.
So what? A guy comes in the first time
with a .50 caliber because
he knows the glass is thick,
then comes back
the next week with a nine?
The job isn't about picking
the stories we like best.
Motherfucker. Now you're going
to lecture me about what the job is?
- My apologies.
- OK. Let's go downtown.
It's a new law, yo.
Three pills, that's felony weight.
And you're on a pre-indicted corner.
- What?
- You better show some stash,
or it's off to Cheltenham.
Those DC boys down there, too, right.
- They love fresh Baltimore ass.
- Mm. Mm-mm.
I ain't know no stash.
- They say it's better than pussy.
- Hah!
- Those my pills.
- Yeah?
Have you ever heard of federal guidelines?
Pre-indicted corners, homeboy.
Three years mandatory.
Unless you mitigate.
- Mit-a-what?
- The stash, front boy.
I don't know no stash. Those my pills, man.
- I'm high right now, look.
- Yeah.
Yeah?
They gonna love him up in there. Come on.
- I saw him first. Bitch is mine.
- Those are my pills, I swear.
That's two.
Get the fuck in the car.
- Damn, fractions?
- He's doing fractions.
Shit, you know what we talked about
in my new class?
- What?
- Slinging.
Yo, I'm not playing.
We talked about business,
about putting shit on the damn street.
- Nigger, please.
- It was like we schooling them.
- Yo, my new class is the shit.
- You going by the gym today?
No, man. I gotta go vial up
what's left on this package so I can re-up.
- All right.
- All right, man.
- Peace, man.
- That shit crazy, though, right?
- I gotta leave soon, Duquan.
- OK.
- What level are you on?
- 12.
Ah.
- I never made it past ten.
- Wanna see me get to 40?
That's cheating.
Want me to show you how?
- Baltimore City Police Department.
- Uh, yes, ma'am, this is Sydney Handjerker
with Handjerker, Cohen & Bromburg.
I'm trying to locate a Sergeant Thomas Hauk
in regards to a client I'm representing.
Hold, please.
- Mayor's office, Lieutenant Hoskins.
- Yes, hello. This is Ervin Pepper
of Pepper, Pepper & Bayleaf.
I'm calling in regards to
a Sergeant Thomas Hauk in regards to...
He's no longer on this detail.
Hold on for a minute.
Major Crimes. May I help you?
Uh, this is Dr. Jay calling
with test results for Thomas Hauk.
He's on the street.
You want to leave a message?
Hello?
- Let's do it.
- Just walk up on him, all right?
Snap one. Make sure he's from New York
first, right? Gotta ask.
Ask what? "You from New York?"
No, ask a Baltimore question,
something a New York nigger won't know.
- What's a Baltimore question?
- I don't know,
maybe something about club music.
They don't know nothing
about that shit up in New York.
- Huh?
- Ask him, like, who Young Leek be.
We're shakin' it, jiggin' it...
Or K-Swift.
Man, I don't know nothing
about that 92Q shit, man.
Man, who gives a fuck, yo?
You don't know Marc Clarke?
"The Big Phat Morning Show"?
You ain't right, girl. The average
Baltimore nigger know all that shit, a'ight?
They don't listen to that shit in New York.
They listen to some bullshit.
- Go ahead.
- Whatever.
- Got a bet going on, man.
- What's up?
Who's your favorite on
"The Big Phat Morning Show"?
Your New York girl, Sonjay.
- Who?
- Kill that show any day.
Snoop, yo. Snoop, yo. Yo.
Chill! Sonjay be on the show, too.
Maybe I ask the questions
from now on, all right?
They entrap some poor bastard on a bet,
haul in $20 of drugs.
They've got to process him,
feed him, property voucher his bike.
Next they're working on some 14-year-old
like he's Bin Laden.
The big haul is three vials of cocaine.
I mean, are you with this?
I've been fighting this bullshit for years.
You pick the targets
that'll make a dent out there,
reduce the violence.
So what's the problem?
- Problem is I do what I'm told.
- Meaning?
Mr. Mayor, I'm no more a racist than you are.
The thing about affirmative action -
I'm just talking policy here, no offense...
- None taken.
- It's a numbers game.
And numbers games
breed more numbers games.
You need a 20% hike in black officers
to match the city demographic.
But that's got to be reflected up the chain,
which means fast-tracking
some people past where their...
How do I say this? Their experience warrants.
And he who owes his good fortune
to the numbers, abides in them.
Gotta show arrests are up 15, 20%?
We'll worry about the quality later.
So what you saw out there, it's a con game,
a Band-Aid on cancer, so no, I'm not with this,
but I do follow orders.
However, if those orders were to change
or if I had the opportunity
to change them myself...
Oh, no, you not!
What's this shit doing in my house?
- I'm stretching bottles, Ma.
- Your daddy bring his work home?
That's what you got a lieutenant for.
Police come through this door
they have this whole house.
This has got to be packed up
and elsewhere right now.
All right, be cool.
Wait till Bey hear about this.
Did you hear that appeal to racial solidarity?
I'd like to kick his pale entitled ass.
Were you listening?
He's no more a racist than I am.
Might have to kick your ass, too.
What have you heard about this fella Daniels?
- Major in the Western.
- Yeah, he's there, but not much politically.
I don't think he's got any suction
with anybody.
Where's the Rice-A-Roni?
Ma, where's the Rice-A-Roni?
A boy on the stoop
looked like he was starving.
- So you cooked it for him?
- No, I just gave it to him.
You just gave it to him.
Boy ate a raw box of Rice-A-Roni?
How much did you sell the groceries for?
Don't look at me like that.
I gotta go out.
- Ten?
- You have your Rice-A-Roni profits.
Michael, come on!
You ain't gonna hold the DSS card
if you ain't gonna do right by me.
You're gonna let me hold that card.
You a hard child.
Next time, don't go selling
the food out of our mouths!
Yeah, like y'all say - don't lie, don't bunk,
don't cheat, don't steal or whatever.
But what about y'all, huh?
What, the government? With the Enron?
Steroids, yeah.
Liquor business?
Booze is the real killer out there.
And cigarettes? Oh, shit.
- You got some smokes in there?
- I'm trying to quit.
And drugs paid your salary, right?
- Not exactly but I get your point.
- We do the same as y'all,
except when we do it, it's like,
"These kids is animals."
Like it's the end of the world coming.
Man, that's bullshit, all right?
Cos it's like, what is it?
Hypocrite...hypocritical?
We got our thing
but it's just part of the big thing.
- Exactly.
- But this corner-boy thing, right?
All y'all did all this talking up in here.
Could you write down the laws to your thing?
- Hell, yeah. I'll do it right now.
- Shit.
No, can y'all do it together?
I give the test on fractions,
half the kids have breakdowns.
I have a lot of kids who can
barely handle whole numbers.
Well, if it's any comfort,
I have, outside of my advanced class,
maybe half a dozen reading at grade level.
Try the periodic table of elements.
Thing is, it's your curriculum
and you have to stick to it.
- I can't. It's absurd.
- You have to.
That test is the difference between
the state taking over the school or not.
- Maybe the state should.
- Mr. Withers...
You don't teach math, you teach the test.
This is about the leave-no-child-behind
stuff getting spoon-fed.
- And what do they learn?
- Find some middle ground.
Every day try to do a little for the statewide
and keep a problem on
the blackboard for Donnelly.
If she comes to visit,
she thinks you're on point.
The rest of the time,
do what you feel like you need to do.
But be careful.
You're still on your evaluation.
The first year isn't about the kids,
it's about you surviving.
Get up. Get up.
Hands on your head.
- I was eating that.
- Fuck you.
- That's my lunch.
Find a wall, motherfuckers. Man...
Pick your feet up.
- This is harassment.
- What did I say?
"Fuck you."
- That's what you said to me.
- There's nothing here, man.
- Oops. My bad.
- You want to play games with me?
I'm going to be in your shit every day
until my camera comes home.
You hear me? Every day.
You and yours. Let's go.
Ah. That felt good.
The old Western DEU rides again.
Yes, sir.
Anyone from the CID
report to the front desk.
Respectfully, sir, I would feel better if you
clear this through the chain of command.
Yes, sir.
I'll think about that.
- Problem with the bosses?
- One in particular.
- That was our mayor-to-be.
- Carcetti?
- Seriously?
- He wants to meet.
You and him? Alone?
He wants to talk about the police department.
What works, what doesn't.
You have the mayor's ear now.
- Look at you.
- Here's the thing. What do I say?
- What do you mean?
- How honest should I be?
It's one thing to talk tactical shit
or enforcement strategies,
but the shit that actually goes on?
If I start on that, I don't know if I can stop.
Cedric, this is your chance.
This is a career.
What if I take my shots at Burrell and Rawls
and he decides not to clean house?
The new mayor calls you up,
asks you for your take on things
- and you don't want to be, what, impolitic?
- Carcetti, I don't even know the man.
If he's calling you, it's because guys
like Burrell and Rawls are on the ropes.
- Maybe.
- I know there's a risk but...
baby, I'd fire away...
both barrels.
All white out here, man. Up top.
All white. All white.
You got that grub, you got that pot.
All white.
Shakin' and jiggin' it, yo.
Who made that track?
Yo, who you talking to, dawg?
I'm asking who Young Leek be.
- You mean Too Fat's cousin? Who?
- Nah.
- Then how the fuck should I know?
- Who the fuck is you...
Aw, shit. Nigger got smoked.
Fuck that nigger.
What up, B?
- Where Ma at?
- Upstairs.
Michael, my daddy came home.
- Daddy came home?
- Look who home.
Michael.
Damn, you grew.
And a pack of Kools for Macia.
Still tricking for that clown?
Why do people talk trash about him?
All I know is he loves me.
When you get tired of him going upside
your head, you'll really know who loves you.
Whatever.
Whoa.
Motherfucker, what?
- He had 12 years.
- Parole.
- It was only a drug charge.
- You swore he wasn't coming back.
This is a good thing, Michael.
It's going to be back the way it was.
The way it was?
We a family again.
You lied to me.
People change, Michael.
He said you can give him
the independence card too.
He gonna take care of all that for us.
Thanks for coming up from Washington.
We're happy for the opportunity.
You've got some heat behind you.
- But down to business.
- The way we see it,
we need a citywide turnaround.
Call it the "Baltimore Miracle" or some shit.
Starting with a 10% drop in crime.
That was your campaign cry,
you want the double digits.
No doubt.
Then he's gotta do a bricks and mortar,
put his name on something downtown.
We're flush with stadiums,
got hotels out of the ass.
You got a good convention center?
And an expansion.
Gotta get something on it that says
"Brought to you by Tommy Carcetti."
Think on it, but you don't have
too much time to decide.
- Anything else?
- Education always polls good.
Uh, no, not the schools.
Our last four administrations
left us with an inner-city system
with inner-city problems.
We get involved, start talking shit,
it becomes our mess.
Gotta respect the depths.
One, you get the drop in crime,
two, build something downtown
and three, stay away from schools.
And, four, keep your boyish good looks.
Do all that,
you might run for governor in 2008,
maybe take back that statehouse for us, hm?
- Can you get the square corners?
- Easy.
- I don't like these backgrounds.
- You don't?
They don't fit so good...
Shi...it. Next time, dude.
You OK?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Something at home?
- No.
- Come on.
- I said no.
OK.
If there's ever anything
you want to talk about...
there's me, but if you'd rather,
I can write you a pass
to see the social worker.
Just say when.
Michael, do you wanna see the social worker?
No.
I've never seen kids like them
this animated in a classroom.
Focused. The corner culture kids, at least.
The ones with deeper problems,
they opted out.
- Deeper problems?
- It's not just corner logic.
I see oppositional defiant disorders,
clinical depression, post-traumatic stress,
and, with Chandra,
borderline psychosis maybe.
With those problems,
we need a social worker here full-time.
But the corner kids, yeah,
they really came alive.
When they talk about what they know,
they stay on point.
Shit, they were even taking turns.
Can we get them in that kind of mindset
with stuff they don't know?
Have them learn on faith alone?
In all honesty, this is uncharted territory.
Where do you go from here?
How about we just let this ride,
see where it takes us?
All right, here's the thing -
once you got it, it's all you.
Anything happen,
I'm-a have to fuck you up.
Yeah, but that's nothing.
The guy trusting me on this, Marlo,
he'll kill you and your whole family.
So don't shake the bottles
cos Marlo weighs that shit.
- I ain't shaking shit.
- See that you don't,
cos if you fuck with them, I'm gonna know.
All right, that's good.
All right, it's good. All right,
you under 13 and shit.
So you safe from everybody
but me and Marlo.
- So I'm a lieutenant now?
- Yeah. You my lieutenant.
And alls I get is an extra $10?
You do this good and we'll talk.
See this guy here? That's the grand jury
prosecutor. Now, you lie to us,
it's just good clean fun.
But you tell tales
to that three-piece motherfucker, oh, shit!
I ain't telling lies.
Gary, let me ask you hypothetically,
how much time does a witness
get for lying to your grand jury?
- You kidding? As much as I can get him.
- What's the max?
- Ten years.
- Oh, people go away for ten years?
Oh, hell, yeah, all the time.
Ten years! I thought
he was gonna say two or three.
That motherfucker went upside my head.
I couldn't see straight.
- Which motherfucker?
- Then they got me on that medication.
It made me groggy as shit. Then this man
starts working at me. Was it him?
- Fuck I did!
- I mean, shit...
I'm still groggy now. I mean, I got to, uh...
Is there a washroom around?
Lying motherfucker.
For real?
Pull over, asshole.
Shit.
Step out of the car, please.
Step out of the car. Put your hands on the car.
Got anything on you?
Have a seat on the curb.
Cross your feet. Hands on your head.
- What the fuck is this powder?
- Lime for my mama's garden.
What, are you building a clubhouse?
- That shoot nails. Be cool.
- I know what it does.
I want my fucking camera.
I heard what you said
at Comstat the other day.
I also hear you're a commander
who knows police work.
- Nice of people to say.
- I did a ride-along in Eastern,
watched some street pops, undercover rips.
- So what am I thinking?
- My guess...
you witnessed a waste of time, money, energy
and, in a few cases, talent.
Rawls says it's Burrell's numbers game. Says
if I unleash him, all that bullshit goes south.
A return of high-end police work
and it'll be the dawning of a new day.
- Rawls said that?
- Yeah.
Says he's just following orders,
being a good soldier.
What do you say?
Mr. Mayor, if you want to talk about
what happens in the street or in the Western,
I'll talk your ear off. But I'm a soldier too.
I don't go up the chain with my opinions.
I can respect that.
I will say this though -
we did have one unit doing high-end stuff,
Major Crimes working out
of an offsite on Clinton Street.
"Did" is past tense. What wrecked it?
Good question, Mr. Mayor.
With Ray Foerster's passing, I need
a new CID commander right away.
Would you object to being
a colonel working under Rawls?
- Under Rawls?
- He is deputy ops, is he not?
Will the mayor make the changes
or leave it to the good soldier?
What I'm really asking is -
how for real are you?
Well, I guess we're going to
find that out together, aren't we...
Colonel Daniels?
What the fuck do we do?
- I don't know.
- These guys don't scare.
If we all kick in, you, me, Sydnor,
maybe we could afford a used camera?
I thought of that. It ain't gonna match
the serial numbers from the one from ISD.
We've gotta get wood on Marlo.
It's the only way.
This Randy kid,
he can't give us a murder, right?
Shit, he can't even give us a body.
But he says some Little Kevin kid
was the one supposed
to tell Lex to go up in that alley.
Plus, what did fucknut say Little Kev said?
"Lex went up the alley
but he ain't coming back."
Maybe he saw the whole thing.
Maybe he's our eyeball witness.
- Little Kevin.
80, 100, 10, 20. 420.
Where's the rest?
Um, I'm on a hard strip.
It's tricky on Lafayette.
- What the fuck are you doing there?
- I gotta build it up.
No, no, you ain't got to build up shit.
Your father built them corners
and they owe you cos they owe him.
Bodie got a real short memory
when it comes to giving props. Hm.
Ma...
I'm going to straighten this shit out right now.
Ma, let me build.
Ma.
Sir.
Bill...
We need to regroup.
Come up with something fresh
for the new administration.
Hm?
I don't mind telling you,
I'm uncomfortable with the way
Carcetti is running around in our shop...
He's talked to me, several times.
Huh.
You're making your move, huh?
We were a good team, you and me.
We were.
- Miss Ella, where Bug at?
- He went home, Michael.
Nah, he waits for me.
The man who picked him up
said he was his father.
And Bug said so, too.
Fuck!
Mm.
What the fuck did you do?
- And why'd you let him do it?
- Listen...
No. That's how you got him with his head up
his ass, unsolving his own fucking murders.
Your job is to turn red to black,
not the other way.
And you, stand the fuck up for yourself.
You don't gotta do the whole thing
on your fingers, little man. Look, first column.
- Six and six is...
- 12.
Put down the two, you bring over the one.
- Bug.
- Hey, big man.
- Get over to me now.
- We were going...
Now.
Yo, hold on.
Yo, you owe me 800 on that, bitch. You owe.