[knock on door]
[Doug] Tom.
[dog barking]
[Doug] Tom, you here?
[dog whines]
Tom!
[barking continuing]
[dog whimpering]
[woman on TV] Sources say
that the FBI was made aware
of the evidence linking the vice president
and a number of cabinet secretaries
with several senior
Russian government officials.
Meanwhile, President Underwood,
who has still not commented on the matter,
in what could be construed as an attempt
to distance herself
and her administration
from the apparent collusion,
has fired all the accused
cabinet secretaries,
making way for the first-ever
all-female cabinet in US history.
[clicks]
Not one, not two,
but threeabortions.
The third oneat 16 weeks.
Think about it.
That's not a few cells
or a collection of cells.
It's more like four and a half inches long
and three and a half ounces. At 16 weeks,
the president's baby
would have been the size...
of this.
My fellow Americans,
there are certain parties out there
that hope to use my private life
for political gain.
I'm going to say this exactly once.
For many years, my late husband and I
tried to start a family.
I downplayed that fact
in the past because...
Well, it's a painful subject.
When I finally became pregnant,
the baby wasn't viable,
and the pregnancy had to be terminated.
End of story.
The baby was viable.
Francis and I, as parents,
were not.
So, let me be clear.
This is the last
I will ever say on this subject.
Okay.
[men and women shouting]
I am so proud of every person
around this table.
Each of them has served this country
with honor
and distinction.
Some as deputy secretaries.
They are all accomplished Americans
and members
of their respective departments.
But I'll let them speak for themselves.
Hello, my name is Jennifer Baumgarten,
and I am the acting Attorney General
of the United States.
Jenny's going to come in very handy.
[Jennifer] And as far
as the Justice Department is concerned,
I share the president's commitment
to cleaning house.
[man] But isn't it customary
for the vice president
to attend all cabinet meetings?
Not necessarily, no.
Listen, ever since I joined
the Underwood administration,
the president and I have worked together
on a daily basis.
Hand in glove. That's the way we work.
Is it true that you were asked to resign?
What? No.
No.
And the Russians and me,
it's preposterous.
Look, the president and I agree
the best way to find out
who's behind these accusations
is to appoint a special prosecutor.
And let him or her do her job.
- Thanks very much.
- [man] One more question, one question!
Mr. Vice President, one question.
One more question!
Mr. Vice President!
Mr. Vice President, one question,
one more question!
Okay. Great. Thank you. Great.
Okay, good. Thanks, thanks. Bye.
Did she find him?
Tom.
- Did she find him?
- No.
Front door was open.
Dog's not there. No one was there.
Okay, Tom, I am so sorry.
I felt like I had no other option.
I mean, I swear,
- I saw someone inside your...
- No, I know. I know.
We can go circle back
and take another look if you want, but...
That doesn't sound like a good idea.
[machine whirring]
[woman] That's your fax.
Great. How much is that?
$1.90 for the first page,
$1.25 for each additional.
And it looks like you've got
quite a few additionals coming in.
But can I just...
Let me just figure out
how much it's gonna cost.
Oh. That's more than enough.
Yeah, thank you.
[printer beep]
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- You bet.
[whirring] [machine beeping]
[beep]
"102.7."
Why did you send the nurse away?
Because she needed to eat.
And I feel fine.
- I find this anything but fine.
- No, no, look...
This fever's good.
I don't think it's supposed
to last this long.
Do you want me to change the sheets?
[sighs]
What's the point?
You know, I support you no matter what.
Whatever you want to try,
but this is...
Research is very good.
Proven effective in Europe.
Do you remember
how dad used to make me
wear long sleeves at dinner?
Do you miss them?
Her, not him.
He was always so sure about what was right.
Mom's doubt actually allowed her
to deepen as time went by.
Depth is overrated.
Do you want to cancel tomorrow?
We can't cancel.
What's wrong, Annie?
Annie? [sighs]
I keep calling Duncan.
And I've heard nothing,
and he still hasn't gone home.
You knew he was gonna find out someday.
Maybe it's for the best.
[man] If you're hungry or thirsty...
[Jane] Angry. Tired. Frustrated.
I should've been debriefed by now.
Again, if you need water
or a cup of coffee...
This is ridiculous.
- [knock on door]
- Excuse me.
[sighs]
No visible scars.
I assume you've been looked at
by a physician.
It's protocol.
So is talking with a senior member
of the Agency.
That won't be happening today.
You're essentially burnt
when it comes to your work
with any of the agencies.
That's the term, isn't it, burnt?
Not necessarily.
Virtually always.
Nobody knows what you said or didn't say
while in captivity.
I didn't say, Claire.
Madam President.
Oh, and have you heard about Mark?
He's made quite a spectacle of himself.
I don't know how much longer
I can keep my voice out of it.
I guess he thought
he could come out from under it.
Yes. Well, the people that know us best,
know best how to hurt us.
President Underwood... Actually,
I've gone back to "Hale."
You're wrong if you think I have...
You are foolish
if you don't tell me what it is.
Guess which kind of people
I'm done suffering, Jane.
You were wise to come.
I told you and I'll tell them.
I don't want the job.
[Seth sighs]
Doug, just promise you'll hear them out
before you do anything.
And just so you're aware,
Bill's not shaking hands at the moment.
[Brett laughs] Doug. May I introduce you?
Annette and Bill Shepherd.
[Annette] Hello.
You remember Fred Amburg.
Doug, for the record,
I really enjoyed our conversations
in the facility.
Oh, come on, man.
All roads lead to Rome, you know?
And Annette and Bill are Rome.
Come. Sit down, please, Mr. Stamper.
[Bill] These guys were just leaving.
[Brett] Well, Mr. Shepherd,
- Annette.
- Brett.
[Fred] Talk soon, Bill.
- Fred.
- Annette.
[Bill]
Frank spoke very highly of you, Doug.
You cold?
I can have 'em switch off the AC.
Humidity in this town, my God,
makes you feel like you're living
inside the mouth of a dog, doesn't it?
Frederic Gustav Amburg
is my very best friend
over 52 years.
We've traded marbles,
stocks...
a fiancée once upon a time.
Please.
You're making me nervous standing there.
[Bill] Oh, Jesus Christ. Get over it.
You should consider yourself lucky
you had Fred to talk to in there.
You're like the guy who
finds $999,000 and says "Yeah,
but it isn't a million."
Brett Cole will be the speaker.
Next in line, if you don't count Mark.
[Bill]
We've gotta get this woman outta there!
Mr. Stamper,
my brother gets a little impatient
when it comes to the president.
We know we share a common enemy in her.
Whatever he left you must be damning.
We know that much.
Frank knew
you were the only other man who truly knew
what his wife was capable of.
The only one he could trust
to do the right thing when the time came.
Unless, Frank was wrong about you.
[Bill] A letter opener.
What does that mean?
How did you get your hands on the will?
[Annette] It's called reach.
You see, the thing is,
whatever brings her down,
could bring Francis down, as well.
Now you listen to me.
Frank was a hell of a guy.
We were going to accomplish
great things together.
[Bill] But this is too damn important
for the future of this country.
A future that includes you.
The past is just that.
Hold on a second.
Do you work for the brother or the sister?
The family.
She's not that fond of you.
I wanted you to know.
What? That I was working for them
all along?
One way or another,
Francis got both of us hired.
We know you've been meeting
with Tom Hammerschmidt.
You need to stay away
from him for a while.
God, this thing takes forever.
I have done nothing wrong.
And I'll tell you something,
I am going to expose her.
[Jane] And yourself.
And then where will you be?
- You're not thinking, Mark.
- What happened?
Did she get to you? She got to you,
is that what you're saying?
I'm saying something's changed
in those steely blue eyes of hers.
Walk away.
My recommendation is walk away
from this shit show.
No. I'm not doing that.
You never even wanted this.
And now you're willing
to fight to the death for it?
Who said anything about "the death?"
Fuck her, Jane. Fuck!
Fuck her.
[Mark sighs, panting]
Forgive me,
but why is your timing always off?
I tried to get you out.
Out.
What a quaint concept.
When the only way out
was never to get in in the first place.
- I swore. I swore.
- Ow!
I swore I would never set foot
in this house again.
What the hell are you doing here?
The optics are awful, Mark.
I mean, really.
It's the only place I feel safe.
[Claire] That looks lovely.
I don't blame her for choosing it.
And that blue-green color,
it's so specific to the French Alps.
Azure, yes, azure.
Well, of course
our little tariff agreement
caused some consternation, Viktor,
but I don't regret it.
Tell me you don't, either.
[laughs]
Right now?
Nothing, really.
Just planning for the future.
Out with the old.
[Mark] Yeah.
And exactly who the fuck was
Jennifer Baumgarten 72 hours ago?
Because I want you to push
for a special prosecutor.
Or... Well, hearings then.
Because it will if you...
Mitch, don't give me that.
[TV news program playing in the background]
It will if you do.
Because I was a Republican a lot longer
than I was a Democrat. You know it.
- Listen to me, Mitch...
- [Cruz] Considering the latest revelations
regarding the vice president,
there's no denying it.
These are serious allegations
that cannot be ignored.
And something tells me
this is just the tip of the iceberg.
I mean, how deep does this go?
- What? I'll call you back.
- And to what end?
- We deserve to know. Look...
- 'Cause I need to call you back.
...people want to associate me
with one party or another.
I'm simply an American
when it comes to values,
way of life.
You have Ms. Stewart meeting
with Tom Yates
in the vice president's home.
Tom Yates, who we now know was someone
the Russians were very interested in.
And now you have the vice president
holed up in that safe house,
- assuring us that everything is...
- Every news outlet is asking for comment.
It doesn't take a genius to realize...
It's terrible how people live
to see others fail.
It's going to be hard for me
to continue here in any capacity.
On the contrary, Kelsey,
I am naming you
my permanent press secretary.
- Ma'am, I ca... I...
- I'm going to announce it
the next time I take questions.
For the time being, though, I think
I should handle the daily press briefings.
I feel like I need
to give them a little face time.
You don't understand, I can't...
I will let you know
when you need to speak.
Don't worry.
We'll get through this together.
Listen, I saw this in my closet today.
And I thought of you.
I want you to have it.
[stammers, sighs]
Tom was looking to move back to New York.
We would have coffee,
the occasional dinner.
He told me he was involved with somebody
he couldn't get away from.
That it was killing him.
I can't think about it.
I won't think about it.
What to do about Kelsey?
I mean, look at that face.
Enjoy the bag.
[Mark] Oh, hi.
So what Melody Cruz just said on the air,
that was your son, I'm guessing.
You need to talk to him or I will.
- Keep your voice down. Bill's resting.
- Where is Duncan?
- Not here.
- Bill. Bill Shepard.
Won't be seeing you today.
[Annette sighs]
Still wearing it?
Why are you allowing me to be gutted?
- Gutted?
- Yes, gutted.
Gutted, gutted.
I told Melody Cruz to run the piece.
I have been nothing but loyal to you.
The press secretary was in your house
- with Tom Yates.
- Oh, my God. Come on.
Even if there isn't an ounce
of truth to it.
Mark, you're the face
of this whole Russia fiasco.
It's bad for the country.
It's bad for Bill and me.
You need to get rid of it.
Burn your house down, if you have to.
Anything that connects you to the story
and get a hold of yourself.
[Claire] How's the Bureau feeling
about the latest revelations
when it comes to Mark Usher?
It's difficult when all the evidence
is coming from Russian intelligence.
But we have to follow every lead.
To be honest, ma'am,
the vice president
is well-liked around town.
Yes, but we're talking about
very serious crimes here, Nathan.
Yes, ma'am.
So, tell me,
once Doug knew you were listening in...
He's been operating pretty much
in plain sight.
He tried to meet with Tom Hammerschmidt.
Again?
And he met with Bill and Annette Shepherd
at the Hay-Adams.
Also, he returned to his apartment
with a canine.
Doug has a dog?
There's one in his apartment.
Another thing that caught my attention
was the two men we have following
Doug's psychiatrist
from the facility contacted me.
Seems Dr. Rosen was pretty shaken up.
He said he blacked out and fell down.
But I mean, it doesn't make any sense...
- You sound very distracted, Nathan.
- Excuse me.
I don't know if it's the lack of sleep
because of the night feedings,
but I wonder if you're still capable
of doing the job that I expect of you.
I promise you, ma'am, I'm fully capable
of executing my duties.
Boy or girl?
- Oh. A boy.
- Oh. I'm so happy for you, Nathan.
They do say second marriages are the best.
[Claire sighs]
What time is it?
[Annette] Don't worry about it.
- Are you okay?
- [mutters]
Can I check your temperature?
[Bill] No.
Every time I wake up,
you people put your hands all over me.
When I went to bed, I was 53 years old.
I don't know how old I am.
Was Mark here?
I heard these voices,
I was going in and out.
- Seth!
- Bill,
- maybe you should go back to your room.
- No, I'm not dead yet.
- [door opens]
- Was he here?
- Yes, but...
- Okay. Well, where is Ms. Skorsky?
We have people looking for her.
We're fairly sure she's still
in the DC area.
But what does she have?
We now know that Ray Meyers
was faxing some kind of document
- to a copy shop here in the city.
- [Bill sighs]
- And anything from your Doug Stamper?
- No, sir.
Bill, please, you're still feverish.
[sighs] Can you give us a minute?
Of course.
Where is he?
[Doug] He's safe.
Which is more than I can say for you.
You know, at times I can't tell
if you're making a threat
or offering help.
Why is Seth Grayson looking
for Janine Skorsky?
I'm assuming the men who turned your place
upside down were looking for her.
She's working on an article.
But she'll have to find
someplace else to publish.
Her newspaper was bought by the Shepherds.
- [dog barks over the phone]
- We still need to meet, Tom.
Yeah.
And, Doug,
you lay a hand on that innocent animal,
and I swear to Christ,
I'll beat the living shit out of you.
Your dog's fine.
[beep]
Seth?
I know you look up to my brother.
And you've been very attentive.
But he's not well, okay?
And from this moment on,
any information you think he needs,
I need to hear it first.
I understand.
He will recover.
Thank you for saying that.
Doug Stamper doesn't like
to be told what to do.
[chuckles]
It only works if he thinks it's his idea.
Listen,
it may be none of my business,
but I haven't been able to reach Duncan
since he received a package
from the White House.
I don't know what it was.
But he was very upset.
Thank you.
You're right.
That's none of your business.
I urged him. Believe me.
I urged him to resign, but he listens
to me half the time, at best.
I need you to understand.
I don't want to hurt Mark again.
There was a troubled young woman...
I wonder why so many stories
have to begin that way.
I know. I know. I hate this story.
I hate that I'm telling you.
I'm tired
of the disposable girl story.
She started as a volunteer
on Brett Cole's first campaign.
Mark and I were consulting.
Brett's wife was as pregnant as could be.
And the troubled young woman
wouldn't leave him alone.
Well, that's how Brett characterized it.
Did he encourage her attention?
Enjoy it?
You bet he did.
He's a man with a man's ego.
Anyway, of course it became a mess
in all the ways these stories do.
And suddenly,
it was Mark's job to clean it up.
He leaned on her too hard.
Badgered and berated her.
"You're ruining Brett's future.
You better disappear."
And so she did.
She jumped off the Roosevelt Bridge.
It fucked with Mark's head, Claire.
He lost his nerve after that. He...
He started to question everything.
Everything.
I'm sorry.
I'm... I mean, this is not me.
Jane.
You're saving him, you know that, right?
Now, tell me the truth.
Did you help Cathy get away?
The FSB have been very helpful,
so you know.
They're very close to locating Cathy.
I've noticed that you always
adjust your hair
right before you tell a lie.
I want you to know I forgive you.
She wants to try and impeach me?
Be my guest, I cannot wait.
They hate her, you know.
The House, all the Senators,
they hate her guts.
By the time this thing is over,
she'll be begging me to...
[Jane] Don't do this.
Everything I've done for that ungrateful...
Don't let this happen again.
I didn't take proper care of you.
As a friend.
Machiavelli died in exile.
Boss Tweed made a deal with the governor,
but in the end, was never released.
Where are you, Jane?
And Nixon was a prisoner of his past
till the day he died.
All men who had no idea how to walk away.
I am still in possession of his body,
and I'll use it, if I have to.
Oh, God.
[sobbing]
No matter what you hear,
I was trying to help you.
[birds chirping]
Jane.
- [Doug] It's around the back.
- You did good.
What is it?
What does she have?
You don't have
to concern yourself with that.
I delivered her, didn't I?
Whatever Janine Skorsky has
will never see the light of day.
She has no right to it.
And her source will be singing
a different tune
when he sees the jail time
he's looking at.
[scoffs] Listen to you, Mr. Grayson.
By the way, what's your title?
Vice president of research and outreach
for the Shepherd Freedom Foundation.
You're like a starfish, Seth.
Your legs grow back.
[Doug clears throat]
Here's her article.
- And the emails?
- There's a copy attached.
Seth's on his way.
And Janine says thank you
for the head's up.
He'll bring the cavalry.
Calamity Janine can handle herself.
My dog?
All right, then.
Did you kill Rachel?
I need to hear you say it.
You need it for yourself.
I did.
But you won't find her.
No one will.
Turn yourself in.
Take me.
Point me in the direction
where you left her.
There are people who cared for her.
I cared for her.
Did Francis kill Zoe?
Tell me if Francis killed Zoe.
Is this still off the record?
Will it be enough for you
to know the truth?
Because you're never
gonna be able to prove it.
Tom, it has to be enough, or I walk away.
- No. Someone has to answer...
- Jesus Christ, he's dead.
But her...
You said it yourself,
she's as guilty as he is.
I'm saying, maybe more.
Maybe he did it all for her.
What d'you got?
Do we have an agreement?
I give you the truth,
and you leave him out of it.
I can't do that.
[scoffs]
It's not a just world, Tom.
But sometimes you have the chance
to make the right person pay,
even if it's for the wrong crime.
Is that enough for you?
Because if it's not, I respect you,
and we can say goodbye.
- No, Doug. It's not enough for me.
- Tom.
- And I do not agree!
I am never going to tell you
that Francis killed the three of them,
Zoe, Russo
and LeAnn.
But you already know the truth.
Yes.
Yes, I do.
On the record.
From here.
What did she do?
[Seth] Ms. Skorsky.
Members of the US Attorney
Cyber Task Force are on their way.
I'm giving you a chance.
And I'm giving you a chance
to go on the record.
Emails or any correspondence
written while at Arcas Refinery
or any subsidiary of Shepherd Unlimited
are the sole property
of Bill and Annette Shepherd.
Were Bill and Annette Shepherd aware
of the possibility that workers might die
at the Arcas plant?
Get that outta my face.
We know what Ray Meyers sent you.
Did you use the Arcas accident
to get the citizens of Bellport
to sign up for this app?
An app that you helped develop
for the Shepherd Freedom Foundation?
Ms. Skorsky,
they're about to confiscate your computer
and any devices.
You can take it right now.
You're not gonna find anything here.
I knew you were coming, Mr. Grayson.
[Nathan] Doug.
I'm ready to see the president.
[Claire] You expect a person
to be true to his character.
You're so careful. You're so good
about cleaning up after yourself.
Why didn't you just get rid of him?
Well, Francis wanted it otherwise.
I was so hoping you'd surprise me.
What are you gonna do, Mark?
You gonna pull out the body,
drape it over the tombstone?
Gelsemium is known to be used
by Russian intelligence.
I want you out of my house.
But from what I understand,
you're pretty much a murderer anyway.
You don't normally make mistakes, do you?
But when you do,
they are something.
Was there some hope in you
that the troubled young woman
would do herself in?
That Congressman Cole
would be relieved somehow.
I'd like you
to get out of my house, Claire.
It's important to be
organized and ruthless.
Three piles, I always say.
The stuff you wanna keep.
The stuff you might need later
that you put in storage.
And the stuff you have to destroy.
- [line trills, click]
- [Jane sighs over phone]
- Jane, it's me.
- I'm so sorry.
Hey, hey.
I don't care that you told her.
You hear me? I don't care.
I have the worst migraine
of my life.
Jane.
Jane, are you okay?
[groaning]
Are you okay?
Jane.
[groans]
[sighs]
I almost forgot.
There's always a fourth pile.
The stuff you don't know what to do with.
Can I get you some water?
Something stronger, maybe?
No, thank you. But don't let me stop you.
I take a month off drinking,
come every Labor Day.
Kind of an academic calendar ritual
to prove to myself
I'm not actually an alcoholic.
[laughs] I'm actually abstaining myself,
at the moment.
For pursuit of...
clarity, I guess.
Would you like to sit down?
Sure.
[Claire sighs]
He's crazy.
Certifiable. You know that, right?
Doug got out of a psychiatric facility
all of a month and a half ago.
And no matter how hard he tries
to revive his political career
or get back in the game...
He's a delusional liar.
And to tell you the truth,
maybe he was a better wife to Francis.
Which is why he was never able
to see things clearly.
I mean, what did he tell you, Tom?
What do you think he told me
that you don't want me to know?
Oh, boy. The fantasies
he must have reported to you.
You need to pity him.
You really do. I do.
Madam President, this type of intrusion
- into a civilian's home...
- Listen, there's no denying
that Francis was a desperate man
who did,
yes, a lot of desperate things.
And I don't know. Maybe towards the end,
he was slightly deranged.
But whatever he did, he did alone.
I was not complicit.
[sighs] And do you...
Do you remember the last interview
you did with my husband?
And the conversation ended
where he asked you if you'd believed
what he'd told you.
Do you remember how you responded, Tom?
I do.
I said, "Not for a second."
Madam President,
when it comes to your complicity,
I think it's best if we meet
under more formal circumstances.
I'll be sending over a list of questions
to your press office.
You can answer them by mail, email.
Or if you prefer,
face-to-face and on the record.
[door opens]
[closes]
[Annette] Hi.
How many years did she clean up after you?
My mother, the housekeeper.
From the second I saw you, Duncan.
Your beautiful little scrunched up face.
Like an old man.
I just knew. It was instant.
We just belonged,
we belonged, we did.
Why didn't you legally adopt me?
I guess, because I didn't have to.
And my father?
Was it...
Oh, no, no, no.
A one night stand.
She...
said she didn't remember his name.
I went to see her.
My birth mother.
She lives not more than
half an hour from here.
Did you know that?
Did you talk to her?
Couldn't.
I couldn't do that to her.
I just...
I just watched her.
How could she let...
I knew I could take care of you.
I knew she couldn't.
If not now,
I hope you can forgive me.
You okay, Duncan?
Help me, Bill.
Who your real parents were,
where they came from...
I never cared about any of that.
Because...
Well, you know why.
[Annette] Say it.
Who he is, Bill.
I don't need this.
Stay where you are.
- No.
- Duncan,
if you and I are to have any chance,
you need to stay right here.
Bill, say it.
Who he is to you. To me.
Honey...
Who is he, goddamn it?
He's not one of us.
You're a coward.
Letting Claire Hale say it for you.
Well, I hope you die.
Let's go. Now!
[Doug] The email links
to corporate minutes that clearly indicate
a foreknowledge of hazard
that resulted in catastrophic harm
and loss of life.
In attendance and party to consent
of the corporate policy
was the entity's chief executive officer
William Shepherd.
Arcas Refinery is liable.
As is Shepherd Unlimited.
The corporation and Bill Shepherd himself
can be charged
with involuntary manslaughter.
Expose him as a murderer
and cost him billions in the process.
Is Ms. Skorsky publishing?
Hmm. I made sure of it.
It's a better story once you arrest him.
And the article will justify the arrest.
We can get some lawyers in here and delay,
at the very least.
No.
Then we can make sure
they walk you out the back.
No, no, no.
No, no. I want the cuffs.
President's gone too far this time.
I want the whole world to see.
And my sister?
You could've handed me this anywhere,
why here?
Seemed appropriate.
You never struck me as nostalgic, Doug.
Could this be
about the posthumous pardoning
you've been imagining for Francis?
You don't belong here.
I sometimes worry about your imagination.
Your slavish devotion.
You can't think beyond him. Not really.
I can imagine you not
in the White House quite clearly.
Oh, my goodness.
You keep saying things like that,
I might not be able to let you leave.
What did you do with it?
The will.
Did you burn it?
He left me everything.
You know it, and I know it.
[yawns] Excuse me.
I get sleepy so early these days.
Oh.
I'm not going to be told
what to do anymore, Doug.
Not by you or anyone or any man,
ever, ever again.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
- Won't be long.
- Whatever.
Turn.
Sit, sit.
Good boy, listen.
- Get down, below the counter.
- Okay, okay.
You do exactly
like I told you before, okay?
Remember, it's all about having fun,
remember?
You be a good boy.
It's gonna be all right.
- Just have fun, alright?
- [dog whines]
Okay. [pants]
[gunshot echoes]
[gunshot fires]
[man on TV]
And in breaking news just in,
we are sad to report that one
of the Washington Herald's
most accomplished journalists and editors
Tom Hammerschmidt
was pronounced dead at the scene
of a robbery gone terribly wrong.
The White House was quick to comment,
as the president had sat down
with the award-winning Hammerschmidt
for an interview only hours before.
Along with her condolences,
the president used the opportunity
to call for greater gun control,
particularly in our inner cities.
Fuck!
[Claire] The last thing he gave you.
If you don't tell me what it means...
[Doug] I was kind of hoping
you could tell me, Claire.
Doug, Tom Hammerschmidt is dead.
Cathy, Jane.
Bill Shepherd is going to prison.
Mark has no one to turn to.
It's just you and me.
Gimme a moment, please.
[retches, coughs]
[hinges squeak, door closes]
Please know. [sighs]
The thought of accelerating the exit
of three poor souls from this earth
is beyond painful.
[gags, gasps] [clears throat]
Sorry about that.
Not at all.
I'm not worried about you anymore, Doug.
You wouldn't do anything to hurt Francis.
You're not capable.
And see, the thing is...
whatever Francis left you,
it doesn't actually belong to you.
We entered our marriage with a his,
hers and ours agreement.
You keep
and do whatever you want with yours,
I keep and do whatever I want with mine.
My daddy and mother insisted,
as you can imagine.
But the prenup we had, had a clause.
If ever we have descendants together
and one of us is first to die,
we agree to waive our rights
to everything passed on.
By which I mean,
all of Francis's assets
are entitled to his heir.
If he should have one.