Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations lived
together in harmony
Then, everthing changed when
the Fire Nation attacked
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them
but when the world needed him most,
he vanished
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar
an Airbender named Aang
and although his airbending
skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before he's ready
to save anyone
but I believe..
Aang can save the world
Subtitles by .:: a b e j o e ::.
Fixed by LEO33
Aang?
Do you wanna talk about it?
Naah.. just a nightmare
I was in the Avatar State
But I was outside my body
watching myself
It was scary
I was scary
Kitara, I want you to have this
This amulet contains water from
the Spirit Oasis
The water has unique properties
Don't lose it
Thank you Master Pakku
Aang, these scrolls will help you
master waterbending
But remember,
there are no substitutes
for a real master.
Sokka
Take care son.
Fly straight to the Earth Kingdom
based to the east of here
General Fong will provide you with
an escort to Omashu
There you'll be safe
to begin your earthbending
training with King Bumi
Appa, yip yip!
Say hi to Gran Gran for me!
Aahh..
This is what I've been missing
Who knew floating on a piece of a driftwood
for 3 weeks with no food or water..
And sea vultures waiting to pluck out
your liver could make one so tense?
I see
It's the anniversary isn't it?
3 years ago today I was banished
I lost it all
I want it back!
I want the Avatar,
I want my honor, my throne!
I want my father not to
think I'm worthless.
I'm sure he doesn't.
Why would he banish you
if he didn't care?
Urgh.. that came out wrong didn't it?
My brother and my uncle has
disgraced the Fire Lord
and brought shame on all of us.
You may have mixed feeling about
attacking members of the royal family
I understand. But I assure you..
If u hesitate, I will not hesitate
to bring you down.
Dismissed.
Princess, I'm afraid the tide will not allow us
to bring the ship into port before nightfall.
I'm sorry Captain, but I do not know
much about the tides
Can you explain something to me?
Of course, your Highness
Do the tides command this ship?
I'm afraid I don't understand.
You said the tides would not allow us
to bring this ship in.
Do the tides command this ship?
No, Princess.
And if I would have you thrown overboard
Would the tides think twice about
smashing you against the rocky shore?
No, Princess
Well then, maybe you should worry less
about the tides if they're already made up
their mind about killing you,
and worry more about me,
who's still mulling it over.
I'll pull us in.
There it is!
Welcome, Avatar Aang.
I am General Fong.
And welcome to all of u, great heroes.
Appa, Momo, brave Sokka,
the mighty Katara.
"Mighty Katara"?
I liked that.
Not bad, not bad.
Avatar Aang, we were all amazed at the
stories of how you single handedly
wiped out an entire Fire Navy fleet
at the North Pole.
I can't imagine what it feels like
to wield such devastating power.
It's an awesome responsibility.
I tried not to think
about it too much.
Avatar, you're ready
to face the Fire Lord now.
What? No I'm not!
Aang still needs to master all
four elements.
Why? With the kind of power he possesses,
power enough to destroy hundreds
of battleships in a matter of minutes,
he could defeat the Fire Lord now!
But, sir, the thing is, Aang can only
do those things when he's in Avatar State.
See, it's a special state where..
I'm well aware
Your eyes and tattoos glow,
and you're able to summon
unbelievable power
Without you we'd be slaughtered
before we even reach their shores.
But with you leading the way,
as the ultimate weapon,
we could cut us warf right through
to the heart of the Fire Nation.
Right, but, I don't know how to
get in or out of the Avatar State.
Much less what to do
once I'm there.
So it's decided then
I'll help you figure out how to
get into the Avatar State
and then you'll face your destiny.
No, nothing's decided.
We already have a plan.
Aang's pursuing his destiny his way.
Well, while you take your time
learning the elements,
the war goes on.
May I show you something?
That's the infirmary,
and those soldiers
are the lucky ones...
they came back.
Everyday the Fire Nation takes lives,
people are dying Aang!
You could end it, now.
Think about it.
Almost perfect.
One hair out of place.
Almost isn't good enough.
General Fong?
Come in, Aang.
Have you thought about our discussion?
L'm in.
L'll fight the Fire Lord.
L told the General l'd help him
by going into the Avatar State.
Aang, no.
This is not the right way.
Why not? Remember when
he took out the Fire Navy?
He was incredible.
There's a right
way to do this...
practice, study and discipline.
Or just glow it up and
stop that Fire Lord.
Lf you two meatheads want to throw away
everything we've worked for,
Fine. Go ahead and glow it up.
Katara, l'm just being realistic.
L don't have time to
do this the right way.
This rare chi-enhancing
tea is a natural stimulant.
Ln an ordinary warrior,
it improves strength and energy tenfold.
Ln you, it may induce the Avatar State.
Tenfold energy, huh?
Ls it working? ls it working?
L can't tell! Somebody tell me
if l'm in the Avatar State
'cause l don't have
a good view of myself.
Am l talking too loud?
L guess he could talk
the Fire Lord to death.
Ooh!
Maybe l can shock yo
u into the Avatar State.
L love surprises.
(shrieking)
(yells)
Still not glowing.
Uh... Uh... Ahh!
You are wearing a
ceremonial piece of clothing
from each of the bending nations.
Now, l will join the
four elements into one!
Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air...
Four elements together as one!
This is just mud.
So, do you feel anything?
(sneezes)
We have to find a way.
Look at these magnificent shells.
L'll enjoy these keepsakes
for years to come.
We don't need any more useless things.
You forget, we have to carry
everything ourselves now.
Hello, brother.
Uncle.
What are you doing here?
Ln my country, we
exchange a pleasant 'hello'
before asking questions.
Have you become
uncivilized so soon, Zuzu?
Don't call me that!
To what do we owe this honor?
Hmm. Must be a family trait.
Both of you so quick
to get to the point.
L've come
with a message from home.
Father's changed his mind.
Family is suddenly
very important to him.
He's heard rumors of
plans to overthrow him,
treacherous plots.
Family are the only ones
you can really trust.
Father regrets your banishment.
He wants you home.
Did you hear me?
You should be happy.
Excited. Grateful.
L just gave you great news.
L'm sure your brother
simply needs a moment to...
Don't interrupt, Uncle!
L still haven't heard my thank you.
L'm not a messenger.
L didn't have to come all this way.
Father regrets?
He... wants me back?
L can see you need time to take this in.
L'll come to call on you tomorrow.
Good evening.
KATARA: Can we talk about something?
AANG: Sure.
Do you remember when we
were at the Air Templee
and you found Monk Gyatso's skeleton?
Lt must have been so
horrible and traumatic for you.
L saw you get so upset that
you weren't even you anymore.
L'm not saying the
Avatar State doesn't have
incredible- and
helpful- power,
but you have to understand,
for the people who love you,
watching you be in
that much rage and pain
is really scary.
L'm really glad you told me that.
But l still need to do this.
L don't understand.
No, you don't.
Every day more and more people die.
L'm already a hundred years late.
Defeating the Fire Lord
is the only way to stop this war.
L have to try it.
L can't watch you do this to yourself.
L'm not coming tomorrow.
Good night.
ZUKO: We're going home.
After three long years.
Lt's unbelievable.
Lt is unbelievable.
L have never known my
brother to regret anything.
Did you listen to Azula?
Father's realized how
important family is to him.
He cares about me.
L care about you.
And if Ozai wants you back,
well, l think it may not
be for the reasons
you imagine.
You don't know how my
father feels about me.
You don't know anything.
Zuko, l only meant that, in our family,
things are not always what they seem.
L think you are
exactly what you seem...
a lazy, mistrustful, shallow old man
who's always been
jealous of his brother.
(yells)
(gasps)
Sokka, Sokka, wake up.
Huh?
L don't think we should be trying
to bring on the Avatar State.
You sure? Yes.
Okay.
Do you think the General will be mad?
What can he say?
You're the Avatar.
Who knows better than you?
Wait. Don't leave without me.
Uncle, you've changed your mind.
Family sticks together, right?
We're finally going home.
AANG: The
thing is...
l don't think we'll ever be
able to trigger it on purpose.
So l guess that's it.
Sure l can't change your mind?
L'm sure.
L can only reach the Avatar State
when l'm in genuine danger.
L see.
L was afraid you'd say that.
Aang!
(yelling)
Men, attack the Avatar!
What are you doing?
L believe we are about to get results.
L'm not your enemy.
L won't fight you.
You can't run forever.
You can't fight forever.
Brother, Uncle...
Welcome.
L'm so glad you decided to come.
Are we ready to depart, Your Highness?
Set our course for home, Captain.
Home.
You heard the Princess.
Raise the anchors.
We're taking the prisoners home.
Your Highness, l...
You lied to me.
Like l've never done that before.
(yelling)
l wonder what crazy
thing they're trying now.
(rumbling)
Maybe we should just
make sure Aang's okay.
What's going on?
The General's gone crazy.
He's trying to force Aang
into the Avatar State.
Good bird-horse thingie.
(roaring)
Maybe you can avoid me, but she can't.
(yells)
(grunts)
l can't move.
Don't hurt her.
) (yells
Katara, no!
Stop this.
You have to let her go.
You could save her if you
were in the Avatar State.
L'm trying. l'm trying!
Aang, l'm sinking.
L don't see glowing.
(screaming)
Please!
You don't need to do this!
Apparently...
l do.
Lt worked.
Lt worked!
(yells)
Zuko, let's go!
You know, Father blames Uncle
for the loss at the North Pole.
And he considers you
a miserable failure
for not finding the Avatar.
Why would he want you back home
except to lock you up
where you can no longer embarrass him?
(grunting)
(yells)
Avatar Aang,
can you hear me?
Your friend is safe.
Lt was just a trick
to trigger the Avatar State.
And it worked!
Lt's time you learned.
The Avatar State is
a defense mechanism
designed to empower you
with the skills and knowledge
of all the first Avatars.
The glow is the combination
of all your past lives
focusing their energy
through your body.
Ln the Avatar State,
you're at your most powerful...
but you're also at
your most vulnerable.
What do you mean?
Lf you are killed in the Avatar State,
the reincarnation cycle will be broken
and the Avatar will cease to exist.
L'm sorry, Katara.
L hope you never have to
see me like that again.
Ha. Are you joking?
That was almost perfect.
We just have to find out a way
to control you when you're like that.
You're out of your mind.
L guess we'll figure it out
on the way to the Fire Nation.
Anybody got a problem with that?
Do you still want an escort to Omashu?
L think we're all set.
Anyone who harbors these traitors
will face the wrath of the Fire Lord.
(gasps)
There will be no place left to hide.
(panting)
l think we 're safe here.
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk