Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony
then everything changed
when the firenation attacked
Only the avatar mastered
all four elements could stop them
but when the world needed
him most he vanished
100 years passed, my brother
and I discovered the new avatar
an airbinder named Aang
And although his airbinding
skill is great,
he has a lot to learn before
he is ready to save anyone.
But I believe...
... Aang can save the world
Appa is missing.
We hope to find him in Ba-Sing-Se
Professor Zei, head of anthropology
at Ba Sing Se University.
This library said to contain
a vast collection of knowledge
Firebenders loose their
bending during a solar eclipse!
We've got to get this information
to the Earth King at Ba Sing Se.
What are you doing
firebending your tea?
So the old guy had some hot tea.
Big deal.
He heated it himself!
Those guys are firebenders.
Book two: Earth
Chapter fourteen: City of Walls and Secrets
Look, the inner wall.
I can't believe we finally
made it to Ba Sing Se in one piece.
Hey don't jinx it!
We could still be attacked by some
giant, exploding Fire Nation spoon.
Or find out the city's been submerged
in an ocean full of killer shrimp.
You been hitting the cactus juice again?
I'm just sayin', weird stuff happens to us.
Don't worry Aang, we'll find Appa.
It's such a big city.
He's a giant bison. Where could
someone possibly hide him? Oh.
Back in the city. Great.
What's the problem? It's amazing!
Just a bunch of walls and rules.
You wait; you'll get sick
of it in a couple of days.
I'm comin' for you buddy.
He's here. I can feel it.
Hello, my name is Joo Dee.
I have been given the great honor
of showing the Avatar around Ba Sing Se.
And you must be Sokka, Katara, and Toph.
Welcome to our wonderful city.
Shall we get started?
Yes!
We have information about the Fire Nation army that
we need to deliver to the Earth King immediately.
Great
let's begin our tour.
And then I'll show you to your new home here.
I think you'll like it.
Maybe you missed what I said.
We need to talk to the King
about the war, it's important.
You're in Ba Sing Se now.
Everyone is safe here.
This is the lower ring.
What's that wall for?
Oh, Ba Sing Se has many walls.
There are the ones outside protecting us, and
the one's inside that help maintain order.
This is where our newest arrivals live,
as well as our craftsman and artisans,
people that work with their hands.
It's so quaint and lively.
You do want to watch your step though.
Why do they have all these poor people
blocked off in one part of the city?
This is why I never came here before.
I always heard it was so different
from the way the monks taught us to live.
I just want our new place to look nice ...
in case someone brings home a lady friend.
This city is a prison. I
don't want to make a life here.
Life happens wherever you are,
whether you make it or not.
Now come on, I found us some new jobs,
and we start this afternoon.
Look at them, firebenders
living right under everyone's nose.
Jet, you saw a man with a hot cup of tea.
It doesn't prove he's a firebender.
And what if he is,
are we supposed to attack them?
I thought we were starting over here,
changing our ways.
We are,
when I get the evidence I need, I'll report
them to the police and let them handle it.
Ok?
This is the middle ring of Ba Sing Se,
home to the financial district,
shops and restaurants and the university.
Yeah, we met a Professor
from Ba Sing Se University.
He took us to an ancient underground library where
we discovered information about the war that is ...
absolutely crucial for the King to hear!
Isn't history fascinating?
Look, here's one of the oldest buildings
in the middle ring, Town Hall.
Is that woman deaf?
She only seems to hear
every other word I say.
It's called "being handled".
Get used to it.
Well, you certainly look
like official tea servers.
How do you feel?
Ridiculous.
Uh, Does this possibly
come in a larger size?
I have extra string in the back.
Have some tea while you wait.
Eeow! This tea is nothing
more than hot leaf juice!
Uncle, that's what all tea is.
How can a member of my own
family say something so horrible?
We'll have to make some
major changes around here.
The Upper Ring is home
to our most important citizens.
Your house is not too far from here.
What's inside that wall?
And who are the mean looking guys in robes?
Inside is the Royal Palace.
Those men are agents of the Dai
Li, the cultural authority of Ba Sing Se.
They are the guardians
of all our traditions.
Can we see the King now?
Oh, no! One doesn't just
pop in on the Earth King.
Here we are. Your new home.
More good news, your request for an audience
with the Earth King is being processed,
and should be put through in about a month.
Much more quickly than usual.
A month!
Six to eight weeks, actually.
Isn't it nice? I think
you will really enjoy it here.
I think we'd enjoy it more
if we weren't staying so long.
Can't we see the King any sooner?
The Earth King is very busy
running the finest city in the world,
but he will see you as
soon as time permits.
If we are going to be here for a month,
we should spend our time looking for Appa.
I'll be happy to escort you
anywhere you would like to go.
We don't need a babysitter.
Oh, I won't get in the way. And to
leave you alone would make me a bad host.
Where shall we start?
I'm sorry, but I haven't heard
anything about a flying bison.
I didn't even know there were any.
If someone wanted to sell a stolen animal
without anyone knowing, where would they go?
Where's the black market?
Who runs it? Come on, you know!
That would be illegal.
You'll have to leave now. Your
lemur is harassing my sparrowkeets.
I've never seen any sandbenders
or nomads around here.
You should ask Professor Zei, he
teaches the class on desert cultures.
Right. And which of your professors could
we ask about the war with the fire nation?
I don't know. I'm not a political science student.
I have to get to class. Ugh!
Well, I'm sorry no one has seen your bison.
Why don't you go get some rest?
Someone will be over with dinner later.
Hey, come with me.
You're the Avatar. I heard
you were in town. I'm Pao.
Nice to meet you, Pao.
So Pao, what's goin' on with this city?
Why is everyone here so scared to talk about the war?
War? Scared? What do you mean?
I can feel you shaking.
Look, I'm just a minor government official.
I've waited 3 years to get this house.
I don't want to get into trouble.
Get in trouble with who?
Listen, you can't mention the war here, and
whatever you do, stay away from the Dai Li.
Would you like a pot of tea?
We've been working in a tea shop all day.
I'm sick of tea!
Sick of tea?
That's like being sick of breathing!
Have you seen our spark
rocks to heat up the water?
They're not there.
You'll have to firebend, old man.
Where are you going?
I borrowed our neighbors, such kind people.
I've got it! I know how
we're gonna see the Earth King!
How are we supposed to do that?
"One doesn't just pop in on the Earth King"
The King is having a party at
the palace tonight for his pet bear.
You mean Platypus-Bear?
No, it just says "Bear".
Certainly you mean his pet Skunk-Bear.
Or his Armadillo-Bear.
Gopher-Bear?
Just..."Bear"
This place is weird.
The palace will be packed.
We can sneak in with the crowd.
Won't work.
Why not?
Well, no offense to you
simple country folk,
but a real society crowd
would spot you from a mile away.
You've got no manners.
Excuse me? I've got no manners?
You're not exactly lady fancy fingers.
I learned proper society
behavior and chose to leave it.
You never learned anything.
And frankly, it's a little too late.
Ah-Ha, but you learned it.
You could teach us.
Yeah, I'm mastering every element.
How hard could manners be?
Good evening, Mr. Sokka Watertribe.
Ms. Katara Watertribe.
Lord Momo of the Momo
Dynasty, your Momo-ness.
Avatar Aang, how you do go on?
Katara might be able to pull it off, but
you two would be lucky to pass as busboys.
But I feel so fancy.
- Earth!
- Fire!
Wow, you look beautiful.
Don't talk to the commoners, Katara.
First rule of society.
We'll get in the party, and then find
a way to let you in through the side gate.
Jet, we need to talk.
What? Oh great, it's you guys. Where have you been?
I could use some help with surveillance here.
We've been talking, and we think
you're becoming obsessed with this.
It's not healthy.
Oh, really? You both think this?
We came here to make a fresh start,
but you won't let this go.
Even though there's no real proof!
Well, maybe if you'd help me.
Jet, you've gotta stop this.
Maybe you've forgotten why
we need to start over.
Maybe you've forgotten about how
the Fire Nation left us all homeless?
How they wiped out all the people we loved.
If you don't want to help me,
I'll get the evidence on my own.
This is the best tea in the city!
The secret ingredient is love.
I think you're due for a raise.
I'm tired of waiting.
These two men are firebenders!
I know they're firebenders!
I saw the old man heating his tea!
He works in a tea shop.
He's a firebender, I'm telling you!
Drop your swords boy, nice and easy.
You'll have to defend yourself. Then everyone will know.
Go ahead, show them what you can do.
You want a show? I'll give you a show.
Invitation please.
I think this will do.
No entry without an invitation.
Step out of line please.
Look, the Pangs and the Yum Soon
Hans are waiting in there for us.
I'm going to have to tell
them who didn't let me in.
Step out of line please.
Sir? I'm sorry to bother you,
but my cousin lost our invitations.
She's blind.
Do you think you could help us?
Our family's inside and
I'm sure they're very worried.
I am honored,
please come with me.
He's taking all the good stuff!
Quiet, you don't know what I had
to do to get seats this near the bear!
It's beautiful, isn't it?
By the way, I'm Long Feng. I'm
a cultural minister to the king.
I'm Kwa mai, and this is Dung.
Now where is your family?
I'd love to meet them.
Um, I don't see 'em right now. But I'm sure
we'll find them soon. Thanks for all your help.
Don't worry, as your escort it would be dishonorable to
abandon you ladies without finding your families first.
We'll keep looking.
Where are they?
Look, I came up with a backup plan.
We dress Momo like a ghost, OK?
He flies by the guards creating a distraction,
then we blast a hole in the wall...
Or, we could go in with these guys.
Toph said we might pass as busboys.
OK, but remember that Momo ghost plan.
I think it's a winner.
You must be getting tired
of using those swords.
Why don't you go ahead and firebend at me.
Please son, you're confused.
You don't know what you're doing!
Bet you wish he'd help you out
with a little fire blast right now.
You're the one who needs help.
You see that? The Fire
nation is trying to silence me.
It'll never happen.
Where are Toph and Katara?
Forget about them, just
keep an eye out for the King.
I don't know what he looks like.
You know, "royal", flowing
robe, fancy jewelry.
That could be anyone.
Another crab puff please.
You found us.
I'd know your little footsteps
anywhere Twinkletoes.
Thanks for letting us in.
Sorry, but the guy who escorted
us in, won't let us out of his sight.
What guy?
What are you doing here?
You have to leave immediately,
or we'll all be in terrible trouble.
Not until we see the King.
You don't understand. You must go.
Sorry! No, don't shout.
The Avatar. Ooh, I didn't
known the Avatar would be here.
You keep their attention
while I look for the King.
Watch this everybody!
Drop your weapons!
Arrest them. They're Firebenders.
This poor boy is confused.
We're just simple refugees.
This young man wrecked my tea
shop, and assaulted my employees.
It's true sir. We saw the whole thing.
This crazy kid attacked
the finest tea maker in the city.
Oh ho ho. That's very sweet.
Come with us son.
You don't understand! They're
Fire Nation! You have to believe me!
Aang, the Earth King.
Greetings your majesty.
Hey, let me go.
Avatar, it is a great honor to meet you. I am Long Feng,
Grand Secretary of Ba Sing Se and head of the Dai Li.
I'd like to talk to you. You're friends
will be waiting for us in the library.
Why won't you let us talk to the King?
We have information that
could defeat the Fire Nation!
The Earth King has no time to get
involved with political squabbles ...
and the day to day minutia
of military activities.
This could be the most important
thing he has ever heard.
What's most important to his royal majesty is
maintaining the cultural heritage of Ba Sing Se.
All his duties relate to
issuing decrees on such matters.
It's my job to oversee the rest of the
city's resources, including the military.
So the King is just a figurehead.
He's your puppet!
Oh, no, no! His majesty
is an icon, a god to his people.
He can't sully his hands with
the hourly change of an endless war.
But we found out about a solar eclipse that
will leave the Fire Nation defenseless.
You could lead an invasion...
Enough, I don't want
to hear your ridiculous plan!
It is the strict policy of Ba Sing Se...
that the war not be
mentioned within the walls.
Constant news of an escalating war will throw the
citizens of Ba Sing Se into a state of panic.
You have to believe me,
they're firebenders!
They won't stop until they win the war.
Calm down, you're safe now.
Our economy would be ruined. Our peaceful way
of life, our traditions would disappear.
There's no war in Ba Sing Se.
What are you talking about? Where do you think
all the refugees come from? You can't hide it.
In silencing talk of conflict, Ba
Sing Se remains a peaceful, orderly utopia.
The last one on Earth.
There is no war within the walls.
Here we are safe.
Here we are free.
You can't keep the truth from all these people.
They have to know.
I'll tell them.
I'll make sure everyone knows!
Until now, you've been
treated as our honored guest.
But from now on, you will be watched
every moment by Dai Li agents.
If you mention the war to anyone,
you will be expelled from the city.
I understand you've been
looking for your bison.
It would be quite a shame if you
were not able to complete your quest.
Now Joo Dee will show you home.
Come with me, please.
What happened to Joo Dee?
I'm Joo Dee. I'll be your host as
long as you're in our wonderful city.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk