Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of
all four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar...
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great.
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
I can't believe it. I
know the war has spread far, ...
but Omashu always seemed... untouchable.
Up until now, it was. Now Ba Sing Se is the
only great Earth Kingdom stronghold left.
This is horrible, but we have to move on.
No. I'm going in to find Bumi.
Aang, stop.
We don't even know if Bumi's still...
What? If he's still what?
Around.
I know you had your heart set on Bumi, ...
but there are other people
around who can teach you earthbending.
This isn't about finding a teacher.
This is about finding my friend.
A secret passage?
Why didn't we just use this last time?
Does that answer your question?
That wasn't as bad as I thought.
They won't let go! Help!
Stop making so much noise.
It's just a purple pentapus.
Hey!
What are you kids doing out past curfew?
Sorry. We were just on our way home.
Wait! What's the matter with him?
Uh... he has pentapox, Sir.
Um... it's highly contagious!
Ahhhhh... It's so awful... I'm dyiiiing...
and deadly...
Wait, I think I've heard of pentapox.
Didn't your cousin Chang die of it?
We'd better go wash our hands.
.. and burn our clothes!
Thank you, sewer friend!
When tracking your brother and uncle, ...
traveling with a royal procession
may no longer be an option.
May no longer be wise... if you
hope to keep the element of surprise.
You're right. The royal
procession is dead weight.
If I want to catch my prey,
I must be agile... nimble.
I need a small, elite team.
It's time to visit some old friends.
Let's find Bumi and get out of here.
Where would they be keeping him?
Somewhere he can't earthbend.
Somewhere made of metal.
There really is no fathoming the
depths of my hatred for this place.
Mai, your father was appointed governor.
We're like royalty here.
Be happy, and enjoy it.
The targets are approaching.
Take them out.
I thought my life was
boring in the Fire Nation.
But this place is unbearably bleak.
Nothing ever happens.
The resistance!
Ty Lee, could that possibly be you?
Azula!
It is so good to see you!
Please, don't let me interrupt your.
.. whatever it is you were doing.
Tell me, what is the daughter
of a nobleman doing here?
Certainly our parents didn't send
us to the Royal Fire Academy for Girls...
to end up in... places like this.
I have a proposition for you.
I'm hunting a traitor.
You remember my old fuddy
duddy uncle, don't you?
Oh yeah. He was so funny.
I would be honored if you
would join me on my mission.
Oh... I... uh... would love to.
But the truth is, I'm really happy here.
I mean, my aura has never been pinker!
I'll take your word for it.
Well, I wouldn't want you to give
up the life you love just to please me.
Thank you, Azula.
Of course, before I leave,
I'm going to catch your show.
Huh? Uh... yeah... sure...
uh... of course...
So, is King Bumi with you
guys? Is he leading the resistance?
Of course not! The day of the invasion,
we readied ourselves for battle.
We were prepared to defend our city...
To fight for our lives and for our freedom.
But before we even had a
chance, King Bumi surrendered.
The day of the invasion, I asked
King Bumi what he wanted to do.
He looked me in the eye and said...
I'm going to do... nothing!
It doesn't matter now. Fighting the
Fire Nation is the only path to freedom.
And freedom is worth dying for.
Actually there's another path to freedom.
You could leave Omashu.
You're directing all your
energy to fight the Fire Nation.
But you're outnumbered. You can't win.
Now's the time to retreat, so
you can live to fight another day.
You don't understand.
They've taken our home, ...
and we have to fight them at any cost!
I don't know, Ya, living to fight another
day is startin' to sound pretty good to me.
Yeah, I'm with the kid!
Fine. But there's thousands
of citizens that need to leave.
How're we going to get them all out?
Suckers!
You're all about to come down
with a nasty case of pentapox.
The marks make ya look sick, but you
gotta act sick, too. Ya gotta sell it!
Now that's what I'm talkin' about.
Years of practice.
Okay everyone! Into sick formation.
Aang, what are you doing?
Aren't you coming with us.
No. I'm not leaving until I find Bumi.
Sorry Momo, I'll feed you later.
Plague! Plague!
What is going on down there?
I saw some kids yesterday who were
sick with pentapox. It must have spread!
Pentapox! Hm, I'm pretty
sure I've heard of that.
Oh, this is terrible.
What should we do?
Drive them out of the city.
.. but don't touch them!
We have to rid the city of this disease!
Fire flakes, Dad?
Oh! How awful!
Flopsie!
Come on, Flopsie.
You gotta help me find Bumi.
Yip Yip! Oh... I guess that
doesn't work with you. Let's go!
We're deeply honored to have the Fire
Lord's daughter at our humble circus.
Uh... tell us if there is anything
we can do to make the show more enjoyable.
I will.
Incredible. Do you think she'll fall?
Of course not.
Then wouldn't it make it more
interesting if you removed the net?
Uh... the thing is... the performers...
You're right, you're right.
That's been done.
I know. Set the net on fire.
Of course, Princess.
Brilliant, just brilliant! Oooo, what
kind of dangerous animals do you have?
Well, our circus boasts
the most exotic assortment...
Release them all!
We looked everywhere. No Bumi.
We've got a problem.
We just did a head count.
Oh no. Did someone get left behind?
No, we have an extra.
So, the resistance has kidnapped my son.
Everything so clever, so tricky.
Just like their King Bumi.
What do you want to do, Sir?
What an exquisite performance.
I can't wait to see how
you'll top yourself tomorrow.
I'm sorry Azula, but unfortunately
there won't be a show tomorrow.
Really?
The universe has given me strong
hints that it's time for a career change.
I want to join you on your mission.
No! Bad Fire Nation baby!
Oh... alright.
Ooo, you're so cute. Mmmmm...
Sure he's cute now, but when he's
older, he'll join the Fire Nation army.
You won't think he's so cute then.
He'll be a killer.
Does that look like the
face of a killer to you?
A messenger hawk!
It's from the Fire Nation governor.
He thinks we kidnapped his son.
So... he wants to make a trade.
His son for King Bumi.
You realize we're probably
walking right into a trap?
I don't think so. I'm sure the Governor
wants his son back as much as we want Bumi.
It's a new day.
I have a good feeling about this.
Please tell me you're here to kill me.
It's great to see you, Mai.
I thought you ran off and joined
the circus? You said it was your calling.
Well, Azula called a little louder.
I have a mission and I need you both.
Count me in. Anything
to get me out of this place.
I apologize.
You've come to Omashu at a difficult time.
At noon we're making a trade with
the resistance to get Tom-Tom back.
Yes, I'm so sorry to hear
about your son, but really, ...
what did you expect by just
letting all the citizens leave?
My father has trusted you with this
city and you're making a mess of things!
Forgive me, Princess.
You stay here. Mai will
handle the hostage trade...
so you don't have a chance to mess it up.
And there is no more "Omashu".
I'm renaming it in honor of
my father, the City of New Ozai.
Hi, everybody!
You brought my brother?
He's here. We're ready to trade.
I'm sorry, but a thought
just occurred to me. Do you mind?
Of course not, Princess Azula.
We're trading a two year old for a king.
A powerful, earthbending king?
It just doesn't seem like
a fair trade, does it?
You're right.
The deal's off.
Whhhoa! See you all later!
Bumi!
The Avatar!
My lucky day.
Aang, is that you? Where did you come from?
Hang on! We're gonna get you out of here.
We've got to get the baby out of here!
Way ahead of ya!
Aang, stop your blowing for a minute.
Now hold on just a duahhh!!!
Just like old times, isn't it, Bumi?
Aang, I need to talk to you!
It's good to see you too!
How are you gonna fight
without your bending?
I seem to manage!
There's Aang!
We can catch him!
Hang on, Bumi! Our ride's here!
You could earthbend all along!?
Well, they didn't cover my face.
I don't understand.
Why didn't you free yourself?
Why did you surrender
when Omashu was invaded?
What's the matter with you, Bumi!?
Listen to me, Aang. There are
options in fighting, called jin.
It's a choice of how you
direct your energy.
I know! There's positive
jin when you're attacking, ...
and negative jin when you're retreating.
And neutral jin when you do nothing!
There three jins?
Well, technically there are eighty five.
But, let's just focus on the third.
Neutral jin is the key to earthbending.
It involves listening and waiting
for the right moment to strike.
That's why you surrendered, isn't it?
Yes, and it's why I can't leave now.
I guess I need to find someone
else to teach me earthbending.
Your teacher will be someone
who has mastered neutral jin.
You need to find someone who
waits and listens before striking.
Hey, Momo!
Momo's mastered a few jins himself!
Goodbye, Aang. I'll see
you when the time is right.
So, we're tracking down
your brother and Uncle, huh?
It'll be interesting seeing
Zuko again, won't it, Mai?
It's not just Zuko and Iroh anymore.
We have a third target now.
Tom-Tom!
Subtitle by rendy1287
Fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk