We need to find King Bumi so Aang
can learn earthbending somewhere safe.
Sounds like you're headed to Omashu.
I present to you the Earth
Kingdom city of O... Oh, no...
I guess I need to find someone
else to teach me earthbending.
You need to find someone who
waits and listens before striking.
In the swamp we see visions of
people we've lost, people we loved...
But what about my vision?
It was someone I had never met.
It's pricey, but I really do like it.
Then you should get it.
You deserve something nice.
I do, don't I? But no. It's
too expensive, I shouldn't.
Alright, then don't.
You know what? I'm gonna get it.
Psst, psst. Hey, you kids like
earthbending? You like throwing rocks?
Then check out Master Yu's
Earthbending Academy.
Look, there's a coupon on the back.
The first lesson is free.
Who knows? This Master Yu could be...
the earthbending teacher
you've been looking for.
Take your stances.
Now, strike as if you're punching
through your opponents head!
So, are you ready to
commit to more lessons?
If you pay for the whole year in advance,
I'll bump you up to the next belt.
Ah, he's not the one.
I think The Boulder is gonna
win back the belt at Earth Rumble 6.
He's gonna have to fight his
way through the best earthbenders...
in the world to even
get a shot at the champ.
Excuse me, but where is this
earthbending tournament exactly?
It's on the Island of Noneoya.
.. none o' ya business!
Oh, I got to remember that one.
I'll take care of this.
Hey strong guys, wait up!
What was I thinking? I don't need a new bag.
Why'd you let me buy this?
You ready to find an earthbending teacher?
Because we're going to Earth Rumble 6!
How did you get them to tell you?
Oh, a girl has her ways.
Hey, front row seats! I wonder
why no one else is sitting here.
I guess that's why.
Welcome to Earth Rumble 6!
I am your host, Shin Fu!
This is just gonna be a bunch of guys
chuckin' rocks at each other, isn't it?
That's what I paid for.
The rules are simple. Just knock the
other guy out of the ring and you win.
Round one! The Boulder
versus The Big Bad Hippo!
Listen up, Hippo. You
may be big, but you ain't bad!
The Boulder's gonna win
this in a landslide.
Hippo mad!
Unbelievable, ladies and gentlemen!
The Hippo is rocking The Boulder!
The Boulder wins!
How about The Boulder?
He's got some good moves.
I don't know. Bumi said I need
a teacher who listens to the earth.
He's just listening to his big muscles.
What do you think Sokka?
Next match, The Boulder
versus Fire Nation Man!
Boo! Boo!
Please to rise for Fire
Nation national anthem.
? Fire Lord, my flame burns for thee!?
Go back to the Fire Nation!
No. No please!
Yeah! Whoo! The Boulder knows how
to put the hurt in the dirt! Yeah! Whoo!
Now, the moment you've all been waiting for.
The Boulder versus your champion...
The Blind Bandit!
She can't really be blind. It's
just part of her character, right?
I think she is.
I think she is... Going down!
The Boulder feels conflicted
about fighting a young, blind girl.
Sounds to me like you're scared, Boulder.
The Boulder's over his
conflicted feelings, ...
and now he's ready
to bury you in a rock-a-lanche!
Whenever you're ready... The Pebble.
It's on!
Your winner, and still
the champion, The Blind Bandit!
No!
How did she do that?
She waited, and listened.
To make things a little
more interesting, ...
I'm offering up this sack of gold pieces
to anyone who can defeat The Blind Bandit!
What? No one dares to face her?
I will!
Go Aang! Avenge The Boulder!
Do people really want to see
two little girls fighting out here?
I don't really want to fight you.
I want to talk to you.
Boo! No talking!
Don't boo at him.
Somebody's a little light on his feet.
What's your fighting
name, The Fancy Dancer?
Where'd you go?
Please, wait!
There you are!
Please listen!
I need an earthbending teacher, ...
and I think it's supposed to be you.
Whoever you are, just leave me alone.
Wait!
Way to go, champ!
I gotta admit, now I'm
really glad I bought this bag.
It matches the belt perfectly.
That is a big relief.
If we want to find The Blind Bandit, ...
the Earthbending Academy
is a good place to start.
Oh great, you again.
Yeah, I didn't think so.
Nicely done.
Hey, you're the kid who
beat The Blind Bandit.
We need to talk to her.
Do you guys know where she lives?
The Blind Bandit's a mystery.
She shows up to fight, then disappears.
Let me handle this. You're
not telling us everything!
No no, I swear it's true! No one knows
where she goes, or who she really is.
That's because we're asking
about the wrong person.
In my vision, I saw a girl in
a white dress with a pet flying boar.
Know anybody like that?
Well, a flying boar is the
symbol of the Bei Fong family.
They're the richest people
in town, probably the whole world.
Yeah, but they don't have a daughter.
Flying boar is good enough for me.
Let's check it out.
Yeah, you better leave.
Hey, I've got my eye on you.
Water Tribe.
I'm telling you, The Boulder
was standing right there.
I saw the kid strike,
but there was no earthbending.
Nothing made contact. The Blind
Bandit just fell out of the ring.
She must have took a dive
and split the money with the kid.
Nobody cheats Xin Fu.
That's the flying boar from my vision.
Come on.
What are you doing here, Twinkle Toes?
How did you know it was me?
Don't answer to Twinkle Toes.
It's not manly!
You're the one whose bag matches his belt.
How did you find me?
Well, a crazy king told me I had to find
an earthbender who listens to the earth.
And then I had a vision
in a magic swamp and...
What Aang is trying to
say is, he's the Avatar, ...
and if he doesn't master
earthbending soon...
he won't be able to
defeat the Fire Lord.
Not my problem. Now get out
of here or I'll call the guards.
Look, we all have to do
our part to win this war.
And yours is to teach Aang earthbending.
Guards! Guards, help!
Toph, what happened?
I thought I heard someone. I got scared.
You know your father doesn't want you...
wandering the grounds
without supervision, Toph.
I'm pleased to hear that Toph's
private lessons are going well, ...
but I want to be sure that she's
not trying anything too dangerous.
Absolutely not. I'm keeping
her at the beginner's level.
Basic forms and breathing exercises only.
Very good.
Excuse me sir, but you have a visitor.
Who thinks they are so important they
can just come to my home unannounced?
Uh, the Avatar, Sir.
Blow on it. It's too hot for her.
Allow me.
Oh my!
Avatar Aang, it's an honor
to have you visit us.
In your opinion, how much longer
do you think the war will last?
I'd like to defeat the Fire
Lord by the end of summer, ...
but I can't do that without
finding an earthbending teacher first.
Well, Master Yu is the
finest teacher in the land.
He's been teaching Toph
since she was little.
Then she must be a great earthbender, ...
probably good enough
to teach someone else.
Toph is still learning the basics.
Yes, and sadly because
of her blindness, ...
I don't think she will
ever become a true master.
Oh, I'm sure she's better
than you think she is.
What's your problem?
Well, shall we move to the
living room for dessert then?
Good night buddy.
Relax. Look, I'm sorry about dinner.
Let's call a truce, okay?
Even though I was born blind,
I've never had a problem seeing.
I see with earthbending. It's
kind of like seeing with my feet.
I feel the vibrations in the earth,
and I can see where everything is.
You, that tree, even those ants.
That's amazing.
My parents don't understand. They've
always treated me like I was helpless.
Is that why you became The Blind Bandit?
Yeah.
Then why stay here where you're not happy?
They're my parents. Where
else am I supposed to go?
You could come with us.
Yeah. You guys get to go wherever you want.
No one telling you what to do, that's the life.
It's just not my life.
We're being ambushed.
I think you kids owe me some money.
Whoever took Aang and Toph left this.
"If you want to see your daughter
again, bring 500 gold pieces to the arena."
It's signed "Xin Fu and The Boulder."
I can't believe it.
I have the Boulder's autograph!
Master Yu, I need you to
help you get my daughter back.
We're going with you.
Poor Toph. She must be so scared.
You think you're so tough...
why don't you come up here
so I can smack that grin off your face?
I'm not smiling.
Toph!
Here's your money. Now let them go.
What about Aang?
I think the Fire Nation will
pay a hefty price for the Avatar.
Now, get out of my ring.
Go. I'll be ok.
Toph, there's too many of them.
We need an earthbender. We need you!
My daughter is blind. She is blind
and tiny and helpless and fragile.
She cannot help you.
Yes, I can.
Let him go. I beat you all
before, and I'll do it again.
The Boulder takes issue with that comment.
Wait.
They're mine.
Hit it harder!
I'm trying!
I never knew. Your daughter's amazing.
She's the greatest
earthbender I've ever seen!
Dad, I know it's probably
hard for you to see me this way, ...
but the obedient little helpless blind
girl that you think I am just isn't me.
I love fighting. I love being an earthbender.
And I'm really, really good at it.
I know I've kept my life
secret from you, ...
but you were keeping
me secret from the whole world.
You were doing it to protect me.
But I'm twelve years old
and I've never had a real friend.
So now that you see who I really am, ...
I hope it doesn't change
the way you feel about me.
Of course it doesn't change
the way I feel about you, Toph.
It's made me realize something.
It has?
Yes. I've let you have
far too much freedom.
From now on, you will be cared
for and guarded 24 hours a day.
But dad!
We are doing this for your own good, Toph.
Please escort the Avatar and his friends out.
They are no longer welcome here.
I'm sorry, Toph.
I'm sorry, too. Good bye, Aang.
Don't worry. We'll find you a teacher.
There are plenty of amazing
earthbenders out there.
Not like her.
Toph! What are you doing here?
My dad changed his mind. He
said I was free to travel the world.
Well, we'd better get out of here.
.. before your dad changes his mind again.
Good idea.
You're gonna be a great teacher, Toph.
Speaking of which, I want
to show you something.
Okay.
Now we're even.
Um, I'll take the belt back.
Sorry.
I know you two are very different...
but I believe you
have a common interest.
The Avatar has kidnapped my daughter.
I want you to do whatever
it takes to bring her home.
Subtitle by rendy1287
Fixed by LEO33
www. leo33.tk
www.leo33.tk