Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
You unlock this door
with the key of imagination.
Beyond it is another dimension-
a dimension of sound,
a dimension of sight,
a dimension of mind.
You're moving into a land
of both shadow and substance,
of things and ideas.
You've just crossed over
into the twilight zone.
Tonight a presentation
so special and unique,
that for the first time
in the five years
we've been presenting
the twlight zone,
we're offering a film
shot in france by others.
Winner of the cannes
film festival of 1962,
as well as other
international awards,
here is a haunting study
of the incredible
from the past master of
the incredible, ambrose bierce.
Here is the french production
of "an occurrence
at owl creek bridge."
First squad, stand fast.
Fall out.
Libbie.
Take his watch.
Yes, sir.
Atten-hut!
A living man
i want to be a living man
in all the world
? he moves around?
? he walks around?
? he turns around?
? i see each tree?
? i read each vein?
? i hear each bug?
? upon each leaf?
? the buzzing flies?
? the splashing fish?
? they moves around?
? this living man?
? a living man?
? i want to be a living man.?
He must be hung!
Soldier, tell... to open fire!
Yes, sir.
If it is necessary,
fire the cannon as well!
Shoulder arms.
Guards, stand fast!
Steady, men. Steady.
He mustn't escape.
There he is.
He's moving.
Peyton farquhar,
you're caught
like a rat in a trap.
In a trap.
Trap. Trap.
Atten-hut!
Shoulder arms!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Load!
Ready!
Fire!
Fire at will!
Commence firing!
? he walks around?
? he turns around?
? i see each tree?
? i read each vein?
? i hear each bug?
? upon each leave?
? the buzzing flies?
? the splashing fish?
? they moves around?
? this living man.?
"An occurrence at owl creek
bridge" in two forms-
as it was dreamed
and as it was lived and died.
This is the stuff of fantasy,
the thread of imagination,
the ingredients
ofthe twilight zone.
And now, mr. Serling.
Twilight zoneregular
charles beaumont
brings us our next offering,
a tale of age and youth
and a beautiful woman.
Our star is ann blyth,
our story, "queen of the nile."
They say that beauty
is only skin deep,
and when the surface
is scratched,
what you might conceivably
find underneath
is something quite
apart from beauty.
This is the rather
intriguing basis
of our next presentation
onthe twilight zone.
Miss ann blyth
in "queen of the nile."
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org