There he is.
Black Jack Massarone.
I saw this, and I thought of you.
- Look at that.
- The guy's local.
He makes them as part of a program
for disabled vets.
A little gift to show my gratitude
for all our work together.
Thanks.
Look at those guys, huh?
They had some times, huh?
We're finally gonna cut the ribbon
for the museum on the 22nd.
They even asked me to make
a little speech on the challenges...
...of contemporary urban development.
Thank you.
Something for you?
I'll have what he's having.
Listen, my buddy in City Plan Check
says they just pulled a permit...
...to turn the old bus station
into a mixed-use.
Zellman still hasn't given me a number.
Has he said anything to you
about another bid?
Oh, we don't talk much.
Take your hat off. Relax.
Yeah. I just started on the Rogaine.
Listen, you think you could ask Ron
if this falls under the same arrangement?
It's kind of soggy,
you wanna know the truth.
Tony, this is federal redevelopment.
I'll look into it.
- So a speech, huh?
- Yeah.
At the Museum of Science and Trucking.
I just wish my mother could have seen it.
Well, wherever she is,
I'm sure she's proud.
Actually, I think I know exactly
where she is, and it's pretty fucking hot.
You had one of those too, huh?
Gentlemen.
Is everything okay here?
Yeah, sure. Just talking.
Okay, then. Have a good night.
So they go through labor, big deal.
Try a prostate exam.
This is great.
And I usually don't like modern art.
The Rat Pack.
Do you know a Joseph "Joey" Cogo?
Not much. I mean, I met him.
Last week.
Me and Chrissy were having dinner
with Tony and his friend, Valentina.
Joey Cogo sent over a bottle of Veuve.
You wanna show her those?
Oh, my God.
Was this man with him?
Yeah, I saw him.
You're sure?
Tuesday night.
Jesus, because of what I said?
You're supposed to be earners. That's...
The top-tier positions.
So each of you, go to your people
on the street. Crack some fucking...
Create some fucking earners out there!
So, what's he saying?
The way I remember, he said:
"That's why you got
the top-tier positions."
This other inaudible
is "crack fucking heads," not "legs."
I need a signature.
Now, that's it. That's all I gotta say.
Frankly, I'm depressed and...
- Depressed and what?
- Depressed and ashamed.
So, what about my Alan Stuart shirt
from that meeting?
Ralph Cifaretto spilt my coffee
and ruined it.
I can petty cash it. Resubmit, okay?
This Crazy Horse pole camera's
working out really good.
Paulie Gualtieri's car again.
She's still lying.
Listen, any chance
you could
ask Ron if this falls
under the same arrangement?
It's kind of soggy,
you wanna know the truth.
- Pie. He was eating.
- Tony, this is federal redevelopment.
I'll look into it.
- So a speech, huh?
- Sound quality is amazing.
New hats. Mike's right in the button.
- Museum of Science and Trucking.
- Just wish my mother could have seen it.
Give it to Angela and shut the door.
Well, wherever she is,
I'm sure she's proud.
What happened to the jury-tampering
investigation on Junior Soprano's trial?
- Actually, I...
- You guys just drop the ball on that?
Massarone's a huge asset.
- Couple him with...
- What, three-year-old airline tickets?
Some ties to the Bevilaqua murder?
Even if Massarone
and a thousand other snitches pan out...
...we've still gotta put Tony on trial.
That's useless until we find out...
...how they penetrated
the anonymous jury system.
And what?
Jury duty's not tough enough?
We don't like to dig into some citizen.
Tough shit.
One of those citizens is a felon.
Get on it.
You know what's going on here, right?
He fucked up his six-figure future
with O'Melveny and Myers...
...when he blew the Junior Soprano trial.
Of course, he'll keep trying him
until he fixes that.
- Hey!
- Hey.
There he is, John Barrymore.
- How are you?
- All right.
I thought nobody ever comes to see you.
I was dropping off some dandelions.
Saw a beautiful patch
in a vacant lot over by 15th Street.
- Nice salad.
- Any word about Tony B?
Yeah, yeah, should be any day now.
Aunt Quintina's gonna call
the moment she hears.
- He's a good kid, your cousin? Smart.
- Yeah.
Fucking weirdo, you ask me.
All right, the vacant
lot over on 15th Street?
That's where all the neighborhood dogs
go to piss.
You goddamn clown.
So, you got anything lined up
for the kid?
Yeah, yeah, air bags.
We pull them from boosted cars.
People buy them
like you wouldn't believe.
Hey, legit dealers, body shops,
they reinstall undeployed bags as new.
- Top dollar.
- Brave, new world.
Jesus Christ, they didn't even
have shoulder belts when I went away.
You'll let me know
when the kid gets out?
Yeah, we'll have a party for him.
All right.
I love you, okay.
Come on, eat. Don't be so sensitive.
I was being polite.
It's like eating red fescue.
I'll take an egg. You want an egg?
Bobby, make my nephew an egg.
I don't want an egg.
Tony B.
A little welcome-home present.
- What's that, a Motorola?
- Yeah.
Supposed to be the best.
So, I figured he could use one.
Call me when he needs me.
All the fellas are getting out, huh?
The class of 2004.
Old rats on a new ship.
Think I'll take an egg.
Make us a couple eggs.
I'm doing it. You told me.
He don't want one.
You and Tony Egg again.
Tony Egg? Tony B.
Like the time you two...
You took that camera in the bathroom...
...at your sister Barbara's confirmation.
Hello.
Oh, that's terrible.
Where's he gonna be laid out?
Who now? Goddamn it.
Well, let us know.
Carmine Lupertazzi.
He passed during the night.
What a fucking blow.
He was a great man.
My cousin told me it was Carmine
who invented point-shaving.
CCNY versus Kentucky, 1951.
Nobody beat the spread.
I bought a black Fleetwood.
Anthony. Anthony, did I ever tell you
I want to be cremated?
About four times.
And don't throw my ashes in somebody's
yard or off some fucking bridge.
I wanna be on a mantelpiece
surrounded by family.
Yeah, under the moose head. I know.
Keep joking. Let me tell you something.
It's like that game
we used to play as kids.
Crack The Whip.
You run around holding hands
as tight as you can...
...and then the line snaps,
somebody lets go...
...and you're next.
Your father meant a lot to all of us,
and not just financially either.
- How are you?
- Looking good.
- Yeah, there you go.
- Fantastic.
What's up, buddy?
- John.
- Gene.
Nicole.
- You remember Mr. Petrille.
- What, honey?
- He meant a lot to us.
- Tough going, right?
Ginny, Phil, how are you doing?
- Hey, kid.
- Angelo.
I'm heartbroken.
- Nicole, you remember Mr. Garepe.
- Of course.
That was my aunt. My cousin's out.
- That's great news.
- Start him off small, T.
You hear that? Your cousin's out.
- Oh, look who's coming.
- What?
- Hey there, handsome.
- Hey, baby.
- How are you?
- Good.
Lorraine, you're looking good.
Yeah, keeping it together
with Pilates and gin.
Sil, Paulie, how is it hanging?
Still got the nice manners, huh?
This is my nephew, Christopher.
Lady shylock, you got some reputation.
Yeah, my mother
said that might happen.
I'd like to introduce you the love of my
life. This is my partner, Jason Evanina.
- Honor to meet you.
- Hi, how are you?
So, Jesus leans off the cross
and whispers to Peter:
"I can see your house from here."
I'm so sorry. This was such a shock.
This is a very hard day.
I just saw Ginny.
The flowers are beautiful.
- John, got a minute?
- Yeah.
Nicole, I'm sorry.
What's going on here?
- What're you talking about?
- My father.
- Look at his hands.
- He looks peaceful.
I'm talking about his rosary. The medal?
You think I don't know what that is?
It's for Opus Dei.
What the fuck is that about?
In his later years, your father
was very sensitive about the church.
Bullshit. Your wife is into Opus Dei.
- You told Colombino to put it there.
- You sure about that?
- Yes, I'm sure about that.
- Body's not even cold.
No respect for anything anymore.
In New Jersey housewife,
fundamentalist shit? I doubt it, John.
You yourself said,
I was like another son to him.
I was being polite. It was his deathbed.
I should have written those words down.
You should have.
They don't mean anything anymore.
You understand what I'm saying?
I saw a huge mushroom cloud...
Edward "Babe" Heffron
...from the shell.
Jim Campbell might be alive today...
...if he hadn't have said to me:
"Heffron, you stay here with your gun.
I'm going up."
All your life...
...you gotta remember what one guy did
because he thought it was his job to do.
And he took a shot for you.
This shit's not supposed to run,
and here I look like a raccoon.
You are irresistible, and you know it.
Danny said I was clingy.
Fuck him. He's the one
with the self-esteem issues.
You don't know what it's like out there,
Ade. You're marrying Christopher.
He's handsome, makes money.
He's got great hair. He...
Okay.
You know I love animals,
but this thing is so gorgeous.
Isn't it? My dad almost had a stroke.
But I told him, "Hey, asshole, I'm the
one taking all the fucking risk here."
I have to fake the invoices.
Sometimes you gotta just take care
of yourself, you know?
Sure you do, honey.
Come here.
Come on.
Let's don't keep your date waiting.
He likes you, I can tell.
We got a white wine for Ade.
That's another apple martini for you.
- Thank you, my dear.
- My 7 and 7.
And a nothing and nothing.
Don't listen to him, Chrissy.
I think what you're doing's brave.
It's not for everybody...
...but things are different
when you don't have that crutch.
We make up for it other ways.
My God, it's hot in here.
What do you expect?
You're dancing in a mink coat.
It's fox.
She's my fox in a fox.
Let's see her box.
Or maybe her socks.
Stupid.
Well, I have to wear fur on the outside on
account of being bare everywhere else.
- You believe this one?
- No shit.
Every place I go, I got substances
I can't enjoy shoved in my face.
But I guess asking you for a little
support system in my own home...
...is way the fuck out of line.
You gotta have some more wine.
Seemed to have a good time tonight.
What the fuck you talking about?
What, Tina?
Come on, that cunt's
too full of herself anyway.
Cunt? She's my maid of honor,
Christopher.
She's no fucking maid, let me tell you.
Great, now I'm upset.
See what I'm talking about?
But I guess it's all my problem.
I'm sorry, baby.
Okay?
Jeez!
Please, stop.
Well, there you are.
My handsome nephew.
Auntie Quin, look at you.
All dolled up, huh?
- I never thought I'd live to see this day.
- Well, here you are. Still here.
- Where's Tony?
- Downstairs...
...getting into one of his old suits.
- I'll buy him some new suits.
- He's fine.
I only wish
he had more to come back to.
That ex-wife of his...
...she uses her answering machine
to ignore me...
...so forget about us seeing the twins.
How's Kelly? How's she doing?
Well, she's lost to us, Anthony.
But Tony says he's gonna
hire a detective.
Look at this.
Two of you were so cute.
Well, even then my cannoli
was bigger than his.
Oh, stop.
Oh, man, there he is.
God, Ton.
Look at us, 15 fucking years.
The language.
Go ahead, say it.
I haven't changed a bit, right?
You look good. You look good.
Say provolone.
Surprise!
Oh, shit.
Very nice, you give me a heart attack.
Ma, it's enough, all right?
Stop crying. I'm embarrassed enough.
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything. Just eat, huh?
Oh, hey.
I got peppers been marinating
for 15 years!
- Hey.
- What?
Where's tubbs?
Artie, what happened here?
Still a ball-breaker, huh?
What the fuck's with him?
Ask him.
You guys have a beef?
I loaned the guy money, then he tried to
kill himself. Guess who got the blame.
Oh, my God, Ton.
My God,
we have all missed you so much.
I swear, you look exactly the same.
You're still full of shit, huh?
Is Nancy here yet? The twins?
No, Nancy couldn't make it.
Her aunt in Bayonne, the sciatica...
- What are you gonna do?
- Cousin!
Jan. Oh, Christ.
Come, I want you to meet my family.
I'm talking to him right now.
Tony, you remember Bobby.
- Good to see you. Welcome home.
- Now my husband.
And guys,
this is your Uncle Tony Blundetto.
Hey there.
How come we never met you before?
I've been away on business.
I never even heard of you.
Stop playing with your ice. Come on.
They let that kid say anything.
Welcome home, Uncle Tony.
Oh, Jesus.
This is Meadow.
God, you turned out beautiful, honey.
And this strapping, young man
is Anthony Jr.
How's Kelly?
Our regular dinner up by you Thursday?
Yes, Daddy.
See, with my family now,
you know, in separation...
...you gotta make an appointment
to see each other.
- I should go see Uncle Zio.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Show him the phone.
Yeah.
Tony.
I'll make this fast
because I know you're all hungry.
I remember, growing up,
I was always asking...
...why I just used to have sisters.
I said to my mother,
"Can't you save up something and...
...then get me a baby brother?"
And my mother said,
"What's wrong with your cousin Tony?"
And she was right
because we were brothers.
Except, you know,
we had the same name.
There was like 50 Tonys in the family.
Some of you remember this.
My dad's name was Johnny and...
...his dad's name was Alfred.
And so whenever we were out
running around, and we'd hear:
"Tony Uncle Johnny," that was for me...
...and "Tony Uncle Al,"
that was for him.
And there was "Tony Uncle Philly."
Remember?
- Right, yeah.
- But...
...he passed away, buon anima.
And Uncle Phil... Uncle Phil,
he passed away a long time ago too.
So anyway...
...Tony's being away...
...it's been hard.
But he's back now...
...for good.
So welcome home.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
Come on, let me hear it.
Welcome home!
Hey, Ton, Meadow is incredible.
She's a fucking Ivy Leaguer.
- You and Carm hit a home run.
- Yeah.
I'm sure Kelly's all right,
wherever she is.
- Hey, her old man was in prison.
- We tried to do everything we could.
I know, I wasn't around.
What can I expect?
I mean, if things had gone
different way back when, who knows?
What do you want from me?
Nothing. I'm just saying,
it's good it wasn't both of us.
Well, these things happen, right?
You're gonna like this place. This is nice.
This is the kind of place
we always talked about having.
Fucking weird.
My cousin in the old man's seat.
It's like Sun Tzu says:
"A good commander is benevolent
and unconcerned with fame."
What?
Sun Tzu,
the Chinese Prince Machiavelli.
Tony turned me on to him.
"Tzu, Tzu."
"Sun Tzu," you fucking ass-kiss.
Hey.
Feech.
You know, I missed you by two weeks
at Allenwood.
This'll help you get started.
Jesus, you're on your feet already?
You hit the ground running,
and you don't look back, huh?
Thank you.
Come on.
So you in on the bus-station project?
Massarone's waiting on a number.
- How's he doing?
- Good.
We had coffee.
He used to bore me, Jack.
He ain't a bad guy
once you get to know him.
I always liked him.
I was very touched
by that funeral the other day.
- Real heart-grabber.
- That fucking little Carmine.
And after what?
Five years in Florida
fixing wet T-shirt contests.
Boy, are you fat.
What did you say?
Reginald Van Gleason III.
Boy, are you fat.
That's good, yeah. Here.
So, I got some ideas, you know,
for you. Get you on your feet.
Unless, of course,
you already know what you wanna do.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Well, yeah, I kind of got an idea.
Yeah?
Like four years in,
I got moved to Springfield.
You know, where they got
the big prison hospital.
It's mostly stab wounds, detox.
Anyway, this guy I knew from Elkton...
...he was telling me
how I could be an orderly.
You know,
and how it's like easy time and all.
Well, you know, so then you're the guy
that hooks everybody up. That's smart.
Yeah, but it wasn't business for me.
I mean, I really got into this shit.
Rehab block had guys
with broken limbs, muscle diseases...
...and we'd help them back.
So, I think this might be a thing I can do.
I got my associate's degree already.
Took me five years.
And now it's only, like, six months
more for my massage license.
So, you wanna run a massage parlor?
No.
I'm gonna be
a licensed massage therapist.
Look, I've been away
from all this a long time.
I mean, if I got a shot at staying out and
putting shit together, I should take it.
Because I was thinking, you know...
...I got this air-bag thing going on...
No, Ton, thanks, but...
I mean, it's a really nice offer...
...but I need regular work
until I'm certified.
Just regular work.
Well, I guess I know
this guy looking for...
...a delivery man for his linen fleet.
- Bobby Gociletto?
- No, no, no, Koreans.
But I don't got my driver's license.
So, why don't you go
to my guy at the DMV?
As far as the union shit,
I can take care of that.
Wow, Ton, thanks. Thank you.
Come here. You're the best,
you know that?
Yeah, yeah.
- Out.
- Why?
Because we are watching a movie,
and you are studying.
And why must we keep
having that conversation?
Here, number one on the American Film
Institute's greatest American movies list.
- Citizen Kane.
- Jesus, it's black and white.
Oh, come on, that is what film club
is all about, trying new things.
Now, to give us some background,
let's see what Leonard Maltin has to say.
"A film that broke all the rules
and invented some new ones.
The cinematography, music
and Oscar-winning screenplay...
...by Welles and Herman J. Something
are all first-rate."
WOW
So it was a sled, huh?
He should have told somebody.
It's fascinating that
the man had all that stuff...
...but he died, you know, alone,
with nothing and nobody.
Good. Prick.
I hated it. "You supply the war, I'll
supply the headlines." How conceited.
- There was the cinematography.
- Yeah, that was very good.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
I saw Laura Basi in the dressing room
at Loehmann's.
Definitely had some work.
D-cup at least, and a lift.
Well, she said she was remodeling
her upstairs, but I had no idea...
So, Carm, how you doing?
I'm okay.
My lawyer, he's a top guy,
Robert Greenberg...
...he says that New Jersey
has this equitable-distribution law.
So apparently 20 years entitles me
to at least half his money.
Well, it should. You made Tony a home.
You raised his children.
Does this guy know how to get it?
Well, it's mostly cash, obviously.
God. All those years,
and you could get nothing.
This other lawyer, Dan Minditch,
says we should play hardball.
You know, go after the real assets.
Marriage is beautiful in the beginning,
but two, three years later...
You'd think there'd be
some romance, at least.
- Janice, you're a newlywed.
- I know.
Six months, and Bobby
still hasn't found my rosebud.
Maybe he should hire a reporter.
So the movie's over, and they all
start talking about their marriages...
...and how miserable they are.
Bitterness.
So besides the movie night?
- You have kids?
- No.
So did you attend
Carmine Lupertazzi's funeral?
I didn't know him.
Movie night was fun, though.
Who was there at
the Tony Blundetto homecoming?
I told you, just family.
God, is that all you think about,
is your fucking work?
You don't care
how I feel about anything.
Okay.
I was married to an agent.
What happened?
Did he cheat on you?
While we were trying to get pregnant,
he climbed right over me...
...to become an assistant supervisor
on the Milken task force.
Moved to Los Angeles
and jumped a pay grade without me.
My God, that... That's terrible.
So where were we?
What am I doing? I can't talk to you.
I can't even talk to Christopher,
and he's my soul mate.
I can't talk to my friends.
I am being, like, ripped apart here
just snitching on people.
For what? What do I get out of it?
Take comfort in the fact
that you're doing the right thing...
...by helping your government.
No, seriously.
For me, it was when I was in college.
My sister's boyfriend, Kyle,
traded our TV for six handguns.
He sold five to a high school kid, then
used the last one to open a coconut.
The ricochet left my sister a paraplegic.
I knew I had to do something
about guys like him.
Nowhere but the FBI is the line clearer
between the good guys and the bad guys.
And you're with the good guys now.
Jesus.
- Hey.
- T.B.
I didn't call for no linen delivery.
What do I find at the pork store?
A bunch a guys beating the meat.
- Wanna deal me in?
- Absolutely.
- Stakes might be a little high for you.
- You know you can't pay us in napkins.
You gotta let that dry before
you put on a second coat?
Fucking Grandpa Munster over here.
You gonna deal those?
They're not candy bars.
You can let some of them go.
What the fuck's that for? Drying shirts?
That's a TAO master massage chair.
I had no idea I was so tense.
Like my back is on vacation.
Well, it could definitely use one.
What the fuck is this?
- Hey, T, you gotta try this.
- He's really fucking good.
There's nothing like the joint to teach
you how to ease another man's tensions.
I'm gone for one hour...
...all of a sudden it turns
into a fucking slumber party.
Somebody woke up
on the wrong side of the bed.
Can I talk to you a minute?
None of your fucking business
which side of the bed I wake up on.
- Jesus, it's just an expression.
- Bullshit.
You know what I'm talking about.
All that Reggie Van Gleason,
"Boy, are you fat."
Things have changed around here.
I'm the boss of this fucking family.
You're crowding me.
You don't make fun of me, got it?
Got it.
And knock off the massage shit.
It's a place of business,
not a Jack LaLanne.
You gotta declare all that?
Most of it, anyway.
- Well, if you had a good bookkeeper...
- Hey, you got change?
Been sliding this stupid bill in and out
of the cigarette machine for like an hour.
An hour? I bet you
can go longer than that.
Listen to you. Why do you
always talk like a whore?
Because men like it.
Yeah?
I think you're right about that.
I am having a fucking time.
Stay out late, come home drunk,
fuck anyone I want.
Yeah, so, what's the difference?
I don't know. It's a mindset.
Jesus Christ.
Ton, I was hoping you'd be here.
I gotta tell you...
...you shouldn't go out and eat
up there in Fairfield no more.
What the fuck you talking about?
I went to collect from my cop up there,
and he gave me a heads-up.
His buddy on the force saw some car out
by Napoleon's diner a couple weeks ago.
And I remembered how
your goomar lives up there.
- Yeah?
- Guy thought maybe they were fags.
But he ran the plate,
and it bounced back a no hit.
Feds.
Cop said they were
just sitting there in the rain.
I know it wasn't me
they tailed that night.
My whole life's
in the fucking rearview.
- Mine too.
- Absolutely.
It's Massarone.
Jesus Christ. If he flipped, I'd be fucked.
- We all would.
- Well, he ain't been to the grand jury...
...because we would have
heard from our girl up there.
They could be just
following him at this point.
- See if they get anything on him.
- They'll bring him in.
Jesus Christ, they've turned a lot fucking
tougher guys than Jack Massarone.
You want me to take care of it?
All right, we don't know shit yet, right?
He did give me that
fucking painting, though.
- There was that, Ton.
- Can't a guy be fucking nice anymore?
Friendly?
So, what do you wanna do?
I wanna be absolutely fucking sure,
that's what I wanna do.
All right, we arrange a meet.
I'll feel him out a little bit.
I gotta do it. I know the guy.
I know the way he thinks.
I know the way he acts.
My old man was good
at vibing people out too.
If Massarone's up to something,
I'll pick it up.
You piece of shit. I don't believe this.
Hold on.
Yeah?
I wanted to thank you for taking
components out of the home theater.
Hey, I bought that for us to watch
movies as a family, okay?
Not to entertain your girlfriends.
I talked to my lawyer about
filing a separation agreement.
I'm not paying a lawyer! We should
be able to settle this thing like adults!
Then stop taking shit out of the house!
- Hey, Tony, what's up?
- Let's take a walk.
- There he is, huh?
- Hey, how you doing?
- Good, good. How you doing?
- Okay.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah. Watch the curb there.
Hey, wait a second.
Before you say anything...
...have you lost a little weight?
You think? I don't know.
Listen, I talked to our friend. You know,
the one that celebrates Hanukkah.
- It's in the works.
- Oh, great, that's good news. Thank you.
Yeah, yeah.
So I been meaning to ask you...
...you noticed anything lately?
What are we talking about?
You weren't followed here, were you?
No, I... I don't think so.
I'm pretty careful.
All right.
Everything else okay? Good?
- EKG and shit, huh?
- Yeah, I guess.
All right.
But I gotta tell you,
I don't like what I'm hearing.
Relax.
It's not worth losing your hair over.
- Right?
- Okay.
All right.
I couldn't tell shit.
What the fuck am I, a mind reader?
So, what's the next step here, Ton?
What?
Said I looked like I lost some weight.
Motherfucker.
Yeah?
Hey, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, hold on.
That Korean, Kim. Something about
your cousin. I don't know.
Yeah.
It's your fucking linen truck.
What do you want me to do about it?
Yeah, yeah, it's okay.
Fire him. Go ahead.
Put him out in the fucking street
for all I care!
If Tony B. wants to pick up
some scratch...
...he could do this Massarone thing.
If it goes.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
The man is trying to go straight!
Don't you give a fuck about your cousin?
I'm sorry, T, you're right.
That was a great party the other night.
Fuck him.
The guy's fucking useless to me.
Was that a yes on Massarone?
Tony's got his own process.
What's to process here?
Honestly, Carm, this is a lot better
than watching Casablanca.
I didn't need to see
that movie again anyway.
Even if it kills Tony, I will have
that system back for next time.
So, what is next on that list?
Number three, The Godfather.
Look at us. We'll kill ourselves
for these cigarettes.
You know they had a bear back here?
So how come Angie Bonpensiero
don't come?
Please. She's not welcome here.
I thought everybody liked her.
Don't you know about Pussy?
He went in the program.
He turned on everybody.
Us, the people he knew his whole life.
Who knows why people
do what they do.
But what kind of person does that?
I mean, it's like Judas or something.
Eating that last supper with Jesus...
...and the whole time he knows
they're gonna crucify him.
I mean, at least Judas didn't go
into any apostle protection program.
He hung himself. He knew what he did.
Oh, look at you. You're shivering.
I didn't know it was that cold, sweetie.
I'll tell you, I don't know how
I'd be holding up. It's just...
I guess you all
are really important to me.
Carm, you'd do the same.
We love you so much.
Ade? You okay?
What's the matter?
I'm... I'm not what you think.
I don't know what to do.
I need... I want to tell you all something.
It's driving me crazy.
Well, you know you can tell us anything.
Oh, God.
She's been drinking like crazy.
Where are you going?
Oh, my God.
- Honey.
- Oh, my God.
I'm fine, okay? Just leave me alone.
No, you're bleeding. Let me drive you.
Ton? It's like 3 in the morning.
Yeah, yeah, well, I couldn't sleep,
so I wanted to see if the phone worked.
Well, yeah, it works great.
I'm in my mother's basement,
and I can really hear you.
Listen, you should know that
that boss there, Kim...
...he's after your ass.
I rub him the wrong way.
Maybe you shouldn't be
a masseuse then.
Look, Tony, the reason I called,
you know, about the other day...
...look, you can kid around
with me, okay?
But not when the other guys are there.
I gotta maintain respect.
No, I know. You're the boss.
Jesus. See, you gotta be careful
what you say on this phone.
It doesn't affect you, but it affects me.
Right. I'm sorry.
So everything good over there?
You know, my mom's on my case.
Who'd have thought we'd both be
on our own again?
Well, you can get back together
with Carm if you want.
She thinks it's up to her,
and she goes from zero to bitch...
...every time I try to show
any warmth, you know.
That's gotta be tough.
Listen, Ton, I gotta be up in two hours.
So go to sleep.
But you're my cousin
and my best friend.
You gotta know we could always talk.
Yeah, well, I'll buy a fucking lunch box.
All right, go to sleep, go to sleep.
We gotta talk about
my compensation overall.
Interferon for my son's MS?
That's 20 a year now.
Ray, you said you were gonna get us a
making ceremony, which you didn't do...
...and here you are, asking for a raise.
Can't you talk to the higher-ups?
Okay. We make Vito Spatafore...
...as running Ralph Cifaretto's
construction business.
Has Chris ever confirmed that?
- You wanna know something?
- What?
This girl, she's totally
ripping off her employer.
Probably over a hundred grand.
What do you mean?
Tina Francesco's her name.
She's a bookkeeper
for this furniture wholesaler.
She makes up vendors,
but writes them real checks.
Then her father cashes them.
Is that, like, a federal crime?
How many checks? I mean, how much?
Like I said,
probably over a hundred grand.
- Tina?
- Francesco.
The father's name is Victor.
It's Brettler and Sons Imports.