New York's only
classic rock station, Q-1043.
Look at this.
The house sang out to us
of both Miami and Taormina
where we had
our honeymoon.
Nicole said,
let's buy it.
Can just about
smell the salt.
You mean the painting
or the view?
Both.
That's called
the "Trumpay la oil".
Fool the eye.
It was done by an artist right
over here in West Hempstead.
I'll be damned.
Follow me, Jerry.
This little bitch
is for you.
It's a Whirlpool Duet.
Top of the line.
Same as mine.
Nicole is head
over heels with it.
This is above
and beyond, Carmine.
Well, thank my father, too,
may he rest in peace.
This is
for Feeport.
It's a token.
You know it's
my understanding, Carmine,
that Johnny's still
sore about that.
That's why I
appreciate your support.
I'm moved up
here now.
You and me are gonna
do great things together.
Amen.
Daddy!
The boat
is sinking!
Carmine!
My God!
I just sailed her up
from Miami three weeks ago.
She was fine.
You should call
the coast guard, Carmine.
Oh!
Whoa!
Ah!
Oh, shit.
It's okay,
take it easy.
After all these
years of marriage,
you know what you
find yourself thinking
in your
private moments...
Please, God,
let me die first.
I don't
wanna miss him.
Well, he's gonna
be alright.
You're lucky.
In some way,
you've been spared that.
Well, you and Tony
calling it quits now.
Maybe we should
cancel the party.
Maybe he'll be fine
by his birthday.
You know he's turning 75,
ma, that's a milestone.
Ooh.
He's got
some bruising.
Very lucky man.
Those hedges
broke his fall.
But a few days of rest
and he should be fine.
The neurologist is
giving him a final look,
and then you can
take him home.
Thank you
so much, doctor.
Thank God.
Ooh.
His roofing days are over,
I'll tell you that right now.
I guess, huh?
So, uh, what do you
think about the party?
Jeez, Ma, I...
well, I think
we should go for it.
Well, what do you think
about inviting Tony?
Well, that's
the thing.
I don't know if
I should or not.
Everybody would
understand if you didn't.
You're separated.
I know, I know.
But just the idea of
having a family party
in the backyard without
Tony there manning the grill,
playing host,
it wouldn't be the same.
Shh.
It's gonna be
okay, baby.
Why don't they take
care of this man?!
I think it's
a very wise decision.
What decision?
I haven't made one.
I thought I heard
you say that you had.
That he wasn't coming.
Maserati.
Kinda draws
attention, no?
Ah, true.
Friends of ours, most of 'em,
probably wouldn't own it.
It was always
a dream of mine
to own a fine
Italian sports car.
A salut' then.
And in the Guinea gray it,
uh, looks fantastic.
Tops out a 176
miles per hour.
Standing quarter,
13 and change.
How many horses?
390.
What'd that set
you back about, uh...
99 and change.
You're spendin' like
you're already on the throne.
Had a good year.
Oh, God bless.
While we're doin'
car talk here, Phil...
Madonna mi',
he won't let that thing go.
He owed me money
and he was duckin' me.
Look, I'm not
sayin' you're wrong.
Phil treats nickels
like manhole covers.
Believe me, I know.
But the captains
loyal to me
need to know I stand
behind them right now.
Fuckin' little Carmine.
This asshole's givin' away
washing machines.
You believe that?
He don't have collision
insurance, fuckin' Phil?
His son-in-law's
a broker.
They let it lapse
lookin' for a better rate.
Fuckin' idiot.
Tony, I ruled
in your favor.
The racetrack.
The money
Philly owed you.
Well if
I'm payin' for it
we do it at pussy's
or we don't do it at all.
His wife's runnin'
the body shop now.
So I can at least
control expenses.
Thanks.
Come on.
Get in, take ya
for a ride.
Fuckin' thing's
so powerful,
I had to take a lesson
from the dealer last night.
Pretty low.
How does Ginny
like the car?
She loves it.
But she hasn't
drivin' with me yet.
With her knee,
she has a little trouble
gettin' into the seat.
Ho.
Tony.
Hey, Ang'.
How are ya?
Good.
Listen, a friend of mine
banged up his car pretty good
so I was thinkin',
you know,
maybe help us both out
and, uh, throw
a little business your way.
You didn't need
to come down.
You just could've
phoned me.
The thing is, I gotta
pay for the repairs.
Long story.
I distracted him
while he was drivin'.'
Anyway, the point
bein' that, uh,
anything you can do
to keep costs in line,
would be a big
help to me.
Well, you look like
you're doin' pretty good
since we had
that phone call, uh,
you know, you asked me could
you take over puss's body shop.
Thank you
for that, Tony.
You didn't
have to say yes,
with all the other kinda
business you do through here.
Uh, anyway,
his name is Phil,
and, uh, Carmela
sends her love.
Please say hello...
Finally.
I left a message
I was gonna come by.
Well, I got in late.
Girl called
in sick.
You should
get a new one.
Have a seat.
May I get you
anything?
How's your father?
Much better.
Oh, thanks.
He'll be fine for
the party, thank God.
Well, that's good.
What party?
75th birthday?
You know, the surprise party
we talked about last summer?
Oh, yeah,
that's comin' up?
Yeah, next Saturday.
But actually that's
why I wanted to come by.
'Cause I think maybe
it would be best...
be easier, anyway,
for both of us, if uh...
If I went
at it alone.
And not have
you there.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, you know my father
would love to have you there,
you know he's crazy
about your sausages
and all the rest
of it, but...
I thought, uh,
you know, why put us and...
and people in an
uncomfortable situation.
Well, I decided right away when
we broke up I wasn't comin'.
Really?
I'm so glad
you understand.
It was hard for me
to come to this decision
let alone tell you.
Well, I'd like
to contribute, anyway.
No, mom and I are
taking care of it.
For Hugh's 75th?
I insist.
You know, I would rather see
you go back to your therapist.
I'd like to see you
go to a therapist.
And I'm not
the only one.
Oh, really?
Well, you can tell them all
that I can't afford it.
Well, it's not really
your business anymore,
whether I go
or what!
Brought you some
Danish and coffee.
Fuckin' medication.
I can't think.
Can't stay awake.
It don't have
that side effect.
But it'll help
your outlook
if you take it consistently
like you're supposed to.
What's on?
It said in the guide
it's an Italian movie.
But even with the captions
I can't tell what's what.
They had Jesus hangin'
off a helicopter.
But you could
tell it was a dummy.
You know who I saw
at the bakery?
How the fuck
could I know?
Rosalie Aprile.
Said they're havin'
a surprise party
for Carmela's father
next week.
He's gonna be 75.
You get an invite?
No, but we go way back
to when Moses wore short pants.
I better
call Hugh.
Tell him not
to expect me.
It's a surprise
party, Jun'.
What, are we children?
Anyway, at our age
it's enough surprise
we're still alive
every morning.
What city and state, please?
In West Orange.
DeAngelis, Hugo.
The call can automatically
be completed by pressing one,
for an additional
charge of.35¢.
What the fuck.
It's over anyhow.
Hello?
Hugo, como esta?
Who is this?
Corrado Soprano.
Oh, ho ho ho.
Corrado.
How are ya?
How am I.
I'm a prisoner
in my own home,
is how I am.
What do
we live for?
Yeah.
Anyhow, I wanted
to wish you abuona fortuna,
and also send
you my regrets.
I'd love to be
at your jubilee.
Junior.
Jubilee?
But the federal government
says I can't leave the house,
and my family
keeps me sedated.
Bobby told me
it was a surprise party
but I told him, I go,
at our age
it's enough surprise
every day when we get up
in the mornin', right?
Ohh,
I suppose so.
So Happy Birthday,
my friend, and many more.
Arrivederci.
To think, when I got
outta the joint,
I thought an airbag
was Paulie Walnuts.
How'd we do this week?
Good.
The Acura dealer,
what's his name,
he took 20 units.
Carlo gave me
the okay to make
some personnel changes
at the warehouse.
Your call.
I don't know.
The airbag thing.
It earns good.
It's not hard work,
Christ knows, but...
But what?
Think I could be of a lot more
service to you in other areas.
And gettin' straightened out
wouldn't hurt neither.
Just eat what's on
your plate right now.
I mean, Christ,
what's it been, a month?
I'm a team player,
cousin.
I'm Charlie Hustle.
If that's what
you want I'll do it.
Look.
If you need
some money...
Get the fuck
outta here.
Alright.
Let's go get a drink.
What should I get Hugh DeAngelis
for his birthday?
I was thinkin' cigars
but then I figured
you were probably
gonna bring some.
Well, actually
I decided not to go.
In light of the situation,
I went, I saw Carm,
I told her I thought
it'd be best if I sit it out.
Hi, Phil.
Joe.
Where's your
brother-in-law, doll?
I wouldn't know.
Hey, Phillip,
how the hell are ya?
How's the neck?
Where's the car?
We all passed a lotta water
since the old days, huh?
I was away when all that shit
went down with your brother.
What the fuck
happened?
We don't like
to talk about it.
Your car's
in here, Phil.
It's all set.
What the fuck
is this?
It was a front-end
collision, Phil.
This new paint
isn't as brilliant.
It's factory paint,
same as original.
It is different,
it's duller.
Something's off
with the seat.
What is it, Phil?
Feels off kilter.
Try it, Joey.
You're right,
it's off its axis.
It reclines
strange, too.
Try it.
Nobody said anything
about the seats.
This is unacceptable.
Come on, Joey.
Give me a call when you
get the job done, alright?
A couple of
days, Phil.
Phil, we did
what was asked of us.
Call me when
it's done right.
So dad,
how does dinner
at Vesuvio's sound
for your birthday
next week?
Just us.
We'll come here first
for the presents,
and then we'll
go over there.
Sure, sure.
That sounds fine.
Did somebody
tell you something?
I know all about it.
You can save
the cloak and dagger.
Huh, what?
Junior Soprano
told me all about it.
That miserable
fucking man.
Ugh!
You don't know
the half.
Relax.
I'm fine
with knowin'.
At my age,
it's surprise enough
to be able to get
outta bed every morning.
So who's comin'
to this shindig?
Goddamn him!
All of us, your brother,
Lester, Dr. Fegoli...
Russ Fegoli?
He's in town?
He retired from
the foreign service.
But they were livin' out
in marin country or wherever.
Well, they
settled on Jersey.
Octavia, the oldest,
lives here.
Wait, who's Dr. Fago?
Fegoli.
Feg.
She of the five page
Christmas card.
"...and on flag day,
papa Russ shook hands
with Andrew Cuomo..."
What an honor.
B.F.D.
The Fegoli kids
finished college.
That's what sticks
in your craw.
What sticks in
my craw is that
when he got that medal
you two weren't even
invited to the ceremony.
It was out
in California.
They knew that
your father
doesn't like to be
out of his element.
Now, here's someone we can
all be proud of, Anthony.
Dr. Fegoli served
in the state department.
In Rome, he was
career assistant
to the ambassador
to the Vatican.
He got a medal
from the Pope himself.
Wow.
But when we were kids
together in the Navy,
he had such a bad
case of the crabs
we used to call him
the governor of Maryland.
Hey, Hugh, stop
acting like a child.
Oh, lighten up.
He's old enough
to hear.
She's right,
knock it off.
Who else is comin'?
Freddy di Novi...
Tony'll love him.
Who else?
Dad, Tony isn't
coming to the party.
Why won't he come?
Well, I felt that, uh,
since we're separated,
we should get used to the idea
of living separate lives.
Oh, that's
a crock a shit.
Hugh, don't talk
to her like that.
This is very
difficult for her.
I've known the man
for 20-something years!
It's his house!
How is it gonna look?
I talked to Tony about it,
he's in agreement with me.
Because you put
the screws to him.
Fine, I'll cancel
the party.
Go right the hell ahead
because I'm not comin'
if the man of
the house isn't there.
Yeah?
Tony, it's Angie.
We did all the repairs
you said on Phil's car.
He came today
and now he found
a dent in the rear.
His seat, there's
a problem with that.
His seat?
I didn't wanna get
into these extras
without checking
with you.
Ang', honey, you wanna run
a body shop, run a body shop.
You said could you claim
your piece of the garage.
So you wanna be
a woman in business,
then do what you think
the situation calls for.
I just wanna put
my kids through college.
That's a good thing, Ang'.
You know some women left alone
like that would've given up.
Tony, before I outlay
for these costs,
yeah, I need to know...
ang', I'm not there,
what do I know?
It's your call.
Ton'?
What's up?
Pussy's body shop is
one of your stops, right?
Well they're fixin'
the fuckin' Shah of Iran's car.
Uh, can you be there
when he picks it up?
Make sure he's happy,
but don't let the shit
spiral out of control.
Right.
I'll take care of it.
Thanks.
On my way to Welsh Farms,
get a triple blueberry sundae.
Good for you.
Enjoy.
Hot summer night.
Go for it.
You deserve it.
Alright, yeah.
I'll talk to ya later.
Opus.
Fine choice.
Angelo, here,
spoke very highly of you
and how you handled yourself
with him in Pennsylvania.
That's why I
wanted to meet you.
We were like
frick and frack in the can.
Angelo's my buddy.
He knew all the Jackie Gleason
stuff by heart.
He acted all
the parts hisself.
Do a little bit
for rusty.
The Mambo thing.
Mambo?
Oh!
Carlos was teaching
you the Mambo?
That's a
different story!
Get out!
So how's your
reentry been?
You doin' okay?
Yeah.
Tony's been
good with me.
I always liked
your cousin.
He's a real gentleman.
Angelo's lookin'
out for you, too.
I told rusty that you
might need a little earn.
Well, yeah, I could use
a little cash injection.
Maybe a push up
the pyramid.
You know,
time served.
We need
somethin' done.
Nice little
payday for you,
and an opportunity for you to
hone that rep you left behind.
And this involves?
Somebody needs to go.
Anyone I know?
New York guy,
not Jersey.
Who's he with?
Friend of a friend.
Not a friend of ours.
Friend of Johnny's.
You guys gotta
settle that shit.
It's not the boat.
It's Lorraine Calluzzo.
Rainey Calluzzo.
Little Carmine
went to school with her.
They go back
that far.
Kill a woman.
Come on.
I can't sign on
right now.
I wanna give my cousin
the benefit of the doubt.
He don't want us involved in
this problem over here anyway.
Why don't you think
about it for a bit?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
But thanks, guys.
We had a big talk
over here the other day
and the consensus seems
to want your presence
at my father's party.
Well, that's nice but
it's kinda short notice now.
Look, it's for
my father, not me.
I made plans to go
fishin' with sil.
Well, he really
wants you there.
If you could find
a way to make it,
I know he would
be very happy.
He's very
fond of you.
The New York Salsicc',
hickory wood, whatever.
You're not
usin' Artie?
Yeah, I got him doin'
appetizers and salads,
but, uh, he's really
there as a guest.
I am cooking.
Tomorrow's gonna
be a mad house,
just, living hell.
I don't know, I'll...
I'll see
what I can do.
Thank you, Tony,
I appreciate it.
Uh, Jerry say
to refrigerate.
Okay.
I think there is
room in the garage.
Hey, carm.
Tony.
I know you're
shorthanded, uh,
I thought you might need
some help around here today.
It's my weekend
with the boys.
They'll stay
out of the way.
Aunt Carmela's nice enough
to let you guys enjoy her pool,
and you wanna
destroy her property.
It's a beach chair.
It can get wet.
Don't get smart!
You wanna go home?
What can I do?
Ah, the dips.
I forgot the dips.
I gotta duck out later.
I could pick some up
for you at grand union.
Grand union closed
its doors 10 years ago.
You know what,
frig the dip.
They're gonna have
to survive with salsa.
Can I make you
a cocktail?
I make a mean
rusty nail.
Now?
Thanks again for lettin'
the kids take a swim.
Aw, sure.
Anytime,
you know that.
Cheers.
They love bein' here.
This is truly
a beautiful home.
What, are you here,
five years now?
I asked you
to get up at 11.
We got a lot
to do today.
Oh, you were
supposed to send this
to Mr. Wegler
for summer school.
Put it down!
Greetings,
birthday people.
You are here,
which is great.
You can help
with the set-up.
Hi, Mrs. Soprano.
Uh, uh, finn this
is our Uncle Tony.
Tony this is
Meadow's friend, Finn.
Hey.
What are you doing?
I'm making grandpa's favorite
maple-walnut icebox cake.
We have cake.
Jerry just...
why don't you
take a swim?
I know you're hot.
Do you have a towel?
I'll bring you
a coffee, too.
I'll be outside.
Cake pan?
Meadow, I have
a lot to do today.
Hello?
I'm making dessert,
to help?
Seems like
a nice guy.
Yep.
Any luck with Kelly?
I been scourin'
the Internet for any trace.
Here is your
cake pan.
And you're gonna
clean up your baking mess.
I can imagine how much
you must miss her.
Your only daughter.
What was she like 11
when she lived with you guys?
We had her 12th birthday party
right before she moved out.
How'd she do
in school back then?
Straight A's.
Oh, my God, what is
the matter with them?!
Don't lift that by yourself,
Hugh, wait for some help.
What are you
doing here?
You always
do this!
The party is
not for hours!
He needs help.
What am I
doin' here?
I'm returning
your port-a-vac.
You said
you needed it.
Happy Birthday,
grandpa.
Later for that,
get your Uncle out here.
He left, he said he told you
he had to bolt for a minute.
He asked us to
watch the twins.
Here, help me
with this.
Oh, my goodness,
what a bother.
Excuse us for living.
How ya doin'?
I'm Tony.
Oh, yeah, the other
Tony's cousin, right?
It reclines
perfectly, try it.
Fuck that.
I don't feel like
I'm sittin' at 12 o'clock.
You're sittin'
at 12 o'clock.
May I?
I don't
give a fuck.
You can sit in there
'til fuckin' St. Gennaro.
It'll still need
to be dealt with.
This car went through
a major collision.
Seems okay.
How could it be
okay if it's askew?
What's the matter, Joey,
you got a fuckin' eye problem?
Look like Stevie Wonder
your eyes rollin' around.
Aw, what'd I say?
I didn't say
nothin', Phil.
Replacin' the seat
will cost a fortune.
Give me
a break, Phil.
The seat is fine.
You just have a problem
with the grain
on the leather
from the factory.
You think
I'm stupid?
Ho, ho!
Don't take
it out on me.
Come on, Joey.
Hey, Phil.
Now, how about this.
They replace the tracks
under the seat,
maybe throw in
a cd player in the dash.
We already
did that.
We replaced
the tracks.
He's got a
cd player.
Jesus God, Duke,
they're hosin' us for
a 2,000 dollar factory seat.
Come on, Joey.
Tony, nice
to meet ya.
Come on,
you comin'?
Joe, try to keep
him cooled down.
Here ya go,
Fredy.
Get it, Jason,
come on!
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Ma, what?
Dr. Fegoli, Russ.
What?
He's allergic
to tomatoes.
Alright, so we
will deal with it.
Jesus.
Don't you have any hors d'oeuvres
without tomatoes?
The prosciutto-wrapped
chevre.
Rosalie just
took 'em out.
An Italian allergic
to pommodori.
Dio mio.
You have
my sympathies.
Well, it wasn't
always like this.
Started when they gave me
radiation for my prostate.
Don't ask me why.
So did you know
Monsignor Kelly?
He was in charge of the tours
at all the catacombs?
I made you
a plate, Russ.
Thank you, Mary.
You know, Carmela's
mother-in-law, Livia,
detested
northern cooking.
Really, why?
She skeeved
the butter.
The father was
like that, too.
The whole Soprano
bunch over there.
So many Neopolitans and
Sigilian' feel that way.
Well, you really have
to go to Italy to know,
and so many
of them don't.
I ate like a champ all
the way up and down the boot.
The whole two weeks.
But those recipes that you
used to send me from Tuscany.
Lena...
My God,
they were a revelation.
Bollito misto,
osso bucco...
Mmm.
The lovely Carmela Soprano.
Would you like
to say a few words?
Oh, he's back,
thank God.
Will you get
the guests arriving?
See?
And where
the hell is Tony?
Have a glass
of wine, carm.
Calm you down
a little.
He is bringing the charcoal
and the sausage.
He's always gotta wait
'til the last minute.
I heard that.
Agh, finally.
Hi, Tony.
Got no faith in me.
I wonder why?
Pins and needles,
needles and pins.
Palumbo's.
The birthday boy's
favorite.
Where is he?
He's out back.
Oh, good.
Honey, try
to pace yourself...
'Fritto misto bacala,
a couple of meatballs too...
Hey, there he is!
Hey, Happy Birthday to Hugh,
got sazeecha for you!
Russ, wait'll ya
taste this stuff.
There's nothin'
else like it.
Tony, I want you to meet a
couple of our oldest friends,
Dr. Russ and Lena Fegoli.
Nice to meet you, sir.
My son-in-law, well,
whatever, Tony Soprano.
Hey.
A doctor
in the house, huh?
That's good,
'cause somebody usually
goes down at these things.
He's just joking.
Unfortunately my doctorate
is in international affairs.
From Princeton.
G.I. Bill.
So you're a doctor like,
uh, Kissinger's a doctor.
Yes.
Russ had an audience
with four Popes.
What section
did you all sit in?
Aw, idiot.
T.B., make sure you
shoot the food tables
before they're pillaged.
Well, I'd, uh...
Love to stay and chat,
but I got a fire to start.
Nice to meet ya, doc.
Nice to meet you.
Everybody!
Could you gather
'round please?
Everybody,
everybody!
Come on over.
I would like to make a toast
to the man of the hour.
A very special man.
A man who I love
more than words
could possibly say.
My father.
Here-here.
You are the best father
and grandfather in the world.
Salut'.
Speech!
You are the greatest,
my little Melly.
Thank you
for everything.
Mm-hm.
Tony, thank you for
having us at your home.
Mar', my lovely bride.
Still the prettiest
girl in the world.
Thank you for puttin' up
with me all these years.
Aww.
Thank all you
freeloaders for coming!
So why don't you
open up your gifts, dad?
Not now, Carmela,
it's very,
uh, mercenary.
Well good, people
spent money on them.
I'll break the ice.
Here.
Open this one.
It's from him.
Aw, you're too much.
A Stratocaster?
Awww.
A Beretta.
Ooh, aww...
Shotgun, oh wow.
This is...
I don't know
what to say.
It's a Giubileo
12-gauge.
28 inch barrel.
Nice to have money.
Get me another
rolling rock, Jay.
What time did you
start drinkin' today?
Probably right
after you got up.
Ho, cuz!
Tony, can you bring
the camera over here
and get a shot
of this?
Sure, I got nothin'
better to do.
Expect a freezer full
of venison this year.
You got it, kid.
Beautiful piece.
The over-under action,
the engraving,
they're artisans.
And you know, I've been to
the Beretta studio in Brescia.
No kiddin'.
I'd love
to see that.
You know that company
goes back to the 1500s.
Madonn'.
Sure, the best pieces,
they never export,
you see.
I want one and
all here to know
what a wild man
Hugo was in his day.
Remember what he did at the bund
meeting in Paterson, Russ?
Threw that cherry bomb
on those Krauts?
Yeah, tell that one.
You made my father's year
with that gun.
He deserves it.
You look beat, Tony,
why don't you take a break?
Nah, I'm alright.
Could use
a beer, though.
Well, you got it.
Thanks.
Salut'.
How's that look?
Done?
You're the grillmeister.
I mean don't
get me wrong.
I still think
we have the greatest
legal system
in the world.
But it's becoming more
and more discriminatory.
I mean, if you're
a minority, or worse,
an immigrant from
an Arab country,
civil rights
don't apply at all.
No place is the breach
of civil rights
more evident than
the penal system.
Rehabilitation?
Please.
Yeah.
That nature of the system
instills a convict mentality
to the point where prison
becomes the only venue
where the convict
can function.
My little
bleedin' heart.
She is wise
beyond her years.
She better be.
All the money
I'm spendin' over
at liberal university
in sunny Harlem.
Come here.
How you doin'?
Good.
Yeah?
Remember when you
were a little girl
what I used
to call you?
What do you mean
you don't remember?
You were too young
to remember?
Don't!
No!
How come you
don't remember?
Remember what I used
to call you, huh?
Ooh.
Hey, ow!
You know Hugh
built this house?
Your friend's maxin' out the
situation down there at puss's.
Sure.
Factory seat.
Two K.
I tried.
Well, I'd hate to see ang'
get stuck with that.
Then again, her friend
over there is takin' me
to the cleaners
with this divorce shit.
I gotta belt-tighten.
Can we get some able-bodied
seamen over here?
Tony b?
What am I,
a fuckin' slave?
Ho!
I didn't have a drop.
Goddamnit.
Lester'll drive,
he's in the bathroom.
Watch your head.
Hey!
Virginia Mayo.
Thank you
for coming.
I'm sorry for everything,
what can I say?
Get my boy
home safe.
You're sorry
for what?
Aw...
No-no I wanna hear.
Oh, please, Carmela.
The off-colored jokes,
the sausage twirling...
Tony.
These are
cultured Italians.
Russ is a success,
a diplomat.
This was a shock
for them.
And he's such a diplomat
he insults his host?
You heard what
he said to Tony.
He's a pompous man.
He always was.
Let's talk about
this another time.
That's why you
didn't want Tony here.
Had nothin' to do with
the marital situation.
All along it was so that
your cultured Italian friends,
who were born and raised
on Arthur Avenue I might add,
wouldn't meet your
"gavone" son-in-law.
He made us all
look like "gavones".
Whatever we are
I am proud of it,
unlike you obviously.
I have always been
proud of my heritage.
Oh, bullshit.
I remember you telling
aunt rose you were glad
deangelis didn't
end in a vowel.
I never said that!
And when meadow came out,
"oh my God, she's so dark".
You're drunk.
I'm going home.
You know, there are
Italians all around
with their closet
selfloathing.
I just never wanted to believe
my mother was one of 'em.
And now what the fuck
are you crying about?
You're secret is out.
Marco.
Polo.
Marco?
Fish outta water!
You're it, Ton'!
Takin' a T-O.
Marco.
Polo.
Here let me...
let me get this.
No, I'm fine.
You have fun.
No, no, really.
Let me...
Forget it, I'll get it.
Tony, put me down!
You look like
you could use a dip!
No, don't you,
I'm serious!
One.
one.
Aj!
Two.
Tony, don't!
Three!
You bastards!
You're it, carm.
Whoo!
Idiots.
Hey, don't
let her get out.
Ho! '
You're still it!
Marco.
Polo.
Alright.
Pleasant dreams,
Hammers.
Night, dad.
Goodnight, grandma.
Goodnight.
Your grandma's
not a maid.
I'll put 'em
in the hamper.
What's this?
I don't know.
Yes, you do.
Shut up.
Am I talkin'
to you, Justin?
I asked you
a question, Jason.
Pins.
From the '96 Olympics
in Atlanta it looks like.
That's when you were stationed
in Saudi Arabia, right, dad?
Yes, that's right.
But I'm talkin'
to your brother.
You took this tonight,
didn't you?
I borrowed it
from AJ.
You stole this from your cousin
who opens his house to you?
I found it on the floor
way in back of AJ's closet.
He doesn't care.
With all
the stuff he has?
He got to go to the Olympics
and everything.
I love
where he lives.
I don't wanna
come back here.
My son steals
from his own family.
You're gonna return it
tomorrow and apologize.
Where are
your gameboys?
That's mine.
Jason's is
in the drawer.
I'm givin' both of these
to the Salvation Army.
I didn't do nothing!
You're just as bad as he is
'cause you didn't stop him!
We should
get going, AJ.
I don't wanna drop you off
at Patrick's too late.
Call me when you
get to Patrick's.
Yeah, I'll try.
He's in
a bad cell area.
He'll try?
Just showin' her
he's not a kid.
Mm...
I think he's showin'
her more than that.
Well, that's inevitable.
It's scary is
what that is.
He'll be fine.
He's in love.
Oh, please.
You know what
it's like at that age.
Hmm?
Can't wait
to see each other.
Can't keep your
hands off each other.
Tony, what are
you doing?
What am I doin'?
Tony, let's
call it a night.
Why?
You tired?
Yes.
Come on.
Artie is right
over there.
He's comatose.
Tony...
This is nice, no?
Doesn't feel nice?
I didn't say that.
No, Tony, don't.
Shh...
So which type of,
uh, torture instrument
we going to use?
Don't wake up
the neighbors.
Yeah.
You have to go where you
have like a two-by-four...
Hello?
Blundetto.
How can I help you?
I'm in.
You asleep?
Here you go, Joey.
It's bigger
than last week's.
Hey, Crystal.
The room is empty.
Come on,
time is money.
Thanks.
Phil'll be
very happy.
Yeah.
Send him and John
my best, huh?
Goodnight, Heather.
Goodnight, Muz.
You're off?
Yeah.
I'm goin' downtown.
Me, too.
Let's go.
See ya next week, Joe.
Hey, Joe.
Hey.
Tony, right?
What, you
come here, too?