That's so funny!
No, it isn't.
You just poked me in the eye!
Well, you poked me first.
I can't find the thing.
Here.
I don't know what the fuck
happened to the DeWALT.
Everything disappears around here.
Especially now that I'm out of the house,
she lets everything go.
Stop! Stop, Uncle Tony,
it's freezing cold!
Uncle Tony, knock it off!
She wants to talk to me
about something.
Thanks for having us up here, Ton.
Jason, don't put pine cones in the filter.
The hell's the matter with you?
No, Dad, watch me!
- He's hitting me!
- Hey! What did I say?
They will probably go through
their entire lives...
...not knowing their father's sperm...
...was smuggled out of jail
to get Nancy pregnant.
It was the least I could do.
I just remembered what happened
to the power drill.
- Pardon me?
- I loaned it to your cousin, Brian.
And he never gave it...
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Is this one of your attacks?
No, I...
I think it's just indigestion.
It's going away.
I had an attack. Full-blown.
- What'd your therapist say?
- I don't see her no more.
- Why not?
- You think you're the only one...
...that has to cut back on shit they need
because of the separation?
Now, what's on your mind?
Mr. Wegler wants us to come to discuss
A.J.'s lousy academic performance.
Is this the same Wegler?
Last year, the riccion
with the Billy Budds?
A.J. got him as a college advisor.
- I told him to start cracking the books.
- Was he supposed to do that...
...after he got back from the Nets game
you took him to on a school night?
It's gotta be hard for him, our situation.
Cut him some slack.
No, that's your department.
I get to be the prison warden over here...
...while you indulge him.
With the iPod, the drums...
Oh, again with the drums. Encourage
extracurricular activity, you said.
Brand-new drums, just like that?
Don't even look in the classifieds.
Why don't you just tell me
when the school meeting is.
Because I don't have to listen to this shit
anymore. That's why we're separated.
Are you kidding me, Tony?
That is not why!
Jas?
Were you knocking?
Hi, Lorraine. I'm Billy.
The fuck?! Jason!
No! Jason!
Jason!
Oh, no!
You were warned, Lorraine.
The money goes up to John.
Fuck.
Lorraine Calluzzo and the kid, Jason.
Fucking Philly Leotardo!
She told me he warned her...
...about giving us points of her take.
Phil's a pimple.
It's goddamn Johnny Sack.
It's his message to the other captains,
that fucking animal.
- Take it easy.
- Fuck that.
Rusty.
Car's here.
I'm telling you, Carmine.
We go all out,
we'll steamroll right over John.
And I predict the guys on the street
in Brooklyn and Queens...
...they'll welcome us as fucking heroes.
It'll be easy.
It's a fucking declaration of war
by Johnny, if you ask me.
Hey.
There he is.
- Let me kiss the ring.
- How about the one in my ass?
- Hey. Good to see you.
- Feech. Good to see you, baby.
Hello there, kid. Good to see you.
- Hey. How are you?
- Hey. How you doing, Feech?
Just talking about that mess
over in New York.
Sounds to me like your friend John
wants to force Little Carmine's hand.
In my day, the top spot would have
gone to Little Carmine.
Unless he was actually retarded,
or crippled or something.
- He's the son.
- Come on, when was that?
Yeah?
- Vodka rocks.
- Thank you, dear.
- Anybody else?
- We need anything else...
...one of the kids'll come out.
Ton? You didn't have any lunch.
- You want a sandwich?
- No, I'm all right. Thanks.
Adriana, hold on a second.
Tommy Pinto's goomar, eh?
When I was coming up...
...she had the long legs up to here,
like that.
Famous beauty. Smart as a whip.
- My compliments.
- Oh, that'd be beautiful.
- Thank you, baby.
- You drove Tommy Pinto?
I was at the Clam Broth House
the night he beat that longshoreman...
...to death over a corner table.
No shit?
Here we go. Memory lane.
It's important these young guys
know the history.
Tell them about when Tony and Jackie
Aprile knocked over your card game.
- Oh, that he doesn't like to talk about.
- I heard this.
- This is a great fucking story.
- He should be dead by now.
They bust in, couple of fucking punks.
Guns out. Bad guys.
This one is fucking scared!
- First of all, it was my game.
- Feech has forgiven...
...even if he hasn't forgotten.
But it's a great yarn, right, Feech?
Yeah.
Actually, it brings me to my business.
Fellas, you wanna give us
a minute, here?
Yeah.
So, what's up?
I came to ask for my game back.
- It's my uncle's game now, Feech.
- Yeah, right, your uncle's.
You also keep a lion's share of the rake.
I'm, in a way,
just asking if I can run it for you.
Why would I need that?
Eleven years I ran it.
No fights, no raids.
Not to mention that
maybe I got it coming.
Considering how it could have gone
after you took the game down...
...if I had been a prick about it.
Or his old man didn't have many friends.
I'll give you 20 percent,
but you gotta rent the house from me.
I could throw some high rollers
your way.
Friends of mine.
All right. Let me get out of here
before I keep talking...
...and fuck this up. Jesus.
Thank you, Don Antonio.
He's a strunz.
He's a busybody, that's all.
He's an egomaniac, Ton.
Always was, always will be.
Nothing's ever good enough.
Praise, money.
Comes in this fucking office,
starts ordering people around.
He's old.
How do you think that feels?
Can I go to the Mudvayne concert
or not?
I'm trying to think of a reason to let you
stay overnight in New York with friends.
But it's not gonna happen.
Todd's mother made arrangements.
She said it'd be better than us driving.
She's not your mother.
Yeah, I know. Believe me.
Isn't life unfair?
So we're at the Peppermint Lounge.
When in walks
these two stewardesses from Braniff.
Everybody's in? Aces high.
Your action, Mr. Taylor.
- Two hundred.
- Hesh?
They're sitting at the bar.
We send them over a bottle of Dom.
Next thing you know, we're in the hotel
room. Me, Frankie and the two broads.
I see you. Raise you three.
- You mother...
- This one...
...this little pothead from Texas,
she fucked me dry.
But she still wanted more!
She's fucking nuts.
So I'm wearing these pointy
featherweights, and I stick the toe in.
- And I'm fucking her with it.
- Don't know where the story's heading...
...but we should all be grateful
he wasn't wearing white bucks.
The maid walks in, and she says,
"What's going on?"
And I say...
Ante up, boys.
Hello, girls!
- Hey.
- Hey, Ton.
- Sir Lawrence from the Meadowlands.
Your Highness. How are you?
Tony, let me introduce
Bernie Brillstein.
- Hey.
- Did you get my list of toys?
- What's up?
- Hey, Ton.
Oh, my cousin.
Kind of high stakes for you, no?
Feech fronted my action.
And thank you for not humiliating me.
Is there something in your parole about
hanging out with degenerates like this?
Hey, come on,
he gets away with anything.
Last time his parole officer
made the unannounced visit...
...he gave him a massage.
- So how's lady luck treating you, huh?
- Jesus-fucking-Christ.
How many times
this guy gotta say hello?
What, did I interrupt
one of your impermeable stories?
Go ahead.
So we had these girls in the hotel room.
Long story short...
...I got my shoe in her snatch...
It falls off and she keels over.
Fuck it. This hand's from thalidomide.
Three ladies, gentlemen.
- Thank you.
- The rich get richer.
So, doc, how's the plans
for the wedding?
Please.
It's not a "wedding planner" anymore.
It's an
"environment and event coordinator."
What the hell? She's my only daughter.
She and Iris have their hearts set...
...on making the "Vows" column
of the Sunday New York Times.
Featured couple of the week.
Our publicist is looking for a hook.
Turns out that Gillian's law degree
from Harvard means bupkis.
Everybody's got that or better.
If it was a black couple or a gay couple,
they'd be in.
My wife calls the Times wedding section
the ladies' sport page.
So, Ira, who's the lucky guy?
Jeremy Silverman. Puppeteer.
Children's Television Workshop.
Father's Asa Silverman. Head of
commercial paper at Goldman Sachs.
- Upper East Side.
- I didn't get my invitation.
Fuck you.
You told me to let you know
when it was a quarter of.
Thank you, Mary.
So with Wesleyan as your fallback,
I think we're in pretty good shape.
Straight A's at Middlebury's
language camp, can't sneeze at that.
And your blues folkloric studies
in Mississippi last summer...
...have an almost community service
spin to them.
I just wish he had the minority thing
going for him.
If we can just nudge Lem's verbals
past 760 on the next round...
...he can basically write his own ticket.
I'm stoked.
Appreciate your help.
Folks.
So let me guess.
He called the English teacher "Daddy-O."
Thing is...
...we are rapidly approaching crisis mode
here with these grades.
And time is of the essence.
Could I ask a question?
I handed in my final list of colleges.
- Did you get that?
- Yes, we talked about this.
So Ramapo and Trenton State.
And our reach schools,
University of Arizona and Arizona State.
I'll take him out there after I drive
him around the ones in New Jersey.
If either of the Arizonas is what
he's got his heart set on...
...he's not gonna get in with these
grades. I know about football, Anthony.
- It's our ace in the hole.
- He says he's trying his best.
SAT-wise, 505 and 430...
I think we can edge-up the math
into the fives the next round.
- Providing Anthony feels he can focus.
- He's had trouble with that before.
Remember, Carm,
when they thought he had ADD?
- You didn't tell me that.
- Anthony, head on back to class.
- Let us talk.
- But if I'm learning-disabled...
...I get unlimited time on my SATs.
- Is that true?
- Let's talk about that later.
So you had time to talk to Dr. Rapke
about last week's testing results?
Yes. She said Anthony has
good interpersonal skills.
She said his affect was...
Where is this? Constricted, she called it.
But that was normal for a teenager...
...and all in all,
he seemed to be handling the split well.
This is not to say I don't get
a ration of shit in every conversation.
Pardon my French.
Well, still...
...there's this thing with his grades.
Do you think it would be a benefit to him
to see a psychologist on a regular basis?
You don't approve of therapy,
Mr. Soprano?
People use it as a crutch.
And I always wonder
what happened to Gary Cooper...
...the strong, silent type?
Well...
...Gary Cooper wasn't a 16-year-old boy.
He was at one time.
And I'm gonna have to agree
with my husband, here, Mr. Wegler.
We sent our daughter to an adolescent
developmentalist, and it was a disaster.
I know my son, he's lazy.
We'll get him a different SAT tutor,
I'll stay on him and he'll work harder.
And that's that.
- They said I might be learning-disabled.
- Hey, didn't he tell you to go to class?
What's going on, Mary?
Domenica Paolini and Sasha Caputo.
They were on their way to school
this morning, and they hit a tree.
Nikka's dead. Sasha's in a coma.
What's that?
It was here when I got here.
If a million zeros can be written on
the front and back of a sheet of paper...
...how many sheets of paper do you
need for a googol of zeroes?
Oh, man, oh, baby, an Xterra SE.
It's loaded.
Three-point-three liter, supercharged.
- What, this is mine?
- Yeah.
You are unbelievable.
- Sticker's still on it.
- He doesn't have enough distractions?
After what happened
to those kids at his school?
Thing's got sensors in the seatbelts.
It's part of Nissan's
Triple Safety philosophy.
- Nice ride.
- You leaving?
- Hour's up.
- You're not getting in?
This is so deck.
- What is this, Bose?
- Yeah, six-CD changer.
- It's got surround sound.
- I feel safer already.
Carmela, this car is a tank.
- What's the matter?
- SUVs eat up more of the ozone.
So you wanna be the sucker
in a regular car that gets decapitated.
- I'm gonna catch shit at school for this.
- So, what do you wanna do?
Screw it.
- Can we take it out?
- Yeah, we can take it out.
Once. Then this baby sits in the garage
till you pull your grades up to a C.
- What?
- You heard your father.
I was talking to him, not you.
I gotta put dinner on.
Tony, I have bills for you.
You better be nice to your mother.
She's got the keys
till your grades are up.
I'll be right back.
The car is a motivational tool.
The carrot and the stick,
you gotta do both.
I could strangle him sometimes.
He can be so hateful.
Well, the smart mouth is not good.
That's minor, believe me.
God, what happened to him?
He was always the sweet one.
He had the concept of sharing
before any of the other toddlers.
Well, Meadow was always sharper,
but I remember the same thing with her.
It's like watching an angel fall.
What, are you crying?
Here's the tutor, in writing,
like you had to have.
I had to call Roto-Rooter.
That's the cheap sound system
for the media room.
Yeah, why should I pay for that?
Because you took the last one.
Your little movie connoisseur friends
are still meeting?
- At least I have friends.
- The fuck's that mean?
- Tony, you have a bunch of flunkies.
- What do you know about it?
They compliment you
on your new shoes.
They tell you that you're not going bald.
Think they really care?
You're the boss, they're scared of you.
They have to kiss your ass.
- Laugh at your stupid jokes.
- What about Artie, then?
- You're turning into a frigging cynic.
- Whatever.
What do I give a shit if they're scared.
I'm running a fucking business,
not a popularity contest.
"I been thinking...
...and I apologize for my use
of fowl language..."
Fowl with a "W."
"...in regards to yourself.
You said some very hurtful things to me
in regards to myself.
But it is still no excuse
to use the vile word that I used...
...of which I am sure you know...
...that I'm talking about."
- Cunt, right?
- Yes, Elliot.
"You don't wish us to be social friends...
...and so that is that.
I still have great 'rigard' for you...
...even though you said
some horrible things.
P.S. I'm doing fine. Anthony."
It came with a bathrobe and a basket full
of Dr. Hauschka bath products.
Ablution.
The desire to cleanse himself
of the deed.
Notice he still fundamentally blames me.
- Hello?
- Mrs. Soprano? Robert Wegler.
Oh, hi, hello. How are you?
After our meeting the other day...
...I had some ideas about
some further strategies for Anthony.
I thought maybe we could meet.
Have lunch, a cup of coffee.
I could share them with you.
- Next week, perhaps?
- Really?
Well, yeah, I guess that'll be okay.
"Happy Birthday," by the Beatles.
You know,
I heard it the other day in the car.
They have such a good drum solo
in the middle, there.
Drum solo?
It's the basic four-four.
You know, Ringo was not their original
drummer. That was Pete Best.
And they fired him.
He put out his own album,
Best of the Beatles.
Sad.
So is this what they call
"common ground"?
Just trying to have
a civilized conversation.
Can I go to my room? I'm full.
- Am I so horrible?
- You are not horrible.
Get over yourself.
Over myself?
What is that supposed to mean?
Just go. Do me a big favor.
If you're gonna be a martyr,
I'll sit here.
Nope, go. Put your plate in the sink.
Two hundred.
- Two to go.
- See, and raise four.
Call.
Tony, you like the Escalade?
Can't keep them on the lot.
I love it.
After I pulled out
that global-positioning shit.
- Oh, right.
- Always got his eye on the big picture.
Up to you.
I think you got that ace,
and I'm not paying you for it.
- Aces over.
- Three threes, my man.
Paulie wins.
- Cards, please.
- You fuck, you.
They used to be a great tax loophole,
those SUVs.
Told all my clients,
write it off on your business.
Accountant dies, goes to heaven.
Same time as the pope.
St. Peter says, "Come on in!"
Then he shows the pope this shithouse.
That's where he'll live,
and he gives him a crust of bread.
Then he shows the CPA
where he's gonna live.
It's a fucking mansion. Servants, broads.
Pope says, "He gets a mansion
and I get a hovel?"
St. Peter says, "Your Holiness,
we got hundreds of popes up here.
This is the first Jewish accountant!"
I used to be able to write off condoms.
What do you get when you cross
an accountant with a giant jet airplane?
A boring 747.
All right, all right, bet two.
Algebra, huh?
Listen...
I have been doing some thinking.
I've decided to let you stay in the city
after the concert.
- How come?
- On one condition, though.
No Hudson Suites.
I talked to Med. She said
you can sleep over at her apartment.
I'll give you cab fare. When
the concert's over, go straight up there.
Sunday morning I want you home,
10:30 sharp.
Thanks.
Don't stay up too late.
Come on. Go, go, go. Hurry.
So you guys like your job?
Beemer, space 43.
Asa, come on!
Can I have your attention?
Apparently there's been
an armed robbery.
Some automobiles were taken.
They left all the American cars.
- Oh, my God.
- I think his skull is broken.
- I'm a doctor. Let me in there.
Brooke, our car is gone.
Now who's a genius
for keeping his Regal?
Asa, they got the SL.
That was a fucking SL55 Convertible.
You know how long my brother
was on the waiting list for that?
A motherfucking year.
You want to go back to that?
Yes! I wanna go back to that!
- Hello?
- Hey, it's me.
- How was Mudvayne?
- They rocked.
Look... Look, I don't think
I'm gonna be able to make it up there.
What are you talking about?
You know Mom's gonna call here.
I'm a total dick if I leave here.
Just tell Mom I'm on my way up.
- She's just gonna call back.
- Come on.
- When do I ever ask you for anything?
- All right, you better stay there.
And be home on time tomorrow.
I don't want any shit from Mom.
Stop.
Frida, why do you and Diego
have separate houses?
Because we are two different people,
but our love makes us into one.
- Hello?
- Med, hi.
Is your brother there?
He's not answering.
- I know, he's asleep.
- What?
I probably shouldn't be telling you this,
but he was pretty zapped.
I knew it. Is he all right?
- Mom, he's fine.
- Just wait until you have children.
Not me, I'm never having kids.
So how are things going?
We're in the middle of a movie, Mom.
Oh, I'm sorry. Good night.
Good night.
- Come on, light the fucker up.
- Give me the lighter.
It's on the table.
All right. Go, go, go.
Go, go, go.
Hold it, hold it!
Open up, it's me.
Come on, open the fucking door.
Where's the patient?
I got a new easel, new oils.
I'm ready to go.
The wedding?
What, do you got everybody outside?
- The ushers and everyone? Bring them in.
- It's a fucking disaster.
- What?
- Somebody hit us.
They stole all the fucking cars.
I had to sedate my own little girl
at her wedding.
- Jesus.
- Yeah, I mean, they had one of those...
...what do you call it,
those car-carrier things?
It was a very well-coordinated
operation.
The cops are on it,
but how much faith have I got in that?
You gotta help me
before they're chopped.
I'm not really in that business, Ira.
Asa's brother's Benz was taken.
This special thing.
I'm fucking gornisht
in Asa's eyes now.
Can't you do anything?
I mean, make some calls?
- That shit's insured.
- He's obsessed with that car.
This fucking Stew guy.
The asshole paid a $30,000 premium
just to place the fucking order.
His glasses, his daybook were in it.
A.J., it's your mother. Call me.
It's my mother.
Ma'am, I can't put you through.
Room 417 has a block on the line.
I am not waiting.
Who knows what's going on.
God help you if anything happens in
there like those children in Westchester.
No! No, don't answer it.
My face is stuck to the rug.
They fucking Krazy-Glued you.
- Housekeeping.
- Oh, fuck, what should we do?
- We're asleep!
- All right, help me.
- Dude, take it easy.
- I'm sorry, man.
Fuck.
Oh, dude.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, fuck me.
- Hello.
- Hi, yeah, it's me.
A.J. stayed in the city with his friends
last night, and he's not home yet.
- And I can't get in touch with him.
- Take it easy. Slow down.
He's probably just sleeping it off.
No, I called Todd's mother
and Todd came home.
He could be dead by now. OD'd.
God knows what else.
- God, why did I let him go?
- He's all right.
I'll take care of it.
- Give me the number of the hotel.
- It's Hudson Suites on the West Side.
Tony, just go there, all right? I'm
so worried I'm not even angry anymore.
All right, all right. I'm on my way.
Anthony?
Goddamn you! I have been going crazy
trying to reach you.
- Later, I don't feel good.
- What happened to your face?
- Leave me alone.
- I want to know what happened.
You never went to Meadow's
after you gave me your word.
- Get off my back.
- You are a liar!
- Fuck you.
- What did you say?
Get back here.
Puritan Salvage.
The big guy's looking for a consignment
from a wedding in Ringwood last night.
- Nothing came in here.
- This Benz SL55. He wants it pulled.
I'll make some calls.
- Where is he?
- In his room.
- What happened to your leg?
- He lied to me, Tony.
- Which means that they both lied.
- She's covering for him.
- It's what sisters are supposed to do.
- Oh, of course, right.
He cursed at me.
- Oh, my God.
- What did he say?
- He's asleep.
- Not anymore.
Oh, hey, Dad.
I was just taking out the trash.
It's garbage day tomorrow.
- What's different about you?
- He has no eyebrows, Tony.
Who did this?
- We were screwing around.
- What'd you say to your mom?
- Tony...
- What did you say?
- I said the F-word.
- You're finished.
You're never gonna drive that car
till you're 45 years old.
- I'm selling it.
- She wouldn't let me talk.
- I was trying to tell her what happened.
- Oh, see, it's my fault.
Let's hear it.
Well, I was gonna go to Meadow's
but there weren't any cabs.
And I didn't think you'd want me
sitting in the street at 11:30 at night.
- And we were right by the hotel.
- Enough of your lying.
- I am not lying.
- Look at your face.
If you got some kind of sexual proclivity
with that teacher or whatever...
...now's the time to tell us.
I mean, what went on up there?
- Poppers and weird sex.
- What? No.
Look, we don't do drugs.
We're not some stupid dopers.
- I had a few beers, it just made me sick.
- How can anybody believe what you say?
Because I told you.
You never believe me.
You had a couple beers.
Yeah.
- You didn't do any drugs?
- No.
Carmela, look it. Couple of beers.
Should be grounded, yeah,
but it's not the end of the world.
What?
Well, you know what?
I am sick of your bullshit.
Both of you.
- He can go live with you.
- Don't get dramatic now, all right?
- Wha...? Great. Good.
- Shut up.
I have never been more serious
in my life.
Take out the trash. Go outside.
What are we gonna do, really?
What did I just say?
No, I mean... I mean really. Come on.
- Did you think I was joking?
- Carmela, this is normal teenage shit.
You remember us?
The CYO dance. We left Artie out
in the snow. He almost lost his fingers.
And we still laugh our asses off about it.
No, I don't really blame A.J.
He's doing exactly what he's supposed
to, testing the limits as much as he can.
- I blame myself.
- What are you talking about?
You don't know what it is
to have him hate you.
- He doesn't hate your guts.
- Oh, thank God he's alive.
It's my fault, Tony. My pathetic need to
compete with you clouded my judgment.
Or I never would have let him stay over
in New York. I knew he wasn't ready.
- I went against all my instincts.
- His eyebrows will grow back!
- Nothing really happened.
- No, you know what happened...
...I said, "Fuck it."
And you know why?
To get him to love me
as much as he loves you.
He loves you, it's just...
You're his mother, it's different.
I can't be the villain anymore, I mean it.
And I can't say "Fuck it."
Take him. Let him live with you.
- Ed Norton?
I'm sorry, Mr. Kramden.
The correct answer is Stephen Foster.
But thanks so much. You've been a
wonderful contestant and a swell sport.
Goodbye, Mr. Kramden.
He's here.
- Hey, tarallis. Expiration date. 2007.
- Put them over there.
Have a seat.
Sounds serious.
You have anything to do
with that takedown in Ringwood?
Why? That a problem?
I told you that doctor
was a friend of mine.
I deliberately used that word.
Are you aware of how many things
a fucking M.D. can do for us?
Sorry, godfather, he was at the game.
I thought he was just another pigeon.
Who authorized you to do it?
And don't call me godfather
with that fucking cute smirk.
I know I was away for a long time...
...but when did that happen, you gotta
ask permission to ply your trade?
Here's your end. Be happy.
When were you gonna tell me
if I hadn't called you here?
I'm here now.
I'm telling you about it now.
That's the second time
I'm playing catch-up with you.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
- The lawn cutting.
What, do I have to send you a memo
every time I move my bowels too?
You're so concerned about me,
why didn't you put those cars...
...through my shops?
What?
Johnny Sack told me
about this guy in Newburgh.
- Johnny Sack?
- Yeah, Johnny Sack.
Anyway, he gave me a better deal
for shipping them whole.
Are you fucking serious?
- I don't like the way I'm being talked to.
- What did I say when you came to me...
...said you wanted back in?
I said as long as you don't step
on anybody's toes.
- In my day...
- And that's another thing.
I don't wanna hear
about how it was in your day.
Keep your antidotes
to local color, the Dynaflows...
...or McGuire Sisters or shit like that.
Otherwise, shut the fuck up!
Jesus Christ, Feech,
I'm trying to ease your transition here...
...and this is the thanks I get?
I'm sorry if I offended you.
You gotta remember,
I still think of you as a kid.
I'll learn.
Yeah?
Yeah.
That's funny.
Come here.
Oh, shit.
We all right?
Just get the SL55 back, okay?
You know,
maybe I was too hard on that guy.
Did I learn nothing from Richie Aprile?
Nip it in the bud.
Feech?
He's well-liked, T.
That's another thing.
All right, well,
don't be so hard on yourself, though.
- Hey. Olson and Johnson.
- How you doing?
Stopped by the bakery,
they said you left already.
That's the Canali suit I promised you.
He said you should try on the jacket,
see how the sleeves are.
- How's that?
- How's that? I look better than Sinatra.
Very nice.
All right.
Hey, I'm having my wine and peaches.
- You want?
- No, thanks. We gotta get going.
- I'll try some peaches.
- Good.
Peaches are from fucking New Zealand,
they're great.
- I'll get you a glass.
- No, we should go. We should go.
- Take care of that thing.
- Can't wait?
Where the fuck you going?
Come on, sit down.
We gotta do this shit.
You don't wanna know. It's fucked up.
What?
My imbecile cousin.
He was welding his boat trailer...
...burns down his garage.
Now we got no place
to park the truck that we got.
What's wrong with the street?
Georgia peaches.
Those are considered the best.
See, he don't want me to know
what's in the truck.
Flat-screen TVs.
Fifty-inch plasma Philipses.
Guy's coming down from Montreal
but he got delayed a couple of days.
I got a garage right here.
My cousin's got a place.
We can lock it there.
Park the load here. This way I'm around.
Keep my glims on the stuff.
Yeah?
How much you gonna want for that?
- Two.
- Fuck you, Feech. It's fucking parking.
You gotta kick in a TV.
Thought I had a plan for Anthony,
but I'm not so sure now.
I don't know if Rutgers' summer program
accepts boys without eyebrows.
So you heard about that.
I was a wreck.
Look what happened to those girls
just driving to school.
We brought in grief counselors.
How's Anthony coping with that?
I have to say he never mentioned it.
They all handle tragedy differently.
He just moved in with his father.
I don't know if he said.
- Really?
- I don't know what you have heard...
...about my husband.
Some.
I mean, he's a good father,
don't get me wrong.
Our daughter's at Columbia.
My friends tell me I'm a snob...
...with this college business,
but with Anthony it's something else.
I just know that if he didn't get into
a good enough school to interest him...
...and he dropped out,
went to work as a waiter or something...
...he wouldn't last a week.
You know, he would be drawn right in...
You know.
My husband doesn't want that
for him either.
You met him.
My husband can be very magnetic.
You know, bigger than life.
And I was so young.
It was very exciting.
Anyway, he's over there.
I don't know, maybe it'll be good.
You know, learning the things
that men need to know.
I don't know.
What about you?
How long have you been at the school?
Since '86.
I suppose that's what caught me up too,
with Astrid.
Some notion of escaping the quotidian.
- So you were married.
- For about, well, five minutes.
Chicken Marsala.
- And the honey balsamic chicken.
- Thank you.
Have you read Madame Bovary?
- No.
- It's almost a perfect novel.
Flaubert writes about
bourgeois loneliness and emptiness.
Emma Bovary destroys herself
for some fantasy in her head.
It's great. It's truly, truly great.
Somehow horrifically funny,
though tragic.
I think you might enjoy it.
I will stop by Borders on my way home.
- Who is it by again?
- Gustave Flaubert.
- Yeah.
- Supervisor Curran, parole board.
Site visit.
- Where's Eddie Stimich?
- He's out sick.
I just wanna take a look around.
Only thing better about here than Russia
is the food.
Good one.
Eddie examined every fucking dust bunny
in the place just last week.
Is that new?
Bequest. Friend of mine passed away.
That your garage?
No, it's where I make
the weapons of mass destruction.
Let's go open it up.
You wanna see my fucking garage?
You never seen an oil stain before?
Let's go.
Here's the wind-up.
And the pitch.
- Come on!
- Fuck Major League Baseball.
Ever since the fucking strike.
Let's watch ballet.
Oh, somebody hot-boxed us?
- I saw you close the window.
- What's that?
It's when you close the windows
and fart on purpose.
- That's a Dutch oven.
- In bed it's a Dutch oven.
- Well, what's a Dutch oven?
- When you fart in bed with a woman...
...and force her head under the covers.
That's awesome.
Yeah, but first you gotta be
in bed with one.
Yeah, you'd be surprised.
Yeah, I would.
Oh, my God. What...? Jesus.
All right, that's enough.
Go upstairs, do your Spanish homework.
- Fifteen minutes.
- No, now.
And he goes down looking.
The end of the inning.
Just got the call.
They put him on a corrections bus
this morning.
This was the better move
than taking him out.
- Man was a legend.
- Christopher agrees, by the way.
Well, that's nice that he agrees.
But I'm not running
a fucking popularity contest.
Mommy, look at me!
Anthony!