The fuck?
Oh.
Aah, shit!
So, "Blundino",
why you fuck me like this?
Fuck you talkin' about?
I got a whole leg
covered with Neosporin.
I just spent an hour with the cops
explainin' how it went down.
I no forget you
professional criminal.
Let me ask you somethin'.
If I really wanted to rob you,
you think I'd have to
put up with this bullshit?
Well, just so you know.
I didn't take your truck.
I lost my study guide,
my fuckin' flashcards.
I'm sick of this fuckin' prejudice
against ex-cons.
I never hire you if I
no need Tony Soprano for union.
Not for him,
I show you the fucking window.
Great.
Hey, I thought you
liked the other one,
the corn pops.
Here, take it.
What, no juice either?
I told ya, write it down, I'll have
the girl pick up whatever you want.
She doesn't know
the difference between
fruit roll-ups and pop-tarts.
I know,
everybody's an idiot to you.
You know they got these places
called supermarkets where you go,
and you buy the
things that you like.
I'll reimburse ya.
And when am I supposed to do that?
Well, as far as I can tell, you spend
most of your time on the phone.
Or sittin' on the couch perfectin'
That pissy look on your face.
Add comin' home drunk,
sounds like you.
What the fuck did you say to me?
- Let the fuck go of me.
- Or what?
- One of these days, you wait,
I'm gonna kick your fuckin' ass.
What's wrong with right now, then?
Huh?
What's wrong with right now?
Come on!
Blah.
Now ya got nothin'.
- Thank you, Mary.
- You're welcome.
I hated to call you in
but I got this midterm report
from Mr. Fiske,
uh, Anthony's English teacher.
And, uh, well it... It doesn't
hit the mail for a few days
and I thought maybe
we could get a jump on it
and avert any real crisis.
Wonderful, another crisis.
Uh, he's still well
below the "c" average
he needs for the
colleges we discussed.
There is also an issue
with his five paragraph essay.
Animal farm?
Anthony submitted his
one-line topic... late.
Then two drafts.
The first was apparently sketchy.
The second, Fiske said, was, uh...
"Suspiciously cogent".
Plagiarism.
He thinks my son cheated?
He spent almost an entire
Saturday afternoon at the library.
I think it's obvious
what's going on here.
What do you mean?
Anyone else shows sudden
improvement, he gets a gold star.
My son gets his act together
and suddenly he's a cheater?
I know what people think, Bob.
Italian-American, father in the...
- ...carting industry...
- are you suggesting some sort of bias
because that's a
very serious charge.
I have met this Mr. Fiske.
He's a cold fish.
Couldn't you or one of
the other teachers talk to him?
Tell him how hard AJ's trying?
Nothing will make a better argument
than continued effort on AJ's part.
But hey,
there... there's still a shot.
This semester's grade
is heavily weighted on
their term paper
on "lord of the flies".
God, my stomach is in knots.
That's why I thought
it important that you come in.
Though it, uh...
Did take me about an
hour to decide what to wear.
Me, too.
Does that mean you've
thought about my dinner offer?
I probably shouldn't say this
but I have thought about
nothing else since you called.
Well, we can't do
justice to any discussion
of "Madame Bovary" over the phone.
That's the thing, though,
that book was way over my head.
Why would you even be
interested in someone like me?
Because of just that.
I mean who admits this stuff?
Not only are you very attractive...
...you're unpretentious,
you say what's on your mind.
So, I'm a big mouth.
I see how that would
attract a man like you.
So, should we grab a meal or not?
Well, there are other
things to think about.
My husband for one.
Well, your husband's gonna
have to get used to the idea
that your life is moving on.
I'm not worried about my life.
Oh, you know what?
Call me naive but
in this day and age
I don't really think your husband...
if he found out, is going to
break his son's teacher's legs.
Not to mention how that would play
in the admissions office at Arizona state.
I don't get it.
What's so funny about that?
Honey?
Aren't you gonna eat somethin'?
Janice made lasagna.
It's not so great but you
need somethin' on your stomach.
We're gonna go.
Gotta stop at my mother's.
Gwen just told us how you met.
They let you use the
Internet in the can?
They let you post an ad.
I gotta read some of that shit.
I bet it's hysterical.
He's, uh, trying to concentrate.
Vascular physiology.
Neurotomy.
Shit.
T made it out like
it was a big gym test.
Some people don't realize
what massage involves.
I'm practically doin' two years of
medical school on my own right now.
One thing I learned in recovery,
other people's definitions of you?
Sometimes they're more about
makin' themselves feel better.
You gotta define yourself.
Keep your eye on the tiger, man.
- See ya, ton'.
- Bye.
I suppose I could speak
with Monsignor Bava,
have him call his nephew at K-Mart.
That'll fix us in the
Huggies department.
Well, the diaper drive
covers clothe the naked.
What do you say we
work on feed the hungry?
Ah, this looks delicious.
Thanks for inviting me, Carm'.
Pleasant surprise, indeed.
So, how goes life these days?
Actually, I think I met somebody.
Really?
Just kinda happened.
We had been, uh,
working on this project together
and suddenly we both realized,
huh, that there
were certain feelings.
And I like him as a person, too,
of course. Don't get me wrong.
The funny thing is,
I was sure he was gay.
He sort of reminded me of you.
He's an intellectual.
You know what I mean.
Anyway we had been friends,
I guess,
and then he called to ask me out
and suddenly all the
formality dropped away.
When I saw him the other day,
he looked at me
with this intensity.
Now, I know it's wrong,
but the truth is, I feel it, too.
You know,
if you really want to discuss this,
I think we should include
Tony in the conversation as well.
Why... why are you sounding,
I don't know, kind of hostile?
I'm not.
Perhaps that's your sin talking.
This is none of Tony's business.
Who knows what he's been up to
and not just during the separation either.
That doesn't change the fact
that you made a commitment...
...to each other before God.
Well, maybe you should send the Papal
Nuncio to Tony and remind him of that.
Why am I the only one
held to any kind of standards?
And for that matter,
if this is wrong,
why did God put
this man in my life?
Is it God that put him there?
Or is there a particular
need you have right now?
See, I never understand this.
Didn't he put the need there?
Say when, Señor.
You!
Office!
5:15, I haven't punched in yet.
This is still my time.
Yeah?
I give you a hard time
about my truck the other day.
Cops find two kids...
feel free to apologize any time.
Anyway, they investigate.
Could be joy ride.
But I think maybe behind
it is my cousin at Northside.
You know if they found my books?
Who knows.
You study hard for
"massagie", yeah?
The licensing test is pretty hard.
Huge failure rate.
If you pass,
then what you do with this?
Be a professional masseur.
You no think of "massagie ghageh"?
You know, small sauna.
Yeah, I could see it.
Four or five tables,
soothing atmosphere.
Pipe in a little Keith Jarret.
First thing I get
stuck with you I think,
oh, shit goddamnit.
He lazy American and criminal.
No good for Kim.
But you work for Kim and future.
Like a Korean people.
I wouldn't say that.
I come from Korea.
Only new shoes
and Uncle's address.
Worser than prison.
But I become "jah-soo-suhng-gah" the boss.
That's why I try to help you.
Help me how?
What are you talkin' about?
I stake you the money
in the storefront.
I got a travel agency
in mini mall over at West Caldwell.
Shitty business
with a fucking three-year lease.
You know, my daughter,
very interested in massage.
Physical therapy.
Top of two-thirds class.
Good for her.
It's a tough nut to crack.
She no like physical
therapy no more.
Cripple people make her sad.
Now, she watch TV,
live at home, do nothing.
You pass test then you,
me, my daughter,
we make the big success journey.
Okay?!
Jesus.
Yeah, alright.
I-I don't know what to say, Kim.
Thanks.
I laid it out for him.
He wants to move back here it's
gotta be with your full approval.
This was your idea?
It was mutual.
He's upset 'cause he don't
get the kinda cereal he likes.
He threw it in the sink.
How am I supposed to focus
at school with no breakfast?
I got dizzy.
I'm sorry. I don't see why the two of you
can't work this out between yourselves.
Well, maybe I don't
wanna live in a place
where people use violence
against children.
Violence?
You're lucky I didn't
put my shoe up your ass.
You see?
Now that's abuse.
I know what my rights are.
I can call social services
and they'll send a case worker.
Go ahead!
He'll get the other shoe!
This is demoralizin'.
- Well, now maybe you see...
- that a son of mine
would even consider
callin' in the authorities!
Go ahead, live where you want.
Fine.
Family meeting?
Try to stay awake, AJ.
Keep walkin'.
I-I just want my old room back.
You wanted to live
with your father, AJ.
Live with your decision.
I don't like it there.
Now that's funny,
I thought I was the problem.
I make you miserable, remember?
Well, I never said that.
- You did.
- Absolutely.
For me to even consider
having you back,
we're gonna have to establish
some non-negotiable ground rules.
Like what kind?
Let your mother talk.
First and foremost,
school comes first.
That means putting the
brakes on your social life,
parties and phone calls, Devin.
You are at a crisis
point grade-wise,
so you will make sure that your
work is done on time and correctly.
Alright.
- I will not tolerate cursing...
- after 16 years
of uninterrupted potty mouth from
you people, I get slammed?
This is my house.
You will treat me with respect.
Well, is that it?
I want you to involve
me in your life a little.
Fine.
Alright.
Go get your stuff from the car.
We played that just right.
Think his time over there with me
whipped him into shape a little.
Hmm.
Think you'll see a difference.
Which muscles attach
to the coracoid process?
'Kay, I fuckin' know this.
It's on the tip of my tongue.
Ho, fuckin' study hall again.
Vito, where the fuck
is my Tupperware?
Keep your shirt on.
My wife's bringin' it
down this afternoon.
Pectoralis minor and the
coracobrachalis, of course.
And...
Come on.
Even I know this.
Fuck, fine, what is it?
Biceps!
The fuck, I knew that.
My mind's all over the place.
Fear knocked at the door.
Faith answered.
It was no one there.
Why do you wanna do this shit?
So you can touch
a bunch a strangers?
You really skeeve the human body,
don't you?
You like this so much,
let me ask ya a question.
Why do pissin', shittin' and fuckin'
all happen within
a two inch radius?
Everybody asks that, Paulie.
There's no answer for it.
They're all sources
of pleasure, though.
Get the fuck outta here.
I know this shit and then
the next minute it's gone.
I don't know how you
do it workin' full time.
If your parole officer's a problem,
give our guy Jimmy Curran a call.
He's a supervisor.
It's not that. It's just all this
pressure now that I got this opportunity.
Sungyon Kim, my boss,
he's gonna back me on
a whole storefront operation.
The Korean?
You're lookin' for money,
why not come to me?
Well this is different.
This self-owned business shit's
like a religion to these people.
Plus, the guy sees somethin' in me.
You know, in some ways,
the whole prison thing is not that
different from bein' an immigrant.
Word to the wise,
remember Pearl Harbor.
We really were the
last people in there.
At least they were subtle about it.
Was it stacking of chairs
or the running the vacuum?
Relax.
Sorry.
"Madame Bovary".
It's a first edition.
Well, modern library's
first edition.
Thank you, that is so sweet.
Honestly, though, I don't know.
The story's very slow.
Nothing really happens.
I think he could've said what he
has to say with a lot less words.
Outside nothing happens.
But inside she has these extremes
of boredom and exhilaration.
You should try it again.
And what a wonderful thing
to have in a den.
You know, you look really
beautiful in this light.
I don't do this a lot.
Mm, do what?
Sitting in a car, with a man,
not really knowing what to do.
Or if I should at all.
And feeling like some teenager
which was believe it or not...
I have to tell you.
I haven't been with anyone.
You're a virgin?
This is my lucky night.
Stop with the jokes.
I'm so glad you're here.
So, how was it?
Oh, cut it out.
So, what is "Abelard and Heloise"?
It looks religious.
I just like to read in there.
Hmph.
It's the classic story.
A 12th century scholar falls
in love with his underage student.
Gets her pregnant.
God, in the 12th century.
Mm, and they're found out.
And her Uncle,
the Abbot, has him castrated.
It's timeless, really.
Even though he becomes
a monk and she a nun,
their passion burns on
through these incredible letters
through the rest of their lives.
You, with these books.
Mm, education should never stop.
It enriches all aspects of life.
Hmm, I know.
I wish someone could
convince AJ of that.
I keep thinking he
could start over in college
but who knows if he's
even gonna get the chance.
He will.
All our students matriculate.
You gotta
be fuckin' kiddin' me.
No way.
Why do they take so long?
All they have to do
is spit out the results.
5-6-2-4-7-3-7-30-2-11.
That's me.
Blundetto.
I'm only authorized to inform
you that your score meets
or exceeds the required minimum
for licensure,
as you're now board
certified in massage
and bodywork by the
state of New Jersey.
Honey, you passed.
You passed.
Oh, Jesus.
I couldn't have done it alone.
Oh, my God, look at you.
You did it baby.
You did it.
Bless me father, for I have sinned.
It's been a month
since my last confession.
Carmela?
I had sex with that man.
I know we talked about commitment,
the sacrament of marriage, but...
I don't know.
You sound remorseful.
I am.
I'm also confused, though.
The truth is I have been
walking around on a cloud,
like Maria in "West Side Story".
It's not right.
Have you heard of
"Abelard and Eloise"?
I think it's "Heloise",
and from what I
remember it ends badly.
I know, exactly.
But, something in
me has been reawakened.
And even if it never
happens again with this man,
just knowing that
feeling of passion again.
I don't know if it's
ever gonna go away.
I'll need it.
If it never happens again?
Carmela,
I can't absolve you of a sin
you're going to continue to commit.
You need to show resolve.
A firm purpose to change.
Yeah, I know, I know.
So, this man takes
you to restaurants.
Fulfills certain physical desires.
Tells jokes.
But will he be there
beyond the here and now?
When you're too old
to walk to the bathroom.
Will he be there to help you?
What, and you think Tony will?
Carmela, you took a vow.
You both did.
For your penance, I want you to do
something kind for Tony.
I don't think I can, father.
Then pray for him.
Not only that God
will touch his heart
but that he'll touch yours as well.
It's not much now, of course,
but it's a pretty flexible space.
Plus you got the dog
groomin' next door...
...in case your Korean friend
wants some lunch.
You know they really do eat dogs.
I mean not all of 'em
but I asked Kim.
Aw, Jesus Christ.
I'm thinkin' of buildin' a row of
rooms here with different themes.
Asian for shiatsu,
a little Danish thing for rolfing,
even though technically
it's Swedish.
Well, sounds like it's all
comin' together.
Look, Ton',
I know you're disappointed.
The fuck you talkin' about?
The way things turned out,
since I left the can.
Goin' civilian.
Over here I'm gonna put
an oasis with big plants,
like a waiting area
for the customers.
Could buy some 30 dollar hand cream
while they look at one of
those fountains with the koi in it.
I can get you the koi.
Really, giant carp?
How the fuck do you get that?
It's done.
Don't give it another thought.
Tony, you here?
- Yeah!
- Out front.
Hey.
I came by to get the keys.
I would have gone by the laundry
but my dad's
such a hard-on at work.
Tell me about it.
Amanda, this is my cousin, Tony.
- Hey.
- Hey, how are ya?
Hey, you believe there's
a dog groomer there?
In case somebody needs a snack?
Place is nice.
A little paint, maybe... Amanda,
this is my cousin Christopher.
Hey.
So, um, I met this guy at a club
on canal.
He says he can hook
us up with ginseng,
fake rhino, nerve tea,
all that herbal shit.
We could, uh, keep it
up front with the koi thing,
if we're still doin' that.
Koi's taken care of.
Well, I gotta book.
Nice meeting you guys.
What's she here for,
happy endings?
She's not gonna do massage at all.
She's Kim's daughter.
She's tryin' to find herself.
She'll do the books and shit.
Nice ass.
The ceiling tiles come right out
so I can install
the sound system myself.
Think you could put
in a word with, uh,
number one daughter there?
- For what?
- You know.
Get some a that kung pao coochie.
You fuckin' guys,
this is important to me.
Sex agrees with you,
you look great.
You're bein' discreet, right?
Well, sneaking around
is actually half the fun.
It's like you have this secret.
You know,
you wanna scream to the world...
Yeah, but...
- Do yourself a favor, though, huh?
- Yeah.
So, how was it?
Uh, I will say that
he took his time.
Oh, you're not
gettin' off that easy.
Come on, details.
Come on.
Hello there.
Hey, AJ.
Hey, aunt Ro.
How was school?
It sucked.
Mr. Wegler pulled
me out of language lab
to go over my term paper notes.
I didn't have my stuff with me so
he puts his faggy hand on my
shoulder and says "do your best".
Well, that's his job,
to get you into college.
Or maybe he's just a big homo.
Could be.
I'm making ziti for dinner. Go start
your assignments, I will call you.
Could I watch TV first?
Promise me you're gonna work later.
Mm, but you gotta help me.
I will.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, my Jackie.
Oh, honey.
They never caught those
goddamn chinks who killed him.
Oh, my God, it hurts.
So I'm findin' the other copy
when gene, the actuary,
completely unloads on me.
Jerk.
Like yellin's gonna make
me do anything but screw up more.
You know you have to remember
that when you're the boss.
The boss.
It's amazing isn't it?
Jerks.
Garbage pails are right there.
Come on.
- Holy fuck.
- What?!
Oh, my God, is it a fetus?
- Oh my God!
- Shh!
It's crack, or crank maybe.
They were drug dealers?
Yeah. They were probably thinkin'
they were bein' tailed by the cops.
Honey, your parole.
Happy?
Come on.
I've never seen that much money
before.
There's gotta be 10, 12 grand.
Look at this,
you're doubly blessed.
You're right, Kim, now this.
I am gonna buy you a ring.
You are the sweetest,
sweetest man.
But you should put
it into the business.
See, I gotta start
thinkin' like that.
It's a learning curve.
Well, it seems to say
here that this piggy represents
intellectualism over the physical.
So maybe the... the
eyeglasses are symbolic.
And that's a good topic
for section two in your outline.
AJ, wake up!
I'm not gonna do this by myself.
How are you gonna finish this paper?
It's not gonna write itself.
So now this, uh, so-called bag.
You sure it wasn't
on some old lady's arm?
I can't believe
she thought it was a baby.
People do that shit.
12 grand? Madonna mi'.
So how many guys you gotta jerk off
on a massage table to make that?
I don't know, what do
you charge without the table?
Ho!
Cristal, gentlemen?
Keep it comin', honey.
From now on, anytime somebody
steps in a pile a shit,
it'll be known as a blundetto.
To the blundetto!
Oh, wait.
I wasn't ready.
Huh!
My God, you scared me.
What are you doing here?
Jesus.
Nice greetin'.
How are you, everything okay?
AJ left this in his room.
Thought he might
need it to turn in.
Did you even look at this?
Who the hell is Anne Dunham?
How the hell should I know?
Well, she's obviously
some girl who was an expert
on "lord of the flies"
three years ago.
This is an A-plus paper.
Since when do you eat duck?
I can't believe he would do this.
Neither can I.
Considerin' how tight
he is with money.
That's not what I meant.
What?
Oh, you think he bought this?
Goddamnit!
Hello?
Hi, I was just laying
here thinking about you.
What are you wearing?
Yes, hello, Mr. Wegler, hi.
I'm afraid now is not a good time.
I'm serious.
I wanna know.
Uh, well yes, thank you very much.
I will make sure
that he brings it in.
Okay goodbye, Mr. Wegler.
I made reservations at that
crab place down by the shore.
Dinner and a little night swimming.
Right, okay, thank you.
What'd that fag want?
Jesus Christ,
Tony, everybody's a fag to you.
You know, maybe you're a fag.
You ever think about that?
Can I help it if I know one
when I see one?
Oh really, what are the signs?
Education, culture...
Suckin' a guy's cock
usually tips me off.
How do you know
who sucks whose cock?
What, do ya got a little secret?
And what do you care,
anyway, if somebody's gay.
It must be some big fear of yours
or you wouldn't talk about it so much.
I forget now. What part
of hell did you say they go to?
Are they with the abortion
doctors or the child molesters?
That was a long time ago.
So now you're all
open minded that you...
...got a couple friends
that are bologna smokers.
Right?
What the fuck are you doing?
Goin' for a swim.
What you... you gonna leave
your goddamn socks here?
Your underpants?!
Hey, that's some beautiful suit.
I had to get it.
It went with the shoes.
Whose got those?
Vito's guy?
Vasily's, custom made.
Only thing I ever found
in the street is my first wife.
Dealer has 20.
Son of a bitch.
I just took a beatin' at craps.
How you guys doin'?
Pocahontas here is scalpin'us.
What's the matter?
Oh, just nothing.
I... I don't know.
I just keep thinking about
AJ and that girl's paper.
Oh, it's a pretty common thing,
Carm', really.
Honestly, you know,
the important thing
is you took a stand.
A lot of parents just take
it in stride or even condone it.
It's just the cheating, you know.
It's just not like him.
He's always done his work.
Poorly, a lot of the time,
and late.
But he always did it,
he never cheated.
Well wait.
Didn't I read somewhere
in his record that
he stole a test at Verbum Dei?
Oh, please,
no, that was just acting out.
He was with a bad crowd.
They were there to
vandalize the science lab
but it was locked,
so they stole some tests.
Well, I was a late bloomer, too.
Union college took a chance on me
because they saw
that I had potential
but I wasn't that mature.
That's all this is.
AJ's just fighting to keep
pace with the kids
who seem further ahead.
You know you ask me,
I think he was driven to cheating.
It's that... that Mr. Fiske.
He is ridiculous with the pressure.
I mean how hopeless would you feel
if you really worked on
something and still got a "D".
I have been there, Carm'. You're
worrying for nothing, I promise.
I have thought about this all day.
You know I almost called
you from the faculty parking lot.
- Oh, Bob.
- What?
Stop.
Bob, I...
What's the matter?
I can't right now, I'm sorry.
I'm too upset.
Carmela, stay, what are you doing?
What kind of mother am I?
I mean look at us.
Do you realize under the laws
of the church I'm still married?
The church?
I can't do this tonight.
I'm sorry.
Jesus, Carmela, come on.
Okay, thanks.
It was a fuckin' blast.
You sure you don't wanna eat?
Steak and eggs up by skyway's.
Ah, I can't.
Come on!
Shut the door.
I'm gonna mang' then hit
the sack for the next 14 hours.
Hey. I thought once
they move you upstairs
you get to leave early.
No such luck.
Got a second?
The Soprano kid.
How is he doin'?
Got his paper yet?
Well, the usual.
Solidly below average.
So what, a "C"?
Well no, that's a little
generous for 10% insight,
90% Cliff notes.
This is an important class, tom.
Anything less than a "C" is gonna
blow that kid out at Arizona state.
You really think it's gonna
make that much of a difference?
As Dean of college admissions
and head of your department,
I happen to know it's a fact.
He's doing his best.
Well, like my dad used to say,
the world needs ditch diggers, too.
Let me ask you something.
How is floating this kid a C-minus
gonna fuck things up here?
AJ soprano's a spoiled lox, Bob.
He'd be lucky to
go to a trade school.
It's a D-plus.
Tom, cut him a break.
So what does it mean to the kid
who really breaks his ass in here
if Fredo Corleone can
get a "C" 'cause you asked?
Is that what this is about?
His background?
Goodnight.
I'll be workin' over at the place.
That's good dedication.
Way to go.
See regular people
need a place to relax, too.
They can't just hop on
a plane to the Bahamas, right?
Hey guys, what do you
think of daddy's business?
Jason, Justin,
I'm talkin' to ya.
I like it.
Yeah, it's nice.
Well, maybe someday
when this thing takes off
you guys can work here,
like as a summer job or somethin'.
Would ya like that?
Workin' with your old man?
Sure.
Alright, put those away.
You gotta do your homework...
...before I take you back or
your mom's gonna kill me.
Mom says we need helmets
to ride the scooters you got us.
We'll stop at sports authority.
Come on, do your homework.
Where?
I don't know.
Here, on the floor over there.
Hold it like this.
Ready?
Haa!
That was fast.
I took a shortcut.
Did you ever think
of painting that ceiling?
Maybe.
How about a glow-in-the-dark
solar system
like I had in college?
I was thinking blue, maybe.
You know, like when you
stick your hand in the Caribbean.
Oh, yeah.
You think union college
is a good place of AJ?
I don't know.
Could be.
You know,
maybe you could tell them
how he's a lot like you
were when you were his age.
That's a thought.
So have you ever
been to the Caribbean?
Yeah, Barbados, once.
Years ago.
Oh, it was beautiful.
Yeah, it is.
Maybe you could bring
up the fact that he has A.D.D.,
because it's not
the stigma it once was.
That's true.
It isn't.
Where are you going?
Mmm.
Faculty lunch, right?
Patty D'Amico brought them.
What's the matter, you okay?
Maybe we should take a time out.
What?
Really, why?
Because every time I think about
putting the arm on tom Fiske
I wanna poke my eyes
out with a knitting needle.
What does that have to do with us?
I just think we should, uh...
Not do this.
Oh, no, here tell me.
I don't know any
other way to put this.
I have been thinking and...
I don't know, I...
I think you're a user, Carmela.
What?
Maybe you saw an opportunity in me
and you just took what you needed.
Oh, that is not true.
I am here because
I enjoy being with you.
That it was wonderful, in fact.
Yeah, it was.
I mean, it is, I know.
How could asking someone you're
with for help be using them?
That's what people do.
Bob, this hurts.
Oh, my.
Oh my stomach I feel sick.
You strong-armed me using the
only weapon you have, your pussy.
How dare you talk to me that way?
Okay, let's pretend you
don't know what I'm talking about.
I don't.
Of course I don't have
a fucking masters degree.
Leaving me with a massive
hard-on the other night
and then practically
attacking me sexually
after you got what you wanted.
You know what, Bob?
You are fucked up.
You need help, you know that?
Fucking idiot I am.
Take it easy.
Yeah. Believe it or not,
I thought you cared about me.
I just thought you
should know how I feel.
Fuck you.
You better watch your step.
Jesus Christ, it's four A.M.
Okay, boys, hands on the table.
Full boat.
Jesus Christ.
Three fuckin' Jacks over here.
You just keep jackin', my friend.
That's it for me, tapioca.
You blew the whole 12 grand?
What are you stupid?
I got 400 left.
Punch in in two hours.
There's no sense goin' home.
Fuck.
Hello?
Hey, hon', I'm over at your mom's.
Great.
Roadway Xpress delivered
five massage tables.
There?
They had that address by mistake.
I told them to deliver here.
They're still in the boxes.
I looked inside, though.
They're pretty spiff.
That Salamanca fabric was worth it.
It's like leather almost.
Great.
What's the matter?
Shit gives me a headache.
Details and all that stuff.
Oh, you, it's no big.
For gosh sake.
We'll get Rudy's truck.
Maybe I have a brain tumor.
Honey, you don't.
This headache in my jaw.
I read it in "Time" magazine.
It's really not that likely, jeez.
I gotta get back to the painting or
I'll never get the fuck outta here tonight.
I am so fucking sick and tired
of your gambling and complaining.
I've got a headache.
When I think of me waiting outside
that prison for you to come out
sometimes I wanna vomit.
I am sick!
I'm evil...
Hey, Henry For'...
Big entrepreneur.
I like color.
My friend, Pak, come by?
Fix the toilet?
It's not fixed. He's gotta
come back with a fuckin' part.
Oh, Pak, he a good plumber.
Right over here, "Wes-a Calwell".
Wes Calwel, Wes Calwel.
West Caldwell.
So, partner,
we open in three day, huh?
Fuckin' stroll in.
I'm over here bustin'
my fuckin' ass!
You fuckin' crazy?!
Work in your fuckin' laundry,
all fuckin' day!
Fuckin' scam artist.
Fuck.
Ah!
The pole is bent.
Somebody been punchin' this door?
You had a man around
you wouldn't need to call me.
Yeah, right.
You're still young, Mel.
A good lookin' woman.
There's no reason you shouldn't
move on with your life,
if that's what you want.
Well, there actually was somebody.
And he seemed very nice.
Oh, that's good.
He was a wolf in sheep's clothing.
He made all these accusations
about my character.
Whatever I say, whatever I do,
because I was married
to a man like Tony,
my motives will always
be called into question.
Well.
Hey.
Sit down.
You want somethin'?
Aaah.
What'd you do?
Back.
Fuckin' job.
A work-related injury.
So, here's the thing.
You mentioned you might need
someone to run the swag airbags.
Bring me a vodka rocks
and get me some kind of a cushion,
will ya?
What happened with
the massage parlor?
It's hard doin' business
with strangers.