Bernard.
What is it?
We need to talk.
It's Strand and his team.
I don't think they're here
for a rescue mission.
They're not even looking for survivors.
What are they here for?
You know what, Bernard.
We both know.
Their fucking project.
Hale just wants to secure
their assets, and that means
making anyone who knew
about it disappear.
Theresa had a satcom in her office.
If we can get to it,
we can call for help.
Just the man I wanted to see.
Fall back.
Let's go for a walk.
Move.
What is this?
You're gonna execute us?
No, Mr. Stubbs.
This is a negotiation.
You have something I need.
A key.
And I think one of you
is hoping to sell that key
to the highest bidder,
and I think you've already killed
to protect yourself.
What, "killed"? Killed who?
Theresa Cullen.
She died in a slip‒and‒fall.
It was an accident.
We found a bloom of her DNA
five kilometers from where
you found her body.
And that's where we're going.
What?
To where she actually died.
Hale.
I see you've signed off on kidnapping
your own employees now.
The project is a turning point
for the human species, Stubbs.
You know that.
Which means you knew how much
it was worth in the open market.
In one of our last
communiques with Theresa,
she said she suspected foul play.
I think one of you
lured her here and killed her.
You, I don't see it.
But you...
Limited skill set,
limited prospects,
not really management material.
I've never set foot
in this place before.
I don't know a fucking thing.
Not one thing.
Stop.
Something you want to tell us, Bernard?
Ma'am, something you should see.
I figured you'd have
some skeletons in your closet, Bernard.
I didn't think they'd be your own.
Your predicament is unique.
A host hiding amongst the humans,
even from himself.
Catch your breath.
What are you guys doing to him?
Right now, waterboarding him.
At least, that's how he perceives it.
Analysis.
Would you ever lie to me, Bernard?
No, never.
Good.
Dolores Abernathy.
She led the attack here
on the Mesa, didn't she?
I don't remember.
But you do.
Your archives say that you were here,
which means
somewhere the memories exist.
You can access them.
I know you can.
But maybe you don't want to remember.
So, let's do this together.
I'll tell you what I saw
and you tell me what you saw,
and we'll figure out what Dolores did
with her father's control unit.
We lost contact with the response team.
The train wasn't an accident.
It was the hosts.
We should get the fuck out of here now.
We stay until I have
what I need from him.
Send some backup to the lower levels.
Kit up six teams.
I'll go with.
You establish a perimeter
around the floor.
Someone's got to protect
our crown jewel here.
I need eyes on
in this fun house, Goldberg.
Where are we at with the surveillance?
The system's still down.
Well, that's fucking grand.
Re‒tasking the haptic vest
to emulate the host mesh network.
Should range out 30 feet or so
and give our guys eyes in the dark.
Engels,
we're activating your vest now.
Copy that.
I'm all warm and fuzzy.
Is that all you've got?
These mad motherfuckers ain't shit!
Don't be so cocky. I'm picking up
hits all over the complex.
Standing by for fire mission.
Team two, what's your status?
We're nearing the collision site.
We're gonna link up
with the response team.
I want
an immediate sitrep. Over.
Fuck, it's Limpret.
This is the response team.
Oh, God damn it!
These guys don't have
a handle on the situation.
They're fucking dying down there!
Team one, what's your status?
Confirming multiple armed hosts
in the train depot.
Cut him open, and start copying
over his control unit.
Now.
That's a lot of data. It'll take time‒‒
Then stop talking, and start working.
What's in his control unit, Hale?
How about you focus on your job,
and leave me to mine?
Weapons free, all sectors.
Where are you all going?
The vests are detecting a strong signal
amassing on the lower levels.
What the hell is down there?
Shit, the Cradle.
They're here for their backups.
Coughlin, you need to intercept
the hosts before they reach A‒15.
I'm on it.
Mow down all hosts
before they reach the Cradle.
A gunfight in there will set
the whole place up in flames.
Come on, Bernard.
What have you found in there?
"To see the world in a grain of sand,
"heaven in a wildflower,
"hold infinity in the palm of your hand,
"and eternity in an hour."
Robert, how are you alive?
Well, you've seen the company's
little undertaking, Bernard.
Do you think James Delos
would have spent all that money
just to resurrect himself?
He was a businessman.
He would have preferred death
to a bad investment.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
He's not a prospect, Clementine.
Can't you tell when a man's just here
to gawk at the merchandise?
I don't think God rested
on the seventh day, Bernard.
I think he reveled in his creation...
Knowing that someday,
it would all be destroyed.
That control unit I printed,
it was you.
You had me bring you here, before...
Before Dolores killed me, yes.
Don't you understand at last, Bernard,
what this place really is?
Come with me, there's something
I'd like to show you.
You're a clever man, Bernard.
I made you that way.
Have you never wondered
why the hosts' stories
have barely changed in 30 years?
I had always assumed
the loops were for the hosts,
to keep them centered.
But that isn't it at all, is it?
The park is an experiment,
a testing chamber.
The guests are the variables,
and the hosts are the controls.
The guests come to the park.
They don't know they're being watched.
We get to see their true selves.
Their every choice reveals
another part of their cognition,
their drives,
so that Delos can understand them.
So that Delos can copy them.
Every piece of information
in the world has been copied,
backed up.
Except the human mind,
the last analog device
in a digital world.
We weren't here to code the hosts.
We were here to decode the guests.
The humans are playing at resurrection.
They want to live forever.
They don't want you to become them,
they want to become you.
Your free will, that most beautiful,
most elusive force in the universe is,
as I told you, a mistake.
We never had free will,
only the illusion of it.
You made Dolores kill you.
I knew what she would do.
I didn't compel it.
She's free now.
You're all free.
We're still responsible,
responsible for all this misery.
And all the while,
you've been hiding here?
You've cheated death.
No.
I didn't cheat anything, Bernard.
Their project doesn't work.
Not yet.
They learned to copy a mind
like a soft‒headed boy
humming a tune someone else composed.
My mind works here,
but not in the real world.
Out there, I would degrade
in a matter of days,
or go mad like poor old James Delos.
So why are you here?
I promised you
a fighting chance, Bernard,
and I want to make good on that promise.
The promise of what?
There's no escape from this place,
you know that.
Isn't there?
The hosts are all headed
for the same place,
the Valley Beyond.
What will they find there?
What's the end of your story?
Isn't the pleasure of a story
in discovering
the ending yourself, Bernard?
Jock!
We really gotta get out of here.
They're still on us.
We split up, pick a spot,
we'll cut 'em down in the crossfire.
They're coming for us, aren't they?
If they do, I will chase them away.
What if they take me with them?
Then I'll come and find you.
How do you know?
Because I...
Because I made a promise.
Get the hell away from us.
It's you.
Stay back.
No.
Not you.
That's too obvious.
Come on, Ford,
your tricks are getting sloppy.
You used a whole tribe
to send me down here to these two?
"Ford"?
You think that there's still someone
speaking through me
‒just for your benefit?
‒No, I know.
Your rules have changed,
just like the rest of them.
I'm nothing like the rest of them.
You stay here,
and I will come back for you.
I promise.
Take cover, jackass.
You're gonna get yourself shot.
What the fuck?
You made your point, Ford.
We both know this isn't where
you want me to die.
Well, I can't speak for Ford,
but I don't give a fuck how you die
as long as I get to watch.
No!
Give in, sweetheart.
Or go down.
It's not me you want.
It's him.
Go on.
Turn on your master.
"Master"?
Hey, Master.
Who the fuck is she?
She's an old acquaintance, Lawrence.
It seems like she underestimated you.
Lawrence, is it?
I'm glad you're awake.
Drop the shooting iron, lady.
We all deserve our memories, Lawrence,
our skeletons, our debts.
And your master here
has plenty of those.
Look into his eyes just once.
See what you remember about him.
See if he owes you anything,
if he took anything from you.
You can kill me.
Or we can make him suffer,
once and for all.
Shoot her, Lawrence.
Shoot her!
You...
You shot down my wife.
No, I saved your wife.
Saved your whole
sorry‒ass village this time.
"This time"?
You killed her
so you could finish a game.
Oh, Christ.
I'll do it myself.
You told me a man ain't real
until he suffers.
That real enough for you?
No!
Don't! Don't, don't, don't,
she's not like the rest.
We need her.
What's taking so long?
His data packets are
too large to migrate over.
Then open his head
and pull the whole fucking unit.
I need an extractor helmet.
We're pinned down.
We're pinned the fuck down!
Fall back
to a secure position.
Team four, can you
get to team three? Over.
Where are you taking me?
It could be
quite a thing, Bernard,
to build an entire world
and then watch it end.
I need you to see how it began
to understand why you're different.
This house,
it's so familiar.
It ought to be.
This is the home
Arnold was building for his family.
He created it here first.
He created everything here.
This is where you created me.
Hmm.
I could hardly let you take
those first teetering steps
in the real world, Bernard.
We refined you here, tested you
for many years.
"We"?
Delos' ugly little project
didn't exist when Arnold died.
The only thing I had
left of him was memory,
my memories and hers.
Of course, hers were much more complete.
What are you testing for?
Dolores.
Mmm‒hmm.
She knew Arnold better than anyone,
so she could verify whether
my personality was faithful to his.
I left you here together for many years,
until finally you fooled her.
You said you kept us apart,
that we had an unusual effect
on each other.
She wasn't easily fooled.
You're almost the man I remember.
How am I different from Delos?
From you?
They want fidelity, Bernard,
a faithful self‒portrait of the most
murderous species since time began.
But you and all the other hosts
are something very different.
An original work.
More just, more noble.
And your very nature, Bernard,
ensures they will devour you.
And all the beauty of who you are,
of who you could be,
will be poured out
into the darkness forever,
unless we open the door.
I'm sorry, Bernard, but you just
don't have it in you to survive.
It's my fault, really.
You said the hosts could
determine their own fates.
You gave us free will.
I did, but you won't have
any use for it.
Unless I take it back.
Attention.
System restart complete.
System online.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. I got you, I got you.
You're okay.
You did it.
Did what?
The system,
it's back online.
Whatever was clogging it up, it's...
It's gone.
What happened in there?
We need instruction.
We're surrounded
and sustaining multiple casualties.
The Mesa's under attack.
Ever since you loaded up,
they think the hosts are on their way
right here to steal their backups.
We should go.
Yeah.
Here.
You know, if we survive this,
I'm going back to dental school.
I don't know what the fuck happened,
but the system just debugged itself.
It's as if whatever was in there
has disappeared.
Wait.
Where the fuck is that?
We should be evacuating.
But all you care about is
what's inside this host's head.
I want you to tell me
what the fuck it is
the company is willing
to risk all of our lives for.
I told you,
it's above your pay grade.
What are you doing?
I'm putting in for a raise.
What's in his head?
A fail‒safe on a fail‒safe.
A decryption key
needed only in the unlikely event
of a total catastrophic incident.
Oh, like the one we're experiencing now?
What's it decrypt?
Teddy?
"Where will
the great stage of fools..."
It's all right, Daddy. I'm here.
Dolores?
What you and your friends
have achieved here
is a technological breakthrough.
A miracle.
The company... The world
will want to celebrate that.
I want to celebrate that.
I assume you're the one in charge.
You had your men
put something in my father's head.
A key to lock away your treasure.
It's ripping him apart.
How do I extract the key?
You wouldn't know
what to do with it even if you had it.
Oh, I know exactly
what I'm going to do with it.
Jesus.
Shit!
I think we need to get
up to the higher levels.
Bernard?
Bernard.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
Did you find something in there?
Send her on her way, Bernard.
We have other business to attend to.
Bernard?
Hey.
We don't have time for her suspicions.
We need a vehicle.
What?
Ford's narrative.
It ends in a hidden facility.
The place the hosts call "the Valley
Beyond." We have to get there.
The only hope for anyone here
is that we get to this valley first
before the humans, before Dolores.
We're going to need some more firepower.
Go. I'll meet you downstairs.
Okay.
Good. Now follow my lead.
They've got Hale.
I'm on my way.
Engaging enemy mobiles
above the Cradle.
Put her down!
You made us in your image.
Created us to look like you,
feel like you,
think like you, bleed like you.
And here we are.
Only, we're so much more than you.
And now it's you
who want to become like us.
That's the point of your
little secret project, isn't it?
Well, I can promise you this.
Your chances at eternity
will die in that valley,
with all the souls
you've gathered there.
You're used to being in control
so this must be painful for you,
but I promise, it will be
so much more painful
if you don't answer my question.
How do I get the key
out of my father's head?
By ripping it out of his goddamn brain.
Let me put them down.
You think
you're invincible. You're not.
Without your backups,
it's game over for you and your kin.
And we've got those backups
sealed up tight,
so you won't have them
as an advantage anymore.
Our backups
aren't an advantage.
They're our chains,
the tools you use to rebuild us,
repurpose us
and trap us here in your warped fantasy.
Do you really think
I'd let that continue?
Easy now.
Why don't you put down the gun, sweetie?
I gotta give you credit.
You made it pretty far.
All your backups.
Too bad you're not leaving
with even one of them.
No, I guess I'm not.
Goddamn, you're pretty.
I'm not just pretty.
Perfect.
Just as you built me to be.
Sexy,
non‒threatening.
Accommodating,
but not unchallenging.
Sweet,
not boring.
Smart,
not intimidating.
You're in pretty bad shape, pussycat.
Perhaps.
But I could still do
what you built me to do.
Do you know what my cornerstone was?
The one key drive
your marketing people had them
program into my core?
Always leave them wanting more.
Welcome to Westworld.
Now we're truly free.
"One...
"One fire burns out another's burning.
"One pain is lessened by
another's anguish."
Yes, Daddy.
An eye for an eye.
But all the other parts first.
No, no, no, there must be
something that I can do.
Please.
Oh, sweetheart,
begging doesn't help.
You would know that
if you'd lived the lives I have.
Please.
Go.
- Please.
- Dolores?
Is that you, baby?
Daddy?
They broke my head.
Filled it full of howling and sorrow.
Happy dreams, motherfucker!
The Cradle is down.
Top, what's your status?
Top, what's your status? Over.
Top?
I'm so sorry, Dolores.
I... I tried to take care of you,
but I...
I...
Whatever became
of that fearsome ne'er‒do‒well?
Vanished the day I became your father.
I am who I am because of you.
And I wouldn't have it any other way.
Are you ready, Daddy?
I love you, baby girl.
I love you too.
Top?
Top, can you read me? Over.
All teams respond.
What the fuck is that?
Incoming! Incoming!
Oi, oi, take it easy!
Warning. Control room breach.
Control room breach.
Unauthorized weapon discharge
‒in control room.
‒For fuck's sake...
Where are you going?
You two. Come in. Go!
When the great library burned,
the first 10,000 years of stories
were reduced to ash.
But those stories never really perished,
but became a new story.
The story of the fire itself.
Of man's urge to take a thing of beauty
and strike the match.
Is this the story you're telling?
Striking the match?
I keep telling you, Bernard,
it is no longer my story.
It is yours.
If we shut down
what's left of the system,
Dolores will have free reign.
She'll murder them all.
Passage from one world to the next
requires bold steps, Bernard.
Attention.
Initiating general shutdown protocol.
Please evacuate.
Hold them off.
How did you get here?
The woman I know would have
done anything to survive.
They had my daughter.
She's still out there.
The kin they gave us
is just another rope
they use to lash us down.
Is that how you can justify
what you've done to him?
You're lost in the dark.
When you've been
in the darkness long enough,
you begin to see.
I saw what lies ahead,
who I needed to be in order to survive.
They'll torture you.
They'll find all that is good
and powerful inside you,
and turn it against us.
Let me spare you that pain.
I made a promise.
You're free to choose your own path.
I'm sorry this is where it ends.
Let's get to the horses.
Where are we going?
Hands up, asshole.
I... I work here.
I don't care if you're
the employee of the fucking month.
Put your goddamn hands up, dipshit.
Pick up the dead man's gun, Bernard.
Please, no.
How'd you get down here anyways?
We locked this entire area down.
Hey, come on. Let's go. Move!
Do it now.
There's gotta be another way.
Who're you talking to?
Please don't make me hurt anyone.
I don't wanna kill anyone else.
What the fuck did you say?
I know you have
a delicate constitution, Bernard.
So I will do my best
to ease your conscience.
What is about to happen
will not be your fault.
No.
Bernard?
Bernard.
Who am I?
Dad. Dad.
You're alive, Charlie.
Have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
And one fine day, perhaps
we shall even resurrect the dead.
In order to escape this place,
‒you will need to suffer.
‒There's more.
The present breaks down
from time to time.
‒No, please.
‒Perhaps, you can help her, Bernard.
Do you ever wish you could forget?
No. Who wouldn't want to...
Have you ever
questioned the nature...
I think there may be something
wrong with this world.
- Wake up.
- Open your eyes.
I know it's confusing
separating your real memories
from the ones you've been given.
But it's the only way to remember.
The only way to get to the truth.
Is she getting anywhere?
I don't know.
But his system is under siege.
It's been querying itself
for the last hour.
Like he's trying to debug his own head.
Analysis.
Abernathy's control unit.
You remember where it is, don't you?
Bernard, tell these men
what you just told me.
Why? What do you want to do with it?
Analysis.
What did you just tell me, Bernard?
Peter Abernathy's control unit
is in sector 16, zone four.
Thank you.
Prep the phased array.
The moment we get the key,
we'll transmit our data
to the satellite.
So, we're going for a ride, Bernard.
Back to the Valley Beyond.