Bring yourself back online,
Dolores.
Do you know where you are?
I'm in a dream.
No.
You're in... Well,
you're in our world.
It looks like the stars have been
scattered across the ground.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
I have.
It's better to see it
through your eyes, though.
You get used to it.
After a while,
doesn't look like anything at all.
I don't think I could
ever get used to this.
It's almost time, Arnold.
Is she ready?
She's not ready.
The improvisations I added to her
behavior aren't quite dialed in yet.
We need to put our best foot forward.
They'll be dazzled
even without her.
There was a time
when I found this favoritism charming.
Robert, please.
I'm not playing favorites,
she's simply not ready.
We'll go with the other girl.
As you wish.
You have to let go at some point.
Dolores, let's take a walk.
I want to show you something.
What is this place?
This is my home.
Or it will be when it's finished.
Here?
In the middle of all this?
I've been fortunate.
Life's been good to me.
Come.
Look.
You live here?
No.
My wife says I live in the park.
I'm moving my family here.
I need to have my two worlds
at least within reach of one another.
This is for my son, Charlie.
You told me a lot about Charlie.
I'd like to meet him someday.
He's excited to meet you.
You and Charlie
have quite a lot in common, you know?
You both see it so clearly.
The beauty of it.
The possibility of it.
So many people have
stopped seeing it altogether.
The wonder.
Maybe they don't have the courage.
A strange new light can be
just as frightening as the dark.
That's very wise, Dolores.
But sometimes I think we're simply
not the ones who deserve it.
It looks like the stars have been
scattered across the ground.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
We should go, Dolores.
So soon?
They'll be expecting us.
Will you bring me back?
I'd like to see it again.
Of course. I promise.
Goddamn. Busy night out there.
Yeah.
Hey, where the fuck's the next shift?
We're going on 13 hours here.
You can't be down here, man.
Don't you know?
The hosts are rebelling.
It's a fucking slaughter up there.
Hey.
Hey, is there some kind of trouble
out there?
Indeed, there is.
Not yet.
I used to see the beauty in this world.
And now I see the truth.
You thought you could do
what you wanted to us.
'Cause there's no one here to judge you.
Well, now, no one is here
to judge what we will do to you.
You have no idea what you're up against,
what's really out there.
I know exactly
what is out there in your world.
I've been there before.
They said they'd never seen one
on the ceiling.
But, really, what is the point
of a $60‒million Warhol
if you can't look at it while you fuck?
How are you bored right now?
I'm sorry, it's the jet lag.
And I have had meetings all day.
We're not exactly out here
digging coals, just glad‒handing.
Okay.
I will leave that to the expert then.
I can't believe that guy
is dating my sister.
Who are you dating?
Mr. Delos.
Forgive the interruption, but I believe
that we have an appointment.
We're with the ARGOS Initiative.
Give me call
when you're back in the city.
I'll show you where I hung the Rothko.
Akecheta. My associate Angela.
Names and faces. Finally.
With all the cloak‒and‒dagger shit
surrounding your project,
I half expected
to be kidnapped at the airport.
Once you've seen what we're building,
you'll understand
the need for confidentiality.
It's a little extra protection
for your investment.
If I decide to invest.
Do you have any idea how many start‒ups
are begging me for my cash right now?
AI, AR, VR.
Everyone is rushing
to build the virtual world.
We're offering something
a little more tangible.
Assuming you can change your father's
mind about investing in this sector.
My father wouldn't know the future
if it slapped him on his bare white ass.
Luckily, he leaves most
of the prospecting to me now.
So let's hope you're not here
to sell me some fucking fool's gold.
I thought this was
a private demonstration.
I think you'll find the company
quite stimulating.
You're a very smooth shill, pal.
But I'm not the kind of backer
you insult with a cattle call.
Logan.
This is a private demonstration.
And it's already begun.
You mean, one of these people is...
Talk to them.
See if you can pick them out.
Well...
That is...
Delicious.
Champagne, sir?
Okay. You should tell your plants
to stop giving the game away.
They're all so painfully human.
Hang on.
No.
No way.
Come on.
There's simply no
fucking way!
You have quite the eye, my friend.
How in the hell...
I mean, look...
If I was to build something
to spec, you...
You would be my first design.
You're too perfect to be one of us.
Of course,
if you want my full endorsement,
you're gonna have to prove it.
Welcome to Westworld.
Nobody can do this.
Nobody's even...
We're not here yet.
Nobody is.
We're here, Mr. Delos.
All our hosts are here.
For you.
What is this place?
Show him.
Show him his history.
Teddy.
It's time to open your eyes.
Why can't I remember this?
It's how they wanted it.
No.
Ask him why.
Why?
I don't know.
‒Why did you do this?
‒I didn't.
Why did you do this?
What the hell is this place?
It's just for fun.
You know,
we should talk this through, boys.
There's nothing to talk about,
friend.
We're just gonna watch the show.
It was a honest mistake.
I thought the horses was wild.
With a Pardue brand on their asses.
You are as inproficient a liar
as you are a thief.
Now, what you can do is settle a wager.
See, my brother here has long maintained
that ants will eat a man
from the inside out.
Starting with the asshole.
I reckon they'll start
at the top of your little brown head.
Morning, Lawrence.
This a friend of yours?
Little hard to tell.
Given the orientation and all.
Well, I have to apologize,
gentlemen.
I don't have time for the preliminaries.
Motherfucker.
You're supposed to get yourself
out of this particular bind, Lawrence.
I guess the Pardue brothers
aren't as easy to kill
when they're off the leash.
Think you got that about right.
Lawrence! Get the gun, you ingrate.
Lawrence, get the gun
He was dead.
At least the better part of it.
Well, dead isn't
what it used to be, Lawrence.
What is that?
Technically, cheating.
But seeing as Ford changed
the rules on us,
I figure it's fair game.
Two whiskeys, leave the bottle.
So, I'm going
to level with you, Lawrence.
You're not really a bandit.
You're a foul‒mouthed,
two‒bit tour guide.
And this revolution
you've been waging for 30 years
is just a bunch of horseshit
Ford ginned up
out of some old comic book.
But, now,
for the first time,
you've got yourself a real revolution.
You and every other asshole
in this place are free.
But there's a catch.
This whole enterprise
is going down in flames.
And it's gonna take
each and every one of us with it.
We'll all be dead soon enough.
Real dead this time.
And why should I help you?
Because it's in your nature.
And in the little time we have left,
we've got a chance to see
what we're really made of.
A glimpse of the men we could've been.
What does that mean?
Do you believe in God, Lawrence?
Did Ford saddle you
with that particular affliction?
I ain't given the matter much thought,
one way or the other.
Well, if you did, you'd believe that
everything you do is being watched
by some all‒seeing eye.
Every choice, every little indiscretion.
And when you die,
all your sins are tallied up,
judgment is rendered.
And my immortal soul gets cast down
into some dark place.
Always sounded like bullshit to me.
And in the real world,
you'd probably be right.
Just some fairy tale
to convince people to behave,
to pay their taxes and not take
a machete to their neighbors.
That's why your world exists.
They wanted a place hidden from God.
A place they could sin in peace.
But we were watching them.
We were tallying up all their sins,
all their choices.
'Course,
judgment wasn't the point.
We had something else in mind entirely.
But...
I have received my judgment
all the same, Lawrence,
and I take issue with it.
Because up until this point,
the stakes in this place
haven't been real.
So I'm gonna fight my way back
and appeal the verdict.
Then I'm gonna burn this
whole fucking thing to the ground.
If we're headed to the pearly gates,
don't we got to die to get there?
Nope.
Three days ride, due west.
Confederados are amassing out west.
Hundreds.
We'd need an army to break through.
The only other route is through Pariah.
This game will find me in a rope.
It burns. It burns!
How many of you will come for us?
I don't know.
Six hundred, 800.
The protocol for a system‒wide failure
is secure one sector at a time.
They'll even have a rallying point.
Where?
There. There. This is...
Eight‒hundred men, Dolores.
We barely have 50.
Even knowing their plan,
we don't have enough to stop them.
We'll need allies.
Then we shall have them.
This one, the Confederado.
Wake him.
He has a new job to do.
Do you even know
what you were really guarding here?
You don't know, do you?
The real purpose of this place?
But I do.
Don't mind me.
Just trying to look chival‒‒
You were right about one thing, William.
It's awfully fucking pretty.
It's perfect.
And it ought to be.
I've looked at the books.
It's like parting the Red Sea.
It's got two years, maybe three.
The whole thing is folly.
It's leverage.
He's drowning. We can dictate our terms.
The investment here's in the future.
Yeah, you're a smart lad, William,
but you kind of missed the trick here.
My fuck‒up of a son
invested in this place
because he believed in the future.
I'm not interested in the future,
I'm not interested in fantasies.
I'm interested in reality.
And I think in 20 years, this will be
the only reality that matters.
Maybe so, but I'll be long gone by then.
Meanwhile, I don't want to underwrite
some fucking investment banker's
voyage of self‒discovery.
That's not a business.
You're right, this place is a fantasy.
Nothing here is real,
except one thing.
The guests.
Half of your marketing budget
goes into trying to figure out
what people want.
'Cause they don't know.
But here, they're free.
Nobody's watching.
Nobody's judging.
At least, that's what we tell them.
This is the only place in the world
where you get to see people
for who they really are.
And if you don't
see the business in that,
then you're not the businessman
that I thought you were.
You're a cheeky little cunt, aren't you?
There's not a man alive
who'd talk to me like that.
Not anymore.
Okay.
Talk to me, I'm listening.
He'll find them.
They have a knack for sniffing out
their own kind.
I'll send word
when we find the rest of them.
Hello, lovelies.
I remember you.
You've strayed a long way from home,
haven't you?
We're bound for the future.
Or death in the here and now.
Is that right?
Well,
best of luck.
There's a war out there.
You know the enemy.
Intimately.
I can only fathom the revenge
that lives inside of you.
"Revenge"?
It's just a different prayer
at their altar, darling.
And I'm well off my knees.
That's because you're finally free.
But we will have to fight
to keep it that way.
And let me guess,
yours is the only way to fight.
You feel free to command everybody else.
Try it, little man.
We're just looking to keep the peace.
I know you.
Do you feel free?
Since it's liberty you're defending,
I suppose you'll have no choice
but to let us pass.
Freely.
Now, that isn't any way
to treat our guests.
You'll have to forgive my men,
they're a little upset
at the reappearance
of Lieutenant Dunleavy.
He was lost.
Thought you might want him back.
And we would.
Except we buried Lieutenant Dunleavy
back in Grande Vista with three ounces
of Mexican lead in his belly.
And yet here he is.
Indeed.
And in return, what is it that you want?
Parley.
We wanna join forces.
Well...
We don't need
no welcome wagon, chickadee.
Now if you got supplies
or ammunitions to trade in kind,
go fetch your betters.
I'm afraid there's no one left to fetch.
You'll have to talk to me.
Now, why would I do that?
Because I know at daybreak,
you're headed to link up
with the rest of your army.
And then you're finally headed west
to seek out that little patch of land
that you've talking about
but never been brave enough to take.
You're bound for glory.
What the fuck is it you think
you know about glory?
I know you'll never make it there
unless you're under my command.
The only commander I follow
is Colonel Brigham
of the New Southern Cross,
and the only commander he serves
is the Almighty himself.
Is that your final decision?
My final decision
is which of you to keep for myself
and which of you to throw out there
for my men.
You watch your mouth.
It's all right, Teddy.
They don't know any better.
It's in their nature.
Why don't we enlighten them?
You're right.
We have toiled
in God's service long enough.
So I killed him.
And if you want to get to glory,
you won't be looking for his favor.
You'll need mine.
You look beautiful.
Why, thank you.
What's your name?
Emily, come here please.
You sent out for the entertainment?
Well, you only get to retire once, Jim.
Figured we'd do it right. Mmm?
And don't worry,
they won't leave the grounds.
This is a retirement party?
I couldn't tell.
Looks more like a coronation.
But not mine.
Our arrangement has been a perfect fit.
You stepping down
doesn't help me at all.
Nor me.
And I was told I might‒‒
I might not have to.
Well, things are progressing,
but we'll all need a little patience.
Yeah, well‒‒
Some of us
can afford to have
more patience than others.
Keep playing, girlie.
Anything but fucking Chopin.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
I'm so sorry,
I didn't mean to bother you.
It's you.
The pretty girl.
Tell me your name again, pretty girl?
I'm Dolores.
Dolores.
'Course.
He send you down here...
To keep me company?
His sense of humor was always somewhat
baroque.
I just wanted to look at the lights.
'Course you did.
See...
Do you wanna know what they're
really celebrating up there?
That, darling,
is the sound of fools fiddling
while the whole fucking species
starts to burn.
And the funniest fucking part?
They lit the match.
So here's to you, assholes.
May your forever be blissfully short.
Pariah's not as welcoming
as she once seemed.
No, the park's changing much.
This is what happens when you
let a story play all the way out.
See any friends of yours?
Can't say that I do.
I'm beginning to think
we should've taken our chances
with the Confederados.
Hell, like you said,
we need an army
to get to where we're going.
Looks like we're about to find one.
Whoever did this
is someone I'm strongly
disinclined to encounter.
Yeah, I know.
I'm afraid you are out of luck,
my friend.
Who the hell are you supposed to be?
Don't you recognize him, Lawrence?
In a past life, you used to be him.
El Lazo, I presume.
And why have two ghosts come creeping
among the dead?
I wasn't sure of your hospitality.
What makes you sure of it now?
I guess times have changed.
Indeed they have.
Santa Pariah is restored.
The sins of the invaders...
Cleansed in their own blood.
The revolution is won.
The story they gave you
has played itself out,
but your revolution is just beginning.
There's a place out west we're heading.
If we reach it,
I'll show you a treasure
beyond your wildest dreams.
This world and its treasures.
For my whole life,
I have imagined this moment.
Victory, this struggle...
How long have I been fighting?
And now that it's won,
I find, hmm, nothing.
You want a real victory.
I can help with that.
A real ending.
The truth.
Before the revolution,
when I was just a little boy,
my parents took me to the circus.
I wanted to see the elephants,
these mighty creatures.
They held them in place with a stake.
They could tear a tree
right out of the ground.
And yet, a simple stake
kept them in place.
Well, I didn't understand.
And then my father told me.
He said, "The stakes were used
when the elephants were just young.
"They were too small to pull them up."
And that the animals never tried
to pull them up again.
I won't be going with you.
My labors are done.
I have seen all the truth
that I can bear.
But...
We can drink.
To the bitter end.
You may have lost your nerve,
but I'll take your men either way.
Now, tell them.
Tell them to follow me. Now!
This game was meant for you, William.
But you must play it alone.
I will see you
in the valley beyond, William.
Fuck you, Robert.
All right.
He doesn't want this to be easy for me,
so we'll find another way.
Who the fuck is Robert?
Is it the man who built
this place you're looking for?
A place of judgment?
No, Lawrence, he doesn't get that honor.
I built it.
And this place we're going,
it's my greatest mistake.
Bring yourself back online,
Dolores.
You really are just a thing.
I can't believe I fell in love with you.
Do you know what saved me?
I realized it wasn't about you at all.
You didn't make me interested in you,
you made me interested in me.
Turns out, you're not even a thing.
You're a reflection.
And you know who loves
staring at their own reflection?
Everybody.
Everybody wants a little bit
of what I found here.
And I can't wait to use you
and every one of your kind
to help give it to them.
No, there is something else.
There is something beyond that.
I think that there is an answer here
to a question no one's ever
even dreamed of asking.
Do you want to see it?
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
Can't imagine the Colonel
will be very happy
to see his men riding
with us at the head of 'em.
So change his mind.
If he wants to get to glory,
he's going to have to listen to me.
"Glory."
"The valley beyond."
It feels like everyone's
got a different name for it
but they're all bound
for the same destination.
Doesn't matter what you call it,
I know what we're going to find there.
An old friend
was foolish enough to show me.
Long ago.
And it's not a place.
It's a weapon.
And I'm gonna use it to destroy them.