(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
Master Bruce.
What is it, Alfred?
Yoru Sensei. Line three.
Konnichiwa, sensei.
(LAUGHS)
ALFRED: I should enjoy
our return to Nippon more
without this unfortunate business.
So would I, Alfred,
but giri cannot be denied.
Ah, yes, giri. Honor, duty, obligation.
PILOT: We'll reach the city of Kuruhara
in an hour, Mr. Wayne.
(STUDENTS GRUNTING)
BRUCE: Of course, I will help
in any way I can, sensei.
But what made you think of calling me?
You cannot hide a warrior's spirit
behind your playboy image, Wayne-san.
Kyodai Ken returned
from America in defeat.
He was beaten by Batman.
So it is said.
Perhaps I thought you might somehow
enlist the aid of this Batman.
- You know him, do you not?
- We've met.
(BREATHING SLOWLY)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come.
A spot of tea
before retiring, Master Bruce?
I have some excellent green brew.
No, thanks, Alfred.
If I might be so bold, Master Bruce,
how did your meeting
with Yoru Sensei go?
It was not good news.
(CRACKING)
I believe I will have that tea, Alfred.
Once upon a time, Alfred,
500 years ago to be exact,
there was a fighting master who learned
how to manipulate the ki lines,
the currents of life force.
He called the art kiba-no-hoko ,
"The Way of the Fang."
It was such an efficient
and terrible fighting art
that the master decided it was
too dangerous to teach.
A mere touch could render
a man unconscious, or cripple him.
There was even a touch that was fatal.
So the master hid the only copy of
the instruction scroll for kiba-no-hoko
in one of the thousand caves
on the slopes of Mount Kajiiki.
He told no one but his eldest son.
The location has been kept
a family secret for 500 years.
ALFRED: And Yoru Sensei?
BRUCE: Is the great-great-great-grandson
of the man who created
that forbidden art.
And the only man who knows
the location of the scroll.
Yoru Sensei has no sons.
When he leaves this world,
the secret leaves with him.
And the kidnapped girl?
Yoru's star student.
Kyodai wants to trade her
for the knowledge of the fang.
ALFRED: To use against you, I expect.
Well, perhaps our cowled friend
can persuade him otherwise.
It's not that easy, Alfred.
He's after Batman as well.
But why?
He fought Bruce Wayne and Batman.
Fighting styles are like fingerprints.
Kyodai knows that we are the same man.
That was Kyodai Ken.
BRUCE: Did he give you
instructions for the exchange?
YORU: Yes. In the Uramachi district
after dark.
A bad part of town,
a place of thieves and the Yakuza.
A ninja would feel safe there.
If you give him a phony map,
he wouldn't know the difference.
True, but I would know.
You are familiar with
the code of Bushido, Wayne-san.
Ninja may lie and cheat. Samurai cannot.
Hai, sensei.
I'll see that the map is delivered.
BATMAN: Let her go, ninja.
You!
Release Kairi.
KYODAI: Throw me the map.
First she goes free.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH GROAN)
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
BRUCE: I can only read
bits and pieces, sensei.
Not enough to understand the techniques.
It seems that age has destroyed
the secrets of kiba-no-hoko.
I wish it were so, Wayne-san.
There is a large part missing.
The location of, and directions
on performing the o-nemuri touch.
I think that Batman is in grave danger.
(RUMBLING)
ALFRED: Another temblor, Master Bruce.
Shall I pack for our return
to Gotham City, sir?
I'm afraid not just yet, old friend.
I thought, that with the recovery
of the young lady
and the destruction of the scroll,
your chores here were finished.
Kyodai has the part of the scroll
that describes the o-nemuri touch.
I'm afraid my Japanese is
a bit rusty, Master Bruce.
It means "big sleep."
A better translation might be
"Eternal sleep."
Oh...
Oh, my.
I cannot tell you
where the fatal point lies, Wayne-san.
I never allowed myself
to read the scroll,
for fear I might someday be tempted
to use the forbidden knowledge.
It could be anywhere, then.
Yes, on a hand, an arm, a leg.
Even a simple defensive block
could mean doom.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Alfred?
(LAUGHING)
No, rich man, but I have him.
You will face me,
as yourself or your alter ego.
It is all the same to me.
Yoru will tell you where.
A single touch.
That's all it will take
to destroy your master.
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Will you fight Kyodai?
I believe the Batman
intends to face him.
Do you think this Batman will fight him?
Batman does as he will.
But I'm fairly sure
he'll choose to meet the ninja.
How do you like
our fire-breather, gaijin?
Impressive, is he not?
BATMAN: Very.
Once again,
you approach unseen, dark one.
You would have made a good ninja.
I would prefer to be a samurai.
But you are like me,
a warrior of the night.
So it would seem.
Let us face each other in the open,
man to man.
Samurai do not hide behind masks.
All right. Take your best shot.
KYODAI: Why do you back away,
night fighter?
Afraid of my touch?
(RUMBLING)
This was a poor choice
for a battleground, Kyodai.
The volcano may claim us all.
It does not matter.
Ninja do not fear death.
Enough. It ends now.
You are strong.
But not strong enough.
Sayonara, Batman.
Leaving so soon, Kyodai?
The o-nemuri touch.
How could you withstand it?
It's impossible.
It's all over, Kyodai.
Your precious technique doesn't work.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(RUMBLING)
Grab it. If you jump and I pull,
you can make it.
Kyodai, the rope!
I couldn't see through the smoke.
Was Kyodai...
I don't know, Alfred. I wish I did.
I saw him use the fatal touch
on you, Master Bruce.
Did he somehow miss?
No. I found his practice dummy.
There was a soft spot on it,
a place jabbed many times.
- I protected that spot on my own body.
- Most ingenious, sir.
I'm sorry about Kyodai, sensei.
We all choose our own paths, Wayne-san.
He walked a dark trail.
It was not your responsibility.
If you see Batman,
tell him I have great respect for him.
Why?
He's as much a ninja as Kyodai was.
Not so. Batman offered to
help his adversary.
And, a lesser man would have used
the knowledge of the o-nemur I touch
against his opponent.
Batman is the essence
of samurai, Wayne-san.
You would do well to remember that.
Domo arigato, sensei.