(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
That's it. Keep her steady.
Now crank her another inch, and...
(RADAR CLICKING)
(THUNDEROUS FLAPPING APPROACHING)
- (EXCLAIMING)
- (SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
(SLURPING)
(SCREAMS)
Ah, forget this.
WORKER: Yeah, it can have the fruit.
(SCREECHING)
(RADAR CLICKING)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Kirk. Kirk, what's the matter?
Nothing. Maybe.
I'm not sure.
Another nightmare?
You've been having
a lot of those lately.
Is there something you wanna tell me?
Then lie down. Go back to sleep.
KIRK: I need some air.
(SQUELCHING)
Ugh.
Now what?
Nothing. Go back to sleep.
I'm telling you it was
some kind of animal, a monstrosity.
The wingspan had to be 15 feet.
WORKER: With huge fangs and claws.
Look what it did to the fruit.
Uh-huh. Thanks. We'll get right on it.
(BEEPING)
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
Alfred.
Trouble, Master Bruce?
You could say that.
Reports of a huge bat creature
the size of a man.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Remind you of anybody?
ALFRED: Present company excepted,
indeed, sir, it does.
I take it Dr. Langstrom has somehow
become the Man-Bat again.
BATMAN: It seems that way.
You don't suppose he's taking
that formula of his again, do you?
I don't know. But I know
where I can find the answer.
Huh?
(GASPS)
Dad. Where is he, Dad?
I'm not your husband's keeper, Francine.
He won't even work with me
anymore, remember?
Can't you see I'm worried?
He's experimenting again
with the bat mutagen. I'm sure of it.
Well, I wouldn't know
anything about that.
He's been holed up in there
since before I got here.
Why don't you ask him yourself?
I'm busy enough with my own research.
(GROWLING)
FRANCINE: I can't
go through it again, Kirk.
I won't go through it.
Francine.
Why, Kirk? Why would you
do this to me? You promised.
(STAMMERS) It's not what you think.
BATMAN: The devil, it isn't.
I'm sick and tired of cleaning up
after you, Langstrom.
- So people have spotted it?
- Yes.
You must have some kind of death wish
to take that stuff again, Doctor.
What? You think
it's happening deliberately?
If I am transforming,
then that thing's still inside me.
I'm not taking the formula.
Stop it, stop it!
I'm sick of hearing about that thing.
I'm sick of my life. I'm sick of you.
Francine. Francine, wait!
If you haven't been taking
the formula again, what's all this?
What do you think? I've been trying
to clean up after you.
Obviously your so-called antidote
didn't work.
How could it have,
if I'm still transforming?
Don't you get it yet, Batman?
You failed.
All right, let's prove it.
Give me your hand.
- What are you doing?
- A DNA sample.
I'll run some tests.
We'll see what the truth is.
Langstrom, look, if you're right...
Save it. You've done enough already.
I'll be in touch.
(BEEPING)
(RADAR CLICKING)
What?
(SCREECHING)
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
(SCREECHING)
(RADAR CLICKING)
(HORNS HONKING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (CROWD SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Huh?
WOMAN: Look!
(SCREECHING)
(BATMAN STRAINING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLARING)
The end of a perfect day.
(BATS SCREECHING)
Indeed, Master Bruce, it does seem
that with a bit more luck,
you could have had him.
I think I got all of him I need.
Well, if she's not at
the ticket counter,
could you page her, please?
This is her husband.
BATMAN: Langstrom.
I have news.
Francine's gone. She really left me.
Not that I can blame her.
Who wants to live with a monster?
You're not a monster, Langstrom,
not anymore.
My tests show that the original antidote
did work after all.
I also got a sample
of the creature's DNA.
And after comparing them,
I'm certain the monster is someone else,
a new bat creature.
We're both off the hook.
- But if it's not me, then...
- Let me worry about that.
You've got other problems.
Right. Maybe I can catch her
before her plane leaves.
You're sure you don't need any help?
Don't worry.
I'll take care of everything.
DR. MARCH: Put that down. Now!
Or I'll fill you
with so much tranquilizer,
you'll be out for a week.
You couldn't leave it alone,
could you, March?
You've recreated the mutagen.
Recreated it? I've refined it.
At night, on my own,
so the others wouldn't know.
I still believe only a creature
like a Man-Bat
can survive the next
evolutionary cataclysm.
And it will.
My new serum could be
even more powerful than Kirk's.
(GRUNTS)
Could be? What do you mean?
I needed to test it,
but before I had the chance...
- You mean, you haven't taken it?
- Of course not.
The experimental batch was destroyed.
I'll have to...
Destroyed how?
I'd been working through the night.
I was just completing
the final combination.
Francine burst in. I was startled.
You have to understand.
I was very tired.
I accidentally dropped the beaker.
The whole night's work, ruined.
Francine never guessed
what I'd been doing.
She even helped me clean up
the mess, all that glass...
Oh! Oh, my Lord! Francine.
The mutagen,
it's in her bloodstream now.
Oh, no!
Is that what it's going to take?
Your daughter's life,
before you end this insanity?
How can I help you, ma'am?
I'm afraid I'm not feeling very well.
- Could you get me some aspirin?
- Certainly.
Kirk. Of all the ridiculous stunts...
I told you...
No, Francine, this time I talk.
You listen.
Whoever the creature is, it's not me.
The Batman can prove it.
But how? Who?
What's the difference anymore?
Come home.
- (GROANS SOFTLY)
- Honey, what's wrong?
I...
(STAMMERING) I don't know.
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Francine!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(PASSENGERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
- Cabin pressure dropping.
- PILOT: Gotta take her down.
Pan-Con 1-4-4 to GCX Control.
Cabin pressure has failed.
Requesting clearance for emergency
landing immediately, do you copy?
(PASSENGERS SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
Hold on!
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREECHING)
(DART GUN FIRES)
- (SCREECHING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GROWLS)
- (BATMAN GROANING)
(SCREECHING)
(RADAR CLICKING)
(GRUNTING)
(BATMAN STRAINING)
(SCREECHES)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREECHING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANS)
Kirk.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
KIRK: I've got you, honey.
And this time, I'm not letting you go.
FRANCINE: Kirk.
KIRK: The nightmare's finally over.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)