(THEME SONG PLAYING)
My fellow citizens,
it is with great civic pride
that we gather here today
to break ground
on the new Gotham penitentiary,
which is been funded
by the Wayne Foundation.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
As you know,
this project was the dream of one man.
And he's with us here today.
Gotham's new District Attorney,
Harvey Dent.
(APPLAUDING)
From this field of weeds and
wild flowers will grow a new institution
to build a better, safer Gotham.
(APPLAUDING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Go! Go! Go!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
This is Gordon. What?
We've got a prison break by air.
The chopper's heading this way.
(LAUGHS) We're home free.
Whoa! What was that?
Just some turbulence.
(SIREN BLARING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Thank you, Andre.
I'm starving. Let's eat.
(SNIFFS)
Shouldn't we wait for your friend?
Bruce? Nah. He's always late.
He probably got hung up on business.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANING)
What happened?
(SCREAMS)
I hear he's rich.
Yeah, Bruce runs around
with a high-class crowd.
(GRUNTING)
But he still manages to get his kicks.
(GROANS)
There's nothing
we don't know about each other.
Who... Who are you?
I'm your worst nightmare.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
This is the police! Nobody move!
I think you'll like him.
If he's your friend, I know I will.
Big wings.
Yeah, yeah, big wings.
Move it along, pal.
(COMM BEEPS)
Alfred, I'm running
a little behind schedule.
I have alerted Mr. Dent, sir.
He and Miss Isley patiently await
your arrival at the Rose Cafe.
How's the food there?
In my humble opinion, sir, exquisite.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
I'll be taking the Cord this evening.
As I anticipated, sir.
It is idling out front
with a full tank of gas.
ALFRED: May I recommend
the Trout Amandine?
I'll give it a try, Alfred.
Wise decision, sir.
Bon appetit.
(BRUCE LAUGHS)
You should've seen Harvey's face.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, look at the time. I have to run.
So soon?
I'm sorry. I have an early meeting
tomorrow. But you stay.
- No.
- I insist.
Spend some time with your crazy friend.
And call me the minute you get home,
Mr. District Attorney.
I'll call you.
Good.
- Nice meeting you, Bruce.
- Same here.
Well, I've been talking to my broker,
and his recommendation was that...
Ooh.
- So what do you think?
- Does she have a sister?
Nope. Pam's one of a kind.
That's why I asked her to marry me.
What?
Yup. That's the Page 1 headline.
(GROANS) Is it getting warm in here?
You're still flushed
from that last kiss.
Harvey, you just met her last week.
And I already know she's the one.
Gosh, it's hot in here.
Marriage is a major step, Harv.
- Don't you think you're rushing it?
- No way.
The moment I laid eyes on Pam,
love hit me right in the face.
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES) Harv, you've lost your mind.
Knock it off.
Harv? Harvey?
Hang on, Harvey. Hang on.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (SIREN WAILING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
- He's not breathing.
- What's the blood pressure?
Isn't that the District Attorney?
- Get his blood pressure, stat.
- Get the EKG
and move him into OR,
ICU Number 3, stat.
Do we have a pulse?
We need a pulse here.
Get the EKG and move him
into the OR, ICU Number 3, stat.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
This is Gordon. What?
Harvey Dent's in a coma
at the medical center. Move out.
(SIREN BLARING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
So, what's the story, Doctor?
Heart attack?
No, Commissioner.
Mr. Dent has been poisoned.
For criminy sakes.
Bullock, get down to that restaurant.
- What's it called, Wayne?
- Uh, the Rose Cafe.
The Rose Cafe.
And find out who did this.
With pleasure.
I want police guards
on duty here around the clock.
Yes, sir.
NURSE: (OVER PA)
Dr. Forrest, dial 118, please.
Dr. Kravitz...
Excuse me, Doctor. Are we talking
about food poisoning here?
I doubt it.
This is the most virulent strain
of poison I've ever come across.
We're doing everything we can,
Mr. Wayne.
Is Harvey going to make it?
The poison is racing through his system.
If he's going to make it,
we need to find the antidote, and fast.
So what'd you put in this mousse?
Chocolate, sugar, eggs, cream...
Strychnine?
No, no, no. No strychnine.
But I added just a pinch of vanilla.
You know who did it? Talk!
Hey, I just clean the dishes, okay?
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
We've isolated the toxin, Alfred.
Indeed we have, sir.
It is a lethal poison derived
from the plant Rosaceae Vularis,
commonly known as the wild thorny rose.
I'll get a plant sample
from the Gotham Botanical Gardens.
We can use it to work up an antidote.
- I'm afraid this is unfeasible.
- Why?
Because, sir, the wild thorny rose
has been extinct for nearly five years.
- Which means, I'm afraid...
- There's no antidote.
(BEEPING)
Fight, Harvey, fight.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Oh, Bruce, I came
as soon as I got your call.
- How is he?
- We're not sure.
- I want to see him.
- Sorry, ma'am, no visitors.
Commissioner Gordon's orders.
(SOBS)
You should try to get some sleep.
Come on, I'll walk you to your car.
(SNIFFLES) Promise to call me
if there's any change?
I will. You get some rest.
Harvey's lucky to have
such a good friend.
- Goodnight, Bruce.
- Goodnight, Pam.
(ENGINE STARTS)
ALFRED: Yes, sir.
BRUCE: Alfred, dig up anything you can
on Pamela Isley.
Who she is, where she's been,
what she does... The works.
ALFRED: Consider it done, sir.
What do you have, Alfred?
Well, sir, Miss Isley
is a research chemist
with Chez Gerard, the cosmetics firm.
She works on the development
of new fragrances.
Their newest
is a perfume called Nightshade.
It's deadly.
Miss Isley has a PhD in botany
from Gotham University,
where she offers
a monthly lecture series
on endangered and extinct plant species.
(BEEPING)
I think Harvey's engagement is off.
Oh, you've done so well today,
sweetheart.
Now get some rest.
And don't worry, I won't clip off
any more of your beautiful petals
unless I need them.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(CHIRPING)
Huh?
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
What has my sweet little flytrap
caught this time?
Um, a little big for a fly.
(GRUNTING)
PAM: (LAUGHS) Batman.
A late night rendezvous?
To what do I owe the honor?
(GROANING) Harvey Dent.
Oh, the poor District Attorney.
I hear he's not expected to live.
Oh, it's so sad.
(SOBS)
(LAUGHS)
Why, Isley?
Oh, please, call me Poison Ivy.
You see,
Harvey had to pay for his crime.
What crime?
Why, murder, of course.
Plowing up a field
of beautiful wild flowers
for that silly penitentiary of his.
This little rose would be extinct today,
if I hadn't saved my precious
from those horrible bulldozers.
The blood of those flowers
are on his hands.
(GRUMBLES)
Uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
Hmm.
So his fate was sealed...
With a kiss.
And now,
so is yours.
(BATMAN STRUGGLING)
Oh, what's wrong? Afraid I have cooties?
(LAUGHS)
- (SPITS)
- Oh...
Now you've gone and hurt my feelings.
Too bad. I was going to share
the antidote with you.
(SIGHS)
Lovely fragrance, don't you think?
I call it "Rose From the Dead."
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
No!
(GROANS)
Murderer!
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREECHING)
No!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(BATMAN GROANS)
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
Enjoy extinction, Batman.
I'm not going alone.
No!
The bottle for the weed.
What's it going to be?
(GROANING)
My baby.
My precious baby!
My pretty baby.
(GROANING)
- Where am I?
- You're in the hospital.
Why? What happened?
You passed out
into your chocolate mousse.
But you're going to be fine.
Now, Harv, about your engagement
to Pamela Isley...
- We're good friends, right?
- Mmm-hmm.
I have to be honest with you,
don't I?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Okay, then...
I think Pam is wrong for you.
Huh?
They can bury me in the ground
as deep as they like.
But I'll grow back.
We always grow back.
Don't we, baby?
(THEME SONG PLAYING)