(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
THE MECHANIC
Is he kidding?
(GUN CLICKING)
Maybe he's new in town.
- Can't you go any faster?
- I'm flooring it now.
(CRASHING AND TIRES SCREECHING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BELL DINGING)
MAN: Hold on, guys!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GROANING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(CRASHING)
(GROANS)
Looks like Earl's
got his work cut out for him.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
What happened?
You been letting the kid drive again?
(LAUGHS SARCASTICALLY)
Actually, we were
playing chicken with a penguin.
- Looks like the penguin won.
- The Penguin?
Or three of his men, at least.
But they flew the coop.
EARL: Then I guess you'll be
needing the loaners again.
(ENGINE STARTING)
- Well?
- The alignment,
the whole suspension, all shot to heck.
(GROANS) I'll call you
in a couple of days.
MARVA: Better make it a week.
Looks like we're gonna have to order
a whole new drive train.
Come on, Robin.
Guess we won't be seeing sunlight
for a while, Dad?
Once we've got the parts
it ought to go quickly.
Better put in the order right now.
Let's see. Twelve-gauge piston pins.
PENGUIN: These are terrible. Terrible!
Come on, boss, give me a break. We got
you the stamps. What more do you want?
I wanted the rare ones! (EXCLAIMS)
The reversed Audubons.
These aren't worth enough to pay
for the repairs to the limousine.
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't
have Percival here peck out your eyes.
(WHIMPERING)
(SQUAWKING)
- Well, I'm waiting.
- MAN: Here's a reason, boss.
If we never banged up the limo,
I'd never have run into my old friend.
The one I told you about. Remember?
Ah, yes, the one who works for that
auto-parts distributor.
Mmm-hmm.
That's me. Rundle. Arnold Rundle.
I process custom orders.
- Go on, Arnie. Show him.
- Right.
This is an order my company
received yesterday.
"Titanium-steel wheel wells,
12-gauge piston pins."
Very few vehicles use such
unusual material as those.
And the point of this is what?
I think these parts were ordered
for the Batmobile.
Huh?
Ah!
Tell him why, Arnie.
Well, right after I got that order,
Falcone told me what happened
to the Batmobile
while it was chasing your limo
the other day.
From the description, I'd say the kind
of damage the Batmobile sustained
might require the kind of
replacement parts in that order.
Yes. Yes, I understand.
You do?
Why, yes. And it's absolutely brilliant.
A first-rate piece of detective work.
You are to be rewarded, sir.
(GASPS) Reward?
Would $300,000 be enough?
- 300,000?
- Oh, all right, 400,000,
but that's my final offer.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Uh... Excuse me.
- I don't get it, boss.
- It's all right here.
Our friend, Mr. Rundle, amassed
newspaper reports of various instances
when the Batmobile was damaged.
Then he checked the dates
against the other times
his company got orders
for these types of materials.
(GASPS)
PENGUIN: In every case, it was a match.
The same exact date.
Excuse me. Where will this take me?
On a sea cruise.
Here. Look at these bills of lading.
(SCREAMS)
ARNOLD: (YELLING) Excuse me!
I'm expected back at the office!
PENGUIN: All the orders
come from the same repair shop
run by a certain Mr. Cooper.
Earl Cooper.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(EXPLOSION)
Earl, my good fellow.
I'm afraid the warranty on this vehicle
has just expired.
It's just like I figured, boss.
The on board computer routes
all the controls through a main switch.
Then we're going to pull
a switch on a switch.
(EXCLAIMING)
Now what?
(GROANS) The flipping thing
darn near electrocuted me.
There's a security device to keep it
from being tampered with.
Then disconnect it.
I wouldn't even know
where to look for it.
Well, I know who does.
And he's going to help us,
aren't you, Earl?
In your dreams, Pinocchio.
And how, pray tell,
did that costumed clown
give you such a bad case of loyalty?
- None of your business.
- PENGUIN: I'm making it my business.
Perhaps you've heard
of my umbrella weapons.
Would you like to see
what one can do to your daughter?
Don't listen to him, Dad.
(MUFFLED YELLING)
Okay. Okay.
If you must know, I used to be
an engineer at Global Motors...
till I predicted one of their new sports
cars would have brake-design problems.
But they ignored my warnings
and introduced a new model anyway.
But, Cooper, the boys in Legal
say we can't be held accountable.
We're talking about people's lives here.
Well, thank you for your time.
Let it go, Earl.
Hey, you've got a bright future here.
- Don't blow it.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
He's gonna report it, I know it.
Then if our Mr. Cooper
is going to become a liability,
I suggest we take steps
to minimize our risk. Hmm?
(BLEEPING)
EARL: That same night, they sicced
some hired muscle on me.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
EARL:
He saved my butt for sure that day.
But long after the Global scandal
was forgotten,
I still had a reputation
as a whistle-blower.
Twenty years in the business,
and I couldn't get work
as a wrench jockey.
I was down to my last dime.
No money, no job,
and no prospects for one.
And then he saved my life again.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Huh?
I need a new car.
EARL: It was a challenge of a lifetime.
It took me six months
to come up with the design specs alone.
Titanium construction,
ablative skin cowling,
tri-nitro propulsion units.
He paid for everything. Cash.
Found this site for a garage, too,
and outfitted it to my specifications
and paid me real well.
But he got his money's worth.
Hmm. He set you up here, huh?
Well, now you're going to set him up.
Be sure to do exactly as I tell you,
or the next person who gets a jolt
out of your security device
will be your charming daughter.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yes, Batman, it's ready
any time you wanna pick it up.
He's on his way.
And we will be ready for him.
(BEEPING)
Won't we, Earl?
(LAUGHS)
All right, gentlemen, battle stations.
The Bat is about to bite...
The dust, that is. Put her in the limo.
Insurance, just in case
you forget your lines.
And do take a good long look
at your friend, the Batman.
After all, you'll be saying adieu
to your best customer.
(LAUGHS)
- Looks great, Earl.
- BATMAN: Big job, wasn't it?
You look tired.
Yeah. Well, it took longer
than I figured.
See? Haven't even had time
to clean up yet.
- Where's Marva?
- EARL: Oh. Down in the basement.
Got some cleaning to do down there,
in the basement.
By the way, I even fixed
the air-conditioning switch.
Uh... Right.
(ENGINE REVVING)
MAN: You did good, old man.
They just left.
- What's bugging you?
- He seemed upset.
- Something's just not right.
- (CAR HONKS)
(FARTING NOISE)
- The Penguin!
- Hang on.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Here they come!
(SNICKERING)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (METAL SCRATCHING)
What are you doing?
(GRUNTING) Nothing.
We've been sabotaged.
(LAUGHS)
(SCREAMS)
(CHUCKLES)
PENGUIN: Bye-bye, Bats.
Man, how did he get control of the car?
He got control of Earl.
Come on, we better bail.
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Stand by to eject.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLES)
I hate to burst your balloon, Batman,
but now it's time for you to go.
- (GRUNTING)
- (ENGINE REVVING)
I got a feeling we're about to take
the hard way down.
- Down? The basement!
- Huh?
Earl. He kept saying "basement."
It's a racing term. When drivers crash,
they say they've gone down
in the basement. He was warning us.
The air-conditioning switch.
He said he'd fixed it.
Ha!
Pity. It was a magnificent vehicle.
(ALL LAUGHING)
All right, Earl!
Right. Blew him sky-high, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
(IMITATES STAMMER) Bat's all, folks.
(LAUGHS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
MAN: Let me down!
What are you doing? Let me down!
Wait! Hey, boss, behind us!
What? It's not possible.
Get us out of here!
Get him off us! Lose him!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ALL GASP)
(ALL SCREAMING)
PENGUIN: Come on.
Let her go, Penguin.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(GRUNTING)
Uh-uh.
I'm gonna miss this place.
Only till you see the new one
I'm setting up for you.
But this time I had my backers
set up dummy corporations
to order the parts through.
So no one can trace you again.
EARL: Yeah? Wait till you see
the new Batmobile.
It's gonna have tritium thrusters,
dual accelerators,
fuel-injected turbo boosters.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(EXCLAIMS)
"One bat for you"?
(GROWLING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)