(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
CATWOMAN: Previously on Batman...
Perfect, my love.
Let's go home.
BATMAN: So, our new cat burglar
is a woman.
You see, we're committed
to building a major resort.
The land is in the middle of nowhere.
It's worthless except to wildcats.
Tomorrow at 2300 hours,
a train under military escort
will pass through Gotham.
We'll hit the train
outside the city, at this point.
(ALARM BEEPING)
- (CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
- What is that?
A cat at the end of its nine lives.
BATMAN: I'll have to try
and trim those claws.
Hey!
Never trifle
with the affections of a woman.
Until next time.
And there will be a next time.
- BATMAN: You're late.
- (GASPS)
Can't you ever walk up to someone
normal-like?
BATMAN: I hear you have
some information.
Under one condition.
Lay off the South Side.
(GASPS)
Keep this up,
and I'll be on you from all sides.
North, south, east and west.
Okay! I get the picture.
There's rumors about some train heist.
- When?
- Tonight.
Red Claw?
Don't know. It's real sketchy.
One thing I can tell you,
no one in the organization
is making the hit.
These are outsiders.
(GASPS)
There's nothing here in the schedules.
A last-minute change?
I'd have been told.
What if it was a military train?
Something the government
wouldn't want us to know about?
Wouldn't be the first time.
Blasted Feds and their secrets.
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
You know, when I saw
those army commercials on TV,
they never said anything
about guarding no plague.
Who'd want to steal
a can of germs, anyway?
(EXPLOSION)
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
Huh?
(BOTH COUGHING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
That's got to do it.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Red Claw, watch out!
Red Claw, a woman?
Do you have a problem with that?
Not at all.
I'm an equal-opportunity crime fighter.
RED CLAW: Stay back, Batman!
I hold the ultimate equalizer.
This plague kills indiscriminately.
You'll die, too.
Along with everyone else
within a 10-mile radius.
Can you risk it, Batman?
Go on, call my bluff.
You've finally met your match, Batman.
Not surprising it's a woman.
Yes, General, but if you'd warned us
about this shipment
we might've had a chance.
So, what do I do now,
evacuate 10 million people?
Maybe we can set up camp
around the Pentagon.
(PHONE RINGING)
Listen, General, I'll call you back.
Gordon here.
Batman.
Thank goodness.
Have you heard from Red Claw?
GORDON: Loud and clear.
We've got 24 hours to come up
with $1 billion in gold bullion,
or she'll release the plague on Gotham.
To think, all this time
the Feds have been looking for a man.
BRUCE: Lately I'm learning
never to underestimate the opposite sex.
I'll be in touch.
Bruce and Selina go to lunch, take two.
I can't tell you how much I've been
looking forward to seeing you again.
Well, this time, I promise
a much more exciting date
than our last one.
Hey.
This time you seem preoccupied.
Sorry.
An unexpected crisis.
You, on the other hand,
look like the cat
who swallowed the canary.
Things are going very well
on the mountain lion front.
I may get that land from Multigon yet.
Really?
What did you find out?
Let's just say, they plan on playing
more than shuffleboard
up at their resort.
(CRASHES)
What in...
Watch out!
An old boyfriend?
Here go your nine lives, kitty-cat.
- (CRASHES)
- (BOTH EXCLAIM)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- Busy fellow.
- What?
BRUCE: Nothing. Hang on.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(CRASHES)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(HORN HONKING)
Brace yourself.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Where'd you learn to drive like that?
BRUCE: Oh, I've been going
to the Paris Grand Prix for years.
You know, one of these days,
I think I'll enter it.
BRUCE: Well, you did
- promise me an exciting time.
- (MIRROR SHATTERS)
It's not every date
where I get to fill out police reports.
SELINA: Thanks for seeing me up.
BRUCE: Just wanted to be sure
they didn't try anything else.
What makes you think
they weren't after you?
A nice guy like me?
(CHUCKLES)
Good night, Bruce.
Selina, if you're
in some kind of trouble,
I wish you'd tell me.
Perhaps I can help.
I really care about you.
I haven't felt this way
in a long, long time.
Thanks, Bruce.
But I've never been able
to play the damsel in distress.
I'll be okay. Don't worry.
MAVEN: But, why would someone
at Multigon try to kill you?
SELINA: Ten to one, it has to do
with those bunkers
under their resort site.
I think it's time I do some digging.
(ISIS MEOWS)
Not this time, Isis.
I'm afraid where I'm going,
they don't allow pets.
ALFRED: It's not that I question
your instincts, sir,
but why would Red Claw
wish to harm Ms. Kyle?
BRUCE: Why, indeed.
But somehow,
Selina has crossed Red Claw's path,
and I mean to find out where.
What an unusual color.
Ms. Kyle's, I presume.
(SNIFFS)
No. It's a cat hair.
Curious, never seen one
quite that color.
Batman has.
(GASPS)
(YELLS)
MAVEN: (GASPS) Get away!
(GROWLS) Huh?
(BLOWS LANDING)
(SCREAMS)
I won't hurt you.
Red Claw is after you and Catwoman.
Catwoman? What are you talking about?
Maven, you must tell me
where she's gone.
These people are killers.
(STAMMERS) The Multigon site.
You're not safe here anymore.
Is there somewhere you can hide?
Well, I guess I could go...
(WHISPERS) Shh. Go quickly.
As long as you know who she is,
you should know how she feels.
She's in love with you.
- (WHIP SWISHING)
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
This ought to keep you out of my hair.
- (GROWLING)
- (SHUSHES)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
These will certainly
enhance the resort's brochure.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
(SNICKERS)
I didn't think you cared.
BATMAN: Come on!
You've got to get out of here.
CATWOMAN: Me? What about you?
There's something I have to pick up.
Welcome to my little resort.
Plan on a short stay.
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
It's never dull, is it, Batman?
You may be surprised to know
these accommodations
are courtesy of your government.
They built this top-secret facility
to shelter high officials
in case of a nuclear incident.
Since you wanted
the plague so badly, Batman,
we've decided to give it to you.
What will you use to blackmail Gotham
if you waste it on us?
Why risk carrying such deadly contents,
when a placebo will do?
By the time they realize
the vial is a fake,
we'll be miles away
with their billion dollars.
(SIZZLING)
The acid should eat through
in a matter of minutes.
Sound evacuation,
and begin sealing the compound.
We wouldn't want the plague
to harm the precious wildlife,
just the vermin in here.
Ugh. Would I like to
get my claws into them.
If I could just get some slack...
What this situation needs
is a woman's touch.
(ALARM BLARING)
(STRAINING)
What a team.
Come on!
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
You've got to get out of here.
Not without you.
I'll be right behind you.
But first,
I've got to destroy the plague.
Now go!
Please.
(RED CLAW GASPS)
(YELLS ANGRILY)
Batman.
(GASPS)
(OVER PA) This is
Police Commissioner Gordon.
You're completely surrounded.
Give yourselves up.
Right where Batman said they'd be.
Looks like this resort is folding.
(CATWOMAN GROANS)
RED CLAW: So are you.
For years, I've fought
to build my network.
I brought countries to their knees.
You will pay, pussycat.
(GROANS)
You will learn
why everyone fears Red Claw.
(ROARING)
Thank you, friend.
Something for you to remember me by.
Hmm. (BLOWS KISS)
Batman, where's the virus?
It went up in smoke,
with Red Claw's future.
I should've known you'd have it all
wrapped up before we got here.
Almost.
Maven?
She's gone.
The terrorists were after both of you.
Have you told the police
you found your cat burglar?
BATMAN: Not yet.
CATWOMAN: Why not?
I didn't want you taken away
like a common criminal.
So, you do care.
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
More than you will ever know.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)