(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(TICKING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
You know me, Bruce.
Staid banker, old conservative stock.
I'm the last person to act impulsively.
But I'm telling you,
this fellow is a revelation.
You should read this.
Dad, you're not gonna proselytize Bruce.
Now you hush, Lisa.
We're raising a generation of cynics.
BRUCE: "Nostromos." Yes, I've read
about him in the Star Enquirer.
Uh, Alfred likes to pick up a copy
now and then.
That man saved my life.
He warned me not to go
on the gambling cruise.
Two days out to sea, the ship sank.
A coincidence.
What about the cave-in
at the Zanza mines?
Or the fires at the Karobi oil field?
His predictions saved me a fortune.
Make a heck of a stockbroker.
Tomorrow I'm hosting a party
in Nostromos' honor.
I want you to be there
to see for yourself.
Sounds great.
But I'll have to check
my horoscope to be sure.
BRUCE: You don't believe in this guy
at all, do you?
Call me crazy, but sometimes
I think his predictions come true
because he makes them happen.
Only thing I do know is these days,
my father won't make a move without him.
Daddy's even part
of a secret brotherhood.
Secret brotherhood?
He won't even tell
his own family what it's about,
thanks to Mr. All-Wise,
All-Wonderful Nostromos.
Peace to all.
Brothers and sisters,
the negative plane is aligned
with the positive,
bringing forth astral harmony.
What?
The vibrations are right for prophecy.
Oh. Okay.
That which you seek and cannot find,
is the seeker.
You are merely the eye
trying to view itself.
This is awfully deep.
(SHUSHING)
We are but radios
for the cosmic transmitter.
Tune your receivers.
Hear the inner voice.
(YELLING)
(ALL TALKING)
WOMAN: What is going on?
Brother Ethan, the inner voice speaks.
Someone here is in grave danger.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
The messenger of death is searching,
crying out for...
You!
(ALL GASP)
(CHATTERING)
(BATS SCREECHING)
But, how did the glass break, sir?
Psychic vibrations, Alfred.
Though I'd bet on
a high-frequency sonic device.
But I have some tricks of my own.
I lifted Nostromos' fingerprints
at the party.
There he is. Alias Carl Fowler.
Professional actor.
Arrested for petty larceny.
Otherwise, no criminal record.
That's his partner.
Lucas. Special-effects man.
Arrested for fraud.
Never convicted.
So, they were both in show business.
Still are.
I just wish I knew
where this act was going.
Hi, Mr. Wayne.
I hear your personal elevator
is working great now.
The repair guy was just out.
Really? I didn't know
there was anything wrong.
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
No one could have predicted
Batman would spot me.
Not even the great Nostromos.
Besides, how do you know Wayne survived?
The news said he got off the elevator
right before it fell,
you pathetic amateur.
Well, you didn't predict
he would die, exactly.
Fool! Can't you see how his death
would have affected the Brotherhood?
How vulnerable they would have felt?
We could have finally hit them
for all they're worth!
(PHONE RINGING)
Peace to all.
Nostromos, I must see you at once.
It's about Bruce Wayne.
Bruce Wayne?
Mmm-hmm. A miracle has happened.
Bruce has seen the light.
It wasn't until that moment,
when I came so close to death,
that I realized you really did have
a divine connection.
To think I ridiculed you.
Can you ever forgive me?
Of course.
I rejoice in your soaring consciousness.
Nostromos, I was thinking,
a man of Bruce's standing,
his influence,
should he not be considered
for the Brotherhood?
Yes. It's preordained.
Welcome, Brother Bruce.
LISA: No, not Bruce!
Lisa, you
don't understand.
Oh, I understand, all right.
You're like all the rest,
suckered in by
this money-grubbing, bogus creep.
Lisa!
You know what my inner voice
tells me, Nostromos?
You've ripped off your last victim.
I'm so sorry. I...
Do not apologize.
She will believe.
They will all believe,
after the Great Fall.
ETHAN: You may have joined us
just in time, Bruce.
For months Nostromos
has been warning the Brotherhood
of an economic collapse in the West.
"The Great Fall"?
Exactly.
But, at Nostromos' direction,
we've set up a superfund
to protect ourselves.
After the fall, we can use it
not only to rebuild fortunes,
but society as well.
And I take it that Nostromos
controls this money.
Oh, no, he can't touch it
without my written approval.
Nostromos insisted
everything be aboveboard.
Of course.
NOSTROMOS: And though,
tonight we bask in the radiance
of Brother Bruce's conversion,
it grieves me to burden your spirits
with solemn news as well.
The Great Fall is at hand.
The Great Fall.
(ALL MURMURING)
NOSTROMOS: The omens rise and converge
with every passing moment.
Yes, my brethren,
the inner voice speaks.
I now see a dawn of destruction.
Riots!
Pillaging!
Carnage!
A society out of control!
Oh, the torment!
The suffering!
(ALL GASP)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
The vision becomes clear.
Brothers, beware!
Argh!
(GROANING)
I am fine.
Brethren, you must transfer all you can
to the Brotherhood's fund by tomorrow.
The stars are
in their proper confluence.
Signs and portents abound.
As prophets of old foretold
cataclysmic changes,
so now, I predict
a massive social upheaval!
This is the end of the old order.
Anarchy and chaos will abound.
The Great Fall has begun.
You gave them $10 million, sir?
And to think,
I was fretting over the electric bill.
I had to keep up appearances, Alfred.
There must be over $300 million
in that fund.
My word!
Well, at least Nostromos can't touch it
without Mr. Clark's authorization.
For now.
But I don't need to be psychic
to predict that Ethan Clark
is about to undergo a spiritual crisis.
Well, Lucas,
our benevolent brothers
transferred another
63 million this morning.
I predict, you and I
are about to become as rich as pigs.
(LAUGHING)
- ETHAN: Nostromos!
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Huh?
Out. Out!
ETHAN: Nostromos.
I got your message.
I'd have been here sooner,
but I've been trying to locate Lisa.
She didn't come home last night.
The inner voice assures me she is fine.
Do you know where she is?
Do not worry.
I see you joining her soon.
Right now,
we have urgent business to discuss.
The voice has warned
that the Brotherhood's fund
is in jeopardy.
What do you mean?
We must convert it
into gold bullion at once.
I've prepared the papers
for your signature.
But, Nostromos, I can't possibly sign
until I've notified the brothers.
There's no time!
But, they must be informed.
It's our obligation.
Perhaps the stars can persuade you.
I see a bad moon rising.
Lisa!
(MUFFLED SPEAKING)
(GASPS)
Sign!
Nostromos, what is this?
I don't understand.
Sign! Or she pays.
Why would you do this?
I believed in you. You saved me.
Please, Nostro...
(MUFFLED TALK)
I have one last prediction for you,
Ethan.
The end will be swift.
Brother Lucas has set
enough explosives in this place
to create a supernova.
I suggest you make your peace quickly.
(SCREAMING)
Ooh!
The control room!
Up there.
You go that way.
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTING)
BATMAN: Your turn to see the light.
Batman?
(EXCLAIMS)
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(MUFFLED GROANING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
You're about to fall
out of orbit, Batman.
(LUCAS GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(SIGHS) I can't believe
I was so gullible.
But that's what I get
for putting my faith in greed.
You weren't the only one, Daddy.
Guilty as charged.
As the Bard once said,
"The fault lies not in the stars,
but in ourselves."
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)