Morty, hurry!
Return the Truth Tortoise!
Morty, whatever you do,
don't drop the Truth Tortoise!
Also really important,
whatever you do,
don't look into its eyes!
I-I did look at it, Rick!
I've been looking at it!
Now you're gonna know
everything, Morty!
Good job! Way to go!
You fucked everything up!
It's in my head!
Ah!
Oh, geez, I-I can't get that
Truth Tortoise out of my head.
Yeah, I told you not
to look into its eyes.
Hey, Morty, let's watch some
interdimensional cable.
Remember how we used to do that?
Rick, I can't... I can't go on.
I-I can't go on like this
with the Truth Tortoise
shit in my head.
I-I wish you could just...
Erase the memory from your mind?
How did you know I was gonna say that?
Come on, Morty, come with me.
After you.
What the hell is this?!
This, Morty, is my archive
of all the experiences
you've begged me to remove
from your life, lest you go insane.
I call them Morty's Mind Blowers.
And we'll be doing this instead
of interdimensional cable.
How long have I been asking
you to remove memories?
Since the first time
your mind was blown.
Ahh, here it is.
Classic.
There's no dust on it because
this isn't the first time
we've done this.
- What?!
- I call this one "Moonspiracy"!
Huh, wow. That's incredible.
What the heck?
Morty, do you realize
how ridiculous that sounds?
Yeah, pretty crazy story, Morty.
Are you serious?
Half the crap we've seen,
and you think that sounds crazy?
I've been to 300 versions
of Earth's moon,
including this one,
and I've never seen signs
of a "regular dude,"
as you describe him,
hanging out up there.
It's probably just
a smudge on the lens.
Smudge on the lens?
Smudge on the lens?!
I know the difference
between a man threatening me
and a smudge on the goddamn lens, Summer!
Morty, calm down!
Are you feeling okay?
I'm fine!
So sensitive.
Kids, I'd like to introduce you all
to our new guidance counselor,
Mr. Lunas.
I look forward to helping guide you all
towards a brighter future.
I believe every student should...
shoot for the moon.
Got you now, you son of a bitch.
What's this?
Proof that Mr. Lunas isn't
who he says he is!
He's not a guidance counselor?
I-I assume he's qualified to be one.
Who isn't?
But he also lives on the moon.
Okay.
Hmm. Is that it?
Is he doing anything to hurt anyone?
Oh, he's up to something.
I think I understand.
"Up to something," "lives on the moon."
Okay, I'll talk to him.
What did he say?
Denied the moon stuff,
but that's what pedophiles do.
They deny.
It's their bread and butter.
- Pedophile?
- You don't think so?
I thought the moon thing
might have been code.
No, he's literally from the moon!
Well, you saw him react.
Moon or not, that dude likes 'em young.
Gordon Lunas was a good Marine.
We don't know what drove
him to take his own life,
but we want to remember
the good things.
Like how, from a certain angle,
some people would say
he looked like a smudge.
Oh, my God, what have I done?
What have I done?
Jesus, I made that guy kill himself!
Only in a literal sense.
Here's one I call "Morty's Menagerie."
They don't all have titles, though.
It's not a "Simpsons" Halloween special,
more like a clip show made
of clips you never saw!
I can't believe we got put
into a menagerie.
So this guy collects living beings?
Yeah, you know like
commemorative plates,
but less off-putting.
You'll get it when you're still
actively dating in your 40s.
Assess this with cold indifference,
you veiny-headed prick!
Hey, keep it down!
Just our luck, menagerie beneath
the "boulder people" of Granitor Seven.
I can't take it anymore, Rick!
Relax, Morty!
I can't relax! R-R-Rick, we...
we gotta get outta here!
I don't care what it takes! Anything!
- Anything?
- Anything!
All right, well, you're gonna
have to take off your shirt.
Not yet. I'll tell you when.
Dear God.
What?
The signal turned out to be...
there's no other way to put it...
- Instructions.
- For?
A vehicle, sir, an interstellar vehicle.
We'll need a pilot.
I wonder if there's a volunteer.
Mm.
Oh, the schematics specify
a second, smaller pilot.
I mean, they really specify smaller.
They have to be exactly 5'3".
Chang, you may have
majored in Liberal Arts,
but I think you're about
to make history.
Primary systems, check.
Auxiliary systems, check.
See you soon.
Okay, now.
Greetings.
You're... You look...
We've possessed forms
your mind can accept.
Here are some customary clothing gifts.
Please, put them on.
- May we?
- Of course, yes.
We followed your instructions.
We have so much to learn from you.
I know, right?
Hey, how come I was able to see
those other people's memories?
I-I wouldn't have been around for that.
Yeah, sometimes I gotta do
a little editing, Morty.
It helps the mind blowers
play a little bit better upon revisiting.
I call this one "The Whole Enchilada.
Here, Morty, this'll make
your urine drinkable.
Now can we keep shopping?
I am Zikzak.
Ah, shit, Morty, get behind me.
It's a fucking alien overlord!
It's okay. Here.
Oh, I misjudged.
"I am Floop Floopian. Please kill me."
That's right, Morty.
The Floop Floopians achieve
an eternal orgasmic afterlife,
so long as they're killed
by a great warrior.
I'm flattered, by the way.
Thank you very much.
So you're gonna kill him?
Eh, let's get some lunch first.
So, you want to get
shot in the head, or...
Well, as long as the wound is fatal,
I don't really mind where you shoot me.
Cool. I'm gonna go take a quick shit.
Well, I gotta say.
You know, I'm a little envious.
Your species has an actual afterlife.
- That's gotta be nice.
- Wh-What do you mean?
Well, you know, here on Earth,
w-we don't know what's going on.
It must be nice for you guys to,
you know, have that...
have that proof's in the pudding,
you know, evidence.
Evidence?
There's supposed to be evidence?
Um, yeah, uh...
Otherwise, how do you
know if it's true?
Wait, you don't...
All right, so you want to do
this here or outside?
Run!
I don't wanna die!
Oh, God, it's all real!
Oh, it hurts!
Oh, I shouldn't have doubted it!
I shouldn't have let you
make me doubt it!
Aah! I blame you, I blame you!
But he said there wasn't any evidence!
That was a ton of evidence!
Well, silver lining.
Now I know their religion's real.
They have a hell,
and it does not look good.
I noticed you never
finished your chimichanga,
so I got some room for it now,
if you know what I mean.
Holy shit!
How many of these are just
horrible mistakes I've made?
I mean, maybe I'd stop making so many
if I let myself learn from them!
Don't break your back
creating a lesson, Morty.
It's a freeform anthology.
I'm getting annoyed
you're not hearing that.
As you can see around me,
your mind's been blown
countless times,
and not always by yourself.
Ah, shit, I don't even...
This better not have been a good one.
What is this?
Great, "Booger AIDS," "AIDS Booger."
I gotta start using real file names.
In the meantime, enjoy a grab bag
of mind blowers I call
"Poop AIDS underscore copy."
I'm not an unreasonable
man, Beth Smith.
I know children are everything
to a mammal.
I will spare one of their lives.
You simply have to choose.
Summer!
Summer.
You're not gonna believe this.
I went to Phoebe instead of Titan.
It's, like, hello, Saturn,
after 10 moons,
time to stop naming and start
numbering, you know?
What's... Wh-What's with you assholes?
Morty, please, don't do this.
Your Morty is gone!
I am Voltamatron, Destroyer of Worlds!
Grandpa Rick, there must be
some scientific way to save him!
Not scientific, but there may be a way.
Morty, I know you're in there.
It's me, your grandpa.
I know I can be mean,
but I love you, Morty.
We all do. You gotta fight this thing.
I know you can.
You're stronger than all of us!
Morty, it's Mom! We love you.
You have to fight it!
Come on, Morty!
Fight that stupid worm thing!
We love you!
We love you so much!
Yes, Morty, come on, you're doing it!
You're doing it!
Should we pull it out?
No, don't touch it.
Just keep loving Morty!
We still love you.
But I do have a thing at 6:00.
Oh, God, do I have to keep looking?
Geez, Morty, come on,
pinch it off already!
Don't! Oh, God, sorry, Morty.
I love you!
God, is there going to be
an intermission?
Excuse me, but I ordered
the large evil space worm.
I know, it's like, is that a demon slug
in your stomach,
or are you just happy to...
Sorry!
Well, I guess it's nice to know
the whole family sucks!
So if the blue ones are my fault
and the purple ones are my family's,
what are the red ones?
Yeah, d-don't read into it, Morty!
Ahh.
Shit! We need to find shelter
before the sunset, Morty.
Venzenulon Nine has a night
temperature of 300 below!
We'll freeze, Morty!
W-We'll be dead in seconds!
I-I think I saw a cave over there.
You've seen too many movies, Morty.
A cave isn't gonna cut it.
We're gonna have to use Beebo.
Beebo led us to water!
He's our friend!
- He won't even feel it!
- Oh, no, no!
You wanna die, Morty?
Get in Beebo!
Oh, no, no!
Brace for the ice limit.
Here it comes!
Wait, are we on Venzenulon Nine
or Venzenulon Seven?
Wait a minute. Why would I ask
for that to be removed?
Are the red ones stuff
you wanted removed?
Ooh, that's clever, Morty,
but I don't use color to sort things
because I'm not a mouse
in a European children's book.
Then why are all those
pink ones by the liquor?
Liquor?
- Shit, that was close.
- We lost Captain Sky.
He gave his life for the uprising.
Yeah. It really makes
you think, huh, Morty?
We should never take
things for granite.
- What?
- I'm just saying, life's short.
We shouldn't take things for granite.
- Are you saying "granite"?
- Well, yeah.
It's "granted," with a "D."
Take things for granted.
Did you actually think it was...
Jesus Christ, Rick,
what are you, a boulder...
a rock person?
How long have you
been saying that wrong?
Oh, you like that, huh?
I b-b-bet that really blows your mind.
I mean, yeah, it's kind of great.
- You want me to erase it?
- What, you can do that?
Ah, shit.
I fucking knew it, you piece of shit!
You... You...
You're a fucking asshole, Rick!
Take it easy, Morty.
Come on. Just relax.
No, I'm not gonna fucking relax!
Come here!
Let go of me, you little bitch!
I'm gonna grab you
by the scruff of your...
- Take that!
- Ohh!
- Umm.
- Umm. Uhh.
- What...
- What's going on?
- Where am I?
- Who are we?
- Who am I?
- I think I'm an adolescent boy.
Huh, and I'm an elderly man.
And we appear to be in some kind
of secret confined space.
- Yeah, umm...
- Don't look at me like that.
For all we know,
you could be the fuckin' weirdo.
Huh, these things are
obviously storage units,
and since we can't remember
what went wrong,
my guess is that the technology
involves memory
and that this thing
on your head is designed to...
Tell us the code, jagoff!
It's pointless.
He's stonewalling.
Rick, if we don't unlock
those vaccines, Earth dies!
You know, it might be time
to step up your interrogation!
Not sure what you're implying, Morty,
but some lines I don't cross.
Yeah, well, I crossed every line I had
when this bastard tried to kill Jessica!
Okay, see those two fleshy
sacs under his chin, Morty?
Grab 'em.
You remember the codes now?
Twist!
Give us the codes, man!
Twist harder, Morty!
Harder!
Okay, let go, let go, let him breathe.
He wants to make a deal.
Half the codes now,
half after you finish.
But can we trust... Wait, what?
F-Finish what?
Y-You know.
I thought I was torturing him!
Oh, and this disappoints you?
Do I tell him we don't
have a deal, Morty?
Because if we can kill our enemies
but we can't jack them off,
then how are we better than them?
Well, what did you find out?
We're partners, I guess,
and we fight aliens,
like "Men in Black"?
"Men in Black," "Men in Black."
I have "Men in Black 2" in here.
So... So you get the general idea.
Not quite.
It's basically an endless
string of callbacks to...
All right, save it for YouTube.
I'll keep looking for clues.
What are you doing?
You want your shelf level or not?
And if I say yes, you're gonna
provide that for me with that?
Yes, see the bubble?
I'm familiar with the bubble, Morty.
I also dabble in precision,
and if you think you
can even approach it
with your sad, naked, caveman eyeball
and a bubble of fucking air,
you're the reason this species
is a failure, and it makes me angry!
You're drunk.
You want to put up a shelf,
put up a shelf.
You want to experience true level?
- Do you?
- Y-yes.
Ugh, all right, come on.
Wow, it's so...
Oh, oh, oh, oh, my God, oh,
Christ, ooh, ooh, ooh, ahh.
Oh, yeah, true level, bitch.
Morty, come on,
we're leaving for school.
Oh, everything's crooked!
Reality is poison!
I want to go back!
I hate this!
- What's his deal?
- Can't live like this!
Shh, shh, shh, shh,
Morty, Morty, Morty.
Go to school, Summer.
I'll go in Morty's memory
and do a little...
Lambs to the cosmic slaughter!
Well?
You seem to be in charge
of what I get to remember.
- Why?
- Good question.
Morty, I need darkness to prime
these optical inductors.
Hit the leftmost light switch
by the door for me.
The left.
Okay, lights on.
So, did I just hear three distinct
light switch clicks?
W-W-What do you mean?
I feel like the three sounds
I heard could be explained
by an initial erroneous flipping
of a switch on the right
followed by a hasty,
corrective flipping
of the requested switch.
Then during the resultant
darkness and silence, a third,
shameful unflipping
of the initially flipped switch.
Is my assessment accurate?
Yeah, that's... that's basically how...
how it all shaked out.
- I'm sorry.
- Ugh. All right, come on.
- What?!
- Come on!
Grab a shovel.
W-What is...
Grab a shovel!
What was that?
I can't find a goddamn
zip tie anywhere!
All right, fuck it!
Ahh, zip tie.
Why are you making me
do this for you again?
Who doesn't wish they could
talk to animals, Rick?
Most humans!
There, I'm done.
Just stay out of trouble!
Gotta keep moving. Can't stop.
Up, down, down, up, up, up,
down, up, stop, down.
The queen needs food.
The babies need food.
The queen makes babies.
The situation in Argentina
has proven less convenient
than predicted.
We'll have to re-destabilize
their economy,
refocus labor class outrage
from upper to middle,
foster a coup, and install
a compliant regime.
Same as Guatemala?
Yes, but you can double-time it.
We need a quorum to pick a new pope
in case the Exxon/Monsanto
thing falls through in Africa.
Why not use chemtrails?
Put a canopy on Uganda.
They're set to agitate any mo...
What?
That kid is watching us.
So, we're squirrels.
He's a kid.
He's watching us like he hears
what we're saying.
Hey, kid. Young man?
Come here, little boy.
Tell Daphne to run a 199
on a possible Dolittle.
Little boy! We'll give you wishes
if you can hear us!
We can make you fly and get candy.
Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck!
Fuck me! Fuck me!
Rick!
Ah, shit, Morty, what did you do?
All right, Morty, pack your shit!
That's only gonna keep 'em down
for a little bit, Morty!
You fucked with squirrels, Morty!
We got a good five minutes
before they're backing up
on our ass, Morty!
We have to pack up and move
to a new reality, Morty!
You know I said we could only
do that a couple of times!
We're fucked over here because
of these damn squirrels, Morty!
I don't know what my reaction is,
but I think I'm mounting
in suspicion of you.
- Well, what are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna remember everything!
Everything!
Yeah!
Ow!
Ah!
Well, what'd you find out?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
what are you gonna do, kill me?
No, I'm not gonna kill you.
I'm gonna kill myself!
All those memories just erased!
Sitting in this room collecting dust!
W-What's the point of going on
if most of everything
that happens just
ends up sitting in here?
All right, kid.
I don't know much aside from
the fact that "Men in Black 2"
was a joyless cash grab, but I do
know that whatever you have
brewing around in your noggin
really connected with you.
I can't deny that,
and I can't deny that I'm
inspired by your passion.
I want in.
Suicide pact!
Yes, yeah, let's do it!
Together, you old son of a bitch!
On three!
One...
Two...
You guys doing Morty's Mind Blowers?
Morty's Mind Blowers?
Grandpa, is this a scenario three?
Uh, w-what's that, and w-who are you?
Oh, man, it's a scenario four.
Ugh, fucking God damn it!
I don't get paid enough for this shit!
There's a Craftsman nearby.
I can smell it.
Whoa, what... what...
Can I help you?
H-How did we fall asleep
during interdimensional cable?
- Yeah, what the hell, Summer?
- Summer, you dumb bitch!
How long were we out, you dumb bitch!
How much interdimensional cable
did we miss, you stupid bitch!
How many improv TV shows
with commercials did we miss, Summer?
Why did you let us fall asleep?
- You dumb bitch!
- You stupid bitch!
All right, Morty, fuck this noise.
Let's get out of here
and go on a classic
- Rick and Morty adventure.
- Yeah, right, Rick, I'm all-in.
No wonder you're constantly fighting
with each other and behind schedule.
- What?
- Nothing.
Rick?
Hello?
Just here for my putter.
Jerry's Mind Blowers?
Follow the boys!
We're charged and aimed
at Alpha Centauri,
ready for transport.
They fell for it!
Let's send Gobo home!
All right!
- Where's Dad?
- He should be here any second.
It's funny, Jerry spent
his life seeking attention,
but in the end, humanity's
instinctive dismissal of him
saved an alien's life.
He knows where to go, right?
Yep, any minute now.
Did it work?
Did you guys get Gobo home?
You have Gobo! You were supposed
to bring him to the hill!
As if. He was in your basket.
He was in your car!
Oh!
Oof! Dibs on his stuff.