Jerry! Jerry, come on!
We got to go!
You got to come with me, Jerry!
- Rick?
- It's important, Jerry.
The fate of the galaxy
rests on your shoulders.
Let's go. Put some pants on.
N-Never mind, there's
no time for pants, Jerry.
I'll make you a pair
of pants on the way.
It's a Rick and Jerry adventure!
Rick and Jerry episode!
Then I thought,
"Hey, what about Jerry?
He's... He's good with regular folk."
This is a real situation where...
where...
where Jerry could really shine.
He's a master convincer."
Rick, I'm not an idiot.
I know what this is.
Oh. Okay, well, I told Morty,
"Look, parents get divorced.
They get sad. He'll be fine,"
but I think he's worried you're
gonna, you know... Pbht!
And you know how Morty gets
when he gets emotional.
It impedes my work.
So, I told him I'd take you out
and give you a win.
Wait. My son asked you to take me
on some kind of pity adventure
to keep me from killing myself?
Wait, w-what did you think it was?
An execution.
Geez! You really do need a win.
No! I-I don't know.
I mean, you never
made me the pants, so...
So, you thought I was gonna drive you
into the middle of the galaxy
and shove you
into the vacuum of space
with your dick hanging out?
And we're seeing how you'd act
if that were about to happen?
I mean, shit, I'll make you
the pants right now.
Take me two seconds to make you pants.
- I have pants at home!
- Jerry, if I make pants,
they'll be better than
your pants at home.
Also, if I wanted to kill you...
Yeah, I get it.
It'd be amazing.
Please, take me home.
I'll tell my son we had
an amazing adventure.
Well, if it's all the same,
could we go get our story straight?
Because you're a terrible liar.
You called me a master convincer!
You believed me?
Huh. This seems... kind of fancy.
Jerry, for all you know,
this is the equivalent
of an alien truck stop.
You have no frame of reference.
You're in a universe
beyond your imagining.
But, yes, it is super fancy.
I mean, my job here is
to make Morty happy.
I'm not gonna take you
somewhere dangerous.
Rick Sanchez.
I told you if I ever saw
your face in here again,
I would stick you like the pig you are.
Shnoopy Bloopers,
I told you if you tried...
there'd be two funerals.
Aaah!
Someone?
Uh, someone? Someone!
My friend! It has been too long.
Oh, it's great to see you again, buddy!
Yeah, you're doing it.
Mr. Sanchez gets anything he wants!
The resort's covered
in an immortality field.
You can't die here.
That's the gimmick.
Okay, but still... bad parenting.
Hey, rich a-holes are rich a-holes.
They all pay top dollar to come here
and enjoy a consequence-free vacation.
No death, no disease, no dismemberment.
Can't even have a heart attack.
Got it. The perfect place
to take the most fragile being
in the universe.
I can tell you expect me
to refute that,
but it's right on the money.
If I come home without you,
I doubt Morty's gonna
let me off the hook.
Yeah, but what if you came
home with Jeff Goldblum?
Jeff Goldblum? What the fuck
are you talking about, Jerry?
Jesus!
Holy fucking shit!
Yo, what's up, "Big Chill"?!
Don't go into that telepod!
Hey, maybe we would have
fun on a fake adventure.
On a fake adventure.
Speaking of, what are we gonna tell Morty?
I don't know. But whatever it is,
we're gonna need a couple
more of these babies!
What's wrong?
Mom, do you think I'm hot?
I... don't think that's
something that matters.
So, I'm not hot?!
I'm saying the part of you
that cares about that
is a part you shouldn't
give any energy to.
That's not an answer!
Because I'm not an issue
of Cosmo, okay?
I'm your mother and a doctor, and...
I'm hideous!
Geez. What's with her?
Teenage-girl stuff.
Is that a... hoof collage?
It's perfectly legal,
if that's what you're wondering.
Cool... zies.
"We just don't have anything
in common anymore, Summer."
Oh, yeah, Ethan?
What do you have in common
with Tricia Lange?
A mutual love of French cinema?
The belief that a carbon tax
is the only viable solution
to climate change?
Or could it be her massive
stripper titties?!
There it is.
Boob-ya!
And that's when Malakai the Squid King
rips off his face,
and beneath it is my face.
- I liked it.
- Thank you, sir.
Yeah, of course he likes it.
Look at him.
Motherfucker got two heads
and three trunks.
All right, we'll put a pin in it.
I'm gonna go take a leak.
What the...
Ah! My hands are dry!
My hands are dry!
My name is Risotto Groupon.
I am the assistant general
manager of the restaurant.
Do you have any comment cards?
Because I might have some thoughts.
My kingdom was usurped by force
with weapons and technology
supplied by your father-in-law!
Hey, he usurped my kingdom, too, man.
He basically got me kicked out
of my home, stole my family.
Then we are brothers,
and you have wondered
what your life could
have been without Rick.
Wondered? Sure.
I mean, I've wondered
about having a vagina.
Would you help me kill him?
What? No!
He's my wife's father.
Move on.
Do you... like theme-park rides?
Oh, you really moved on.
There is a popular attraction
here called the Whirly Dirly.
Between the first whirly
and the third dirly,
the ride dips just outside
the immortality field.
You're asking me to lure
Rick to his death?
I'm only asking you to go
on a ride with Rick,
get off the ride without Rick,
and go home to your family,
where you can...
wonder about having a vagina.
Okay, okay, that was
a very specific example
pulled from thin air.
I don't want to be known
as the vagina guy.
Risotto, you're needed. Someone ordered
the Nuzzy Guzzy Fresh
and Fluzzy Special.
Look, I'm not like Rick,
so you're free to do as you please.
But there comes a time
in every man's life
when he must choose the foundation
on which his legacy will be built...
one of compromise or one of blood.
♪ Once a time of year,
there's a special person here ♪
Oh, yeah.
That's what I'm talking about.
Oops! Okay, a little more
on the other side, then.
Oh, come on!
Oh, geez!
Aah! Stop!
So, the hospital just let you
walk right out of there
with horse parts in a bag?
For Christ's sakes, Morty,
women going through a divorce
need a creative outlet.
What was that?
Summer!
I'm coming, Summer!
What the hell happened?!
How do we get her back to normal?!
I don't know, man!
This thing is pretty complicated.
I-I'm gonna call Rick.
Well, hold on.
We can't just call your grandpa
whenever there's a problem.
We can handle this ourselves.
I mean, I don't see
the point in trying to.
This is obviously Rick-level shit.
I have a medical degree.
Is that what this is about?
L-Like, you want to prove yourself?
Oh, it's not about anything, Morty.
How dare you?
Okay, good.
Then I'll just call... Ow!
Morty, I need this.
Hey, Jerry, triple trunks here
says he knows a place
where the ladies drop panties
for anyone bi-pedal.
Yeah, I'm not really interested.
My heart still belongs to Beth.
Oh. Huh. Okay.
What, you don't think I have a shot?
I didn't say that.
Excuse me.
May I have another one of these?
Coming right up.
Hmm, things weren't always
so bad between Beth and me.
We had some good times
when we were younger.
Oh, yeah, I bet.
That's how teenage pregnancy
happens, my friend.
Yeah, no.
Things were pretty great,
even until a couple of years ago.
Jerry, I get it.
That's around the time
I moved in with you guys.
Oh, I guess you're right.
Jerry, you know, I hope
you're not suggesting
that I had anything to do
with your marriage breaking up,
because there are some major
issues between you and Beth
that have been there
since you guys met.
Hey, to new beginnings.
To the Whirly Dirly.
The Whirly Dirly?
All right, what's going on here?
When did you get cool?!
When you stole my wife!
I should have done
that a long time ago!
We're going on the Whirly Dirly!
Whirly Dirly, baby.
Aha, look at this.
It says "normalize."
I bet if we just press that...
But... if the machine
was made by spider people,
normal would mean eight legs.
Oh, God! Are you gonna
go on another spiel
like you did with the flesh-colored crayon?
I'm pretty sure "normalize"
will make her normal.
Aah!
I'd call that progress.
- She's huge!
- And normal!
- I'm not normal!
- Mom!
Okay, this says "reverse."
Done and done.
I don't think that's a good idea.
Oh, come on! What else could
"reverse" possibly mean?
Aah!
Mom, call Rick!
Thank you.
There's a customer-service
number on here.
Mom!
Oh, man. This is gonna be awesome!
I got to hand it to you, Jerry.
This was a solid idea.
Uh, yeah. Uh-huh.
And you know what?
I'll cop to it.
I put a lot of strain on your marriage.
It wasn't fair.
I'm sorry.
- What?!
- I didn't respect your marriage.
I certainly didn't do it any favors.
And for what it's worth,
I'll apologize to Beth
for it when we get home.
Whoo! Whirly Dirly! Yeah!
Stop the ride!
We got to get off.
What are you talking about, buddy?
We got to get out of this thing.
We got to get out!
Jerry, come on, man!
We haven't even gotten
to the first whirly.
No, no, this sucks.
It's so boring.
I mean, I'm falling asleep here.
Let's just get out and
crawl down the sides.
Ah, get down!
Duck down!
It's more fun when you scrunch down.
Jerry, what the...
Oh, shit.
Rick, up here! There's a spot
where you can kill him!
Good call, Jerry!
- Hey, how'd you know about that?
- Uh...
Lisa?
So, uh, Jerry, big fan
of the Whirly Dirly, are you?
Not anymore.
Obviously.
But when you were,
how did you know about it?
We had a deal, Jerry Smith.
It's a really common name.
Now, take it easy, Rick.
You've been in a serious
roller-coaster crash.
It's... It's no time
to be thinking about
who did or didn't play a role
in your attempted murder.
Get it off me!
It's eating me!
Look, I confess, okay?
They told me about all the bad
stuff you did to this planet
and reminded me of all the bad
stuff you did to me.
But then you said you were
sorry, and I realized
you're not a monster...
not like this thing.
Fuck! It's got me good.
This is a mislead, right?
You're inventing a thing to save me.
That would be called a knife, Jerry.
It's been invented.
I'm making a way out of here.
One seat ought to do it.
I'm sorry. I-I made a mistake.
- I won't do it again!
- Nobody ever does.
You self-righteous piece of shit!
You took my family!
I took your family?
Who do you think had
more taken from them
when you shot 20cc of liquid
dream-killer into my daughter?
She was Rick's daughter, Jerry.
She had options!
Oof.
That all ended because
she felt sorry for you.
You act like prey,
but you're a predator!
You use pity to lure in your victims!
That's how you survive!
I survive because I know everything.
That snakes survives
because children wander off,
and you survive because people think,
"Oh, this poor piece of shit.
He never gets a break.
I can't stand the deafening silent wails
of his wilting soul.
I guess I'll hire him or marry him."
- Rick!
I knew you wouldn't let me die.
That was never an option.
Because you never had a son.
No, because I need a living organism
coated in gibble snake bile
to attract a shmooglite runner.
- Wait, what's happening?
- Use that confusion, Jerry.
It'll make you wriggle more like
an abandoned newborn.
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck, Rick?!
Help! Help me!
Aaah!
There's a space port 20 miles south.
We'll be able to board
a galaxy class cruise ship
and jump through a wormhole
that will put us
within spitting distance
of the Milky Way.
But, hey, it's about the journey,
not the destination, right, Jerry?
Just stay put, sweetie!
Mom's still on hold.
Morphizer customer service.
How may I help you?
Yes, I'm having a little trouble
with one of your machines.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that, ma'am.
Do you see a little compartment
on the side of the machine?
Let me check.
Yes, got it.
- Mom?
- Great!
Now, do you see the little
button next to it?
- I do.
- Give that button a push.
- Okay.
- Mom, listen to me!
We're free!!
Okay, so I pushed the button,
and three little men ran out.
What do I do next?
Hello?
I think we got disconnected.
- Morty!
- Don't "Morty" me!
I tricked Rick into taking
Dad on an adventure
because I thought I could get a break
from this kind of shit, but no!
Like father, like goddamn daughter!
You want to be like Rick,
congratulations!
You're just as arrogant
and just as irresponsible!
Everything okay here?
Mind your own goddamn business, Gene!
I'm having a conversation
with my mother here!
Kissing Rick's ass isn't gonna
help him keep him around, Mom,
but it will help you lose
everyone else.
Like I lost Summer.
Hey, you haven't lost her yet.
No, I definitely did.
She's gone.
God damn it!
Go ahead.
- Oh, come on.
- What's happening?
Your friend has class C or above
cybernetic augmentations.
Emphasis on the above.
In any case,
he needs to be neutralized.
- What?! Wait!
- Ugh!
Brain hurty.
What did you do?
It's a synaptic dampener
that blocks violent tendencies
and controversial thought.
He will now be an ideal passenger.
I want cookies and
a 90-minute cut of "Avatar."
Seriously?
- Quit it.
- It'll wear off in six hours.
It's cheaper than banning
dangerous people from flights.
I mean, let everybody
buy a ticket, right?
Otherwise, the terrorists win.
Aah!
I'm sorry I'm not a classic
maternal archetype.
Okay, I don't know what to do
when you people come to me
with your weird puberty issues.
What are you gonna do
when your daughter asks you
if she's attractive?
- I'll say, "Yes"!
- Morty, gross!
Well, she's gonna be super hot.
Her mother's gonna be Jessica.
Wait, when did Summer ask you that?!
Right before she Clive Barkered herself.
Why?
Wait, I know where she is!
Ethan and Summer were
supposed to go camping,
and then he dumped Summer
for this girl Tricia Lange,
who's got huge boobies, and took her.
Campsite... The one with the name
that sounds like somebody
gave up halfway through naming it.
Uh... Camp Flabanabba!
Mama's coming, baby.
Mama's coming, and she cares
about your titties!
They have sweet smiggle honey cookies.
Mmm! And low-calorie petroleum flakes.
Obviously cookies.
Let's get you the flakes, then.
Okay, but it's not what I wanted.
Well, maybe next time, you won't be
such a dumb piece of shit
and you can pick for yourself.
- That's not nice.
- What's that?
Did you just have
a controversial thought?
- No.
- That's what I thought, bitch.
You little punk-ass.
This is the best.
I agree. You've made things even easier
than if you hadn't been incompetent.
Uh-oh. We get shoot-shoot now.
All right, folks, if you could
please take your seats,
we're about to enter the wormhole.
So, I hope everybody
bought a dinner first.
- Nice.
Jerry, step over there
and lock yourself in the escape pod.
- You're not killing us?
- I'm killing Rick.
You're free to go.
You're no threat to me or anyone.
Now you're just being mean.
Yeah, you're mean!
No offense.
Mean would be shooting you, Jerry.
This is saving a bullet.
Go back to your quietly ashamed family
and live out the rest of your days
in denial of your vagina fantasies.
It was a one-time thought
that everyone has!
What are you doing?
I'm being triumphantly brave!
It's not triumphant or brave.
You're not risking anything.
You might shoot me.
I think you know I won't.
Because you know I feel sorry for you.
You're just doing this
so you can tell yourself
you fought... Ow!
Temporal shield compromised.
Congratulations, Jerry.
You get to die a man.
Uh, that's okay!
I'll leave!
Please don't shoot.
I-I'm the vagina guy, remember?
Whoa! What is happening to me?
Where is this? Where am I?
Am I dead?
A-Am I... Am I still alive?
Those aren't the questions
you should be asking.
- Huh?!
- Shh!
Ah, got ya!
Come here, you little pumpkin.
I have shit on my ass.
Whoa, fuck this!
Who am I?
I'm time! I'm literally time!
Whooooa!
Aah!
Oh, God. I feel like
our souls were united,
and we were all one with eternity.
Our body's unchanged,
yet our minds have lived
a thousand lifetimes.
Is that enough time
for me to forgive you?
I don't know, but it's enough time
for a synaptic dampener to wear off.
Jesus!
He hadn't decided he was
still going to kill us!
He was talking himself into it.
I've seen it before.
Cosmic apotheosis wears off
faster than salvia.
I'm starting to believe you
because I just finished merging
with your essence for an endless epoch,
and I'm already back
to thinking you're an asshole.
Fine with me.
Let's just go our separate ways.
Sounds like you and the word "epoch"
have a lot of catching up to do.
Wait, don't leave me!
All right, folks, you're free to get up
and walk around the cabin
and maybe take
the wormhole out for breakfast.
Okay, you can do the dinner one
or the breakfast one, but not both.
You think you got
that thing figured out?
Yeah, I know what I'm doing.
Good. Because I have an idea.
It's actually a contraction
of "some" and "more."
- You see that?
- Oh, wow.
I was way off.
Morty, what's happening here?
Summer got into my grandpa's garage,
messed around, and turned
herself into a monster.
My mom did the same
to make her feel better.
She's a good mom.
Oh, my God.
I have to go call my mother!
- Tricia, wait!
- Ethan! Ethan!
Hey, it's okay. Sit down.
You made my sister cry, Ethan.
You messed with her body image.
- Look, Morty, I...
- Shh, shh, shh.
Careful, Ethan.
Your s'more is burning.
Uh, I guess we better get
on the same page
about our fake adventure.
- Right.
- I'll make you a deal.
I'll leave out the part where
you tried to murder me...
And I'll leave out the part
where you admitted
to sabotaging our marriage.
You want to...
Nah, if the family sees me like this,
they'll feel sorry for me.
Which is no longer my signature move.
Later days, amigo.
Actually, I just realized,
I don't have my wallet,
and my bus pass is in there,
so maybe...
Stay strong, Jerry.
I believe in you!
I tell you, fellas.
This is the life.
It certainly is.
To freedom!
Ooh! Looks like a 4-22.
Ooh, a couple cranks
on the scaling knob
with a four dilabyte cross fade
would fix that up in a jiff.
Four? You'd be lucky
to clear 13% de-morphized
with that kind of range.
Gentlemen, gentlemen,
what did we agree on?
No work talk!
Let's just relax and enjoy
our retirement, shall...
Oh, my God!
Aaah!