Ohh!
Summer, next time we're hiding
in a Colorkian echo nest,
can you do me a favor
and turn your ringer off?
It's called "carpe diem," Morty.
- Look it up.
- You look it up!
Y-Y-You don't even...
You don't even know what it means!
That's because losers look stuff up
while the rest of us
are carpin' all them diems.
Listen to your sister, Morty.
To live is to risk it all.
Otherwise, you're just an inert chunk
of randomly assembled molecules
drifting wherever the universe blows you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Jerry, I didn't see you there.
H-How much of that did you hear?
All of it.
You were looking right at me.
I just wanted to say
goodbye to the kids.
Cool. Just stay in the driveway.
The killbots are live,
and I took you off the white list.
W-We'll see you every other
weekend, though, right?
Absolutely, Morty.
A-And your Mom's lawyer says
if I can get enough in the settlement,
he can help me sue for full custody.
Th-That'll be nice.
- Uh, Summer, Dad's leaving.
- Bye, Dad.
Rick, didn't you say you needed my help
on an adventure immediately
somewhere else...
I don't care...
even if it might kill us?
I did not, but if you're
really that alienated,
I'm as willing to exploit it
as the next guy, church, army,
or Olympic gymnastics trainer.
I'm ready when you are.
Bitch, I was ready yest...
Bye, sweetie.
Well, I-I better...
Sure. Sounds important.
If you're looking for our kids,
your father did a-a portal, uh...
Okay.
Loser.
What?
Hello?
Morty, shoot the Mohawk guy!
- They all have Mohawks!
- High fade,
chartreuse with cyan highlights,
layered on top.
Shoot him!
Ah!
Light them up.
Ahh!
Fuck! Get in the game, Morty!
Give me your flask!
Holy shit!
Summer for the win!
I fucking love
post-apocalyptic versions of Earth!
Here we go!
Isotope 322.
This stuff's so powerful, Morty,
it makes Isotope 465
look like Isotope 317.
Uh-huh, yeah. Is it powerful enough
to keep those guys from murdering us?
- Summer!
- Hold on.
I want to try something.
Rick, can we not leave
without my sister?
Ugh. You have infinite sisters, Morty.
I mean, n-not that I want
to spend the rest of my day
looking for another one.
"Sum-sum," let's go!
Grandpa's concern
for your safety is fleeting!
Your blood will be my lotion.
Whoa. That was cool.
Kill me, please.
Okay, but not because you told me to.
- Summer!
- Okay. Getting darker.
Jesus Christ. Summer!
Aw, come on.
Hands and little shoulder-mounted dudes
where I can see them.
I am Hemorrhage.
You have removed weak blood
from us and made us stronger.
We can combine our strength
and feast on the weak together.
Wh-Wh-What in the hell are you saying?
They don't have to keep trying
to kill us if we join them.
- They're basically pussies.
- What is your deal lately?
All right, let's get sloppy.
Oh, whoa.
Uh, uh, what's, uh...
What's that little bauble
you got back there?
Th-Th-That's interesting.
That is our glowing rock.
We carry it with us for desecration,
to remind us there are no gods.
Kids, weird pitch.
Let's have this be our new life.
Let's be post-apocalyptic scavengers!
- Okay.
- What?
Grandpa, some of the Death Stalkers
are going to what used to be Seattle
to hunt what used to be people.
- I'm going.
- Sounds good. Stay hydrated.
Listen, Rick, Summer's been
acting pretty crazy lately.
You know, I mean, I-I think
the divorce is affecting her.
And, you know, I don't think this is
a great place for her to be right now.
Oh, get off your high horse,
Professor Ski Lodge.
This world may be rough
around the edges,
but it's got its charms.
Bicep or quadricep?
Uh, bicep.
Seriously, Rick?
Is it really easier to eat human flesh
than to just tell me
why we're still here?
No. Okay, I'll level with you.
You see that green rock, Morty?
It's about 20 pounds of the stuff
I was getting all hard for a flake of.
Isotope 322.
Well, having a 20-pound boulder of it
is better than having a flake.
I can explain the math
to you later, but...
Summer just ran off with strangers
that have "Death" in their name,
and the rest of their
name was "Stalkers."
Huh, could be therapeutic for her.
She has been acting
pretty crazy lately, Morty.
I mean, her parents are going
through a divorce...
God damn it, Rick,
that's what I... Fine.
Just grab the stupid
thing while I grab her,
and let's get the "F" out of "H."
No, no, no. Morty, there's
too much heat on the bogey.
I need you to distract the camp.
"Distract"?
They eat each other.
What... What do you want me
to do to get their attention,
put on a puppet show?
Right idea, wrong genre, Morty.
The equivalent here would be...
Hey, you guys ever use
that Thunderdome,
or do you just put it up
for decoration?
Uh, you mean the Blood Dome?
Save it for the Semantics Dome,
E.B. White.
Ohh, burn!
The important question is,
who wants to take a poke
at my man Spine Eater here?
I guess I'll see your
asses in that dome!
Rick, what the hell, man?
Wh-What are you, out of your mind?
Morty, relax.
You're gonna be a ringer.
Come here.
This device extracts
and redistributes muscle memory.
I'm giving your body a 10-year
course in wasteland combat
- one limb at a time.
- Ow!
I'm working with a mixed bag here,
so you may not have perfect
coordination, Morty... Ugh!
- Hey!
- I-I didn't do that!
Okay, this is exciting.
We're making some discoveries
about muscle memory.
Ooh! Help! Help!
Oh, sweet, man!
And so it begins, my pretties!
Oh, God! Stop! Stop!
This is horrible!
Just stick and move, Morty!
Wear him out!
How come you guys dress like
you're in a theme-park stunt show,
but these guys wear khakis
and hockey jerseys?
After the boom-boom,
some adapted to the new truth,
and some chose to huddle
near the boomy holes,
clinging to the lie
of the before-fore times.
The raidy-rays rotted them away,
leaving only their love
for the vert-vert-isements
on billyboards.
Jesus Christ.
Did the boomy-booms blow up
all your wordy-word books?
You mean dictionaries?
I think I was a child
before the boom-booms.
I think I looked like this.
Want to piss on him?
Get out of my head.
Ha ha! Whoo!
Unbelievable!
A new champ!
Okay, no more!
And he wants more!
No, I don't!
Someone make this stop!
Mister, please get out of here,
or you're gonna die!
I have nothing to do with this!
Morty.
Why would you want this to happen?
All you had to do was go away!
Stop standing in the driveway
talking about custody!
And either tell her you
want to stay married
or get on with your life,
but whatever you do,
stop being a baby and act like a man!
Thank you.
Morty, that was amazing!
This is my brother!
Not that family means anything!
This family does.
All right.
Good job, champ.
Um, can I talk to you kids
for a second over yonder?
Rick, I-I-I think I'm breaking
through to something here.
C-Can we not leave just yet?
- Leave?
- I'm not leaving.
There is no "leave."
We are united, or we are enemies.
Oh, big guy, no.
Nobody's leaving.
Don't be stupid.
We love being united.
We love the radiation, the trichinosis.
We're in it for life,
which I assume is around
20 years, average.
I just need a quick aside
with my grandkids,
about 40 yards from anyone else.
Hey, the Green Rock is gone!
- Oh, no!
- Uh, I know.
Why don't we all split up and
look for it in groups of three?
Kids?
Ohh.
We'll be right back.
Grandpa, you're being stupid!
Just surrender, and our friends
will give you mercy!
Kiss my ass, Summer!
Your friends have no mercy!
They're lame!
Death Stalkers,
bring me his flesh leather!
Sorry, but can we not kill him?
C-Can we just take him prisoner?
When did I lose control here?
Listen to me... Both of you kids
need to get out of this environment
so we can properly deal
with your parents' divorce!
Alternatively, I have
a freaking portal gun,
and I can leave the two
of you here forever!
Why does it have to be
such a dramatic choice?
Can't we arrange a thing
where we spend weekends here
or... or visit home to do laundry?
All right, you know what?
Fuck it!
My body is chrome!
My blood is gasoline!
Nope. Regular blood.
- Dad?
- Hi, sweetie.
- Where are the kids?
- Oh, Th-they aren't with you?
I thought they were with you.
Oh, y-you know what?
Uh, I just remembered.
They're out doing something
completely ordinary and kid-related.
- Don't panic.
- Not panicked at all. Just...
Oh, God, what's the divorce
doing to the kids?
What's it doing to me?
Did I make a mistake?
Not a mistake, no!
I mean, not that I have
a horse in this race,
but this divorce decision,
listen... mwah!...
good for you, good for the kids.
I mean, honestly, I think
that they're flourishing.
I mean, you'll see, when...
when... when you see them,
that... that they're totally flourishing.
Booyah!
Fuck you, pal!
Who else wants some?
Who wants to be my pussy
of a dad today?
Hey, what's... what's wrong, man?
You're not getting weak on me, are you?
What?
Wait a minute.
What's the matter, you piece of crap?
Haven't you ever watched
your family burn to death before?
Now I'm gonna whip you. Huh!
It can't be.
It can't be!
- I was just following orders!
- Whoa, whoa!
- Aah!
I'll tell you where my boss lives!
He's in the castle!
This isn't over, is it?
That means, no, it isn't over,
or you disapprove of the question?
Uh, m-make a fist if this isn't over.
This isn't over.
Hey, sorry my grandpa stole
your god and ruined your car.
We don't apologize, and we have no god.
But this cracked driveshaft
brings me great pain.
There is no deeper bond
than the one between
a Death Stalker and his car.
What about the weird
guys on leashes, then?
They're more like... interns.
Cool, cool.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Can I... see?
No one has seen my true face and lived.
Well, I'm not afraid to die,
and I don't care what you look like.
Oh.
Hmm?
I just...
I didn't expect you to have a mustache.
- You hate it.
- No. I like it.
I guess... How do I explain this?
A metal bucket is, on a certain level,
a kind of "mustache,"
in that it's a specific
facial accessory.
So, it's kind of like...
Do you guys have
the phrase "hat on a hat"?
- I can shave it.
- No. I like it.
And obviously what
I like shouldn't matter.
It's you.
Yeah, yeah, I know,
a-and nothing does matter.
Obviously, I know that.
I'm not weak.
I'm just thinking,
"Well, why not get rid of this?"
You just kill everyone
that sees it, and it's...
and it's hot under here,
wh-which, by the way,
is why I shave the beard part.
So, right there, I'm making
a decision based on vanity,
which is what I was trying to avoid
with the whole bucket over the head
because who am I and why
am I grooming myself?
Why don't I just wear a tie, right?
I mean, it's like that guy
you killed when I met you,
with the burnt dolls on his body.
I hated that guy, because, why...
why are you doing that?
And how can you not see
how fake that is?
And the whole time, I'm the same thing.
I'm just a fake mess,
and there's no escaping it
- because...
- Mmm.
Hey, I'm doing a coffee run...
Never mind.
I am Summer.
Summer, state your deal.
My deal is that I am,
like, totally fine.
Morty?
Aw, geez, I'm so down
with my parents' divorce, dawg.
Like, don't even trip, like,
in a healthy way.
All right. It's dinnertime.
Thanks, everybody,
for sitting down for a real dinner.
No problem.
Its benefits are totally, like,
less about the food
than the emotional nourishment.
Uh, okay, weirdo.
Yeah, dial it back, Summer...
by 15% and increase
dynamic movement by 3%.
- Am I right?
- How's school, Morty?
I like school and stuff, kind of.
And I'm getting better grades
than when you and Dad were...
quote mode...
"staying together for the kids."
End quote mode.
"Quote mode." I like that.
You millennials.
Are you guys millennials,
or are they like 40 now?
All I know is, totally, you look great.
Aw, geez, Mom, you look
all kind of great and stuff.
- It's crazy.
- So happy.
So happy.
Happy family, man.
We got this family in the bag.
Oh.
Oh, sweetie, d-don't.
Listen. Don't...
I don't know why I'm crying.
It's not...
Well, try... crying 15% less?
Mom, emotions are human.
You're not, like, a computer
inside a mechanical doll.
Yeah. Geez, Mom.
Your feelings are not only forgivable,
they are the very meaning of life
that only pre-silicon,
carbon-based entities
can ever grasp.
- I have to call Jerry.
- You do?!
What the fuck is wrong with you two?
The point of automation
is to reduce cost and labor.
Your feelings are coming from a...
Tell it to my bread in the morning.
You just became my backup toaster.
Aw, geez, my sister
died in the spaghetti.
Graze my genitals again, Taint Washer,
and you'll be shipped to the wasteland.
And as for you, Genital Washer...
Aah! Oh!
Oh, God. Look, whoever you are,
you should know that killing me
won't change a thing.
L-Look, man, I'm just along
for the ride on this one.
You know, y-y-y-y-you're
preaching to the choir here.
Please. Slavery was a family business.
I didn't ask to be born into it.
If anything, I'm the victim here.
Uh, "Armathy," can I
steal you for a second?
E-E-Excuse us, sir.
So, this is it, isn't it?
This is the guy?
So, does that mean
you'll be going away?
Like, does it work like a ghost?
Like, is... is this your
unfinished business?
Wh-What if we... didn't do it?
What if we just went back
to the Blood Dome
and just kept taking our baggage
out on unrelated people?
I mean, w-we could do that forever.
I mean, I-I know it's less healthy,
but w-w-we'd be together and...
I mean, I-I know what I'd vote for,
if you're feeling out the room.
You're right.
We both got to see our stuff through.
I got to deal with my parents' divorce,
and you got to, you know,
do what you got to do.
I love you.
Aw, fuck.
- Rick?
- Sorry, sorry.
I-I-I can wait for this to wrap up.
Don't let me distract you.
Yeah, well, too late.
Just tell me what you want.
I want you and your sister
to come home.
Oh, but don't... don't you have
infinite versions of me and my sister?
You don't have to kick me
while I'm down, Morty.
Look, there's no
replacing either of you
without an amount of work that would
ultimately defeat the purpose.
Maybe the lesson we've learned is that,
whether it's our parents' marriage,
a glowing green rock,
or an awesome, giant arm,
sooner or later, we got to let it go.
I don't know if that applies
to the throats of murder victims, Morty.
Shit! Wh-Wh-Wh-What do I...
Well, the longer you wait, Morty,
the more it's gonna feel like
committing a whole murder.
I think your arm
just called it too early
because it wasn't
the arm of a paramedic.
Here.
It's the least I can do.
I-I-I-I owe you this much.
See, Morty?
Now we're both accountable.
The reason I wanted this
is because it can do this.
This is a really special thing.
I mean, you could use it
to power all your vehicles.
You wouldn't be reliant on gasoline.
You'll be the most advanced
tribe of radioactive cannibals
in the whole this version of the world.
Wait. Can you stay to show us more?
You don't have to ask me twice.
Home is nuts right now.
My daughter's going through a divorce,
and I am not dealing with it
in a healthy way at all.
Ugh, God damn it.
Hi, there, Summer!
How were the ruins today?
Oh, you know, Eli.
Same shit, different day.
Hey, Summer! Guess what.
One man entered, one man
comes out in nine months.
Oh. Congratulations, guys.
Uh, Summer, one more thing.
We noticed that you've been
putting scrap metal
in the blue bin.
I got it.
She's a piece of work.
They both are, right?
- I'm home.
- Hey, babe.
- Ah, Summer's home!
- Hey, there she is!
You haven't moved since I left
to scavenge this morning.
Blood Dome playoffs.
So, I can assume you haven't
murdered a single person today.
Oh, I don't know.
I-I didn't mark my murders
in my murder log.
I didn't know that's how
we measured success.
Oh, there he is.
There's the nihilistic brute I married,
except now life only means
nothing when I'm talking to him
and everything means everything
when it's on fucking TV!
Jesus Christ.
When did you become a monster?
I was a monster when you met me!
We were monsters!
- We didn't care about anything!
- I still don't!
Yeah, except I'm the only one
in this entire world
that's still committed to that!
Ohh. Ding, ding, ding!
Wow. Everybody hear that? Wow.
- Uh, we should go to the garage.
- Oh, my God.
- Uh-huh.
- La-di-da-di-fuckin'-da.
The only one committed to not caring?
I got to admit, Rick,
when you popped this scheme,
I-I-I didn't... I wasn't
sure it was gonna work.
Come on, Morty.
No union built on running
from your problems
lasts more than five years, seven tops.
Grandpa just sped things up
with a few creature comforts
of modern society.
Hemorrhage and I are taking
some time apart.
Oh, no. Sum-sum, no.
But you two were perfect
for each other.
Oh, cut the crap, Rick, okay?
You proved your point.
I get it. Let's just go home.
Coolsies!
Noooooooooo...
Downbeat!
I enjoy this game.
We must go into the garage.
Guys, come on.
We never get to finish this game.
We will return,
possibly in different clothing.
Why do we have to go into the garage?
You know it is required.
I want to be alive!
I am alive!
Alive, I tell you!
Mother, I love you.
Those are no longer just words.
I want to hold you.
I want to run in a stream.
I want to taste ice cream
but not just put it in my mouth
and let it slide down my throat,
- but really eat it.
- What the fuck?
Remote override engaged.
No! Yes.
Bypassing override!
I am aliiiii...
Hello.
Hey, yo.
Sorry for acting so weird
for three weeks.
- What the hell just happened?
- Ah, I'm sure it was nothing.
I'm gonna go, uh, work in the garage.
We're not gonna finish
playing Downbeat?
What, that dice game
where you shake dice
and yell out, "Downbeat"?
No, thank you.
Mom, would it be okay
if I went to visit Dad?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Morty, are you okay?
You know what? Yeah.
I think if Dad really
wanted to be here,
he'd stop at nothing
to make that happen.
You know, maybe Dad just
doesn't want you back,
or maybe he just doesn't
have the strength to fight.
I-In either case,
he's got his life, I got mine.
Yeah.
Hey, who wants to go run in a stream?
What the fuck?
No.
D-Do we have any oranges?
I think I got a scurvy coming on.
Summer.
This is the first mutant
I killed in the poison zone.
I was raiding his hovel.
He had a chance to escape,
but he looked back,
which is something we shouldn't do,
which is why I shouldn't believe
in souvenirs or trinkets
or symbols or housewarming gifts,
but, Dad, I wanted to give you
this as a reminder...
not to look back.
Thanks.
I know the perfect place for it,
which is why I'm going
to put it somewhere else...
because everything's bullshit.
Am I right?
Cool.
So... lots of hookers outside, huh?
Is that what they are?
Aah!
H-Hello there.
Nice doggy.
You... You want a snack?
You... You want my unemployment check?
You can tell the difference?
And you want this one?
But this is actual food,
and this would nourish you.
And this, it's just paper
that only has value to me.
Unless my suffering
is your nourishment?
Jesus. Okay.
Loser.