1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:10,896 --> 00:00:15,336
I hope the United States
will keep out of this war.

3
00:00:15,423 --> 00:00:18,335
I believe that it will.

4
00:00:18,415 --> 00:00:21,590
And I give you assurance and reassurance

5
00:00:21,676 --> 00:00:27,535
that every effort of your government
will be directed toward that end.

6
00:00:27,661 --> 00:00:33,412
As long as it remains
within my power to prevent,

7
00:00:33,492 --> 00:00:39,047
there will be no blackout of peace
in the United States.

8
00:01:34,070 --> 00:01:38,326
After World War I
there was a surge of isolationism,

9
00:01:38,406 --> 00:01:42,737
a feeling we had no reason
to become involved in World War I

10
00:01:42,818 --> 00:01:44,618
and we'd made a mistake

11
00:01:44,698 --> 00:01:49,215
and there were a lot of debts owed
by European countries,

12
00:01:49,301 --> 00:01:51,440
and the country went isolationist.

13
00:01:51,526 --> 00:01:55,160
I haven't the slightest idea
of European affairs.

14
00:01:55,248 --> 00:01:57,931
- Let Europe fight their own battles.
- War? Not for me.

15
00:01:58,010 --> 00:02:00,770
This time America should keep out -
and I know I will.

16
00:02:00,849 --> 00:02:02,453
If war breaks out in Europe,

17
00:02:02,537 --> 00:02:06,062
this country should heed the advice
of its first president

18
00:02:06,143 --> 00:02:08,478
and avoid all foreign entanglement.

19
00:02:09,635 --> 00:02:14,195
(narrator) In early 1940, Britain's
ambassador in Washington reported

20
00:02:14,277 --> 00:02:16,000
that nine out of ten Americans

21
00:02:16,080 --> 00:02:18,840
were determined
to keep America out of the war.

22
00:02:18,919 --> 00:02:21,450
A few, like the American Nazi Party,

23
00:02:21,528 --> 00:02:24,016
even wanted America
to aid Britain's enemies.

24
00:02:24,137 --> 00:02:27,159
(speaking German)

25
00:02:27,244 --> 00:02:29,852
(man shouts)

26
00:02:41,094 --> 00:02:43,854
(man) The country
was enormously divided.

27
00:02:43,933 --> 00:02:48,069
There was the America First movement,
which was advocating isolationism;

28
00:02:48,191 --> 00:02:50,330
on the other hand there was

29
00:02:50,416 --> 00:02:54,901
the Committee to Defend America
by Aiding the Allies.

30
00:02:54,982 --> 00:02:56,509
We had these curious voices

31
00:02:56,632 --> 00:03:00,003
such as Charles Lindbergh's,
the voices of isolationism.

32
00:03:00,084 --> 00:03:05,529
In the past, we have dealt with a Europe
dominated by England and France.

33
00:03:05,609 --> 00:03:10,475
In the future, we may have to deal
with a Europe dominated by Germany.

34
00:03:10,558 --> 00:03:14,278
(Ball) Charles Lindbergh,
thanks to his extraordinary exploit,

35
00:03:14,394 --> 00:03:17,723
was a very popular figure -
he was almost a folk hero.

36
00:03:17,809 --> 00:03:19,685
So he would have influence.

37
00:03:19,804 --> 00:03:23,557
I suppose that celebrities
of all characters have influence,

38
00:03:23,640 --> 00:03:26,936
otherwise they wouldn't be
endorsing products all the time.

39
00:03:27,016 --> 00:03:31,075
(Lindbergh)..but it should not involve
the internal affairs of Europe.

40
00:03:31,160 --> 00:03:37,216
They never were, and never will be,
carried on according to our desires.

41
00:03:37,298 --> 00:03:40,517
(applause)

42
00:03:40,636 --> 00:03:43,124
There was a strong
anti-British antipathy

43
00:03:43,245 --> 00:03:45,078
in certain parts of the country.

44
00:03:45,163 --> 00:03:46,996
It was felt that Britain

45
00:03:47,081 --> 00:03:50,377
was trying very hard
to drag us into its war.

46
00:03:50,457 --> 00:03:53,982
(marching band music)

47
00:03:58,207 --> 00:04:01,927
(narrator) 1940 was presidential
election year in the United States

48
00:04:02,005 --> 00:04:06,064
and Roosevelt's main concern that summer
was to get himself re-elected.

49
00:04:09,793 --> 00:04:11,746
Ladies and gentlemen,

50
00:04:11,827 --> 00:04:18,538
the 22nd convention of the
Republican Party will now come to order.

51
00:04:18,617 --> 00:04:24,247
Even as we meet,
lights are going out in Europe.

52
00:04:24,372 --> 00:04:26,052
Blackouts of dictators

53
00:04:26,137 --> 00:04:30,392
take the place
of lighthouses of free men.

54
00:04:30,472 --> 00:04:37,521
Ours is the grave responsibility
to preserve the lighthouses of liberty.

55
00:04:37,608 --> 00:04:39,747
In the name...

56
00:04:39,871 --> 00:04:42,010
of the people...

57
00:04:42,096 --> 00:04:45,315
of the whole United States...

58
00:04:45,396 --> 00:04:48,767
I place in nomination...

59
00:04:48,849 --> 00:04:52,252
that valiant American...

60
00:04:52,340 --> 00:04:56,137
Franklin Delano Roosevelt!

61
00:04:57,481 --> 00:04:59,204
(narrator) After France's fall,

62
00:04:59,322 --> 00:05:02,312
most Americans were disposed
to aid Britain in some way,

63
00:05:02,391 --> 00:05:06,527
but still more were strongly opposed
to entering the war on Britain's side.

64
00:05:06,611 --> 00:05:09,067
(Willkie)..third-term candidate

65
00:05:09,144 --> 00:05:12,166
has not kept faith
with the American people.

66
00:05:12,251 --> 00:05:15,655
(narrator) Roosevelt's opponent
in the election that autumn

67
00:05:15,742 --> 00:05:19,954
was an out-and-out anti-war candidate,
Wendell Willkie.

68
00:05:20,845 --> 00:05:25,667
(Willkie) If his promise
to keep our boys out of foreign wars

69
00:05:25,794 --> 00:05:29,776
is no better than his promise
to balance the budget,

70
00:05:29,861 --> 00:05:34,039
they're already
almost on the transports.

71
00:05:36,766 --> 00:05:39,941
(narrator) But with the Nazis
triumphant everywhere,

72
00:05:40,027 --> 00:05:42,820
Roosevelt couldn't afford
to wait to be re-elected

73
00:05:42,905 --> 00:05:46,308
before putting America
on some sort of war footing.

74
00:05:46,396 --> 00:05:50,607
(Roosevelt) The Congress
has debated without partisanship

75
00:05:50,693 --> 00:05:53,148
and has now enacted a law

76
00:05:53,225 --> 00:05:58,702
establishing a selective method
of augmenting our armed forces.

77
00:05:58,788 --> 00:06:04,724
We must, and we will,
marshal our great potential strength

78
00:06:04,849 --> 00:06:08,799
to fend off war from our shores.

79
00:06:10,988 --> 00:06:14,087
(man) More than 16 million
young Americans

80
00:06:14,210 --> 00:06:19,688
are reviving the 300-year-old
American custom of the muster,

81
00:06:19,773 --> 00:06:23,144
by which,
from the earliest colonial times,

82
00:06:23,226 --> 00:06:25,757
every able-bodied citizen

83
00:06:25,835 --> 00:06:29,971
was subject to the call for service
in the national defence.

84
00:06:40,835 --> 00:06:46,739
The first number
drawn by the secretary of war

85
00:06:46,820 --> 00:06:51,993
is serial number 158.

86
00:06:52,076 --> 00:06:54,291
(cheering)

87
00:06:54,378 --> 00:06:57,171
I am honoured
to be one of those first called

88
00:06:57,294 --> 00:07:00,819
and I'll try very hard
to make a real good soldier.

89
00:07:00,900 --> 00:07:02,853
And I'm proud of you.

90
00:07:02,972 --> 00:07:06,376
(Willkie) If you elect me
president of the United States,

91
00:07:06,463 --> 00:07:13,403
I shall never send an American boy
to fight in any European war.

92
00:07:15,134 --> 00:07:21,539
I consider it a public duty
to answer falsifications with facts.

93
00:07:21,656 --> 00:07:27,668
I will not pretend
that I find this an unpleasant duty.

94
00:07:27,756 --> 00:07:30,211
(laughter)

95
00:07:32,781 --> 00:07:37,877
I am an old campaigner
and I love a good fight.

96
00:07:37,961 --> 00:07:40,252
(cheering)

97
00:07:40,378 --> 00:07:43,215
(narrator)
Roosevelt got his good fight,

98
00:07:43,293 --> 00:07:46,665
though to stay in the race
he had promised, like his opponent,

99
00:07:46,746 --> 00:07:51,111
not to send American boys
to fight in foreign wars.

100
00:07:52,079 --> 00:07:54,534
- Name, please?
- Franklin D Roosevelt.

101
00:07:55,608 --> 00:07:58,631
(narrator) November 5, 1940,
was election day,

102
00:07:58,716 --> 00:08:00,669
and by midnight America's choice

103
00:08:00,749 --> 00:08:03,280
of president for another four years
was clear.

104
00:08:03,358 --> 00:08:07,232
(man) The results are now conclusive -
Roosevelt wins.

105
00:08:07,310 --> 00:08:09,492
(cheering)

106
00:08:22,732 --> 00:08:26,213
(narrator) Now Roosevelt
felt he had a mandate

107
00:08:26,339 --> 00:08:29,285
to give Britain all aid short of war.

108
00:08:29,369 --> 00:08:32,359
But he could only move slowly,
for America was still deeply divided.

109
00:08:33,168 --> 00:08:36,997
(Corwin) Many of the war measures,
such as steps to give aid to Britain

110
00:08:37,081 --> 00:08:41,292
at the time when England
was standing alone and was beleaguered,

111
00:08:41,378 --> 00:08:43,789
just squeaked by in Congress.

112
00:08:43,871 --> 00:08:49,731
Even a programme of armament,
of military preparedness,

113
00:08:49,818 --> 00:08:53,495
got through Congress
on very, very close votes,

114
00:08:53,578 --> 00:08:58,597
one-vote margins
in a total of 400 votes.

115
00:08:58,719 --> 00:09:01,937
(Harriman) Then the extraordinary
legislation, Lend-Lease,

116
00:09:02,018 --> 00:09:07,877
was proposed in December of 1940
and became law in March of '41,

117
00:09:07,964 --> 00:09:09,459
and under that the president

118
00:09:09,576 --> 00:09:12,642
did everything he possibly could
to give aid to Britain.

119
00:09:12,722 --> 00:09:17,207
My instructions
when I went over to represent him

120
00:09:17,325 --> 00:09:20,468
were very simple, very brief.

121
00:09:20,548 --> 00:09:23,800
They were to contact
the British government

122
00:09:23,886 --> 00:09:29,899
to find out what we could do
to help Britain - short of war.

123
00:09:30,024 --> 00:09:32,391
And we began at once
doing all sorts of things

124
00:09:32,480 --> 00:09:36,735
which were not really neutral
under the literal interpretation -

125
00:09:36,815 --> 00:09:41,070
for instance, we were preparing
British naval vessels in American ports

126
00:09:41,150 --> 00:09:46,017
and we escorted convoys
across the Atlantic as far as Iceland,

127
00:09:46,099 --> 00:09:49,395
and we transferred
two million tons of ships.

128
00:09:51,547 --> 00:09:54,995
The immediate problem was to get people
to understand what it was.

129
00:09:55,076 --> 00:09:59,594
In this, I think Mr Roosevelt's
very simple analogy

130
00:09:59,680 --> 00:10:03,816
of lending your neighbour a fire hose
when there's a fire

131
00:10:03,900 --> 00:10:08,232
was a most persuasive
simple illustration.

132
00:10:08,312 --> 00:10:11,913
(Roosevelt) The people of Europe
who are defending themselves

133
00:10:11,995 --> 00:10:15,716
do not ask us to do their fighting.

134
00:10:15,870 --> 00:10:19,122
They ask us for the implements of war -

135
00:10:19,208 --> 00:10:23,267
the planes, the tanks,
the guns, the freighters -

136
00:10:23,390 --> 00:10:29,141
which will enable them to fight
for their liberty and our security.

137
00:10:29,221 --> 00:10:33,782
We must be
the great arsenal of democracy.

138
00:10:33,863 --> 00:10:39,843
For us, this is an emergency
as serious as war itself.

139
00:10:39,925 --> 00:10:45,981
In those days, the business community
regarded Roosevelt

140
00:10:46,063 --> 00:10:51,967
as, at a minimum,
a major deputy of the devil,

141
00:10:52,048 --> 00:10:56,304
and Roosevelt was deeply suspicious
of the businessmen,

142
00:10:56,383 --> 00:11:02,472
so that the people who were associated
with the mobilising of the war

143
00:11:02,560 --> 00:11:04,851
had a divided interest.

144
00:11:04,939 --> 00:11:08,463
Some of them felt that their
main purpose in being in Washington

145
00:11:08,545 --> 00:11:13,062
was to put a curb on the
socialist excesses of the New Deal.

146
00:11:13,149 --> 00:11:15,408
Some of them
were uneasy about being there -

147
00:11:15,489 --> 00:11:22,123
they had the feeling of people who were
playing in an orchestra in a brothel.

148
00:11:22,203 --> 00:11:28,870
And there was
also a great unwillingness...

149
00:11:28,993 --> 00:11:32,867
We hear now
about the military-industrial complex -

150
00:11:32,945 --> 00:11:35,967
in those days
there was a great unwillingness

151
00:11:36,053 --> 00:11:38,464
to convert from civilian industry.

152
00:11:38,546 --> 00:11:43,609
There was a feeling that war production
would be a very unprofitable business,

153
00:11:43,726 --> 00:11:48,472
it would lose markets for automobiles,
for tyres, for chemicals, and so forth.

154
00:11:51,168 --> 00:11:54,464
(Galbraith) There was a problem
with some of the unions

155
00:11:54,544 --> 00:11:57,611
up until June of 1941.

156
00:11:57,690 --> 00:12:00,146
Until Russia was in the war,

157
00:12:00,222 --> 00:12:03,289
and in the days of the
Molotov-Ribbentrop pact,

158
00:12:03,368 --> 00:12:07,089
there was foot-dragging on the part
of some of the union leaders.

159
00:12:07,166 --> 00:12:09,196
And there were strikes.

160
00:12:09,276 --> 00:12:11,229
(narrator) Four times as many workers

161
00:12:11,310 --> 00:12:13,644
were on strike in 1941
as in the year before.

162
00:12:13,727 --> 00:12:18,441
That spring, nearly half a million
coal miners struck for almost a month,

163
00:12:18,522 --> 00:12:22,200
while on the west coast a walk-out
that summer at North American Aviation

164
00:12:22,321 --> 00:12:26,499
delayed deliveries of planes to Britain
for several weeks.

165
00:12:26,579 --> 00:12:30,409
It took troops
to get production moving again.

166
00:12:40,851 --> 00:12:44,954
But although Roosevelt was still
reluctant to lead America into war,

167
00:12:45,032 --> 00:12:48,022
the war was now
catching up with America.

168
00:12:48,102 --> 00:12:54,998
June 11th, 1941: an American freighter,
the Robin Moor, was sunk by a U-boat.

169
00:12:55,122 --> 00:12:58,189
Roosevelt used this as a pretext
for occupying Iceland

170
00:12:58,268 --> 00:13:01,258
and relieving
the British garrisons there.

171
00:13:01,338 --> 00:13:06,630
September 4th: a US destroyer, Greer,
was attacked by a U-boat near Iceland.

172
00:13:06,709 --> 00:13:10,582
Roosevelt now told his navy
to shoot on sight.

173
00:13:10,660 --> 00:13:15,527
October 16th : the US destroyer Kearney
was struck by a German torpedo

174
00:13:15,648 --> 00:13:19,826
while escorting a convoy in mid-Atlantic
and 11 of her crew were killed.

175
00:13:19,906 --> 00:13:21,400
Roosevelt used this incident

176
00:13:21,517 --> 00:13:24,584
to push through Congress
the repeal of the Neutrality Act.

177
00:13:24,663 --> 00:13:28,646
We have wished to avoid shooting.

178
00:13:28,730 --> 00:13:32,560
But the shooting has started.

179
00:13:32,643 --> 00:13:39,921
And history has recorded
who fired the first shot.

180
00:13:40,009 --> 00:13:42,770
In the long run, however,

181
00:13:42,887 --> 00:13:49,095
all that will matter
is who fired the last shot.

182
00:13:49,178 --> 00:13:50,782
(applause)

183
00:13:50,866 --> 00:13:57,763
The repeal of our Neutrality Act will be
the last step on the road to war.

184
00:13:57,887 --> 00:14:02,219
If we load our ships
with contraband of war

185
00:14:02,299 --> 00:14:05,551
and send them into combat zones,

186
00:14:05,637 --> 00:14:08,507
they will most certainly be sunk.

187
00:14:08,591 --> 00:14:14,221
And that means war - a war
which in the opinion of many of us,

188
00:14:14,307 --> 00:14:17,865
although designed
to save democracy abroad,

189
00:14:17,952 --> 00:14:23,091
will surely destroy it at home
right here in America.

190
00:14:23,783 --> 00:14:28,115
(narrator) On October 30
the US destroyer Reuben James was sunk

191
00:14:28,195 --> 00:14:30,301
with the loss of 115 lives.

192
00:14:30,382 --> 00:14:33,786
Officers and all hands forward perished.

193
00:14:33,873 --> 00:14:37,626
Myself and 45 men
are all that are alive.

194
00:14:37,748 --> 00:14:40,204
(narrator)
Despite pressure from Churchill,

195
00:14:40,280 --> 00:14:43,608
who dearly wanted America in the war,
Roosevelt now did nothing.

196
00:14:43,695 --> 00:14:47,831
It was clear it would take much more
than the drowning of 100 or so US seamen

197
00:14:47,915 --> 00:14:49,671
to bring America into the war.

198
00:14:49,756 --> 00:14:53,706
There was even a sentiment -
I remember this being expressed -

199
00:14:53,785 --> 00:14:58,225
to the effect that England
would fight to the last American.

200
00:14:58,312 --> 00:15:02,906
There were steps that were developing -
gradual steps, to be sure -

201
00:15:02,992 --> 00:15:07,019
somewhat comparable to the steps
that took place in World War I.

202
00:15:07,097 --> 00:15:11,156
One incident after another - the
torpedoing of the Sussex got us excited,

203
00:15:11,241 --> 00:15:13,652
then there was the Lusitania episode...

204
00:15:13,773 --> 00:15:18,181
In the same way, I think that with the
moves that Mr Roosevelt was making,

205
00:15:18,261 --> 00:15:22,015
the cash-and-carry programme
that he had,

206
00:15:22,098 --> 00:15:26,735
the protection of the convoys,
the destroyer deal...

207
00:15:26,855 --> 00:15:31,220
One thing and another was occurring
that would be apt to produce, I think,

208
00:15:31,306 --> 00:15:34,066
an incident that would set the war off.

209
00:15:34,643 --> 00:15:36,553
(narrator) That incident was massive

210
00:15:36,638 --> 00:15:39,813
and it came in an unexpected place:
Pearl Harbour.

211
00:15:39,899 --> 00:15:41,961
(radio) All army and navy bases

212
00:15:42,048 --> 00:15:45,801
on the island of Oahu in Hawaii
are now under air attack.

213
00:15:45,884 --> 00:15:49,365
For the latest news,
keep tuned to this station.

214
00:15:49,452 --> 00:15:52,136
(Galbraith)
My superior, who was in charge

215
00:15:52,214 --> 00:15:55,204
of all civilian operations
of the war, was away,

216
00:15:55,284 --> 00:15:59,878
so I was then sent on to the
great meeting of the wartime leaders

217
00:15:59,964 --> 00:16:03,838
that convened in Washington
on the night of Pearl Harbour.

218
00:16:03,916 --> 00:16:09,131
I remember my sense of mission
in going to that meeting.

219
00:16:09,210 --> 00:16:11,425
We had all seen the war coming.

220
00:16:11,512 --> 00:16:13,497
Here was the day and here was the hour,

221
00:16:13,584 --> 00:16:17,948
and here was I, attending the meeting
with the other great men.

222
00:16:18,034 --> 00:16:22,945
We got to the meeting and the
other "great men" - myself included -

223
00:16:23,060 --> 00:16:24,860
were one hell of a disappointment,

224
00:16:24,978 --> 00:16:27,661
because nobody could think
of anything to say or do.

225
00:16:27,779 --> 00:16:29,273
It seemed a good idea to see

226
00:16:29,351 --> 00:16:33,378
what materials were threatened
by the Japanese advance.

227
00:16:33,456 --> 00:16:36,369
Everybody was coming in
during the course of this,

228
00:16:36,449 --> 00:16:40,780
some in sport jackets,
some in tennis shoes,

229
00:16:40,899 --> 00:16:46,529
and it became terribly evident
that nobody had any real information

230
00:16:46,654 --> 00:16:49,905
as to where
these strategic commodities came from.

231
00:16:49,992 --> 00:16:54,432
And eventually the whole discussion
bogged down, I remember,

232
00:16:54,519 --> 00:16:56,581
on the question of kapok.

233
00:16:56,667 --> 00:17:03,072
Kapok, everybody thought... It was
clearly listed as a strategic material,

234
00:17:03,189 --> 00:17:05,950
it evidently came
from that part of the world,

235
00:17:06,067 --> 00:17:09,973
and nobody could think, for God's sake,
what the stuff was used for.

236
00:17:10,095 --> 00:17:12,583
(sirens)

237
00:17:18,343 --> 00:17:23,133
I ask that the Congress declare

238
00:17:23,216 --> 00:17:30,844
that since the unprovoked
and dastardly attack by Japan

239
00:17:30,927 --> 00:17:36,710
on Sunday December 7, 1941,

240
00:17:36,797 --> 00:17:42,122
a state of war has existed

241
00:17:42,245 --> 00:17:47,034
between the United States
and the Japanese empire.

242
00:17:47,117 --> 00:17:49,757
(applause)

243
00:17:49,841 --> 00:17:55,243
(narrator) Even now Roosevelt didn't
ask that the US declare war on Germany -

244
00:17:55,327 --> 00:17:59,386
although Britain had already allied
herself with the US against Japan.

245
00:17:59,470 --> 00:18:02,383
But Hitler decided for him.

246
00:18:03,422 --> 00:18:08,059
For some unexplained reason, Hitler
declared war on the United States,

247
00:18:08,141 --> 00:18:11,316
which relieved Roosevelt
of all of his difficulties.

248
00:18:11,402 --> 00:18:15,810
I was practising law in Chicago -
that is, at the time of Pearl Harbour -

249
00:18:15,891 --> 00:18:19,688
and I can tell you that if Hitler
had not made this decision,

250
00:18:19,765 --> 00:18:22,558
if he had simply done nothing,

251
00:18:22,643 --> 00:18:26,167
that there would have been
enormous sentiment

252
00:18:26,249 --> 00:18:31,803
in many parts of the United States
that the Pacific war now was our war,

253
00:18:31,889 --> 00:18:35,217
that the European war
was for the Europeans

254
00:18:35,303 --> 00:18:38,707
and we should concentrate
all our efforts against the Japanese.

255
00:18:48,462 --> 00:18:51,255
Oh, give me land, lots of land

256
00:18:51,340 --> 00:18:54,177
Under starry skies above

257
00:18:54,255 --> 00:18:56,819
Don't fence me in

258
00:18:56,902 --> 00:19:01,572
Let me ride through
the wide open country that I love

259
00:19:01,660 --> 00:19:03,493
Don't fence me in

260
00:19:03,578 --> 00:19:06,720
(Corwin) People sold their homes
at a fraction of their value,

261
00:19:06,801 --> 00:19:10,707
they were certain the west coast would
be under attack, that we'd be bombed.

262
00:19:10,791 --> 00:19:13,398
There were even blackouts
along the west coast,

263
00:19:13,514 --> 00:19:15,467
as there were along the east coast.

264
00:19:15,548 --> 00:19:18,614
And there were even
some false alerts here.

265
00:19:18,694 --> 00:19:20,908
(air-raid siren)

266
00:19:38,912 --> 00:19:43,659
(narrator) Not everybody
took these precautions seriously.

267
00:19:56,636 --> 00:19:59,354
To European eyes, America's going to war

268
00:19:59,475 --> 00:20:03,502
had moments both ludicrous and familiar.

269
00:20:15,972 --> 00:20:19,922
("When Johnny Comes Marching Home")

270
00:20:39,490 --> 00:20:41,824
The men will cheer
and the boys will shout

271
00:20:41,945 --> 00:20:43,821
The ladies they will all turn out

272
00:20:43,902 --> 00:20:45,931
And we'll all feel gay

273
00:20:46,012 --> 00:20:49,732
When Johnny comes marching home

274
00:20:49,810 --> 00:20:53,335
Living among us
are those we call aliens.

275
00:20:54,069 --> 00:20:59,514
We must remember
that our parents or our grandparents

276
00:20:59,593 --> 00:21:02,004
or our great-grandparents

277
00:21:02,087 --> 00:21:05,961
all were aliens in their day.

278
00:21:06,038 --> 00:21:12,291
If you believe you have knowledge
of any improper activity of any alien

279
00:21:12,369 --> 00:21:16,777
you should report the fact
to the nearest FBI office.

280
00:21:16,857 --> 00:21:20,338
Don't try to be the law yourself.

281
00:21:23,725 --> 00:21:25,328
There was a tremendous change -

282
00:21:25,413 --> 00:21:28,053
the change being
that we were the same individuals

283
00:21:28,137 --> 00:21:29,893
as prior to December 7;

284
00:21:29,978 --> 00:21:34,419
on December 8, when we went to school,
many of our classmates and friends

285
00:21:34,505 --> 00:21:38,531
called us "dirty Japs",
teased us, harassed us,

286
00:21:38,610 --> 00:21:41,981
and our so-called friends
were no longer friends.

287
00:21:42,063 --> 00:21:45,816
In the First World War, as you know,
the Germans were hated thoroughly

288
00:21:45,899 --> 00:21:48,267
and there was a great deal
of discrimination

289
00:21:48,393 --> 00:21:50,041
and harassment of the Germans.

290
00:21:50,120 --> 00:21:54,026
In the Second World War, we were at war
with three different nationalities,

291
00:21:54,109 --> 00:21:56,477
the Italians, the Germans
and the Japanese.

292
00:21:56,565 --> 00:21:58,856
And I remember that Thomas Mann

293
00:21:58,943 --> 00:22:02,010
and Bruno Walter
spoke up for the Germans

294
00:22:02,128 --> 00:22:06,187
and said they couldn't be removed
because that would be the last despair,

295
00:22:06,271 --> 00:22:10,298
having fled Nazi Germany, to be
again put into a concentration camp.

296
00:22:10,376 --> 00:22:13,289
And Joe DiMaggio's mother spoke up,

297
00:22:13,407 --> 00:22:16,888
and that was very moving,
in San Francisco.

298
00:22:16,975 --> 00:22:19,430
But the Japanese had really nobody.

299
00:22:24,801 --> 00:22:26,711
I think picking on the Japanese

300
00:22:26,796 --> 00:22:32,394
was partly a logistically rational thing
that the army could handle -

301
00:22:32,474 --> 00:22:38,563
they said, we can't handle the Germans,
but we can handle the Japanese.

302
00:22:38,689 --> 00:22:42,410
After all, they couldn't have moved
all the Germans and Italians -

303
00:22:42,488 --> 00:22:43,982
they would have had to move

304
00:22:44,099 --> 00:22:47,776
half the people out of New York.
It would've been ridiculous.

305
00:22:51,043 --> 00:22:53,377
(Ball) These people
had always been unpopular

306
00:22:53,460 --> 00:22:58,599
because they competed with the American
farmers in truck gardening and so on,

307
00:22:58,716 --> 00:23:00,134
and worked very much harder

308
00:23:00,250 --> 00:23:03,197
and cultivated their land
very much more efficiently.

309
00:23:03,281 --> 00:23:06,882
So a lot of people
took advantage of their situation

310
00:23:06,964 --> 00:23:09,331
to create antipathy toward them.

311
00:23:09,420 --> 00:23:12,180
And the government
acted hastily and rather brutally

312
00:23:12,259 --> 00:23:14,244
- it's not a very attractive chapter.

313
00:23:14,330 --> 00:23:18,357
(narrator) More than 100,000 Japanese
Americans were interned en masse,

314
00:23:18,435 --> 00:23:20,497
mostly those on the west coast,

315
00:23:20,584 --> 00:23:25,723
whereas the 600,000 German and Italian
Americans were treated individually.

316
00:23:25,801 --> 00:23:28,791
(Uno) Although we had heard rumours
of an evacuation,

317
00:23:28,871 --> 00:23:33,388
we didn't realise
that it was going to indeed take place.

318
00:23:33,474 --> 00:23:38,221
We were told that we could
only take what we could carry.

319
00:23:39,613 --> 00:23:43,562
Evacuees had three choices:
they either had to sell their property,

320
00:23:43,641 --> 00:23:45,780
abandon it or store it.

321
00:23:45,866 --> 00:23:49,391
And in many cases, because
of the uncertainty of the situation,

322
00:23:49,472 --> 00:23:53,379
many people just disposed of their
property as best they could.

323
00:23:53,462 --> 00:23:58,100
We were then put on buses
and taken to assembly centres.

324
00:24:00,982 --> 00:24:02,738
From the assembly centres

325
00:24:02,823 --> 00:24:07,002
we lived in horse stalls
or in quickly made tarpaper barracks.

326
00:24:07,082 --> 00:24:09,799
The mental anguish
that my mother went through,

327
00:24:09,883 --> 00:24:13,832
having four of her sons in the service
of the United States government

328
00:24:13,949 --> 00:24:18,205
and having her husband
labelled a dangerous enemy alien...

329
00:24:28,336 --> 00:24:31,555
We had guards, watch towers,
machine guns...

330
00:24:31,635 --> 00:24:35,039
It was a picture of incarceration.

331
00:24:35,127 --> 00:24:38,530
We felt that we were prisoners -
prisoners in our own country.

332
00:25:17,711 --> 00:25:20,549
It was certain
there'd be no more rubber for a while

333
00:25:20,627 --> 00:25:24,031
and we'd have to make do with the stock
of rubber tyres that we had.

334
00:25:24,157 --> 00:25:28,063
And it wasn't in the authority of our
agency to stop the sale of rubber tyres,

335
00:25:28,185 --> 00:25:29,985
so we drew up an order anyway

336
00:25:30,103 --> 00:25:33,202
and we had an anonymous young man
circulate it

337
00:25:33,288 --> 00:25:39,725
in the Office of Production Management
that had to clear all pieces of paper.

338
00:25:39,810 --> 00:25:44,327
Walked in, with "Here's the tyre order,
sir." Everybody signed it.

339
00:25:49,209 --> 00:25:53,388
And we froze the whole nation's
stock of rubber tyres.

340
00:26:24,198 --> 00:26:26,074
Everybody got work.

341
00:26:26,154 --> 00:26:30,824
This was very much appreciated after
the long, deep depression of the 1930s.

342
00:26:30,950 --> 00:26:34,016
You might've thought inflation
would be the major problem,

343
00:26:34,096 --> 00:26:37,544
because in most countries, in most wars,
it's been a major problem.

344
00:26:37,625 --> 00:26:40,189
But very early we mobilised,

345
00:26:40,311 --> 00:26:44,905
we put in a rationing, and, although
there was a small amount of grumbling,

346
00:26:45,030 --> 00:26:48,096
it's amazing how well
the rationing system worked.

347
00:26:48,214 --> 00:26:52,775
(Galbraith) There was a tendency
to accept shortages with one exception.

348
00:26:52,856 --> 00:26:56,838
People were very resistant
to gasoline rationing.

349
00:26:56,923 --> 00:27:01,866
Clothing shortages, food shortages,
coffee, sugar, people would accept.

350
00:27:01,949 --> 00:27:08,507
But there was no form of
rascality, chicanery, thievery, larceny

351
00:27:08,586 --> 00:27:12,416
that people wouldn't engage in
to get extra gasoline.

352
00:27:12,499 --> 00:27:15,718
I think the thing they most resented

353
00:27:15,798 --> 00:27:19,901
was the extreme youth
of many of us who were doing it.

354
00:27:19,980 --> 00:27:22,315
The Office of Price Administration,

355
00:27:22,397 --> 00:27:25,616
as I look back on it,
must've been very hard to take.

356
00:27:25,696 --> 00:27:28,337
I was then 31.

357
00:27:28,420 --> 00:27:33,364
David Ginsberg, my immediate associate,
general counsel, was 29,

358
00:27:33,446 --> 00:27:37,582
and most everybody else
was younger than we were -

359
00:27:37,666 --> 00:27:39,085
including Richard Nixon,

360
00:27:39,163 --> 00:27:42,261
who was one of the more
obscure employees of the agency.

361
00:27:42,347 --> 00:27:45,980
There's a famous wartime picture
of Sewell Avery,

362
00:27:46,068 --> 00:27:48,250
a great tycoon of the last age,

363
00:27:48,332 --> 00:27:51,932
who was head of Montgomery Ward
and brought it out of the Depression,

364
00:27:52,015 --> 00:27:55,735
being carried out of his office
by two American soldiers in uniform

365
00:27:55,813 --> 00:28:00,068
because he wouldn't comply
with the War Labor Board.

366
00:28:00,148 --> 00:28:04,251
Our war programme
for the coming fiscal year

367
00:28:04,330 --> 00:28:09,469
will cost 56 billion dollars.

368
00:28:09,547 --> 00:28:14,294
That means taxes and bonds...

369
00:28:14,381 --> 00:28:17,142
and bonds and taxes.

370
00:28:17,220 --> 00:28:20,778
- Ohh...
- We have a squeal with each orchid.

371
00:28:23,397 --> 00:28:27,150
Want to get your orchid?
Come this way, please.

372
00:28:27,963 --> 00:28:30,450
2250. This is really
a handsome thing to have.

373
00:28:30,533 --> 00:28:33,937
You're getting this
as a premium for a war bond for $2250,

374
00:28:34,024 --> 00:28:36,359
so it's really a good purchase
for anybody.

375
00:28:36,480 --> 00:28:38,662
Let's have a look at that.

376
00:28:38,743 --> 00:28:42,617
Hope is looking at the shoe.
He may increase his bid to $2255.

377
00:28:42,695 --> 00:28:44,571
(laughter)

378
00:28:44,651 --> 00:28:47,521
You're going to come up a little,
aren't you, flabby?

379
00:28:47,605 --> 00:28:49,209
(laughter)

380
00:28:49,293 --> 00:28:52,163
I shouldn't, but I'll go 25.

381
00:28:53,091 --> 00:28:58,613
Our enemies aren't pushovers.
They're savage, skilful and relentless.

382
00:28:58,693 --> 00:29:02,293
They've trained for years for
just this chance to enslave the world,

383
00:29:02,376 --> 00:29:06,631
and that's just what they intend to do.
And they'll use every trick and tool.

384
00:29:06,711 --> 00:29:10,967
But on the other hand,
they aren't supermen.

385
00:29:11,046 --> 00:29:14,113
They didn't come down from Mars.

386
00:29:14,192 --> 00:29:17,488
They can be licked
and they will be licked.

387
00:29:17,607 --> 00:29:19,178
By men.

388
00:29:19,256 --> 00:29:21,471
(cheering)

389
00:29:21,558 --> 00:29:23,663
We fought in 1917

390
00:29:23,745 --> 00:29:25,698
Rum-di-di dum dum dum

391
00:29:25,778 --> 00:29:28,234
And drove the tyrants from the sea

392
00:29:28,310 --> 00:29:30,263
Rum did-di dum dum dum

393
00:29:30,344 --> 00:29:32,558
We're in a bigger, better war

394
00:29:32,684 --> 00:29:34,789
For your patriotic pastime

395
00:29:34,871 --> 00:29:39,006
We don't know what we're fighting for
But we didn't know the last time

396
00:29:39,091 --> 00:29:41,731
So load the cannon,
draw the blade

397
00:29:41,815 --> 00:29:43,615
Rum-di-di dum dum dum

398
00:29:43,695 --> 00:29:48,561
Come on and join the big parade...

399
00:29:52,173 --> 00:29:56,200
Rum-di-di dum dum, rum-di-di dum dum,
rum-di-di dum dum dum

400
00:29:56,278 --> 00:29:58,613
Let the drums roll out

401
00:29:58,695 --> 00:30:00,648
Let the trumpets call

402
00:30:00,767 --> 00:30:02,677
While the people shout

403
00:30:02,762 --> 00:30:04,672
Strike up the band

404
00:30:04,757 --> 00:30:07,016
It was the airplanes
of the treacherous foe

405
00:30:07,097 --> 00:30:09,083
that brought my husband to his death,

406
00:30:09,207 --> 00:30:12,655
and if I can qualify
as an airplane worker at Vega

407
00:30:12,737 --> 00:30:15,071
and with my hands
help to keep 'em flying,

408
00:30:15,154 --> 00:30:17,521
I will feel
that I am carrying on for him.

409
00:30:17,647 --> 00:30:19,524
Hear the cymbals ring

410
00:30:19,604 --> 00:30:21,709
Calling one and all

411
00:30:21,791 --> 00:30:23,667
To the martial swing

412
00:30:23,747 --> 00:30:25,853
Strike up the band

413
00:30:25,934 --> 00:30:28,149
There is work to be done, to be done

414
00:30:28,236 --> 00:30:30,222
There's a war to be won, to be won

415
00:30:30,308 --> 00:30:32,599
Come, you son of a, son of a gun

416
00:30:32,686 --> 00:30:35,021
Take your stand

417
00:30:35,103 --> 00:30:37,013
Fall in line, yea a bow

418
00:30:37,098 --> 00:30:39,816
Come along, let's go

419
00:30:39,899 --> 00:30:42,769
Hey, leader, strike up the band

420
00:30:42,892 --> 00:30:44,386
We are doing our share,

421
00:30:44,503 --> 00:30:48,180
but we're going to do
infinitely more than we have done.

422
00:30:48,263 --> 00:30:52,016
We have in our town today two mothers,

423
00:30:52,099 --> 00:30:56,278
each of whom has given two sons already.

424
00:30:56,358 --> 00:31:01,180
And, as I said before, we'll give
our sons, we'll give our lives,

425
00:31:01,268 --> 00:31:03,374
but, by the help and grace of God,

426
00:31:03,455 --> 00:31:08,474
we will not give up our free America
or our democratic way of life.

427
00:31:09,248 --> 00:31:11,779
Strike up the band

428
00:31:13,622 --> 00:31:15,531
Yankee-doo doodle-doo doodle-doo

429
00:31:15,617 --> 00:31:17,951
We'll come through,
doodle-doo doodle-doo

430
00:31:18,034 --> 00:31:20,096
For the red, white and blue,
doodle-doo

431
00:31:20,182 --> 00:31:22,942
Lend a hand

432
00:31:23,021 --> 00:31:24,821
With the flag unfurled

433
00:31:24,901 --> 00:31:27,268
We can lick the world

434
00:31:27,356 --> 00:31:35,027
Hey, leader, strike up the band

435
00:31:38,597 --> 00:31:41,358
(narrator)
On the night of Pearl Harbour,

436
00:31:41,436 --> 00:31:44,229
one man had been happy -
Winston Churchill.

437
00:31:44,314 --> 00:31:47,380
For now he knew Britain was saved.

438
00:31:47,459 --> 00:31:49,827
A few days later
he journeyed to Washington

439
00:31:49,915 --> 00:31:52,282
to make sure the war
was going to be fought

440
00:31:52,370 --> 00:31:56,277
on the British plan of Europe first
and the Pacific second,

441
00:31:56,360 --> 00:31:59,764
and to cement
the new Anglo-American alliance.

442
00:31:59,851 --> 00:32:03,452
What kind of a people
do they think we are?

443
00:32:03,534 --> 00:32:06,371
Is it possible they do not realise

444
00:32:06,450 --> 00:32:10,815
that we shall never cease
to persevere against them

445
00:32:10,939 --> 00:32:13,470
until they have been taught a lesson

446
00:32:13,548 --> 00:32:16,690
which they and the world
will never forget.

447
00:32:24,712 --> 00:32:29,120
(narrator) Time, Churchill knew,
was on the Allies' side.

448
00:32:29,200 --> 00:32:34,722
With America's industrial might
behind them, they could not lose.

449
00:32:35,914 --> 00:32:37,016
(shouts order)

450
00:32:44,163 --> 00:32:47,916
1942 began badly
for the Americans in the Pacific.

451
00:32:47,999 --> 00:32:53,706
Manila, capital of the Philippines,
fell to the Japanese on January 1.

452
00:32:56,171 --> 00:32:58,735
The Japanese
pushed the American forces

453
00:32:58,818 --> 00:33:01,535
back into the narrow peninsular
of Bataan.

454
00:33:08,448 --> 00:33:10,433
The American plan was to hold out there

455
00:33:10,519 --> 00:33:13,923
for six months or so,
until reinforcements came.

456
00:33:14,010 --> 00:33:16,694
But the reinforcements never did come,

457
00:33:16,773 --> 00:33:21,333
and nor had Bataan
been really prepared for a siege.

458
00:33:43,743 --> 00:33:47,464
The American troops besieged at Bataan
had no air support,

459
00:33:47,541 --> 00:33:51,644
were short of medical supplies
and their morale was poor.

460
00:33:51,723 --> 00:33:54,942
Even their commander-in-chief,
General MacArthur,

461
00:33:55,061 --> 00:33:57,744
had left them for safer shores.

462
00:33:59,396 --> 00:34:03,575
Their bitter ballad:
"We are the battling bastards of Bataan

463
00:34:03,655 --> 00:34:06,492
No mama, no papa, no Uncle Sam

464
00:34:06,570 --> 00:34:09,712
No aunts, no uncles,
no cousins, no nieces,

465
00:34:09,793 --> 00:34:12,739
No pills, no planes or artillery pieces

466
00:34:12,824 --> 00:34:15,737
And nobody gives a goddamn."

467
00:34:17,850 --> 00:34:20,533
Cock-a-hoop with the ease
of their victory so far,

468
00:34:20,612 --> 00:34:26,820
the Japanese called on the Americans
beleaguered in Bataan to surrender.

469
00:34:26,904 --> 00:34:33,156
The voice of the Philippines calling
the attention of everyone everywhere.

470
00:34:33,924 --> 00:34:41,017
Everyone everywhere, Filipinos
and Americans all over the country...

471
00:34:43,400 --> 00:34:46,041
(narrator) They tried leaflets too...

472
00:34:48,618 --> 00:34:54,477
aimed mostly at the Filipino soldiers
among the American forces.

473
00:34:55,485 --> 00:34:59,435
The Japanese closed in for the kill.

474
00:35:36,804 --> 00:35:38,299
In early May, 1942,

475
00:35:38,377 --> 00:35:42,098
the American commander in the
Philippines, General Wainwright,

476
00:35:42,175 --> 00:35:46,616
bowed to the inevitable and surrendered
the remainder of his forces.

477
00:35:46,702 --> 00:35:51,492
(interpreter) I've decided to accept,
in the name of humanity,

478
00:35:51,575 --> 00:35:59,126
the formal surrender of all American
and Philippine army troops

479
00:35:59,209 --> 00:36:01,239
in the Philippine Islands.

480
00:36:01,358 --> 00:36:09,029
You will - repeat, will - surrender all
troops to the proper Japanese officer.

481
00:36:10,067 --> 00:36:13,056
(narrator)
80,000 Americans surrendered,

482
00:36:13,136 --> 00:36:18,351
the largest mass capitulation
in American military history.

483
00:36:18,430 --> 00:36:21,343
The Japanese made the Americans
march in the blazing sun

484
00:36:21,423 --> 00:36:25,056
to prison camps
100 or so miles from Bataan.

485
00:36:25,144 --> 00:36:30,087
Deprived of water and medicine,
starved and brutally beaten,

486
00:36:30,170 --> 00:36:33,618
some 10,000 soldiers
died along the way -

487
00:36:33,699 --> 00:36:37,573
more than had been killed
in the actual fighting for Bataan.

488
00:36:47,280 --> 00:36:51,689
By that spring of 1942, the Japanese
conquests were at their peak.

489
00:36:51,769 --> 00:36:55,905
Surely the British and Americans would
now want to make peace, argued Tokyo -

490
00:36:55,989 --> 00:37:00,048
a peace that would allow the Japanese
to retain their conquests.

491
00:37:00,133 --> 00:37:04,727
But already bold steps were being taken
to strike back at the Japanese

492
00:37:04,813 --> 00:37:08,490
here in the heart of their empire,
Tokyo.

493
00:37:08,573 --> 00:37:11,944
I was on this cruiser
called the Northampton

494
00:37:12,026 --> 00:37:17,089
and we were several days out at sea
when we saw the Hornet coming up.

495
00:37:17,243 --> 00:37:20,462
And the Hornet
had very unusual planes on deck -

496
00:37:20,543 --> 00:37:22,572
you could see them from a long way.

497
00:37:22,653 --> 00:37:26,832
They were large
land-based planes - B-25s.

498
00:37:28,177 --> 00:37:35,543
(man) We had only one real worry -
that would have been a dead calm.

499
00:37:35,620 --> 00:37:37,114
Under those conditions,

500
00:37:37,193 --> 00:37:40,641
taking off the carrier deck
with the heavy loads that we had

501
00:37:40,761 --> 00:37:42,900
would have been at best precarious.

502
00:37:42,986 --> 00:37:45,397
The worst thing we thought might happen

503
00:37:45,480 --> 00:37:48,731
would be a completely alerted Japan
waiting for us.

504
00:37:48,818 --> 00:37:54,143
What did happen was that
the morning just before take-off

505
00:37:54,227 --> 00:37:57,020
we encountered
two Japanese fishing boats.

506
00:37:57,104 --> 00:38:02,243
They spotted our task force,
sent a message to the mainland,

507
00:38:02,322 --> 00:38:05,464
but, unfortunately for the Japanese,

508
00:38:05,545 --> 00:38:09,494
were sunk
before they could repeat the message.

509
00:38:12,949 --> 00:38:16,506
So we achieved almost complete surprise.

510
00:38:37,502 --> 00:38:42,369
The actual amount of damage done
was minimal.

511
00:38:42,490 --> 00:38:47,051
We were 16 aeroplanes,
each with one ton of bombs.

512
00:38:47,170 --> 00:38:52,189
In the later stages of World War II,
the 20th Air Force under LeMay

513
00:38:52,273 --> 00:38:56,681
was sending out 500 aeroplanes,
each with 10 tons of bombs.

514
00:38:56,800 --> 00:39:00,936
So we dropped 16
against a later raid of 5,000,

515
00:39:01,020 --> 00:39:04,086
so the damage was not at all great.

516
00:39:04,166 --> 00:39:06,850
However, it did have some advantages.

517
00:39:06,928 --> 00:39:10,758
One, we had had
nothing but bad news at home,

518
00:39:10,841 --> 00:39:13,253
so it was the first good news
our folks got

519
00:39:13,374 --> 00:39:16,702
and it was appreciated as good news.

520
00:39:16,788 --> 00:39:20,116
It caused the Japanese
to question their warlords,

521
00:39:20,202 --> 00:39:23,880
who had informed them
that Japan would never be attacked.

522
00:39:26,686 --> 00:39:31,509
(narrator) The Doolittle raid stung
Japan's leaders and made them careless.

523
00:39:32,057 --> 00:39:33,235
Ever since Pearl Harbour,

524
00:39:33,323 --> 00:39:37,076
Japan's navy had sought a decisive
battle with America's navy,

525
00:39:37,160 --> 00:39:42,714
a battle that would decide
once and for all mastery of the Pacific.

526
00:39:49,743 --> 00:39:52,885
In early June, 1942,
the Japanese carriers

527
00:39:52,966 --> 00:39:56,032
rendezvous'd close to Midway Island,

528
00:39:56,112 --> 00:39:59,669
some 1300 miles northwest of Hawaii.

529
00:40:14,028 --> 00:40:16,014
(speaking Japanese)

530
00:40:16,906 --> 00:40:19,775
(translator)
We had ceased to be as wary as before.

531
00:40:19,898 --> 00:40:23,575
The Americans knew in advance
that we would attack Midway.

532
00:40:23,696 --> 00:40:26,718
They were waiting for us
and we walked into their trap.

533
00:41:57,191 --> 00:41:59,373
(narrator)
But while the Japanese navy's

534
00:41:59,493 --> 00:42:01,675
attention was focused on Midway Island,

535
00:42:01,757 --> 00:42:03,633
the American navy were preparing

536
00:42:03,713 --> 00:42:06,048
to strike back
at the Japanese carrier fleet.

537
00:42:06,130 --> 00:42:09,349
(man) We had a wonderful advantage -
we were breaking their code

538
00:42:09,468 --> 00:42:10,842
and they didn't know it.

539
00:42:10,926 --> 00:42:13,796
So we had some idea
what was going to happen there.

540
00:42:13,880 --> 00:42:15,680
We were on the scene

541
00:42:15,760 --> 00:42:20,823
with the carrier force in the right spot
to meet them.

542
00:43:23,090 --> 00:43:26,647
(narrator) Midway, one of the greatest
sea battles of all time,

543
00:43:26,735 --> 00:43:30,412
meant the US regained
naval control of the Pacific

544
00:43:30,494 --> 00:43:35,317
and was the end of Japan's hope
of any further conquests.

545
00:43:36,748 --> 00:43:38,242
The four Japanese carriers

546
00:43:38,321 --> 00:43:41,649
that had launched the raid
on Pearl Harbour six months before

547
00:43:41,735 --> 00:43:45,260
were destroyed by planes
from the very American carriers

548
00:43:45,342 --> 00:43:49,936
that had been at sea
and escaped destruction that day.

549
00:43:53,859 --> 00:43:57,994
The Battle of Midway doomed Japan.

550
00:43:58,079 --> 00:44:03,404
The Midway battle was, many people say,
the turning point of the Pacific war -

551
00:44:03,488 --> 00:44:08,584
that is, the turning point
from complete retreat on our part,

552
00:44:08,667 --> 00:44:13,687
or at least an attempt
to establish a stalemate, and offensive.

553
00:44:13,770 --> 00:44:19,247
(narrator) Turning point
not just at sea, but on land too.

554
00:44:21,289 --> 00:44:24,127
The island of Guadalcanal
in the Solomons,

555
00:44:24,205 --> 00:44:28,646
the southernmost limit
of the Japanese conquests.

556
00:44:33,221 --> 00:44:35,981
In August 1942, the Allies returned.

557
00:44:36,060 --> 00:44:39,737
For the Americans,
it was their first invasion of the war.

558
00:44:39,820 --> 00:44:44,490
(man) We had such a tiny fraction
of America's force and money -

559
00:44:44,577 --> 00:44:46,944
resources and manpower resources.

560
00:44:47,032 --> 00:44:49,563
90% went to Europe.

561
00:44:49,679 --> 00:44:54,011
We had such a tiny little thread
of existence down there.

562
00:44:54,091 --> 00:44:56,503
It was our first offensive
in the Pacific

563
00:44:56,585 --> 00:45:00,186
and we went in with only one division.

564
00:45:18,990 --> 00:45:23,398
The Japanese were tough fighters
and they never would give up.

565
00:45:23,479 --> 00:45:26,272
We had isolated a Japanese regiment

566
00:45:26,356 --> 00:45:29,575
in what was known as
the Gifu strongpoint,

567
00:45:29,656 --> 00:45:32,798
and they fought until
we actually had to annihilate them.

568
00:45:32,878 --> 00:45:36,511
We used loudspeakers
after we had surrounded them

569
00:45:36,600 --> 00:45:39,928
and tried to persuade them to surrender,
but they wouldn't.

570
00:45:40,014 --> 00:45:46,681
Japanese shouldn't have made
such a great effort in Guadalcanal.

571
00:45:46,805 --> 00:45:49,412
They could have saved their strength.

572
00:45:50,756 --> 00:45:52,786
(flies buzzing)

573
00:46:28,430 --> 00:46:32,566
(narrator) At long last the tide had
turned for the Allies in the Pacific.

574
00:46:32,689 --> 00:46:35,711
But it was still as yet only a sideshow.

575
00:46:35,796 --> 00:46:39,244
The main energies
were being reserved for Europe.

576
00:46:39,326 --> 00:46:41,050
It was really a little odd

577
00:46:41,168 --> 00:46:44,692
to the Americans in the general public
at that time

578
00:46:44,774 --> 00:46:48,604
that we were spending
so little effort in the Pacific.

579
00:46:48,687 --> 00:46:52,594
President Roosevelt made up his mind
that the defeat of Hitler

580
00:46:52,677 --> 00:46:57,588
was by far the most important
to achieve first -

581
00:46:57,664 --> 00:47:00,457
he was the most dangerous
of the enemies.

582
00:47:00,542 --> 00:47:02,145
And he was very skilful

583
00:47:02,268 --> 00:47:06,786
in keeping American public opinion
directed towards Europe,

584
00:47:06,872 --> 00:47:09,283
although we did have
a very major operation

585
00:47:09,366 --> 00:47:11,700
in Japan
and a very successful operation,

586
00:47:11,783 --> 00:47:14,238
after we recovered
from the tremendous blow

587
00:47:14,315 --> 00:47:17,489
of the loss of a substantial
part of our navy at Pearl Harbour.

588
00:47:17,576 --> 00:47:24,472
I think that generally public opinion
had the feeling, as we say in baseball,

589
00:47:24,558 --> 00:47:27,166
the big league was in Europe

590
00:47:27,244 --> 00:47:31,804
and in the United Kingdom -
I include that in Western Europe.

591
00:47:31,886 --> 00:47:34,603
The decision was made early

592
00:47:34,686 --> 00:47:39,673
that Europe came first -
and it was a wise decision -

593
00:47:39,751 --> 00:47:41,125
in spite of the fact

594
00:47:41,208 --> 00:47:45,846
we got the devil knocked out of us
in the Pacific for a long time.

595
00:47:45,927 --> 00:47:50,521
That was the right decision
and I think everybody recognised it.

596
00:47:50,608 --> 00:47:53,674
Now, of course, the navy protested

597
00:47:53,754 --> 00:47:57,965
at being left
way underpowered in the Pacific.

598
00:47:58,051 --> 00:48:04,914
And it did put us up to
very heavy casualties and all of that.

599
00:48:04,995 --> 00:48:10,287
But I think the country in general
agreed with the decision

600
00:48:10,366 --> 00:48:13,923
that the real threat was in Europe.

601
00:48:14,010 --> 00:48:16,880
We could take care of the Japs
in our own good time,

602
00:48:16,964 --> 00:48:22,748
but the real thing that had to be met
was on the Continent.

603
00:48:33,346 --> 00:48:36,750
This is the army, Mr Jones

604
00:48:36,837 --> 00:48:40,940
No private rooms or telephones

605
00:48:41,058 --> 00:48:44,276
You had your breakfast in bed before

606
00:48:44,357 --> 00:48:48,263
But you won't have it there any more

607
00:48:48,347 --> 00:48:50,103
Here we teach you how to kill:

608
00:48:50,188 --> 00:48:53,330
get the opponent on the ground
as quick as possible

609
00:48:53,411 --> 00:48:56,019
and snuff out his life
by kicking with both feet,

610
00:48:56,097 --> 00:48:57,700
one foot, the flat of the hand,

611
00:48:57,785 --> 00:49:00,774
a rabbit punch,
gouging the eyes out, ripping the mouth.

612
00:49:00,854 --> 00:49:03,112
The gentle art of killing a man

613
00:49:03,232 --> 00:49:07,411
is to get him on the ground
and kick in this manner. See?

614
00:49:12,018 --> 00:49:14,582
Come on, all of you do that.
Come on.

615
00:49:15,701 --> 00:49:19,182
Do what the buglers command

616
00:49:19,269 --> 00:49:23,251
They're in the army and not in a band

617
00:49:23,336 --> 00:49:27,318
This is the army, Mr Brown

618
00:49:27,402 --> 00:49:30,730
You and your baby went to town

619
00:49:30,817 --> 00:49:34,068
She had you worried,
but this is war

620
00:49:34,154 --> 00:49:37,832
And she won't worry you any more

621
00:49:37,914 --> 00:49:41,821
Mr Jones, Mr Green

622
00:49:41,942 --> 00:49:43,775
Mr Brown...

623
00:49:43,861 --> 00:49:49,873
Mr Churchill
did have a real antipathy, I think,

624
00:49:49,961 --> 00:49:56,901
toward getting ashore what he would call
prematurely onto the European continent.

625
00:49:56,981 --> 00:49:59,120
He had very vivid memories

626
00:49:59,207 --> 00:50:03,647
of the sacrifice
of a British generation in World War I.

627
00:50:03,734 --> 00:50:07,608
Passchendaele and the Somme -
they were always nightmares to him.

628
00:50:07,724 --> 00:50:09,556
After all this passion

629
00:50:09,680 --> 00:50:12,517
that had been aroused
as a result of Pearl Harbour

630
00:50:12,634 --> 00:50:16,235
and our being in the war, marching
and counter-marching and training,

631
00:50:16,317 --> 00:50:18,303
we just had to get ashore someplace.

632
00:50:18,427 --> 00:50:20,075
In view of the British attitude,

633
00:50:20,154 --> 00:50:24,519
which felt we weren't prepared
to go into the main theatre,

634
00:50:24,604 --> 00:50:27,900
we sniffed around for another spot
to express our strength

635
00:50:27,980 --> 00:50:29,736
and it turned out it was Africa.

636
00:50:29,822 --> 00:50:34,153
Over there

637
00:50:34,234 --> 00:50:36,339
Send the word, send the word

638
00:50:36,420 --> 00:50:38,450
Over there

639
00:50:38,531 --> 00:50:40,898
That the Yanks are coming

640
00:50:40,986 --> 00:50:43,277
The Yanks are coming

641
00:50:43,364 --> 00:50:46,616
The drums rum-tumming everywhere

642
00:50:47,163 --> 00:50:49,148
So prepare

643
00:50:49,234 --> 00:50:51,493
Say a prayer

644
00:50:51,575 --> 00:50:53,527
Send the word, send the word

645
00:50:53,608 --> 00:50:55,670
To beware

646
00:50:55,756 --> 00:50:57,786
We'll be over

647
00:50:57,866 --> 00:51:00,048
We're coming over

648
00:51:00,130 --> 00:51:04,952
And we won't come back
till it's over over there

649
00:51:08,839 --> 00:51:13,247
And we won't come back
till it's over over there

650
00:51:15,629 --> 00:51:18,237
(narrator) November, 1942.

651
00:51:18,353 --> 00:51:20,994
600 ships, loaded with men and material,

652
00:51:21,115 --> 00:51:24,716
set sail for North Africa -
Operation Torch.

653
00:51:24,798 --> 00:51:29,665
Said Roosevelt, when he heard the news,
"At last we're on our way."
