1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:16,497 --> 00:00:20,556
(narrator) September 1, 1939.

3
00:00:20,640 --> 00:00:22,746
Germany attacks Poland.

4
00:00:23,518 --> 00:00:28,188
Adolf Hitler ignores Britain and France
which had promised to fight for Poland.

5
00:01:09,248 --> 00:01:15,152
Sunday September 3. The British prime
minister Neville Chamberlain broadcasts.

6
00:01:15,233 --> 00:01:19,412
(Chamberlain) This morning
the British ambassador in Berlin

7
00:01:19,492 --> 00:01:23,671
handed the German government
a final note

8
00:01:23,750 --> 00:01:28,889
stating that unless
we heard from them by 11 o'clock

9
00:01:28,968 --> 00:01:33,790
that they were prepared at once
to withdraw their troops from Poland,

10
00:01:33,879 --> 00:01:37,250
a state of war would exist between us.

11
00:01:38,713 --> 00:01:44,310
I have to tell you now that
no such undertaking has been received

12
00:01:44,391 --> 00:01:49,945
and that consequently
this country is at war with Germany.

13
00:02:46,273 --> 00:02:48,258
(chanting / cheering)

14
00:02:56,171 --> 00:02:59,696
(narrator) Danzig, taken
from Germany after the First World War,

15
00:02:59,777 --> 00:03:01,425
welcomed its liberators.

16
00:03:01,504 --> 00:03:04,679
To many good Germans the city's capture
symbolised the end

17
00:03:04,765 --> 00:03:07,864
of the humiliating Treaty of Versailles.

18
00:03:26,172 --> 00:03:30,461
Hitler swept forward
to congratulate his victorious troops.

19
00:03:30,546 --> 00:03:35,336
He said they'd rescued his people
from Polish barbarism.

20
00:03:47,235 --> 00:03:50,639
The Germans thrust into Poland
from the west and north.

21
00:03:50,726 --> 00:03:54,708
In two weeks the Polish army
had virtually ceased to exist.

22
00:03:54,793 --> 00:03:57,662
Warsaw was one of the few places
to hold out.

23
00:03:57,747 --> 00:03:59,886
The Russians,
by agreement with Germany,

24
00:04:00,010 --> 00:04:03,229
seized parts of Poland
they claimed as theirs by right.

25
00:04:03,310 --> 00:04:06,452
The two conquerors met at Brest-Litovsk.

26
00:04:06,532 --> 00:04:11,551
It was the scene of the Russian
surrender to Germany in 1918.

27
00:04:15,126 --> 00:04:18,115
The official German greeting in Russian

28
00:04:18,195 --> 00:04:22,374
said German soldiers had always
respected Russian soldiers.

29
00:04:22,492 --> 00:04:26,933
The clash of Nazi and Communist was,
for the moment, conveniently forgotten.

30
00:04:28,745 --> 00:04:32,498
The final bombardment of Warsaw
began on September 23.

31
00:04:45,549 --> 00:04:47,916
(Polish national anthem)

32
00:04:56,176 --> 00:04:58,860
For nearly three weeks Warsaw Radio

33
00:04:58,939 --> 00:05:02,419
had defiantly played
the Polish national anthem.

34
00:05:16,318 --> 00:05:19,231
On September 27 the anthem stopped.

35
00:05:24,413 --> 00:05:28,210
- (announcement in Polish)
- (air-raid siren)

36
00:05:32,853 --> 00:05:34,806
Warsaw was reduced to rubble.

37
00:05:48,007 --> 00:05:50,495
The capital's commander surrendered.

38
00:06:34,544 --> 00:06:36,802
Poland, swallowed by Germany
and Russia,

39
00:06:36,884 --> 00:06:39,143
disappeared into a new dark age.

40
00:06:39,224 --> 00:06:42,552
Arrests, deportations, executions began.

41
00:06:42,639 --> 00:06:44,777
(siren)

42
00:06:48,892 --> 00:06:52,067
Britain's war started
with a false alarm.

43
00:06:52,153 --> 00:06:54,335
September 3.

44
00:06:54,417 --> 00:06:58,399
(man) I remember
when the outbreak of war came.

45
00:06:58,483 --> 00:07:00,818
We were in the cabinet room

46
00:07:00,900 --> 00:07:05,614
at the moment
that the ultimatum expired.

47
00:07:05,734 --> 00:07:08,069
(narrator) Lord Butler
was a junior minister.

48
00:07:08,151 --> 00:07:13,138
(Butler) And we were just beginning
to congratulate the prime minister

49
00:07:13,254 --> 00:07:16,974
on his broadcast
when we heard a terrible wailing,

50
00:07:17,052 --> 00:07:20,849
which of course
was the first air-raid siren.

51
00:07:23,190 --> 00:07:26,212
Chamberlain took it very seriously

52
00:07:26,336 --> 00:07:31,552
and his wife appeared with an enormous
basket full of things for the night

53
00:07:31,630 --> 00:07:36,803
and Thermos flasks
and things to read and so on.

54
00:07:36,925 --> 00:07:39,762
And so we all went and sheltered.

55
00:07:39,879 --> 00:07:44,593
I went and sheltered after some delay
in the Foreign Office.

56
00:07:44,674 --> 00:07:48,046
The whole of the Horse Guards Parade
was empty of people

57
00:07:48,127 --> 00:07:50,539
and there was nobody in sight anywhere.

58
00:07:50,621 --> 00:07:54,986
When I got there, there was no furniture
so I had to sit on the floor.

59
00:07:55,071 --> 00:07:58,868
And an air-raid warden
said that there would be no gas.

60
00:07:58,946 --> 00:08:03,540
But of course there wasn't really
any war for some time,

61
00:08:03,627 --> 00:08:05,809
quite apart from being no gas.

62
00:08:05,890 --> 00:08:07,876
(air-raid siren)

63
00:08:17,630 --> 00:08:22,541
(narrator) So, no war that day,
or for many months.

64
00:08:22,617 --> 00:08:25,684
People settled down
to enjoy the unexpected reprieve.

65
00:08:25,763 --> 00:08:29,713
It was perfect weather
for a late holiday - or invading Poland.

66
00:08:29,791 --> 00:08:31,777
(military band)

67
00:09:39,424 --> 00:09:41,955
People had braced themselves
for a grimmer war.

68
00:09:42,032 --> 00:09:45,055
Hospitals were cleared
to take air-raid casualties.

69
00:09:45,140 --> 00:09:48,860
The experts predicted
over a million injured in two months.

70
00:09:57,954 --> 00:10:02,089
Children and their mothers evacuated
from the cities - 1.5 million of them.

71
00:10:02,212 --> 00:10:05,845
For some, a nightmare.
For others, an adventure.

72
00:10:05,934 --> 00:10:09,534
(man) We assembled
in a playground rather like this.

73
00:10:09,617 --> 00:10:12,791
The kids were there and the parents.

74
00:10:12,878 --> 00:10:18,781
Children had the gas mask over
their shoulder and labels tied to them.

75
00:10:20,359 --> 00:10:24,189
(woman) The women had to decide
whether to keep their children with them

76
00:10:24,310 --> 00:10:26,842
or whether to allow them to go out.

77
00:10:27,380 --> 00:10:30,249
Now, one would think
that this was an easy decision.

78
00:10:30,334 --> 00:10:33,738
Why not keep your children with you -
the natural thing to do?

79
00:10:33,825 --> 00:10:36,585
But against this
was the terrible thought

80
00:10:36,664 --> 00:10:38,923
that there was going to be gas,

81
00:10:39,004 --> 00:10:42,452
that there was going to be
terrible bombing and death

82
00:10:42,534 --> 00:10:45,600
and that children would be maimed.

83
00:10:47,598 --> 00:10:51,504
(man) Everyone was crying -
the parents and children -

84
00:10:51,588 --> 00:10:55,799
and as we moved off especially,
people burst into tears.

85
00:10:55,885 --> 00:10:59,027
My mother was more unhappy
about the wrench of us going

86
00:10:59,146 --> 00:11:01,360
rather than the war itself.

87
00:11:01,448 --> 00:11:04,699
My sister was crying.
I personally wasn't.

88
00:11:04,824 --> 00:11:10,378
I was rather excited at the prospect
of leaving this part of London.

89
00:11:12,305 --> 00:11:15,142
We thought we'd travelled
to the other side of the world,

90
00:11:15,220 --> 00:11:18,974
but in fact, we came to Denham, here,
only 20 miles from London.

91
00:11:20,093 --> 00:11:23,421
I promised my mother
I wouldn't be separated from my sister,

92
00:11:23,507 --> 00:11:27,534
so we went to the village hall
with all the other kids,

93
00:11:27,612 --> 00:11:31,791
and because we wouldn't be separated,
we were the last ones to find a billet.

94
00:11:31,871 --> 00:11:35,199
It was like being auctioned off
at the time.

95
00:11:35,285 --> 00:11:39,541
But when we finally got a house
to take us in, it was fantastic.

96
00:11:39,620 --> 00:11:42,533
It was a new world
that opened out to us.

97
00:11:42,613 --> 00:11:48,516
I mean, we had toothbrushes
and sheets on the bed and hot water.

98
00:11:48,675 --> 00:11:51,282
Imagine hot water!
We just couldn't get over it.

99
00:11:51,360 --> 00:11:54,459
And we didn't know
what eiderdowns were for.

100
00:11:54,544 --> 00:11:58,418
In the morning
we went blackberry picking.

101
00:11:58,534 --> 00:12:03,052
Then we heard the sirens,
so we rushed back to our billet.

102
00:12:03,138 --> 00:12:08,583
The woman there reassured us and said
not to worry, and we sat down to lunch.

103
00:12:08,663 --> 00:12:13,485
It was the first fully laid-out table
I'd ever seen in my life.

104
00:12:13,573 --> 00:12:18,243
And war was declared,
I think, that same lunchtime.

105
00:12:18,791 --> 00:12:22,086
She said not to worry
and passed us the horseradish sauce.

106
00:12:22,167 --> 00:12:25,538
But I think a number of children
suffered really deeply

107
00:12:25,620 --> 00:12:27,682
being away from their families.

108
00:12:27,807 --> 00:12:30,490
They suffered a sense of rejection.

109
00:12:30,569 --> 00:12:35,436
They exhibited their senses of rejection
and sorrow and suffering

110
00:12:35,556 --> 00:12:39,921
very often by
strange behaviour problems,

111
00:12:40,007 --> 00:12:43,564
by bedwetting, perhaps not eating.

112
00:12:43,651 --> 00:12:47,710
31 arrived, with two junior nurses,
I think.

113
00:12:47,795 --> 00:12:53,698
They were pretty dirty
and two of them got impetigo.

114
00:12:53,780 --> 00:12:56,147
I had young children at the time.

115
00:12:56,235 --> 00:12:58,374
And I put them into a large room.

116
00:12:58,460 --> 00:13:02,061
You've no idea... I had no idea
that such things existed in England.

117
00:13:02,143 --> 00:13:04,751
They relieved themselves
all over the carpet

118
00:13:04,829 --> 00:13:07,971
and the place was a shambles.

119
00:13:08,550 --> 00:13:11,998
(man shouts orders)

120
00:13:18,448 --> 00:13:21,820
(narrator) There was no heroic rush
to volunteer for the forces.

121
00:13:21,901 --> 00:13:23,811
You waited your turn to be called up

122
00:13:23,896 --> 00:13:26,962
for processing
in the military sausage machine.

123
00:13:27,042 --> 00:13:28,875
All rather leisurely.

124
00:13:31,185 --> 00:13:33,171
(church bells)

125
00:13:34,753 --> 00:13:36,586
But a rush to get married.

126
00:13:36,671 --> 00:13:40,469
In August and September, the highest
number of weddings ever recorded.

127
00:13:40,546 --> 00:13:42,728
White the only wear.

128
00:13:44,766 --> 00:13:51,248
White for the blackout too, to make sure
car drivers can see you in the dark.

129
00:13:51,787 --> 00:13:54,395
At first the blackout
was a bit of a joke.

130
00:13:58,923 --> 00:14:03,288
Then road casualties shot up
and the blackout wasn't funny any more.

131
00:14:03,373 --> 00:14:04,977
There were no air raids,

132
00:14:05,061 --> 00:14:09,808
but thousands of people were killed
or injured in accidents in the blackout.

133
00:14:13,425 --> 00:14:17,255
Depressing, too. Without it, you could
almost forget there was a war on.

134
00:14:17,338 --> 00:14:20,285
Every night, every home
had to be blacked out.

135
00:14:20,407 --> 00:14:22,863
The air-raid warden
looking for chinks of light

136
00:14:22,939 --> 00:14:25,503
became more hated than Hitler.

137
00:14:28,157 --> 00:14:30,765
The government closed cinemas
and entertainments

138
00:14:30,843 --> 00:14:32,217
at the beginning of the war.

139
00:14:32,300 --> 00:14:34,832
A fortnight later
they were allowed to open again.

140
00:14:34,909 --> 00:14:40,431
(band plays "We're Going to Hang Out
the Washing on the Siegfried Line")

141
00:15:05,179 --> 00:15:11,192
In spite of total war, there were nearly
a million and a half unemployed.

142
00:15:16,420 --> 00:15:19,104
Sir John Simon,
the chancellor of the exchequer,

143
00:15:19,182 --> 00:15:21,058
introduced an emergency budget.

144
00:15:21,139 --> 00:15:23,779
In three hours' time

145
00:15:23,863 --> 00:15:27,889
all budget secrets will be revealed.

146
00:15:28,467 --> 00:15:34,522
I am confident
that, whatever may be the burdens

147
00:15:34,605 --> 00:15:38,435
which have to be carried
by the British taxpayer,

148
00:15:38,518 --> 00:15:42,195
my fellow countrymen will bear them

149
00:15:42,316 --> 00:15:46,452
with the same resolution and courage

150
00:15:46,575 --> 00:15:49,641
as our fighting men will show

151
00:15:49,721 --> 00:15:56,387
when they discharge their grimmer task
on the field of battle.

152
00:15:56,473 --> 00:15:58,458
(cheering)

153
00:16:07,062 --> 00:16:10,128
The blackout budget.
Income tax up to 7s 6d.

154
00:16:10,207 --> 00:16:13,000
A 60% tax on excess profit.

155
00:16:13,085 --> 00:16:15,299
In retrospect, mild enough,

156
00:16:15,425 --> 00:16:17,880
but a Conservative MP, Chips Channon,

157
00:16:17,957 --> 00:16:21,253
thought it demolished
the edifice of capitalism.

158
00:16:22,829 --> 00:16:27,424
Another Tory, Leo Amery, wanted
a tougher war. Why not bomb Germany?

159
00:16:27,510 --> 00:16:29,998
The air minister Kingsley Wood said no.

160
00:16:30,080 --> 00:16:33,147
German munition works
were private property

161
00:16:33,226 --> 00:16:35,027
and the Germans would retaliate.

162
00:16:35,106 --> 00:16:37,136
The opening phase of the war

163
00:16:37,216 --> 00:16:40,937
was one of the most extraordinary
periods through which I've lived,

164
00:16:41,014 --> 00:16:43,545
because it was a period of euphoria

165
00:16:43,662 --> 00:16:45,953
on the part of the people
of this country.

166
00:16:46,040 --> 00:16:49,139
For a long time
there were quite a lot of unemployed,

167
00:16:49,263 --> 00:16:53,628
while the Germans
were manufacturing arms at full stretch,

168
00:16:53,713 --> 00:16:58,121
particularly in the Skoda works
in Czechoslovakia,

169
00:16:58,240 --> 00:17:00,804
which they had by that time occupied.

170
00:17:00,887 --> 00:17:04,139
Now, all this time the Germans
were a beehive of activity.

171
00:17:04,302 --> 00:17:06,669
We were doing absolutely nothing.

172
00:17:06,757 --> 00:17:10,631
We'd gone to war
for the defence of Poland.

173
00:17:10,709 --> 00:17:14,812
In the event, we did nothing
to help Poland at all.

174
00:17:14,890 --> 00:17:16,876
We never lifted a finger.

175
00:17:16,962 --> 00:17:19,297
For the first three months of the war,

176
00:17:19,379 --> 00:17:23,286
the greatest number of casualties
were in the blackout.

177
00:17:23,369 --> 00:17:29,545
We confined our war effort to dropping
leaflets on the German people

178
00:17:29,661 --> 00:17:32,301
telling them that it was a bad idea
to go to war

179
00:17:32,423 --> 00:17:34,834
and that it was a pity
that they'd done it

180
00:17:34,917 --> 00:17:36,673
and perhaps we might make peace.

181
00:17:38,600 --> 00:17:40,433
(narrator) The Phoney War.

182
00:17:40,518 --> 00:17:43,235
When a German plane
crashed in Scotland in November,

183
00:17:43,319 --> 00:17:46,538
people came from miles around to see it.

184
00:17:49,687 --> 00:17:53,823
And the Luftwaffe's dead were buried
with full military honours.

185
00:18:05,263 --> 00:18:09,170
Three British divisions went off
to France at the beginning of the war.

186
00:18:09,253 --> 00:18:14,272
More followed. "Nearly 200,000 men,"
said the war minister proudly.

187
00:18:14,356 --> 00:18:16,844
The French had mobilised
six million men.

188
00:18:16,926 --> 00:18:20,374
They grumbled that the British
weren't taking the war seriously.

189
00:18:20,456 --> 00:18:25,901
(Gracie Fields)
Wish me luck as you wave me goodbye

190
00:18:25,980 --> 00:18:31,655
(men join in)
Cheerio, here I go on my way

191
00:18:31,735 --> 00:18:36,525
Wish me luck as you wave me goodbye

192
00:18:36,608 --> 00:18:41,703
With a cheer, not a tear, make it gay

193
00:18:41,787 --> 00:18:46,773
Give me a smile
I can keep all the while

194
00:18:46,851 --> 00:18:52,023
In my heart while I'm away

195
00:18:52,107 --> 00:18:57,093
Till we meet once again, you and I

196
00:18:57,171 --> 00:19:03,576
Wish me luck as you wave me goodbye

197
00:19:08,987 --> 00:19:12,894
(narrator) In France,
training for a war that ended in 1918.

198
00:19:13,016 --> 00:19:16,267
The newsreel reporter tried hard
to make it sound impressive.

199
00:19:16,392 --> 00:19:19,763
(reporter) The force, instead of
being thrown into the line,

200
00:19:19,845 --> 00:19:23,642
is able to perfect its training
in conditions similar to those at home.

201
00:19:23,719 --> 00:19:28,160
This bayonet drill in gas masks is our
reply to transparent Nazi propaganda

202
00:19:28,247 --> 00:19:33,190
which seems to indicate that Germany
is preparing to employ poison gas.

203
00:19:33,272 --> 00:19:36,262
Infantry battalions exercise
with their weapons,

204
00:19:36,341 --> 00:19:39,408
awaiting the moment
for their use in actual warfare.

205
00:19:39,526 --> 00:19:41,511
The mortar platoon goes into action

206
00:19:41,636 --> 00:19:44,047
with a rapidity acquired
by constant practice.

207
00:19:44,130 --> 00:19:48,341
Steel helmets assume a fashionable
appearance with camouflage.

208
00:19:51,572 --> 00:19:53,907
(narrator)
French and British generals too

209
00:19:53,989 --> 00:19:56,445
prepared for their part
in the battle to come.

210
00:20:05,691 --> 00:20:08,528
The British dug in
on the Belgian frontier.

211
00:20:08,606 --> 00:20:11,367
In December it was decided
that when fighting began

212
00:20:11,445 --> 00:20:15,046
they'd leave their defences
and advance into Belgium.

213
00:20:15,128 --> 00:20:19,155
Anything helped
to keep their minds off the war.

214
00:20:19,924 --> 00:20:22,258
("Maginot Line" by George Formby)

215
00:20:22,341 --> 00:20:25,058
Now, imagine me in the Maginot line

216
00:20:25,142 --> 00:20:27,400
Sitting on a mine in the Maginot line

217
00:20:27,520 --> 00:20:29,887
Now it's turned out nice again

218
00:20:29,975 --> 00:20:32,431
The army life is fine

219
00:20:32,508 --> 00:20:34,766
French girls make a fuss of me

220
00:20:34,848 --> 00:20:36,724
I'm not French as you can see

221
00:20:36,804 --> 00:20:39,336
But I know what they mean
when they say oui, oui

222
00:20:39,413 --> 00:20:42,512
Down on the Maginot line

223
00:20:42,598 --> 00:20:45,390
Now, imagine me in the Maginot line

224
00:20:45,475 --> 00:20:47,657
Sitting on a mine in the Maginot line

225
00:20:47,738 --> 00:20:50,194
Now it's turned out nice again

226
00:20:50,270 --> 00:20:52,223
The army life is fine

227
00:20:52,304 --> 00:20:54,987
At night myself to sleep I sing

228
00:20:55,066 --> 00:20:57,205
To my old tin hat I cling

229
00:20:57,291 --> 00:20:59,550
I have to use it now for everything

230
00:20:59,670 --> 00:21:01,426
Down on the Maginot line

231
00:21:01,550 --> 00:21:03,535
(cheering)

232
00:21:10,834 --> 00:21:14,467
(narrator) "Winston's back,"
the navy was told on September 3.

233
00:21:14,555 --> 00:21:18,538
Chamberlain was reluctant to recall
his most bitter political opponent

234
00:21:18,622 --> 00:21:21,764
with a reputation
for military adventure.

235
00:21:24,031 --> 00:21:26,519
But Churchill was popular
with the public.

236
00:21:26,602 --> 00:21:29,166
He had warned them war was coming.

237
00:21:29,249 --> 00:21:32,162
Now, with surprising energy
for a 64-year-old,

238
00:21:32,242 --> 00:21:34,271
he proved a willing leader.

239
00:21:46,743 --> 00:21:49,842
The RAF dropped leaflets,
the army dug trenches,

240
00:21:49,966 --> 00:21:53,141
but Churchill's navy
was Britain's strongest arm.

241
00:21:55,260 --> 00:21:59,090
And the first lord of the admiralty
was often in the news.

242
00:21:59,174 --> 00:22:01,967
We are in a very different position

243
00:22:02,128 --> 00:22:06,842
from that we were in ten weeks ago.

244
00:22:06,923 --> 00:22:10,601
We are far stronger
than we were ten weeks ago.

245
00:22:10,683 --> 00:22:13,400
We are far better prepared

246
00:22:13,484 --> 00:22:18,121
to endure the worst malice
of Hitler and his Huns

247
00:22:18,203 --> 00:22:20,996
than we were at the beginning
of September.

248
00:22:21,080 --> 00:22:23,262
(narrator) The news
that a German battleship

249
00:22:23,343 --> 00:22:26,901
was sinking British merchantmen
gave the chance to take the offensive.

250
00:22:32,129 --> 00:22:36,460
Churchill concentrated much of
the navy's strength on finding her.

251
00:22:36,541 --> 00:22:40,098
One hunting group patrolled off
the River Plate in South America.

252
00:22:40,186 --> 00:22:43,666
Three cruisers -
Exeter, Ajax and Achilles.

253
00:22:43,754 --> 00:22:47,278
At dawn on December 13
they sighted a heavier German ship.

254
00:22:47,360 --> 00:22:50,688
It was the pocket battleship
Admiral Graf Spee.

255
00:22:50,774 --> 00:22:53,535
Although outgunned,
the cruisers engaged her.

256
00:22:53,652 --> 00:22:56,641
The Battle of the River Plate began.

257
00:23:00,135 --> 00:23:03,736
(man) Within about five minutes
of the alarm being sounded,

258
00:23:03,818 --> 00:23:07,419
Graf Spee and Exeter
were shooting at each other

259
00:23:07,540 --> 00:23:13,170
and the Ajax and Achilles
were both shooting at the Graf Spee,

260
00:23:13,294 --> 00:23:16,055
concentrating their gunfire.

261
00:23:16,671 --> 00:23:19,278
The Exeter was quite soon hit

262
00:23:19,356 --> 00:23:22,073
and received early damage.

263
00:23:22,195 --> 00:23:25,523
Her foremost guns
only fired a few rounds each

264
00:23:25,610 --> 00:23:27,562
before they were out of action.

265
00:23:27,643 --> 00:23:31,779
She continued as long as she
possibly could with her after turret,

266
00:23:31,901 --> 00:23:37,040
but the ship herself was badly damaged.
Her speed was reduced.

267
00:23:40,111 --> 00:23:45,938
The six-inch-gun cruisers before long
turned directly towards the Graf Spee

268
00:23:46,020 --> 00:23:48,202
so as to close the range still faster

269
00:23:48,283 --> 00:23:51,502
and the captain of the Graf Spee

270
00:23:51,621 --> 00:23:56,837
did not follow up the Exeter entirely,

271
00:23:56,915 --> 00:24:01,826
but indeed before very long
started heading towards Montevideo.

272
00:24:02,708 --> 00:24:08,076
But we could not see
any spectacular damage inflicted on him,

273
00:24:08,156 --> 00:24:11,681
and indeed his speed
seemed to be unimpaired

274
00:24:11,762 --> 00:24:17,743
and his heavy guns were still firing
regularly and with very good accuracy.

275
00:24:21,277 --> 00:24:23,644
(narrator) The Graf Spee took on fuel

276
00:24:23,732 --> 00:24:27,290
and put ashore the crews
of the merchant ships she'd sunk.

277
00:24:33,554 --> 00:24:38,114
Captain K Langsdorff asked the Uruguayans
for permission to stay

278
00:24:38,196 --> 00:24:41,644
but was told he must clear the port
in 72 hours.

279
00:24:46,176 --> 00:24:48,390
So he buried his dead.

280
00:24:48,478 --> 00:24:51,696
Believing that heavier British ships
were waiting for him,

281
00:24:51,777 --> 00:24:55,607
he prepared to carry out
his final orders from Berlin.

282
00:24:59,527 --> 00:25:02,778
(Woodhouse) As soon as he started
pulling his anchor up

283
00:25:02,903 --> 00:25:06,536
we got news of it from our people ashore

284
00:25:06,662 --> 00:25:10,841
and we sent off our aircraft.

285
00:25:10,921 --> 00:25:15,132
In due course we got the signal
from the aircraft,

286
00:25:15,218 --> 00:25:17,018
which was a very welcome one:

287
00:25:17,098 --> 00:25:19,280
"Graf Spee has blown herself up."

288
00:25:25,039 --> 00:25:29,327
(narrator) Two days later,
Langsdorff shot himself.

289
00:25:33,556 --> 00:25:37,812
Churchill made the most of a victory
won by bluff rather than gun power.

290
00:25:37,930 --> 00:25:40,538
Two of the cruisers were brought home.

291
00:25:40,615 --> 00:25:44,248
("A Life on the Ocean Wave"
by Henry Russell)

292
00:25:45,373 --> 00:25:48,624
Their crews marched
through the City of London to Guildhall

293
00:25:48,787 --> 00:25:52,158
and the first lord of the admiralty
basked in their glory.

294
00:25:52,240 --> 00:25:55,262
(Churchill) The brilliant sea fight

295
00:25:55,386 --> 00:25:59,215
which you executed,

296
00:25:59,337 --> 00:26:02,512
those who are here executed,

297
00:26:04,018 --> 00:26:08,154
takes its place in our naval annals

298
00:26:08,276 --> 00:26:13,983
and I may add
that in a dark, cold winter,

299
00:26:14,146 --> 00:26:18,020
it warmed the cockles
of the British heart.

300
00:26:18,098 --> 00:26:19,778
(cheering)

301
00:26:25,310 --> 00:26:27,492
(air-raid siren)

302
00:26:35,439 --> 00:26:39,650
(narrator) Helsinki, November 30, 1939.

303
00:26:39,735 --> 00:26:42,648
Finland has refused
to hand over bases and territory

304
00:26:42,728 --> 00:26:44,604
demanded by her neighbour Russia.

305
00:26:44,684 --> 00:26:47,402
The Russians attack.

306
00:27:12,691 --> 00:27:15,146
The massive Russian army
crossed the frontier,

307
00:27:15,223 --> 00:27:17,405
apparently set
for the kind of easy victory

308
00:27:17,525 --> 00:27:19,096
the Germans had had in Poland.

309
00:27:25,083 --> 00:27:28,607
But the Finns, few in number,
fought back.

310
00:27:36,324 --> 00:27:40,197
Camouflaged Finnish ski troops
knew how to use their own conditions,

311
00:27:40,313 --> 00:27:44,678
moving round the Russian flanks,
cutting their supply lines.

312
00:27:48,063 --> 00:27:50,125
The Russian advance ground to a halt,

313
00:27:50,212 --> 00:27:53,049
confirming the German belief
that the Russian army,

314
00:27:53,127 --> 00:27:57,383
purged by Stalin of many
of its regular officers, couldn't fight.

315
00:28:09,317 --> 00:28:11,652
Whole Russian divisions were destroyed.

316
00:28:11,734 --> 00:28:15,292
Those who weren't taken prisoner
died in the snow -

317
00:28:15,379 --> 00:28:19,438
for the Russians,
a humiliating, if temporary, failure.

318
00:28:56,007 --> 00:28:58,037
In Britain it was snowing, too.

319
00:28:58,156 --> 00:29:02,105
The censorship tried to hush it up
but people couldn't help noticing it.

320
00:29:02,184 --> 00:29:05,817
To the trials of the blackout were added
the worst winter for 45 years,

321
00:29:05,944 --> 00:29:10,232
a coal shortage, burst pipes
and food rationing.

322
00:29:11,583 --> 00:29:14,147
The RAF was grounded.

323
00:29:18,259 --> 00:29:21,401
Troops were called in
to keep the trains running.

324
00:29:28,771 --> 00:29:30,680
For the navy, another victory.

325
00:29:30,804 --> 00:29:33,368
Taking refuge in a Norwegian fjord,

326
00:29:33,451 --> 00:29:37,859
the Graf Spee's supply ship Altmark
was cornered by British destroyers.

327
00:29:37,940 --> 00:29:41,159
Ignoring Norwegian neutrality,
they boarded her

328
00:29:41,239 --> 00:29:45,069
and after a fight
released 300 British prisoners.

329
00:29:47,109 --> 00:29:50,437
For Hitler the seizure of the Altmark
was a setback.

330
00:29:50,524 --> 00:29:53,742
He hastened his plans to invade Norway.

331
00:30:00,614 --> 00:30:03,297
(cheering)

332
00:30:04,028 --> 00:30:07,094
For Churchill, another popular triumph.

333
00:30:07,174 --> 00:30:09,814
He too had his eyes on Norway.

334
00:30:19,489 --> 00:30:22,282
Churchill's colleagues
had discussed for months

335
00:30:22,366 --> 00:30:24,733
his plan for British action in Norway,

336
00:30:24,822 --> 00:30:27,582
but some, like the foreign secretary
Lord Halifax,

337
00:30:27,661 --> 00:30:29,494
were difficult to persuade.

338
00:30:33,684 --> 00:30:36,630
Churchill now added a plan
to help Finland

339
00:30:36,715 --> 00:30:39,355
as part of the Norwegian operation.

340
00:30:39,439 --> 00:30:43,192
He proposed to stop
Germany's important supply of iron ore,

341
00:30:43,275 --> 00:30:46,646
which came from Sweden
to the Norwegian port of Narvik.

342
00:30:46,728 --> 00:30:51,442
Then it was shipped to Germany
through neutral Norwegian waters.

343
00:30:54,171 --> 00:30:56,156
Churchill wanted to mine the waters

344
00:30:56,281 --> 00:30:59,303
and he added enticingly
that if Narvik were captured

345
00:30:59,388 --> 00:31:04,178
it could be used as a base for helping
Finland against Communist Russia.

346
00:31:06,754 --> 00:31:10,552
Churchill knew that his plan might mean
retaliation by Hitler in Norway,

347
00:31:10,629 --> 00:31:14,612
and helping Finland
could mean war with Russia.

348
00:31:17,075 --> 00:31:20,370
Chamberlain was concerned
about innocent Norwegian lives

349
00:31:20,451 --> 00:31:22,360
and the effect on American opinion.

350
00:31:22,446 --> 00:31:24,780
Eventually, he was persuaded.

351
00:31:24,863 --> 00:31:27,503
(man) I think that deep down
he still hoped

352
00:31:27,587 --> 00:31:31,460
that perhaps the major clash of armies
could be avoided.

353
00:31:31,538 --> 00:31:33,905
He thought that Germany

354
00:31:33,993 --> 00:31:36,328
was on the verge of starvation,

355
00:31:36,410 --> 00:31:38,440
or if not on the verge of starvation,

356
00:31:38,520 --> 00:31:42,503
it anyhow would be brought to the verge
of starvation by economic warfare.

357
00:31:42,587 --> 00:31:44,387
He thought also that deep down

358
00:31:44,467 --> 00:31:47,533
the German people didn't support Hitler,

359
00:31:47,613 --> 00:31:51,290
that this was a clique and that
if we did our propaganda properly

360
00:31:51,373 --> 00:31:54,515
there would perhaps be
a revolt of the generals

361
00:31:54,595 --> 00:31:56,657
or somebody else against Hitler

362
00:31:56,744 --> 00:32:02,298
and that therefore dropping propaganda
leaflets by bomber command of the RAF

363
00:32:02,383 --> 00:32:06,104
rather than bombs
was a good way of conducting the war.

364
00:32:06,182 --> 00:32:10,164
Anything to stop
the real major outbreak.

365
00:32:10,248 --> 00:32:15,846
And that is why I think to some extent
the campaigns in Norway

366
00:32:15,926 --> 00:32:19,145
were something acceptable
to Chamberlain,

367
00:32:19,264 --> 00:32:21,369
because it kept the war distant.

368
00:32:21,451 --> 00:32:26,514
It kept the idea of a real big clash,

369
00:32:26,592 --> 00:32:30,880
a repetition of Passchendaele
or the Somme, far away.

370
00:32:31,004 --> 00:32:35,718
It meant that war would be localised
and perhaps some miracle would happen.

371
00:32:35,799 --> 00:32:38,210
Perhaps Hitler would die
or be assassinated

372
00:32:38,293 --> 00:32:41,392
and the whole thing would end
with the minimum of bloodshed.

373
00:32:42,551 --> 00:32:44,537
Finland today

374
00:32:46,311 --> 00:32:51,134
amidst her snows and her frozen lakes

375
00:32:53,255 --> 00:32:59,082
is fighting against the forces
of unscrupulous violence

376
00:32:59,163 --> 00:33:01,694
just as we are ourselves.

377
00:33:01,772 --> 00:33:04,260
(applause)

378
00:33:05,110 --> 00:33:10,664
And her need calls
for our sympathy and our aid.

379
00:33:14,087 --> 00:33:16,073
(no sound)

380
00:33:18,614 --> 00:33:21,298
(narrator) British aid
did go to Finland, but late.

381
00:33:21,377 --> 00:33:24,246
The Russians
brought all their weight to bear

382
00:33:24,331 --> 00:33:26,436
and overwhelmed the Finnish defences.

383
00:33:32,195 --> 00:33:35,796
The day the British steeled themselves
to force a landing in Norway,

384
00:33:35,878 --> 00:33:37,831
Finland surrendered.

385
00:33:37,912 --> 00:33:43,160
So Britain was saved from war against
Russia and Germany at the same time.

386
00:33:44,549 --> 00:33:48,226
The armistice terms gave Russia
most of what she wanted.

387
00:33:52,874 --> 00:33:56,399
Hundreds of thousands of Finns
had to evacuate their homes.

388
00:34:05,343 --> 00:34:07,295
The French prime minister Daladier

389
00:34:07,376 --> 00:34:10,246
had staked everything
on helping Finland.

390
00:34:10,330 --> 00:34:12,861
He was replaced by Paul Reynaud.

391
00:34:14,013 --> 00:34:16,773
Reynaud went on pressing
for Churchill's operation

392
00:34:16,852 --> 00:34:18,957
to cut off the German iron ore.

393
00:34:19,039 --> 00:34:23,404
An Allied meeting in London
decided to mine Norwegian waters.

394
00:34:23,489 --> 00:34:25,365
Churchill had got his way.

395
00:34:29,474 --> 00:34:33,031
British and French troops
stood ready to invade Norway.

396
00:34:35,766 --> 00:34:39,094
The mines were laid on April 8.

397
00:34:49,692 --> 00:34:52,453
A few days earlier,
no thought of Norway in his mind,

398
00:34:52,531 --> 00:34:56,863
Chamberlain had proclaimed
that Hitler had missed the bus.

399
00:34:56,943 --> 00:35:01,887
And General Ironside
dared the Germans to do their worst.

400
00:35:06,112 --> 00:35:09,942
Hitler's invasion force
sailed on April 6.

401
00:35:47,124 --> 00:35:50,191
The Luftwaffe took over
most of the Norwegian airfields.

402
00:35:50,270 --> 00:35:52,300
(marching band)

403
00:35:59,670 --> 00:36:03,270
The German march into Oslo
was led by a band.

404
00:36:11,179 --> 00:36:15,206
Norway had no standing army,
only half-trained militia.

405
00:36:15,284 --> 00:36:18,536
The Norwegians
were antimilitarist by tradition

406
00:36:18,622 --> 00:36:22,987
and they had seen German newsreels
of the blitzkrieg on Poland.

407
00:36:23,072 --> 00:36:26,139
No one wanted Oslo
to go the way of Warsaw.

408
00:36:26,218 --> 00:36:28,018
There was little resistance.

409
00:36:42,753 --> 00:36:46,049
The Allied operation in Norway
was a muddle from the start.

410
00:36:46,129 --> 00:36:52,142
Troops were embarked, disembarked,
embarked again, without vital equipment.

411
00:36:55,107 --> 00:36:59,624
A contingent of French troops sailed
with the British, plentifully equipped.

412
00:37:10,453 --> 00:37:13,933
Unlike the British,
they were trained for winter conditions,

413
00:37:14,021 --> 00:37:17,087
but they hadn't got straps
for their skis.

414
00:37:25,492 --> 00:37:28,361
Even the expedition's objectives
were confused.

415
00:37:28,484 --> 00:37:32,009
Trondheim in central Norway
was to be captured by a pincer attack

416
00:37:32,090 --> 00:37:34,272
from Andalsnes and Namsos.

417
00:37:34,354 --> 00:37:36,569
So some troops were diverted south.

418
00:37:36,694 --> 00:37:39,913
But Churchill's mind
was still fixed on Narvik,

419
00:37:39,994 --> 00:37:42,449
and it was there
the first battle took place.

420
00:38:11,376 --> 00:38:13,024
The navy bombarded Narvik

421
00:38:13,102 --> 00:38:16,092
and German destroyers already there
took a battering.

422
00:38:16,172 --> 00:38:17,895
But the advantage was lost.

423
00:38:17,975 --> 00:38:21,924
The British army commander didn't make
a direct assault on the town.

424
00:38:27,144 --> 00:38:31,432
British Territorials did land
at Namsos and Andalsnes.

425
00:38:31,518 --> 00:38:34,998
They had no skis,
no proper maps of Norway,

426
00:38:35,085 --> 00:38:37,955
and no heavy guns.

427
00:38:40,073 --> 00:38:45,365
There was little they could do when
they ran into the well-equipped Germans.

428
00:38:49,971 --> 00:38:53,375
Captain Martin Lindsay
was with the British force at Namsos.

429
00:38:53,462 --> 00:38:56,834
(Lindsay) There was no hope at all
for this operation

430
00:38:56,915 --> 00:39:01,782
because it was entirely improvised
at short notice and in a great hurry

431
00:39:01,864 --> 00:39:06,775
and the force had no aircraft
supporting it and no artillery.

432
00:39:06,890 --> 00:39:10,764
But even more important,
all the ground was covered with snow

433
00:39:10,841 --> 00:39:13,908
and the only way to operate
was with ski troops,

434
00:39:13,987 --> 00:39:16,246
and we hadn't got ski troops.

435
00:39:16,328 --> 00:39:19,240
Therefore the troops
were confined to the road.

436
00:39:19,358 --> 00:39:24,684
Whenever the Germans got onto the hills
on the flank they had to retire.

437
00:39:28,873 --> 00:39:32,747
(narrator) The British
couldn't stop the Luftwaffe

438
00:39:32,825 --> 00:39:35,999
from blitzing
the little Norwegian towns.

439
00:39:36,086 --> 00:39:40,221
German control of the Norwegian
airfields was the key to the battle.

440
00:39:56,304 --> 00:40:00,515
The Germans advanced,
capturing hundreds of British prisoners.

441
00:40:04,207 --> 00:40:08,037
Some of these were flown to Berlin
and paraded before Hitler.

442
00:40:11,189 --> 00:40:13,950
Others were put in front
of German newsreel cameras.

443
00:40:14,067 --> 00:40:19,664
You seem to be in a good mood. You don't
find Germans as bad as you expected?

444
00:40:19,745 --> 00:40:21,807
- Oh, no, certainly not.
- Oh, no.

445
00:40:21,893 --> 00:40:24,577
I was captured at Fåberg by the Germans.

446
00:40:24,655 --> 00:40:27,492
From there I came to Lillehammer

447
00:40:27,609 --> 00:40:30,250
and we had a supper.

448
00:40:30,333 --> 00:40:34,698
It consisted of brown bread, Gorgonzola,

449
00:40:34,784 --> 00:40:38,341
wine which the Germans gave to us,
cigarettes.

450
00:40:38,467 --> 00:40:42,449
And a hot meal each day.

451
00:40:42,533 --> 00:40:45,097
And I'm getting on fairly decent.

452
00:40:45,219 --> 00:40:48,394
I hope the war will soon be over
and we'll all go back home.

453
00:40:50,897 --> 00:40:53,264
(narrator)
Most did go home ingloriously,

454
00:40:53,352 --> 00:40:57,149
abandoning Andalsnes and Namsos
still burning.

455
00:41:08,008 --> 00:41:12,416
Chased by the Luftwaffe - the Norwegian
campaign rammed home the lesson

456
00:41:12,496 --> 00:41:17,483
that sea power without air power
could no longer win battles.

457
00:41:43,687 --> 00:41:47,440
Their only honour the part they played
in bringing down a government,

458
00:41:47,523 --> 00:41:51,156
for now the machinery of democracy
began to work.

459
00:41:54,160 --> 00:41:56,113
As the troops disembarked,

460
00:41:56,194 --> 00:42:00,100
an angry parliament was assembling
to debate the disaster.

461
00:42:00,184 --> 00:42:02,792
Feeling cut across party lines.

462
00:42:02,869 --> 00:42:06,666
Captain Lindsay, a Tory, went to
the leader of the Labour opposition.

463
00:42:06,744 --> 00:42:12,069
(Lindsay) Well, I was the first person
from this force to reach London.

464
00:42:12,192 --> 00:42:16,066
I went to see Mr Attlee on the morning
of the first day of the debate

465
00:42:16,143 --> 00:42:18,129
and I gave him a memorandum

466
00:42:18,215 --> 00:42:22,165
about the appalling improvisation
and deficiencies in Norway,

467
00:42:22,243 --> 00:42:26,575
because I was convinced that we should
lose the war if we went on like that,

468
00:42:26,655 --> 00:42:29,373
which he gave to Herbert Morrison

469
00:42:29,456 --> 00:42:32,249
to help him open for the opposition
that afternoon.

470
00:42:32,333 --> 00:42:36,742
The Norway debate was the only
decisive debate I ever attended

471
00:42:36,822 --> 00:42:40,499
during my 34 years as a member
of the House of Commons

472
00:42:40,620 --> 00:42:42,682
because it was the only division

473
00:42:42,769 --> 00:42:45,835
which definitely brought about
the fall of a government.

474
00:42:45,915 --> 00:42:47,944
For nearly a year before that debate

475
00:42:48,025 --> 00:42:51,396
there had been a piling-up
of bitterness and anguish

476
00:42:51,477 --> 00:42:53,158
in the breasts of people

477
00:42:53,242 --> 00:42:57,650
who wanted Britain to go all out
and win the war against Hitler.

478
00:42:57,731 --> 00:43:02,401
And so you can imagine
that the debate was a very fierce one -

479
00:43:02,488 --> 00:43:08,086
not only the Labour opposition
but also Conservatives.

480
00:43:08,166 --> 00:43:13,229
They felt that the whole conduct
of the war could not be carried on

481
00:43:13,307 --> 00:43:18,599
under a man whom they had already
assailed at the time of Munich

482
00:43:18,678 --> 00:43:22,431
and whom they realised
was not really by nature a war leader.

483
00:43:22,553 --> 00:43:25,270
Gradually, the temperature
began to rise,

484
00:43:25,392 --> 00:43:28,032
and when Herbert Morrison
for the Labour Party

485
00:43:28,154 --> 00:43:31,831
announced that they were going to divide
at the end of the debate

486
00:43:31,952 --> 00:43:34,134
against the government...

487
00:43:34,254 --> 00:43:36,589
There was an action group

488
00:43:36,671 --> 00:43:42,039
of which Clement Davies was chairman,
the Liberal leader, and I was secretary.

489
00:43:42,119 --> 00:43:45,447
It was an all-party committee,

490
00:43:45,533 --> 00:43:49,712
committed to pressing for
more decisive action during the war

491
00:43:49,792 --> 00:43:52,007
and a more vigorous posture

492
00:43:52,094 --> 00:43:54,385
and more vigorous prosecution
of the war.

493
00:43:54,472 --> 00:43:58,346
And we decided to hold a meeting
after Morrison's announcement

494
00:43:58,424 --> 00:44:01,370
and we asked Leo Amery
to preside over it.

495
00:44:01,455 --> 00:44:03,866
It was an enormously attended meeting.

496
00:44:03,949 --> 00:44:06,742
Many Conservative
members of parliament were there

497
00:44:06,826 --> 00:44:09,160
and I felt something was happening.

498
00:44:09,281 --> 00:44:11,769
There were a great many
members of parliament

499
00:44:11,852 --> 00:44:15,376
who had never been hitherto
members of our action group

500
00:44:15,458 --> 00:44:17,138
who fetched up at the meeting.

501
00:44:17,223 --> 00:44:19,482
The feeling at the meeting
was passionate.

502
00:44:19,563 --> 00:44:23,971
And I felt, at that time,
that a great many Conservative members

503
00:44:24,052 --> 00:44:26,735
were not only prepared
to abstain in the division

504
00:44:26,814 --> 00:44:29,029
but even to vote against the government.

505
00:44:29,116 --> 00:44:33,863
And I came down from that meeting
with feelings of great tension.

506
00:44:33,950 --> 00:44:40,617
Meanwhile, Churchill had been putting up
a great defence of the government,

507
00:44:40,740 --> 00:44:45,607
and it was ironical again there
because the debate was about Norway

508
00:44:45,689 --> 00:44:48,712
and Norway had been
a series of disasters for which,

509
00:44:48,797 --> 00:44:53,816
although he might not be blamed
because they may have been unavoidable,

510
00:44:53,900 --> 00:44:57,271
he was directly responsible
as first lord of the admiralty.

511
00:44:57,391 --> 00:45:01,526
And Amery made
a most formidable speech

512
00:45:01,611 --> 00:45:04,142
in which he quoted Cromwell's words:

513
00:45:04,220 --> 00:45:07,438
"You have been here long enough
for any good you have done."

514
00:45:07,519 --> 00:45:09,701
"In the name of God, go."

515
00:45:09,783 --> 00:45:11,768
And then Lloyd George came down

516
00:45:11,893 --> 00:45:15,417
and made the most devastating speech
I've ever heard even him make

517
00:45:15,499 --> 00:45:18,216
in which he concluded
by saying to Chamberlain:

518
00:45:18,300 --> 00:45:20,482
"You have asked the nation
for sacrifices

519
00:45:20,640 --> 00:45:24,044
but there is one sacrifice
that is more necessary than any other,

520
00:45:24,131 --> 00:45:26,586
and that is
the sacrifice of your own office."

521
00:45:26,663 --> 00:45:29,030
When the result was announced

522
00:45:29,118 --> 00:45:32,948
and the Conservative majority
fell to about 80,

523
00:45:33,032 --> 00:45:36,327
and that meant the fall
of the government in the circumstances,

524
00:45:36,408 --> 00:45:40,085
I could see Chamberlain,
I can see him now, blanch.

525
00:45:40,244 --> 00:45:45,340
He had asked for friendship

526
00:45:45,423 --> 00:45:47,486
from those who were his friends

527
00:45:47,572 --> 00:45:52,132
and he hadn't got it, and he walked
out of the chamber a solitary figure.

528
00:45:52,214 --> 00:45:54,669
And I felt very sorry for him
at that moment

529
00:45:54,746 --> 00:45:57,157
because I knew that he knew
that he was done.

530
00:45:57,240 --> 00:46:00,382
And I remember Chamberlain
going to his room afterwards

531
00:46:00,462 --> 00:46:03,255
and saying he wondered
whether this could go on.

532
00:46:03,340 --> 00:46:08,817
But it wasn't till the next day that he
really realised that his number was up.

533
00:46:08,903 --> 00:46:12,383
On that particular day the whips,
I think, tried to explain to him

534
00:46:12,471 --> 00:46:15,231
that it might have been worse
and that sort of thing,

535
00:46:15,348 --> 00:46:17,028
but those of us who were with him

536
00:46:17,113 --> 00:46:19,677
could see the writing on the wall
by that time.

537
00:46:19,760 --> 00:46:23,360
During those two days, 9 and 10 May,

538
00:46:23,443 --> 00:46:27,349
there was great doubt
as to who would succeed Chamberlain.

539
00:46:27,433 --> 00:46:31,383
The Labour Party made it clear that if
there was to be a coalition government,

540
00:46:31,461 --> 00:46:34,025
which by now
everybody thought necessary,

541
00:46:34,108 --> 00:46:36,170
they would not serve under Chamberlain.

542
00:46:36,257 --> 00:46:40,283
The choice, therefore,
was between Churchill and Halifax.

543
00:46:41,168 --> 00:46:43,808
(narrator) Lord Halifax
was the obvious successor,

544
00:46:43,930 --> 00:46:46,843
Chamberlain's trusted colleague.

545
00:46:46,922 --> 00:46:52,902
But no peer had been prime minister
for nearly 40 years. As for his rival...

546
00:46:52,984 --> 00:46:56,006
(Colville) Churchill was viewed
with grave misgiving

547
00:46:56,130 --> 00:46:59,578
by the establishment,
as it would now be called.

548
00:46:59,659 --> 00:47:03,795
Everybody at 10 Downing Street
and Whitehall generally,

549
00:47:03,879 --> 00:47:08,320
the cabinet offices, and in very large
sectors of the Conservative Party,

550
00:47:08,407 --> 00:47:10,316
were frightened of Churchill.

551
00:47:10,401 --> 00:47:13,882
They thought he was an adventurer.
They remembered Gallipoli.

552
00:47:13,969 --> 00:47:17,876
They thought that they did not want
to see the fortunes of this country

553
00:47:17,959 --> 00:47:21,211
at a most critical moment
in its whole history

554
00:47:21,297 --> 00:47:26,393
handed over to somebody who might do
the most extraordinary things

555
00:47:26,476 --> 00:47:29,313
and undertake
the most astonishing adventures.

556
00:47:29,392 --> 00:47:32,033
And they all, after all,
realised that Norway,

557
00:47:32,116 --> 00:47:35,487
this fiasco from which
we were just hoping to recover

558
00:47:35,569 --> 00:47:37,903
or had just been saved
in the nick of time,

559
00:47:37,986 --> 00:47:40,441
was largely the inspiration
of Churchill.

560
00:47:40,518 --> 00:47:44,926
It was a very fine idea
but it didn't work, just like Gallipoli.

561
00:47:45,007 --> 00:47:52,634
And therefore it was with
a certain amount of fear of Churchill

562
00:47:52,718 --> 00:47:55,282
that I think the minds of most people

563
00:47:55,365 --> 00:47:58,736
in the centre of government
and in the centre of Whitehall

564
00:47:58,895 --> 00:48:01,306
turned towards Halifax.

565
00:48:01,388 --> 00:48:05,796
Halifax was safe. He was clever.
He was a fellow of All Souls.

566
00:48:05,877 --> 00:48:12,162
He was a man of indisputable charm
and absolute integrity.

567
00:48:12,246 --> 00:48:16,686
And it was hoped that he would perhaps
be sent for by the king.

568
00:48:16,773 --> 00:48:19,031
The Labour Party approached me -

569
00:48:19,113 --> 00:48:22,517
Hugh Dalton and Herbert Morrison -

570
00:48:22,604 --> 00:48:26,324
and they both talked
in favour of Halifax

571
00:48:26,402 --> 00:48:29,883
and they thought
that Halifax ought to take over.

572
00:48:29,970 --> 00:48:33,189
I think their idea always was

573
00:48:33,269 --> 00:48:36,565
that Churchill would run the war
under Halifax,

574
00:48:36,646 --> 00:48:39,209
an idea which didn't appeal to Halifax.

575
00:48:39,293 --> 00:48:41,704
I remember Churchill telling me

576
00:48:41,825 --> 00:48:44,924
that the critical moment came

577
00:48:45,009 --> 00:48:51,217
when Chamberlain asked Halifax and him
to join him in the cabinet room.

578
00:48:51,339 --> 00:48:55,747
And the three of them were there.

579
00:48:55,828 --> 00:49:00,924
Halifax was sitting beside Chamberlain,

580
00:49:01,007 --> 00:49:03,418
who suddenly turned to Churchill
and said:

581
00:49:03,539 --> 00:49:08,209
"Tell me, Winston, do you see any reason
why in the 20th century

582
00:49:08,297 --> 00:49:12,050
a prime minister should not be
in the House of Lords?"

583
00:49:12,171 --> 00:49:17,540
And Churchill thought
that this was a trap.

584
00:49:17,619 --> 00:49:21,493
If he said,
"No, I see no reason at all,"

585
00:49:21,571 --> 00:49:24,102
he thought Chamberlain
would turn to Halifax

586
00:49:24,180 --> 00:49:27,475
and say, "In that case,
if the king were to ask my advice

587
00:49:27,556 --> 00:49:29,770
I could perhaps suggest you."

588
00:49:29,858 --> 00:49:33,261
On the other hand, it would be difficult
for him to say, "Yes, I do,"

589
00:49:33,349 --> 00:49:36,568
because then there could be
no alternative but himself.

590
00:49:36,648 --> 00:49:40,401
So he turned round and stood staring
over the Horse Guards Parade

591
00:49:40,485 --> 00:49:42,317
and did not reply to the question.

592
00:49:42,441 --> 00:49:45,463
The decision, I think,
was largely taken by Halifax

593
00:49:45,549 --> 00:49:51,452
who told me he had a pain in his stomach
an hour or two before the meeting

594
00:49:51,534 --> 00:49:54,371
and did not really want
to be prime minister,

595
00:49:54,449 --> 00:49:57,057
whereas the man who did want
to be prime minister -

596
00:49:57,135 --> 00:49:59,426
he was quite determined - was Churchill.

597
00:50:00,626 --> 00:50:04,991
(narrator) At dawn the Germans swept
into Holland, Belgium and Luxembourg.

598
00:50:05,076 --> 00:50:09,441
The war was at last
coming very close home to Britain.

599
00:50:12,903 --> 00:50:16,852
As the Allied armies braced themselves
for battle, Chamberlain resigned

600
00:50:16,931 --> 00:50:21,110
and advised the king
to send for Churchill.

601
00:50:21,228 --> 00:50:23,290
(Colville) Churchill would be a gamble,

602
00:50:23,415 --> 00:50:28,325
and perhaps when you're
at a very serious moment of your lives,

603
00:50:28,402 --> 00:50:30,617
a gamble is not the thing to undertake,

604
00:50:30,704 --> 00:50:33,726
and so it was with great despair

605
00:50:33,812 --> 00:50:38,143
that we all heard
on the evening of 10 May

606
00:50:38,224 --> 00:50:41,290
that the king had sent for Churchill.
