1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:32,610 --> 00:00:35,294
(narrator) Every day now,
for more than 30 years,

3
00:00:35,372 --> 00:00:38,165
this couple have carried out
this quaint ceremony

4
00:00:38,250 --> 00:00:43,313
meant, before their god,
to expiate the guilt of seven souls.

5
00:00:46,652 --> 00:00:49,564
(chanting)

6
00:00:55,898 --> 00:00:57,774
This is Japan

7
00:00:57,854 --> 00:01:01,575
and the seven souls belong to
the seven Japanese war criminals

8
00:01:01,652 --> 00:01:05,133
hanged by the Allies after 1945.

9
00:02:08,944 --> 00:02:11,203
Japan suffered more than most countries

10
00:02:11,284 --> 00:02:14,274
from the Great Depression
after the First World War.

11
00:02:14,354 --> 00:02:16,186
The population was increasing fast

12
00:02:16,310 --> 00:02:22,061
and every year produced
another million mouths to feed.

13
00:02:24,674 --> 00:02:29,039
Japan had no mineral resources
of her own, unemployment was high,

14
00:02:29,162 --> 00:02:33,221
and crop failures brought
disastrous famines in rural areas.

15
00:02:33,306 --> 00:02:37,746
(man) Public life was very hard
in those days

16
00:02:37,910 --> 00:02:40,473
and most of the young military officers

17
00:02:40,557 --> 00:02:45,042
came from low-class
agricultural families.

18
00:02:45,122 --> 00:02:49,334
And our culture was in
a very, very hard position.

19
00:02:49,419 --> 00:02:52,409
(man speaking Japanese)

20
00:02:54,943 --> 00:02:57,584
(translator)
1930 was the time when Japan

21
00:02:57,667 --> 00:03:02,883
entered what might be called
her convulsive period of history.

22
00:03:04,765 --> 00:03:09,282
The influence
of the ultra-nationalists grew

23
00:03:09,369 --> 00:03:13,504
and such incidents as
the young officers' revolt of May 15

24
00:03:13,589 --> 00:03:18,411
placed Japan step by step
under the power of the military.

25
00:03:18,499 --> 00:03:21,795
The politicians took second place
to the army.

26
00:03:24,369 --> 00:03:28,166
(man) The Japanese army
had been in disrepute

27
00:03:28,244 --> 00:03:31,343
till about the beginning of the 1930s,

28
00:03:31,428 --> 00:03:38,019
and then they came back through
the so-called patriotic societies -

29
00:03:40,713 --> 00:03:43,124
many of them no more than gangsters

30
00:03:43,206 --> 00:03:47,691
who could commit any misdeed
in the name of patriotism.

31
00:03:47,772 --> 00:03:50,336
(yelling)

32
00:04:01,852 --> 00:04:04,689
Those were the years
certain authors have described

33
00:04:04,806 --> 00:04:09,017
as the period of
government by assassination.

34
00:04:09,103 --> 00:04:11,165
And there were several assassinations

35
00:04:11,251 --> 00:04:14,470
of prime ministers and leaders
in those days

36
00:04:14,589 --> 00:04:17,688
just because they had liberal views

37
00:04:17,773 --> 00:04:21,144
or because they favoured

38
00:04:21,226 --> 00:04:24,368
better relations
with the United States, Britain,

39
00:04:24,449 --> 00:04:28,355
or more other democratic-minded nations.

40
00:04:31,469 --> 00:04:34,416
(narrator) The army also controlled
the education system.

41
00:04:34,500 --> 00:04:36,104
A respect for the martial arts

42
00:04:36,188 --> 00:04:41,513
was inculcated into every Japanese child
from an early age.

43
00:04:47,199 --> 00:04:51,378
To the Japanese,
their emperor was a god.

44
00:04:51,457 --> 00:04:55,058
But Hirohito chose to reign,
not to rule.

45
00:04:55,140 --> 00:04:57,933
He allowed himself
to be manipulated by the military,

46
00:04:58,018 --> 00:05:01,892
and since every Japanese was pledged
to serve the emperor unto death,

47
00:05:01,969 --> 00:05:06,410
his connivance was
a considerable asset to the army.

48
00:05:07,724 --> 00:05:09,786
To solve Japan's economic problems,

49
00:05:09,872 --> 00:05:13,506
the army favoured expansion
on the Asian mainland.

50
00:05:13,594 --> 00:05:18,111
Korea had long been Japan's, and since
her victory over Tsarist Russia in 1905,

51
00:05:18,198 --> 00:05:22,377
Japan had also been allowed
to station troops in Manchuria.

52
00:05:22,456 --> 00:05:24,747
Manchuria was mostly empty wilderness,

53
00:05:24,835 --> 00:05:27,824
but it contained raw materials
that Japan lacked,

54
00:05:27,904 --> 00:05:30,238
such as coal and iron ore.

55
00:05:43,212 --> 00:05:46,889
Impatient that the politicians back
in Tokyo did not see the obvious need

56
00:05:46,971 --> 00:05:49,033
to seize Manchuria once and for all,

57
00:05:49,158 --> 00:05:53,599
a group of extremists in 1931
infiltrated the Japanese garrisons there

58
00:05:53,685 --> 00:05:57,133
and persuaded them
to take on Manchuria's feeble army.

59
00:06:09,453 --> 00:06:11,515
(yelling)

60
00:06:29,671 --> 00:06:31,427
Against little real opposition,

61
00:06:31,513 --> 00:06:34,382
the Japanese army soon controlled
the whole country,

62
00:06:34,467 --> 00:06:38,449
driving the luckless Manchurians
before them.

63
00:06:43,943 --> 00:06:46,583
The world was shocked,
but did nothing...

64
00:06:46,667 --> 00:06:48,652
(all yell)

65
00:06:50,964 --> 00:06:54,521
apart from a rebuke
at the League of Nations.

66
00:06:54,608 --> 00:06:57,140
Japan, however,

67
00:06:57,217 --> 00:07:00,894
finds it impossible to accept

68
00:07:00,977 --> 00:07:04,654
the report adopted by the assembly.

69
00:07:05,044 --> 00:07:07,532
(reporter)
And so Japan leaves the League.

70
00:07:07,652 --> 00:07:12,748
The Far Eastern war cloud
casts its shadow over the whole world.

71
00:07:18,932 --> 00:07:21,801
(narrator) As they had occupied
Manchuria with such ease

72
00:07:21,886 --> 00:07:24,526
and without interference
from the rest of the world,

73
00:07:24,610 --> 00:07:27,479
the Japanese generals there
soon turned their attention

74
00:07:27,602 --> 00:07:30,286
to Manchuria's next-door neighbour,
China.

75
00:07:30,364 --> 00:07:33,539
The China of 500 million souls.

76
00:07:33,625 --> 00:07:39,758
The China that for centuries had thought
itself secure behind its Great Wall.

77
00:07:39,840 --> 00:07:42,753
In July, 1937,
an incident was manufactured

78
00:07:42,833 --> 00:07:46,783
whereby the Chinese appeared
to fire on the Japanese.

79
00:07:46,861 --> 00:07:50,844
Without waiting to investigate,
Japan invaded China.

80
00:08:10,609 --> 00:08:15,977
Disunited and ill-equipped, the Chinese
were no match for the ruthless Japanese.

81
00:08:31,825 --> 00:08:35,699
Within a matter of weeks, the Japanese
had overrun most of northern China

82
00:08:35,776 --> 00:08:37,533
and were bombing Peking.

83
00:08:40,227 --> 00:08:42,835
(air-raid siren)

84
00:09:01,174 --> 00:09:05,048
Peking soon fell,
and it was then Shanghai's turn.

85
00:09:55,997 --> 00:10:00,405
Once Shanghai had fallen, the Japanese
forces advanced up the Yangtze valley

86
00:10:00,486 --> 00:10:05,046
to threaten
the then-capital of China, Nanking.

87
00:11:13,609 --> 00:11:15,595
(all yell)

88
00:11:25,042 --> 00:11:28,992
It was here at Nanking
in December, 1937,

89
00:11:29,070 --> 00:11:32,060
that the Japanese perpetrated
what was, until then,

90
00:11:32,139 --> 00:11:34,780
one of the worst atrocities
of this century,

91
00:11:34,863 --> 00:11:39,807
when their troops massacred
more than 200,000 Chinese in cold blood.

92
00:11:46,987 --> 00:11:53,501
Even the Nazis were shocked, and offered
to mediate to prevent further bloodshed.

93
00:11:53,585 --> 00:11:55,997
But the Japanese generals
were unyielding

94
00:11:56,117 --> 00:11:58,179
as their military successes mounted.

95
00:11:58,266 --> 00:12:02,521
By the summer of 1938, the Japanese had
captured a considerable part of China,

96
00:12:02,678 --> 00:12:04,817
including most of the major cities,

97
00:12:04,903 --> 00:12:07,620
but they were only conquering territory,
not people,

98
00:12:07,704 --> 00:12:11,152
as the Chinese retreated
into their vast hinterland.

99
00:12:11,233 --> 00:12:14,681
Worse for the Japanese,
their conquests incurred the suspicion

100
00:12:14,763 --> 00:12:17,785
of their old enemy to the north, Russia.

101
00:12:24,814 --> 00:12:29,452
In the summer of 1938, Russian and
Japanese troops battled for possession

102
00:12:29,533 --> 00:12:33,745
of a barren hill
on the Soviet-Manchurian border.

103
00:12:42,309 --> 00:12:44,447
The Japanese received such a drubbing

104
00:12:44,572 --> 00:12:48,980
that they opted for a settlement
after only two weeks.

105
00:13:09,739 --> 00:13:12,031
Ten months later,
another squabble broke out

106
00:13:12,118 --> 00:13:14,148
and once again the Japanese were beaten,

107
00:13:14,228 --> 00:13:17,829
this time by none other
than General Zhukov.

108
00:13:26,351 --> 00:13:30,225
It made them wary of further conflicts
with the Soviet Union.

109
00:13:30,303 --> 00:13:31,568
(all yelling)

110
00:13:35,099 --> 00:13:38,547
But it also pushed them
closer to Germany and Italy.

111
00:13:38,628 --> 00:13:40,538
- Banzai!
- (all yell)

112
00:13:50,176 --> 00:13:54,279
Living in Japan became difficult
for other Westerners.

113
00:13:54,358 --> 00:13:58,232
You were constantly under
the supervision of police.

114
00:13:58,309 --> 00:14:02,641
You were always, as a European,
suspected of being a spy.

115
00:14:02,721 --> 00:14:05,634
In the railway stations,
you'd often see posters

116
00:14:05,714 --> 00:14:09,271
of a man with a Sherlock Holmes cap
and a curly pipe,

117
00:14:09,397 --> 00:14:12,080
which said, "Beware of spies".

118
00:14:12,159 --> 00:14:17,561
You had the intensified activities
of the thought police and the Kempeitai,

119
00:14:17,645 --> 00:14:21,704
who controlled speech and thought.

120
00:14:21,789 --> 00:14:25,815
Then you had the introduction of
a national uniform called Kokomin-fuku.

121
00:14:25,894 --> 00:14:30,488
After leaving school, people were
supposed to wear these to go to work.

122
00:14:30,574 --> 00:14:31,643
And they were khaki

123
00:14:31,725 --> 00:14:36,515
and they were similar
to the uniforms worn by the servicemen.

124
00:14:36,597 --> 00:14:39,467
And then the cinema and plays,

125
00:14:39,551 --> 00:14:45,029
the complexion of these became more
martial and more a glorification of war,

126
00:14:45,114 --> 00:14:50,210
and the radio would play more
and more music of a military nature.

127
00:14:53,900 --> 00:14:59,913
Then on the political field you had the
Taisai Yukusankai, the one-party system

128
00:15:00,000 --> 00:15:01,723
that made it easy for the military

129
00:15:01,803 --> 00:15:07,019
to consolidate
their influence over the country.

130
00:15:09,131 --> 00:15:11,771
(nationalistic song)

131
00:15:23,249 --> 00:15:25,234
(applause)

132
00:15:28,505 --> 00:15:31,145
There was constantly
the sight and sounds

133
00:15:31,229 --> 00:15:34,022
of soldiers being sent off ceremoniously

134
00:15:34,106 --> 00:15:36,594
to the front in China.

135
00:15:36,677 --> 00:15:38,477
(Bush) They were always taught that

136
00:15:38,556 --> 00:15:41,274
the greatest thing
that could happen to any family

137
00:15:41,357 --> 00:15:45,187
was to be able to give a son or two sons
or three sons or seven sons

138
00:15:45,270 --> 00:15:46,841
to the service of their country

139
00:15:46,958 --> 00:15:50,559
and to die for the emperor
and the imperial family.

140
00:15:51,447 --> 00:15:56,849
(Mutsu) You had the so-called
ash boxes, remains of soldiers,

141
00:15:56,933 --> 00:16:00,458
coming back to Japan,
so we knew we were at war.

142
00:16:07,560 --> 00:16:10,779
(narrator) Western influences
had grown in Japan in the '30s,

143
00:16:10,898 --> 00:16:13,888
which the military disliked
and now discouraged.

144
00:16:13,967 --> 00:16:19,030
(Bush) I remember my former wife -
it must have been about 1938 -

145
00:16:19,108 --> 00:16:22,207
coming from a hairdressers'
where she had her hair waved

146
00:16:22,292 --> 00:16:24,704
and being stopped by a policeman,

147
00:16:24,786 --> 00:16:29,227
who told her that this was
a sign of Western decadence -

148
00:16:29,313 --> 00:16:32,990
you shouldn't have your hair waved.

149
00:16:33,073 --> 00:16:35,713
Dancing, even Western music -

150
00:16:35,797 --> 00:16:40,936
except classical music, which was mostly
German, Beethoven, sort of thing -

151
00:16:41,014 --> 00:16:42,890
was frowned upon.

152
00:16:42,971 --> 00:16:48,907
Dancehalls were closed down and any kind
of pleasure introduced from the West,

153
00:16:48,994 --> 00:16:54,668
the military did their best to
prohibit it and rub it out altogether.

154
00:16:58,470 --> 00:17:04,755
(Bush) When I left Japan, early '40,
there was rationing, prices were high,

155
00:17:04,839 --> 00:17:07,130
students of high schools, universities,

156
00:17:07,218 --> 00:17:10,164
were doing military training
practically every day,

157
00:17:10,248 --> 00:17:15,267
you had army officers attached to
every school to supervise such training.

158
00:17:15,351 --> 00:17:18,570
And so it was a nation
preparing for war.

159
00:17:18,957 --> 00:17:20,484
(yells)

160
00:17:41,976 --> 00:17:44,431
(narrator) The China war
dragged on into 1940,

161
00:17:44,546 --> 00:17:47,187
though the Japanese generals
were looking to end it

162
00:17:47,270 --> 00:17:50,183
without too much loss of face.

163
00:17:56,133 --> 00:17:59,962
But Hitler's swift victories over
Holland and France in May, 1940,

164
00:18:00,046 --> 00:18:02,806
and the seemingly imminent
defeat of Britain

165
00:18:02,885 --> 00:18:07,064
made the Japanese generals
greedy for more.

166
00:18:14,318 --> 00:18:21,716
Generally speaking, the Japanese public
was very elated by the German success.

167
00:18:21,799 --> 00:18:25,203
The catchword in those days
was "Don't miss the bus".

168
00:18:28,359 --> 00:18:30,847
Within three months of France's fall,

169
00:18:30,930 --> 00:18:33,461
the puppet Vichy government
had been persuaded

170
00:18:33,538 --> 00:18:36,222
to allow Japanese troops
to enter French Indochina,

171
00:18:36,301 --> 00:18:40,895
ominously close to the Philippines,
then an American dependency.

172
00:18:40,981 --> 00:18:42,705
America reacted sharply

173
00:18:42,784 --> 00:18:47,116
by embargoing supplies to Japan
of iron ore and aviation fuel.

174
00:18:47,196 --> 00:18:50,677
The embargo pushed Japan
still closer to the Axis.

175
00:19:08,450 --> 00:19:10,174
In Berlin in September, 1940,

176
00:19:10,253 --> 00:19:15,960
Germany, Italy and Japan
concluded the Tripartite Pact.

177
00:19:16,047 --> 00:19:19,189
The two wars at opposite ends
of the globe were now linked,

178
00:19:19,269 --> 00:19:22,717
though not yet joined.

179
00:19:29,896 --> 00:19:33,923
Japan's pro-German foreign minister
Yosuke Matsuoka

180
00:19:34,001 --> 00:19:38,213
followed up his goodwill trip to Hitler
with a visit in April, 1941, to Moscow,

181
00:19:38,298 --> 00:19:41,245
where he signed a neutrality treaty
with Stalin.

182
00:19:42,595 --> 00:19:49,611
(man) The Soviet Union had already
posed a threat to Japanese security,

183
00:19:49,692 --> 00:19:56,097
and so the army was itching
for a showdown with the Soviet Union.

184
00:19:56,176 --> 00:19:59,472
The navy, on the other hand,

185
00:19:59,552 --> 00:20:02,269
wanted to advance southward

186
00:20:03,274 --> 00:20:06,263
because the resources

187
00:20:07,686 --> 00:20:13,469
our country lacked
were largely in the South Seas.

188
00:20:13,555 --> 00:20:17,036
And so Japan was, so to speak,
pulled apart

189
00:20:17,162 --> 00:20:22,487
between the army ambition
and naval design.

190
00:20:22,571 --> 00:20:27,787
But when the time for intervention
against the north passed,

191
00:20:27,904 --> 00:20:32,312
the army naturally joined with the navy.

192
00:20:35,462 --> 00:20:38,408
(narrator) Japan had
the strongest navy in the Pacific,

193
00:20:38,492 --> 00:20:43,010
but when she occupied the rest of
French Indochina in the summer of 1941,

194
00:20:43,096 --> 00:20:45,006
the United States embargoed oil,

195
00:20:45,091 --> 00:20:48,724
which left the Japanese navy
critically short of it.

196
00:20:58,903 --> 00:21:01,892
Japan could either climb down
and suffer loss of face,

197
00:21:02,010 --> 00:21:04,377
or else move south to seize these,

198
00:21:04,465 --> 00:21:08,295
the oil wells of the Dutch East Indies.

199
00:21:08,379 --> 00:21:11,445
Serious planning for such a move
began straight away.

200
00:21:11,563 --> 00:21:17,925
Special jungle training and amphibious
landing exercises were put in hand.

201
00:21:43,559 --> 00:21:44,781
Army leaders argued that

202
00:21:44,902 --> 00:21:49,038
unless an invasion of the Dutch East
Indies began before the end of 1941,

203
00:21:49,122 --> 00:21:52,341
a shortage of oil
would rule it out forever.

204
00:21:52,421 --> 00:21:56,099
Even so, some Japanese politicians
still hadn't given up hope

205
00:21:56,181 --> 00:21:59,433
of achieving Japan's aims
by diplomatic means.

206
00:21:59,557 --> 00:22:01,358
But time was short.

207
00:22:01,476 --> 00:22:04,618
The generals had given the diplomats
until mid-October.

208
00:22:04,698 --> 00:22:09,063
When that deadline passed,
Hirohito, on Marquis Kido's advice,

209
00:22:09,148 --> 00:22:12,826
invited his war minister General Tojo
to form a government.

210
00:22:12,908 --> 00:22:16,661
There are many interpretations
of Marquis Kido's actions

211
00:22:16,745 --> 00:22:21,262
in choosing General Tojo
as the prime minister

212
00:22:21,349 --> 00:22:26,335
over the last cabinet
preceding the outbreak of the war.

213
00:22:26,413 --> 00:22:31,007
I myself asked this point

214
00:22:31,093 --> 00:22:34,574
and Marquis Kido's reply was:

215
00:22:34,661 --> 00:22:39,757
"Nobody except Tojo
was powerful enough to control the army,

216
00:22:39,840 --> 00:22:41,979
which was running amok."

217
00:22:42,679 --> 00:22:49,346
And also: "Tojo was deeply devoted
to the person of the emperor,

218
00:22:49,432 --> 00:22:54,876
and if His Majesty
made his wish known to General Tojo,

219
00:22:54,956 --> 00:22:57,902
Tojo would faithfully
abide by such a wish."

220
00:22:57,987 --> 00:23:00,671
(speaking Japanese)

221
00:23:06,082 --> 00:23:09,486
(narrator) But even General Tojo
shrank from the brink of war.

222
00:23:09,611 --> 00:23:14,172
He extended the deadline for diplomacy
another month, until November 25,

223
00:23:14,292 --> 00:23:18,809
sending special envoys to Washington to
negotiate the ending of the oil embargo.

224
00:23:18,934 --> 00:23:22,916
(man) Say a few words for us, sir.
If you come quite close...

225
00:23:23,001 --> 00:23:27,867
Gentlemen, you all know
how difficult my mission is.

226
00:23:27,950 --> 00:23:30,012
But I will do all I can

227
00:23:30,098 --> 00:23:33,928
to make it a successful one
for the sake of two countries,

228
00:23:34,011 --> 00:23:37,186
Japan and the United States.

229
00:23:37,272 --> 00:23:41,025
(narrator) And so that autumn,
with scant sincerity on either side,

230
00:23:41,109 --> 00:23:43,717
the diplomatic charade was played out.

231
00:23:43,794 --> 00:23:45,518
(Kase) The government undertook

232
00:23:45,598 --> 00:23:48,544
the difficult negotiations
with the United States,

233
00:23:48,628 --> 00:23:52,840
but the temper of the nation
grew more militaristic,

234
00:23:52,925 --> 00:23:58,250
which made it practically impossible
to continue the negotiations.

235
00:23:58,335 --> 00:24:01,128
(narrator) While the diplomats
talked in Washington,

236
00:24:01,212 --> 00:24:03,896
in Tokyo the militarists
put the finishing touches

237
00:24:03,974 --> 00:24:05,545
to their plans of conquest.

238
00:24:06,468 --> 00:24:09,872
To capture the oil wells intact
called for a surprise assault,

239
00:24:09,959 --> 00:24:13,789
not just on the Dutch East Indies,
but also on Malaya and the Philippines.

240
00:24:13,872 --> 00:24:17,244
Having got the oil, there was
the problem of getting it back to Japan

241
00:24:17,325 --> 00:24:20,347
unhindered by either the Royal Navy
based at Singapore,

242
00:24:20,433 --> 00:24:26,795
or the massive United States Pacific
fleet based in Hawaii at Pearl Harbour.

243
00:24:26,878 --> 00:24:29,638
(man speaking Japanese)

244
00:24:31,252 --> 00:24:33,314
(translator)
It was felt that if war came

245
00:24:33,400 --> 00:24:36,193
and Japan were to fight
in a conventional way,

246
00:24:36,278 --> 00:24:39,758
she had little hope of winning.

247
00:24:39,845 --> 00:24:42,213
And so the idea was to strike a blow

248
00:24:42,339 --> 00:24:45,023
against the American fleet
at Pearl Harbour

249
00:24:45,140 --> 00:24:48,511
simultaneously as the war started.

250
00:24:52,621 --> 00:24:54,192
There were three main problems

251
00:24:54,271 --> 00:24:56,147
in attacking Pearl Harbour.

252
00:24:56,227 --> 00:24:58,332
The first was to keep it a secret,

253
00:24:58,414 --> 00:25:00,399
because if the Americans knew

254
00:25:00,486 --> 00:25:05,046
a Japanese fleet was approaching,
then they would immediately attack it.

255
00:25:05,128 --> 00:25:07,736
The second
concerned which route to take,

256
00:25:07,813 --> 00:25:10,606
and the third
concerned the attack itself,

257
00:25:10,729 --> 00:25:13,293
whether it would be possible
to use torpedoes

258
00:25:13,376 --> 00:25:16,213
in the shallow waters of Pearl Harbour.

259
00:25:17,635 --> 00:25:24,531
(man) The most difficult problem
was torpedo launching in shallow water.

260
00:25:25,538 --> 00:25:27,294
The British navy

261
00:25:27,379 --> 00:25:31,788
attacked the Italian fleet at Taranto

262
00:25:33,825 --> 00:25:37,076
and I owe it very much for this lesson

263
00:25:37,162 --> 00:25:40,491
in shallow-water launching.

264
00:25:40,577 --> 00:25:43,447
(man) We made a model of Pearl Harbour

265
00:25:43,531 --> 00:25:48,168
and the situation of the battleships
and other warships.

266
00:25:50,974 --> 00:25:55,644
We sent our agent to Pearl Harbour.

267
00:25:55,731 --> 00:26:01,253
(man) Sometimes I went
Japanese teahouse in Aliwa Height.

268
00:26:02,253 --> 00:26:08,538
From there, I saw the fleet
in Pearl Harbour.

269
00:26:09,542 --> 00:26:15,326
Sometimes I go round Pearl Harbour

270
00:26:15,412 --> 00:26:17,594
by taxi or bus.

271
00:26:17,676 --> 00:26:24,768
Sometimes I walk along the front,
drinking beer, to get information.

272
00:26:24,850 --> 00:26:27,490
I did, you know, fishing.

273
00:26:27,574 --> 00:26:31,131
I measured the depth of the sea,

274
00:26:31,218 --> 00:26:34,131
but it was very... danger.

275
00:26:34,211 --> 00:26:39,808
And one time I was ordered
to see the torpedo gate.

276
00:26:39,889 --> 00:26:44,374
So I went to the prohibited area
of Pearl Harbour,

277
00:26:44,454 --> 00:26:49,932
but I could not discover
the submarine gate.

278
00:26:51,091 --> 00:26:56,078
I sent my information

279
00:26:57,613 --> 00:27:03,135
by commercial telegram, in code.

280
00:27:04,135 --> 00:27:08,882
(narrator) The Japanese carrier fleet
had left Japan on November 26.

281
00:27:08,969 --> 00:27:12,144
It took them 11 days to sail,
undetected,

282
00:27:12,230 --> 00:27:14,838
the 4,000 or so miles to this point,

283
00:27:14,954 --> 00:27:17,977
a mere 200 miles short of Hawaii.

284
00:27:18,062 --> 00:27:22,121
The Americans had broken the Japanese
codes and knew war was imminent,

285
00:27:22,205 --> 00:27:26,537
but they had not found out
where the Japanese might strike them.

286
00:27:26,617 --> 00:27:31,255
"Climb Mount Niitaka"
came the message from Tokyo.

287
00:27:31,336 --> 00:27:35,166
It was the signal for war to commence.

288
00:27:35,249 --> 00:27:41,109
6am on the morning of
Sunday, December 7, 1941.

289
00:27:42,193 --> 00:27:48,249
The first of 400 Japanese bombers
and torpedo planes take to the air.

290
00:28:08,857 --> 00:28:12,610
Their destination: Pearl Harbour.

291
00:28:15,494 --> 00:28:19,095
In the early morning of December 7,

292
00:28:19,177 --> 00:28:21,053
Joseph L Lockard and myself

293
00:28:21,134 --> 00:28:26,764
were detailed to operate a problem
from our radar unit.

294
00:28:27,771 --> 00:28:31,753
The problem was to last from 4am to 7am.

295
00:28:31,837 --> 00:28:34,979
And it was a training programme.

296
00:28:35,060 --> 00:28:41,542
I was the plotter and
Joseph Lockard was the radar operator.

297
00:28:41,620 --> 00:28:46,793
We picked up a very large blip,
which we had never seen before,

298
00:28:46,876 --> 00:28:49,713
and proceeded to plot that flight in.

299
00:28:49,792 --> 00:28:52,662
It was then that I suggested
that we send the information

300
00:28:52,746 --> 00:28:55,234
in to our information centre.

301
00:28:55,317 --> 00:29:00,947
I called in and the switchboard operator
told me that there was no one there.

302
00:29:01,033 --> 00:29:04,710
Did we wish to have someone call back
to our radar station?

303
00:29:04,793 --> 00:29:08,667
And that's when this Lieutenant Tyler
called back

304
00:29:08,744 --> 00:29:13,109
and told us, in essence, to forget it.

305
00:29:14,307 --> 00:29:17,984
We continued the flight
until about 20 minutes of eight,

306
00:29:18,067 --> 00:29:24,734
when the flight seemed to disperse to
the right and to the left of the island.

307
00:29:52,097 --> 00:29:55,774
(man) I was on board
the USS California, tied to quay 3.

308
00:29:55,856 --> 00:29:58,617
I was on the quarterdeck,
getting ready for a colour -

309
00:29:58,695 --> 00:30:01,685
as a matter of fact,
I was a member of the band.

310
00:30:01,764 --> 00:30:04,907
And looking slightly to the south,

311
00:30:06,407 --> 00:30:10,160
I could see planes coming that
direction, and some from that direction.

312
00:30:10,243 --> 00:30:13,113
That was about the time
of general quarters.

313
00:30:13,197 --> 00:30:15,838
And I dropped my instrument,
which was a clarinet,

314
00:30:15,959 --> 00:30:18,251
went down below into my battle station,

315
00:30:18,338 --> 00:30:24,165
and, about five minutes later,
torpedoes hit us and exploded.

316
00:30:25,167 --> 00:30:30,230
(man #2) I was aboard the West Virginia
when the first airplanes came over.

317
00:30:30,308 --> 00:30:34,793
They were built similar
to our Helldivers, in those days.

318
00:30:34,873 --> 00:30:37,590
And the pilot had the greenhouse back,

319
00:30:37,674 --> 00:30:40,893
and he flew so low
that I still remember him.

320
00:30:40,973 --> 00:30:46,495
He had the leather helmet,
like World War II had, and the goggles,

321
00:30:46,575 --> 00:30:49,749
and the reason I remember,
he had a real thick moustache.

322
00:30:49,836 --> 00:30:52,748
As he flew over, he kind of smiled
and looked at the ship

323
00:30:52,828 --> 00:30:57,193
and flew over towards the hangar there,
when he starts laying his first bomb.

324
00:31:04,721 --> 00:31:09,162
I saw the Arizona blow up,
and it was like she just rained sailors.

325
00:31:09,248 --> 00:31:13,733
Those were the ones fortunate enough
to live, the ones blown off the ship.

326
00:31:13,852 --> 00:31:16,765
I ran to the stern first
to see if I could get off that way,

327
00:31:16,844 --> 00:31:19,332
cos everything was burning
at this time.

328
00:31:19,453 --> 00:31:22,978
And so then I ran to the fo'c's'le.

329
00:31:23,059 --> 00:31:26,617
And then there was a lot of oil,
but it hadn't caught fire at this time.

330
00:31:26,704 --> 00:31:29,726
So I said, "The best thing to do
is to dive off there."

331
00:31:29,812 --> 00:31:34,220
So I hit the water
and swam around this way

332
00:31:34,300 --> 00:31:39,669
and then came up over this rock there,
and this is where I landed.

333
00:31:39,787 --> 00:31:43,693
The thing I remember most about
that morning was terror and confusion.

334
00:31:43,815 --> 00:31:47,645
First place, it was early in the
morning - everybody wasn't quite awake,

335
00:31:47,728 --> 00:31:50,216
and to have somebody
trying to kill you at that hour

336
00:31:50,337 --> 00:31:54,319
kinda confuses you at best.

337
00:31:54,442 --> 00:31:58,348
We were taking power and steam
from the dock,

338
00:31:58,432 --> 00:32:00,308
since we were alongside for repairs,

339
00:32:00,388 --> 00:32:04,218
and somebody in the confusion cut our
power and steam line, so we were left...

340
00:32:04,302 --> 00:32:06,407
Everything had to be operated in manual.

341
00:32:06,488 --> 00:32:09,206
We only had one battery en masse
that we could use,

342
00:32:09,289 --> 00:32:11,242
which was the port five-inch battery,

343
00:32:11,322 --> 00:32:14,269
so we started using it on the aircraft
as they came in.

344
00:32:14,353 --> 00:32:17,605
The low-flying torpedo planes
all came directly over the hill

345
00:32:17,691 --> 00:32:19,906
and down this way toward battleship row,

346
00:32:19,993 --> 00:32:22,601
so we were able to get
some pretty good shots at 'em,

347
00:32:22,717 --> 00:32:24,473
even though we were in manual.

348
00:32:24,558 --> 00:32:28,191
However, the guns had to be served
by manual means -

349
00:32:28,280 --> 00:32:31,040
we had to pass ammunition by hand.

350
00:32:31,119 --> 00:32:33,988
We had a young chaplain aboard, JG,
at the time -

351
00:32:34,073 --> 00:32:37,793
he'd been aboard less than two months.
His name was Hallow M Forgy,

352
00:32:37,871 --> 00:32:40,741
and he was...

353
00:32:40,825 --> 00:32:43,313
As for his battle station,
he didn't have one -

354
00:32:43,395 --> 00:32:47,225
he was concerned with crew morale -
so he marched along the gun deck,

355
00:32:47,309 --> 00:32:49,872
saying, "Praise the Lord
and pass the ammunition."

356
00:33:38,065 --> 00:33:39,975
You live with these ships all the time -

357
00:33:40,060 --> 00:33:42,516
you never dream
they could be damaged like this.

358
00:33:42,631 --> 00:33:46,810
There were ships afire, ships burning,
explosions going on all over the place.

359
00:33:52,682 --> 00:33:56,054
(man) My first knowledge of the attack
was when I was awakened

360
00:33:56,135 --> 00:34:00,729
by the sound of bombs dropping and
the roaring of aircraft all around us.

361
00:34:00,816 --> 00:34:05,562
I ran out on the lanai and saw
immediately they were Japanese planes

362
00:34:05,650 --> 00:34:08,213
and there was a fella
standing next to me who said,

363
00:34:08,297 --> 00:34:10,282
"It certainly looks real, doesn't it?"

364
00:34:10,368 --> 00:34:12,550
And I said, "Yes, I'm afraid it is."

365
00:34:12,632 --> 00:34:14,694
I ran over to my offices

366
00:34:14,780 --> 00:34:16,384
and I was standing alongside

367
00:34:16,507 --> 00:34:19,453
the commander-in-chief himself,
Admiral Kimmel,

368
00:34:19,538 --> 00:34:24,481
and we were glumly watching the havoc,
the carnage, that was going on.

369
00:34:24,563 --> 00:34:28,622
And suddenly he reached up,
a motion of this kind,

370
00:34:28,707 --> 00:34:31,729
and tore off
his four-star shoulder boards,

371
00:34:31,814 --> 00:34:37,063
which indicated his rank and title
as Commander-in-Chief of Pacific Fleet.

372
00:34:37,147 --> 00:34:40,977
He stepped into his adjacent office
and when he came out,

373
00:34:41,060 --> 00:34:43,930
he realised that
he was going to lose command

374
00:34:44,014 --> 00:34:48,958
and he had donned
two-star rear-admiral shoulder boards.

375
00:35:33,467 --> 00:35:36,870
(narrator) All nine battleships
of the United States Pacific fleet

376
00:35:36,958 --> 00:35:38,180
had been sunk or ruined,

377
00:35:38,262 --> 00:35:41,132
together with several
destroyers and cruisers,

378
00:35:41,216 --> 00:35:44,238
but no aircraft carriers.

379
00:35:44,324 --> 00:35:45,742
Luckily for the Americans,

380
00:35:45,820 --> 00:35:49,846
the carriers had been at sea
that particular Sunday morning.

381
00:35:55,028 --> 00:35:58,901
However,
the Japanese were well satisfied.

382
00:36:00,360 --> 00:36:05,838
(Fuchida) The United States
Pacific fleet was not prepared

383
00:36:06,844 --> 00:36:09,943
and we succeeded.

384
00:36:10,565 --> 00:36:12,246
(cheering)

385
00:36:14,709 --> 00:36:16,967
(narrator)
The Japanese did not just succeed

386
00:36:17,049 --> 00:36:19,689
against the Americans at Pearl Harbour.

387
00:36:19,811 --> 00:36:23,488
On December 10, the pride
of the Royal Navy in the Pacific,

388
00:36:23,571 --> 00:36:27,171
the Prince of Wales and the Repulse,
were sunk.

389
00:36:27,254 --> 00:36:31,357
(cheering)

390
00:36:31,436 --> 00:36:34,425
That same day, Guam fell.

391
00:36:34,505 --> 00:36:37,342
(cheering)

392
00:36:37,421 --> 00:36:40,825
On December 23, Wake Island.

393
00:36:40,912 --> 00:36:43,782
(cheering)

394
00:36:43,866 --> 00:36:47,423
On Christmas Day, Hong Kong.

395
00:36:47,511 --> 00:36:49,496
(cheering)

396
00:36:52,997 --> 00:36:58,322
On New Year's Day, 1942,
Manila, capital of the Philippines.

397
00:36:58,406 --> 00:37:01,167
(cheering)

398
00:37:01,974 --> 00:37:05,149
On January 19, Borneo.

399
00:37:05,235 --> 00:37:07,799
(cheering)

400
00:37:07,921 --> 00:37:12,907
But the biggest prize of all
awaited the Japanese in Malaya.

401
00:37:13,944 --> 00:37:17,392
(man)
The plan for the defence of Malaya

402
00:37:17,474 --> 00:37:21,838
was based entirely on the air force.

403
00:37:21,962 --> 00:37:27,440
And there were to be
some 335 first-class aircraft,

404
00:37:27,563 --> 00:37:31,088
with the army protecting their bases
and their aerodromes,

405
00:37:31,170 --> 00:37:33,701
and the idea was that they should attack

406
00:37:33,779 --> 00:37:37,379
the Japanese whilst they were at sea

407
00:37:38,382 --> 00:37:41,449
and destroy them or damage them

408
00:37:41,528 --> 00:37:44,169
before the campaign started.

409
00:37:44,252 --> 00:37:49,545
Percival's idea was
to oppose the Japanese as they landed.

410
00:37:49,623 --> 00:37:57,065
And that didn't come off -
they were able to land in Thailand

411
00:37:57,143 --> 00:38:01,813
and we would not break the neutrality,

412
00:38:01,900 --> 00:38:05,151
and so we were at a disadvantage
from the start.

413
00:38:05,890 --> 00:38:08,879
(narrator) The Japanese
were outnumbered two to one.

414
00:38:08,997 --> 00:38:14,093
They had only the poorest of maps,
usually pages torn from school atlases,

415
00:38:14,177 --> 00:38:18,388
but they kept the British on the run,
not stopping to consolidate or regroup.

416
00:38:18,474 --> 00:38:21,191
(Smyth) One reason
we were thrown onto the defensive,

417
00:38:21,274 --> 00:38:24,187
the Japanese employed 300 tanks.

418
00:38:24,267 --> 00:38:26,067
We hadn't any tanks at all.

419
00:38:26,722 --> 00:38:28,937
(narrator)
British strategists had decreed

420
00:38:29,024 --> 00:38:32,898
that armour was not suited
to jungle warfare.

421
00:38:39,459 --> 00:38:43,333
Back in Whitehall, the British
thought the jungle impenetrable,

422
00:38:43,449 --> 00:38:47,323
whereas in some places it was cleared,
in others not so dense,

423
00:38:47,401 --> 00:38:52,311
and, anyway, the really dense patches
could always be bypassed by sea -

424
00:38:52,388 --> 00:38:56,021
which was precisely
what the Japanese did.

425
00:39:18,745 --> 00:39:21,308
(Okada) The jungle is
not such a terrible place.

426
00:39:21,392 --> 00:39:26,214
We can live on rice, salt and
sesame seeds, and salted fish, you see.

427
00:39:26,302 --> 00:39:28,834
This can keep a soldier going
a long time.

428
00:39:28,911 --> 00:39:30,787
The jungle did not have the fear for us

429
00:39:30,906 --> 00:39:35,118
that it seems to have had
for some of the Allied soldiers.

430
00:39:39,922 --> 00:39:42,213
(narrator) The Japanese
had bombed Singapore

431
00:39:42,301 --> 00:39:44,210
the same morning as Pearl Harbour.

432
00:39:44,334 --> 00:39:48,164
The lights of the great port had guided
them in and remained on during the raid

433
00:39:48,247 --> 00:39:51,389
because no one knew
how to switch them off.

434
00:39:51,470 --> 00:39:57,406
Such confusion was to typify Singapore's
reaction to the Japanese onslaught.

435
00:39:57,493 --> 00:40:01,246
(Bush) I remember
a British national newspaper ran a story

436
00:40:01,330 --> 00:40:03,239
in which the opinion was expressed

437
00:40:03,325 --> 00:40:05,507
that the Japanese
would never be good flyers

438
00:40:05,588 --> 00:40:08,425
because they had no sense of balance

439
00:40:08,504 --> 00:40:13,949
through being carried on
the backs of their mothers as children.

440
00:41:00,296 --> 00:41:05,818
(narrator) The Japanese secret weapon
in Malaya was... the bicycle.

441
00:41:30,221 --> 00:41:34,476
When their tyres punctured, the Japanese
soldiers simply rode on their rims.

442
00:41:34,556 --> 00:41:38,812
To the retreating British, the clatter
on the stony road sounded like tanks,

443
00:41:38,891 --> 00:41:41,226
and added to their fear.

444
00:42:07,396 --> 00:42:12,186
I think the fundamental reason
why we failed in Malaya

445
00:42:12,307 --> 00:42:16,137
was that we were stretched to the limit
at that time

446
00:42:16,220 --> 00:42:19,287
in our war with Germany and Italy

447
00:42:19,366 --> 00:42:26,416
and there simply were not
the trained men, air forces and ships

448
00:42:26,540 --> 00:42:31,178
that we should have supplied
to beat the Japanese attack.

449
00:42:42,155 --> 00:42:47,981
The priority of arms and equipment
for Malaya at that time was very low.

450
00:42:48,063 --> 00:42:49,634
They were only number four,

451
00:42:49,751 --> 00:42:53,701
after Great Britain,
the Middle East and Russia.

452
00:42:53,818 --> 00:42:59,339
Also, with regard to men,
the first priority was the Middle East,

453
00:42:59,419 --> 00:43:02,103
and Malaya only came second.

454
00:43:02,181 --> 00:43:07,354
Some of the Australians that arrived
in Malaya had never even fired a rifle.

455
00:43:07,476 --> 00:43:11,349
So we did field
very much a second eleven

456
00:43:11,466 --> 00:43:15,721
against the very highly trained
and strongly supported Japanese.

457
00:43:16,299 --> 00:43:18,831
(narrator)
Like the Americans at Pearl Harbour,

458
00:43:18,908 --> 00:43:24,157
the British in Malaya wrongly believed
the Japanese air force was poor,

459
00:43:24,241 --> 00:43:28,497
but now British air cover waned
and eventually disappeared.

460
00:43:28,576 --> 00:43:31,828
There was no effective plan
to stop the Japanese by land

461
00:43:31,952 --> 00:43:34,593
and too little determination to resist.

462
00:43:38,513 --> 00:43:41,655
Your forces

463
00:43:41,735 --> 00:43:45,871
are not so aggressive as we expected.

464
00:44:16,264 --> 00:44:18,981
The British planners
had thought that, at worst,

465
00:44:19,064 --> 00:44:21,977
northern Malaya could hold out
for at least three months,

466
00:44:22,057 --> 00:44:26,771
enough time to enable substantial
reinforcements to be sent to Singapore.

467
00:44:26,852 --> 00:44:31,642
But it took the Japanese, under
General Yamashita, just seven weeks

468
00:44:31,725 --> 00:44:35,860
to advance the 600 miles
down the Malayan peninsula.

469
00:44:42,697 --> 00:44:45,337
On February 8, 1942,

470
00:44:45,421 --> 00:44:48,291
they crossed the thousands yards
of the Straits of Johor

471
00:44:48,375 --> 00:44:50,863
onto the island of Singapore.

472
00:44:52,710 --> 00:44:56,343
No defences had been built
on the northern shore of the island,

473
00:44:56,432 --> 00:44:59,531
so the Japanese were able to land
relatively unmolested.

474
00:44:59,654 --> 00:45:01,564
What is more,
they were able to capture

475
00:45:01,649 --> 00:45:04,977
most of Singapore's water supplies
with ease.

476
00:45:08,478 --> 00:45:12,734
By now, the Japanese bombers
raided Singapore at will,

477
00:45:12,813 --> 00:45:15,072
for there was virtually no air defence.

478
00:45:16,228 --> 00:45:19,021
The Japanese, in fact,
were almost out of ammunition

479
00:45:19,144 --> 00:45:22,439
and were considering
withdrawing to the mainland,

480
00:45:22,520 --> 00:45:26,502
but, unknown to them,
British morale had collapsed.

481
00:45:29,157 --> 00:45:32,331
(speaking Japanese)

482
00:45:34,643 --> 00:45:37,665
(translator) General Yamashita
had not prepared any plans

483
00:45:37,750 --> 00:45:40,893
in the event of a British surrender.

484
00:45:42,431 --> 00:45:47,647
And so when, on February 15,
Major Wild, General Percival's emissary,

485
00:45:47,764 --> 00:45:51,561
arrived at our forward headquarters
at 3pm,

486
00:45:51,639 --> 00:45:53,668
no one there believed him.

487
00:45:56,511 --> 00:45:59,042
I was ordered to discuss with him

488
00:45:59,158 --> 00:46:04,406
his suggestion of a meeting between
General Percival and General Yamashita.

489
00:46:04,491 --> 00:46:06,630
Major Wild wanted General Yamashita

490
00:46:06,716 --> 00:46:09,171
to go to the governor general's
residence,

491
00:46:09,286 --> 00:46:11,468
but did not mention surrender.

492
00:46:11,550 --> 00:46:16,264
I told him it was out of the question
for General Yamashita to go anywhere

493
00:46:16,345 --> 00:46:19,063
and that his general must come to us.

494
00:46:19,146 --> 00:46:24,668
Eventually Major Wild agreed to this
and said he would bring him at 6pm,

495
00:46:24,747 --> 00:46:27,694
but again made no mention of surrender.

496
00:46:27,778 --> 00:46:33,256
When I reported this to my superiors,
they were suspicious and unbelieving.

497
00:46:33,341 --> 00:46:37,826
However, I returned at six
to meet General Percival and Major Wild.

498
00:46:38,482 --> 00:46:40,849
I guided them to the Ford factory,

499
00:46:40,937 --> 00:46:45,116
where the meeting with General Yamashita
was to take place.

500
00:46:45,196 --> 00:46:48,370
Because of this disbelief
on the Japanese side,

501
00:46:48,457 --> 00:46:53,127
they were still setting up tables
when we arrived.

502
00:46:53,214 --> 00:46:56,160
Straight away General Yamashita
asked General Percival

503
00:46:56,245 --> 00:46:57,968
whether he was surrendering.

504
00:46:58,048 --> 00:47:02,565
But the British general merely talked
about wanting to keep 1,500 soldiers

505
00:47:02,690 --> 00:47:05,527
to maintain peace and order
in Singapore.

506
00:47:05,606 --> 00:47:08,399
General Yamashita again asked
about surrender,

507
00:47:08,483 --> 00:47:12,848
but General Percival went on
talking about these 1,500 troops.

508
00:47:12,972 --> 00:47:16,605
And so these two conversations
continued in parallel

509
00:47:16,732 --> 00:47:18,565
and time was passing.

510
00:47:18,650 --> 00:47:21,367
Finally, General Yamashita
could wait no longer.

511
00:47:21,451 --> 00:47:25,816
He banged the table and asked
General Percival if he was surrendering.

512
00:47:25,901 --> 00:47:29,927
Otherwise, the Japanese would launch
an immediate night attack.

513
00:47:30,006 --> 00:47:31,991
Would that be all right?

514
00:47:32,078 --> 00:47:37,217
Percival replied, no,
he did not want any more attacks.

515
00:47:37,334 --> 00:47:41,316
So again General Yamashita asked,
"Will you surrender?"

516
00:47:41,400 --> 00:47:44,696
And at last General Percival said yes.

517
00:47:44,815 --> 00:47:46,800
(cheering)

518
00:47:57,590 --> 00:48:01,420
(narrator) Singapore had been thought
by the British to be impregnable,

519
00:48:01,503 --> 00:48:04,067
but they were thinking
of an attack from the sea.

520
00:48:04,151 --> 00:48:09,552
Indeed, all the big fortress guns
pointed seaward, not landward.

521
00:48:09,713 --> 00:48:13,969
Said Churchill later, "The possibility
of Singapore having no landward defences

522
00:48:14,049 --> 00:48:15,772
no more entered into my mind

523
00:48:15,852 --> 00:48:20,063
than that of a battleship being launched
without a bottom."

524
00:48:20,149 --> 00:48:24,666
We were so surprised,
because we expected that

525
00:48:24,752 --> 00:48:32,424
your forces were about 50,000 in total.

526
00:48:32,502 --> 00:48:35,677
And we found out that there were about

527
00:48:35,763 --> 00:48:42,659
110,000 prisoners in Singapore.

528
00:48:42,746 --> 00:48:46,149
(narrator) Singapore's fall
was the worst military disaster

529
00:48:46,237 --> 00:48:48,725
in British history.

530
00:48:48,846 --> 00:48:52,523
More than 130,000 troops
laid down their arms

531
00:48:52,605 --> 00:48:56,086
in the largest capitulation
the British army has ever known.

532
00:48:56,173 --> 00:49:00,309
The Japanese soldiers
are told not to be prisoners,

533
00:49:00,854 --> 00:49:02,687
so it's quite natural,

534
00:49:02,772 --> 00:49:08,369
when they see the tens of thousands
of white prisoners at Singapore,

535
00:49:08,450 --> 00:49:10,435
they look down on them.

536
00:49:21,494 --> 00:49:24,102
Thousands
of British and Commonwealth troops

537
00:49:24,180 --> 00:49:27,431
had arrived in Singapore
only days before,

538
00:49:27,517 --> 00:49:30,125
just in time to surrender.

539
00:49:39,219 --> 00:49:43,322
Singapore's fall meant that the whole
of Southeast Asia lay at Japan's feet.

540
00:49:43,400 --> 00:49:46,422
Within weeks, the Japanese army
was at the borders of India

541
00:49:46,508 --> 00:49:49,956
and the Japanese navy was steaming
close to the shores of Australia.

542
00:49:50,037 --> 00:49:54,096
They had succeeded
beyond their wildest dreams.

543
00:49:59,015 --> 00:50:01,623
For the British, a last humiliation.

544
00:50:01,700 --> 00:50:06,567
The garrison was paraded
before the triumphant Japanese.

545
00:50:38,607 --> 00:50:41,520
The sun had set on one imperial power.

546
00:50:46,050 --> 00:50:49,149
On another, the sun was still rising.
