1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:18,952 --> 00:00:21,363
(narrator) May 26, 1940.

3
00:00:29,848 --> 00:00:33,023
Along roads lined with their
smashed and abandoned equipment,

4
00:00:33,109 --> 00:00:37,320
British and French armies retreat to the
only Channel port still open to them:

5
00:00:37,406 --> 00:00:39,545
Dunkirk.

6
00:00:39,631 --> 00:00:42,162
Ten miles away, along the Channel coast,

7
00:00:42,240 --> 00:00:46,069
German armour awaits
Hitler's orders to attack.

8
00:00:47,074 --> 00:00:48,754
On the Dunkirk beaches,

9
00:00:48,838 --> 00:00:51,556
nearly half a million men -
British and French -

10
00:00:51,639 --> 00:00:57,542
face surrender, or the slim chance
of rescue by ships from England.

11
00:01:52,754 --> 00:01:54,281
(man)
There were masses of troops

12
00:01:54,365 --> 00:01:57,083
and they came down
in a sort of a V-shape

13
00:01:57,166 --> 00:02:01,531
to a crocodile, semi-single file,
as they got near the water's edge.

14
00:02:01,616 --> 00:02:06,560
Of course, many of these soldiers were
going out up to their necks in water

15
00:02:06,642 --> 00:02:08,595
and climbing into, say,
minesweepers

16
00:02:08,676 --> 00:02:10,738
that could get in
nearly as close as that.

17
00:02:10,824 --> 00:02:13,890
Others on the beach were
embarking in the small boats.

18
00:02:13,970 --> 00:02:17,036
But there didn't seem to be
any panic or worry at all.

19
00:02:17,116 --> 00:02:19,680
One came across
lots of these small boats,

20
00:02:19,763 --> 00:02:23,822
many of them with perhaps
a dozen or so soldiers on board,

21
00:02:23,945 --> 00:02:26,279
heading back for England resolutely.

22
00:02:26,362 --> 00:02:30,650
One quite often offered to
take their crews of soldiers off them

23
00:02:30,774 --> 00:02:32,879
so they could go back for more,
and they said:

24
00:02:32,960 --> 00:02:36,790
"No fear. We've got our 12 pongos, and
we're going back to England with them."

25
00:02:36,912 --> 00:02:38,406
"You go and get your own."

26
00:02:39,828 --> 00:02:42,316
(man) The beach was...
There were thousands of men,

27
00:02:42,437 --> 00:02:45,383
Iike Margate beach on a bank holiday.

28
00:02:46,618 --> 00:02:50,099
The troops was in a pretty bad state.
They were in a bad way.

29
00:02:50,800 --> 00:02:53,593
There was one man especially,
I shall always remember.

30
00:02:53,677 --> 00:02:56,973
He came on board -
he'd had his teeth blown out -

31
00:02:57,092 --> 00:03:00,234
and he was holding a rifle
with a fixed bayonet.

32
00:03:00,353 --> 00:03:02,186
We had to take the arms
off everyone,

33
00:03:02,271 --> 00:03:05,141
but we couldn't shift
the gun out of his hands.

34
00:03:05,225 --> 00:03:09,481
His hands gripped it,
and they was... fixture.

35
00:03:10,635 --> 00:03:14,464
A chap was on the beach, and then he
gets aboard a ship and thinks he's safe.

36
00:03:14,548 --> 00:03:16,730
But they really did think this.
They said:

37
00:03:16,811 --> 00:03:20,489
"England, home and beauty -
let us get there, boyo."

38
00:03:20,610 --> 00:03:23,021
(McBeath) We were most impressed.
They were tired.

39
00:03:23,103 --> 00:03:25,864
Most of them went to sleep.

40
00:03:28,743 --> 00:03:32,038
Our job was to stop enemy aircraft
getting at those troops

41
00:03:32,119 --> 00:03:36,986
because, believe me, if enemy aircraft
had superiority of the air at Dunkirk,

42
00:03:37,106 --> 00:03:40,281
they would have massacred
those fellows on the beach.

43
00:03:40,367 --> 00:03:42,931
They had no guns,
they had no anti-aircraft.

44
00:03:43,015 --> 00:03:47,761
And German bombers
and German dive bombers - the Stukas -

45
00:03:47,887 --> 00:03:52,252
would have just murdered them. And
we couldn't have got those troops off.

46
00:03:52,337 --> 00:03:55,479
Another thing the Germans tried to do
was to sink the ships.

47
00:03:55,598 --> 00:03:59,351
They knew that the fellows
couldn't swim to England,

48
00:03:59,435 --> 00:04:01,420
so they had to try and get on the ships.

49
00:04:01,545 --> 00:04:06,335
And if they could sink these ships, the
British army would have been trapped.

50
00:04:10,752 --> 00:04:14,549
(narrator) The RAF tried to keep the
German air force away from the beaches,

51
00:04:14,627 --> 00:04:18,654
but six destroyers
and over 200 craft were sunk.

52
00:04:21,878 --> 00:04:26,319
Fighter Command lost nearly half
its strength in the French campaign -

53
00:04:26,405 --> 00:04:28,969
100 planes
in the Dunkirk operations alone.

54
00:04:29,052 --> 00:04:31,038
(engine spluttering)

55
00:04:38,413 --> 00:04:40,869
Dunkirk was a major defeat,

56
00:04:40,945 --> 00:04:44,120
but the inspired efforts
of the Royal Navy and the little ships

57
00:04:44,206 --> 00:04:48,495
saved 330,000 British and French troops.

58
00:04:49,654 --> 00:04:51,869
For a week, the weather was fine,

59
00:04:51,956 --> 00:04:54,826
and the German army was held off.

60
00:04:54,910 --> 00:04:59,471
(Good) I don't think they thought they
would get them off. That's my opinion.

61
00:04:59,552 --> 00:05:01,767
But it was an act of God that they did.

62
00:05:01,854 --> 00:05:05,335
The weather was good,
the sea was like a millpond,

63
00:05:05,422 --> 00:05:07,910
and this was a great help to everybody.

64
00:05:07,993 --> 00:05:11,517
If it had been rough water, you'd
have never got them off of Dunkirk,

65
00:05:11,599 --> 00:05:15,505
because when those rollers
go up that beach, they go.

66
00:05:15,627 --> 00:05:18,846
(McBeath) Any moment,
a breakthrough by the German army

67
00:05:18,965 --> 00:05:21,070
could have stopped the whole operation.

68
00:05:21,152 --> 00:05:24,709
I don't think,
despite the valiant endeavours

69
00:05:24,796 --> 00:05:28,626
of the British and French troops
who were keeping the Germans back,

70
00:05:28,710 --> 00:05:32,659
that they could have stopped the might
of the German armour getting through

71
00:05:32,738 --> 00:05:35,105
if Hitler had so wanted to do it.

72
00:05:36,574 --> 00:05:40,753
(narrator) What was left of Dunkirk
surrendered on June 4.

73
00:05:40,833 --> 00:05:43,626
Thousands of troops
could not be rescued.

74
00:05:46,473 --> 00:05:48,764
A fortnight later,
France stopped fighting,

75
00:05:48,928 --> 00:05:52,453
and the British prime minister,
Churchill, broadcast to the world:

76
00:05:52,534 --> 00:05:57,750
(Churchill) What General Weygand had
called the Battle of France is over.

77
00:05:57,828 --> 00:06:01,735
The Battle of Britain
is about to begin.

78
00:06:01,818 --> 00:06:07,493
Hitler knows that he will have to break
us in this island, or lose the war.

79
00:06:07,995 --> 00:06:12,360
If we can stand up to him,
all Europe may be free,

80
00:06:12,445 --> 00:06:18,349
and the life of the world may move
forward into broad, sunlit uplands.

81
00:06:19,121 --> 00:06:20,921
But if we fail,

82
00:06:21,001 --> 00:06:26,752
then the whole world will
sink into the abyss of a new dark age.

83
00:06:27,830 --> 00:06:31,550
Let us therefore
brace ourselves to our duty...

84
00:06:32,472 --> 00:06:35,003
and so bear ourselves

85
00:06:35,081 --> 00:06:39,446
that if the British Empire
and its Commonwealth

86
00:06:39,608 --> 00:06:41,670
last for a thousand years,

87
00:06:41,756 --> 00:06:43,971
men will still say:

88
00:06:44,940 --> 00:06:47,853
"This was their finest hour. "

89
00:06:59,289 --> 00:07:00,707
(whistle / cheering)

90
00:07:03,279 --> 00:07:06,574
(narrator) Britain prepared
to face immediate invasion.

91
00:07:06,693 --> 00:07:10,097
A new evacuation of children began
from the south and east-coast areas

92
00:07:10,185 --> 00:07:12,945
where a German landing
might be expected.

93
00:07:15,901 --> 00:07:19,152
Some parents sent their children
overseas to safety.

94
00:07:19,239 --> 00:07:22,381
But this was stopped
when a U-boat sank a British liner

95
00:07:22,500 --> 00:07:25,031
with 90 children on board.

96
00:07:31,707 --> 00:07:35,111
To guard against invasion, over a
million men not required by the forces

97
00:07:35,237 --> 00:07:38,456
volunteered to form the Home Guard.

98
00:07:50,046 --> 00:07:53,374
They drilled with broomsticks
as there were no rifles to spare,

99
00:07:53,498 --> 00:07:57,677
and rehearsed bloodthirsty defences
against a German attack.

100
00:08:18,551 --> 00:08:22,610
The regular army's training
seems to have impressed the newsreels.

101
00:08:22,694 --> 00:08:25,760
(newsreel) They have turned
kick-starter pushers.

102
00:08:25,840 --> 00:08:28,753
Shanks' pony has given way
to a spanking motorbike.

103
00:08:28,832 --> 00:08:32,782
The left-right, left-right blokes
have both feet off the ground.

104
00:08:32,899 --> 00:08:35,354
They're part of Britain's
mighty mobile mounties,

105
00:08:35,431 --> 00:08:39,796
all keen to welcome Adolf when he drops
in for a cup of tea and a cream bun.

106
00:08:39,881 --> 00:08:42,674
A battalion of infantry on wheels
is on exercise -

107
00:08:42,759 --> 00:08:46,818
a swift-moving striking force that
will do the enemy a bit of no good.

108
00:08:46,941 --> 00:08:51,458
They learn under conditions
they might meet with on active service.

109
00:08:51,583 --> 00:08:57,104
Up and down they go, but unlike the Hun
they're always on the level.

110
00:08:58,297 --> 00:09:01,319
(narrator) The army had brought back
their rifles from Dunkirk,

111
00:09:01,404 --> 00:09:05,005
but almost everything else
had been abandoned in France.

112
00:09:05,087 --> 00:09:10,150
In June, the only fully-equipped
division in Britain was Canadian.

113
00:09:10,228 --> 00:09:14,484
I remember in June going down
to the Southeast corner of Britain,

114
00:09:14,563 --> 00:09:16,855
where General Thorne was in command -

115
00:09:16,942 --> 00:09:20,313
Kent, Surrey, Sussex,
that sort of area,

116
00:09:20,395 --> 00:09:24,650
a possible landing area for the Germans,
if they were going to attempt it -

117
00:09:24,730 --> 00:09:28,985
and I remember sending a memorandum
to Winston which must be in his papers.

118
00:09:29,103 --> 00:09:31,395
If I remember right,
I said something like this:

119
00:09:31,482 --> 00:09:34,853
the troops were in very good heart
and very well trained,

120
00:09:34,935 --> 00:09:41,373
but there was
no antitank weapon of any kind,

121
00:09:41,457 --> 00:09:44,785
no antitank guns, and no tanks.

122
00:09:44,871 --> 00:09:49,083
That was in the area where, if the
Germans landed, they might be expected.

123
00:09:49,168 --> 00:09:51,307
The cupboard was bare.

124
00:09:51,930 --> 00:09:55,259
(narrator) The king rejoiced
that Britain stood alone,

125
00:09:55,345 --> 00:09:57,800
with no more allies to pamper.

126
00:09:57,877 --> 00:10:00,790
The head of Fighter Command,
Sir Hugh Dowding, agreed.

127
00:10:00,908 --> 00:10:04,508
He had lost too many planes
helping the French.

128
00:10:05,819 --> 00:10:10,184
Station names and signposts were
removed to baffle invading Germans.

129
00:10:10,346 --> 00:10:12,909
The effect was to baffle
British travellers.

130
00:10:13,568 --> 00:10:18,861
Antitank barriers deprived the Germans
or an easy advance along the railways.

131
00:10:24,119 --> 00:10:28,833
In the invasion areas, the countryside
disappeared under coils of barbed wire.

132
00:10:28,991 --> 00:10:33,127
The beaches, too,
were wired to below low-water mark.

133
00:10:33,211 --> 00:10:36,615
JB Priestley remembers
a visit to the seaside.

134
00:10:36,702 --> 00:10:42,256
I went down one hot summer day -
late summer -

135
00:10:42,342 --> 00:10:46,292
to one of the seaside resorts
on the Kent coast.

136
00:10:47,291 --> 00:10:49,779
The last time I visited,
it was packed out -

137
00:10:49,861 --> 00:10:54,193
the beaches absolutely crammed,
and all the fun of the fair going on.

138
00:10:54,312 --> 00:11:00,215
Then to see it on this
strange, bright, empty day,

139
00:11:00,297 --> 00:11:04,934
the beaches deserted,
a lot of barbed wire all over the place,

140
00:11:05,054 --> 00:11:11,142
I felt then that, in a way, this was
a kind of symbol of what people felt,

141
00:11:11,231 --> 00:11:16,752
and that they were ready
to abandon this for the time being

142
00:11:16,832 --> 00:11:19,199
in order to get on with the war.

143
00:11:21,704 --> 00:11:25,305
(narrator) Churchill was everywhere,
no longer a suspect politician,

144
00:11:25,387 --> 00:11:28,758
but the living embodiment
of the British will to resist.

145
00:11:28,840 --> 00:11:31,022
It was a situation
he seemed to revel in,

146
00:11:31,104 --> 00:11:33,286
describing a vivid picture of himself

147
00:11:33,367 --> 00:11:37,503
leading a last-man defence
of a devastated Whitehall.

148
00:11:37,587 --> 00:11:42,225
Immediately Churchill became prime
minister, the pace in Whitehall changed.

149
00:11:42,306 --> 00:11:46,485
People started not merely to think fast,
but to act fast.

150
00:11:46,565 --> 00:11:50,471
Distinguished civil servants could be
seen running down the passages.

151
00:11:50,554 --> 00:11:53,195
Churchill himself
was physically very energetic.

152
00:11:53,317 --> 00:11:56,841
He would suddenly make the most
extraordinary and energetic sorties.

153
00:11:56,923 --> 00:12:00,251
He would inspect troops,
marching at great speed down the ranks,

154
00:12:00,337 --> 00:12:03,360
and outpacing
all the younger men following him.

155
00:12:03,445 --> 00:12:07,810
I remember one evening he said he was
going to inspect some new works,

156
00:12:07,895 --> 00:12:13,340
and although he was 65 years old,
he vaulted over a brick wall

157
00:12:13,420 --> 00:12:16,901
and landed feet first
in a pool of liquid cement.

158
00:12:16,988 --> 00:12:20,436
And with an impertinence
which in retrospect I'm surprised at,

159
00:12:20,517 --> 00:12:24,773
I said, "You've met your Waterloo,"
as he was stuck in the cement.

160
00:12:24,853 --> 00:12:28,879
He turned to me and said,
"How dare you? Anyhow, my Blenheim."

161
00:12:32,986 --> 00:12:35,823
(narrator) In the arms factories
they worked long hours

162
00:12:35,902 --> 00:12:38,040
to fill the gaps in British defences.

163
00:12:38,127 --> 00:12:41,422
Production reached a peak in June,
then fell as workers tired.

164
00:12:41,503 --> 00:12:44,111
But the spurt lasted
through the critical time.

165
00:12:46,375 --> 00:12:48,405
Production of fighter planes doubled.

166
00:12:48,485 --> 00:12:52,893
A hundred new Spitfires and Hurricanes
a week replenished Dowding's forces.

167
00:12:52,974 --> 00:12:55,844
The minister of aircraft production,
Lord Beaverbrook,

168
00:12:55,928 --> 00:13:00,413
took care to make ordinary people
feel part of the production battle.

169
00:13:00,493 --> 00:13:03,865
My father was a master of propaganda.

170
00:13:03,946 --> 00:13:06,434
There were the pots and pans,

171
00:13:06,517 --> 00:13:09,659
where everyone was asked
to give up pots and pans and railings.

172
00:13:09,739 --> 00:13:11,954
Stanley Baldwin
didn't give up his gates,

173
00:13:12,041 --> 00:13:15,369
but most people gave up all
they could in the way of metal.

174
00:13:15,456 --> 00:13:19,711
The pilots and we all knew you couldn't
make aircraft out of pots and pans,

175
00:13:19,829 --> 00:13:24,424
but it brought the people to realise
that it was a desperate situation.

176
00:13:24,510 --> 00:13:28,875
The response was tremendous. They
had piles and piles of pots and pans -

177
00:13:28,960 --> 00:13:34,056
not knowing what to do with them.
But he was a great propagandist.

178
00:13:34,139 --> 00:13:36,507
(narrator) But where was
the German invasion?

179
00:13:37,055 --> 00:13:38,779
(fanfare)

180
00:13:43,270 --> 00:13:47,100
In June 1940, Hitler had not begun
to think about invading Britain.

181
00:13:47,183 --> 00:13:52,247
He was celebrating his French victory,
and expected Britain to make peace.

182
00:13:52,324 --> 00:13:55,543
Berlin gave him a hero's welcome
when he returned there on July 6

183
00:13:55,624 --> 00:13:58,843
with Admiral Raeder
and his other commanders in chief.

184
00:13:58,923 --> 00:14:02,905
Only the German navy
seemed to have plans for an invasion.

185
00:14:02,990 --> 00:14:05,248
By the time Hitler
began to take an interest,

186
00:14:05,368 --> 00:14:09,046
the army had its own plans
and was critical of the navy's.

187
00:14:11,699 --> 00:14:14,994
Both looked to Göring, the Luftwaffe
chief, to win control of the air -

188
00:14:15,075 --> 00:14:17,027
vital for an invasion.

189
00:14:17,108 --> 00:14:21,549
And Göring believed the Luftwaffe
on its own could knock out Britain.

190
00:14:21,635 --> 00:14:25,891
Arguments between the services
went on for months.

191
00:14:26,469 --> 00:14:28,760
The army at first
wanted to land 40 divisions

192
00:14:28,848 --> 00:14:31,411
on a wide front between
Ramsgate and Lyme Bay,

193
00:14:31,495 --> 00:14:34,714
and press on to a line from Maldon
in Essex to the Severn Estuary,

194
00:14:34,833 --> 00:14:36,785
sealing off London.

195
00:14:36,866 --> 00:14:39,888
This was later scaled down
to a landing by nine divisions

196
00:14:40,012 --> 00:14:43,994
between Folkestone and Brighton,
supported by two airborne divisions -

197
00:14:44,078 --> 00:14:46,490
about 200,000 men in all.

198
00:14:46,649 --> 00:14:49,595
By September, Britain had overcome
her earlier weakness

199
00:14:49,680 --> 00:14:53,859
and had 16 divisions available
in the Southeast.

200
00:14:57,583 --> 00:15:02,330
An invasion fleet from all parts of
Germany assembled in northern ports.

201
00:15:05,064 --> 00:15:07,781
Landing craft were built,
and boats converted

202
00:15:07,865 --> 00:15:10,276
to carry troops and amphibious tanks.

203
00:15:12,392 --> 00:15:15,000
The army thought the fleet too small.

204
00:15:15,077 --> 00:15:18,219
The navy thought even that size fleet
difficult to protect.

205
00:15:18,300 --> 00:15:21,366
Both agreed
that air supremacy was vital.

206
00:15:21,446 --> 00:15:25,472
The invasion, codenamed Operation
Sea Lion, was set for mid-September.

207
00:15:25,551 --> 00:15:30,647
The plans did not impress the Luftwaffe,
on whom everything depended.

208
00:15:30,730 --> 00:15:33,829
(man) In my opinion,
the plan was not serious.

209
00:15:33,914 --> 00:15:40,930
Especially the navy didn't want
to have the responsibility,

210
00:15:41,012 --> 00:15:45,115
and the navy
has asked the air force first of all

211
00:15:45,194 --> 00:15:50,442
to establish the absolute...
the absolute air superiority

212
00:15:50,526 --> 00:15:52,818
over the invasion area.

213
00:15:54,056 --> 00:15:58,192
The preparation the navy did
was not very convincing.

214
00:15:58,276 --> 00:16:03,524
Also, our preparation...
My wing was designated to be

215
00:16:03,647 --> 00:16:07,597
one of the two wings
to be transferred to England,

216
00:16:07,675 --> 00:16:11,658
and our preparations were... ridiculous.

217
00:16:12,202 --> 00:16:15,803
The air force was not
trained and prepared

218
00:16:15,885 --> 00:16:20,097
to conduct an independent air war
over England.

219
00:16:31,884 --> 00:16:34,567
(narrator)
The Luftwaffe's first targets

220
00:16:34,646 --> 00:16:36,937
were merchant convoys
and harbours,

221
00:16:37,024 --> 00:16:41,313
particularly in
the narrow seas of the Channel.

222
00:16:41,398 --> 00:16:43,809
Dover became known as Hellfire Corner.

223
00:16:43,892 --> 00:16:47,689
There was always something for the
newsreel camera or the news reporter -

224
00:16:47,767 --> 00:16:51,215
for instance, Charles Gardner
of the BBC:

225
00:16:52,294 --> 00:16:56,429
(newsreel) Now the Germans are
dive-bombing a convoy out at sea.

226
00:16:56,514 --> 00:16:59,307
There are one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven.

227
00:16:59,391 --> 00:17:02,643
There's one going down
on its target now.

228
00:17:02,729 --> 00:17:05,140
Boom. No, he hasn't hit a single ship.

229
00:17:05,261 --> 00:17:10,204
There are about ten ships in the
convoy, but he hasn't hit a single one.

230
00:17:10,287 --> 00:17:15,350
They come in a steep dive. You can
see the bombs leave the machines.

231
00:17:15,428 --> 00:17:18,111
You can hear our own guns
going like anything now.

232
00:17:18,919 --> 00:17:22,552
There's a fight going on.
You can hear the machine-gun bullets.

233
00:17:22,640 --> 00:17:25,477
That was a bomb, as you may imagine.

234
00:17:25,556 --> 00:17:28,240
There's another bomb dropping.

235
00:17:29,162 --> 00:17:31,344
It's dropped... It missed the convoy.

236
00:17:31,464 --> 00:17:33,755
They haven't hit the convoy
in all this.

237
00:17:35,032 --> 00:17:37,869
We've just hit a Messerschmitt!
That was beautiful.

238
00:17:37,986 --> 00:17:43,125
He's coming right down now. I think
definitely that was that first contest.

239
00:17:43,242 --> 00:17:46,723
Absolute steep dive. I'll just move
round so I can watch him a bit more.

240
00:17:46,810 --> 00:17:49,647
Here he comes.
He's going slap into the sea.

241
00:17:49,726 --> 00:17:51,482
And there he goes - bam!

242
00:17:51,567 --> 00:17:54,557
Oh, boy! I've never seen
anything so good as this.

243
00:17:54,636 --> 00:17:58,892
The RAF fighters
have really got these boys taped.

244
00:18:00,890 --> 00:18:04,687
(narrator) The convoy system was
disrupted, and harbours like Dover h it.

245
00:18:04,765 --> 00:18:07,099
But while the town suffered casualties,

246
00:18:07,182 --> 00:18:11,208
Dowding had not yet been forced
to commit his full fighter strength.

247
00:18:11,287 --> 00:18:13,578
The unique thing about Fighter Command

248
00:18:13,665 --> 00:18:16,961
was that when war broke out
in September 1939...

249
00:18:17,694 --> 00:18:23,597
we had there a system covering
the entire country for air defence.

250
00:18:23,679 --> 00:18:29,123
And that system was based on radar,
or, as we called it in those days, RDF.

251
00:18:29,587 --> 00:18:32,653
We had this chain of radar stations
around the coast,

252
00:18:32,733 --> 00:18:35,450
and they were looking out
up to 100 miles.

253
00:18:35,533 --> 00:18:37,486
And they were feeding, on land lines,

254
00:18:37,605 --> 00:18:42,319
all the information
to the headquarters of Fighter Command.

255
00:18:42,401 --> 00:18:45,238
(Aitken) Radar really won
the Battle of Britain,

256
00:18:45,316 --> 00:18:49,419
because without it we would have been
doing standing patrols -

257
00:18:49,536 --> 00:18:54,523
and with the limited number of aircraft
and pilots, you couldn't have done it.

258
00:18:54,601 --> 00:18:57,394
As it was, we could wait on the ground,

259
00:18:57,478 --> 00:18:59,769
and then radar would watch.

260
00:18:59,857 --> 00:19:04,527
And through the various controls,
we would be told to take off

261
00:19:04,614 --> 00:19:09,436
at a time when the Germans were
massing over Calais or over Abbeville.

262
00:19:09,525 --> 00:19:14,893
And so, therefore, we wasted no petrol,
no time, no energy -

263
00:19:15,011 --> 00:19:18,885
in fact, we could sleep
in between patrols.

264
00:19:18,962 --> 00:19:23,600
And then we'd take off, and we would be
directed towards the German formation,

265
00:19:23,719 --> 00:19:28,204
given height, distance and their
numbers - which was very important.

266
00:19:30,011 --> 00:19:33,383
(narrator) On August 13,
Göring changed his tactics.

267
00:19:33,503 --> 00:19:36,721
He ordered an attack on radar stations
and fighter airfields,

268
00:19:36,802 --> 00:19:40,283
which Fighter Command
was bound to defend.

269
00:19:42,672 --> 00:19:46,927
While German bombers blitzed airfields
that defended London and the Southeast,

270
00:19:47,007 --> 00:19:49,571
escorting fighters
dealt with British fighters

271
00:19:49,654 --> 00:19:53,058
that came up to attack the bombers.

272
00:20:13,018 --> 00:20:16,815
Fighting over England
put the Luftwaffe at a disadvantage.

273
00:20:16,893 --> 00:20:21,105
It was expected, but not equipped,
to win a decisive battle alone.

274
00:20:24,067 --> 00:20:27,820
The German bombers were not designed
to carry a heavy enough bomb load.

275
00:20:27,904 --> 00:20:32,345
German fighters had only enough fuel
to stay over England for half an hour,

276
00:20:32,431 --> 00:20:35,268
whereas the British fighters,
close to their bases,

277
00:20:35,347 --> 00:20:40,213
could land and refuel quickly enough
to rejoin the battle.

278
00:20:41,408 --> 00:20:43,438
(Galland) Our range
was very limited,

279
00:20:43,518 --> 00:20:47,392
and we could only cover
a small part of the British islands,

280
00:20:47,470 --> 00:20:50,187
including London.

281
00:20:50,270 --> 00:20:54,177
But over London, as an example,
we could only stay for ten minutes,

282
00:20:54,260 --> 00:20:56,323
to come back to our bases.

283
00:20:58,365 --> 00:21:04,269
So this limited range
of our fighters and the escort

284
00:21:04,350 --> 00:21:09,752
has been perhaps the... main point...

285
00:21:11,793 --> 00:21:16,780
which avoided an effective
air offensive against Britain.

286
00:21:18,200 --> 00:21:20,567
(narrator)
The Luftwaffe misled its pilots

287
00:21:20,655 --> 00:21:23,416
about the damage
done to British airfields.

288
00:21:23,494 --> 00:21:26,212
They claimed eight
had been virtually destroyed.

289
00:21:26,295 --> 00:21:28,477
In fact, none had been knocked out,

290
00:21:28,559 --> 00:21:31,854
and those damaged
were quickly patched up again.

291
00:21:31,935 --> 00:21:35,655
The German pilots, faced
by resistance they hadn't expected,

292
00:21:35,733 --> 00:21:37,762
became pessimistic about winning.

293
00:21:37,843 --> 00:21:43,440
We fighting crews were convinced
that we couldn't win the battle

294
00:21:43,521 --> 00:21:49,534
and we couldn't force England
to surrender by attacking

295
00:21:49,621 --> 00:21:55,950
without any operation
from the part of the army or the navy.

296
00:21:56,028 --> 00:21:59,934
Therefore, we were asking
that the High Command

297
00:22:00,018 --> 00:22:03,695
should order the invasion -
the Sea Lion.

298
00:22:05,504 --> 00:22:09,301
(narrator) A mere 1,400 British
fighter pilots and their ground crews

299
00:22:09,379 --> 00:22:11,790
stood between Britain and invasion.

300
00:22:11,872 --> 00:22:16,619
Their responsibility was great - too
great, perhaps, to bear thinking about.

301
00:22:16,706 --> 00:22:19,696
The face they showed the world
was dashing and carefree.

302
00:22:19,776 --> 00:22:24,260
(man) I think they took the situation
not the least bit seriously,

303
00:22:24,341 --> 00:22:26,675
from the point of view
of their lives generally.

304
00:22:26,758 --> 00:22:30,009
Some fellows would just
kick a ball around or lie around,

305
00:22:30,134 --> 00:22:36,190
some would sleep, read paperbacks,
listen to the radio -

306
00:22:36,272 --> 00:22:38,258
and that was our life.

307
00:22:43,945 --> 00:22:47,775
I wanted to shoot an plane down, but
I didn't want to shoot a German down.

308
00:22:47,859 --> 00:22:49,659
I really did not.

309
00:22:49,738 --> 00:22:54,987
We did hear stories of Germans
shooting our fellows in parachutes,

310
00:22:55,071 --> 00:22:57,712
and we used to think
that was pretty horrible,

311
00:22:57,795 --> 00:23:00,937
but we weren't sure
whether it was true or not.

312
00:23:01,018 --> 00:23:07,226
I know I had an experience of a German
aircrew getting draped over my own wing.

313
00:23:07,310 --> 00:23:12,448
He'd baled out of a bomber and got
caught on my wing with his parachute.

314
00:23:12,527 --> 00:23:17,546
I was jolly careful to get him off
as easily and as quickly as I could,

315
00:23:17,630 --> 00:23:20,390
by yawing the aeroplane
and shaking him off.

316
00:23:20,469 --> 00:23:23,764
There was no chivalry between
the German air force and the British.

317
00:23:23,883 --> 00:23:27,484
Absolutely none. Not as far as
I was concerned. I hated them.

318
00:23:27,566 --> 00:23:30,785
They were trying to do something to us -
trying to enslave us.

319
00:23:53,999 --> 00:23:55,832
(narrator) The climax of the battle

320
00:23:55,918 --> 00:23:58,406
came at the end of August,
start of September.

321
00:23:58,488 --> 00:24:02,853
Upon the result depended Hitler's
decision to launch his invasion.

322
00:24:02,977 --> 00:24:09,644
But the battle was between a comparative
handful of individuals on either side.

323
00:24:18,553 --> 00:24:21,390
(Aitken) The fights
were rather extraordinary,

324
00:24:21,469 --> 00:24:24,109
because although
there were a lot of aircraft about,

325
00:24:24,231 --> 00:24:29,021
suddenly, when you were fighting
a particular man, the sky became empty.

326
00:24:36,047 --> 00:24:39,037
(Holmes) No one ever considered
that he would be killed.

327
00:24:39,116 --> 00:24:43,143
Death was something which was
just put at the back of your mind.

328
00:24:43,260 --> 00:24:47,897
If it was not, you'd have just got the
jitters about it and been very worried.

329
00:24:48,401 --> 00:24:53,191
If a fellow did go missing, it was just,
"Poor old so-and-so, he's had it,"

330
00:24:53,273 --> 00:24:55,226
and that was that.

331
00:24:58,030 --> 00:25:02,700
Inwardly, of course, you'd feel it
tremendously if you lost a pal.

332
00:25:02,788 --> 00:25:07,043
But you didn't... you didn't
dwell on the subject of death at all.

333
00:25:07,123 --> 00:25:11,945
Sometimes you could tell if a fellow was
going to get killed. He sort of lost it.

334
00:25:14,220 --> 00:25:18,127
My greatest friend was killed.
He was shooting at a Messerschmitt,

335
00:25:18,210 --> 00:25:20,818
and another Messerschmitt
hit him from behind.

336
00:25:20,934 --> 00:25:25,113
I was shouting at him, and you couldn't
do anything - and you saw him go in.

337
00:25:25,193 --> 00:25:28,259
That affected you,
but you had to get on with it.

338
00:25:28,339 --> 00:25:32,474
Your friends affected you deeply.
Terrible. But you couldn't help it.

339
00:25:35,781 --> 00:25:39,077
(narrator) In the last week of August
and the first week of September,

340
00:25:39,157 --> 00:25:42,486
103 of Fighter Command's pilots died.

341
00:25:42,572 --> 00:25:45,791
128 were seriously wounded.

342
00:25:47,713 --> 00:25:52,230
Six key airfields in the Southeast were
put out of action for days at a time.

343
00:25:52,317 --> 00:25:54,531
Against German fighters and bombers,

344
00:25:54,618 --> 00:25:57,641
Britain was now losing fighters
even faster than Germany -

345
00:25:57,726 --> 00:25:59,711
nearly 500 in two weeks.

346
00:26:01,294 --> 00:26:04,393
The last week in August,
the first week in September -

347
00:26:04,478 --> 00:26:07,806
those two weeks were the worst for us,

348
00:26:07,893 --> 00:26:11,067
because by that last week in August,

349
00:26:11,154 --> 00:26:15,136
the Germans had been pounding
the airfields mercilessly,

350
00:26:15,220 --> 00:26:20,622
and 31 August
was probably our worst day.

351
00:26:20,706 --> 00:26:23,729
Fighter Command
was very nearly on its knees.

352
00:26:23,814 --> 00:26:26,181
Dowding was very conscious of that.

353
00:26:26,346 --> 00:26:29,598
What was worrying him was
the constant pounding of the airfields,

354
00:26:29,684 --> 00:26:33,820
and he was wondering
how much longer he could hold out -

355
00:26:33,904 --> 00:26:36,238
when I say "he",
I mean Fighter Command.

356
00:26:36,321 --> 00:26:38,961
Because he was still facing
that big problem

357
00:26:39,045 --> 00:26:41,762
of denying the Germans
air superiority,

358
00:26:41,884 --> 00:26:44,295
and yet they were
knocking airfields to pieces,

359
00:26:44,378 --> 00:26:46,866
with the threat of
knocking out Fighter Command.

360
00:26:46,948 --> 00:26:51,204
On 6 September, the king and queen
visited Fighter Command,

361
00:26:51,283 --> 00:26:53,422
and there were quite a few people

362
00:26:53,508 --> 00:26:57,797
who commented on
how tired Dowding appeared to be.

363
00:26:57,882 --> 00:27:01,483
The day after, 7 September,

364
00:27:01,565 --> 00:27:07,119
an invasion alert was issued -
"invasion imminent" -

365
00:27:07,243 --> 00:27:10,462
and all that day
things were remarkably quiet.

366
00:27:10,542 --> 00:27:14,449
All of us were beginning to wonder
what the devil was going to happen next.

367
00:27:14,532 --> 00:27:17,936
And then, late afternoon,
the Germans launched

368
00:27:18,062 --> 00:27:22,852
what many of the pilots in the air
having to face this onslaught

369
00:27:22,934 --> 00:27:26,459
found to be just about the heaviest
attack they'd ever known.

370
00:27:26,540 --> 00:27:30,872
And then came what Dowding
later described as "the miracle" -

371
00:27:30,952 --> 00:27:34,750
the attack didn't go to the airfields,
it went to London,

372
00:27:34,827 --> 00:27:36,933
and the airfields were spared.

373
00:27:37,014 --> 00:27:39,044
Five minutes to five,

374
00:27:39,124 --> 00:27:41,306
the sirens went.

375
00:27:41,388 --> 00:27:46,210
Walking out onto my veranda,
looking down the river,

376
00:27:46,337 --> 00:27:48,671
the sky was full of planes.

377
00:27:48,754 --> 00:27:53,926
Within a couple of minutes, the bombs
started dropping in the Millwall Dock,

378
00:27:54,010 --> 00:27:56,498
and I could watch 'em.

379
00:27:56,580 --> 00:27:58,839
And it went on
for some considerable time.

380
00:27:58,997 --> 00:28:02,445
On that first Saturday,
they practically obliterated

381
00:28:02,527 --> 00:28:06,280
from the Silvertown Way to Silvertown.

382
00:28:06,363 --> 00:28:09,996
As a matter of fact, the whole of
the Tidal Basin, Custom House,

383
00:28:10,085 --> 00:28:13,914
right up to Silvertown was obliterated -
make no mistake about it.

384
00:28:15,034 --> 00:28:17,794
If it had continued,
that type of bombing,

385
00:28:17,873 --> 00:28:19,520
in the daylight...

386
00:28:19,637 --> 00:28:22,933
It was hitting everything
of consequence -

387
00:28:23,013 --> 00:28:26,843
shipyards, gasworks,

388
00:28:26,927 --> 00:28:30,560
oil firms, everything of consequence.

389
00:28:30,648 --> 00:28:34,630
Nearly all the bombs were dropping
in the proper target area.

390
00:28:35,789 --> 00:28:38,888
(narrator) That night,
250 bombers returned -

391
00:28:38,973 --> 00:28:42,072
the burning docks and warehouses
an unmistakable marker.

392
00:28:42,158 --> 00:28:45,453
But Göring's change of tactics
relieved the pressure.

393
00:28:50,559 --> 00:28:54,007
Fighter Command regrouped.
London burned.

394
00:29:18,489 --> 00:29:21,708
After the raid on September 7,
many rescue workers and firemen

395
00:29:21,788 --> 00:29:24,276
worked 40 hours nonstop.

396
00:29:24,359 --> 00:29:27,578
"Most of us had the wind up
to start with," one of them said,

397
00:29:27,658 --> 00:29:30,986
"but you looked around
and saw the rest doing their job."

398
00:29:49,833 --> 00:29:53,892
On September 15, the Luftwaffe
mounted another major daylight attack,

399
00:29:53,976 --> 00:29:55,962
expecting no opposition.

400
00:29:56,125 --> 00:29:59,605
But this time the Spitfires and
Hurricanes were waiting for them.

401
00:30:51,907 --> 00:30:56,621
On that day, September 15,
56 German planes were shot down.

402
00:30:57,240 --> 00:31:00,339
Britain had retained
command of the air by day.

403
00:31:04,031 --> 00:31:07,479
The Royal Air Force
had won the Battle of Britain.

404
00:31:20,873 --> 00:31:23,404
September 1940.

405
00:31:23,481 --> 00:31:25,467
Now there were no more daylight raids,

406
00:31:25,553 --> 00:31:28,346
and there could be no invasion
before the spring.

407
00:31:28,431 --> 00:31:32,534
But Britain's cities became targets
for the night bombers.

408
00:31:32,612 --> 00:31:36,486
For 76 nights in succession,
London was bombed.

409
00:31:36,564 --> 00:31:39,892
Queuing for shelter at dusk
became an orderly ritual,

410
00:31:39,978 --> 00:31:45,151
the evening alerts, the dawn all-clear,
part of Londoners' lives.

411
00:31:47,997 --> 00:31:50,528
(air-raid siren)

412
00:31:58,278 --> 00:32:00,809
(hum of aeroplane engines)

413
00:32:48,268 --> 00:32:50,559
I used to hear the planes come over,

414
00:32:50,646 --> 00:32:55,011
and they was, in my opinion,
trying to break the backs of the houses.

415
00:32:55,097 --> 00:32:57,628
I'd listen and shudder.
"The next one's mine."

416
00:32:57,705 --> 00:33:02,649
They'd have, say, six bombs.
"One, two, three, four... This is mine."

417
00:33:02,731 --> 00:33:05,721
"No." Over the next one, they'd go,
and miss my house.

418
00:33:05,800 --> 00:33:07,481
That went on all night.

419
00:33:07,565 --> 00:33:12,312
About ten to eight, I said to my wife
and my in-laws, "I'll be off now."

420
00:33:12,399 --> 00:33:17,113
I walked out of the door -
lovely big three-floor houses they were.

421
00:33:17,195 --> 00:33:22,749
I walked up Approach Road, 20 yards
from the church, which was our post,

422
00:33:22,834 --> 00:33:25,475
and suddenly there was a... (whoosh)

423
00:33:25,558 --> 00:33:27,588
Nothing, I heard nothing.

424
00:33:27,668 --> 00:33:30,581
I talked about this
to people afterwards -

425
00:33:30,661 --> 00:33:32,952
the bomb that hit them,
they never heard.

426
00:33:33,039 --> 00:33:36,913
Now, I wonder if the people sitting
here now had that same experience.

427
00:33:36,991 --> 00:33:39,402
The bomb that hit you, you never heard.

428
00:33:39,485 --> 00:33:41,285
And I fell flat on my face.

429
00:33:41,365 --> 00:33:43,350
I picked myself up, I turned round.

430
00:33:43,475 --> 00:33:47,992
All I could see was a grey curtain
hanging in the middle of a wide road -

431
00:33:48,078 --> 00:33:50,762
about twice as wide as this pub.

432
00:33:50,841 --> 00:33:53,787
There was just
a brownish-grey curtain hanging there.

433
00:33:54,907 --> 00:33:56,937
Come, come

434
00:33:57,017 --> 00:33:58,818
Come and make eyes at me

435
00:33:58,897 --> 00:34:01,079
Down at the Old Bull and Bush

436
00:34:01,161 --> 00:34:02,764
La-la-la, la-la

437
00:34:02,849 --> 00:34:04,572
Come, come

438
00:34:04,652 --> 00:34:06,485
Drink some port wine with me

439
00:34:06,570 --> 00:34:09,134
Down at the Old Bull and Bush

440
00:34:10,177 --> 00:34:13,854
La-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la-la-la-la

441
00:34:13,936 --> 00:34:17,308
Just let me hold your hand, dear

442
00:34:17,811 --> 00:34:19,459
Do, do

443
00:34:19,576 --> 00:34:21,299
Come and have a drink or two

444
00:34:21,379 --> 00:34:24,521
Down at the Old Bull and Bush,
Bush, Bush!

445
00:34:25,062 --> 00:34:27,047
(man) No matter what shelter
you went in,

446
00:34:27,134 --> 00:34:32,230
there was always someone there
who would provide the entertainment

447
00:34:32,390 --> 00:34:34,921
to sort of take away the strain.

448
00:34:35,881 --> 00:34:40,595
(narrator) Underground stations, it was
decided, must not be used as shelters.

449
00:34:40,677 --> 00:34:45,085
But people simply took them over
and the authorities had to accept it.

450
00:34:45,741 --> 00:34:47,235
(woman) We was all singing,

451
00:34:47,314 --> 00:34:50,183
we was all happy -
just like there was no war at all.

452
00:34:50,268 --> 00:34:51,446
There was a canteen.

453
00:34:51,534 --> 00:34:55,637
I used to sing as well and cheer
people up when the bombs was going.

454
00:34:55,716 --> 00:35:00,386
Until one night, it was very bad, and I
was praying for the big guns to start.

455
00:35:05,038 --> 00:35:09,949
I was talking to a gunnery sergeant
who had been stationed in Hyde Park,

456
00:35:10,026 --> 00:35:14,391
and he told us without any hesitation -
and he cried when he told us:

457
00:35:14,476 --> 00:35:17,236
"When we was sent into London,

458
00:35:17,353 --> 00:35:20,954
we simply elevated our guns
to its maximum and fired."

459
00:35:21,113 --> 00:35:24,910
"We knew that every shell we pumped up
had no chance of hitting a plane,

460
00:35:25,026 --> 00:35:28,093
but don't tell me
it didn't give you courage."

461
00:35:28,172 --> 00:35:32,460
And there's not a person sitting round
this table, I think, can say it didn't -

462
00:35:32,546 --> 00:35:36,376
once they heard those guns firing,
they thought, "Good, we've got 'em now."

463
00:35:36,459 --> 00:35:40,256
But they only knew that it was the
morale - and that's all it did to 'em.

464
00:35:40,334 --> 00:35:44,316
But the bombs just had to come down.
There was nothing to stop them.

465
00:35:55,373 --> 00:35:56,976
(narrator) For 76 mornings,

466
00:35:57,061 --> 00:36:00,236
rescue squads dug through rubble,
searching for survivors.

467
00:36:00,322 --> 00:36:05,036
(man) A bomb dropped on
a block of flats, about four storeys,

468
00:36:05,156 --> 00:36:07,490
and it took the whole front out.

469
00:36:07,573 --> 00:36:11,206
And they said, "There's an old chap
up there. He won't go in a shelter."

470
00:36:11,294 --> 00:36:15,168
So we go up, and when we got up there,
the old chap was snoring his head off,

471
00:36:15,246 --> 00:36:20,232
about 20 empty bottles round his bed,
and the bed's nearly out in the street!

472
00:36:20,310 --> 00:36:22,765
And he never woke up then!

473
00:36:27,599 --> 00:36:32,662
We saw an old lady staggering around,
and we said, "You'll have to come out."

474
00:36:32,740 --> 00:36:34,421
She came out
and all she had on

475
00:36:34,505 --> 00:36:38,030
was half of what
should've been a nightdress.

476
00:36:38,610 --> 00:36:42,287
I said, "You'll have to put something
on, make yourself a bit decent."

477
00:36:42,370 --> 00:36:45,850
She was about 80-odd,
and she was completely in a daze.

478
00:36:45,976 --> 00:36:51,573
She said, "I'll go and get something,"
and she came out with her hat on!

479
00:36:57,102 --> 00:37:00,899
(narrator) People somehow got to work
through a nightmare of upended buses,

480
00:37:00,977 --> 00:37:03,923
cratered roads, bombed railways.

481
00:37:04,007 --> 00:37:06,299
(man on radio) London calling...

482
00:37:06,386 --> 00:37:10,904
(narrator) Radio reporters told America
and the world that London could take it.

483
00:37:10,990 --> 00:37:13,554
The spirit of Londoners
won sympathy and help.

484
00:37:13,637 --> 00:37:16,550
But the United States remained neutral.

485
00:37:17,512 --> 00:37:22,149
While Britain stood alone,
from September 1940 to May 1941,

486
00:37:22,231 --> 00:37:26,486
40,000 people were killed in raids -
half of them Londoners.

487
00:37:27,947 --> 00:37:30,478
Hundreds of thousands of people
were homeless,

488
00:37:30,556 --> 00:37:33,960
eating, living,
sleeping in rest centres.

489
00:37:35,428 --> 00:37:38,680
Clothing and everything else
had vanished with their home.

490
00:37:38,804 --> 00:37:40,485
But not morale.

491
00:37:40,569 --> 00:37:44,977
To be clean, you couldn't very well say,
"I'm going to have a bath today,"

492
00:37:45,058 --> 00:37:48,855
cos you was afraid the warning
would go halfway through it.

493
00:37:48,933 --> 00:37:53,068
So you'd have a bowl of water, have a
wash and perhaps get your neck done,

494
00:37:53,153 --> 00:37:55,520
and run and take all your things
in the shelter -

495
00:37:55,646 --> 00:37:57,632
finish your bath perhaps the next day.

496
00:37:57,718 --> 00:38:01,515
Never actually have a bath properly.
Step in and step out.

497
00:38:01,593 --> 00:38:04,844
You get used to it.
You can get used to anything.

498
00:38:04,931 --> 00:38:11,489
It was not an uncommon sight to see:
"No windows but plenty of spirit."

499
00:38:11,606 --> 00:38:15,971
Or, "Sorry we've got no front door.
Don't trouble to knock, just come in."

500
00:38:16,057 --> 00:38:19,505
And you'd see these funny little notices
put up outside a door.

501
00:38:19,624 --> 00:38:23,760
This was the sort of thing that made
you think there was something in it.

502
00:38:23,845 --> 00:38:27,718
The more you saw it, the more you felt
encouraged to be able to go out.

503
00:38:27,796 --> 00:38:32,783
Once you'd gone out to go on to a job
and your family were left behind,

504
00:38:32,860 --> 00:38:35,468
you always felt that somehow:

505
00:38:35,546 --> 00:38:37,531
"The Joneses or the Smiths up the road,

506
00:38:37,618 --> 00:38:41,753
if anything happens at home,
they'll look after 'em."

507
00:38:45,482 --> 00:38:49,160
(narrator) Factories went on working,
by night as well as by day.

508
00:38:49,242 --> 00:38:52,613
But night workers were
constantly interrupted by raids.

509
00:38:52,695 --> 00:38:57,060
There was no real defence
against German bombing at night.

510
00:38:57,145 --> 00:39:01,019
Fighter Command's helplessness
worried its chief, Dowding.

511
00:39:01,097 --> 00:39:05,428
I once went to Redhill with him when
the bombers were coming over London.

512
00:39:05,547 --> 00:39:10,108
There was a squadron commanded
by a fellow called Jimmy Little.

513
00:39:10,189 --> 00:39:15,482
He said to me in the car going down,
"Max, I hold my head in my hands

514
00:39:15,560 --> 00:39:20,624
at the thought of people being bombed
and I cannot do anything about it."

515
00:39:20,701 --> 00:39:23,068
(narrator) To the relief
of the authorities,

516
00:39:23,157 --> 00:39:26,561
Buckingham Palace was bombed
as well as East London.

517
00:39:26,648 --> 00:39:30,979
Now it could be seen that king, queen
and people were all in it together.

518
00:39:33,477 --> 00:39:37,917
King George and Queen Elizabeth won
respect by touring the blitzed areas.

519
00:39:38,004 --> 00:39:42,215
They had come to the throne in the wake
of the Duke of Windsor's abdication.

520
00:39:42,301 --> 00:39:46,785
Now, for the first time, they emerged
as popular figures in their own right.

521
00:39:46,866 --> 00:39:48,851
(cheering)

522
00:39:49,935 --> 00:39:53,765
Churchill too, with exuberance,
persuaded most political opponents

523
00:39:53,848 --> 00:39:55,954
to forget his past.

524
00:39:56,035 --> 00:39:59,712
(man) The average East Londoner
didn't care twopence for Churchill,

525
00:39:59,795 --> 00:40:01,519
as a man or a politician,

526
00:40:01,598 --> 00:40:05,505
but the man who filled up
Chamberlain's place,

527
00:40:05,588 --> 00:40:08,043
he was a leader.

528
00:40:08,120 --> 00:40:12,561
And every time he opened his mouth,
he inspired confidence into the people -

529
00:40:12,647 --> 00:40:15,331
whether they accepted him
as a Conservative...

530
00:40:15,409 --> 00:40:20,124
But he was there, he was for 'em,
and he was against the common enemy.

531
00:40:22,584 --> 00:40:26,141
(narrator) But sometimes
he got a mixed reception.

532
00:40:26,228 --> 00:40:28,946
(man) I remember,
just off Green Street,

533
00:40:29,029 --> 00:40:31,560
an avenue where Churchill
came down.

534
00:40:31,638 --> 00:40:35,163
There was a devil of a great crater
as big as this pub.

535
00:40:35,244 --> 00:40:39,762
There were crowds of women trying to
get things out of the shattered houses.

536
00:40:40,615 --> 00:40:45,438
Churchill, after having a look round,
he said, "We can take it."

537
00:40:45,526 --> 00:40:50,316
And the women told him what they could
take, in no unmistakable manner.

538
00:40:50,398 --> 00:40:54,654
They said, "We're the ones that are
taking it - you're out of the way."

539
00:41:05,322 --> 00:41:08,268
(narrator) December 29, 1940.

540
00:41:08,353 --> 00:41:13,983
German planes scattering incendiary
bombs set the City of London ablaze.

541
00:41:14,069 --> 00:41:17,627
There were 1,500 fires
in and around the city.

542
00:41:17,714 --> 00:41:21,696
St Paul's Cathedral
was surrounded by fire.

543
00:41:24,965 --> 00:41:28,031
(man) You could see the fire of London.

544
00:41:28,111 --> 00:41:31,559
60 miles away, you could see the fire.

545
00:41:37,740 --> 00:41:41,799
(woman) That night I was in a shelter,
and it was burning above me.

546
00:41:41,884 --> 00:41:45,332
We all had to get out,
and we wasn't panicking a bit.

547
00:41:45,413 --> 00:41:49,669
And we had to run
to the top of Commercial Road,

548
00:41:49,748 --> 00:41:53,077
to a factory that had a shelter
down below in the basement.

549
00:41:53,163 --> 00:41:56,491
And as we were running along,
there was fires all burning around.

550
00:41:56,577 --> 00:42:00,102
I could feel the heat on the floor -
the puddles were hot.

551
00:42:00,222 --> 00:42:04,510
And in the shelter, we stood all night,
sleeping on each other's shoulders.

552
00:42:04,596 --> 00:42:09,310
I stood all night sleeping
on somebody else's shoulder.

553
00:42:13,573 --> 00:42:18,134
(man) Eventually, we used
so much water, we ran out of it.

554
00:42:18,215 --> 00:42:21,357
And there we stood,
letting the fires burn -

555
00:42:21,438 --> 00:42:24,809
and we couldn't do nothing about it.

556
00:42:31,336 --> 00:42:34,402
(narrator) The heart of
the City of London was destroyed,

557
00:42:34,482 --> 00:42:37,046
but St Paul's survived.

558
00:42:38,894 --> 00:42:42,527
Manchester, Coventry, Birmingham,
Swansea, Liverpool and many more

559
00:42:42,615 --> 00:42:46,292
shared London's ordeal - all were
within reach of the German air force,

560
00:42:46,375 --> 00:42:48,590
with bases in France
and the Low Countries.

561
00:42:48,677 --> 00:42:52,703
It was more difficult for British
bombers to reach German cities.

562
00:42:52,782 --> 00:42:58,379
The government looked for some other way
of carrying the war to the enemy.

563
00:42:58,460 --> 00:43:02,366
We decided the only place
where we could fight the enemy

564
00:43:02,450 --> 00:43:07,622
was the North African desert,
the Middle East theatre generally.

565
00:43:07,706 --> 00:43:11,765
There was nowhere else. We couldn't
hope to make a landing in France

566
00:43:11,849 --> 00:43:16,443
in any foreseeable future, and therefore
couldn't injure the Germans that way.

567
00:43:16,530 --> 00:43:20,404
So the two alternatives...
They weren't alternatives.

568
00:43:20,481 --> 00:43:25,119
The two possibles were bombing,
and fighting in the Middle East.

569
00:43:25,200 --> 00:43:27,960
And that is why
from those very early days

570
00:43:28,077 --> 00:43:33,937
we began to push, agitate,
ask for more armour in the Middle East.

571
00:43:34,024 --> 00:43:38,694
We had to take the armour out of
the line, out of the defence of Britain.

572
00:43:38,820 --> 00:43:41,919
There was no other way of doing it.

573
00:43:42,426 --> 00:43:43,997
(narrator) On December 10, 1940,

574
00:43:44,114 --> 00:43:47,639
two Commonwealth divisions
under General Wavell

575
00:43:47,720 --> 00:43:51,670
attacked the big Italian army
in North Africa.

576
00:43:53,360 --> 00:43:57,496
Slightly to their own surprise,
they advanced with great speed.

577
00:43:58,501 --> 00:44:00,530
Fortress after fortress was taken.

578
00:44:00,611 --> 00:44:02,750
100,000 prisoners were captured.

579
00:44:02,874 --> 00:44:06,475
Now there seemed to be a chance
to get at the main enemy, Germany -

580
00:44:06,596 --> 00:44:09,770
through Yugoslavia and Greece.

581
00:44:09,857 --> 00:44:13,457
We did think that if it were possible

582
00:44:13,540 --> 00:44:21,822
to bring certain Balkan countries
into conflict with Hitler,

583
00:44:21,903 --> 00:44:26,541
the consequences of that
might be really unforeseeable -

584
00:44:26,661 --> 00:44:28,570
couldn't predict the result.

585
00:44:28,655 --> 00:44:32,944
The view of the War Cabinet
and the Defence Committee

586
00:44:33,029 --> 00:44:38,016
was that, if the Greeks were going to
defend themselves against the Germans,

587
00:44:38,093 --> 00:44:41,268
we should bring them what help we could.

588
00:44:41,393 --> 00:44:43,073
And Dill and I were sent out,

589
00:44:43,196 --> 00:44:47,222
after Wavell's victory,
to Cairo to look into this business.

590
00:44:47,301 --> 00:44:52,015
When we got there, Wavell said, "I hope
you won't mind what I'm going to say."

591
00:44:52,096 --> 00:44:55,119
"I didn't think I ought to waste time -

592
00:44:55,204 --> 00:44:58,117
I've begun the movement of troops
and the concentration

593
00:44:58,196 --> 00:45:00,302
to enable us to go to Greece."

594
00:45:00,383 --> 00:45:04,442
(narrator) The landing in Greece
was meant to forestall a German attack.

595
00:45:04,527 --> 00:45:07,930
To many Greeks,
it seemed likely to hasten it.

596
00:45:08,018 --> 00:45:10,123
They had held their own against Italy,

597
00:45:10,243 --> 00:45:13,571
but when the Germans attacked
on April 6, 1941,

598
00:45:13,657 --> 00:45:16,221
Greece was overwhelmed in three weeks.

599
00:45:16,305 --> 00:45:19,251
So was Yugoslavia,
which had joined the Allies.

600
00:45:19,335 --> 00:45:23,394
50,000 Commonwealth troops
were evacuated.

601
00:45:23,479 --> 00:45:26,621
One has to admit that...

602
00:45:27,737 --> 00:45:31,338
we didn't obtain
the objectives we'd hoped for.

603
00:45:31,420 --> 00:45:35,479
We weren't able to conduct,
with the help of the Yugoslavs,

604
00:45:35,602 --> 00:45:39,322
any effective campaign in the Balkans.

605
00:45:39,400 --> 00:45:42,881
Turkey, it is true,
remained a defensive pad,

606
00:45:42,968 --> 00:45:47,376
but we lost Greece
and lost many men - brave men -

607
00:45:47,457 --> 00:45:49,519
and more were captured.

608
00:45:50,219 --> 00:45:53,438
So in that sense,
the balance sheet was much against us.

609
00:45:53,518 --> 00:45:57,807
And it was a depressing time,
no question of that.

610
00:45:57,892 --> 00:46:00,532
(narrator) By May 1941,
Germany and her allies

611
00:46:00,616 --> 00:46:04,216
controlled most of Continental Europe.

612
00:46:04,299 --> 00:46:07,245
And in North Africa,
a small German force under Rommel

613
00:46:07,330 --> 00:46:10,090
had recaptured
nearly all the British gains.

614
00:46:10,207 --> 00:46:13,732
The British tried to hold Crete
as a naval base.

615
00:46:19,568 --> 00:46:21,216
With complete command of the air,

616
00:46:21,295 --> 00:46:24,361
the Germans attacked Crete
with 16,000 parachutists -

617
00:46:24,440 --> 00:46:29,307
the first large-scale airborne assault
in the history of warfare.

618
00:46:30,234 --> 00:46:34,903
In spite of heavy losses, they gained
a foothold on a vital airfield, Maleme,

619
00:46:34,991 --> 00:46:37,784
which meant that
more troops could be flown in.

620
00:46:57,051 --> 00:46:58,577
Helped by intensive bombing,

621
00:46:58,662 --> 00:47:03,103
the Germans were able to advance
against a bigger Commonwealth force.

622
00:47:03,726 --> 00:47:07,054
Once again, air power won the battle.

623
00:47:07,140 --> 00:47:10,621
Commonwealth losses:
13,000 killed, wounded or captured.

624
00:47:10,708 --> 00:47:15,422
And another evacuation to add
to the list of Norway, France, Greece.

625
00:47:15,504 --> 00:47:19,715
The British people wondered
how much more they would have to take.

626
00:47:19,801 --> 00:47:23,554
(Colville) Churchill thought
Crete should be held at all costs.

627
00:47:23,637 --> 00:47:27,162
If we lost Crete, we lost our base
in the Eastern Mediterranean -

628
00:47:27,244 --> 00:47:29,229
our naval base and our air base.

629
00:47:29,891 --> 00:47:33,142
And he kept on
telegraphing to Wavell, saying:

630
00:47:33,229 --> 00:47:39,863
"Surely you can spare just a dozen tanks
for the defence of Maleme airfield",

631
00:47:39,942 --> 00:47:44,383
the chief airfield in Crete,
"against German paratroops."

632
00:47:44,469 --> 00:47:47,077
And Wavell replied
that he had no tanks -

633
00:47:47,155 --> 00:47:52,174
they were all having their tracks mended
or their engines greased or something -

634
00:47:52,296 --> 00:47:55,166
and that he couldn't spare even a dozen.

635
00:47:55,250 --> 00:47:58,545
Well, Crete was lost.
It was a great disaster -

636
00:47:58,626 --> 00:48:02,030
upset everybody in the House
of Commons, upset the country.

637
00:48:02,117 --> 00:48:07,136
It was a low point for us in the war,
in the spring of 1941.

638
00:48:07,220 --> 00:48:12,435
I used to be up
until 2:30 in the morning,

639
00:48:12,514 --> 00:48:16,999
broadcasting to America
and the Dominions and so on.

640
00:48:17,080 --> 00:48:22,481
And I'd snatch
some pretty dicey sort of sleep

641
00:48:22,566 --> 00:48:25,861
in the basement of Broadcasting House.

642
00:48:25,942 --> 00:48:31,310
I'd come out in the morning,
and then I'd walk around, and I'd think:

643
00:48:31,390 --> 00:48:36,333
"I don't think there can be much more
of this, because everything's going."

644
00:48:36,454 --> 00:48:39,553
On those mornings, you thought,
"Another two weeks of this

645
00:48:39,638 --> 00:48:42,398
and there'll be nothing around here
but rubble."

646
00:48:48,769 --> 00:48:51,103
(narrator) On May 10, 1941,

647
00:48:51,186 --> 00:48:54,405
London suffered its most destructive
night raid of the war.

648
00:48:54,485 --> 00:48:57,966
Over 3,000 people
were killed or injured.

649
00:49:00,317 --> 00:49:03,383
Hundreds of fires had to be left
to burn themselves out.

650
00:49:03,501 --> 00:49:07,407
There seemed no end in sight
to the slaughter and destruction.

651
00:49:07,491 --> 00:49:12,281
But although Londoners didn't know,
it was the turning point.

652
00:49:12,363 --> 00:49:15,124
In April, '41,

653
00:49:15,202 --> 00:49:19,949
Hitler assembled
all the commanders in France.

654
00:49:21,149 --> 00:49:24,629
And... during two hours,

655
00:49:24,717 --> 00:49:31,919
he talked to us about
the part two of the Battle of Britain.

656
00:49:33,349 --> 00:49:37,298
And... he told us later -

657
00:49:37,377 --> 00:49:42,593
two of us,
namely my friend Mölders and myself -

658
00:49:44,129 --> 00:49:50,458
that it has only been in order to
camouflage the offensive against Russia.

659
00:49:51,265 --> 00:49:53,404
This has been in April, '41.

660
00:49:54,411 --> 00:49:57,707
And the raid on 10 May

661
00:49:57,825 --> 00:50:01,884
can only be considered
as a camouflage of the...

662
00:50:03,542 --> 00:50:07,721
beginning of the Russian campaign.

663
00:50:11,637 --> 00:50:14,474
(narrator) Among the victims
of the raid on May 10

664
00:50:14,553 --> 00:50:16,047
was the House of Commons.

665
00:50:16,125 --> 00:50:19,999
For exactly a year,
a year of disappointment and defeat,

666
00:50:20,077 --> 00:50:22,718
the Commons had
sustained Churchill in office.

667
00:50:22,801 --> 00:50:25,485
But the important battle had been won.

668
00:50:25,563 --> 00:50:28,356
Britain had survived.

669
00:50:28,441 --> 00:50:30,317
Now it was Russia's turn.
