== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==
(narrator) No country, no people
suffered so terribly in the war
as the Soviet Union.
Nowhere else are
the memories of war so alive today,
and so profound.
The German invasion
brought about a catastrophe
which it seemed at first
no nation could survive.
In the siege of Leningrad alone,
which lasted for over two years,
more human beings died
than the total war dead of Britain
and the United States combined.
Yet it was here that Hitler was broken.
The Russian people faced
the possibility that they might perish,
and overcame it.
We are hoping for the victory.
We are quite sure
that the victory will come sometime,
and we hoped that
our hardships would end.
(narrator)
Kharkov, under German occupation, 1942.
Hitler had written in Mein Kampf:
"The colossal empire in the east
is ripe for dissolution."
"And the end of Jewish domination
in Russia
will also be the end of Russia
as a state."
The Soviet system was to be demolished.
But there was more. It was in Russia
that Hitler would find Lebensraum -
new territory for German colonisation.
The Soviet peoples
would be treated as mere natives
in a German colonial empire.
Their cities would be Germanised
or razed to the ground.
They would be pedlars,
backward peasants,
domestic servants, labourers.
Communists and intellectuals
were exterminated.
The least sign of defiance
brought instant reprisal.
(speaking Russian)
(interpreter) The occupiers
were harsh, very harsh,
especially in those areas
where the partisans were active.
In the Ukraine, 511 villages
were burnt down by the Nazis
before the population could escape.
In one village, Pisk, near Kiev,
which was totally razed to the ground,
babies were thrown into the fire.
(narrator) Before the war,
the regions now occupied by the Germans
had produced nearly three quarters
of the country's coal and iron,
a third of its beef and grain,
almost all its sugar.
By autumn 1941, the Germans controlled
what had been the industrial and
agricultural heart of the Soviet Union.
The invaders found that
the Russians had tried to destroy
everything they had to leave behind.
Villages burned, the summer harvest
flamed in the fields around them.
By that autumn,
the Germans had advanced for 600 miles
over scorched earth.
In some of the Baltic republics,
which had only been annexed
by the Soviet Union a year before,
the Germans were made welcome
by local nationalists.
In parts of the Ukraine,
some of the peasants made the
traditional offering of bread and salt.
The bodies of nationalists shot by
Soviet security at the last moment
were brought out
and carried through the streets.
For a brief moment, it seemed to some
that these submerged nations
might become
willing partners of the Nazis.
Communists were hunted down.
And in all the places
the Nazis occupied,
the round-up of the Jews began.
In the path of the German,
Russia seemed to be crumbling away.
Stalin had the defeated commander
of the Western Front and his staff
arrested and shot.
Monuments of Soviet construction,
even the Dnieper Dam,
the very symbol of the Five-Year Plans,
had to be blown up and abandoned.
Locomotives were wrecked,
though they were needed as never before,
for there now began an evacuation
which in the end was to save Russia
and change the course of the war.
1500 factories moved on 18,000 trains
with over a million workers
to the safety of eastern Russia
and the Urals.
One witness said:
"It was as if the earth tilted up
and everything human or mechanical
rolled from west to east."
(speaking Russian)
(interpreter)
There was no factory when we arrived.
There were only storehouses
where materials were kept.
We began by emptying the stores
and clearing the land around it.
We were working up to 14 hours a day.
(narrator) In bleak places,
lacking food or sleep,
the Russians reconstructed a new war
industry beyond the reach of the Nazis.
When we emptied the storehouses,
the machinery arrived.
Where the warehouses used to be,
we built a new factory.
(patriotic Russian song)
(narrator) Unlike the Germans,
the Russians, from the first hour,
waged a total war.
Every pair of hands
was set to the machines
as the men were drafted
into the battles of the west.
War work strained everyone to the heart.
11 to 15 hours a day, rations short,
worry about a husband or a son
at the front,
exhaustion like a permanent illness.
But for the camera,
they wore a cheerful, determined face.
Now the Germans
were breaking through to Leningrad,
Russia's second city
and capital of the revolution.
(Russian marching song)
The workers were given rifles.
Harking back to the days of revolution,
Leningrad's leaders encouraged
the whole city to stand and fight.
Untrained,
they marched out to face the panzers
within sight
of their own factory chimneys.
The chance to get non-combatants
out of Leningrad was missed.
Anyway, most families preferred to stay.
My husband,
he got two places on a plane,
and he asked me suddenly
to take the child and go with him,
but I refused because
I couldn't leave my mother
and his mother, my mother-in-law,
here in the besieged city.
So I told him
to take the old lady with him
and I remained in Leningrad
with my mother and child.
(narrator) In September,
the German ring closed.
Over two and half million people
were trapped in the city,
400,000 of them children.
Leningrad's only link with Russia
was across Lake Ladoga.
The greatest of all sieges
was beginning.
Now Stalin intervened.
Marshal Voroshilov,
in command of Leningrad, was sacked.
In his place was sent
Marshal Georgi Zhukov,
who was to become
one of the great commanders of the war.
His deputy was the hard and resourceful
Andrei Zhdanov,
Leningrad's Communist Party chief.
Leningrad soon felt
the new team's determination.
Outside the city,
Zhukov threatened that anyone
who retreated further would be shot.
Inside, the security forces
hunted down spies and defeatists.
Zhdanov's men ended the wastage of food,
mobilising everybody
for the city's defence.
Every major building was mined
in case the Germans broke in.
But the German attempt
to take Leningrad by storm failed.
(siren)
Berlin ordered: "The Führer has decided
to raze the city of Petersburg
from the face of the earth."
"There is no reason for the
future existence of this large city."
The Leningraders were to be bombarded
and starved to death.
Day after day, the bombers came over.
German gunners could see the spires
of Leningrad from their lines.
Their shells could strike
every district, every street.
Lake Ladoga remained
the only gap in the enemy ring.
When it froze, an ice road for supplies
was built across its surface.
Trucks fell through the ice
or were destroyed by air attack.
The ice road could bring too little in
and take too few civilians out
to keep Leningrad
from the onset of starvation.
Everything was running out.
The trams and buses stopped.
In the darkness and intense cold
of the North Russian winter,
there was no longer heating
or electric light.
Workers, half-conscious with hunger,
kept the arms factories turning,
even when shells had torn off the roof.
Tanks of raw, unpainted steel drove
out of the factory into the front line.
Bread was now made with
sweepings, cattle-cake, sawdust.
People ate soap, linseed oil,
the paste for wallpaper.
Housewives and children
got only four and half ounces
of this "bread" a day.
Frozen and silent,
Leningrad refused to die.
The libraries stayed open.
People took inspiration
from the new literature of the blockade.
(Olga) Poetry was, for us,
a great force that kept us alive.
(narrator)
"If what they say of Leningrad is true,
the tears have frozen
in the people's eyes."
"We cry no longer, for no tears
could quench our burning hate."
"And hate is our only course."
"The guarantee of life,
the cure for grief,
the one uniting,
warming, guiding force."
And the end of November,
December and January
were the most tragic of times.
Firstly, it was cold - minus 40.
Then the famine, the hunger, began to...
to... to be felt.
And people began to starve
and to die from cold.
(narrator) The siege went on.
There were few ways
to hit back at the Germans.
One was with naval guns
from the warships trapped in the port.
On land, small raiding parties
penetrated behind the German trenches.
They cut supply lines,
they captured prisoners
and collected information.
They descended on collaborators
and tried them on the spot.
January 1942.
About 4,000 people
were dying in Leningrad each day.
(Olga) When I went to the shops
to receive my ration for my family,
if I passed on the way there two bodies,
on the way back there were four.
(narrator) Outside the ring, the
Russians fought to loosen the blockade
and to speed up the pitifully slow
convoys across the frozen lake.
But there was no major offensive
to break the siege ring, and no airlift.
The battles before Moscow
had first call on men and equipment.
Spring brought new fears.
The murderous cold slackened,
but melting snowdrifts
revealed thousands of corpses
in the streets and yards.
A campaign was launched
to clean up the city.
There was no epidemic.
Now the ice road was melting.
Although there would be a difficult time
before the lake was clear for ships,
the mood in Leningrad
was turning confident.
(Olga) When the sun began to shine,
then we began to clean
and to wash.
Of course,
now we had water in our homes.
We began to feel normal again.
(narrator) The city council dared
to send a few trams back on the streets.
(Olga) We greeted the tram as an
old forgotten friend coming back to us.
I remember I clapped my hands when
I saw the tram running along Liteiny.
(narrator) The survivors felt stronger.
Their rations were increased.
Squads of volunteers went from
house to house bringing help to families
who, in the winter, had almost
lost contact with the city outside.
Children who should have been evacuated
eight months before
were taken by ship across Lake Ladoga.
The ships brought back
troops and munitions
to relieve the gaunt men
in the trenches.
Leningrad began to look more like
a military base.
The worst of the siege was over.
Though the bombardment went on,
it now made sense to repair the damage.
Peat was dug for fuel
against the next winter.
Schoolchildren and professors of botany
helped to plant every open space
with vegetables.
There were no worries
about food for the Germans
occupying the prairies of the Ukraine.
For 50 years, German expansionists
had looked to this region
to free Germany
from dependence on imports by sea.
General Manstein said, "A large part of
the population will have to go hungry."
"Nothing, out of
a misguided sense of humanity,
may be given to the population,
unless they are in the service
of the German Wehrmacht."
In Kiev, the Ukrainian capital,
plans to win over local nationalists
with the promise of an anti-Russian
puppet state never got off the ground.
They were brushed aside
by the army and the SS.
The reality was
work under German overseers
or deportation to the Reich.
Each village
learned the price of defiance.
In Moscow in early 1942
there was confidence.
The winter fighting had revealed
that the Germans were no more invincible
than Napoleon had been.
But it seemed to Russians
that they bore the burden
of the war against Fascism alone
and that the West was not doing enough.
When Stalin began to call for
a second front, a landing in the west,
the people joined willingly
in the meetings organised to support it.
Molotov, the foreign minister,
was told by Western diplomats
that though they admired
the heroism of the Red Army,
a second front was not yet practical.
Stalin didn't believe them.
(speaking Russian)
Stalin was in direct command of an army
becoming harder and more formidable
every day.
But the Russians did not pretend
to be immune to grief.
Tens of thousands
knew this poem by heart...
"Wait for me, and I'll return."
"Only, wait very hard."
"Wait when you are filled with sorrow
as you watch the yellow rain."
"Wait when the winds
sweep the snowdrifts."
"Wait in the sweltering heat."
"Wait when others have stopped waiting,
forgetting their yesterdays."
"Wait even when from afar
no letters come to you."
"Wait even when
others are tired of waiting."
my mother and son think I am no more,
and when friends sit around the fire
drinking to my memory."
"Wait, and do not hurry
to drink to my memory too."
"Wait, for I'll return,
defying every death."
"And let those who do not wait
say that I was lucky."
"They never will understand
that in the midst of death
you with your waiting saved me."
"Only you and I will know
how I survived."
"It's because you waited,
as no one else did."
There were still disasters to come.
In May, the Germans beat off
a Russian offensive near Kharkov.
As the Red Army advanced,
the panzers cut round its flanks.
The Soviet commanders
begged to be allowed to pull back
before it was too late,
but Stalin, pushing advice aside,
forbade them to retreat.
The German pincers closed.
Most of the men of three Russian armies
were forced to lay down their arms.
In the whole war, over five million
Russian soldiers were taken prisoner.
Less than two million survived.
For the British especially,
the Russians were now
"Our gallant Soviet ally."
But, at first, help could only come
through the Arctic convoys
heading for Murmansk and Archangel
through the killing ground of the
German U-boats, bombers and warships.
In July 1942,
this one convoy lost 80% of its ships.
But the courage of British seamen
could not make the convoys carry enough
for Russia's gigantic needs.
1942 was the year of deep war -
defeat fought off,
but as yet no sign of victory.
This was a time of bitter endurance,
a season for learning to bear
disappointment and loss.
Once, it seemed possible
that German soldiers
were only brother workers in uniform,
but now Soviet writers
spoke in words of hate.
"One can bear anything -
the plague, hunger and death -
but one cannot bear the Germans."
"One cannot bear these fish-eyed oafs
contemptuously snorting
at everything Russian."
"We cannot live as long
as these grey-green slugs are alive."
"Today there are no books,
today there are no stars in the sky."
"Today there is only one thought -
kill the Germans."
"Kill them all
and dig them into the earth."
"Then we can go to sleep."
"Then we can think again
of life and books
and girls and happiness."
"We shall kill them all,
but we must do it quickly or
they will desecrate the whole of Russia
and torture to death
millions more people."
As the Soviet soldiers advanced,
they found what Germans
had been doing to civilians.
(priest chanting)
The churches were full once more.
The priesthood was invited
to pray for the life of holy Russia
to work on the patriotism
of the worshippers.
The icons were honoured again.
The public campaign for atheism
was dropped.
(congregation singing)
The Germans murdered
Jews and Communists.
They murdered those
suspected of supporting the partisans.
They murdered hostages.
After battle, in retreat,
they just murdered.
To the north, the Russians prepared to
attack the German ring round Leningrad.
As they waited, runners brought the news
of the surrender of the German armies
at Stalingrad.
For army and people, this was the sudden
glow of victory at the tunnel's end.
Now they knew they would win.
At Leningrad,
the relieving troops broke through.
(speaking Russian)
They forced open a land route.
The 16-month blockade was over.
But they did not break the siege.
The Germans and Finns
still lay around the city.
(speaking Russian)
(Olga) It was such a feeling
I can't relate it.
I went to my neighbour across the yard,
and we kissed each other
and told each other:
"Now we shall live. There is a way out."
(narrator) In a fortnight,
a railway was laid through the gap.
Food and fuel
began to roll into Leningrad.
The symbols of old Russian honour
were restored to the army
as they had been to the church.
(patriotic Russian song)
Propaganda
united Lenin with Alexander Nevski...
..the 18th century hero, Suvorov...
..heroes of the Red cavalry,
mighty ghosts cheering forward
the avengers of the Soviet motherland.
The insignia of a traditional and
professional army were brought back.
Gold braid was imported from Britain.
Political commissars lost rank.
The years of the purges were forgotten.
(Russian marching song)
(speaking Russian)
(interpreter) Every Soviet citizen felt
himself a part of the common struggle.
Some people say
it was the Fascists' cruelty
which led to resistance
in the Ukraine and other occupied lands.
No.
I believe resistance was inevitable.
Soviet people in the rear could not
hold themselves back from the struggle.
(narrator) In 1941, behind the lines
partisan bands began to form.
At first, they lacked arms.
They grew slowly.
German deportations for forced labour
made thousands flee to the forests,
where they joined the partisans.
(patriotic song)
Soon the partisans
became a formidable army
operating against
the enemy lines of communication.
The penalty for collaboration was death.
On a mere suspicion
of sympathy for the enemy,
whole national groups,
the Volga Germans, the Crimean Tatars,
were deported to central Asia.
For individual collaborators, no mercy.
As German prisoners
were paraded through Leningrad,
people struck out at an enemy
they could reach.
In the steppes of Soviet Asia, in
the new factories and mines of Siberia,
the most desperate production effort of
modern times was coming to its climax.
Russia has been caught
with obsolete aircraft,
unfit for close battle support.
Now the plants turned out
9,000 modern aircraft every month.
In 1943, military output
finally outstripped Germany's.
Above all, it was the tank.
In 1943,
the factories built 24,000 of them.
More than any other weapon,
it was the tank,
especially the famous T-34,
which won the battle
on the Eastern Front.
With the American trucks
now streaming in from Persia,
this torrent of armour
moved up to the line.
The Russians knew that in July 1943
the Germans would launch their
full strength against them once more.
They knew too
that the blow would fall at Kursk.
They must hold firm.
Then the Red Army, now
the biggest land force ever seen in war,
would strike back.
The Germans planned to drive
into the shoulders of the Kursk bulge,
hoping to cut off the huge Soviet army,
then hit at Moscow.
They brought up 70 divisions -
almost a million men -
with the new Tiger tanks
and Ferdinand guns.
Hitler had intended to strike in May,
but there were delays in production
and building up reserves.
Weeks passed.
When the German were ready to attack,
the Russians were waiting for them.
(speaking Russian)
(interpreter) We were all prepared.
We were more than ready
to meet Hitler's attack.
We knew we had enough armour
to stop the Fascists
breaking through our defences.
Our reconnaissance patrols
had captured prisoners.
From them
we learned that Hitler's troops
planned to start the attack
at 2:30 in the morning on July 5.
The news was given to our troops.
(speaking Russian)
(interpreter) The commander
sits in the observation post,
the soldiers are in the trenches,
and tomorrow
the enemy is expected to attack.
You can imagine
what thoughts are in his mind.
There were more than
a hundred tanks every kilometre.
When tanks are moving,
the whole earth trembles.
And the guns fire,
but the soldier just sits.
(narrator)
Soviet aircraft took off at dawn
to wreck the German bombers
waiting on their airfields.
The Germans kept to the timetable.
On the morning of July 5,
the panzer divisions moved forward.
Kursk was the biggest tank battle
in history.
In the north, the German pincer
made ten miles in five days, and halted,
with 50,000 dead
and 400 tanks destroyed.
In the south, in an even vaster battle,
a 20-mile dent
was made in the Russian defences,
but the Germans were spent.
On July 15,
Hitler called off the Kursk offensive.
The Red Army went over to the attack.
Under bombardment,
the sappers went ahead
to cut a path into the German defences.
Through the gap,
the tanks plunged forward,
the troops riding on their sides.
These were the new Russian soldiers,
very different
from the defeated masses of 1941.
Their clothes were shabby,
but their weapons were clean.
They were tough, chasing the enemy
into close-quarter battle.
They were resourceful,
trained to live off the land
and to cross rivers on their own.
If there was no boat,
a bench or a log would do.
They went without regular leave or pay,
but now their morale
was fierce and high.
In military terms, it was Kursk which
decided how the European war would end.
When this supreme German effort failed,
the Soviet victory began.
The fighting to break through
German positions was hard and slow,
but after nine days
the Red Army had recaptured
all the ground lost
in this last German offensive.
The Germans began to fall back,
destroying everything as they went.
Now they were under constant attack
by Soviet fighters.
The Luftwaffe
had lost command of the air.
Suddenly, the towns of occupied Russia
were full of armour moving west.
After two years,
the conquerors were pulling out.
(air-raid siren)
At Leningrad,
the Germans were still at the outskirts,
the city still under shellfire.
The siege was not to be finally broken
until January the following year.
The strength of Russia, like a gigantic
spring compressed back to its limit,
was now bursting forward.
The first cities were liberated.
On August 5, 1943,
Orel and Belgorod were freed.
In each town, those who had died
in battle were buried.
"Do not call me, Father,
do not seek me."
"Do not call me, do not wish me back."
"We're on a route uncharted,
Fire and blood erase our track."
"On we fly on wings of thunder,
Nevermore to sheath our swords."
"All of us in battle fallen,
Not to be brought back by words."
"Will there be a rendezvous?
I know not."
"I only know we still must fight."
"We are sand grains in infinity,
Never to meet, nevermore see light."
"Farewell then, my son,
farewell then, my conscience,
My youth and my solace,
My one and my only."
"And let this farewell
be the end of a story
Of solitude vast,
and which none is more lonely,
In which you remain barred
forever and ever
From light and from air,
with your death pangs untold."
"Untold and unsoothed,
not to be resurrected,
Forever and ever an 18-year-old."
"Farewell, then.
No trains ever come from those regions,
Unscheduled or scheduled,
no aeroplanes fly there."
"Farewell then, my son,
for no miracles happen,
As in this world
dreams do not come true."
"Farewell.
I will dream of you still as a baby,
Treading the earth
with little, strong toes."
"The earth
where already so many lie buried."
"This song to my son, then,
is come to its close."
In Moscow, Stalin announced:
"Tonight at 2400 hours on August 5,
the capital of our country, Moscow,
will salute the valiant troops
who liberated Orel and Belgorod."
(shouting in Russian)
"Eternal glory to the heroes who fell
in the struggle for the freedom
of our country."
"Death to the German invaders."
In November, Kiev was freed.
(upbeat Russian song)
Russia was saved by its soldiers
and by its people.
But in the earth,
never to welcome the coming of peace,
lay 20 million dead.