1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:10,627 --> 00:00:13,038
(peal of bells)

3
00:00:20,602 --> 00:00:23,973
(narrator) Forlorn monsters today,

4
00:00:24,055 --> 00:00:27,197
in May 1940,
these forts of the Maginot line

5
00:00:27,277 --> 00:00:31,030
were France's first-line defence
against the Germans.

6
00:00:36,830 --> 00:00:41,817
Half a million French soldiers
lurked beneath these man-made hills.

7
00:00:44,273 --> 00:00:46,149
These were the most extensive,

8
00:00:46,268 --> 00:00:50,404
the most elaborate forts
ever constructed.

9
00:00:50,488 --> 00:00:53,707
Here the guns would halt the Hun -

10
00:00:53,787 --> 00:00:56,351
provided the Hun came this way.

11
00:01:59,967 --> 00:02:01,843
"Thank God for the French army,"

12
00:02:01,923 --> 00:02:04,870
said Winston Churchill
when Hitler came to power.

13
00:02:04,954 --> 00:02:06,132
But in 1933

14
00:02:06,220 --> 00:02:10,705
the French army was no longer
the superlative weapon it once had been.

15
00:02:12,627 --> 00:02:15,923
French military manuals
devoted page after page

16
00:02:16,003 --> 00:02:18,108
to the tactics of the First War,

17
00:02:18,228 --> 00:02:23,051
although Hitler had said, "The next war
will be very different from the last."

18
00:02:27,704 --> 00:02:31,305
The French had helped introduce
the tank and the aeroplane,

19
00:02:31,388 --> 00:02:34,562
but now did little to extend their use.

20
00:02:34,649 --> 00:02:37,595
They had pioneered motor transport
in warfare,

21
00:02:37,718 --> 00:02:41,821
but went back now
to relying on railways and the horse -

22
00:02:41,899 --> 00:02:43,700
especially the horse.

23
00:02:54,330 --> 00:02:57,396
(man) It was a period
of very deep decay,

24
00:02:57,514 --> 00:03:03,690
probably caused by the excess of effort
during the First World War.

25
00:03:03,767 --> 00:03:08,132
We suffered from an illness
which is not peculiar to the French -

26
00:03:08,218 --> 00:03:11,437
the illness of having been victorious

27
00:03:11,555 --> 00:03:15,734
and believing that we were right
and very clever.

28
00:03:16,811 --> 00:03:20,609
Victory is a very dangerous
opportunity.

29
00:03:20,725 --> 00:03:23,594
(chanting in French)

30
00:03:29,127 --> 00:03:33,153
(narrator) France between the wars
was deeply divided.

31
00:03:33,232 --> 00:03:37,792
Factions clashed, alliances altered,
cabinets came and went in the cascade,

32
00:03:37,874 --> 00:03:41,093
some lasting a few hours,
some a few months.

33
00:03:41,211 --> 00:03:43,699
Rarely did one last a whole year.

34
00:03:49,422 --> 00:03:54,670
On the very day Hitler came to power
France was without a government.

35
00:03:54,754 --> 00:03:59,850
It was again without one when he
marched into Austria five years later.

36
00:04:05,266 --> 00:04:07,252
The Left in France
was concerned more

37
00:04:07,338 --> 00:04:10,251
with hounding rogues
in high places at home,

38
00:04:10,330 --> 00:04:12,240
than curbing fascism elsewhere.

39
00:04:13,553 --> 00:04:15,463
The Right so hated the Left

40
00:04:15,548 --> 00:04:19,029
it was prepared to countenance
dictatorship.

41
00:04:20,574 --> 00:04:24,939
As early as 1934
the victor of Verdun, Marshal Pétain,

42
00:04:25,024 --> 00:04:28,090
was proposed as France's saviour
from communism,

43
00:04:28,170 --> 00:04:30,080
although he was then nearly 80.

44
00:04:30,165 --> 00:04:33,340
These deep divisions
were to fetter France

45
00:04:33,426 --> 00:04:35,914
when she faced the need to re-arm.

46
00:04:35,996 --> 00:04:38,943
The whole of the possessing classes,

47
00:04:39,027 --> 00:04:41,974
the Right if you like,

48
00:04:42,058 --> 00:04:45,659
preferred the idea of the Germans

49
00:04:45,741 --> 00:04:47,803
to their own communists.

50
00:04:47,889 --> 00:04:50,224
You didn't have to walk round
these streets

51
00:04:50,306 --> 00:04:52,838
and see "pour qui et pourquoi"
written on them,

52
00:04:52,915 --> 00:04:56,593
or the hammer and sickle, to realise
nobody was going to lift a finger.

53
00:05:09,911 --> 00:05:12,933
(narrator) France in the '30s
built a series of great forts

54
00:05:13,057 --> 00:05:14,813
along her frontier with Germany,

55
00:05:14,898 --> 00:05:19,230
and because her war minister
then happened to be one André Maginot,

56
00:05:19,310 --> 00:05:23,031
these forts came to be known
as the Maginot line.

57
00:05:24,911 --> 00:05:28,632
The Maginot forts
were truly 20th-century wonders.

58
00:05:29,477 --> 00:05:32,881
Electric trains took the troops
from barracks to gun turret,

59
00:05:33,006 --> 00:05:34,381
from arsenal to canteen.

60
00:05:34,464 --> 00:05:38,022
There were cinemas underground,
sun-ray rooms, air conditioning,

61
00:05:38,109 --> 00:05:39,985
the lot.

62
00:05:41,178 --> 00:05:44,474
Theirs was a vast
Jules Verne type of world

63
00:05:44,554 --> 00:05:47,042
hundreds of feet below ground.

64
00:05:47,125 --> 00:05:50,224
They called it The Shield of France.

65
00:05:50,309 --> 00:05:53,713
The Maginot line failed to protect
all of France's eastern flank.

66
00:05:53,800 --> 00:05:57,248
It was only 87 miles long

67
00:05:57,368 --> 00:06:01,121
and it stopped 250 miles
short of the Channel.

68
00:06:15,016 --> 00:06:17,547
Should the alarm
ever have to sound in grim earnest,

69
00:06:17,625 --> 00:06:19,228
French strategists argued that

70
00:06:19,313 --> 00:06:24,561
their troops would need to confront the
Germans on Belgian, if not German, soil.

71
00:06:24,645 --> 00:06:28,094
Besides, to extend the Maginot line
along the Belgian frontier

72
00:06:28,213 --> 00:06:29,861
would not only be expensive,

73
00:06:29,940 --> 00:06:35,417
but would make the Belgians think that
if war came, France would forsake them.

74
00:06:36,884 --> 00:06:39,601
The folly of this thinking
was shown up in 1936

75
00:06:39,684 --> 00:06:42,052
when, without consulting the French,

76
00:06:42,140 --> 00:06:45,435
the Belgian King Leopold
opted for neutrality

77
00:06:45,516 --> 00:06:50,459
and closed his borders,
even to French military observers.

78
00:06:52,959 --> 00:06:57,596
All too late France began extending
the Maginot line to the sea.

79
00:06:58,522 --> 00:07:03,116
But by May 1940
it was far from finished.

80
00:07:12,985 --> 00:07:14,971
(shouting in French)

81
00:07:24,686 --> 00:07:28,287
France had suffered a terrible
loss of life in the Great War.

82
00:07:28,369 --> 00:07:31,850
Now French military thinking
became wholly defensive,

83
00:07:31,976 --> 00:07:34,539
forgetting Napoleon's favourite maxim:

84
00:07:34,661 --> 00:07:38,186
"The side that stays
within its fortifications is beaten."

85
00:07:49,892 --> 00:07:52,456
Since the French spurned any notion

86
00:07:53,076 --> 00:07:54,571
of taking the offensive,

87
00:07:54,649 --> 00:07:58,752
the Maginot line ironically protected
Germany better than it protected France.

88
00:07:58,831 --> 00:08:02,661
A German colonel, Heinz Guderian,
the year the Maginot line was completed,

89
00:08:02,744 --> 00:08:06,956
published a book with a prophetic title:
Achtung Panzer.

90
00:08:07,041 --> 00:08:10,948
A book never properly studied by
the French or English general staff,

91
00:08:11,031 --> 00:08:13,791
yet these pages expound
a new kind of warfare -

92
00:08:13,870 --> 00:08:19,118
the concentrated use of tanks with
infantry and air force in close support:

93
00:08:19,203 --> 00:08:21,188
Blitzkrieg.

94
00:08:26,185 --> 00:08:28,520
We had had tanks
in the First World War,

95
00:08:28,602 --> 00:08:31,090
we knew all the difficulties
of the game,

96
00:08:31,173 --> 00:08:34,042
while the Germans,
who didn't have them,

97
00:08:34,127 --> 00:08:37,760
had the feeling of those
who are attacked by tanks.

98
00:08:37,848 --> 00:08:41,798
And while we considered
that the tanks were a little awkward

99
00:08:41,876 --> 00:08:43,328
and difficult to use,

100
00:08:43,411 --> 00:08:48,965
the Germans jumped at the new weapons
with the appetite of the new rich.

101
00:08:55,342 --> 00:08:59,478
(narrator) Paris, July 14, 1939.

102
00:09:00,829 --> 00:09:04,462
The last Bastille Day parade
of the Third Republic.

103
00:09:07,351 --> 00:09:11,300
A few days earlier, Britain's
war minister, visiting Paris, had said,

104
00:09:11,417 --> 00:09:15,138
"France has the greatest army
in the world."

105
00:09:15,254 --> 00:09:19,968
Like the parade itself, such statements
were meant merely to raise morale.

106
00:09:23,310 --> 00:09:25,918
Parisians had hardly got back
from their holidays

107
00:09:26,034 --> 00:09:28,490
before they found themselves
once more at war

108
00:09:28,566 --> 00:09:30,672
with their traditional foe.

109
00:09:40,997 --> 00:09:44,750
But whereas in 1914
the cry had been "On to Berlin",

110
00:09:44,833 --> 00:09:47,855
this time it was
"Let's get it over with."

111
00:09:55,000 --> 00:09:58,328
Ironically, French mobilisation
was too efficient.

112
00:09:58,414 --> 00:10:00,519
The call-up of skilled technicians

113
00:10:00,601 --> 00:10:03,700
brought many vital war industries
almost to a halt.

114
00:10:03,785 --> 00:10:08,804
It was only after weeks of confusion
that these men were released.

115
00:10:24,349 --> 00:10:27,295
Nor was France going to war united.

116
00:10:27,380 --> 00:10:30,173
The bitternesses of French politics
continued.

117
00:10:30,257 --> 00:10:33,782
Ministers looked to their own futures
instead of their country's

118
00:10:33,863 --> 00:10:37,267
and many took their cue
from such leadership.

119
00:10:41,881 --> 00:10:45,985
Paris didn't alter much with
the coming of war, save in appearance.

120
00:10:46,102 --> 00:10:51,317
The most popular song that autumn of
1939 was Paris Will Always Be Paris.

121
00:10:51,396 --> 00:10:54,080
(Maurice Chevalier)
Par précaution on a beau mettre

122
00:10:54,158 --> 00:10:55,914
Des croisillons à nos fenêtres

123
00:10:56,000 --> 00:10:58,182
Passer au bleu nos devantures

124
00:10:58,263 --> 00:11:00,402
Et jusqu 'aux pneus de nos voitures

125
00:11:00,488 --> 00:11:02,474
Désentoiler tous nos musées

126
00:11:02,560 --> 00:11:04,851
Chambouler les Champs-Elysées

127
00:11:04,939 --> 00:11:07,197
Emmailloter de terre battue

128
00:11:07,279 --> 00:11:09,461
Toutes les beautés de nos statues

129
00:11:09,581 --> 00:11:12,221
Voiler le soir les réverbères

130
00:11:12,305 --> 00:11:16,593
Plonger dans le noir
la Ville Lumière

131
00:11:16,678 --> 00:11:20,661
Paris sera toujours Paris

132
00:11:20,745 --> 00:11:24,652
La plus belle ville du monde

133
00:11:24,735 --> 00:11:28,183
Malgré l'obscurité profonde

134
00:11:28,265 --> 00:11:31,898
Son éclat ne peut être assombri

135
00:11:32,024 --> 00:11:35,582
Paris sera toujours Paris

136
00:11:35,669 --> 00:11:39,269
Plus on réduit son éclairage

137
00:11:39,352 --> 00:11:42,909
Plus on voit briller son courage,
sa bonne humeur et son esprit

138
00:11:43,035 --> 00:11:47,094
Paris sera toujours Paris

139
00:11:49,710 --> 00:11:52,929
(narrator) While their Polish allies
were routed in the East,

140
00:11:53,010 --> 00:11:55,847
the French, like the British,
did little in the West.

141
00:11:55,926 --> 00:11:58,992
There was the so-called
Sarre offensive -

142
00:11:59,071 --> 00:12:01,406
the only French offensive,
in fact, of the war.

143
00:12:12,653 --> 00:12:16,057
A few French divisions
advanced five miles,

144
00:12:16,144 --> 00:12:18,937
but they didn't even try
to penetrate the Siegfried line,

145
00:12:19,021 --> 00:12:20,592
at that time still unfinished.

146
00:12:20,671 --> 00:12:22,471
And while Poland fought on,

147
00:12:22,551 --> 00:12:25,693
there were no German tanks at all
on the Western Front.

148
00:12:25,812 --> 00:12:30,372
The newsreel commentators of the day,
though, didn't doubt the French resolve.

149
00:12:30,454 --> 00:12:33,673
(newsreel) We read the communiqués
from the French High Command.

150
00:12:33,753 --> 00:12:37,660
This is the living story
behind those brief, unvarnished reports.

151
00:12:37,743 --> 00:12:40,613
Our cameramen in the advanced
lines on German territory

152
00:12:40,697 --> 00:12:42,039
watch observation posts

153
00:12:42,117 --> 00:12:46,787
at the bridge over the Rhine
between Kehl and Strasbourg.

154
00:12:50,826 --> 00:12:55,037
This was a German railway station,
now in the hands of French troops.

155
00:12:57,539 --> 00:13:02,209
From fortified outposts
the vigilant watch is never relaxed.

156
00:13:12,809 --> 00:13:16,027
The Maginot line, built as
the first line of defence for France,

157
00:13:16,108 --> 00:13:18,519
has become the second line
behind the attack.

158
00:13:18,602 --> 00:13:20,936
The gradual but steady advance
of French troops

159
00:13:21,019 --> 00:13:24,848
has brought their camouflaged artillery
in range of the Siegfried outposts.

160
00:13:24,932 --> 00:13:27,725
There is no haste,
only a grim, relentless pressure

161
00:13:27,809 --> 00:13:29,260
on the Nazi emplacements.

162
00:13:29,344 --> 00:13:31,875
Metre by metre the poilus
are moving forward.

163
00:13:31,953 --> 00:13:39,504
If the French army would have attacked
at the beginning of September

164
00:13:40,163 --> 00:13:45,302
with their very strong superiority

165
00:13:45,380 --> 00:13:48,173
in division, in armoured cars -

166
00:13:48,258 --> 00:13:52,361
we lacked all armoured cars
on the Western Front at that time -

167
00:13:52,439 --> 00:13:57,000
in artillery and air force,

168
00:13:57,082 --> 00:14:02,985
the German forces
on the so-called Western Front

169
00:14:03,066 --> 00:14:08,697
could stand no more
than one or two weeks.

170
00:14:10,356 --> 00:14:12,265
(narrator) Before Poland surrendered,

171
00:14:12,351 --> 00:14:16,181
the French commander ordered
his men back behind the Maginot line -

172
00:14:16,264 --> 00:14:19,177
a withdrawal the Germans
did nothing to prevent.

173
00:14:19,256 --> 00:14:20,937
One Frenchman wrote at the time,

174
00:14:21,060 --> 00:14:23,427
"After the prologue
of the phoney offensive,

175
00:14:23,515 --> 00:14:25,500
we were ripe for the phoney war."

176
00:14:25,587 --> 00:14:28,118
(Charles Trenet)
Le vent dans les bois fait hou-hou

177
00:14:28,195 --> 00:14:30,258
La biche aux abois fait mê-ê-ê

178
00:14:30,344 --> 00:14:32,558
La vaisselle cassée fait
fric-fric-frac

179
00:14:32,646 --> 00:14:34,937
Et les pieds mouillés
font flic-flic-flac

180
00:14:35,024 --> 00:14:36,366
Mais... boum!

181
00:14:36,444 --> 00:14:38,932
Quand notre coeur fait boum

182
00:14:39,014 --> 00:14:40,770
Tout avec lui dit boum

183
00:14:40,856 --> 00:14:43,038
L'oiseau dit boum, c'est l'orage

184
00:14:43,119 --> 00:14:45,072
Brrrrr!

185
00:14:45,153 --> 00:14:48,753
Boum! L'éclair qui, lui, fait boum

186
00:14:48,836 --> 00:14:51,127
Et le bon Dieu dit boum...

187
00:14:51,253 --> 00:14:55,279
(narrator) For several minutes each day
the Maginot guns boomed out,

188
00:14:55,358 --> 00:15:00,148
usually to impress visitors
such as the Duke of Windsor.

189
00:15:00,230 --> 00:15:02,412
Et s'il fait boum,
s'il se met en colère

190
00:15:02,647 --> 00:15:04,709
Il entraîne avec lui des merveilles

191
00:15:04,795 --> 00:15:05,821
Boum!

192
00:15:05,946 --> 00:15:08,358
Le monde entier fait boum

193
00:15:08,440 --> 00:15:12,466
Tout avec lui dit boum
quand notre coeur fait boum-boum...

194
00:15:12,545 --> 00:15:15,644
(narrator) Little attempt was made
to harass the enemy.

195
00:15:15,768 --> 00:15:17,491
Even bombing the Ruhr
was forbidden

196
00:15:17,571 --> 00:15:20,441
in case the Luftwaffe retaliated
against French factories.

197
00:15:20,525 --> 00:15:24,737
Journalists were taken up to the lines
to see the inactivity.

198
00:15:24,822 --> 00:15:28,881
I stayed at an observation post
on the Rhine

199
00:15:28,965 --> 00:15:33,679
watching the Germans washing,
playing football,

200
00:15:33,761 --> 00:15:36,598
and I said to the sentry,

201
00:15:36,677 --> 00:15:39,895
"Why don't you shoot them?
Why don't you shoot at them?"

202
00:15:40,014 --> 00:15:42,273
"No," he said,
"They're behaving all right."

203
00:15:42,355 --> 00:15:45,038
"They don't shoot at us,
why should we shoot at them?"

204
00:15:45,117 --> 00:15:48,565
Boum! Le monde entier fait boum

205
00:15:48,646 --> 00:15:50,447
Tout avec lui dit boum

206
00:15:50,526 --> 00:15:54,007
Quand notre coeur
fait boum-boum-boum

207
00:15:54,094 --> 00:15:56,199
Fait boum-boum

208
00:15:56,281 --> 00:15:59,227
Brrrrr! Boum!

209
00:16:02,650 --> 00:16:07,058
(narrator) Life at the front
was dreary and drab.

210
00:16:18,302 --> 00:16:22,711
Badly paid, leave became an obsession
for the French soldier

211
00:16:22,791 --> 00:16:26,119
and was used mainly
to make a little on the side.

212
00:16:31,116 --> 00:16:34,564
The winter of 1939
was the coldest for half a century.

213
00:16:34,646 --> 00:16:37,177
Even the Channel froze at Boulogne.

214
00:16:38,597 --> 00:16:42,045
The French halted work
on the Maginot extension.

215
00:16:42,127 --> 00:16:46,841
The Germans, however,
forged ahead with their plans.

216
00:16:47,575 --> 00:16:50,946
As winter wore on, French morale sank.

217
00:16:51,334 --> 00:16:55,666
Discipline deteriorated
and drunkenness became rife.

218
00:16:55,746 --> 00:16:59,118
Special rooms were set aside
in railway stations

219
00:16:59,199 --> 00:17:03,531
where men could recover
before rejoining their units.

220
00:17:07,831 --> 00:17:13,124
Few French generals ever bothered to
inspect, let alone meet, their troops,

221
00:17:13,202 --> 00:17:16,421
but then their commander-in-chief,
General Gamelin,

222
00:17:16,502 --> 00:17:19,033
rarely set foot
outside his headquarters.

223
00:17:19,111 --> 00:17:23,748
Already 68 at the beginning of 1940,
his military record was so impeccable

224
00:17:23,829 --> 00:17:27,463
that no one dreamed of asking him
to make way for a younger man.

225
00:17:27,589 --> 00:17:33,722
(Beaufre) Gamelin was very clever,
but with no guts at all,

226
00:17:33,804 --> 00:17:35,680
and he was liked by the politicians

227
00:17:35,761 --> 00:17:38,128
because he was an easy
commander-in-chief.

228
00:17:39,406 --> 00:17:43,006
(narrator) Gamelin chose for his
headquarters this château at Vincennes,

229
00:17:43,089 --> 00:17:45,303
just outside Paris.

230
00:17:45,390 --> 00:17:49,646
(Beaufre) That choice reveals
what the man was, you know.

231
00:17:49,726 --> 00:17:53,752
The enemy were not the Germans.
It was the French government.

232
00:17:54,636 --> 00:17:58,270
(narrator) Vincennes
was where England's Henry V died

233
00:17:58,358 --> 00:18:01,457
and where the spy Mata Hari
was executed.

234
00:18:04,343 --> 00:18:09,286
It was described by one visitor as
"a submarine without a periscope".

235
00:18:09,368 --> 00:18:12,467
Almost unbelievably,
it had no radio communications,

236
00:18:12,553 --> 00:18:16,110
it was not linked by teleprinter with
any other headquarters in the field.

237
00:18:16,197 --> 00:18:21,827
Instead, messages were dispatched
regularly on the hour by motorcycle.

238
00:18:23,372 --> 00:18:26,438
Gamelin seldom bothered his staff
with orders,

239
00:18:26,518 --> 00:18:29,311
preferring simply to suggest guidelines.

240
00:18:33,769 --> 00:18:37,446
His long-term strategy was to wait
until the Allies could match the Germans

241
00:18:37,528 --> 00:18:41,009
in numbers and equipment
before launching any major offensive,

242
00:18:41,096 --> 00:18:44,392
even though that would mean
waiting until 1941.

243
00:18:44,511 --> 00:18:48,799
Meanwhile, he was concerned
to keep the war away from French soil -

244
00:18:48,884 --> 00:18:53,325
hence his interests in any odd stratagem
pushed his way.

245
00:18:53,411 --> 00:19:00,886
We had a plan to go to attack Russia
through Norway - Narvik -

246
00:19:00,969 --> 00:19:03,729
which led to the landing in Narvik.

247
00:19:03,808 --> 00:19:10,290
We had a plan to attack
the oil plants in Baku from Syria.

248
00:19:10,369 --> 00:19:14,929
We had the plans to raise
the Balkans with us

249
00:19:15,049 --> 00:19:20,494
by landing in Salonika
and joining the Yugoslavs, and so on.

250
00:19:20,574 --> 00:19:27,011
But all this was dreams, absolutely
foolish and out of the reality.

251
00:19:27,096 --> 00:19:28,819
But that stemmed from the fact

252
00:19:28,899 --> 00:19:32,696
that we thought that the war
couldn't be decided on the main front

253
00:19:32,774 --> 00:19:36,877
because of the inviolability
of that front.

254
00:19:36,994 --> 00:19:40,168
(narrator) Gamelin had 100 divisions
on that front in May 1940,

255
00:19:40,255 --> 00:19:44,008
plus another ten of the British
expeditionary force.

256
00:19:45,280 --> 00:19:50,027
40 manned the Maginot line,
while five guarded the Swiss frontier.

257
00:19:50,114 --> 00:19:56,290
Another 40, the best, were to go into
neutral Belgium once Germany attacked.

258
00:19:56,368 --> 00:19:57,819
But when that happened

259
00:19:57,903 --> 00:20:01,852
the pivot of Gamelin's front
would be here, in the Ardennes.

260
00:20:06,266 --> 00:20:09,136
The impenetrable Ardennes.

261
00:20:09,220 --> 00:20:11,206
But was it?

262
00:20:20,538 --> 00:20:22,141
On maps back at headquarters

263
00:20:22,226 --> 00:20:24,714
its thick woods
and narrow, winding roads

264
00:20:24,796 --> 00:20:27,895
probably did make the Ardennes
seem impenetrable -

265
00:20:27,981 --> 00:20:32,345
which is presumably why Gamelin chose
to guard this 100-mile stretch of front

266
00:20:32,431 --> 00:20:37,952
with ten of his weakest,
least-trained, worst-equipped divisions.

267
00:20:38,070 --> 00:20:42,020
(man) The Ardennes came to be chosen
for the main thrust

268
00:20:42,099 --> 00:20:46,736
since it offered an opportunity
to circumvent the Maginot line.

269
00:20:46,856 --> 00:20:50,227
And besides we were conscious
of the fact

270
00:20:50,309 --> 00:20:53,604
that there were only minor French troops

271
00:20:53,762 --> 00:20:58,901
which held the positions
in this section of the French front.

272
00:20:58,979 --> 00:21:03,693
We knew that the French High Command

273
00:21:03,775 --> 00:21:08,140
had dispersed his tanks.

274
00:21:09,031 --> 00:21:14,356
The French had more tanks
and some better tanks, heavier tanks,

275
00:21:14,440 --> 00:21:17,353
than we have had panzers.

276
00:21:17,433 --> 00:21:22,070
But we managed our panzer troops -

277
00:21:22,152 --> 00:21:27,215
what Guderian said in his instructions.

278
00:21:27,292 --> 00:21:32,618
(man) "Strike hard and quickly
and don't disperse your forces."

279
00:21:39,838 --> 00:21:42,707
(narrator) The spring of 1940
was remarkably sunny.

280
00:21:42,792 --> 00:21:45,891
Nowhere was it more peaceful
than here in the Ardennes,

281
00:21:45,976 --> 00:21:49,424
where the generals had said
the Germans would never attack.

282
00:21:49,506 --> 00:21:51,186
Yet reports had been pouring in

283
00:21:51,270 --> 00:21:54,293
that nearly 50 Wehrmacht divisions
were on the move -

284
00:21:54,378 --> 00:21:56,713
reports which the French
chose to ignore.

285
00:21:56,795 --> 00:22:01,509
They even learned the date
of the attack, but still did nothing.

286
00:22:01,591 --> 00:22:05,465
As Gamelin put it,
they preferred "to await events".

287
00:22:05,542 --> 00:22:08,150
Their waiting was almost over.

288
00:22:15,824 --> 00:22:18,158
5:30am precisely.

289
00:22:18,241 --> 00:22:20,532
May 10, 1940.

290
00:22:32,551 --> 00:22:35,344
The German offensive
began spectacularly enough

291
00:22:35,428 --> 00:22:38,724
with the invasion of neutral Holland
from the air.

292
00:22:38,804 --> 00:22:41,565
Their target: the bridges
over the broad Meuse estuary.

293
00:22:47,091 --> 00:22:50,266
If they could be captured
before the Allied troops reached them,

294
00:22:50,352 --> 00:22:52,338
Holland would be cut in two.

295
00:22:57,143 --> 00:23:01,354
The boldness of the German move
stunned the Dutch.

296
00:23:01,440 --> 00:23:04,506
Their soldiers were soon
surrendering in droves.

297
00:23:06,235 --> 00:23:07,839
Further south in Belgium,

298
00:23:07,923 --> 00:23:11,557
the Germans had another
spectacular success that first day -

299
00:23:11,645 --> 00:23:13,521
the capture of Eben-Emael,

300
00:23:13,601 --> 00:23:18,239
the strongest fort in the world
and the linchpin of Gamelin's line.

301
00:23:19,164 --> 00:23:23,605
That line had been breached
before any Allied troops arrived.

302
00:23:26,760 --> 00:23:29,401
(whistle blows)

303
00:23:33,551 --> 00:23:37,348
Gamelin persisted in moving his armies
north into Belgium and Holland.

304
00:23:37,426 --> 00:23:39,990
40 of his best divisions,
almost half his strength,

305
00:23:40,073 --> 00:23:42,681
including all of the British
expeditionary force,

306
00:23:42,759 --> 00:23:45,781
and they were moving
straight into the trap

307
00:23:45,866 --> 00:23:48,736
Hitler and his generals
had set for them.

308
00:23:53,386 --> 00:23:55,874
It wasn't long before the troops
were passing

309
00:23:55,956 --> 00:23:58,673
the first pitiful, straggling lines
of refugees.

310
00:23:58,757 --> 00:24:01,856
Lines that were to hamper
the Allied reinforcements,

311
00:24:01,941 --> 00:24:03,894
just as the Germans had planned.

312
00:24:03,974 --> 00:24:08,153
The great idea on the Germans' part
was speed,

313
00:24:08,233 --> 00:24:12,598
and they sent ahead of the army

314
00:24:12,683 --> 00:24:17,320
policemen with truncheons and white
gloves who went on motorbicycles.

315
00:24:17,402 --> 00:24:20,806
They all had their Michelin Guide
for France,

316
00:24:20,893 --> 00:24:23,883
they knew exactly
where the roads were.

317
00:24:28,911 --> 00:24:32,632
The German panzers were pouring over
the border into Luxembourg.

318
00:24:32,710 --> 00:24:34,542
Their column stretched 100 miles,

319
00:24:34,628 --> 00:24:37,388
presenting a prime target
to any would-be bomber,

320
00:24:37,467 --> 00:24:39,955
but Allied air activity
that first day was busy

321
00:24:40,037 --> 00:24:44,981
supporting the British and French
move north into Belgium.

322
00:24:49,628 --> 00:24:54,223
The Luftwaffe were striking
at Allied aeroplanes on the ground.

323
00:24:57,800 --> 00:25:01,401
At one RAF base near Reims,
the planes lined up in neat rows

324
00:25:01,483 --> 00:25:05,815
were destroyed
in the opening minutes of the attack.

325
00:25:08,811 --> 00:25:13,525
50 British and French airfields
were attacked that first day

326
00:25:13,606 --> 00:25:15,898
and the losses were heavy.

327
00:25:21,164 --> 00:25:24,612
But while Allied air chiefs
were counting their losses,

328
00:25:24,694 --> 00:25:28,644
the panzers had just about penetrated
the impenetrable Ardennes

329
00:25:28,722 --> 00:25:32,247
and were set to fall upon the weak
French garrisons

330
00:25:32,328 --> 00:25:34,434
along the Meuse here at Sedan.

331
00:25:35,589 --> 00:25:38,993
The panzers reached Sedan
late on the third day of the offensive,

332
00:25:39,081 --> 00:25:41,220
although Gamelin had calculated

333
00:25:41,344 --> 00:25:44,672
they couldn't possibly be here
before the ninth day.

334
00:25:52,278 --> 00:25:56,534
All the bridges over the Meuse were
blown up by the French on May 12th -

335
00:25:56,613 --> 00:25:58,370
all except one.

336
00:25:59,107 --> 00:26:02,403
This old weir some 40 miles
north of Sedan had been left

337
00:26:02,483 --> 00:26:07,001
for fear of lowering the water level
so much that the river could be forded.

338
00:26:07,087 --> 00:26:10,458
But the French also left it
relatively unguarded,

339
00:26:10,540 --> 00:26:15,362
as one panzer commander,
Erwin Rommel, soon found out.

340
00:26:27,113 --> 00:26:32,668
Next morning the Luftwaffe's resources
were hurled into action above Sedan.

341
00:26:36,321 --> 00:26:40,303
Gamelin still refused to believe
the Germans could cross of the Meuse

342
00:26:40,388 --> 00:26:42,188
before another three or four days.

343
00:26:46,181 --> 00:26:48,821
Hitler was unwilling to wait that long.

344
00:26:48,905 --> 00:26:52,309
He was working
to the timetable of 1940, not 1914.

345
00:26:53,547 --> 00:26:56,842
What's more, the French generals
still had their eyes firmly fixed

346
00:26:56,923 --> 00:27:00,556
on what was happening
in Belgium and Holland.

347
00:27:06,706 --> 00:27:09,652
There were big French guns
on the west bank of the Meuse,

348
00:27:09,775 --> 00:27:12,535
but they limited firing
in case they ran out of ammunition

349
00:27:12,614 --> 00:27:15,178
before the battle proper began.

350
00:27:15,913 --> 00:27:20,660
So the German panzers were able to pick
off the French pillboxes one by one.

351
00:27:20,747 --> 00:27:25,265
Soon thousands of French gunners
had taken to their heels.

352
00:27:36,669 --> 00:27:40,805
As suddenly as it had started,
the German bombardment stopped.

353
00:27:42,155 --> 00:27:45,450
As though still performing
one of their winter war games,

354
00:27:45,531 --> 00:27:49,284
the German infantrymen
prepared to cross the Meuse.

355
00:28:15,302 --> 00:28:19,820
By midnight on May 13,
still only day four of the offensive,

356
00:28:19,906 --> 00:28:23,463
not only were German infantrymen
across the Meuse in force,

357
00:28:23,551 --> 00:28:26,540
but German sappers
were bridging the river

358
00:28:26,620 --> 00:28:29,566
and making ready
for the panzers to cross.

359
00:28:33,219 --> 00:28:34,593
That night of May 13,

360
00:28:34,715 --> 00:28:38,664
the British expeditionary force,
far to the north in Belgium,

361
00:28:38,743 --> 00:28:41,809
had still not seen serious fighting,

362
00:28:41,889 --> 00:28:45,293
yet the battle was now virtually
decided.

363
00:28:50,636 --> 00:28:55,884
(Beaufre) The morale of the French
High Command was very quickly broken.

364
00:28:56,468 --> 00:29:01,640
When we happened to know that the front
had been broken through at Sedan,

365
00:29:01,762 --> 00:29:05,243
the feeling was that everything
was lost.

366
00:29:05,330 --> 00:29:11,037
I saw General Georges,
who was commanding the northeast front,

367
00:29:11,161 --> 00:29:15,875
I saw him sobbing and saying,

368
00:29:15,957 --> 00:29:21,708
"There has been some... deficiencies,"

369
00:29:21,788 --> 00:29:25,967
and he fell in a chair and sobbed.

370
00:29:39,206 --> 00:29:42,502
(narrator) French counterattacks
were poorly organised

371
00:29:42,582 --> 00:29:45,878
and seldom pressed home
with any persistence.

372
00:29:58,580 --> 00:30:01,876
Tank for tank, the French
were a match for the Germans,

373
00:30:01,956 --> 00:30:04,323
but the panzers always fought
en masse

374
00:30:04,412 --> 00:30:07,969
and the French tanks
were prone to mechanical trouble.

375
00:30:08,056 --> 00:30:12,421
Time after time they had to be
left behind on the battlefield.

376
00:30:27,699 --> 00:30:31,224
German infantry divisions
were now catching up with the panzers

377
00:30:31,305 --> 00:30:32,876
at the Meuse crossing point.

378
00:30:32,993 --> 00:30:37,707
Everything on the German side at least
was going according to plan.

379
00:30:52,214 --> 00:30:53,938
For the Allied air forces,

380
00:30:54,017 --> 00:30:58,502
after their almost total inactivity
on May 13, May 14 was hectic.

381
00:30:58,583 --> 00:31:02,303
British and French bombers raided
the pontoon bridges across the Meuse

382
00:31:02,381 --> 00:31:03,832
with reckless abandon.

383
00:31:07,445 --> 00:31:09,016
Too late, the French generals

384
00:31:09,248 --> 00:31:12,238
had recognised this sector's
vital importance.

385
00:31:12,317 --> 00:31:17,642
But despite the courage of the Allied
pilots, the result was disastrous.

386
00:31:23,558 --> 00:31:27,159
Nearly half the Allied planes
did not return.

387
00:31:27,241 --> 00:31:29,608
In the words of the official
RAF history:

388
00:31:29,735 --> 00:31:35,442
"No higher rate of loss has ever been
experienced by the Royal Air Force."

389
00:31:35,528 --> 00:31:40,776
After May 14th
the skies were undeniably German.

390
00:31:43,431 --> 00:31:46,759
On that day too Holland surrendered.

391
00:31:47,766 --> 00:31:51,902
Nothing short of a miracle
could save France now.

392
00:31:58,125 --> 00:32:02,566
With the bridgehead secure,
the panzers were poised to break out.

393
00:32:02,652 --> 00:32:07,442
The battle for Sedan was now
giving way to the battle for France.

394
00:32:07,524 --> 00:32:11,507
The most crucial phase of the whole
German plan was about to begin -

395
00:32:11,629 --> 00:32:17,151
the swing north to the coast that would
trap the Allied armies in Belgium.

396
00:32:17,231 --> 00:32:22,479
As soon as news of the Sedan defeat
reached Paris, panic set in.

397
00:32:30,121 --> 00:32:32,303
Those who could, left.

398
00:32:38,715 --> 00:32:41,890
The French High Command,
not yet privy to the German plan,

399
00:32:41,976 --> 00:32:45,501
assumed Hitler intended
to capture Paris immediately.

400
00:32:45,621 --> 00:32:47,115
To protect the capital,

401
00:32:47,193 --> 00:32:50,140
troops were pulled back
from elsewhere along the Meuse,

402
00:32:50,224 --> 00:32:54,403
which only served
to widen the German bridgeheads.

403
00:33:03,307 --> 00:33:06,100
Gamelin refused to believe
his tactics were at fault

404
00:33:06,222 --> 00:33:08,404
and assumed
he must have been betrayed.

405
00:33:08,486 --> 00:33:12,283
While gendarmes searched for
fifth columnists behind the lines,

406
00:33:12,361 --> 00:33:16,038
Gamelin reacted by sacking
20 or so of his front-line commanders,

407
00:33:16,159 --> 00:33:18,690
almost at random.

408
00:33:23,371 --> 00:33:25,663
The Allied troops
were ordered back from Belgium

409
00:33:25,788 --> 00:33:29,542
and on May 17th Brussels fell.

410
00:33:36,109 --> 00:33:38,792
It was also the end for Gamelin.

411
00:33:38,871 --> 00:33:41,205
He was replaced
as commander-in-chief

412
00:33:41,288 --> 00:33:44,158
by General Weygand,
recalled from virtual retirement.

413
00:33:44,242 --> 00:33:46,042
France had become desperate.

414
00:33:46,122 --> 00:33:49,722
A 73-year-old
was replacing a 68-year-old,

415
00:33:49,805 --> 00:33:54,213
and Weygand had spent the last year
in Syria and was out of touch.

416
00:33:54,294 --> 00:33:59,432
At this time too Marshal Pétain, now 84,
became deputy prime minister.

417
00:33:59,511 --> 00:34:02,501
Before leaving Spain,
where he'd been France's ambassador,

418
00:34:02,580 --> 00:34:03,999
Pétain told General Franco,

419
00:34:04,077 --> 00:34:09,325
"My country has been beaten. This
is the work of 30 years of Marxism."

420
00:34:09,409 --> 00:34:12,967
(Spears) He was completely
on the side of the defeatists.

421
00:34:13,054 --> 00:34:15,313
He was a very, very old man

422
00:34:15,394 --> 00:34:22,258
and he'd been recalled in the hopes that
his name would bolster French morale.

423
00:34:22,338 --> 00:34:24,324
It did nothing of the sort.

424
00:34:25,177 --> 00:34:28,658
(narrator) Trying in their own way
to contain the German break-out,

425
00:34:28,745 --> 00:34:32,302
the French generals
drew halt lines on their maps,

426
00:34:32,428 --> 00:34:36,760
only to hear the panzers had passed them
even before the orders had been issued.

427
00:34:41,559 --> 00:34:43,893
(gunfire)

428
00:34:44,014 --> 00:34:45,618
In the dash to the coast,

429
00:34:45,702 --> 00:34:50,187
the German commanders were always
one jump ahead of the French.

430
00:35:02,736 --> 00:35:06,184
Hordes of prisoners
fell into German hands.

431
00:35:06,266 --> 00:35:08,830
Many columns,
10,000 or 20,000-strong,

432
00:35:08,951 --> 00:35:13,698
simply threw away their weapons
and marched without being told,

433
00:35:13,785 --> 00:35:17,004
their officers at their head,
toward the German lines.

434
00:35:18,159 --> 00:35:24,215
(Warlimont) The French troops did not
prove the same soldierly discipline

435
00:35:24,297 --> 00:35:25,792
as in the First World War.

436
00:35:41,101 --> 00:35:48,543
I think this was caused by the
Maginot spirit and the long phoney war,

437
00:35:48,621 --> 00:35:53,793
so that the French soldiers believed
that they will have no more war.

438
00:35:55,526 --> 00:35:58,396
(narrator) Not just ordinary troops
fell into German hands,

439
00:35:58,480 --> 00:35:59,550
but generals too.

440
00:35:59,631 --> 00:36:01,279
On May 19th General Giraud,

441
00:36:01,396 --> 00:36:05,346
newly appointed commander
of France's 9th Army, was captured:

442
00:36:05,424 --> 00:36:07,759
by a group of tanks,
according to the French;

443
00:36:07,841 --> 00:36:10,831
by a field kitchen unit,
according to the Germans.

444
00:36:14,670 --> 00:36:18,653
But most tragic of all
was the plight of the refugees.

445
00:36:25,029 --> 00:36:29,895
At one time 12 million people
were on the roads of northern France,

446
00:36:29,978 --> 00:36:32,695
bound for goodness knows where.

447
00:36:50,772 --> 00:36:54,645
(Waterfield) All the civilians
would ask us what they were to do,

448
00:36:54,762 --> 00:36:57,217
because the government
had not told them what to do.

449
00:36:57,294 --> 00:37:00,927
We said, "For heaven's sake, stay
where you are. Don't get on the roads."

450
00:37:01,015 --> 00:37:04,419
But they all got in a panic and left.

451
00:37:04,506 --> 00:37:07,267
One old lady had a key
which she gave to us

452
00:37:07,345 --> 00:37:10,749
and we said, "Why?
You mustn't give us your key."

453
00:37:10,836 --> 00:37:13,095
"Oh, well, in the last war
I took away my key

454
00:37:13,177 --> 00:37:15,784
and when I came back
I had the key but no house."

455
00:37:29,175 --> 00:37:34,958
My worst memory was seeing two German
planes coming along at roof level,

456
00:37:35,083 --> 00:37:36,501
machine-gunning,

457
00:37:36,579 --> 00:37:40,376
and one realised then
how awful it was for the refugees.

458
00:37:40,454 --> 00:37:42,439
(planes approaching)

459
00:37:47,206 --> 00:37:49,159
(gunfire)

460
00:38:20,277 --> 00:38:25,220
(narrator) The Germans had advanced
200 miles in just seven days,

461
00:38:25,302 --> 00:38:28,751
and on May 20th
they reached the Channel.

462
00:38:29,945 --> 00:38:32,814
The Daily Telegraph reported
that telephone lines

463
00:38:32,899 --> 00:38:35,582
between Paris and London
had been cut.

464
00:38:35,661 --> 00:38:39,840
A Post Office spokesman didn't know
when normal service might be resumed.

465
00:38:44,140 --> 00:38:46,322
With the panzers at the coast,

466
00:38:46,403 --> 00:38:52,306
the best of the Allied armies drawn into
Belgium were now cut off from the south.

467
00:38:52,388 --> 00:38:55,639
Belatedly the French
tried to force a way through to them.

468
00:38:55,726 --> 00:38:57,984
Their attack was too puny.

469
00:38:58,066 --> 00:39:00,903
But they argued
the British had let them down.

470
00:39:02,747 --> 00:39:05,354
(Beaufre) The recriminations started

471
00:39:05,432 --> 00:39:10,724
with the unilateral withdrawal
of the British army.

472
00:39:10,803 --> 00:39:16,587
The orders were to attack southwards,
near Arras,

473
00:39:16,673 --> 00:39:20,077
and, without warning,

474
00:39:20,164 --> 00:39:24,682
we happened to know that the British
were withdrawing to Dunkirk.

475
00:39:29,640 --> 00:39:32,401
We have not the right
to criticise this too much

476
00:39:32,479 --> 00:39:34,738
because, after all,
we were the bosses

477
00:39:34,819 --> 00:39:36,423
and we lost the battle,

478
00:39:36,508 --> 00:39:40,457
and this gives a good excuse
for the British to be selfish.

479
00:39:40,574 --> 00:39:43,062
But anyway, they were very selfish.

480
00:39:56,304 --> 00:39:59,293
(narrator) On May 25th Boulogne fell.

481
00:40:03,440 --> 00:40:06,888
On May 26, Calais.

482
00:40:09,923 --> 00:40:13,906
Weygand's appointment had given
the French a flicker of optimism.

483
00:40:13,990 --> 00:40:16,445
It soon faded when
his counterattack failed

484
00:40:16,522 --> 00:40:21,116
and news of Belgium's capitulation
reached Paris on May 28.

485
00:40:21,203 --> 00:40:26,757
Thereafter, the mood became
steadily more and more defeatist.

486
00:40:29,374 --> 00:40:33,171
(Waterfield) I think the defeatism
came at the top.

487
00:40:33,249 --> 00:40:37,352
There was a very strong peace move
among certain politicians,

488
00:40:37,431 --> 00:40:41,305
some of them were even pro-German
and wanted jobs with the Germans.

489
00:40:41,421 --> 00:40:47,324
When things went badly, this group got
larger and became more dominant.

490
00:40:48,979 --> 00:40:51,193
(narrator) Prime Minster Reynaud
fought back

491
00:40:51,319 --> 00:40:53,534
by dismissing from his cabinet
weaker spirits

492
00:40:53,659 --> 00:40:55,994
and bringing in fighting men
like de Gaulle,

493
00:40:56,076 --> 00:40:58,946
now entering the political arena
for the first time.

494
00:40:59,069 --> 00:41:01,752
But the war
was virtually out of their hands.

495
00:41:01,831 --> 00:41:05,628
Perhaps it was that that prompted the
special service of prayer at Notre Dame

496
00:41:05,706 --> 00:41:08,237
on that Sunday before Dunkirk.

497
00:41:08,315 --> 00:41:10,267
(organ plays)

498
00:41:21,167 --> 00:41:27,026
(Spears) The French very soon accepted
the idea of defeat and surrendered.

499
00:41:27,113 --> 00:41:33,442
To them it was rather a conception
of the old days of the royalty

500
00:41:33,520 --> 00:41:37,153
when you just exchanged
a couple of provinces,

501
00:41:37,242 --> 00:41:39,959
paid a certain number of millions,

502
00:41:40,042 --> 00:41:44,450
and then called it a day,
hoping you'd be more lucky next time.

503
00:41:51,283 --> 00:41:54,382
(narrator) Dunkirk fell on June 4.

504
00:41:54,928 --> 00:41:59,063
Hitler ordered church bells to be rung
for three days throughout Germany

505
00:41:59,186 --> 00:42:03,780
to mark what he described as
"the greatest German victory ever".

506
00:42:09,123 --> 00:42:11,611
With the panzers reorganised
and re-equipped,

507
00:42:11,693 --> 00:42:14,410
the day after Dunkirk fell,

508
00:42:14,494 --> 00:42:18,630
the second major German offensive
in the West began.

509
00:42:48,101 --> 00:42:51,397
Although outnumbered now
by more than two to one,

510
00:42:51,477 --> 00:42:52,972
the French fought stubbornly -

511
00:42:53,050 --> 00:42:55,418
much more aggressively, in fact,

512
00:42:55,506 --> 00:42:57,840
than at any time during
the battle for the Meuse.

513
00:43:11,542 --> 00:43:17,172
But after three days of bloody fighting,
disaster once more overtook the French.

514
00:43:25,238 --> 00:43:27,420
Another breakthrough by Rommel.

515
00:43:27,502 --> 00:43:32,488
In a matter of hours
he had reached the Seine at Rouen.

516
00:43:47,759 --> 00:43:51,665
Elsewhere the panzers
were passing almost effortlessly

517
00:43:51,749 --> 00:43:54,280
through the heartland of France.

518
00:44:03,795 --> 00:44:05,977
All roads pointed to Paris.

519
00:44:07,094 --> 00:44:11,884
On June 10th
the French government left the capital.

520
00:44:11,967 --> 00:44:15,797
On that day Mussolini
brought Italy into the war.

521
00:44:19,371 --> 00:44:22,623
On the day we left Paris

522
00:44:22,709 --> 00:44:29,529
we went to this Vincennes headquarters
of Gamelin

523
00:44:29,615 --> 00:44:34,525
and... we heard on the radio

524
00:44:34,602 --> 00:44:39,775
all the songs and music
of the Italian war, you know.

525
00:44:39,896 --> 00:44:43,192
"Giovinezza" and all that, you know.

526
00:44:43,272 --> 00:44:45,564
And we thought...

527
00:44:45,689 --> 00:44:49,093
And that is where I heard
the first time somebody say,

528
00:44:49,181 --> 00:44:50,937
"It can't go on like that."

529
00:44:51,022 --> 00:44:53,237
"We must have an armistice."

530
00:44:53,324 --> 00:44:56,237
We had the greatest difficulty
getting out of Paris

531
00:44:56,317 --> 00:44:58,924
because everybody,
although Paris was empty,

532
00:44:59,040 --> 00:45:03,787
all the roads outside Paris
were absolutely full of motorcars,

533
00:45:03,874 --> 00:45:08,621
people even going in and out of the
trees at the side to try and get ahead.

534
00:45:08,708 --> 00:45:14,492
But we were able to get off the
main roads into the countryside,

535
00:45:14,578 --> 00:45:18,375
and then it was most extraordinary
because it was beautiful weather,

536
00:45:18,453 --> 00:45:20,787
all the villagers were very welcoming

537
00:45:20,908 --> 00:45:24,050
and brought out their best cognac,
their best wine,

538
00:45:24,131 --> 00:45:27,001
because they said,
"Why leave it for the Germans?"

539
00:45:27,123 --> 00:45:31,073
Arriving in the airspace over Paris

540
00:45:31,152 --> 00:45:37,132
I observed that great columns of German
infantry had already entered the town.

541
00:45:38,901 --> 00:45:44,194
Observing this and remembering
that we had failed to reach this goal

542
00:45:44,273 --> 00:45:48,713
all through the First World War,

543
00:45:48,800 --> 00:45:53,437
I felt such joy and exultation

544
00:45:53,518 --> 00:45:59,269
that I asked the pilot of my
small plane, a so-called Storch,

545
00:45:59,350 --> 00:46:05,406
whether it would be possible to perform
a landing on the Place de la Concorde.

546
00:46:05,527 --> 00:46:09,858
After circling around some time,

547
00:46:09,939 --> 00:46:14,925
he and... we came down
on the Place de la Concorde,

548
00:46:15,003 --> 00:46:18,832
which was entirely free of any traffic

549
00:46:19,798 --> 00:46:24,163
and landed on the outside
of the Champs Elysées.

550
00:46:31,308 --> 00:46:35,868
(narrator) Two days after Paris fell,
the new prime minister, Marshal Pétain

551
00:46:35,950 --> 00:46:38,055
asked the Germans for an armistice.

552
00:46:38,137 --> 00:46:41,585
Reynaud had been opposed to
a separate peace and resigned.

553
00:46:41,666 --> 00:46:47,034
In most of France the news of
an armistice was received with relief.

554
00:46:50,260 --> 00:46:53,206
Hitler insisted on using
for the negotiations

555
00:46:53,329 --> 00:46:57,082
Marshal Foch's old railway carriage
in the woods of Compiègne,

556
00:46:57,166 --> 00:47:00,886
where the 1918 armistice
had been signed.

557
00:47:00,964 --> 00:47:04,335
It was the supreme humiliation
for France.

558
00:47:24,520 --> 00:47:28,731
(Beaufre) One must have lived
the retreat in France,

559
00:47:28,893 --> 00:47:33,105
with this enormous movement of crowds.

560
00:47:33,190 --> 00:47:37,446
It's something which you can't
understand if you haven't seen it.

561
00:47:37,525 --> 00:47:40,777
We thought that really
that had to be stopped.

562
00:47:50,685 --> 00:47:55,474
(narrator) Once the French had signed,
Hitler ordered the site destroyed.

563
00:47:55,557 --> 00:47:58,350
Germany had had its revenge.

564
00:47:59,048 --> 00:48:02,147
(announcement in French)

565
00:48:12,476 --> 00:48:15,193
(narrator) Paris radio,
now under German control,

566
00:48:15,276 --> 00:48:18,910
broadcast the terms of the armistice.

567
00:48:52,107 --> 00:48:56,089
Paris had now to adapt
to a new wave of tourists.

568
00:48:56,173 --> 00:48:58,432
Among the first was Hitler himself,

569
00:48:58,513 --> 00:49:01,351
making the only trip of his life
to the city,

570
00:49:01,429 --> 00:49:03,644
and a fleeting one at that.

571
00:49:16,507 --> 00:49:21,296
For four bleak years France was to
disappear from the forefront of the war.

572
00:49:22,108 --> 00:49:28,284
Some Frenchmen chose a courageous
resistance at home or overseas,

573
00:49:28,361 --> 00:49:32,191
others were to settle into a routine
of apathetic collaboration.

574
00:49:32,812 --> 00:49:35,911
Many connived at Hitler's
new order for Europe -

575
00:49:35,996 --> 00:49:38,178
the Vichy version.

576
00:50:01,585 --> 00:50:04,881
For Paris there remained
one more humiliation.

577
00:50:14,898 --> 00:50:16,240
The German triumphal parade

578
00:50:16,317 --> 00:50:19,230
followed the exact route
of the French victory procession

579
00:50:19,348 --> 00:50:21,759
after the First World War.

580
00:50:36,919 --> 00:50:42,549
It had taken the Wehrmacht just five
weeks to humble their historic foe.

581
00:50:57,137 --> 00:50:59,352
In the words of Winston Churchill:

582
00:50:59,439 --> 00:51:02,767
"The Battle of France was now over."

583
00:51:02,854 --> 00:51:05,265
"The Battle of Britain
was about to begin."
