1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:19,259 --> 00:00:22,478
(narrator) Russia: mid-June 1941.

3
00:00:22,559 --> 00:00:25,505
A bewildered, uncertain country.

4
00:00:25,589 --> 00:00:29,921
Rumours abounded
of invasion by Hitler's Germany.

5
00:00:47,803 --> 00:00:51,752
Here in the Kremlin, Russia's leaders
seemed oblivious of the Nazi threat,

6
00:00:51,831 --> 00:00:53,784
or if not oblivious, then complacent,

7
00:00:53,903 --> 00:00:57,809
as if, by ignoring it,
it might disappear.

8
00:01:03,379 --> 00:01:07,361
Yet already, millions of German troops
were poised along Russia's border

9
00:01:07,445 --> 00:01:10,238
to launch the bloodiest land battle
in history -

10
00:01:10,323 --> 00:01:14,197
the battle that was eventually
to decide the Second World War.

11
00:02:09,366 --> 00:02:13,502
(crowd)
Ein Volk, ein Reich, ein Führer!

12
00:02:13,586 --> 00:02:17,645
Wenn die Soldaten
durch die Stadt marschieren

13
00:02:17,730 --> 00:02:19,792
Öffnen die Mädchen

14
00:02:19,878 --> 00:02:21,372
Die Fenster und die Türen

15
00:02:21,451 --> 00:02:23,666
Ei warum
Ei darum

16
00:02:23,906 --> 00:02:25,554
Ei warum
Ei darum

17
00:02:25,671 --> 00:02:29,468
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

18
00:02:29,623 --> 00:02:33,497
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa...

19
00:02:33,574 --> 00:02:37,906
(narrator) Hitler in July 1940,
returning from France in triumph,

20
00:02:37,986 --> 00:02:40,594
stood at the pinnacle of his power.

21
00:02:40,710 --> 00:02:42,237
..Die Mädchen ach so gerne

22
00:02:42,321 --> 00:02:44,274
Ei warum
Ei darum

23
00:02:44,508 --> 00:02:46,494
Ei warum
Ei darum

24
00:02:46,580 --> 00:02:50,454
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

25
00:02:50,647 --> 00:02:54,706
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

26
00:03:03,959 --> 00:03:07,909
(narrator) The sureness of His
victories astonished even his generals.

27
00:03:07,988 --> 00:03:13,968
Their doubts had been answered,
their opposition could be discounted.

28
00:03:15,354 --> 00:03:20,875
It was now that Hitler confided to them
it would be the Russians' turn next.

29
00:03:25,904 --> 00:03:27,398
(crowd) Sieg Heil!

30
00:03:27,515 --> 00:03:30,582
(narrator) In Mein Kampf,
Adolf Hitler had written :

31
00:03:30,661 --> 00:03:33,608
"When we speak of new territory,
we must think of Russia."

32
00:03:33,692 --> 00:03:36,256
"Destiny itself points the way there."

33
00:03:36,339 --> 00:03:38,794
(German national anthem)

34
00:03:41,787 --> 00:03:45,115
(narrator) Russia would provide
living space for the German Volk -

35
00:03:45,201 --> 00:03:46,696
Lebensraum.

36
00:03:47,311 --> 00:03:51,523
(crowd) Heil! Heil! Heil!

37
00:04:03,732 --> 00:04:08,216
Heil! Heil! Heil!

38
00:04:08,297 --> 00:04:10,021
(narrator) The ordinary German,

39
00:04:10,100 --> 00:04:13,047
Iike the ordinary Russian
or ordinary person anywhere,

40
00:04:13,169 --> 00:04:17,764
had been surprised by Hitler's pact
with Stalin in August 1939.

41
00:04:17,850 --> 00:04:21,375
To him, as to them, it had seemed
the least likely about-face

42
00:04:21,456 --> 00:04:24,249
by the world's bitterest rivals.

43
00:04:32,889 --> 00:04:36,446
The Nazi-Soviet Pact
had served its purpose for Hitler.

44
00:04:36,533 --> 00:04:40,789
He had not been hindered
while he dealt with Poland and France.

45
00:04:40,869 --> 00:04:43,552
Stalin, for his part,
gained a breathing space

46
00:04:43,631 --> 00:04:47,810
while he put his army in order after
the blood-letting purges of the '30s.

47
00:04:47,889 --> 00:04:53,902
He had gambled, too, on a lengthy
struggle between Germany and the Allies.

48
00:04:59,015 --> 00:05:03,609
But the German victories in the west
had been swifter than he had expected.

49
00:05:03,696 --> 00:05:09,021
(man) Hitler wanted to attack Russia
already in the fall of 1940,

50
00:05:09,105 --> 00:05:14,964
and let himself, for once, be persuaded

51
00:05:15,052 --> 00:05:20,148
that it would be impossible
to go to war at that late time

52
00:05:20,231 --> 00:05:23,330
on account of the weather in Russia,

53
00:05:23,876 --> 00:05:26,090
and for the reason that it would be

54
00:05:26,178 --> 00:05:31,241
urgent and necessary

55
00:05:31,318 --> 00:05:33,424
to enforce the German army,

56
00:05:33,505 --> 00:05:35,872
as well as the German air force,

57
00:05:35,961 --> 00:05:38,983
before entering into this new campaign.

58
00:05:39,068 --> 00:05:45,353
In August '39, when Hitler
had signed the pact with Russia,

59
00:05:45,437 --> 00:05:47,466
in the evening, there was a movie,

60
00:05:47,547 --> 00:05:53,373
and this movie showed the parade of
the Russian troops before the Kremlin.

61
00:05:53,455 --> 00:05:58,202
He was very much impressed and
was relieved that now, with the pact,

62
00:05:58,327 --> 00:06:01,469
this army is neutralised.

63
00:06:02,471 --> 00:06:08,908
But afterwards, when the German troops
met the Russian ones

64
00:06:08,993 --> 00:06:11,939
in occupying Poland,

65
00:06:12,023 --> 00:06:14,435
officers reported to Hitler

66
00:06:14,517 --> 00:06:21,916
that the equipment
of those Russian units were very poor.

67
00:06:21,998 --> 00:06:24,606
He first didn't believe it so much,

68
00:06:24,684 --> 00:06:27,750
but then when the Russians
attacked the Finns

69
00:06:27,830 --> 00:06:31,234
and they didn't have any progress,

70
00:06:31,321 --> 00:06:35,686
he was convinced
that this was really the truth

71
00:06:35,848 --> 00:06:41,632
and he was now considering
the Russian army

72
00:06:41,756 --> 00:06:43,786
no more as strong as before.

73
00:06:47,818 --> 00:06:52,183
(narrator) Doubts about the Red Army's
strength had been raised inside Russia.

74
00:06:52,268 --> 00:06:55,138
The purges of the '30s
had decimated its leadership.

75
00:06:55,222 --> 00:07:00,241
90% of its generals, 80% of its colonels
and well over half its corps commanders

76
00:07:00,325 --> 00:07:03,499
had been put to death at Stalin's whim.

77
00:07:10,146 --> 00:07:14,664
Every single commander
of a military district was eliminated.

78
00:07:14,750 --> 00:07:18,929
Every single commander
of an army division has been eliminated.

79
00:07:19,008 --> 00:07:22,991
Every single commander of a regiment,
with some exceptions here,

80
00:07:23,075 --> 00:07:24,755
also eliminated.

81
00:07:24,840 --> 00:07:30,088
Now, you see, this is a little more
than political weakness.

82
00:07:30,211 --> 00:07:32,819
The army was beheaded, so to speak.

83
00:07:50,621 --> 00:07:53,992
(narrator) After the Red Army's
poor performance against the Finns,

84
00:07:54,074 --> 00:07:56,867
steps were taken to reform it.

85
00:07:56,951 --> 00:08:00,399
When news reached Moscow of
the Wehrmacht's crushing of the French,

86
00:08:00,481 --> 00:08:03,121
these reforms were accelerated.

87
00:08:03,205 --> 00:08:06,838
They were still incomplete
by the summer of 1940.

88
00:08:06,926 --> 00:08:08,988
All the same, Stalin seized his chance

89
00:08:09,074 --> 00:08:11,944
while Hitler was preoccupied
with the battle for Britain

90
00:08:12,029 --> 00:08:17,932
to grab first the Baltic States
of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania,

91
00:08:18,013 --> 00:08:19,999
and then, within the same month,

92
00:08:20,085 --> 00:08:24,908
those parts of Romania known as
Bessarabia and northern Bukovina -

93
00:08:24,996 --> 00:08:27,363
a move that, to Hitler,
brought Russian troops

94
00:08:27,451 --> 00:08:31,009
uncomfortably close
to the Romanian oil wells at Ploesti,

95
00:08:31,134 --> 00:08:33,239
Germany's only oil supply,

96
00:08:33,321 --> 00:08:37,118
vital for its tanks and planes
and ships.

97
00:08:43,871 --> 00:08:46,402
But with the bulk of his forces
still in the west,

98
00:08:46,480 --> 00:08:49,121
Hitler did not intervene.

99
00:08:49,204 --> 00:08:51,386
Instead, he stepped up
diplomatic pressure

100
00:08:51,506 --> 00:08:55,183
to woo the Balkans into the German fold.

101
00:09:02,056 --> 00:09:04,849
First, King Boris of Bulgaria
was invited

102
00:09:04,934 --> 00:09:08,033
to visit Hitler that autumn
at Berchtesgaden,

103
00:09:08,118 --> 00:09:10,726
and he was followed
by Prince Paul of Yugoslavia

104
00:09:10,803 --> 00:09:13,673
and by young King Michael of Romania.

105
00:09:13,758 --> 00:09:15,514
Michael was already under the sway

106
00:09:15,599 --> 00:09:18,741
of his pro-German prime minister,
Antonescu.

107
00:09:21,124 --> 00:09:25,608
When news broke that Romania
and Hungary had joined the Axis,

108
00:09:25,689 --> 00:09:27,718
the Russians reacted sharply.

109
00:09:27,799 --> 00:09:32,895
They accused Berlin of violating
the spirit of the August 1939 pact.

110
00:09:32,978 --> 00:09:38,652
The frail Soviet-German friendship
was beginning to fall apart.

111
00:09:41,342 --> 00:09:44,670
Hitler, that same month,
further strengthened the Axis.

112
00:09:44,756 --> 00:09:48,706
He signed a new military alliance
with Italy and with Japan -

113
00:09:48,785 --> 00:09:51,152
the Tripartite Pact.

114
00:09:52,775 --> 00:09:56,724
It was aimed, allegedly,
at only the United States and Britain.

115
00:09:56,803 --> 00:10:01,669
The Russians thought otherwise.
They protested angrily.

116
00:10:10,499 --> 00:10:13,827
Hitler invited Stalin's closest adviser,
Molotov,

117
00:10:13,914 --> 00:10:16,860
to Berlin that November 1940,

118
00:10:16,944 --> 00:10:21,080
to help, as he put it,
"clarify the situation".

119
00:10:23,543 --> 00:10:27,417
It was a disastrous visit
for Soviet-German relations.

120
00:10:37,661 --> 00:10:40,454
(Speer) When Molotov visited Berlin,

121
00:10:40,539 --> 00:10:44,336
he was obviously afraid of
being poisoned by bacteria

122
00:10:44,414 --> 00:10:49,739
and he asked that all the plates,
all the glasses he used

123
00:10:49,823 --> 00:10:53,620
are boiled before they came in use.

124
00:10:53,698 --> 00:10:56,262
(man) He was blunt in his remarks

125
00:10:56,345 --> 00:10:58,953
and he didn't spare Hitler at all.

126
00:10:59,031 --> 00:11:01,638
Very uncompromising,

127
00:11:01,716 --> 00:11:06,463
hardly smiling at all,
reminding me of my mathematics teacher,

128
00:11:06,550 --> 00:11:10,958
with the spectacles -
hostile spectacles -

129
00:11:11,039 --> 00:11:15,065
looking at his pupil, Hitler,
and saying,

130
00:11:15,144 --> 00:11:16,671
"Is our agreement -

131
00:11:16,793 --> 00:11:18,823
last year's agreement - still valid?"

132
00:11:18,942 --> 00:11:21,004
Hitler thought it was a mistranslation.

133
00:11:21,090 --> 00:11:22,846
He said, "Of course. Why not?"

134
00:11:22,970 --> 00:11:24,651
And Molotov said, "Yes,

135
00:11:24,735 --> 00:11:27,419
I ask this question
because of the Finns."

136
00:11:27,497 --> 00:11:30,138
"You're on very friendly relations
with the Finns."

137
00:11:30,221 --> 00:11:34,051
"You invite people from Finland to
Germany and send the missions there."

138
00:11:34,134 --> 00:11:38,957
"The Finns are very dangerous people.
They undermine our security."

139
00:11:39,045 --> 00:11:41,184
"We'll have to do something about that,

140
00:11:41,270 --> 00:11:43,485
and we are going
to do something about that."

141
00:11:43,572 --> 00:11:47,479
Whereupon Hitler exploded and said,
"I understand you very well."

142
00:11:47,562 --> 00:11:52,199
"You want to wage war against Finland,

143
00:11:52,281 --> 00:11:55,762
and that is quite out of the question,
do you hear me? Impossible!"

144
00:11:55,849 --> 00:12:00,409
"Because my supplies
of iron and of nickel

145
00:12:00,491 --> 00:12:04,365
and of other important raw materials
would be cut."

146
00:12:04,443 --> 00:12:06,625
It was a very tough,

147
00:12:06,706 --> 00:12:11,617
almost a heavyweight championship
in political discussion.

148
00:12:11,693 --> 00:12:14,454
(narrator) Even while Molotov
was still in Berlin,

149
00:12:14,532 --> 00:12:19,901
Hitler ordered his generals to plan
an attack on Russia for May 15, 1941.

150
00:12:19,980 --> 00:12:25,348
They responded with a detailed scheme
which he named "Operation Barbarossa"

151
00:12:25,428 --> 00:12:28,679
after the red-bearded Prussian emperor
who, centuries earlier,

152
00:12:28,766 --> 00:12:31,526
had crusaded against the Slavs.

153
00:12:31,605 --> 00:12:34,442
Hitler's generals had taken
some convincing.

154
00:12:34,559 --> 00:12:38,356
To attack Russia with Britain resisting
was to fight a war on two fronts,

155
00:12:38,434 --> 00:12:40,922
something that
even Mein Kampf maintained

156
00:12:41,004 --> 00:12:43,645
to be the gravest of military mistakes.

157
00:12:43,728 --> 00:12:47,787
But Hitler argued,
and with some truth that winter of 1940,

158
00:12:47,910 --> 00:12:51,587
that Britain, although not beaten,
was not a threat,

159
00:12:51,670 --> 00:12:57,922
so an eastern campaign would be the only
front, provided it was over quickly.

160
00:13:00,493 --> 00:13:05,240
Years earlier, Hitler had written,
"Armies do not exist for peace."

161
00:13:05,327 --> 00:13:10,238
"They exist solely
for triumphant exertion in war."

162
00:13:27,195 --> 00:13:30,108
The Wehrmacht's morale
was at its height.

163
00:13:30,188 --> 00:13:34,062
Where was it to march next?
It couldn't move against Britain on land

164
00:13:34,139 --> 00:13:36,780
and amphibious warfare
was not to Hitler's liking.

165
00:13:36,863 --> 00:13:39,045
Magnetism alone, it seemed,

166
00:13:39,165 --> 00:13:42,962
must draw it against its sole
remaining antagonist within Europe,

167
00:13:43,040 --> 00:13:46,793
draw it in the same way
as Napoleon's armies had been drawn

168
00:13:46,877 --> 00:13:50,248
when they, too, had been left
champing at the bit along the Channel -

169
00:13:50,406 --> 00:13:52,773
eastwards, ever eastwards,

170
00:13:52,861 --> 00:13:55,699
to the boundless motherland of Russia.

171
00:14:30,728 --> 00:14:33,445
The Red Army in 1941
was the largest in the world.

172
00:14:33,528 --> 00:14:35,176
In tanks, it outnumbered,

173
00:14:35,255 --> 00:14:40,503
in airplanes, it equalled the rest
of the world's armies put together.

174
00:14:48,912 --> 00:14:52,241
Despite its shortcomings,
the Red Army was better equipped

175
00:14:52,327 --> 00:14:54,738
than previous Wehrmacht victims,

176
00:14:54,821 --> 00:14:59,567
and its reorganisation since the fiasco
of the Finnish war was well under way.

177
00:14:59,731 --> 00:15:03,638
But what of its morale?
Hitler felt sure he knew the answer:

178
00:15:03,721 --> 00:15:05,369
"You have only to kick in the door

179
00:15:05,448 --> 00:15:09,551
and the whole rotten structure
will come crashing down."

180
00:15:10,550 --> 00:15:13,769
Russia's leaders still thought
they could buy time

181
00:15:13,850 --> 00:15:16,948
while their army made ready
for the struggle.

182
00:15:25,704 --> 00:15:29,883
By March 1941, Russian troops were
already being faced by German troops

183
00:15:29,963 --> 00:15:34,022
along the borders of Hungary
and Romania, and even Bulgaria.

184
00:15:34,106 --> 00:15:37,739
Yugoslavia, too, looked like
becoming a German satellite until,

185
00:15:37,828 --> 00:15:39,737
encouraged by British intelligence,

186
00:15:39,823 --> 00:15:44,263
a popular uprising in Belgrade
pushed out the Nazi puppets.

187
00:15:44,350 --> 00:15:48,758
Incredibly, Moscow
concluded a pact with the rebels.

188
00:15:48,838 --> 00:15:52,820
The very next day,
Hitler attacked Yugoslavia.

189
00:15:57,278 --> 00:16:01,643
Incensed by the revolt,
he named the operation "Retribution".

190
00:16:40,324 --> 00:16:44,230
Operation Retribution
meant postponing Operation Barbarossa

191
00:16:44,314 --> 00:16:46,845
by five crucial weeks.

192
00:16:46,923 --> 00:16:52,749
But now Russia stood by while
the Wehrmacht overran her newest ally.

193
00:17:07,946 --> 00:17:13,315
Hitler marched into Greece, again
without Moscow so much as protesting.

194
00:17:18,036 --> 00:17:21,440
This inaction made Hitler
even more headstrong

195
00:17:21,528 --> 00:17:24,474
as his armies swept on
to further easy victories.

196
00:17:34,226 --> 00:17:36,638
Stalin's spies had been
sending back reports

197
00:17:36,720 --> 00:17:39,328
of German troop concentrations
along his borders,

198
00:17:39,406 --> 00:17:41,894
reports which he chose to ignore.

199
00:17:41,976 --> 00:17:45,042
When Western diplomats warned him too,
he shrugged them off.

200
00:17:45,122 --> 00:17:46,616
He argued to his cronies

201
00:17:46,695 --> 00:17:49,641
that however inevitable
a Nazi-Soviet conflict might be,

202
00:17:49,726 --> 00:17:52,748
these present reports
were simply a British ruse.

203
00:17:52,833 --> 00:17:57,274
(man) The interesting thing was
that both Roosevelt and Churchill

204
00:17:57,399 --> 00:18:01,381
informed Stalin
that Hitler was going to attack Russia.

205
00:18:01,465 --> 00:18:03,146
Stalin thought that was a trick

206
00:18:03,307 --> 00:18:04,725
on our part

207
00:18:04,803 --> 00:18:08,524
to get him to mobilise and to divert,

208
00:18:08,601 --> 00:18:10,325
to provoke Hitler into attack.

209
00:18:10,404 --> 00:18:12,935
Stalin was very conscious that

210
00:18:13,013 --> 00:18:14,737
in World War I,

211
00:18:14,816 --> 00:18:18,646
it was the Tsar's mobilisation

212
00:18:18,730 --> 00:18:23,399
that caused the German -

213
00:18:23,487 --> 00:18:26,204
the Kaiser - to attack Russia,

214
00:18:26,287 --> 00:18:28,743
and he wasn't going
to have any part of it.

215
00:18:28,819 --> 00:18:32,300
There is a traditional
pathological mistrust.

216
00:18:32,387 --> 00:18:35,148
When the British say something,

217
00:18:35,226 --> 00:18:40,137
Stalin's philosophy used to tell us,
"You must think the opposite".

218
00:18:40,214 --> 00:18:42,199
If the British warn us,

219
00:18:42,324 --> 00:18:48,075
that must mean that
they try to put us against the Germans.

220
00:18:48,155 --> 00:18:53,404
For that reason - the main reason -
he neglected all the warnings.

221
00:18:53,488 --> 00:18:55,747
(narrator) May Day in Moscow, 1941.

222
00:18:56,289 --> 00:18:58,427
(rousing, patriotic song)

223
00:19:02,197 --> 00:19:04,761
A particularly impressive
military parade,

224
00:19:04,844 --> 00:19:06,873
as if to reassure the Russian people

225
00:19:06,992 --> 00:19:11,357
in the face of all the rumours
of impending invasion.

226
00:19:19,346 --> 00:19:21,986
Russian diplomacy
was aimed at appeasing Hitler,

227
00:19:22,070 --> 00:19:28,050
hoping to delay any attack until the
Red Army's reforms would be complete.

228
00:19:30,664 --> 00:19:32,878
And so, while the generals lectured,

229
00:19:32,965 --> 00:19:36,523
the diplomats rushed grain and
much-needed raw materials to Germany,

230
00:19:36,610 --> 00:19:40,091
turned a blind eye to the incursions
of German reconnaissance planes

231
00:19:40,178 --> 00:19:41,705
over Soviet territory

232
00:19:41,828 --> 00:19:45,046
and even slowed down
their building of frontier defences

233
00:19:45,127 --> 00:19:47,767
so as not to offend Berlin.

234
00:19:51,419 --> 00:19:53,558
Yet even as Stalin's defence commissar

235
00:19:53,644 --> 00:19:56,710
shook hands with
Hitler's military attaché in Moscow,

236
00:19:56,790 --> 00:20:00,772
three million German troops
were moving up to the border.

237
00:20:00,857 --> 00:20:04,960
The biggest land battle in history
was about to begin.

238
00:20:42,866 --> 00:20:44,971
The shock was all the greater
when it came.

239
00:20:45,053 --> 00:20:47,344
I remember that night, I'd been out

240
00:20:47,431 --> 00:20:50,454
and came home rather late
and turned on the radio,

241
00:20:50,539 --> 00:20:52,524
and I got onto, I think it was Kharkov

242
00:20:52,611 --> 00:20:54,182
or Kiev or somewhere like that,

243
00:20:54,260 --> 00:20:57,327
and there were accounts going on

244
00:20:57,406 --> 00:20:59,359
of bombing and attacks and things,

245
00:20:59,440 --> 00:21:02,506
which I thought was
a sort of Orson Welles programme,

246
00:21:02,586 --> 00:21:06,383
Iike when he bombed New York,
remember?

247
00:21:06,460 --> 00:21:08,828
Then we checked around
and found it was real.

248
00:21:19,504 --> 00:21:24,415
We were told that the Red Army
will never fight on its own territory,

249
00:21:24,492 --> 00:21:28,049
that the very first shot
will be made on enemy's territory.

250
00:21:28,137 --> 00:21:29,937
Then, suddenly, on the 22nd,

251
00:21:30,016 --> 00:21:33,388
we were told that Sevastopol
is being bombed, Kiev is being bombed,

252
00:21:33,469 --> 00:21:37,419
Smolensk, bombed.
The enemy smashed, wiped out our forces.

253
00:21:53,227 --> 00:21:56,064
(man) After the success
of the other campaigns,

254
00:21:56,143 --> 00:22:01,588
we had confidence
that Barbarossa would be successful too.

255
00:22:06,616 --> 00:22:11,527
(man #2) The first period
of the advance was very quick.

256
00:22:11,604 --> 00:22:16,426
We made more than 100km per day.

257
00:22:20,658 --> 00:22:26,409
(man #3) We hadn't lost a battle,
so we were used to being victorious.

258
00:22:26,528 --> 00:22:29,016
(narrator) Hitler's plan
was for three armies

259
00:22:29,098 --> 00:22:33,888
to seek out and destroy
the Russian forces within four months.

260
00:22:34,009 --> 00:22:36,879
(man #4) I never was in a war before.

261
00:22:36,963 --> 00:22:39,330
We had no fear

262
00:22:39,418 --> 00:22:44,362
because we thought
we will win the war against Russia,

263
00:22:44,482 --> 00:22:50,418
because the wars against
Poland and France,

264
00:22:50,928 --> 00:22:54,758
we had ended with victories for Germany.

265
00:23:00,557 --> 00:23:02,205
(narrator) As well as surprise,

266
00:23:02,284 --> 00:23:06,692
the Germans had overwhelming superiority
in men and fire power

267
00:23:06,811 --> 00:23:10,259
at those points
chosen for their armoured thrusts.

268
00:23:10,340 --> 00:23:15,087
Three Russian infantry divisions
were annihilated that first day,

269
00:23:15,213 --> 00:23:18,082
and another five cut to pieces.

270
00:23:26,837 --> 00:23:30,089
(man #2) During the River Bug crossing,

271
00:23:30,213 --> 00:23:37,109
we were attacked
by several obsolete Russian aircraft

272
00:23:37,234 --> 00:23:39,765
that were shot down immediately

273
00:23:39,843 --> 00:23:41,948
and we were very impressed

274
00:23:42,068 --> 00:23:45,745
by the superiority of our air force
at the beginning.

275
00:23:55,457 --> 00:23:57,519
(narrator) During the first two days,

276
00:23:57,606 --> 00:24:01,239
2,000 Russian planes were destroyed,
mostly on the ground.

277
00:24:05,394 --> 00:24:09,268
The world's largest air force
had been well-nigh eradicated.

278
00:24:10,803 --> 00:24:16,707
Their air cover gone, the Russian
frontier armies wilted and disappeared.

279
00:24:27,761 --> 00:24:32,169
In a week, the Wehrmacht
was already halfway to Moscow.

280
00:24:32,940 --> 00:24:37,457
In a month, the Germans had won an area
double the size of their own country.

281
00:24:37,544 --> 00:24:41,832
("Wenn die Soldaten
durch die Stadt marschieren")

282
00:24:41,917 --> 00:24:43,870
Wenn die Soldaten

283
00:24:43,950 --> 00:24:46,132
Durch die Stadt marschieren

284
00:24:46,214 --> 00:24:48,090
Öffnen die Mädchen

285
00:24:48,171 --> 00:24:49,971
Die Fenster und die Türen

286
00:24:50,050 --> 00:24:52,232
Ei warum
Ei darum

287
00:24:52,467 --> 00:24:54,224
Ei warum
Ei darum

288
00:24:54,347 --> 00:24:58,144
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

289
00:24:58,376 --> 00:25:02,631
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

290
00:25:02,749 --> 00:25:04,549
Zweifarben Tücher

291
00:25:04,629 --> 00:25:06,888
Schnauzbart und Sterne

292
00:25:06,969 --> 00:25:08,802
Herzen und küssen

293
00:25:08,888 --> 00:25:10,764
Die Mädchen ach so gerne

294
00:25:10,844 --> 00:25:15,405
Ei warum
Ei darum

295
00:25:15,486 --> 00:25:23,157
Ei bloß wegen dem Schingderassa,
Bumderassasa

296
00:25:31,523 --> 00:25:34,774
(narrator) Russian cities
fell like ninepins to the panzers.

297
00:25:34,861 --> 00:25:37,195
One was captured
with its trams still running.

298
00:25:37,316 --> 00:25:42,684
Its citizens, heading to work, cheered
German tanks, thinking them their own.

299
00:25:45,641 --> 00:25:51,849
(man #2) We were, in parts, very
friendly received by the population.

300
00:25:52,432 --> 00:25:58,183
We had the impression that
we could win the population in Russia.

301
00:26:05,476 --> 00:26:07,964
(narrator) Like the French
the summer before,

302
00:26:08,046 --> 00:26:10,577
the Russians used their tanks
in penny packets

303
00:26:10,655 --> 00:26:14,911
instead of the mass formations
of the German panzers.

304
00:26:20,476 --> 00:26:23,269
Easy meat
for the German antitank gunners,

305
00:26:23,354 --> 00:26:26,420
their blazing hulks
littered the battlefield.

306
00:26:26,500 --> 00:26:28,867
6,000 Russian tanks were lost

307
00:26:28,955 --> 00:26:34,400
in just two engagements
at Minsk and Smolensk in July.

308
00:26:34,479 --> 00:26:37,578
(lively German song)

309
00:26:53,240 --> 00:26:57,376
(narrator) Half a million Russians
were killed in the first fortnight,

310
00:26:57,460 --> 00:27:00,177
and nearly a million taken prisoner.

311
00:27:02,716 --> 00:27:07,386
As the weeks went by, the Russian losses
mounted, bewildering the Germans,

312
00:27:07,512 --> 00:27:11,494
who refused to believe such profligacy
in human life could possibly continue.

313
00:27:16,067 --> 00:27:18,096
As in France the year before,

314
00:27:18,177 --> 00:27:21,625
Hitler was concerned more
to destroy enemy forces in the field

315
00:27:21,707 --> 00:27:25,427
than to capture cities
or to conquer territory.

316
00:27:28,689 --> 00:27:31,559
His generals
didn't always see it that way.

317
00:27:31,643 --> 00:27:33,705
Tempted, perhaps, by golden spires,

318
00:27:33,791 --> 00:27:37,469
they vied with each other to be
the captor of this or that great city,

319
00:27:37,551 --> 00:27:39,766
especially Moscow.

320
00:28:01,568 --> 00:28:05,016
To capture the Russian capital
without delay, the generals argued,

321
00:28:05,097 --> 00:28:06,777
would be decisive.

322
00:28:06,862 --> 00:28:10,157
Hitler preferred to destroy
the Russian forces in the south first,

323
00:28:10,276 --> 00:28:13,495
hoping for a decisive battle there.

324
00:28:13,576 --> 00:28:17,100
Moscow was not his first priority.

325
00:28:17,182 --> 00:28:21,513
In August,
he ordered his panzers to swing south.

326
00:28:22,975 --> 00:28:24,808
Kiev,

327
00:28:24,893 --> 00:28:29,454
the capital of the Ukraine,
was taken in mid-September.

328
00:28:33,142 --> 00:28:35,902
In one of the most spectacular
encircling movements

329
00:28:35,981 --> 00:28:37,475
in military history,

330
00:28:37,554 --> 00:28:40,237
the German panzers
took prisoner at Kiev

331
00:28:40,316 --> 00:28:43,687
nearly
three quarters of a million Russians.

332
00:28:56,621 --> 00:28:58,115
German newsreel cameramen

333
00:28:58,194 --> 00:29:01,260
made great play of these
long columns of luckless Russians

334
00:29:01,340 --> 00:29:04,635
for whom frontline fighting
was now over.

335
00:29:04,716 --> 00:29:07,083
But ahead lay another hell -

336
00:29:07,171 --> 00:29:10,270
imprisonment at the hands of the Nazis.

337
00:29:10,356 --> 00:29:13,836
Of every hundred Russian prisoners
seen here,

338
00:29:13,962 --> 00:29:17,682
only three would ever return alive.

339
00:29:32,646 --> 00:29:34,675
By the end of September '41,

340
00:29:34,756 --> 00:29:37,014
after just three months of war,

341
00:29:37,096 --> 00:29:39,966
the Russians had lost
nearly three million men.

342
00:29:41,623 --> 00:29:44,536
But Russian resilience
before such fatal-seeming blows

343
00:29:44,615 --> 00:29:47,638
was to astonish the world.

344
00:30:03,069 --> 00:30:06,626
The German was told
to regard his Russian foe as subhuman,

345
00:30:06,714 --> 00:30:10,194
but it was not long before
the German frontline soldier, at least,

346
00:30:10,281 --> 00:30:14,231
came to think of him
as more superhuman than subhuman.

347
00:30:14,310 --> 00:30:18,140
The Russians seldom cried out
when wounded

348
00:30:18,223 --> 00:30:22,129
and there always seemed to be
more of them on the horizon.

349
00:30:22,213 --> 00:30:24,624
One Wehrmacht colonel wrote:

350
00:30:24,707 --> 00:30:26,692
"In fighting Russia,

351
00:30:26,778 --> 00:30:30,303
the German army is like an elephant
attacking a host of ants."

352
00:30:30,385 --> 00:30:33,222
"The elephant will kill thousands,
maybe millions,

353
00:30:33,300 --> 00:30:37,403
but in the end,
their numbers will overcome him

354
00:30:37,482 --> 00:30:40,429
and he will be eaten to the bone."

355
00:30:44,042 --> 00:30:46,105
(man) Orientation in Russia

356
00:30:46,191 --> 00:30:50,905
is as difficult as it is in the desert,

357
00:30:50,987 --> 00:30:54,358
only you don't see the horizon.

358
00:30:54,439 --> 00:30:56,043
You are lost.

359
00:30:56,127 --> 00:30:59,117
The immense space here was so immense

360
00:30:59,197 --> 00:31:04,107
that we had many soldiers

361
00:31:05,105 --> 00:31:07,472
who became melancholy.

362
00:31:08,481 --> 00:31:10,848
The valley -

363
00:31:10,936 --> 00:31:14,766
flat valleys, flat hills,
flat valleys, flat hills -

364
00:31:14,849 --> 00:31:17,490
endless. There was no limit.

365
00:31:17,612 --> 00:31:19,674
We could not see an end

366
00:31:19,760 --> 00:31:24,321
and it was so disconsolate.

367
00:31:24,402 --> 00:31:27,621
We saw the big fields -

368
00:31:27,702 --> 00:31:29,807
the cornfields -

369
00:31:29,927 --> 00:31:31,880
from the horizon to the horizon.

370
00:31:31,960 --> 00:31:33,945
We never saw it before.

371
00:31:34,032 --> 00:31:36,094
It's very large.

372
00:31:36,180 --> 00:31:42,695
Unimaginable vastness of this country,

373
00:31:42,779 --> 00:31:45,496
and we advanced
from one river to the other,

374
00:31:45,580 --> 00:31:49,333
from one position to the other,
and there was no end to it.

375
00:32:14,967 --> 00:32:19,910
(narrator) "Trade space for time"
was the traditional Russian strategy.

376
00:32:19,993 --> 00:32:21,902
Time was not on Hitler's side

377
00:32:21,988 --> 00:32:25,708
if he was to achieve
his decisive victory before winter.

378
00:32:25,786 --> 00:32:28,426
(Russell) I remember
flying back from Kuibyshev

379
00:32:28,510 --> 00:32:33,606
and there was this great tank trap they
were digging all round, outside Moscow,

380
00:32:33,689 --> 00:32:38,556
and one saw what looked like ants
moving around it,

381
00:32:38,638 --> 00:32:41,585
and it was practically
the entire population of Moscow -

382
00:32:41,669 --> 00:32:43,928
man, woman and child - digging.

383
00:32:44,048 --> 00:32:48,794
I think they did tap every emotional
resource that was available to them.

384
00:32:48,882 --> 00:32:51,599
I remember, for instance,
a lot of churches being open

385
00:32:51,682 --> 00:32:55,479
that had been shut for a long time.

386
00:32:55,557 --> 00:32:58,241
(Tokaty) In that very situation,

387
00:32:58,319 --> 00:33:01,691
something else appeared among us -

388
00:33:01,772 --> 00:33:04,183
the tradition of Borodino.

389
00:33:04,266 --> 00:33:07,485
Borodino is the place
where Napoleon was defeated.

390
00:33:07,565 --> 00:33:13,087
And suddenly, religious feeling
just appeared from nowhere

391
00:33:13,166 --> 00:33:16,233
and that helped to unite people.

392
00:33:17,080 --> 00:33:20,484
(narrator) With the Ukraine subdued
and Leningrad surrounded,

393
00:33:20,571 --> 00:33:24,171
Hitler now turned his attention
to the biggest prize of all,

394
00:33:24,254 --> 00:33:25,476
Moscow,

395
00:33:25,558 --> 00:33:28,199
something his generals
had been beseeching him to do

396
00:33:28,282 --> 00:33:31,501
since the start of the campaign.

397
00:33:35,034 --> 00:33:38,755
Moscow in October '41
was already a frontline city.

398
00:33:38,833 --> 00:33:42,433
German troops had been
only 200 miles away since August,

399
00:33:42,516 --> 00:33:45,353
when Hitler had diverted his panzers
southwards.

400
00:33:47,733 --> 00:33:50,908
Rumours had been rife
of early capitulation.

401
00:33:50,994 --> 00:33:53,907
The city had long been placed
under military rule.

402
00:33:55,790 --> 00:33:59,696
Hardly a day went by
without a visit from the Luftwaffe.

403
00:34:17,159 --> 00:34:20,225
The battle for Moscow
began in earnest in early October.

404
00:34:20,305 --> 00:34:24,441
Straight away,
things went wrong for its defenders.

405
00:34:30,395 --> 00:34:32,424
(squealing)

406
00:34:34,423 --> 00:34:35,994
In two vast pincer movements,

407
00:34:36,073 --> 00:34:39,706
the Germans captured
another 700,000 Russian troops.

408
00:34:39,794 --> 00:34:42,784
Goebbels summoned
American war correspondents to Berlin

409
00:34:42,863 --> 00:34:45,853
to announce Moscow's impending fall.

410
00:34:45,933 --> 00:34:48,388
(man #3) We had had
a very beautiful summer.

411
00:34:48,465 --> 00:34:52,753
No problems - climatic problems -
or anything of this sort.

412
00:34:52,838 --> 00:34:59,200
As I remember it, it started snowing
and becoming cold around October 10,

413
00:34:59,283 --> 00:35:06,027
and then we knew immediately that we
were totally unprepared and unequipped

414
00:35:06,151 --> 00:35:08,639
for what was lying ahead of us.

415
00:35:08,721 --> 00:35:11,132
(narrator)
When one panzer commander asked

416
00:35:11,215 --> 00:35:13,168
when he could expect winter clothing,

417
00:35:13,248 --> 00:35:17,766
he was told not to make further
unnecessary requests of this type.

418
00:35:17,852 --> 00:35:20,842
On the day the first snows fell
before Moscow,

419
00:35:20,921 --> 00:35:23,485
its defenders received a new commander,

420
00:35:23,568 --> 00:35:28,391
Zhukov, something German intelligence
didn't consider worth telling Hitler,

421
00:35:28,479 --> 00:35:30,890
although Zhukov had led
Leningrad's defence

422
00:35:31,011 --> 00:35:33,848
with enormous energy
since mid-September.

423
00:35:33,927 --> 00:35:38,564
But Moscow's defence was to be
a bigger test of Zhukov's generalship.

424
00:35:40,372 --> 00:35:43,165
The first snows soon melted,

425
00:35:43,250 --> 00:35:46,272
turning roads into quagmires.

426
00:35:49,119 --> 00:35:52,993
(man #5) Only a few roads in Russia
were paved.

427
00:35:53,071 --> 00:35:59,127
Therefore, in autumn,
the terrible period of mud was beginning

428
00:35:59,209 --> 00:36:03,006
and the roads became deeply softened,

429
00:36:03,084 --> 00:36:06,565
and therefore useless for motorcars,

430
00:36:06,652 --> 00:36:09,216
except tanks.

431
00:36:14,095 --> 00:36:21,340
(man #1) We had, as infantry,
to march along the sides of the roads

432
00:36:21,423 --> 00:36:25,296
to let pass cars and the tanks.

433
00:36:27,446 --> 00:36:33,502
(man #6) The wheels of my guns
were broken.

434
00:36:33,929 --> 00:36:37,181
(man #2) And within a period
of two or three days,

435
00:36:37,267 --> 00:36:40,900
we had to improvise mobility

436
00:36:40,989 --> 00:36:47,044
by requisitioning pannier horses
and wagons.

437
00:36:49,237 --> 00:36:56,831
We all were quite happy about the
success of the German armies in Russia,

438
00:36:56,948 --> 00:36:59,895
but the first inkling
that something is wrong

439
00:36:59,979 --> 00:37:03,776
was when Goebbels
made a big action in all Germany

440
00:37:03,892 --> 00:37:08,803
to collect furs and winter clothes
for the German troops.

441
00:37:08,880 --> 00:37:12,405
Then we knew something was ahead
which was not foreseen.

442
00:37:14,903 --> 00:37:20,348
(man #7) We had no warm mantles
and nothing,

443
00:37:20,466 --> 00:37:24,797
only the things we had
also in summertime.

444
00:37:24,878 --> 00:37:27,748
(man #8) And we were actually angry

445
00:37:27,832 --> 00:37:30,898
that we didn't have better equipment.

446
00:37:32,819 --> 00:37:34,695
(narrator) The weather worsened.

447
00:37:34,776 --> 00:37:37,918
Many German commanders
favoured halting for the winter.

448
00:37:38,037 --> 00:37:39,456
Hitler would have none of it.

449
00:37:39,533 --> 00:37:42,523
Convinced victory would be his
before winter proper,

450
00:37:42,602 --> 00:37:44,708
he ordered his generals on, on,

451
00:37:44,828 --> 00:37:49,193
as soon as the ground
had hardened enough to bear his panzers.

452
00:37:51,311 --> 00:37:56,789
The welcome delay allowed Zhukov
to organise Moscow's defences.

453
00:38:06,235 --> 00:38:10,949
The Russians had less than
400 tanks left to defend Moscow.

454
00:38:11,031 --> 00:38:13,944
Space was running out fast for Zhukov,

455
00:38:14,023 --> 00:38:16,358
but time was still on his side

456
00:38:16,440 --> 00:38:20,696
as the cold winds of winter
swept in from the north.

457
00:38:25,149 --> 00:38:27,604
But, on October 14,

458
00:38:27,719 --> 00:38:30,207
a panzer group broke through
and took Kalinin,

459
00:38:30,328 --> 00:38:33,241
less than 100 miles away to the north.

460
00:38:33,321 --> 00:38:37,652
A few days later, another unit
took Mozhaysk, 60 miles west,

461
00:38:37,733 --> 00:38:42,905
while an infantry division
reached Gorki, just 40 miles away.

462
00:38:45,099 --> 00:38:47,161
Panic gripped Moscow's citizens.

463
00:38:47,247 --> 00:38:51,426
Those who could, left - two million,
including most government departments.

464
00:38:51,506 --> 00:38:55,335
Even Lenin's coffin was evacuated,
along with other Kremlin treasures.

465
00:38:55,419 --> 00:38:59,139
(Russell) It was a bit of a shock
when, in those two or three days -

466
00:38:59,217 --> 00:39:02,436
I suppose they were just
the advance spear tip probably -

467
00:39:02,516 --> 00:39:05,124
a few chaps on motorbikes or something
got to within

468
00:39:05,202 --> 00:39:07,613
40 or 50 kilometres of Moscow.

469
00:39:07,696 --> 00:39:11,831
Then there was, I must say,
considerable shock in Moscow.

470
00:39:11,916 --> 00:39:13,519
People were trying to get out.

471
00:39:13,604 --> 00:39:16,244
They thought
the German army was going to roll in.

472
00:39:16,328 --> 00:39:18,357
(Tokaty) In fact, I should imagine,

473
00:39:18,438 --> 00:39:20,893
from October 16

474
00:39:20,970 --> 00:39:23,763
to about October 20,

475
00:39:23,847 --> 00:39:26,640
an average citizen of Moscow
probably expected

476
00:39:26,725 --> 00:39:30,128
that Moscow will fall
within the next few days,

477
00:39:30,292 --> 00:39:33,053
and that was what
the panic was about, really.

478
00:39:33,131 --> 00:39:37,878
People used just to stop
top-ranking secret service officers

479
00:39:37,965 --> 00:39:40,988
and shout insults at them
without any fear.

480
00:39:41,073 --> 00:39:43,681
In normal times,
you couldn't do anything like that.

481
00:39:43,758 --> 00:39:48,473
These were the only times when,
probably, a very weak force of Germans,

482
00:39:48,554 --> 00:39:53,072
if they would manage to drop a unit
of some kind of parachutists inside,

483
00:39:53,158 --> 00:39:55,951
we would have real trouble.

484
00:39:56,035 --> 00:39:59,287
(narrator) But while Hitler plotted
his final attack on Moscow,

485
00:39:59,373 --> 00:40:02,821
Zhukov, too, planned an attack.

486
00:40:02,903 --> 00:40:04,550
But with what?

487
00:40:04,629 --> 00:40:08,077
He had already withdrawn as many troops
as he dared from other sectors

488
00:40:08,158 --> 00:40:10,951
to defend Moscow.

489
00:40:11,036 --> 00:40:14,669
But there was one reserve
the Russians had not yet touched,

490
00:40:14,757 --> 00:40:16,896
nor ever thought they would be able to.

491
00:40:16,982 --> 00:40:19,623
The 40 divisions of the Siberian front,

492
00:40:19,706 --> 00:40:24,879
among the best troops in Russia,
trained to fight in winter conditions.

493
00:40:25,001 --> 00:40:29,595
Since June, they had been expecting
a Japanese attack.

494
00:40:33,825 --> 00:40:37,382
Midway through October,
Stalin's master spy in Tokyo

495
00:40:37,469 --> 00:40:41,027
reported Japan's eyes were elsewhere.

496
00:40:41,114 --> 00:40:44,333
This time, Stalin believed his spies.

497
00:40:44,452 --> 00:40:47,703
He moved the Siberian divisions
to Moscow.

498
00:40:50,820 --> 00:40:52,850
Even at this moment of crisis,

499
00:40:52,930 --> 00:40:56,957
Moscow took time off to celebrate
the anniversary of the revolution,

500
00:40:57,035 --> 00:40:59,905
and Stalin showed himself to his people.

501
00:41:01,831 --> 00:41:06,119
(Tokaty) We could say,
in spite of all his shortcomings,

502
00:41:06,204 --> 00:41:13,145
that Stalin rendered a very great
service to the USSR by that presence

503
00:41:13,225 --> 00:41:15,255
because it showed two things:

504
00:41:15,335 --> 00:41:19,973
one, the supreme commander
did not run away,

505
00:41:20,054 --> 00:41:24,310
secondly, Stalin retained his nerve.

506
00:41:24,389 --> 00:41:29,867
That sense of nerve spread at once
into all the armed forces.

507
00:41:29,952 --> 00:41:35,354
All the commanders began saying,
"Stalin himself, he is here."

508
00:41:40,656 --> 00:41:42,609
(people cheer)

509
00:41:54,928 --> 00:42:00,940
(narrator) The ground had hardened.
The panzers were able to roll again.

510
00:42:01,526 --> 00:42:05,160
On November 26, they entered Istra,

511
00:42:05,248 --> 00:42:07,353
just 30 miles west of Moscow,

512
00:42:07,473 --> 00:42:13,224
and four days later had taken
Krasnaya Polyana, just 25 miles north.

513
00:42:18,944 --> 00:42:21,891
As yet,
Zhukov had not used his Siberians

514
00:42:21,975 --> 00:42:24,845
and German intelligence
had not stumbled on the presence

515
00:42:24,929 --> 00:42:27,144
of such numbers of fresh troops.

516
00:42:27,269 --> 00:42:31,448
But the Germans
were having troubles of their own.

517
00:42:34,098 --> 00:42:38,616
(man #1) And one morning,
it was finished.

518
00:42:38,702 --> 00:42:41,844
All was frozen,

519
00:42:41,925 --> 00:42:45,602
and the cars were sitting in the mud,
frozen,

520
00:42:45,684 --> 00:42:48,292
and the tanks could not roll

521
00:42:48,370 --> 00:42:51,970
and, in this moment,
my heart broke down.

522
00:42:52,053 --> 00:42:55,927
And there was, in the distance,
a large town,

523
00:42:56,004 --> 00:43:00,674
and I think that was the first time
and the last time I have seen Moscow.

524
00:43:02,680 --> 00:43:06,313
(narrator) Temperatures were down
to minus 40 degrees centigrade.

525
00:43:06,401 --> 00:43:10,275
Oil solidified
in the sumps of lorries and tanks.

526
00:43:10,391 --> 00:43:12,955
The intense cold
affected the soldiers, too.

527
00:43:13,038 --> 00:43:16,257
There were more casualties
from frostbite and stomach troubles

528
00:43:16,338 --> 00:43:17,865
than from fighting.

529
00:43:17,949 --> 00:43:20,011
(man #3) We had no winter shoes.

530
00:43:20,098 --> 00:43:27,692
We had no equipment whatsoever
to fight or stand the cold.

531
00:43:27,771 --> 00:43:31,720
And I think this became
a very, very big problem right away.

532
00:43:31,799 --> 00:43:35,673
We lost a considerable part
of our equipment -

533
00:43:35,750 --> 00:43:39,854
guns,
heavy and light equipment in general.

534
00:43:39,932 --> 00:43:42,420
We, of course, due to the cold,

535
00:43:42,503 --> 00:43:46,758
lost a lot of people
who got frostbitten,

536
00:43:46,838 --> 00:43:51,781
and we had not even
the necessary amount of ointments

537
00:43:51,864 --> 00:43:55,421
or the most simple and primitive things
to fight it.

538
00:43:56,429 --> 00:43:59,495
Of 900 men in my battalion,

539
00:43:59,575 --> 00:44:03,863
200 fell out because of freezing

540
00:44:04,908 --> 00:44:06,893
in the first 14 days.

541
00:44:08,437 --> 00:44:10,118
(man #3) As it became colder,

542
00:44:10,202 --> 00:44:14,152
towards the end of November
and early December,

543
00:44:14,230 --> 00:44:19,294
most of our artillery
had become completely unusable.

544
00:44:20,330 --> 00:44:26,997
(man #6) We had not the lubrication oil
suitable for this winter war.

545
00:44:27,159 --> 00:44:29,374
Nevertheless, the Russians had it

546
00:44:29,461 --> 00:44:34,208
and suddenly our soldiers realised

547
00:44:34,295 --> 00:44:37,165
that from one moment to the next,

548
00:44:37,249 --> 00:44:40,086
the weapon didn't shoot any more.

549
00:44:43,234 --> 00:44:48,330
(man #8) Well, the worst memory was
if the vehicles got frozen in the ground

550
00:44:48,413 --> 00:44:51,555
and the motor oil was thick
so we couldn't move.

551
00:44:51,636 --> 00:44:56,426
And we needed and we wanted to move.
I think that was the worst.

552
00:44:56,854 --> 00:45:02,942
(man #1) In Russia, there were
no signposts to mark the ways.

553
00:45:03,030 --> 00:45:05,671
To find our roads,

554
00:45:05,754 --> 00:45:10,577
we had set the frozen bodies of horses

555
00:45:10,665 --> 00:45:13,153
along the snow walls

556
00:45:13,235 --> 00:45:16,793
to find the way during the snowdrifts.

557
00:45:16,880 --> 00:45:22,477
And the scenery was so disconsolate -

558
00:45:22,558 --> 00:45:25,929
always snow and snow.

559
00:45:27,852 --> 00:45:30,570
(man #4) We always were alone,

560
00:45:30,653 --> 00:45:34,865
dreaming what time
we will be back in Berlin.

561
00:45:35,679 --> 00:45:39,509
(narrator) But the powers that be
in Berlin refused to believe the worst.

562
00:45:39,592 --> 00:45:43,149
The newsreels
made it all seem great fun.

563
00:45:53,135 --> 00:45:55,818
The reality was different.

564
00:45:58,698 --> 00:46:04,328
(man #2) At that time,
we had advanced almost 2,000 kilometres.

565
00:46:12,778 --> 00:46:16,575
Hitler, at first,
did not want to conceive

566
00:46:16,652 --> 00:46:21,247
that this crisis was the end
of all his strategical planning,

567
00:46:21,371 --> 00:46:24,743
but the army knew better,

568
00:46:24,824 --> 00:46:29,767
and the Russians did

569
00:46:29,888 --> 00:46:31,950
the most important part

570
00:46:32,075 --> 00:46:34,606
in convincing Hitler, too,

571
00:46:34,684 --> 00:46:37,139
that the Russian campaign
of this first year

572
00:46:37,216 --> 00:46:39,704
had failed and had come to an end.

573
00:46:45,618 --> 00:46:47,374
(narrator) December 6.

574
00:46:47,459 --> 00:46:50,329
With the Wehrmacht's morale
at its lowest,

575
00:46:50,413 --> 00:46:53,894
although some German troops
were just 15 miles from the Kremlin,

576
00:46:53,981 --> 00:46:56,240
Zhukov unleashed his Siberians.

577
00:46:56,974 --> 00:46:59,920
(man #4) It was astonishing this time -

578
00:47:00,005 --> 00:47:04,751
the first time -
I saw the Russian tanks,

579
00:47:04,839 --> 00:47:06,639
34,

580
00:47:06,718 --> 00:47:10,472
running through the fields
and through the snow.

581
00:47:10,555 --> 00:47:16,306
Our own tanks couldn't drive,
couldn't shoot,

582
00:47:16,386 --> 00:47:18,994
because it was too cold.

583
00:47:30,505 --> 00:47:34,716
(man #6) When I wanted to go back,
I met Russians everywhere,

584
00:47:34,801 --> 00:47:38,173
and so this was the first impression

585
00:47:38,293 --> 00:47:41,926
that there was no victory any more.

586
00:48:23,486 --> 00:48:25,898
(narrator) As the Russians
regained territory,

587
00:48:26,019 --> 00:48:29,892
they began to uncover
the horror of the Nazi occupation.

588
00:49:16,353 --> 00:49:19,605
"Comrade, kill your German"
became the catch phrase.

589
00:49:19,691 --> 00:49:22,146
In the first month
of the counteroffensive,

590
00:49:22,261 --> 00:49:25,589
more than 300,000 Germans
were killed or captured.

591
00:49:25,676 --> 00:49:29,625
(man #4) The worst memory
of this retreat

592
00:49:29,742 --> 00:49:31,772
was the fear,

593
00:49:31,853 --> 00:49:33,838
every day and every night,

594
00:49:33,924 --> 00:49:37,023
to come in captivity.

595
00:49:37,108 --> 00:49:43,361
(man #3) We had seen enough of the
enemy to know that in cases like that,

596
00:49:43,439 --> 00:49:46,385
prisoners were hardly taken.

597
00:50:28,057 --> 00:50:31,777
(man #1) It was the first time
that our soldiers remarked

598
00:50:31,855 --> 00:50:34,921
the dark shadows of the coming times.

599
00:50:47,124 --> 00:50:51,260
(man #4) When we must retreat
from Moscow,

600
00:50:52,649 --> 00:50:57,166
the Russian population
and the Russian soldiers must think:

601
00:50:57,253 --> 00:51:01,006
"It's possible to defeat
the German army."

602
00:51:04,772 --> 00:51:07,794
(narrator) Two days
after the Russian offensive began,

603
00:51:07,880 --> 00:51:10,335
the Japanese struck at Pearl Harbour.

604
00:51:10,450 --> 00:51:14,051
The war was taking
a very different turn.
