1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,672
== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==

2
00:00:12,736 --> 00:00:17,450
(narrator) Down this road
on a summer day in 1944,

3
00:00:17,531 --> 00:00:19,516
the soldiers came.

4
00:00:21,329 --> 00:00:23,588
Nobody lives here now.

5
00:00:29,462 --> 00:00:32,680
They stayed only a few hours.

6
00:00:32,761 --> 00:00:34,288
When they had gone,

7
00:00:34,372 --> 00:00:38,475
a community, which had lived
for a thousand years, was dead.

8
00:00:41,469 --> 00:00:46,029
This is Oradour-sur-Glane in France.

9
00:00:47,031 --> 00:00:52,094
The day the soldiers came
the people were gathered together.

10
00:00:52,172 --> 00:00:55,652
The men were taken
to garages and barns,

11
00:00:55,778 --> 00:00:59,651
the women and children
were led down this road,

12
00:01:00,957 --> 00:01:04,175
and they were driven into this church.

13
00:01:05,330 --> 00:01:09,847
Here, they heard the firing
as their men were shot.

14
00:01:11,007 --> 00:01:13,462
Then they were killed, too.

15
00:01:14,575 --> 00:01:18,906
A few weeks later
many of those who had done the killing

16
00:01:18,987 --> 00:01:22,314
were themselves dead in battle.

17
00:01:26,275 --> 00:01:30,760
They never rebuilt Oradour.
Its ruins are a memorial.

18
00:01:32,643 --> 00:01:37,160
Its martyrdom stands for thousand
upon thousand of other martyrdoms

19
00:01:37,285 --> 00:01:40,078
in Poland, in Russia,

20
00:01:40,162 --> 00:01:43,261
in Burma, in China,

21
00:01:43,346 --> 00:01:45,375
in a world at war.

22
00:02:41,080 --> 00:02:43,066
(military march)

23
00:02:46,298 --> 00:02:48,479
Germany, 1933.

24
00:02:49,865 --> 00:02:53,847
A huge, blind excitement
fills the streets.

25
00:02:54,392 --> 00:02:56,847
The National Socialists
have come to power

26
00:02:56,924 --> 00:02:59,182
in a land tortured by unemployment,

27
00:02:59,264 --> 00:03:04,086
embittered by loss of territory,
demoralised by political weakness.

28
00:03:04,174 --> 00:03:07,425
Perhaps this will be the new beginning.

29
00:03:12,307 --> 00:03:15,296
Most people think the Nazis
a little absurd here,

30
00:03:15,376 --> 00:03:16,902
too obsessive there.

31
00:03:16,987 --> 00:03:20,587
But perhaps the time
for thinking is over.

32
00:03:24,467 --> 00:03:26,998
Adolf Hitler did not seize power.

33
00:03:27,076 --> 00:03:31,135
He was offered it just
as his voting strength was declining.

34
00:03:31,257 --> 00:03:34,203
The politicians
who made Hitler chancellor argued,

35
00:03:34,288 --> 00:03:36,971
"We are hiring him."

36
00:03:37,050 --> 00:03:41,610
Their figurehead was
the ancient President von Hindenburg.

37
00:03:43,917 --> 00:03:46,939
Communists and Socialists
tried to take Hitler coolly.

38
00:03:47,024 --> 00:03:49,086
"This wouldn't last," they said.

39
00:03:49,172 --> 00:03:52,314
Conservative anti-Nazis
took comfort from the fact

40
00:03:52,395 --> 00:03:55,875
that their old war leader Hindenburg,
still head of state,

41
00:03:55,962 --> 00:03:58,908
was known to despise
the vulgar little corporal.

42
00:03:58,993 --> 00:04:00,978
(speaking German)

43
00:04:04,670 --> 00:04:06,655
So, fertig?

44
00:04:10,693 --> 00:04:13,104
Na, jetzt wird es fertig sein.

45
00:04:15,834 --> 00:04:20,045
(all shout out "Heil!")

46
00:04:25,424 --> 00:04:28,032
With mock solemnity,
Hitler and his lieutenants

47
00:04:28,109 --> 00:04:31,829
walked to the ceremonial opening
of parliament.

48
00:04:31,945 --> 00:04:35,546
The party's strength had been built up
by revolutionary violence.

49
00:04:35,628 --> 00:04:39,654
They had never imagined that
they could take office legally.

50
00:04:39,733 --> 00:04:43,213
When the old Reichstag building
was mysteriously gutted by fire,

51
00:04:43,339 --> 00:04:47,321
Hitler seized his chance
to suspend all civil liberties.

52
00:04:47,405 --> 00:04:50,962
His followers could hardly believe
their luck.

53
00:04:55,730 --> 00:04:59,559
The old Hindenburg, the symbol
of apparent continuity, presided

54
00:04:59,642 --> 00:05:03,930
as they turned office into power
by acts of sham legality.

55
00:05:04,016 --> 00:05:06,427
In March, when the Reichstag voted

56
00:05:06,509 --> 00:05:09,073
to allow Hitler
to govern without parliament,

57
00:05:09,156 --> 00:05:11,611
Hindenburg made no comment.

58
00:05:13,414 --> 00:05:15,825
The legal chancellor
marched irresistibly

59
00:05:15,946 --> 00:05:19,623
into the role of the legal dictator.

60
00:05:36,316 --> 00:05:40,222
Hitler proclaimed the new Germany,

61
00:05:40,344 --> 00:05:43,214
and meant it to last a thousand years.

62
00:05:45,561 --> 00:05:48,169
The new Germany
began to round up its enemies -

63
00:05:48,784 --> 00:05:55,112
Communists, Socialists, impertinent
journalists, even Reichstag deputies.

64
00:05:55,190 --> 00:05:57,143
Antreten zum Arbeiten.

65
00:05:58,796 --> 00:06:01,895
At Oranienburg concentration camp,
just north of Berlin,

66
00:06:02,018 --> 00:06:06,274
conditions were at first crude
rather than brutal.

67
00:06:08,118 --> 00:06:14,599
At this time the camps were run
by the Sturmabteilungen - the SA.

68
00:06:14,678 --> 00:06:17,852
They bullied more than they murdered.

69
00:06:29,946 --> 00:06:35,084
From the first moment, Hitler unleashed
his promised campaign against the Jews.

70
00:06:35,163 --> 00:06:39,603
The SA organised boycotts
of Jewish-owned shops.

71
00:06:39,690 --> 00:06:42,711
The real point
was to encourage the German people

72
00:06:42,835 --> 00:06:47,549
to think and act anti-Semitic
as a matter of course.

73
00:06:47,669 --> 00:06:49,654
The outside world was horrified,

74
00:06:49,779 --> 00:06:52,615
but there were those,
including many German Jews,

75
00:06:52,694 --> 00:06:56,219
who thought the anti-Jewish campaign
the work of Nazi extremists -

76
00:06:56,338 --> 00:07:01,249
something Herr Hitler would put
a stop to when he felt more secure.

77
00:07:03,397 --> 00:07:06,310
There was to be
a cultural revolution, too.

78
00:07:06,389 --> 00:07:11,255
German culture would be purged
of the Jewish-Bolshevist taint.

79
00:07:11,376 --> 00:07:18,697
(singing in German)

80
00:07:21,964 --> 00:07:24,833
Books flew into the fire.

81
00:07:24,918 --> 00:07:28,518
Many of those who flung them
were students and teachers.

82
00:07:28,601 --> 00:07:32,397
And, as the sparks rose,
the intellectuals fled -

83
00:07:32,513 --> 00:07:34,575
writers and scientists -

84
00:07:34,662 --> 00:07:39,299
to give their talents
to Western Europe and America.

85
00:07:40,262 --> 00:07:44,550
A hundred years before
the German-Jewish poet, Heine,

86
00:07:44,636 --> 00:07:47,353
whose books now went into the fire,
had warned:

87
00:07:47,436 --> 00:07:52,761
"Where one burns books,
there one eventually burns people."

88
00:07:55,262 --> 00:07:57,291
(peal of church bells)

89
00:07:58,484 --> 00:08:02,358
Some of Hitler's most earnest followers
found new ways to show loyalty -

90
00:08:02,435 --> 00:08:06,691
they married or got married
all over again under a Nazi ritual.

91
00:08:17,051 --> 00:08:20,270
The Nazis had mass support
among the unemployed,

92
00:08:20,350 --> 00:08:23,569
but less among the organised workers.

93
00:08:24,493 --> 00:08:26,020
The left wing of the party

94
00:08:26,105 --> 00:08:29,279
wanted to start a workers' movement
inside the factories,

95
00:08:29,365 --> 00:08:31,351
but Hitler took a simpler course.

96
00:08:31,437 --> 00:08:35,692
He granted the unions the May Day
holiday they had always demanded.

97
00:08:35,772 --> 00:08:38,335
Next day he abolished the unions.

98
00:08:39,608 --> 00:08:42,215
Nazi supporters
were basically middle class -

99
00:08:42,293 --> 00:08:46,658
shopkeepers ruined by the Depression,
clerks who had lost their savings,

100
00:08:46,781 --> 00:08:49,542
craftsmen squeezed out
by mass production.

101
00:08:52,190 --> 00:08:55,180
(chants of "Sieg Heil!")

102
00:08:56,832 --> 00:08:59,702
These were Hitler's worshippers.

103
00:09:01,090 --> 00:09:03,457
(congregation singing)

104
00:09:07,957 --> 00:09:10,640
To this army of those
who had come down in the world

105
00:09:10,719 --> 00:09:13,741
belonged the small farmers,
the peasants.

106
00:09:13,826 --> 00:09:16,619
Hitler had enlisted them
during the Depression.

107
00:09:17,279 --> 00:09:21,108
Now he told them that their blood
and soil were Germany's treasure.

108
00:09:21,192 --> 00:09:24,487
He passed laws to give them
safe possession of their fields

109
00:09:24,568 --> 00:09:26,826
and he gave them bread.

110
00:09:41,830 --> 00:09:44,394
The Treaty of Versailles in 1919

111
00:09:44,477 --> 00:09:47,652
had bitten deep
into Germany's frontiers.

112
00:09:50,040 --> 00:09:54,066
Alsace-Lorraine and the Saarland
had been lost.

113
00:09:54,183 --> 00:09:57,478
East Prussia was cut off
by the new Polish state,

114
00:09:57,559 --> 00:09:59,970
Silesia cut in two,

115
00:10:00,091 --> 00:10:03,080
Danzig, a League of Nations city.

116
00:10:03,159 --> 00:10:05,189
(man speaking in German)

117
00:10:06,957 --> 00:10:12,020
To every patriot, Germany could not
be free while Versailles stood.

118
00:10:12,136 --> 00:10:16,925
Hitler alone seemed the saviour foretold
by the monuments of the border:

119
00:10:17,008 --> 00:10:22,223
"Never, German, forget
what blind hate stole from thee."

120
00:10:22,302 --> 00:10:24,058
(German national anthem)

121
00:10:24,143 --> 00:10:29,391
"Wait for the hour that avenges
the bleeding frontier crime."

122
00:10:36,035 --> 00:10:39,406
Abroad there were some
who admired the way

123
00:10:39,488 --> 00:10:41,670
this new Germany stood up for herself.

124
00:10:41,751 --> 00:10:44,970
In America we've had reports
against your new government,

125
00:10:45,050 --> 00:10:49,109
and, in most cases, this has caused
hasty demonstrations everywhere.

126
00:10:49,193 --> 00:10:52,215
I can now say to you that
the American people today realise

127
00:10:52,339 --> 00:10:55,022
these stories are untrue
and without foundation.

128
00:10:55,101 --> 00:10:58,243
I find that there's a new,
fresh vitality here in Germany

129
00:10:58,323 --> 00:11:01,270
under your great leader
and chancellor, Adolf Hitler,

130
00:11:01,354 --> 00:11:02,848
of whom I'm a great admirer.

131
00:11:04,231 --> 00:11:06,031
The new Germany will live

132
00:11:06,111 --> 00:11:09,591
for you have the best centralised
government in the world today.

133
00:11:09,678 --> 00:11:11,479
(narrator) In fact, the new Germany

134
00:11:11,558 --> 00:11:14,351
was a bundle of different interests
and grievances

135
00:11:14,435 --> 00:11:17,457
held together by the strap
of the National Socialist Party,

136
00:11:17,543 --> 00:11:20,106
and the buckle of the strap was Hitler.

137
00:11:20,190 --> 00:11:22,556
(Hitler speaking German)

138
00:11:56,710 --> 00:12:01,227
Well, really, it was the only party
that promised to get us out of the hole.

139
00:12:01,313 --> 00:12:06,256
And their idea was principally

140
00:12:06,377 --> 00:12:10,283
that that would only be possible

141
00:12:10,366 --> 00:12:16,379
if we developed as a nation
a team spirit, a solidarity,

142
00:12:16,466 --> 00:12:20,023
and pulling all on the same rope,

143
00:12:20,110 --> 00:12:25,206
instead of quarrelling
about petty differences of opinions

144
00:12:25,289 --> 00:12:29,500
in foreign politics and social politics,
and so on and so forth.

145
00:12:30,161 --> 00:12:32,190
(speaks German)

146
00:12:33,921 --> 00:12:35,753
(translator) What did he promise?

147
00:12:35,839 --> 00:12:38,020
Work and bread for the masses,

148
00:12:38,102 --> 00:12:43,088
for the millions of workers who were
unemployed and hungry at that time.

149
00:12:43,166 --> 00:12:46,537
Nowadays, in our prosperous society,

150
00:12:46,657 --> 00:12:49,220
work and bread
doesn't mean anything any more,

151
00:12:49,304 --> 00:12:52,904
but then it was
an absolutely basic need.

152
00:12:52,986 --> 00:12:56,783
And this promise,
which wouldn't make any sense today,

153
00:12:56,861 --> 00:13:00,843
then it sounded like
a promise of paradise.

154
00:13:03,919 --> 00:13:06,178
(speaks German)

155
00:13:06,298 --> 00:13:09,931
(translator) All this seemed
ideal ground for a prophet to say:

156
00:13:10,057 --> 00:13:14,651
"I will lead you to the promised land.
I will deliver you from evil."

157
00:13:14,776 --> 00:13:18,725
Anyone who said that
would be greeted with enthusiasm.

158
00:13:26,092 --> 00:13:29,496
Of course, there were people
who said this is a false prophet,

159
00:13:29,583 --> 00:13:32,758
but who was to know
whether they were right or not?

160
00:13:32,844 --> 00:13:34,447
At that time no one did.

161
00:13:34,532 --> 00:13:37,674
(people singing
"Silent Night" in German)

162
00:13:42,818 --> 00:13:45,884
(narrator) Christmas, 1933.

163
00:13:45,964 --> 00:13:48,222
One year of Hitler's Reich.

164
00:13:49,493 --> 00:13:52,821
Peace on earth,
goodwill towards men.

165
00:13:53,943 --> 00:13:58,121
The concentration camps were full,
parliament a rubber stamp,

166
00:13:58,239 --> 00:14:00,880
political parties
and trade unions abolished,

167
00:14:00,963 --> 00:14:05,174
the Jews out of the civil service,
a free press strangled,

168
00:14:05,298 --> 00:14:08,015
personal liberties destroyed.

169
00:14:11,858 --> 00:14:16,113
Germany lived under
a permanent state of emergency.

170
00:14:23,098 --> 00:14:28,575
Adolf Hitler's state
was all-powerful, even almighty.

171
00:14:31,077 --> 00:14:33,062
(church bells ringing)

172
00:14:36,447 --> 00:14:38,706
But he still felt threatened.

173
00:14:38,788 --> 00:14:41,580
He feared his old conservative rivals.

174
00:14:41,665 --> 00:14:43,879
He feared the army.

175
00:14:43,966 --> 00:14:48,102
And he feared those sections of his own
party which were still revolutionary,

176
00:14:48,186 --> 00:14:51,056
like the leadership
of the storm troopers.

177
00:14:51,178 --> 00:14:54,703
The army, too, hated the SA.

178
00:14:54,784 --> 00:15:01,833
Hitler saw how he could conciliate
the generals and clear his own path.

179
00:15:01,920 --> 00:15:08,401
The head of the SA was one of
his oldest comrades, Ernst Röhm.

180
00:15:08,479 --> 00:15:12,538
On June 30, 1934, Röhm was arrested...

181
00:15:12,622 --> 00:15:13,844
(gunshot)

182
00:15:13,927 --> 00:15:15,192
..and shot.

183
00:15:15,269 --> 00:15:17,757
His SA commanders
and more than 1 00 others

184
00:15:17,840 --> 00:15:19,978
dragged from their beds were shot, too.

185
00:15:20,065 --> 00:15:22,094
(gunfire)

186
00:15:23,249 --> 00:15:26,085
Murder exploded across Germany.

187
00:15:26,202 --> 00:15:29,301
The killers were the new force
in Germany -

188
00:15:29,386 --> 00:15:32,179
the SS, Hitler's bodyguard -

189
00:15:32,264 --> 00:15:36,016
which now became
his personal instrument of terror.

190
00:15:37,174 --> 00:15:41,429
Göring gave a press conference
at the propaganda ministry.

191
00:15:41,509 --> 00:15:43,876
Goebbels was the minister of propaganda,

192
00:15:43,964 --> 00:15:46,986
but Goebbels had wisely stayed
with Hitler at that time

193
00:15:47,071 --> 00:15:49,635
because Göring hated his guts

194
00:15:49,718 --> 00:15:54,203
and might have taken the opportunity
to bump him off if he'd been in Berlin.

195
00:15:54,283 --> 00:15:57,916
Göring had that press conference
for the foreign press.

196
00:15:58,004 --> 00:16:02,870
Before that the telephones had been
cut off to all foreign countries.

197
00:16:02,953 --> 00:16:05,975
Göring came striding in and said,

198
00:16:06,137 --> 00:16:10,196
"I know you boys
always like to have a story," -

199
00:16:10,280 --> 00:16:15,572
he used the English word -
"I've got a story for you all right,"

200
00:16:15,651 --> 00:16:21,739
and described how
that previous night and that morning

201
00:16:21,865 --> 00:16:26,655
he and Hitler had acted against
dissident forces,

202
00:16:26,775 --> 00:16:31,412
both of the Right and of the Left,

203
00:16:31,494 --> 00:16:33,752
that Röhm had been shot,

204
00:16:33,834 --> 00:16:37,085
that a second revolution
had been quashed.

205
00:16:37,171 --> 00:16:43,576
He also made a rather obscure reference
to General von Schleicher

206
00:16:43,655 --> 00:16:47,942
who had preceded Hitler
as German chancellor.

207
00:16:48,028 --> 00:16:52,512
Then he left the room, came back again
in a few seconds and said:

208
00:16:52,593 --> 00:16:55,767
"It's been suggested
that I didn't make myself quite clear

209
00:16:55,854 --> 00:16:57,610
about General von Schleicher."

210
00:16:57,695 --> 00:17:01,023
"He was shot dead this morning
while resisting arrest."

211
00:17:01,454 --> 00:17:07,237
30 June, '34,
was a very, very important day,

212
00:17:07,324 --> 00:17:13,379
because it became obvious that
this government, as a government,

213
00:17:13,461 --> 00:17:16,145
started to become a murderer.

214
00:17:16,224 --> 00:17:20,173
You remember that
they shot a great number of people

215
00:17:20,251 --> 00:17:23,273
without any bringing them to court.

216
00:17:23,397 --> 00:17:25,382
They just killed them.

217
00:17:25,469 --> 00:17:32,942
And not only direct enemies of Hitler
in that moment -

218
00:17:33,064 --> 00:17:37,472
not only Röhm, the head of the SA -

219
00:17:37,553 --> 00:17:42,299
but also other people
who they felt were unpleasant.

220
00:17:42,386 --> 00:17:45,375
And they just did it at the same time.

221
00:17:45,455 --> 00:17:47,866
(solemn dirge)

222
00:17:53,588 --> 00:17:56,959
(narrator) That summer
another rival disappeared.

223
00:17:58,306 --> 00:18:03,369
President Hindenburg
died in his bed on August 2.

224
00:18:05,633 --> 00:18:07,586
While the old man was still breathing

225
00:18:07,666 --> 00:18:10,307
Hitler had abolished
the office of president,

226
00:18:10,390 --> 00:18:13,107
proclaiming himself
Führer and Chancellor,

227
00:18:13,190 --> 00:18:15,721
head of state and government.

228
00:18:21,477 --> 00:18:24,084
And before his corpse was laid to rest,

229
00:18:24,162 --> 00:18:26,955
Hitler usurped his command
over the army.

230
00:18:27,576 --> 00:18:30,751
The armed forces paraded
to swear a new oath.

231
00:18:30,837 --> 00:18:34,011
Where once they had sworn loyalty
to the constitution,

232
00:18:34,136 --> 00:18:38,042
now they pledged themselves to Hitler,
personally, by name.

233
00:18:38,663 --> 00:18:43,452
- Ich schwöre bei Gott...
- (men repeat sentence)

234
00:18:43,535 --> 00:18:46,175
..diesen heiligen Eid...

235
00:18:46,335 --> 00:18:48,823
(men repeat)

236
00:18:48,905 --> 00:18:54,230
..dass ich den Führer
des Deutschen Reiches und Volkes...

237
00:18:54,314 --> 00:18:58,951
(men repeat)

238
00:18:59,033 --> 00:19:00,942
..Adolf Hitler...

239
00:19:01,027 --> 00:19:03,057
(men repeat)

240
00:19:03,176 --> 00:19:07,540
(narrator) For German officers,
an oath was almost physically real.

241
00:19:10,349 --> 00:19:12,564
Hitler had trapped them.

242
00:19:12,651 --> 00:19:17,397
Now they could not disobey him
without disobeying the fatherland.

243
00:19:17,485 --> 00:19:20,659
- Ich schwöre...
- (men repeat)

244
00:19:20,745 --> 00:19:23,538
- Ich schwöre bei Gott...
- (men repeat)

245
00:19:23,622 --> 00:19:26,535
Ich schwöre Adolf Hitler...

246
00:19:26,615 --> 00:19:28,753
Adolf Hitler.

247
00:19:28,840 --> 00:19:30,366
(men) Adolf Hitler.

248
00:19:30,451 --> 00:19:31,716
Adolf Hitler!

249
00:19:31,793 --> 00:19:33,288
(men) Adolf Hitler.

250
00:19:33,366 --> 00:19:34,785
Adolf Hitler!

251
00:19:34,862 --> 00:19:36,586
(train whistle)

252
00:19:38,775 --> 00:19:43,260
Hitler kept u p the pace. That same month
the Germans had to go again to the polls

253
00:19:43,340 --> 00:19:47,137
to approve his assumption
of state and government powers.

254
00:19:47,215 --> 00:19:49,429
By now the machinery
of ballot management

255
00:19:49,516 --> 00:19:53,498
by threat, propaganda, forgery and fraud
was functioning excellently.

256
00:19:53,621 --> 00:19:55,650
(crowd chant in German)

257
00:20:00,066 --> 00:20:02,859
Hitler had a 90% Ja.

258
00:20:03,634 --> 00:20:07,037
Four million still voted Nein.

259
00:20:08,122 --> 00:20:09,496
Hitler proclaimed:

260
00:20:09,618 --> 00:20:14,986
"For the next thousand years, there will
be no other revolution in Germany."

261
00:20:19,630 --> 00:20:23,111
The Nazis preached the doctrine
of "folk-community",

262
00:20:23,198 --> 00:20:27,147
of learning to be Germans
one of another.

263
00:20:27,226 --> 00:20:31,514
Winter Help, the main street collection
for charity, was one symbol,

264
00:20:31,599 --> 00:20:35,080
and the leaders of the party,
for the benefit of the cameras,

265
00:20:35,167 --> 00:20:38,036
showed themselves as folk comrades, too.

266
00:20:39,387 --> 00:20:41,678
Göring displayed himself -

267
00:20:41,765 --> 00:20:45,714
a war hero, a man who laughed
and enjoyed life,

268
00:20:45,793 --> 00:20:49,164
a moderating force in the party,
it was believed.

269
00:20:49,245 --> 00:20:52,420
Joseph Goebbels,
the little propaganda minister,

270
00:20:52,506 --> 00:20:55,757
whom the backstreet
called "poison dwarf".

271
00:20:55,844 --> 00:20:59,368
His sharpness was feared,
but respected.

272
00:21:00,639 --> 00:21:04,774
- Warum lachen Sie?
- Die Dame spricht nicht Deutsch.

273
00:21:04,897 --> 00:21:10,680
The deputy Führer, Rudolf Hess,
a puzzling figure to the crowds.

274
00:21:10,805 --> 00:21:16,478
The Nazi way of ruling was to be remote,
but to seem not to be.

275
00:21:16,559 --> 00:21:20,236
All classes were encouraged
to relish the same meals -

276
00:21:20,318 --> 00:21:23,843
the soldier, the boss,
the worker, the banker.

277
00:21:23,924 --> 00:21:26,259
The party believed in community,

278
00:21:26,341 --> 00:21:29,483
but the industrialists stayed rich.

279
00:21:29,564 --> 00:21:32,815
They had financed the Nazis
when they seemed likely to win,

280
00:21:32,901 --> 00:21:37,461
and now they submitted to Nazi direction
without too much distaste.

281
00:21:37,543 --> 00:21:40,030
Business was picking up fast.

282
00:21:42,146 --> 00:21:45,517
The economy was reviving
when the Nazis came to power,

283
00:21:45,599 --> 00:21:47,431
but they reaped the credit,

284
00:21:47,517 --> 00:21:51,117
speeding recovery
with an enormous public works programme

285
00:21:51,199 --> 00:21:52,923
for the unemployed.

286
00:21:53,002 --> 00:21:59,364
Other nations, where mass unemployment
persisted, watched Germany with envy.

287
00:22:27,336 --> 00:22:32,475
The workless built the autobahns -
the first motorways in the world,

288
00:22:32,553 --> 00:22:36,306
binding a still-provincial Germany
together.

289
00:22:36,389 --> 00:22:39,259
The autobahns were not least
for private pleasure,

290
00:22:39,343 --> 00:22:42,562
in the fascist notion
of Strength through Joy.

291
00:22:42,681 --> 00:22:45,473
And they were presented
less as a transport system

292
00:22:45,596 --> 00:22:48,051
than as a triumph of national will,

293
00:22:48,128 --> 00:22:50,233
Linked with other prestige projects,

294
00:22:50,315 --> 00:22:53,795
like the design
for the Führer's new Berlin.

295
00:23:13,523 --> 00:23:15,509
(woman) Voll Anmut und Gesundheit,

296
00:23:15,595 --> 00:23:19,469
gläubig und ihrer großen Pflichten
und Aufgaben bewusst,

297
00:23:19,546 --> 00:23:23,266
sind sie glückliche Mädel
unserer großen Zeit.

298
00:23:26,068 --> 00:23:28,751
(narrator) These were members
of Faith and Beauty,

299
00:23:28,830 --> 00:23:31,437
older sister to
the League of German Maidens,

300
00:23:31,515 --> 00:23:33,882
the girls' equivalent
of the Hitler Youth.

301
00:23:33,970 --> 00:23:35,574
And so on.

302
00:23:35,696 --> 00:23:41,555
All young people learnt party songs,
drilled and danced and belonged.

303
00:23:48,356 --> 00:23:49,927
(cheering)

304
00:23:51,962 --> 00:23:55,639
Each year the farmers and their wives
gathered at the Buckeberg

305
00:23:55,721 --> 00:23:58,438
to meet their Führer at harvest time.

306
00:23:58,522 --> 00:24:03,923
In 1936 those who stood and waited
for the leader numbered one million.

307
00:24:08,534 --> 00:24:09,985
The leader was late.

308
00:24:10,068 --> 00:24:12,981
He always arrived late -
it built up tension.

309
00:24:13,061 --> 00:24:16,050
(crowd cheer and shout "Heil, Hitler!")

310
00:24:22,766 --> 00:24:25,559
(band strikes up)

311
00:24:54,491 --> 00:24:57,819
Then he came,
letting the excitement spill over.

312
00:24:57,905 --> 00:24:59,509
As he marched to the rostrum,

313
00:24:59,593 --> 00:25:02,844
the masses were allowed
to see him close and even to touch him.

314
00:25:02,931 --> 00:25:07,066
Deliberately,
women were placed in the front rows.

315
00:25:07,189 --> 00:25:11,292
(translator)
When he went up the mountain,

316
00:25:11,370 --> 00:25:13,934
I couldn't understand
how it was possible

317
00:25:14,056 --> 00:25:16,008
that people could shout so much.

318
00:25:18,122 --> 00:25:22,868
Yet when he came towards our group,
I too came under his spell

319
00:25:22,955 --> 00:25:27,822
and shouted "Heil!"
just like everyone else.

320
00:25:27,904 --> 00:25:32,814
But then when he was really close,
greeting people to his left and right,

321
00:25:32,891 --> 00:25:38,903
shaking their hand and exchanging
a few words, and he also shook my hand,

322
00:25:38,991 --> 00:25:43,628
I suddenly noticed that
everybody in his immediate presence

323
00:25:43,709 --> 00:25:46,775
was completely silent.

324
00:25:47,891 --> 00:25:51,415
For the first ten minutes
he wasn't a good speaker.

325
00:25:51,535 --> 00:25:57,547
He just began warming up
and finding the words.

326
00:25:57,634 --> 00:26:02,850
But then he turned out to be
a terribly good speaker, you know.

327
00:26:02,928 --> 00:26:07,336
He just...
I don't know the words in English.

328
00:26:07,455 --> 00:26:10,629
Er massierte his public!

329
00:26:12,097 --> 00:26:17,923
And the whole atmosphere

330
00:26:18,004 --> 00:26:20,492
grew more and more hysterical.

331
00:26:21,610 --> 00:26:29,281
He was interrupted nearly
after every phrase by big applause,

332
00:26:29,359 --> 00:26:33,844
and women began screaming.

333
00:26:33,924 --> 00:26:41,552
It was like a mass religious ceremony.

334
00:26:44,320 --> 00:26:46,884
Well, I listened to his speech

335
00:26:46,967 --> 00:26:54,212
and I felt that more and more
excited atmosphere in the hall

336
00:26:54,294 --> 00:27:00,427
and for some seconds again and again
I had a feeling,

337
00:27:00,509 --> 00:27:04,994
"What a pity that
I can't share that belief

338
00:27:05,074 --> 00:27:07,179
of all those thousands of people,

339
00:27:07,261 --> 00:27:11,439
that I am alone,
that I am contrary to all that."

340
00:27:11,519 --> 00:27:17,302
It was very funny. I thought,
"He is talking all the nonsense I know,

341
00:27:17,388 --> 00:27:19,450
the nonsense he always talked."

342
00:27:19,575 --> 00:27:25,554
But still, I felt it must be wonderful

343
00:27:25,636 --> 00:27:31,037
just to jump into that bubbling pot

344
00:27:31,122 --> 00:27:36,184
and be a member
of all those who are believers.

345
00:27:36,262 --> 00:27:38,870
(siren / uproar)

346
00:27:50,034 --> 00:27:53,983
(woman) One lady in our village,
she went to Berlin

347
00:27:54,100 --> 00:27:57,733
to a birthday reception
for Adolf Hitler,

348
00:27:57,821 --> 00:28:02,687
and she came back and told us,
"The Führer shook hands with me."

349
00:28:02,770 --> 00:28:07,559
And from this time on
she was like a saint in our village.

350
00:28:17,424 --> 00:28:21,024
("Adolf Hitler's Edelweiss")

351
00:28:27,436 --> 00:28:31,921
Hitler's home life took place on a ledge
in Bavaria, at Berchtesgaden.

352
00:28:32,001 --> 00:28:35,176
These pictures are from
the home movies of Eva Braun,

353
00:28:35,262 --> 00:28:38,862
the discreet young woman
who stayed with him till his death.

354
00:28:38,983 --> 00:28:42,616
To the Berghof, for tea and tactics,
came the elect.

355
00:28:42,704 --> 00:28:45,159
Some a little ill at ease,

356
00:28:45,236 --> 00:28:46,960
some genuinely intimate.

357
00:28:48,689 --> 00:28:51,056
(song continues)

358
00:29:26,705 --> 00:29:31,877
Even in private Hitler had to correspond
to the image sold to the public.

359
00:29:33,227 --> 00:29:35,212
Adolf with children.

360
00:29:36,487 --> 00:29:38,517
Adolf with dogs.

361
00:29:40,017 --> 00:29:42,624
Adolf with a magnifying glass.

362
00:29:49,991 --> 00:29:51,976
Adolf with friends.

363
00:29:56,627 --> 00:30:01,417
Out for a walk, like a good
Bavarian bourgeois on a Sunday.

364
00:30:08,519 --> 00:30:11,541
In this closed circle
Eva Braun posed herself

365
00:30:11,627 --> 00:30:16,416
as the girl who was
natural, healthy, joyfully physical.

366
00:30:53,824 --> 00:30:58,690
Up at the Berghof
there were jovial, friendly bodyguards

367
00:30:58,773 --> 00:31:00,758
and colder ones.

368
00:31:00,844 --> 00:31:04,063
Heinrich Himmler, lord of the SS,

369
00:31:04,144 --> 00:31:08,279
came with Heydrich,
his terrible, handsome lieutenant.

370
00:31:14,616 --> 00:31:18,369
On formal occasions,
the SS Guard turned out.

371
00:31:18,452 --> 00:31:22,588
They were the reality of the great
tyranny centred in distant Berlin,

372
00:31:22,672 --> 00:31:26,197
their hands soon to be red
with the blood of millions.

373
00:31:27,084 --> 00:31:31,262
For that reality,
Hitler would leave his chintz chair,

374
00:31:31,342 --> 00:31:35,062
his tea parties and his mistress.

375
00:31:35,140 --> 00:31:38,238
The car was waiting
at the foot of the steps.

376
00:31:42,927 --> 00:31:44,912
(brass band)

377
00:31:47,991 --> 00:31:52,857
If Germany was to be strong again,
Germany must re-arm.

378
00:31:52,940 --> 00:31:59,726
A people frightened by war had to become
once more familiar with arms,

379
00:31:59,806 --> 00:32:01,562
to touch them,

380
00:32:01,648 --> 00:32:03,448
to play at soldiers.

381
00:32:22,977 --> 00:32:25,508
Germany had to train pilots.

382
00:32:25,585 --> 00:32:27,724
Versailles forbade Germany an air force,

383
00:32:27,810 --> 00:32:31,029
so the League for Air Sports
used gliders

384
00:32:31,109 --> 00:32:34,862
to train men, still officially
civilians, for the future Luftwaffe.

385
00:32:36,518 --> 00:32:37,860
(excited shouting)

386
00:32:39,242 --> 00:32:42,646
And the army began to swell
beyond the limits set by Versailles

387
00:32:42,733 --> 00:32:45,526
from the moment
Hitler became chancellor.

388
00:32:45,610 --> 00:32:48,981
In secret, it trebled its strength
in two years.

389
00:32:49,906 --> 00:32:51,892
(men singing)

390
00:33:02,873 --> 00:33:06,625
Any foreign military attaché
could see what was happening,

391
00:33:06,709 --> 00:33:08,585
but the world did nothing decisive,

392
00:33:08,665 --> 00:33:12,222
and in March 1935
Germany announced conscription -

393
00:33:12,348 --> 00:33:15,337
a peacetime army of half a million men.

394
00:33:21,056 --> 00:33:24,351
The new tanks came out into the open.

395
00:33:33,063 --> 00:33:36,511
The first Luftwaffe squadrons flew past.

396
00:33:44,457 --> 00:33:47,249
The new German navy was under way.

397
00:33:55,006 --> 00:33:57,340
Hitler kept Europe bewildered.

398
00:33:57,423 --> 00:34:03,052
Proclaiming Versailles extinct,
he proposed a limit on armaments.

399
00:34:03,216 --> 00:34:06,314
Britain, the first democracy
to make a pact with the Nazis,

400
00:34:06,400 --> 00:34:07,970
signed a naval agreement.

401
00:34:08,087 --> 00:34:10,226
Hitler was reassured.

402
00:34:10,312 --> 00:34:14,677
It might be safe to start tampering
with the hated frontiers.

403
00:34:14,762 --> 00:34:18,363
One part of Versailles
had already been undone.

404
00:34:18,445 --> 00:34:21,664
In January 1935
the territory of the Saar,

405
00:34:21,783 --> 00:34:25,656
the little coal-mining region
which had been German before 1918,

406
00:34:25,734 --> 00:34:29,029
voted overwhelmingly,
and under international supervision,

407
00:34:29,110 --> 00:34:31,793
to return to Germany.

408
00:34:38,777 --> 00:34:42,028
Next door, the Rhineland
remained a demilitarised zone.

409
00:34:42,114 --> 00:34:44,253
Beyond dispute,
this was part of Germany,

410
00:34:44,378 --> 00:34:47,247
but to recover it
would directly challenge the Allies

411
00:34:47,331 --> 00:34:49,207
and, above all, France.

412
00:34:50,592 --> 00:34:56,222
The troops rode over the Rhine bridges
at dawn on March 7, 1936.

413
00:34:56,308 --> 00:34:59,832
Secretly, the commanders were ready
to bolt back across the river

414
00:34:59,914 --> 00:35:01,714
if France showed any sign of fight.

415
00:35:01,832 --> 00:35:03,817
But there was none.

416
00:35:05,745 --> 00:35:08,156
The Rhineland city of Cologne
and all Germany

417
00:35:08,238 --> 00:35:10,344
went wild with relief and delight.

418
00:35:10,924 --> 00:35:13,836
A part of German honour
had been recovered.

419
00:35:13,916 --> 00:35:16,753
Hitler had taken a chance and won.

420
00:35:18,251 --> 00:35:24,077
Two years later, Austria, Hitler's
birthplace, lay ripe for the taking.

421
00:35:24,197 --> 00:35:29,335
Austrian Nazis were rioting
for Anschluss - union with Germany.

422
00:35:29,414 --> 00:35:34,051
To prevent a plebiscite on independence,
Hitler marched in.

423
00:35:40,616 --> 00:35:43,834
The German troops were greeted
by hysterical crowds.

424
00:35:43,915 --> 00:35:48,475
Vienna suffered a Jew-baiting terror
which even Germany had not yet seen.

425
00:35:48,595 --> 00:35:51,202
Austria became a province.

426
00:35:51,280 --> 00:35:54,760
Germany's neighbours,
appalled, uncertain, unprepared,

427
00:35:54,848 --> 00:35:57,062
once again did nothing.

428
00:36:04,170 --> 00:36:07,573
Czechoslovakia
was no lost German province,

429
00:36:07,661 --> 00:36:13,182
but an independent nation, allied
to Britain, France and the Soviet Union.

430
00:36:13,261 --> 00:36:17,168
Within its northern border
lived the Sudeten Germans.

431
00:36:17,251 --> 00:36:20,699
Hitler incited this minority,
which had never been part of Germany,

432
00:36:20,857 --> 00:36:23,191
to demand union with the Reich.

433
00:36:23,274 --> 00:36:25,685
Europe prepared for war.

434
00:36:27,187 --> 00:36:30,099
But though Czechoslovakia
was ready to fight,

435
00:36:30,217 --> 00:36:32,322
Britain and France gave way.

436
00:36:32,404 --> 00:36:35,121
At Munich, in September 1938,

437
00:36:35,204 --> 00:36:37,615
Chamberlain for Britain,

438
00:36:37,736 --> 00:36:39,950
Italy's Mussolini,

439
00:36:40,038 --> 00:36:42,525
Daladier for France

440
00:36:42,608 --> 00:36:44,484
signed with Hitler the treaty

441
00:36:44,564 --> 00:36:47,248
which stripped Czechoslovakia
of the Sudetenland

442
00:36:47,326 --> 00:36:49,737
and left her broken and abandoned.

443
00:37:04,167 --> 00:37:06,229
The Germans crossed the border,

444
00:37:06,315 --> 00:37:10,646
welcomed as liberators
by the Sudeten population.

445
00:37:11,571 --> 00:37:14,670
At home, the German generals
who opposed Hitler,

446
00:37:14,755 --> 00:37:19,577
hoping that a rebuff over Czechoslovakia
would fatally injure his prestige,

447
00:37:19,665 --> 00:37:22,153
gave up their plots in despair.

448
00:37:40,764 --> 00:37:44,900
Hitler sat with his troops in the field
and planned ahead.

449
00:37:46,787 --> 00:37:50,158
The Sudetenland was easily digested.

450
00:37:50,239 --> 00:37:52,847
The next course could be taken fast.

451
00:37:55,572 --> 00:37:59,630
The shrunken Czech lands and Slovakia
lay helpless before him.

452
00:37:59,715 --> 00:38:02,857
He struck on March 1 5, 1939.

453
00:38:05,622 --> 00:38:08,874
The German troops reached Prague
the same day.

454
00:38:08,960 --> 00:38:11,415
There was no resistance.

455
00:38:12,950 --> 00:38:17,281
The last democracy in Central Europe
was wiped out.

456
00:38:19,970 --> 00:38:23,417
The Czechs
would never trust the West again.

457
00:38:23,537 --> 00:38:26,178
The West trusted Hitler no more,

458
00:38:26,261 --> 00:38:30,472
and realised at last
that only force would stop him.

459
00:38:40,148 --> 00:38:43,137
Berlin: more cheers, more worship.

460
00:38:44,176 --> 00:38:47,973
Yet what was in the minds
of those who cheered?

461
00:38:48,050 --> 00:38:49,960
Very few wanted wars of conquest

462
00:38:50,045 --> 00:38:51,845
or hoped, like Hitler,

463
00:38:51,925 --> 00:38:55,798
for a German empire
from the Urals to the Atlantic.

464
00:38:55,876 --> 00:38:59,979
Most thought they were taking back
what had been robbed from them

465
00:39:00,096 --> 00:39:05,344
and restoring, not destroying,
the order and unity of Europe.

466
00:39:05,428 --> 00:39:07,883
(jubilant singing)

467
00:39:16,975 --> 00:39:23,063
For these crowds it seemed that
Hitler's statesmanship could never fail.

468
00:39:23,151 --> 00:39:25,213
Others who stayed at home that night

469
00:39:25,299 --> 00:39:28,703
feared a war was coming
which might destroy Germany itself.

470
00:39:28,790 --> 00:39:32,423
But now they saw no hope
for a rising against Hitler,

471
00:39:32,511 --> 00:39:34,726
they were left with the moral question:

472
00:39:34,813 --> 00:39:39,178
"Should one resist a tyranny
without hope of success?"

473
00:39:40,261 --> 00:39:45,814
Well, I think it's difficult
first of all to make up your mind

474
00:39:45,976 --> 00:39:49,883
that you should do something
against a government.

475
00:39:51,078 --> 00:39:54,526
This is very rare, first of all.

476
00:39:54,646 --> 00:39:58,825
Secondly, if it is extremely dangerous,

477
00:39:58,904 --> 00:40:02,308
as it is in a dictatorship,

478
00:40:02,395 --> 00:40:07,217
it's even more complicated
because everybody likes his own life.

479
00:40:08,571 --> 00:40:13,165
I think everything that came to us
when we were living in Germany

480
00:40:13,290 --> 00:40:16,202
came very gradually.

481
00:40:16,282 --> 00:40:23,374
That was part, perhaps, of the way
Hitler managed these things.

482
00:40:23,494 --> 00:40:26,516
It came on us rather drip by drip,

483
00:40:26,601 --> 00:40:29,852
rather like an anaesthetic,
one could almost say,

484
00:40:29,977 --> 00:40:37,343
and it was only when a specific thing
that he did hit you personally

485
00:40:37,419 --> 00:40:43,245
that you actually realised
what was going on.

486
00:40:44,555 --> 00:40:50,610
In my particular case, I think
I could say that it hit me personally

487
00:40:50,692 --> 00:40:55,635
when the Jewish doctor of my children,

488
00:40:55,718 --> 00:40:58,358
whom I'd always had, came...

489
00:40:58,441 --> 00:41:03,384
He was a very busy man, but he seemed
to be having always more time to spare.

490
00:41:03,467 --> 00:41:05,725
I remember one night

491
00:41:05,807 --> 00:41:10,596
he came and spent the night
looking after my very sick child.

492
00:41:10,679 --> 00:41:13,319
And in the morning the child was better

493
00:41:13,402 --> 00:41:17,309
and when he left he asked me,

494
00:41:17,392 --> 00:41:20,262
did I still want him
to look after my children?

495
00:41:20,346 --> 00:41:23,979
And I was tired and I said,
"Well, for goodness' sakes, why not?"

496
00:41:24,067 --> 00:41:27,241
And he told me that
his clinic, his children's clinic,

497
00:41:27,328 --> 00:41:30,885
which he had started in Hamburg
was going...

498
00:41:30,972 --> 00:41:34,376
He was going to be dismissed,
and he'd had threatening letters

499
00:41:34,463 --> 00:41:39,057
that if he laid his hands on
Aryan children, he was in for trouble.

500
00:41:41,867 --> 00:41:47,999
(narrator) In November 1938
a Jew shot a German diplomat in Paris.

501
00:41:48,081 --> 00:41:50,689
The Nazi leaders organised a reprisal.

502
00:41:50,767 --> 00:41:55,785
Synagogues were burned and Jewish
shops looted all over Germany.

503
00:41:56,943 --> 00:41:59,474
On that "Crystal Night",

504
00:41:59,551 --> 00:42:02,726
named for the smashed glass
sparkling in the gutters,

505
00:42:02,812 --> 00:42:06,915
thousands of Jews
were thrown into concentration camps.

506
00:42:09,602 --> 00:42:11,587
(speaks German)

507
00:42:15,088 --> 00:42:17,771
(translator) Do you want to know
how the night was?

508
00:42:17,850 --> 00:42:20,413
If you want to know, I will tell you.

509
00:42:20,535 --> 00:42:25,096
We were all shoved together,
beaten and punched

510
00:42:25,215 --> 00:42:29,274
and made to stand in ranks
and be counted and so on.

511
00:42:30,548 --> 00:42:34,650
Because I'd been a soldier
I didn't find that so very difficult,

512
00:42:34,729 --> 00:42:38,286
but the others
who didn't fall in properly,

513
00:42:38,373 --> 00:42:40,740
they were beaten right away.

514
00:42:42,440 --> 00:42:44,272
And the most terrible thing was

515
00:42:44,358 --> 00:42:46,965
when somebody grabbed hold
of a big, strong man,

516
00:42:47,043 --> 00:42:49,607
he said, "Don't grab me."

517
00:42:49,690 --> 00:42:53,323
"What? I shouldn't grab you!"
And he hit him.

518
00:42:56,864 --> 00:43:02,799
And this man was immediately
overpowered by three people - SS people.

519
00:43:02,886 --> 00:43:04,872
A block was brought.

520
00:43:04,958 --> 00:43:08,678
He was tied down to it
and the camp commander said,

521
00:43:08,756 --> 00:43:13,894
"The Jew Israel," or "The Jew Itzik," -
I can't remember exactly now -

522
00:43:13,973 --> 00:43:16,307
"is sentenced to 25 lashes."

523
00:43:19,344 --> 00:43:21,482
Then a huge man came,

524
00:43:21,569 --> 00:43:25,933
an SS man with a huge horsewhip,
and started to beat him.

525
00:43:27,668 --> 00:43:33,069
The man just groaned a bit at first,
but then he shouted, "Stop, stop!"

526
00:43:33,154 --> 00:43:35,871
The commander said,
"What do you mean, stop?"

527
00:43:35,954 --> 00:43:39,674
"We'll start all over again,
from the beginning."

528
00:43:39,752 --> 00:43:43,080
But after three more lashes
the blood was spurting,

529
00:43:43,166 --> 00:43:46,232
then he stopped and salt
was rubbed into the wounds,

530
00:43:46,312 --> 00:43:48,526
or pepper, I can't remember.

531
00:43:48,614 --> 00:43:50,675
The man was dragged away.

532
00:43:50,762 --> 00:43:53,217
We never saw him again.

533
00:43:54,982 --> 00:44:01,157
Of course, in '38,
when the synagogues were burning,

534
00:44:01,234 --> 00:44:03,601
everybody knew what was going on.

535
00:44:03,728 --> 00:44:08,398
I remember that my brother-in-law,
the husband of my sister Lena,

536
00:44:08,485 --> 00:44:13,962
when he went in the morning after
the day of the Reichskristallnacht -

537
00:44:14,047 --> 00:44:16,764
"Crystal Night", or how you say -

538
00:44:17,883 --> 00:44:20,600
he went by train to his office downtown

539
00:44:20,684 --> 00:44:24,055
and between the stations of
Savignyplatz and Zoological Garden

540
00:44:24,213 --> 00:44:29,276
there is the Jewish synagogue, ja,
and he saw that it was burning, ja?

541
00:44:29,354 --> 00:44:32,190
And he murmured, "Kulturschande."

542
00:44:32,269 --> 00:44:37,408
That is an insult for culture -
"Shame to our culture."

543
00:44:37,486 --> 00:44:41,512
Well, right away a gentleman
in front of him turned his Revers

544
00:44:41,591 --> 00:44:46,959
and showed his Parteiabzeichen -
party badge, ja?

545
00:44:47,038 --> 00:44:51,904
And took out his papers
that he was a man of the Gestapo,

546
00:44:51,987 --> 00:44:56,973
and he had to show his papers,
to give his address,

547
00:44:57,051 --> 00:45:01,415
and was ordered to come to the party
office next morning, nine o'clock.

548
00:45:11,666 --> 00:45:13,652
(narrator) April, 1939.

549
00:45:13,776 --> 00:45:17,529
The Wehrmacht prepares to celebrate
Hitler's 50th birthday.

550
00:45:18,610 --> 00:45:23,018
They hope for the usual
"Führer weather" - a fine day.

551
00:45:34,530 --> 00:45:37,978
The Führer drives through Berlin,
under the Brandenburg Gate

552
00:45:38,059 --> 00:45:42,576
and down the Siegesallee -
the Avenue of Victories.

553
00:45:58,468 --> 00:46:04,141
The army lining his route has increased
sevenfold in just four years.

554
00:46:14,925 --> 00:46:17,685
Among the Wehrmacht's 51 divisions,

555
00:46:17,763 --> 00:46:22,128
the new panzer units -
the instrument of blitzkrieg.

556
00:46:36,100 --> 00:46:39,351
In spite of appearances,
the high command is by no means sure

557
00:46:39,438 --> 00:46:42,427
that this army is fit for war... yet.

558
00:46:43,849 --> 00:46:46,184
Hitler is ready to overrule them.

559
00:47:05,792 --> 00:47:10,123
The word in every diplomatic
conversation that summer was Danzig.

560
00:47:10,242 --> 00:47:13,417
The free city,
with its mixed German-Polish people,

561
00:47:13,503 --> 00:47:15,259
had been separated from Germany

562
00:47:15,344 --> 00:47:19,218
and made the responsibility
of a League of Nations commissioner.

563
00:47:20,945 --> 00:47:25,080
Danzig and East Prussia
were now sundered from the Reich

564
00:47:25,165 --> 00:47:29,114
by a strip of Polish territory -
the Corridor.

565
00:47:29,193 --> 00:47:31,527
Hitler was demanding
the return of Danzig

566
00:47:31,609 --> 00:47:35,330
and free access to East Prussia
across the Corridor.

567
00:47:35,407 --> 00:47:37,207
Poland refused.

568
00:47:37,287 --> 00:47:42,426
In March, 1939, Britain and France
guaranteed her frontiers.

569
00:47:42,504 --> 00:47:47,600
In August, Britain promised to fight
if Poland was attacked.

570
00:47:48,987 --> 00:47:53,243
Once again, myths about the persecution
of a German minority were used

571
00:47:53,322 --> 00:47:56,192
to build up a case
for armed intervention.

572
00:47:56,276 --> 00:48:00,258
German refugees told piteous tales
of Polish brutality.

573
00:48:00,342 --> 00:48:02,372
(speaks German)

574
00:48:06,979 --> 00:48:10,427
Nazi propaganda filmed them greedily
for the cinema newsreels

575
00:48:10,508 --> 00:48:13,683
throughout July and August.

576
00:48:14,383 --> 00:48:18,289
Hitler's plan was to wipe Poland
off the map.

577
00:48:18,372 --> 00:48:20,827
But this might mean
war with Soviet Russia,

578
00:48:20,904 --> 00:48:22,552
and he was not ready for that.

579
00:48:23,551 --> 00:48:26,999
His foreign minister, Ribbentrop,
flew to Moscow on August 23

580
00:48:27,080 --> 00:48:30,376
to sign the Nazi-Soviet Pact.

581
00:48:30,495 --> 00:48:32,829
Poland's fate was sealed.

582
00:48:37,515 --> 00:48:40,689
The new alliance
stunned the unsuspecting West.

583
00:48:40,814 --> 00:48:42,799
(newsreel intro)

584
00:48:45,532 --> 00:48:47,518
Germany gloated.

585
00:48:50,059 --> 00:48:52,121
(reporter speaking German)

586
00:48:57,041 --> 00:49:00,063
You will have read the report
about the agreement reached

587
00:49:00,148 --> 00:49:04,742
between Russia and Germany,
which has surprised the world.

588
00:49:04,828 --> 00:49:08,461
As the life of all nations depends,
in the last resort,

589
00:49:08,549 --> 00:49:11,648
upon mutual respect
for one another's rights

590
00:49:11,733 --> 00:49:16,480
and reasonable confidence that they can
each live their life in their own way,

591
00:49:17,219 --> 00:49:18,790
I would earnestly hope...

592
00:49:25,889 --> 00:49:30,635
..which cannot be retraced,
reason may yet prevail.

593
00:49:30,761 --> 00:49:32,561
(narrator) The German newsreels

594
00:49:32,640 --> 00:49:35,859
tried to show Britain
distracted, still uncertain.

595
00:49:35,939 --> 00:49:38,503
(reporter speaking German)

596
00:49:45,798 --> 00:49:48,133
(reporter continues in German)

597
00:49:53,471 --> 00:49:57,726
(narrator) One young German
left England for home.

598
00:49:58,496 --> 00:50:01,333
(man) I had a girlfriend
whom I wanted to marry

599
00:50:01,412 --> 00:50:07,118
and I said, "Well, I'll dare go home."

600
00:50:07,204 --> 00:50:13,107
When I came to Cologne
I read the first German newspapers,

601
00:50:14,608 --> 00:50:22,126
and I knew at once that
there was great danger of a war now.

602
00:50:22,204 --> 00:50:28,062
The tone of the German press
was absolutely hysterical.

603
00:50:28,802 --> 00:50:33,396
And I thought what a fool I was.

604
00:50:33,482 --> 00:50:37,585
I had just gone home in that moment!

605
00:50:38,891 --> 00:50:43,485
(narrator) All over Europe
the reservists got their telegrams.

606
00:50:43,571 --> 00:50:49,703
In the last hours of peace, the soldiers
put on uniform with a tired grin.
