1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:10,857 --> 00:00:14,032
(narrator) No country, no people

3
00:00:14,157 --> 00:00:18,183
suffered so terribly in the war
as the Soviet Union.

4
00:00:18,799 --> 00:00:22,356
Nowhere else are
the memories of war so alive today,

5
00:00:22,443 --> 00:00:24,931
and so profound.

6
00:00:25,014 --> 00:00:27,469
The German invasion
brought about a catastrophe

7
00:00:27,546 --> 00:00:31,420
which it seemed at first
no nation could survive.

8
00:00:31,498 --> 00:00:36,364
In the siege of Leningrad alone,
which lasted for over two years,

9
00:00:36,447 --> 00:00:38,585
more human beings died

10
00:00:38,672 --> 00:00:43,691
than the total war dead of Britain
and the United States combined.

11
00:00:45,079 --> 00:00:48,068
Yet it was here that Hitler was broken.

12
00:00:49,069 --> 00:00:53,586
The Russian people faced
the possibility that they might perish,

13
00:00:53,672 --> 00:00:56,039
and overcame it.

14
00:00:56,166 --> 00:00:57,770
We are hoping for the victory.

15
00:00:57,854 --> 00:01:02,677
We are quite sure
that the victory will come sometime,

16
00:01:02,765 --> 00:01:07,555
and we hoped that
our hardships would end.

17
00:02:04,148 --> 00:02:07,782
(narrator)
Kharkov, under German occupation, 1942.

18
00:02:12,282 --> 00:02:14,115
Hitler had written in Mein Kampf:

19
00:02:14,238 --> 00:02:18,417
"The colossal empire in the east
is ripe for dissolution."

20
00:02:18,497 --> 00:02:21,137
"And the end of Jewish domination
in Russia

21
00:02:21,221 --> 00:02:24,243
will also be the end of Russia
as a state."

22
00:02:25,978 --> 00:02:29,077
The Soviet system was to be demolished.

23
00:02:31,004 --> 00:02:36,296
But there was more. It was in Russia
that Hitler would find Lebensraum -

24
00:02:36,375 --> 00:02:39,135
new territory for German colonisation.

25
00:02:42,820 --> 00:02:45,657
The Soviet peoples
would be treated as mere natives

26
00:02:45,736 --> 00:02:47,875
in a German colonial empire.

27
00:02:47,961 --> 00:02:51,638
Their cities would be Germanised
or razed to the ground.

28
00:02:52,642 --> 00:02:55,664
They would be pedlars,
backward peasants,

29
00:02:55,749 --> 00:02:57,964
domestic servants, labourers.

30
00:03:18,231 --> 00:03:21,559
Communists and intellectuals
were exterminated.

31
00:03:21,645 --> 00:03:25,857
The least sign of defiance
brought instant reprisal.

32
00:03:26,786 --> 00:03:29,197
(speaking Russian)

33
00:03:29,280 --> 00:03:33,110
(interpreter) The occupiers
were harsh, very harsh,

34
00:03:33,193 --> 00:03:37,601
especially in those areas
where the partisans were active.

35
00:03:37,682 --> 00:03:42,504
In the Ukraine, 511 villages
were burnt down by the Nazis

36
00:03:42,593 --> 00:03:45,310
before the population could escape.

37
00:03:46,314 --> 00:03:49,489
In one village, Pisk, near Kiev,

38
00:03:49,575 --> 00:03:52,717
which was totally razed to the ground,

39
00:03:52,874 --> 00:03:55,744
babies were thrown into the fire.

40
00:04:01,276 --> 00:04:02,727
(narrator) Before the war,

41
00:04:02,811 --> 00:04:04,873
the regions now occupied by the Germans

42
00:04:04,998 --> 00:04:06,907
had produced nearly three quarters

43
00:04:06,993 --> 00:04:08,640
of the country's coal and iron,

44
00:04:08,757 --> 00:04:10,896
a third of its beef and grain,

45
00:04:10,983 --> 00:04:13,438
almost all its sugar.

46
00:04:13,975 --> 00:04:16,768
By autumn 1941, the Germans controlled

47
00:04:16,852 --> 00:04:21,763
what had been the industrial and
agricultural heart of the Soviet Union.

48
00:04:29,398 --> 00:04:32,420
The invaders found that
the Russians had tried to destroy

49
00:04:32,505 --> 00:04:34,567
everything they had to leave behind.

50
00:04:34,654 --> 00:04:39,869
Villages burned, the summer harvest
flamed in the fields around them.

51
00:04:40,293 --> 00:04:43,435
By that autumn,
the Germans had advanced for 600 miles

52
00:04:43,516 --> 00:04:46,309
over scorched earth.

53
00:04:49,117 --> 00:04:50,993
In some of the Baltic republics,

54
00:04:51,074 --> 00:04:54,369
which had only been annexed
by the Soviet Union a year before,

55
00:04:54,488 --> 00:04:58,395
the Germans were made welcome
by local nationalists.

56
00:05:00,396 --> 00:05:01,771
In parts of the Ukraine,

57
00:05:01,854 --> 00:05:06,339
some of the peasants made the
traditional offering of bread and salt.

58
00:05:10,832 --> 00:05:14,814
The bodies of nationalists shot by
Soviet security at the last moment

59
00:05:14,937 --> 00:05:17,849
were brought out
and carried through the streets.

60
00:05:22,264 --> 00:05:26,061
For a brief moment, it seemed to some
that these submerged nations

61
00:05:26,139 --> 00:05:29,129
might become
willing partners of the Nazis.

62
00:05:31,203 --> 00:05:33,342
Communists were hunted down.

63
00:05:35,117 --> 00:05:37,572
And in all the places
the Nazis occupied,

64
00:05:37,687 --> 00:05:40,021
the round-up of the Jews began.

65
00:06:01,243 --> 00:06:06,229
In the path of the German,
Russia seemed to be crumbling away.

66
00:06:06,307 --> 00:06:11,294
Stalin had the defeated commander
of the Western Front and his staff

67
00:06:11,410 --> 00:06:13,624
arrested and shot.

68
00:06:19,274 --> 00:06:22,526
Monuments of Soviet construction,
even the Dnieper Dam,

69
00:06:22,651 --> 00:06:24,942
the very symbol of the Five-Year Plans,

70
00:06:25,029 --> 00:06:27,593
had to be blown up and abandoned.

71
00:06:33,623 --> 00:06:37,453
Locomotives were wrecked,
though they were needed as never before,

72
00:06:37,536 --> 00:06:41,672
for there now began an evacuation
which in the end was to save Russia

73
00:06:41,795 --> 00:06:45,013
and change the course of the war.

74
00:06:54,263 --> 00:06:59,588
1500 factories moved on 18,000 trains
with over a million workers

75
00:06:59,673 --> 00:07:03,470
to the safety of eastern Russia
and the Urals.

76
00:07:03,547 --> 00:07:05,380
One witness said:

77
00:07:05,466 --> 00:07:08,412
"It was as if the earth tilted up

78
00:07:08,535 --> 00:07:12,746
and everything human or mechanical
rolled from west to east."

79
00:07:12,832 --> 00:07:14,817
(speaking Russian)

80
00:07:16,783 --> 00:07:19,500
(interpreter)
There was no factory when we arrived.

81
00:07:19,584 --> 00:07:23,381
There were only storehouses
where materials were kept.

82
00:07:26,106 --> 00:07:30,820
We began by emptying the stores
and clearing the land around it.

83
00:07:34,163 --> 00:07:37,032
We were working up to 14 hours a day.

84
00:07:38,383 --> 00:07:40,946
(narrator) In bleak places,
lacking food or sleep,

85
00:07:41,030 --> 00:07:46,627
the Russians reconstructed a new war
industry beyond the reach of the Nazis.

86
00:07:49,470 --> 00:07:51,532
When we emptied the storehouses,

87
00:07:51,657 --> 00:07:53,916
the machinery arrived.

88
00:07:54,918 --> 00:07:58,060
Where the warehouses used to be,

89
00:07:58,179 --> 00:08:00,088
we built a new factory.

90
00:08:00,174 --> 00:08:02,313
(patriotic Russian song)

91
00:08:15,174 --> 00:08:18,623
(narrator) Unlike the Germans,
the Russians, from the first hour,

92
00:08:18,704 --> 00:08:21,159
waged a total war.

93
00:08:21,236 --> 00:08:23,767
Every pair of hands
was set to the machines

94
00:08:23,845 --> 00:08:27,249
as the men were drafted
into the battles of the west.

95
00:08:27,374 --> 00:08:30,015
War work strained everyone to the heart.

96
00:08:30,904 --> 00:08:33,664
11 to 15 hours a day, rations short,

97
00:08:33,781 --> 00:08:36,149
worry about a husband or a son
at the front,

98
00:08:36,237 --> 00:08:39,150
exhaustion like a permanent illness.

99
00:08:45,713 --> 00:08:49,924
But for the camera,
they wore a cheerful, determined face.

100
00:08:53,885 --> 00:08:56,645
Now the Germans
were breaking through to Leningrad,

101
00:08:56,724 --> 00:09:00,750
Russia's second city
and capital of the revolution.

102
00:09:05,241 --> 00:09:07,499
(Russian marching song)

103
00:09:12,837 --> 00:09:15,019
The workers were given rifles.

104
00:09:15,100 --> 00:09:17,162
Harking back to the days of revolution,

105
00:09:17,249 --> 00:09:21,231
Leningrad's leaders encouraged
the whole city to stand and fight.

106
00:09:21,315 --> 00:09:24,873
Untrained,
they marched out to face the panzers

107
00:09:24,998 --> 00:09:28,140
within sight
of their own factory chimneys.

108
00:09:30,101 --> 00:09:33,549
The chance to get non-combatants
out of Leningrad was missed.

109
00:09:33,630 --> 00:09:37,308
Anyway, most families preferred to stay.

110
00:09:37,390 --> 00:09:42,137
My husband,
he got two places on a plane,

111
00:09:42,224 --> 00:09:47,320
and he asked me suddenly
to take the child and go with him,

112
00:09:47,442 --> 00:09:51,468
but I refused because
I couldn't leave my mother

113
00:09:51,585 --> 00:09:57,761
and his mother, my mother-in-law,
here in the besieged city.

114
00:09:57,839 --> 00:10:00,294
So I told him
to take the old lady with him

115
00:10:00,371 --> 00:10:03,928
and I remained in Leningrad
with my mother and child.

116
00:10:04,859 --> 00:10:08,307
(narrator) In September,
the German ring closed.

117
00:10:08,427 --> 00:10:11,569
Over two and half million people
were trapped in the city,

118
00:10:11,650 --> 00:10:14,520
400,000 of them children.

119
00:10:14,604 --> 00:10:17,779
Leningrad's only link with Russia
was across Lake Ladoga.

120
00:10:17,865 --> 00:10:20,429
The greatest of all sieges
was beginning.

121
00:10:21,280 --> 00:10:23,538
Now Stalin intervened.

122
00:10:23,620 --> 00:10:26,795
Marshal Voroshilov,
in command of Leningrad, was sacked.

123
00:10:26,881 --> 00:10:29,521
In his place was sent
Marshal Georgi Zhukov,

124
00:10:29,605 --> 00:10:32,474
who was to become
one of the great commanders of the war.

125
00:10:32,559 --> 00:10:36,738
His deputy was the hard and resourceful
Andrei Zhdanov,

126
00:10:36,817 --> 00:10:39,348
Leningrad's Communist Party chief.

127
00:10:42,380 --> 00:10:46,592
Leningrad soon felt
the new team's determination.

128
00:10:46,677 --> 00:10:48,128
Outside the city,

129
00:10:48,212 --> 00:10:51,736
Zhukov threatened that anyone
who retreated further would be shot.

130
00:10:52,700 --> 00:10:57,185
Inside, the security forces
hunted down spies and defeatists.

131
00:10:57,266 --> 00:10:59,754
Zhdanov's men ended the wastage of food,

132
00:10:59,836 --> 00:11:03,055
mobilising everybody
for the city's defence.

133
00:11:08,929 --> 00:11:12,911
Every major building was mined
in case the Germans broke in.

134
00:11:15,105 --> 00:11:19,284
But the German attempt
to take Leningrad by storm failed.

135
00:11:20,707 --> 00:11:22,201
(siren)

136
00:11:25,771 --> 00:11:30,026
Berlin ordered: "The Führer has decided
to raze the city of Petersburg

137
00:11:30,106 --> 00:11:32,059
from the face of the earth."

138
00:11:32,139 --> 00:11:36,046
"There is no reason for the
future existence of this large city."

139
00:11:39,083 --> 00:11:43,524
The Leningraders were to be bombarded
and starved to death.

140
00:11:49,941 --> 00:11:52,352
Day after day, the bombers came over.

141
00:12:42,232 --> 00:12:45,909
German gunners could see the spires
of Leningrad from their lines.

142
00:12:45,992 --> 00:12:50,127
Their shells could strike
every district, every street.

143
00:13:08,243 --> 00:13:12,150
Lake Ladoga remained
the only gap in the enemy ring.

144
00:13:12,233 --> 00:13:17,831
When it froze, an ice road for supplies
was built across its surface.

145
00:13:27,426 --> 00:13:31,943
Trucks fell through the ice
or were destroyed by air attack.

146
00:13:41,812 --> 00:13:46,220
The ice road could bring too little in
and take too few civilians out

147
00:13:46,301 --> 00:13:49,597
to keep Leningrad
from the onset of starvation.

148
00:13:50,751 --> 00:13:54,549
Everything was running out.
The trams and buses stopped.

149
00:13:54,626 --> 00:13:58,533
In the darkness and intense cold
of the North Russian winter,

150
00:13:58,616 --> 00:14:01,638
there was no longer heating
or electric light.

151
00:14:01,724 --> 00:14:04,746
Workers, half-conscious with hunger,

152
00:14:04,831 --> 00:14:07,046
kept the arms factories turning,

153
00:14:07,172 --> 00:14:10,346
even when shells had torn off the roof.

154
00:14:17,453 --> 00:14:22,626
Tanks of raw, unpainted steel drove
out of the factory into the front line.

155
00:14:23,975 --> 00:14:28,536
Bread was now made with
sweepings, cattle-cake, sawdust.

156
00:14:28,617 --> 00:14:31,684
People ate soap, linseed oil,

157
00:14:31,763 --> 00:14:33,825
the paste for wallpaper.

158
00:14:33,912 --> 00:14:35,406
Housewives and children

159
00:14:35,485 --> 00:14:40,122
got only four and half ounces
of this "bread" a day.

160
00:14:52,864 --> 00:14:55,123
Frozen and silent,

161
00:14:55,204 --> 00:14:57,496
Leningrad refused to die.

162
00:14:58,504 --> 00:15:00,642
The libraries stayed open.

163
00:15:00,729 --> 00:15:05,639
People took inspiration
from the new literature of the blockade.

164
00:15:06,790 --> 00:15:08,929
(Olga) Poetry was, for us,

165
00:15:09,054 --> 00:15:12,273
a great force that kept us alive.

166
00:15:12,353 --> 00:15:15,146
(narrator)
"If what they say of Leningrad is true,

167
00:15:15,231 --> 00:15:17,522
the tears have frozen
in the people's eyes."

168
00:15:17,609 --> 00:15:22,170
"We cry no longer, for no tears
could quench our burning hate."

169
00:15:22,251 --> 00:15:25,012
"And hate is our only course."

170
00:15:25,090 --> 00:15:28,309
"The guarantee of life,
the cure for grief,

171
00:15:28,390 --> 00:15:31,947
the one uniting,
warming, guiding force."

172
00:15:32,955 --> 00:15:36,588
And the end of November,
December and January

173
00:15:36,677 --> 00:15:39,394
were the most tragic of times.

174
00:15:39,477 --> 00:15:43,078
Firstly, it was cold - minus 40.

175
00:15:43,160 --> 00:15:47,219
Then the famine, the hunger, began to...

176
00:15:47,304 --> 00:15:50,708
to... to be felt.

177
00:15:50,795 --> 00:15:53,250
And people began to starve

178
00:15:53,327 --> 00:15:55,280
and to die from cold.

179
00:15:57,470 --> 00:16:00,111
(narrator) The siege went on.

180
00:16:01,882 --> 00:16:04,719
There were few ways
to hit back at the Germans.

181
00:16:05,335 --> 00:16:09,056
One was with naval guns
from the warships trapped in the port.

182
00:16:10,207 --> 00:16:15,882
On land, small raiding parties
penetrated behind the German trenches.

183
00:16:22,484 --> 00:16:24,470
They cut supply lines,

184
00:16:24,556 --> 00:16:26,585
they captured prisoners

185
00:16:26,666 --> 00:16:29,230
and collected information.

186
00:16:36,372 --> 00:16:40,584
They descended on collaborators
and tried them on the spot.

187
00:16:50,606 --> 00:16:53,061
January 1942.

188
00:16:53,176 --> 00:16:58,392
About 4,000 people
were dying in Leningrad each day.

189
00:17:25,556 --> 00:17:28,655
(Olga) When I went to the shops

190
00:17:28,740 --> 00:17:31,806
to receive my ration for my family,

191
00:17:31,886 --> 00:17:34,679
if I passed on the way there two bodies,

192
00:17:34,763 --> 00:17:37,371
on the way back there were four.

193
00:18:20,034 --> 00:18:24,290
(narrator) Outside the ring, the
Russians fought to loosen the blockade

194
00:18:24,369 --> 00:18:28,046
and to speed up the pitifully slow
convoys across the frozen lake.

195
00:18:28,129 --> 00:18:33,421
But there was no major offensive
to break the siege ring, and no airlift.

196
00:18:34,574 --> 00:18:40,172
The battles before Moscow
had first call on men and equipment.

197
00:18:45,969 --> 00:18:49,035
Spring brought new fears.

198
00:18:49,114 --> 00:18:51,100
The murderous cold slackened,

199
00:18:51,186 --> 00:18:54,667
but melting snowdrifts
revealed thousands of corpses

200
00:18:54,792 --> 00:18:57,400
in the streets and yards.

201
00:19:01,046 --> 00:19:04,265
A campaign was launched
to clean up the city.

202
00:19:12,517 --> 00:19:14,656
There was no epidemic.

203
00:19:26,136 --> 00:19:28,012
Now the ice road was melting.

204
00:19:28,093 --> 00:19:32,730
Although there would be a difficult time
before the lake was clear for ships,

205
00:19:32,812 --> 00:19:35,103
the mood in Leningrad
was turning confident.

206
00:19:35,651 --> 00:19:40,365
(Olga) When the sun began to shine,
then we began to clean

207
00:19:40,447 --> 00:19:42,661
and to wash.

208
00:19:42,748 --> 00:19:46,000
Of course,
now we had water in our homes.

209
00:19:46,125 --> 00:19:49,147
We began to feel normal again.

210
00:19:50,114 --> 00:19:54,326
(narrator) The city council dared
to send a few trams back on the streets.

211
00:19:54,411 --> 00:19:59,856
(Olga) We greeted the tram as an
old forgotten friend coming back to us.

212
00:19:59,936 --> 00:20:05,184
I remember I clapped my hands when
I saw the tram running along Liteiny.

213
00:20:30,052 --> 00:20:32,889
(narrator) The survivors felt stronger.

214
00:20:33,006 --> 00:20:35,690
Their rations were increased.

215
00:20:49,120 --> 00:20:53,026
Squads of volunteers went from
house to house bringing help to families

216
00:20:53,109 --> 00:20:57,474
who, in the winter, had almost
lost contact with the city outside.

217
00:21:05,425 --> 00:21:08,491
Children who should have been evacuated
eight months before

218
00:21:08,570 --> 00:21:11,178
were taken by ship across Lake Ladoga.

219
00:21:18,430 --> 00:21:20,841
The ships brought back
troops and munitions

220
00:21:20,962 --> 00:21:23,493
to relieve the gaunt men
in the trenches.

221
00:21:23,571 --> 00:21:27,052
Leningrad began to look more like
a military base.

222
00:21:30,477 --> 00:21:32,768
The worst of the siege was over.

223
00:21:32,855 --> 00:21:37,264
Though the bombardment went on,
it now made sense to repair the damage.

224
00:21:38,802 --> 00:21:41,792
Peat was dug for fuel
against the next winter.

225
00:21:43,904 --> 00:21:46,742
Schoolchildren and professors of botany

226
00:21:46,820 --> 00:21:50,345
helped to plant every open space
with vegetables.

227
00:21:57,486 --> 00:22:00,093
There were no worries
about food for the Germans

228
00:22:00,171 --> 00:22:02,353
occupying the prairies of the Ukraine.

229
00:22:02,435 --> 00:22:05,883
For 50 years, German expansionists
had looked to this region

230
00:22:05,964 --> 00:22:09,216
to free Germany
from dependence on imports by sea.

231
00:22:11,949 --> 00:22:17,165
General Manstein said, "A large part of
the population will have to go hungry."

232
00:22:17,243 --> 00:22:20,495
"Nothing, out of
a misguided sense of humanity,

233
00:22:20,581 --> 00:22:22,337
may be given to the population,

234
00:22:22,423 --> 00:22:25,827
unless they are in the service
of the German Wehrmacht."

235
00:22:52,501 --> 00:22:56,756
In Kiev, the Ukrainian capital,
plans to win over local nationalists

236
00:22:56,836 --> 00:23:01,124
with the promise of an anti-Russian
puppet state never got off the ground.

237
00:23:01,210 --> 00:23:04,734
They were brushed aside
by the army and the SS.

238
00:23:04,816 --> 00:23:09,071
The reality was
work under German overseers

239
00:23:09,189 --> 00:23:11,524
or deportation to the Reich.

240
00:23:15,059 --> 00:23:18,278
Each village
learned the price of defiance.

241
00:23:25,149 --> 00:23:27,866
In Moscow in early 1942
there was confidence.

242
00:23:27,950 --> 00:23:29,750
The winter fighting had revealed

243
00:23:29,830 --> 00:23:33,125
that the Germans were no more invincible
than Napoleon had been.

244
00:23:33,206 --> 00:23:34,503
But it seemed to Russians

245
00:23:34,625 --> 00:23:37,647
that they bore the burden
of the war against Fascism alone

246
00:23:37,733 --> 00:23:40,799
and that the West was not doing enough.

247
00:23:43,027 --> 00:23:47,054
When Stalin began to call for
a second front, a landing in the west,

248
00:23:47,132 --> 00:23:51,235
the people joined willingly
in the meetings organised to support it.

249
00:23:51,544 --> 00:23:54,719
Molotov, the foreign minister,
was told by Western diplomats

250
00:23:54,805 --> 00:23:58,024
that though they admired
the heroism of the Red Army,

251
00:23:58,105 --> 00:24:01,508
a second front was not yet practical.

252
00:24:01,596 --> 00:24:03,581
Stalin didn't believe them.

253
00:24:03,667 --> 00:24:05,653
(speaking Russian)

254
00:24:08,463 --> 00:24:10,493
Stalin was in direct command of an army

255
00:24:10,573 --> 00:24:13,901
becoming harder and more formidable
every day.

256
00:24:16,098 --> 00:24:19,622
But the Russians did not pretend
to be immune to grief.

257
00:24:19,704 --> 00:24:22,617
Tens of thousands
knew this poem by heart...

258
00:24:23,617 --> 00:24:26,487
"Wait for me, and I'll return."

259
00:24:26,571 --> 00:24:28,938
"Only, wait very hard."

260
00:24:29,602 --> 00:24:33,705
"Wait when you are filled with sorrow
as you watch the yellow rain."

261
00:24:33,784 --> 00:24:36,272
"Wait when the winds
sweep the snowdrifts."

262
00:24:37,006 --> 00:24:38,807
"Wait in the sweltering heat."

263
00:24:38,886 --> 00:24:43,447
"Wait when others have stopped waiting,
forgetting their yesterdays."

264
00:24:43,528 --> 00:24:47,587
"Wait even when from afar
no letters come to you."

265
00:24:47,672 --> 00:24:50,891
"Wait even when
others are tired of waiting."

266
00:24:50,971 --> 00:24:54,801
"Wait even when
my mother and son think I am no more,

267
00:24:54,884 --> 00:24:58,409
and when friends sit around the fire
drinking to my memory."

268
00:24:58,491 --> 00:25:03,051
"Wait, and do not hurry
to drink to my memory too."

269
00:25:03,133 --> 00:25:06,963
"Wait, for I'll return,

270
00:25:07,046 --> 00:25:09,185
defying every death."

271
00:25:09,310 --> 00:25:13,413
"And let those who do not wait
say that I was lucky."

272
00:25:13,491 --> 00:25:16,743
"They never will understand
that in the midst of death

273
00:25:16,829 --> 00:25:20,233
you with your waiting saved me."

274
00:25:20,704 --> 00:25:23,574
"Only you and I will know
how I survived."

275
00:25:23,658 --> 00:25:27,684
"It's because you waited,
as no one else did."

276
00:25:30,717 --> 00:25:33,052
There were still disasters to come.

277
00:25:33,134 --> 00:25:37,575
In May, the Germans beat off
a Russian offensive near Kharkov.

278
00:25:37,661 --> 00:25:41,611
As the Red Army advanced,
the panzers cut round its flanks.

279
00:25:51,741 --> 00:25:54,578
The Soviet commanders
begged to be allowed to pull back

280
00:25:54,657 --> 00:25:56,566
before it was too late,

281
00:25:56,652 --> 00:26:01,092
but Stalin, pushing advice aside,
forbade them to retreat.

282
00:26:01,217 --> 00:26:03,399
The German pincers closed.

283
00:26:03,481 --> 00:26:07,846
Most of the men of three Russian armies
were forced to lay down their arms.

284
00:26:30,259 --> 00:26:35,355
In the whole war, over five million
Russian soldiers were taken prisoner.

285
00:26:36,705 --> 00:26:39,879
Less than two million survived.

286
00:26:44,646 --> 00:26:46,785
For the British especially,

287
00:26:46,910 --> 00:26:50,816
the Russians were now
"Our gallant Soviet ally."

288
00:26:51,859 --> 00:26:56,267
But, at first, help could only come
through the Arctic convoys

289
00:26:56,347 --> 00:26:58,835
heading for Murmansk and Archangel

290
00:26:58,918 --> 00:27:03,981
through the killing ground of the
German U-boats, bombers and warships.

291
00:27:09,200 --> 00:27:14,448
In July 1942,
this one convoy lost 80% of its ships.

292
00:27:17,448 --> 00:27:21,355
But the courage of British seamen
could not make the convoys carry enough

293
00:27:21,438 --> 00:27:24,002
for Russia's gigantic needs.

294
00:27:24,852 --> 00:27:29,184
1942 was the year of deep war -

295
00:27:29,264 --> 00:27:33,062
defeat fought off,
but as yet no sign of victory.

296
00:27:33,638 --> 00:27:36,202
This was a time of bitter endurance,

297
00:27:36,285 --> 00:27:40,159
a season for learning to bear
disappointment and loss.

298
00:27:42,270 --> 00:27:44,681
Once, it seemed possible
that German soldiers

299
00:27:44,764 --> 00:27:46,826
were only brother workers in uniform,

300
00:27:46,912 --> 00:27:50,589
but now Soviet writers
spoke in words of hate.

301
00:27:51,631 --> 00:27:55,264
"One can bear anything -
the plague, hunger and death -

302
00:27:55,391 --> 00:27:57,605
but one cannot bear the Germans."

303
00:27:57,693 --> 00:28:00,301
"One cannot bear these fish-eyed oafs

304
00:28:00,378 --> 00:28:03,062
contemptuously snorting
at everything Russian."

305
00:28:03,179 --> 00:28:06,779
"We cannot live as long
as these grey-green slugs are alive."

306
00:28:06,862 --> 00:28:11,193
"Today there are no books,
today there are no stars in the sky."

307
00:28:11,274 --> 00:28:15,071
"Today there is only one thought -
kill the Germans."

308
00:28:15,149 --> 00:28:18,171
"Kill them all
and dig them into the earth."

309
00:28:18,256 --> 00:28:20,286
"Then we can go to sleep."

310
00:28:20,366 --> 00:28:23,662
"Then we can think again
of life and books

311
00:28:23,781 --> 00:28:26,312
and girls and happiness."

312
00:28:29,574 --> 00:28:31,101
"We shall kill them all,

313
00:28:31,185 --> 00:28:34,786
but we must do it quickly or
they will desecrate the whole of Russia

314
00:28:34,868 --> 00:28:37,585
and torture to death
millions more people."

315
00:28:49,293 --> 00:28:51,432
As the Soviet soldiers advanced,

316
00:28:51,519 --> 00:28:55,850
they found what Germans
had been doing to civilians.

317
00:29:44,424 --> 00:29:47,446
(priest chanting)

318
00:29:47,531 --> 00:29:50,291
The churches were full once more.

319
00:29:59,539 --> 00:30:02,681
The priesthood was invited
to pray for the life of holy Russia

320
00:30:02,762 --> 00:30:05,708
to work on the patriotism
of the worshippers.

321
00:30:09,092 --> 00:30:11,503
The icons were honoured again.

322
00:30:11,586 --> 00:30:14,652
The public campaign for atheism
was dropped.

323
00:30:14,732 --> 00:30:16,990
(congregation singing)

324
00:30:40,590 --> 00:30:44,464
The Germans murdered
Jews and Communists.

325
00:30:44,541 --> 00:30:48,415
They murdered those
suspected of supporting the partisans.

326
00:30:48,531 --> 00:30:50,898
They murdered hostages.

327
00:30:59,235 --> 00:31:01,494
After battle, in retreat,

328
00:31:01,575 --> 00:31:04,031
they just murdered.

329
00:31:17,343 --> 00:31:22,286
To the north, the Russians prepared to
attack the German ring round Leningrad.

330
00:31:22,407 --> 00:31:24,513
As they waited, runners brought the news

331
00:31:24,594 --> 00:31:28,391
of the surrender of the German armies
at Stalingrad.

332
00:31:29,888 --> 00:31:34,483
For army and people, this was the sudden
glow of victory at the tunnel's end.

333
00:31:34,569 --> 00:31:38,289
Now they knew they would win.

334
00:32:03,956 --> 00:32:08,015
At Leningrad,
the relieving troops broke through.

335
00:32:09,481 --> 00:32:11,434
(speaking Russian)

336
00:32:19,034 --> 00:32:24,249
They forced open a land route.
The 16-month blockade was over.

337
00:32:24,328 --> 00:32:26,467
But they did not break the siege.

338
00:32:26,553 --> 00:32:30,034
The Germans and Finns
still lay around the city.

339
00:32:31,004 --> 00:32:33,611
(speaking Russian)

340
00:32:33,727 --> 00:32:36,095
(Olga) It was such a feeling
I can't relate it.

341
00:32:36,183 --> 00:32:39,282
I went to my neighbour across the yard,

342
00:32:39,367 --> 00:32:41,734
and we kissed each other
and told each other:

343
00:32:41,861 --> 00:32:44,654
"Now we shall live. There is a way out."

344
00:32:45,237 --> 00:32:48,412
(narrator) In a fortnight,
a railway was laid through the gap.

345
00:32:48,920 --> 00:32:52,291
Food and fuel
began to roll into Leningrad.

346
00:32:57,974 --> 00:33:00,003
The symbols of old Russian honour

347
00:33:00,122 --> 00:33:02,992
were restored to the army
as they had been to the church.

348
00:33:03,115 --> 00:33:05,220
(patriotic Russian song)

349
00:33:06,951 --> 00:33:10,749
Propaganda
united Lenin with Alexander Nevski...

350
00:33:14,471 --> 00:33:17,341
..the 18th century hero, Suvorov...

351
00:33:22,566 --> 00:33:24,399
..heroes of the Red cavalry,

352
00:33:24,522 --> 00:33:28,472
mighty ghosts cheering forward
the avengers of the Soviet motherland.

353
00:33:32,848 --> 00:33:37,670
The insignia of a traditional and
professional army were brought back.

354
00:33:39,868 --> 00:33:42,280
Gold braid was imported from Britain.

355
00:33:42,362 --> 00:33:45,537
Political commissars lost rank.

356
00:33:47,158 --> 00:33:50,987
The years of the purges were forgotten.

357
00:33:51,071 --> 00:33:53,133
(Russian marching song)

358
00:34:27,057 --> 00:34:28,781
(speaking Russian)

359
00:34:28,860 --> 00:34:33,421
(interpreter) Every Soviet citizen felt
himself a part of the common struggle.

360
00:34:33,502 --> 00:34:36,033
Some people say
it was the Fascists' cruelty

361
00:34:36,150 --> 00:34:41,060
which led to resistance
in the Ukraine and other occupied lands.

362
00:34:41,137 --> 00:34:43,122
No.

363
00:34:46,278 --> 00:34:49,115
I believe resistance was inevitable.

364
00:34:54,488 --> 00:34:59,431
Soviet people in the rear could not
hold themselves back from the struggle.

365
00:35:10,102 --> 00:35:15,275
(narrator) In 1941, behind the lines
partisan bands began to form.

366
00:35:15,358 --> 00:35:17,388
At first, they lacked arms.

367
00:35:17,468 --> 00:35:19,803
They grew slowly.

368
00:35:26,139 --> 00:35:29,892
German deportations for forced labour
made thousands flee to the forests,

369
00:35:29,975 --> 00:35:33,772
where they joined the partisans.

370
00:35:33,850 --> 00:35:35,650
(patriotic song)

371
00:35:47,316 --> 00:35:49,683
Soon the partisans
became a formidable army

372
00:35:49,772 --> 00:35:53,601
operating against
the enemy lines of communication.

373
00:36:23,149 --> 00:36:25,789
The penalty for collaboration was death.

374
00:36:25,873 --> 00:36:28,328
On a mere suspicion
of sympathy for the enemy,

375
00:36:28,405 --> 00:36:32,279
whole national groups,
the Volga Germans, the Crimean Tatars,

376
00:36:32,356 --> 00:36:34,419
were deported to central Asia.

377
00:36:34,505 --> 00:36:37,756
For individual collaborators, no mercy.

378
00:36:46,935 --> 00:36:49,728
As German prisoners
were paraded through Leningrad,

379
00:36:49,812 --> 00:36:53,184
people struck out at an enemy
they could reach.

380
00:37:09,417 --> 00:37:13,858
In the steppes of Soviet Asia, in
the new factories and mines of Siberia,

381
00:37:13,944 --> 00:37:19,160
the most desperate production effort of
modern times was coming to its climax.

382
00:38:05,276 --> 00:38:08,222
Russia has been caught
with obsolete aircraft,

383
00:38:08,307 --> 00:38:10,947
unfit for close battle support.

384
00:38:11,031 --> 00:38:15,319
Now the plants turned out
9,000 modern aircraft every month.

385
00:38:15,404 --> 00:38:20,042
In 1943, military output
finally outstripped Germany's.

386
00:38:30,290 --> 00:38:32,429
Above all, it was the tank.

387
00:38:32,515 --> 00:38:36,956
In 1943,
the factories built 24,000 of them.

388
00:38:38,730 --> 00:38:41,414
More than any other weapon,
it was the tank,

389
00:38:41,531 --> 00:38:44,095
especially the famous T-34,

390
00:38:44,178 --> 00:38:47,244
which won the battle
on the Eastern Front.

391
00:39:00,790 --> 00:39:03,583
With the American trucks
now streaming in from Persia,

392
00:39:03,667 --> 00:39:07,192
this torrent of armour
moved up to the line.

393
00:39:09,115 --> 00:39:11,908
The Russians knew that in July 1943

394
00:39:11,992 --> 00:39:17,012
the Germans would launch their
full strength against them once more.

395
00:39:17,172 --> 00:39:20,041
They knew too
that the blow would fall at Kursk.

396
00:39:20,126 --> 00:39:22,614
They must hold firm.

397
00:39:22,696 --> 00:39:26,799
Then the Red Army, now
the biggest land force ever seen in war,

398
00:39:26,878 --> 00:39:28,863
would strike back.

399
00:39:30,906 --> 00:39:32,510
The Germans planned to drive

400
00:39:32,633 --> 00:39:34,738
into the shoulders of the Kursk bulge,

401
00:39:34,819 --> 00:39:37,427
hoping to cut off the huge Soviet army,

402
00:39:37,505 --> 00:39:39,796
then hit at Moscow.

403
00:39:46,828 --> 00:39:49,927
They brought up 70 divisions -
almost a million men -

404
00:39:50,012 --> 00:39:52,729
with the new Tiger tanks
and Ferdinand guns.

405
00:39:52,813 --> 00:39:54,798
Hitler had intended to strike in May,

406
00:39:54,884 --> 00:39:58,681
but there were delays in production
and building up reserves.

407
00:40:05,550 --> 00:40:07,350
Weeks passed.

408
00:40:07,430 --> 00:40:12,907
When the German were ready to attack,
the Russians were waiting for them.

409
00:40:12,992 --> 00:40:18,667
(speaking Russian)

410
00:40:18,747 --> 00:40:20,700
(interpreter) We were all prepared.

411
00:40:20,819 --> 00:40:24,147
We were more than ready
to meet Hitler's attack.

412
00:40:24,233 --> 00:40:25,728
We knew we had enough armour

413
00:40:25,806 --> 00:40:28,643
to stop the Fascists
breaking through our defences.

414
00:40:36,894 --> 00:40:40,342
Our reconnaissance patrols
had captured prisoners.

415
00:40:42,879 --> 00:40:45,486
From them
we learned that Hitler's troops

416
00:40:45,564 --> 00:40:50,551
planned to start the attack
at 2:30 in the morning on July 5.

417
00:40:51,587 --> 00:40:54,534
The news was given to our troops.

418
00:40:54,618 --> 00:40:56,342
(speaking Russian)

419
00:40:56,460 --> 00:41:00,213
(interpreter) The commander
sits in the observation post,

420
00:41:00,296 --> 00:41:02,631
the soldiers are in the trenches,

421
00:41:02,713 --> 00:41:06,041
and tomorrow
the enemy is expected to attack.

422
00:41:08,813 --> 00:41:12,534
You can imagine
what thoughts are in his mind.

423
00:41:20,438 --> 00:41:24,344
There were more than
a hundred tanks every kilometre.

424
00:41:24,428 --> 00:41:27,985
When tanks are moving,
the whole earth trembles.

425
00:41:28,072 --> 00:41:30,211
And the guns fire,

426
00:41:30,298 --> 00:41:33,210
but the soldier just sits.

427
00:41:42,306 --> 00:41:44,564
(narrator)
Soviet aircraft took off at dawn

428
00:41:44,646 --> 00:41:48,279
to wreck the German bombers
waiting on their airfields.

429
00:41:59,570 --> 00:42:01,829
The Germans kept to the timetable.

430
00:42:03,752 --> 00:42:08,422
On the morning of July 5,
the panzer divisions moved forward.

431
00:42:37,858 --> 00:42:41,840
Kursk was the biggest tank battle
in history.

432
00:42:41,925 --> 00:42:46,485
In the north, the German pincer
made ten miles in five days, and halted,

433
00:42:46,567 --> 00:42:50,320
with 50,000 dead
and 400 tanks destroyed.

434
00:42:52,130 --> 00:42:54,192
In the south, in an even vaster battle,

435
00:42:54,278 --> 00:42:57,191
a 20-mile dent
was made in the Russian defences,

436
00:42:57,309 --> 00:42:59,917
but the Germans were spent.

437
00:42:59,994 --> 00:43:04,359
On July 15,
Hitler called off the Kursk offensive.

438
00:43:08,972 --> 00:43:12,343
The Red Army went over to the attack.

439
00:43:55,048 --> 00:43:57,263
Under bombardment,
the sappers went ahead

440
00:43:57,388 --> 00:44:00,989
to cut a path into the German defences.

441
00:44:12,619 --> 00:44:15,303
Through the gap,
the tanks plunged forward,

442
00:44:15,381 --> 00:44:18,142
the troops riding on their sides.

443
00:44:39,129 --> 00:44:41,114
These were the new Russian soldiers,

444
00:44:41,239 --> 00:44:44,414
very different
from the defeated masses of 1941.

445
00:44:45,459 --> 00:44:48,634
Their clothes were shabby,
but their weapons were clean.

446
00:44:48,759 --> 00:44:53,199
They were tough, chasing the enemy
into close-quarter battle.

447
00:44:53,286 --> 00:44:54,583
They were resourceful,

448
00:44:54,667 --> 00:44:59,381
trained to live off the land
and to cross rivers on their own.

449
00:45:01,994 --> 00:45:05,323
If there was no boat,
a bench or a log would do.

450
00:45:10,435 --> 00:45:13,730
They went without regular leave or pay,

451
00:45:13,811 --> 00:45:16,648
but now their morale
was fierce and high.

452
00:45:20,755 --> 00:45:26,232
In military terms, it was Kursk which
decided how the European war would end.

453
00:45:27,392 --> 00:45:31,266
When this supreme German effort failed,
the Soviet victory began.

454
00:45:33,185 --> 00:45:36,818
The fighting to break through
German positions was hard and slow,

455
00:45:36,906 --> 00:45:39,624
but after nine days
the Red Army had recaptured

456
00:45:39,707 --> 00:45:43,537
all the ground lost
in this last German offensive.

457
00:46:07,445 --> 00:46:12,464
The Germans began to fall back,
destroying everything as they went.

458
00:46:12,547 --> 00:46:16,345
Now they were under constant attack
by Soviet fighters.

459
00:46:19,031 --> 00:46:22,512
The Luftwaffe
had lost command of the air.

460
00:46:34,185 --> 00:46:39,553
Suddenly, the towns of occupied Russia
were full of armour moving west.

461
00:46:40,554 --> 00:46:44,842
After two years,
the conquerors were pulling out.

462
00:46:46,385 --> 00:46:48,295
(air-raid siren)

463
00:46:49,608 --> 00:46:52,674
At Leningrad,
the Germans were still at the outskirts,

464
00:46:52,754 --> 00:46:54,893
the city still under shellfire.

465
00:47:02,000 --> 00:47:06,789
The siege was not to be finally broken
until January the following year.

466
00:47:11,859 --> 00:47:16,846
The strength of Russia, like a gigantic
spring compressed back to its limit,

467
00:47:16,924 --> 00:47:19,258
was now bursting forward.

468
00:47:19,340 --> 00:47:22,592
The first cities were liberated.

469
00:47:39,597 --> 00:47:42,281
On August 5, 1943,

470
00:47:42,359 --> 00:47:45,578
Orel and Belgorod were freed.

471
00:47:47,884 --> 00:47:52,095
In each town, those who had died
in battle were buried.

472
00:47:55,096 --> 00:47:58,043
"Do not call me, Father,
do not seek me."

473
00:47:58,127 --> 00:48:01,455
"Do not call me, do not wish me back."

474
00:48:01,580 --> 00:48:05,759
"We're on a route uncharted,
Fire and blood erase our track."

475
00:48:05,839 --> 00:48:09,974
"On we fly on wings of thunder,
Nevermore to sheath our swords."

476
00:48:10,097 --> 00:48:14,615
"All of us in battle fallen,
Not to be brought back by words."

477
00:48:15,622 --> 00:48:18,534
"Will there be a rendezvous?
I know not."

478
00:48:18,614 --> 00:48:20,829
"I only know we still must fight."

479
00:48:20,916 --> 00:48:23,480
"We are sand grains in infinity,

480
00:48:23,563 --> 00:48:27,088
Never to meet, nevermore see light."

481
00:48:30,162 --> 00:48:33,915
"Farewell then, my son,
farewell then, my conscience,

482
00:48:33,998 --> 00:48:35,799
My youth and my solace,

483
00:48:35,878 --> 00:48:38,213
My one and my only."

484
00:48:38,295 --> 00:48:40,859
"And let this farewell
be the end of a story

485
00:48:40,942 --> 00:48:44,271
Of solitude vast,
and which none is more lonely,

486
00:48:44,357 --> 00:48:47,040
In which you remain barred
forever and ever

487
00:48:47,119 --> 00:48:48,494
From light and from air,

488
00:48:48,577 --> 00:48:50,759
with your death pangs untold."

489
00:48:50,841 --> 00:48:53,328
"Untold and unsoothed,

490
00:48:53,411 --> 00:48:58,048
not to be resurrected,
Forever and ever an 18-year-old."

491
00:48:58,130 --> 00:49:01,458
"Farewell, then.
No trains ever come from those regions,

492
00:49:01,544 --> 00:49:04,796
Unscheduled or scheduled,
no aeroplanes fly there."

493
00:49:05,534 --> 00:49:08,709
"Farewell then, my son,
for no miracles happen,

494
00:49:08,795 --> 00:49:12,516
As in this world
dreams do not come true."

495
00:49:12,593 --> 00:49:16,346
"Farewell.
I will dream of you still as a baby,

496
00:49:16,430 --> 00:49:19,496
Treading the earth
with little, strong toes."

497
00:49:19,576 --> 00:49:22,369
"The earth
where already so many lie buried."

498
00:49:22,453 --> 00:49:26,589
"This song to my son, then,
is come to its close."

499
00:49:31,776 --> 00:49:33,915
In Moscow, Stalin announced:

500
00:49:34,001 --> 00:49:39,249
"Tonight at 2400 hours on August 5,
the capital of our country, Moscow,

501
00:49:39,334 --> 00:49:42,934
will salute the valiant troops
who liberated Orel and Belgorod."

502
00:49:43,017 --> 00:49:44,314
(shouting in Russian)

503
00:49:49,040 --> 00:49:50,916
"Eternal glory to the heroes who fell

504
00:49:50,997 --> 00:49:53,364
in the struggle for the freedom
of our country."

505
00:49:53,452 --> 00:49:55,361
"Death to the German invaders."

506
00:50:01,700 --> 00:50:04,690
In November, Kiev was freed.

507
00:50:44,093 --> 00:50:46,079
(upbeat Russian song)

508
00:51:26,218 --> 00:51:30,048
Russia was saved by its soldiers
and by its people.

509
00:51:31,052 --> 00:51:35,308
But in the earth,
never to welcome the coming of peace,

510
00:51:35,426 --> 00:51:38,186
lay 20 million dead.
