1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:12,162 --> 00:00:14,376
(man) I don't think many of the aircrew

3
00:00:14,464 --> 00:00:17,027
knew what strategic bombing
really meant.

4
00:00:17,111 --> 00:00:19,828
(man #2) As schoolboys,
we joined the air force,

5
00:00:19,911 --> 00:00:21,712
cos there was a war being fought

6
00:00:21,791 --> 00:00:25,010
and there was a bit of glamour
attached to the air force.

7
00:00:25,091 --> 00:00:29,608
(man #1) If you couldn't
get the Kraut in his factory,

8
00:00:29,694 --> 00:00:32,684
it was just as easy
to knock him off in his bed.

9
00:00:32,764 --> 00:00:38,514
If old Granny Shickelgruber next door
got the chop, that's hard luck.

10
00:00:38,595 --> 00:00:43,997
There are a lot of people who say
that bombing can never win a war.

11
00:00:44,887 --> 00:00:50,790
Well, my answer to that is that it has
never been tried yet, and we shall see.

12
00:02:08,330 --> 00:02:10,818
(tea dance)

13
00:02:13,816 --> 00:02:16,534
(narrator) After the Battle of Britain,

14
00:02:16,617 --> 00:02:19,836
the Royal Air Force
had cause to celebrate.

15
00:02:22,026 --> 00:02:25,507
Fighter Command had shown how difficult
it was to destroy a country

16
00:02:25,594 --> 00:02:28,693
which could defend its own air space.

17
00:02:31,503 --> 00:02:36,751
A lesson the air staff, apparently,
neglected to teach itself.

18
00:02:39,636 --> 00:02:44,458
Lord Trenchard had founded the service
as a force of strategic bombers.

19
00:02:44,547 --> 00:02:47,721
Fighters for defence were secondary.

20
00:02:50,225 --> 00:02:52,439
Long-range bombers, it was argued,

21
00:02:52,527 --> 00:02:55,319
could win wars
without costly land battles.

22
00:02:55,404 --> 00:02:58,012
They would bomb the industrial heart
out of an enemy

23
00:02:58,089 --> 00:03:01,079
and totally demoralise
his civilian population.

24
00:03:03,806 --> 00:03:09,327
In 1939, the RAF was not really equipped
to put this thesis to the test.

25
00:03:09,407 --> 00:03:14,393
But after Dunkirk, it was the only force
capable of attacking Germany.

26
00:03:14,471 --> 00:03:17,308
And the British public
desperately needed an attack.

27
00:03:19,996 --> 00:03:23,367
(newsreel) The British Empire
is building up a bomber force

28
00:03:23,449 --> 00:03:28,817
designed as the offensive air weapon
to smash the heart of Germany.

29
00:03:33,385 --> 00:03:35,600
The first daylight raids
were disastrous.

30
00:03:35,687 --> 00:03:39,823
Bombers fell easy prey to the Luftwaffe.

31
00:03:39,907 --> 00:03:42,166
("Bring Back My Bomber And Me")

32
00:03:53,910 --> 00:03:57,631
Still the RAF persevered,
though losses mounted.

33
00:03:57,708 --> 00:04:01,811
Heavy casualties forced Bomber Command
to start flying at night.

34
00:04:01,890 --> 00:04:03,952
("Bring Back My Bomber And Me")

35
00:04:09,486 --> 00:04:11,516
(man) OK, chaps, here we go.

36
00:04:12,249 --> 00:04:15,729
(indistinct radio contact)

37
00:04:15,816 --> 00:04:18,272
(radio) Taxi out and take off.

38
00:04:18,349 --> 00:04:20,607
("Bring Back My Bomber And Me")

39
00:04:39,411 --> 00:04:42,171
Do you see what I see, skipper?

40
00:04:42,288 --> 00:04:44,470
(man)
What do you see, my Scottish friend?

41
00:04:44,552 --> 00:04:47,803
Fog. Dirty, yellow, stinking fog.

42
00:04:50,345 --> 00:04:53,411
(narrator) For aircrews
trained to attack in daylight,

43
00:04:53,491 --> 00:04:55,214
night flying had its problems.

44
00:04:55,294 --> 00:04:57,399
To find a target in Germany,

45
00:04:57,481 --> 00:04:59,008
in the dead of night,

46
00:04:59,092 --> 00:05:02,845
in any average weather conditions,

47
00:05:02,928 --> 00:05:05,296
was quite far beyond the task

48
00:05:05,384 --> 00:05:07,337
of any bomber crews.

49
00:05:10,793 --> 00:05:14,394
We're over the Dutch coast.
Too much cloud to see where.

50
00:05:15,359 --> 00:05:18,992
(narrator) Patriotic films had no
difficulty in giving the impression

51
00:05:19,080 --> 00:05:21,535
that determination
and a diet of raw carrots

52
00:05:21,612 --> 00:05:24,831
could overcome the law saying
you cannot see in the dark.

53
00:05:24,911 --> 00:05:28,785
- Can't see anything else but the Rhine.
- I hope it's not the Danube.

54
00:05:28,863 --> 00:05:32,344
Keep on going. You might be able
to pick up something with lights on.

55
00:05:32,431 --> 00:05:35,802
If you could get visual pinpoints
en route,

56
00:05:35,884 --> 00:05:41,820
you could get within five or seven miles
of the targets.

57
00:05:45,513 --> 00:05:48,001
- Bomb doors open.
- Steady.

58
00:05:48,084 --> 00:05:51,412
(narrator) Once the target was reached,
it was a piece of cake...

59
00:05:51,498 --> 00:05:52,917
Bombs gone.

60
00:05:55,872 --> 00:06:00,008
..provided you were just
blowing up a studio model.

61
00:06:03,046 --> 00:06:04,922
I hope we haven't
kept you waiting, sir.

62
00:06:05,003 --> 00:06:07,032
Good Lord, no. Come and sit down.

63
00:06:09,530 --> 00:06:12,093
- How did you get on?
- Caused a hell of a great big fire.

64
00:06:12,215 --> 00:06:16,012
Buckets of smoke.
Visible, ooh, 50 miles away.

65
00:06:17,203 --> 00:06:20,880
Well, old boy,
how about some bacon and eggs?

66
00:06:28,635 --> 00:06:30,588
(narrator) The truth was different.

67
00:06:30,669 --> 00:06:34,957
In fact, in those days,
and it's been proved since,

68
00:06:35,042 --> 00:06:40,564
three bombs in every 100 got
within five miles of the aiming point.

69
00:06:45,324 --> 00:06:50,540
In diesem Schlafsaal wurden neun Kinder
getötet und fünf schwer verletzt.

70
00:06:50,618 --> 00:06:55,059
(narrator) Inaccurate bombing
could be embarrassing.

71
00:06:55,874 --> 00:06:58,482
The German propaganda ministry
quickly capitalised

72
00:06:58,560 --> 00:07:01,124
on the destruction
of this children's hospital.

73
00:07:01,207 --> 00:07:03,193
Das sind die Opfer
der britischen Mordbuben,

74
00:07:03,279 --> 00:07:05,734
die dieses gemeine Verbrechen ganz
bewusst begangen haben.

75
00:07:05,811 --> 00:07:08,342
Es wird unerbittlich gesühnt werden.

76
00:07:10,300 --> 00:07:14,359
But the war cabinet's view
was that Germany had to be bombed.

77
00:07:14,443 --> 00:07:18,196
And this was the only strategic
bombing Britain could then undertake.

78
00:07:18,279 --> 00:07:21,575
Coventry and Liverpool indicated
German industry would suffer

79
00:07:21,694 --> 00:07:24,258
if its workers were bombed out.

80
00:07:24,993 --> 00:07:29,205
Professor Lindemann told Churchill that
de-housing a third of German workers

81
00:07:29,329 --> 00:07:31,816
would bring industrial production
to a halt.

82
00:07:31,899 --> 00:07:35,925
And there was popular pressure
to avenge the Blitz.

83
00:07:36,925 --> 00:07:39,380
We ask no favours of the enemy.

84
00:07:41,068 --> 00:07:47,932
We seek from them no... compunction.

85
00:07:49,470 --> 00:07:51,346
On the contrary,

86
00:07:51,427 --> 00:07:56,719
if tonight the people of London
were asked to cast their votes

87
00:07:57,565 --> 00:08:00,861
as to whether a convention
should be entered into

88
00:08:00,941 --> 00:08:03,276
to stop the bombing of all cities,

89
00:08:03,358 --> 00:08:05,922
an overwhelming majority would cry:

90
00:08:06,005 --> 00:08:09,486
"No, we will mete out to the Germans

91
00:08:09,573 --> 00:08:14,822
the measure and more than the measure
they have meted out to us."

92
00:08:21,466 --> 00:08:26,791
(narrator) But the Germans were now
meting it out to the British bomber.

93
00:08:35,239 --> 00:08:39,833
By the end of 1941,
Britain had lost 700 aircraft.

94
00:08:52,235 --> 00:08:58,367
The navy and the army were demanding
bombers for the Atlantic and the desert.

95
00:08:58,450 --> 00:09:01,746
Bomber Command
stood to be put out of business.

96
00:09:01,826 --> 00:09:04,434
In the face of mounting losses,

97
00:09:04,512 --> 00:09:07,534
the cabinet ordered bombing operations
to be cut down,

98
00:09:07,619 --> 00:09:09,834
to save the bomber force.

99
00:09:12,798 --> 00:09:15,362
During the respite in February 1942,

100
00:09:15,446 --> 00:09:19,003
Sir Arthur Harris took over as
Commander-in-Chief, Bomber Command.

101
00:09:19,090 --> 00:09:24,001
He was determined to succeed
with new tactics and new bombers.

102
00:09:24,078 --> 00:09:28,595
(Harris) The Nazis entered this war
under the rather childish delusion

103
00:09:28,681 --> 00:09:31,213
that they were going to bomb
everybody else

104
00:09:31,290 --> 00:09:34,432
and nobody was going to bomb them.

105
00:09:34,973 --> 00:09:41,106
At Rotterdam, London, Warsaw
and half a hundred other places,

106
00:09:41,265 --> 00:09:45,444
they put that rather naive theory
into operation.

107
00:09:46,253 --> 00:09:50,999
They sowed the wind and now
they are going to reap the whirlwind.

108
00:09:51,086 --> 00:09:55,451
I put them onto the north German ports
in the Baltic,

109
00:09:55,537 --> 00:09:59,411
because, having flown
quite a bit at night myself,

110
00:09:59,488 --> 00:10:03,700
I realised that the easiest targets
to get hold of, of course,

111
00:10:03,785 --> 00:10:06,732
were always the ones on the coastline.

112
00:10:06,816 --> 00:10:10,187
Because if you can see anything,
you can see a coastline.

113
00:10:10,307 --> 00:10:13,449
If you can see a coastline
with its odd shapes,

114
00:10:13,530 --> 00:10:18,090
you can find your way along to ports
and recognise them.

115
00:10:18,172 --> 00:10:22,460
(narrator) Lubeck and Rostock
were the first major targets.

116
00:10:22,546 --> 00:10:25,229
As ports, they were easy to find.

117
00:10:26,919 --> 00:10:28,981
And they burnt well.

118
00:10:29,797 --> 00:10:35,394
In March 1942,
230 bombers destroyed half Lubeck.

119
00:10:35,475 --> 00:10:39,424
In April,
Rostock was bombed into flames.

120
00:10:39,503 --> 00:10:43,333
The style was set: night area bombing.

121
00:10:44,222 --> 00:10:47,364
This was to become the pattern
for the next three years.

122
00:10:47,444 --> 00:10:51,197
It was terrifying,
it was indiscriminate,

123
00:10:51,281 --> 00:10:55,001
but as far as Bomber Command
was concerned, there was no alternative.

124
00:10:56,038 --> 00:10:57,216
How many occasions,

125
00:10:57,342 --> 00:11:00,594
looking out of the window,
or walking out in the garden,

126
00:11:00,680 --> 00:11:04,859
could you see up to 18 or 20,000 feet?

127
00:11:04,939 --> 00:11:06,968
Maybe on two or three days at most.

128
00:11:07,087 --> 00:11:11,190
On how many occasions can you
guarantee if you see up to it here,

129
00:11:11,269 --> 00:11:14,989
that you could see down to it
500 miles away,

130
00:11:15,067 --> 00:11:17,358
in the other end of Europe?

131
00:11:17,446 --> 00:11:19,780
That was the situation.

132
00:11:19,863 --> 00:11:23,922
There's no possibility
of hitting the individual targets,

133
00:11:24,006 --> 00:11:26,494
consistently small targets,

134
00:11:27,459 --> 00:11:32,249
until we got
the navigational electronic aids

135
00:11:32,331 --> 00:11:36,587
that would show those targets up
in the dark or through clouds.

136
00:11:38,086 --> 00:11:43,149
(narrator) The first electronic aid
to navigation now came into service.

137
00:11:43,265 --> 00:11:44,487
It was called GEE.

138
00:11:44,570 --> 00:11:48,094
Three radio transmitters in England
sent an invisible grid of signals

139
00:11:48,214 --> 00:11:50,200
across western Europe.

140
00:11:55,235 --> 00:11:58,454
By monitoring the signals
and plotting them on a map,

141
00:11:58,534 --> 00:12:02,092
a navigator could tell
where his aircraft was.

142
00:12:04,136 --> 00:12:06,853
GEE was first used at Cologne.

143
00:12:06,936 --> 00:12:10,613
Here, Harris threw in every bomber
he could scrape up

144
00:12:10,696 --> 00:12:13,151
for a monumental prestige attack.

145
00:12:16,527 --> 00:12:19,211
(Harris) In your hands
lie the means of destroying

146
00:12:19,328 --> 00:12:24,925
a major part of the resources by which
the enemy's war effort is maintained.

147
00:12:25,006 --> 00:12:29,337
Press home your attack.
If you individually succeed,

148
00:12:29,418 --> 00:12:32,484
you will have delivered
the most devastating blow

149
00:12:32,564 --> 00:12:34,855
against the very vitals of the enemy.

150
00:12:34,981 --> 00:12:38,003
Let him have it right on the chin.

151
00:12:38,088 --> 00:12:41,613
Send that message
to all groups and stations.

152
00:12:43,306 --> 00:12:46,099
I was trying to show them
what could be achieved

153
00:12:46,183 --> 00:12:48,976
with something approaching
an adequate force,

154
00:12:49,061 --> 00:12:54,004
and that it would be achieved
without abnormal casualties.

155
00:12:56,887 --> 00:13:01,874
(newsreel) The dark hours over Hitler's
Germany are about to be made hideous.

156
00:13:01,951 --> 00:13:05,672
The men of Bomber Command
know well what they have to do.

157
00:13:05,749 --> 00:13:08,739
A calm, moonlit night,
everything ready and waiting,

158
00:13:09,356 --> 00:13:11,461
from planes to carrier pigeons.

159
00:13:11,543 --> 00:13:14,946
They seem to know the ops are on.
Come on, fellas, get cracking.

160
00:13:22,822 --> 00:13:25,004
(newsreel #2)
Round the clock with the RAF.

161
00:13:25,124 --> 00:13:28,877
At station after station, there
are heavies, including Lancasters,

162
00:13:28,960 --> 00:13:32,135
the heavy bomber of the moment,
ready for tonight.

163
00:13:32,221 --> 00:13:35,822
For tonight is going
to be very, very interesting -

164
00:13:35,904 --> 00:13:37,508
a thousand-bomber night.

165
00:13:52,133 --> 00:13:56,344
(narrator) On that night, May 30, 1942,

166
00:13:56,429 --> 00:13:59,833
1,046 bombers took off for Cologne.

167
00:14:03,987 --> 00:14:07,545
(woman) Wir hörten auch gleich
kurz darauf das Brummen

168
00:14:07,632 --> 00:14:08,734
der anfliegenden Bomber.

169
00:14:08,821 --> 00:14:11,768
(translator) We heard the drone
of the approaching bombers

170
00:14:11,852 --> 00:14:15,878
and guessed that
it was a heavy formation.

171
00:14:20,369 --> 00:14:24,002
And soon after,
the first bombs fell around us.

172
00:14:24,129 --> 00:14:28,035
We were all shaking with fear.
Some people nearly fainted.

173
00:14:28,119 --> 00:14:30,759
Many of the patients were crying.

174
00:14:30,843 --> 00:14:34,323
The roaring and crashing
came closer and closer.

175
00:14:34,449 --> 00:14:38,323
We really thought
all hell was breaking loose.

176
00:14:39,820 --> 00:14:41,959
Our part of the city was in flames.

177
00:14:42,045 --> 00:14:44,958
People were running out of cellars
and out of houses.

178
00:14:45,038 --> 00:14:46,761
Some were buried in the rubble.

179
00:14:46,879 --> 00:14:49,367
Others were caught
by the falling masonry.

180
00:14:49,450 --> 00:14:56,041
Many people actually caught fire,
running around like living torches.

181
00:14:57,391 --> 00:15:03,250
(man) We really didn't expect, in '42,
that such a heavy raid would take place.

182
00:15:03,338 --> 00:15:06,404
We were only used to smaller attacks,

183
00:15:06,483 --> 00:15:13,118
and when I got the news that about
1,000 bombers were attacking Cologne,

184
00:15:13,236 --> 00:15:14,763
it was incredible.

185
00:15:19,796 --> 00:15:24,237
The morale of the people
was not shattered too much.

186
00:15:24,323 --> 00:15:28,917
It was more like a short shock
which passed away.

187
00:15:31,996 --> 00:15:36,437
(narrator) German industry remained
resilient, although the industrial Ruhr

188
00:15:36,523 --> 00:15:38,858
was under attack throughout 1942.

189
00:15:38,940 --> 00:15:41,930
Damage was extensive,
but there was some slack in the economy

190
00:15:42,009 --> 00:15:45,305
to be taken up in more war production.

191
00:15:45,923 --> 00:15:49,872
The Nazi war machine was skilled
at orchestrating civilian morale.

192
00:15:49,951 --> 00:15:52,559
("Deutschlandlied")

193
00:16:14,658 --> 00:16:16,840
(man) Flugzeuggeräusch.

194
00:16:16,921 --> 00:16:18,907
(telephone rings)

195
00:16:21,832 --> 00:16:26,426
Bitte mal die Geschwindigkeit
von 02:15 Uhr nachmessen.

196
00:16:28,085 --> 00:16:29,995
(siren)

197
00:16:31,270 --> 00:16:34,794
The Germans could give as well as take.

198
00:16:34,876 --> 00:16:38,858
The Luftwaffe was acutely aware of
the lesson radar-controlled RAF fighters

199
00:16:38,981 --> 00:16:42,734
had taught it
during the Battle of Britain.

200
00:16:43,316 --> 00:16:48,455
Air defence chief General Kammhuber
evolved a most efficient system.

201
00:16:48,534 --> 00:16:49,985
Across the North Sea coast

202
00:16:50,068 --> 00:16:53,593
stretched an early-warning radar grid,
the Kammhuber Line.

203
00:16:53,675 --> 00:16:56,315
This grid was divided into boxes.

204
00:16:56,399 --> 00:17:00,959
In each box was a night fighter,
waiting like a spider for the fly.

205
00:17:01,041 --> 00:17:07,632
We overtook the plane on the side,
so he thought, "Ah, he hasn't seen me."

206
00:17:09,328 --> 00:17:13,616
He still did some corkscrewing
or waving.

207
00:17:13,701 --> 00:17:18,764
I just banked slightly to give
the gunners a good view underneath.

208
00:17:18,842 --> 00:17:23,665
I moved off maybe ten degrees to port
and starboard during this manoeuvre,

209
00:17:23,753 --> 00:17:26,622
but it wasn't violent
in any sense at all.

210
00:17:26,745 --> 00:17:33,107
And then I was shooting this way
and diving directly,

211
00:17:33,190 --> 00:17:38,439
or with a - what we said -
schräge Musik,

212
00:17:38,523 --> 00:17:42,320
two two-centimetre cannons,

213
00:17:42,398 --> 00:17:45,388
the same, only flying underneath,

214
00:17:45,544 --> 00:17:49,025
and waiting, moving very easy.

215
00:17:49,112 --> 00:17:53,138
We did the same
parallel to the other one, shooting.

216
00:17:53,217 --> 00:17:59,153
Between the motors
you had about 5,000 litres of gasoline,

217
00:17:59,240 --> 00:18:01,957
and that was burning very easily.

218
00:18:02,041 --> 00:18:06,482
The advent of the Kammhuber Line,
and all that went with it,

219
00:18:06,568 --> 00:18:11,511
was a startling sort of thing
to be confronted with,

220
00:18:11,594 --> 00:18:17,300
because the German night defences
took a terrible toll of British bombers.

221
00:18:17,387 --> 00:18:20,376
(aircrew singing "Home on the Range" )

222
00:18:22,297 --> 00:18:24,589
(narrator) But now the RAF
was no longer alone.

223
00:18:40,406 --> 00:18:45,807
Hiya, fellas. There's your birdseed
for Hitler. Come and get it.

224
00:18:51,800 --> 00:18:55,096
(narrator) Throughout 1942,
the US Eighth Army Air Force

225
00:18:55,176 --> 00:18:57,817
had been building up in England.

226
00:19:00,931 --> 00:19:04,684
The American air chiefs
believed they could succeed in daylight

227
00:19:04,767 --> 00:19:07,714
without suffering the losses
the British had done.

228
00:19:07,798 --> 00:19:12,665
They were convinced
they could bomb accurately by day.

229
00:19:12,747 --> 00:19:14,809
(man) Charlie's doing his twirl again.

230
00:19:14,896 --> 00:19:16,958
(man #2)
Wish I had something like that.

231
00:19:17,044 --> 00:19:19,532
(man) You guys wouldn't know
what to do with it.

232
00:19:19,614 --> 00:19:23,718
Took six months to teach you
how to pull a trigger.

233
00:19:23,835 --> 00:19:27,894
(man #3) Can the small talk.
You need to come home.

234
00:19:29,359 --> 00:19:34,029
Their aircraft were very heavily armed.
Some carried up to 12 machine guns.

235
00:19:34,155 --> 00:19:38,443
And they were trained
to fly in close formation.

236
00:19:38,528 --> 00:19:41,627
(man) Formation flying
was really the name of the game

237
00:19:41,713 --> 00:19:45,193
as far as the Eighth Air Force
was concerned.

238
00:19:45,280 --> 00:19:50,496
There was never anything like it
happened before or since.

239
00:19:53,951 --> 00:19:59,548
They actually were sort of making
their own rules up as they went along,

240
00:19:59,629 --> 00:20:02,619
because it was just a brand-new concept.

241
00:20:02,698 --> 00:20:07,946
You made it possible
to have a more concentrated firepower

242
00:20:08,031 --> 00:20:11,511
from the gunner's positions
of all your aeroplanes.

243
00:20:11,637 --> 00:20:18,348
The fact that you could depend
on good formation, tight formation,

244
00:20:20,308 --> 00:20:25,709
not only helped you
in defence of fighter attack,

245
00:20:27,827 --> 00:20:33,152
it made your chances of achieving
good bombing results much better.

246
00:20:33,236 --> 00:20:36,794
Because if you're bombing,
a squadron of aeroplanes was bombing,

247
00:20:36,920 --> 00:20:40,793
and the pattern was
a good, tight pattern,

248
00:20:40,871 --> 00:20:46,087
your results were bound to be good.

249
00:20:47,969 --> 00:20:49,692
(man) Bombs away.

250
00:20:49,772 --> 00:20:53,100
(narrator) Early raids into France
bore out American optimism.

251
00:20:53,186 --> 00:20:56,590
Later, over Germany,
it was a different story.

252
00:20:56,677 --> 00:20:59,044
They found at first, yes, the bombers

253
00:20:59,133 --> 00:21:01,741
could cope pretty well with the fighters

254
00:21:01,857 --> 00:21:03,733
and take acceptable losses,

255
00:21:03,852 --> 00:21:06,263
if penetrations were not too deep,

256
00:21:06,345 --> 00:21:10,753
if they kept good formation and they had
supporting fire, one from the other.

257
00:21:10,834 --> 00:21:13,551
But the Germans were learning too.

258
00:21:13,635 --> 00:21:16,963
They learned how to make their attacks
and penetrate formations.

259
00:21:17,049 --> 00:21:20,802
And they started the head-on attacks,
to try to get the leader

260
00:21:20,924 --> 00:21:22,528
and spread the formation.

261
00:21:22,612 --> 00:21:24,979
Once they got the formation spread out,

262
00:21:25,067 --> 00:21:29,814
then they could pick the bombers off
at will. More or less, anyway.

263
00:21:43,751 --> 00:21:46,850
(narrator)
But it was too early to admit defeat.

264
00:21:50,235 --> 00:21:55,865
At night, the British bombers flew on,
hundreds at a time, but each on its own.

265
00:21:55,951 --> 00:22:00,773
(man) We used to see them go over in
the early evening, one by one in trail,

266
00:22:00,862 --> 00:22:03,579
I would not have changed places
for them.

267
00:22:03,662 --> 00:22:08,223
I'd much rather have
the close formation, the firepower,

268
00:22:08,304 --> 00:22:10,760
than go over the way they did.

269
00:22:10,837 --> 00:22:14,317
(man #2) Flying with the RAF,
you were Single Charlie.

270
00:22:14,404 --> 00:22:17,165
Just after we'd crossed the Dutch coast,

271
00:22:17,243 --> 00:22:19,458
I felt a terrific bang in my face.

272
00:22:20,888 --> 00:22:25,100
The windscreen was shot away
and I'd been wounded in the forearm,

273
00:22:25,185 --> 00:22:29,779
the shoulder and the head. The plane
went out of control temporarily.

274
00:22:34,584 --> 00:22:37,836
I didn't see any sense
in saying that I'm wounded,

275
00:22:37,922 --> 00:22:43,247
in case they all thought,
"He's going to pop off any minute now."

276
00:22:43,408 --> 00:22:46,966
Again, the gun exploded
in the front of the plane beside us

277
00:22:47,091 --> 00:22:51,150
and the shell hit the engineer
who stood beside me in the forearm.

278
00:22:51,273 --> 00:22:56,184
And I had bits in my leg and they
sort of skinned the skin off my hand.

279
00:22:57,143 --> 00:22:59,707
The port elevator had been shot off -

280
00:22:59,790 --> 00:23:03,510
it keeps the plane straight,
on each side of the tail,

281
00:23:03,588 --> 00:23:05,464
and the port one had been shot off.

282
00:23:05,545 --> 00:23:08,305
This meant that you had
to hold the stick back, right back,

283
00:23:08,384 --> 00:23:12,595
as if you're going to climb like this,
to keep the plane straight and level.

284
00:23:12,719 --> 00:23:17,313
The bomb aimer had to help push it back
because this hand was pretty weak,

285
00:23:17,399 --> 00:23:18,926
my shoulder had been hit

286
00:23:19,011 --> 00:23:22,993
and it was keeping the stick back by
holding my hands in front.

287
00:23:23,077 --> 00:23:26,024
And the engineer held it
with his other hand, his good arm.

288
00:23:26,108 --> 00:23:30,320
So we held it, combined, back,
to keep the plane straight and level.

289
00:23:30,405 --> 00:23:33,580
It wasn't
a "press on regardless" feeling,

290
00:23:33,666 --> 00:23:38,959
it was just a fact that
the four engines were still flying.

291
00:23:39,076 --> 00:23:41,793
If we'd had any engine cut,
I'd have thought,

292
00:23:41,876 --> 00:23:43,981
"Well, we can't get any further."

293
00:23:44,063 --> 00:23:46,823
But another factor here was,
had I turned back,

294
00:23:46,940 --> 00:23:50,847
we'd have another 700 planes
that are more or less on the same track,

295
00:23:50,930 --> 00:23:53,494
and spread something like
eight or ten miles broad

296
00:23:53,616 --> 00:23:56,529
and maybe
four to six thousand feet deep.

297
00:23:56,608 --> 00:24:02,544
And you're turning back right into them,
heading through this lot to get back.

298
00:24:02,632 --> 00:24:06,997
And then again, had I turned off, say
at 90 degrees, to try and avoid them,

299
00:24:07,082 --> 00:24:09,995
you're still turning across
quite a number of them.

300
00:24:10,074 --> 00:24:13,402
Then I watched the target indicators
and opened the bomb doors

301
00:24:13,489 --> 00:24:17,089
and kept the plane steady as I could
on the target indicators, and level.

302
00:24:17,210 --> 00:24:19,545
This is one of the things
they made a fuss about,

303
00:24:19,627 --> 00:24:21,919
that we'd a picture
of the target after all this.

304
00:24:22,006 --> 00:24:26,992
But as soon as we'd a picture taken,
I turned to head for base.

305
00:24:28,259 --> 00:24:32,362
One of the things
I remember feeling on this trip

306
00:24:32,441 --> 00:24:35,889
was that we had to get back,
because I knew we were wounded.

307
00:24:35,971 --> 00:24:40,226
None of the other members could fly it,
even on normal straight and levels,

308
00:24:40,306 --> 00:24:42,565
so to fly it at night
with one elevator gone,

309
00:24:42,684 --> 00:24:46,896
and having the stick in your belly
and no instruments, as it were,

310
00:24:47,020 --> 00:24:49,082
would've been pretty well impossible.

311
00:24:49,168 --> 00:24:53,424
We were shot at a few times on the way
back, but we weren't hit again.

312
00:24:53,542 --> 00:24:57,371
Eventually, we came over England,
when I saw these beacons flashing.

313
00:25:04,552 --> 00:25:08,000
As it touched down, the legs
of the undercarriage collapsed.

314
00:25:08,082 --> 00:25:11,835
We went along on our belly
for maybe 50 yards or so.

315
00:25:11,957 --> 00:25:15,863
And came to a stop. Switched off
engines to keep the fire hazard down.

316
00:25:15,947 --> 00:25:19,896
It was then only, that I knew
the navigator was killed,

317
00:25:19,975 --> 00:25:22,845
because he'd slid forward beside me.

318
00:25:37,124 --> 00:25:39,808
(man) About how many enemy fighters
did you see?

319
00:25:39,886 --> 00:25:42,604
(pilot) I couldn't keep track,
but I counted about 65.

320
00:25:42,687 --> 00:25:45,709
(pilot #2) I stopped trying to count
when I got to 50, sir.

321
00:25:45,795 --> 00:25:48,162
(man) I think
it was generally understood

322
00:25:48,250 --> 00:25:51,043
that the combat tour was 25 missions,

323
00:25:51,127 --> 00:25:53,768
because you'd be dead
by the end of that time,

324
00:25:53,889 --> 00:25:57,839
so there wasn't any point
in asking you to stay around any longer.

325
00:25:57,918 --> 00:26:00,558
(narrator)
Bomber crews lived a curious war.

326
00:26:00,642 --> 00:26:03,009
One day in action, the next on the town.

327
00:26:03,097 --> 00:26:05,781
When our group wasn't flying,

328
00:26:05,859 --> 00:26:08,271
they'd usually go into London.

329
00:26:08,353 --> 00:26:10,568
Spend the day in London.

330
00:26:10,655 --> 00:26:13,754
And sometimes,
if they had some money left,

331
00:26:13,839 --> 00:26:18,018
they'd call up to find out if there
was a mission going the next day,

332
00:26:18,098 --> 00:26:19,854
and if not, they'd stay over.

333
00:26:19,939 --> 00:26:23,006
(man) Flak will be heavy,
probably accurate,

334
00:26:23,085 --> 00:26:25,300
but you've been through worse before.

335
00:26:25,387 --> 00:26:30,679
Remember that your biggest enemy
still is single-engine fighter planes.

336
00:26:36,321 --> 00:26:39,234
I recall one evening
in the officers' club.

337
00:26:39,313 --> 00:26:44,060
Our operations officer was pouring
Scotch into a one-armed bandit,

338
00:26:44,147 --> 00:26:46,711
you know, these things
that you put quarters in,

339
00:26:46,795 --> 00:26:50,821
trying to persuade the machine
to deliver a jackpot.

340
00:26:50,900 --> 00:26:58,418
But... I guess it was a kind of an eat,
drink and be merry sort of life.

341
00:26:59,493 --> 00:27:02,406
("American Patrol" by Glenn Miller)

342
00:27:09,200 --> 00:27:12,146
The going's gonna be rough.

343
00:27:12,230 --> 00:27:17,675
You'll have to pull your necks in there
and stay in there and pitch, every man.

344
00:27:43,229 --> 00:27:46,600
(Corcoran)
I think that flying is so impersonal,

345
00:27:46,682 --> 00:27:48,973
that is to say combat flying,

346
00:27:49,061 --> 00:27:51,930
that you don't get
that intimate sense of loss

347
00:27:52,053 --> 00:27:54,420
if you see an aeroplane get shot down

348
00:27:54,508 --> 00:27:58,142
that you'd have
if your buddy on a battlefield

349
00:27:58,230 --> 00:28:01,252
had his head blown off
right within arm's length.

350
00:28:05,711 --> 00:28:08,962
(narrator) Men came from Britain,
America, Occupied Europe,

351
00:28:09,049 --> 00:28:10,849
and the British Commonwealth

352
00:28:10,929 --> 00:28:15,643
to fight and die in
the most determined air offensive yet.

353
00:28:16,722 --> 00:28:20,050
In January 1943, at Casablanca,
Churchill and Roosevelt

354
00:28:20,136 --> 00:28:23,126
decided to combine
the British and US bombing efforts

355
00:28:23,244 --> 00:28:25,732
in preparing Nazi Europe for D-day.

356
00:28:27,541 --> 00:28:30,639
U-boat yards, aircraft plants...

357
00:28:32,298 --> 00:28:34,207
..armament factories,

358
00:28:34,293 --> 00:28:37,053
oil installations and transport,

359
00:28:37,132 --> 00:28:42,151
were deemed priority targets
for round-the-clock precision bombing.

360
00:28:47,030 --> 00:28:51,012
But precision bombing at night
was still impossible for Harris.

361
00:28:51,097 --> 00:28:54,392
An attempt to pick off the Ruhr dams
with specially designed bombs

362
00:28:54,473 --> 00:28:56,764
was only partially successful,

363
00:28:56,851 --> 00:29:00,147
and cost the lives
of some of the best aircrews.

364
00:29:10,087 --> 00:29:15,794
Though the raid led to improved accuracy
later on, not all the dams were hit.

365
00:29:15,880 --> 00:29:19,405
Ruhr arms production was unaffected.

366
00:29:19,486 --> 00:29:23,360
Harris believed that only the mounting
onslaught of night area bombing

367
00:29:23,438 --> 00:29:26,308
would crush German industrial capacity.

368
00:29:26,392 --> 00:29:29,567
(Mahaddie) At this time,
we were getting better aircraft.

369
00:29:29,691 --> 00:29:32,103
The Lancaster
was coming out in great numbers.

370
00:29:32,185 --> 00:29:37,204
We were losing the less efficient
Stirling and the Halifax.

371
00:29:37,326 --> 00:29:39,541
We were getting better radar devices.

372
00:29:39,628 --> 00:29:45,225
And we had extremely good navigators,
selected navigators.

373
00:29:45,306 --> 00:29:47,445
And this was the essence
of the whole thing.

374
00:29:47,531 --> 00:29:52,824
And these navigators were able
to get much closer to an aiming point

375
00:29:52,902 --> 00:29:54,812
than we had previously.

376
00:29:54,897 --> 00:29:59,535
Then we laid great lanes of flares,
hundreds of flares.

377
00:29:59,616 --> 00:30:01,601
Even if we missed the aiming point,

378
00:30:01,726 --> 00:30:07,859
we would identify some
very positive feature on the ground,

379
00:30:07,941 --> 00:30:11,237
Iike a lake or a bend in the river.

380
00:30:11,317 --> 00:30:14,264
And from there,
we could then creep on to the target

381
00:30:14,348 --> 00:30:18,222
and put flares down,
different coloured flares.

382
00:30:18,300 --> 00:30:21,246
And then later on,
we got target indicators.

383
00:30:21,369 --> 00:30:27,654
And these were... Just imagine
a great bunch of incandescent grapes

384
00:30:27,737 --> 00:30:34,558
falling from 2,000, 4,000, wherever
we wanted them to detonate from.

385
00:30:35,334 --> 00:30:37,592
(narrator) At the end of July 1943,

386
00:30:37,674 --> 00:30:42,770
Harris deployed his improving technology
with devastating effect on Hamburg.

387
00:30:42,892 --> 00:30:46,645
(Harris) The effectiveness
of the first Hamburg raid

388
00:30:46,728 --> 00:30:51,639
was due to us at last getting permission

389
00:30:51,715 --> 00:30:54,967
to use something
we'd had in the bag for a long time,

390
00:30:55,092 --> 00:30:57,503
which was known as "window",

391
00:30:57,585 --> 00:31:02,332
which was the dropping
of clouds of aluminium paper strips,

392
00:31:02,419 --> 00:31:07,941
which completely upset
not only the German location apparatus,

393
00:31:08,020 --> 00:31:10,661
but also their gun-aiming apparatus.

394
00:31:29,083 --> 00:31:32,836
(man) None of us,
neither civilians nor firemen,

395
00:31:32,919 --> 00:31:35,941
knew what happened on this night.

396
00:31:36,027 --> 00:31:38,241
It was a very heavy raid,

397
00:31:38,329 --> 00:31:43,697
but we had almost the same
one year before.

398
00:31:44,314 --> 00:31:47,609
We were not prepared
for the fire storm

399
00:31:47,690 --> 00:31:51,443
which broke out
half an hour after the raid.

400
00:31:55,171 --> 00:31:58,499
(narrator) The effect of the bombing,
combined with a heat wave,

401
00:31:58,585 --> 00:32:01,837
was to create
a man-made tornado of flame.

402
00:32:01,923 --> 00:32:03,908
A fire storm.

403
00:32:06,719 --> 00:32:10,516
Und diese ganze Gegend
wurde von Kanälen...

404
00:32:10,593 --> 00:32:13,311
(translator)
I went to this area near the docks.

405
00:32:13,394 --> 00:32:15,379
It was crossed by canals.

406
00:32:15,466 --> 00:32:19,143
People tried to leap down into them
out of the flames,

407
00:32:19,226 --> 00:32:21,331
but the water was on fire.

408
00:32:28,011 --> 00:32:31,918
It's difficult to explain
why the water was burning.

409
00:32:32,001 --> 00:32:37,064
There were many ships, small ships,
moored in the canals.

410
00:32:37,180 --> 00:32:42,810
They had exploded, and burning oil
had been released onto the water.

411
00:32:44,585 --> 00:32:49,222
And the people, who were themselves
on fire, jumped into it.

412
00:32:49,342 --> 00:32:55,093
And they burnt, swam,
burnt and went under.

413
00:33:16,658 --> 00:33:21,066
Most people
were killed by the fierce heat,

414
00:33:21,223 --> 00:33:27,967
not burnt or suffocated
or poisoned by carbon monoxide.

415
00:33:28,090 --> 00:33:30,654
We think that in some places,

416
00:33:30,738 --> 00:33:36,564
the temperature
reached 1,000 degrees centigrade.

417
00:33:40,137 --> 00:33:43,203
(narrator) The British night attacks
and American day raids

418
00:33:43,283 --> 00:33:45,236
lasted nearly a week.

419
00:33:45,316 --> 00:33:47,226
30,000 died.

420
00:33:47,311 --> 00:33:53,520
In Hamburg,
we really found out the first time

421
00:33:53,603 --> 00:33:58,819
that the morale of the German people
can be shattered so much

422
00:33:58,897 --> 00:34:02,193
that work for industry,

423
00:34:02,273 --> 00:34:06,300
the work in the armaments industry,
would collapse.

424
00:34:12,248 --> 00:34:14,354
(narrator) At the time, Speer said

425
00:34:14,435 --> 00:34:18,155
six more raids like that
would have finished the war.

426
00:34:21,187 --> 00:34:24,362
The Allies did not have that capacity.

427
00:34:26,942 --> 00:34:29,124
The shock passed.

428
00:34:33,080 --> 00:34:35,611
At the same time, the Eighth Air Force

429
00:34:35,689 --> 00:34:40,207
had stepped up
the intensity of its daylight raids.

430
00:34:40,331 --> 00:34:44,009
Next group will bomb
from an altitude of 13,000 feet.

431
00:34:46,431 --> 00:34:48,537
We feel that this low altitude

432
00:34:48,618 --> 00:34:52,906
will be equalised by the element
of surprise which is with us.

433
00:34:54,756 --> 00:34:58,935
(narrator) Two weeks after Hamburg,
they planned to deal their knockout blow

434
00:34:59,015 --> 00:35:01,230
against German industry.

435
00:35:01,317 --> 00:35:02,920
(man) Lights, please.

436
00:35:03,005 --> 00:35:07,064
This group of buildings here
is your target.

437
00:35:07,148 --> 00:35:10,095
This building will be the aiming point.

438
00:35:10,179 --> 00:35:13,660
If your bomb pattern
is concentrated in this area,

439
00:35:13,747 --> 00:35:17,380
it should very effectively
knock out the factory.

440
00:35:17,507 --> 00:35:20,987
(narrator) The target was the
ball-bearing factories at Schweinfurt,

441
00:35:21,113 --> 00:35:23,830
producing a major part
of Germany's needs.

442
00:36:07,918 --> 00:36:10,755
The attacking force
was to be split into two.

443
00:36:10,834 --> 00:36:13,365
The first wave would fight
to a secondary target,

444
00:36:13,443 --> 00:36:16,814
the Messerschmitt aircraft plant
at Regensburg.

445
00:36:16,895 --> 00:36:19,994
Then it would fly on unhindered
to North Africa.

446
00:36:20,118 --> 00:36:22,606
The second wave,
ten minutes behind the first,

447
00:36:22,689 --> 00:36:24,565
would then arrive at Schweinfurt,

448
00:36:24,645 --> 00:36:27,897
whilst the German fighters
were on the ground refuelling.

449
00:36:27,983 --> 00:36:30,929
Their battle
would be during the trip home.

450
00:36:32,663 --> 00:36:35,805
(pilot) I went in
without any fighter escort at all,

451
00:36:35,886 --> 00:36:40,480
and flew clear across Europe
without fighter escort,

452
00:36:40,567 --> 00:36:45,586
with about 125 aeroplanes
that I had in the division at the time.

453
00:36:47,434 --> 00:36:51,570
(narrator) German air defence staff
plotted the path of the first wave

454
00:36:51,654 --> 00:36:55,331
as it flew further and further
into Germany.

455
00:36:56,219 --> 00:36:59,242
They could not tell
the plan was going wrong.

456
00:36:59,327 --> 00:37:02,775
British weather helped to upset
the Americans' careful plans.

457
00:37:02,895 --> 00:37:06,146
Unexpected low cloud
delayed the takeoff of the second wave.

458
00:37:06,233 --> 00:37:09,332
The result: the Luftwaffe,
refuelled and re-armed,

459
00:37:09,417 --> 00:37:10,988
was waiting for them.

460
00:37:11,067 --> 00:37:13,750
Well, we didn't expect an attack

461
00:37:13,829 --> 00:37:17,965
coming that far into the country
without fighter escort.

462
00:37:18,049 --> 00:37:21,148
And we were all very astonished.

463
00:37:24,955 --> 00:37:27,977
(man) Null. Anfrage Viktor.

464
00:37:51,657 --> 00:37:58,215
Schweinfurt was the result of very good
conditions in favour of German fighters,

465
00:37:58,294 --> 00:38:01,393
and the fact
we could bring all our fighters

466
00:38:01,516 --> 00:38:04,844
into operation
to intercept the bomber stream.

467
00:38:04,931 --> 00:38:09,677
This altogether
has favoured our results.

468
00:38:14,292 --> 00:38:17,543
(narrator)
21 Flying Fortresses were lost

469
00:38:17,630 --> 00:38:21,110
before the first bomb fell
on Schweinfurt.

470
00:38:27,796 --> 00:38:31,321
(Lemay) The first division,
coming in later, had heavier losses,

471
00:38:31,402 --> 00:38:35,276
because they had to go back out
in addition to coming in.

472
00:38:35,354 --> 00:38:39,304
I think we wound up the day
by losing about 60 aeroplanes,

473
00:38:39,382 --> 00:38:43,060
which didn't make anybody very happy.

474
00:38:44,523 --> 00:38:47,393
Ich kam dann noch mal hoch und bin
von unten ins Ziel und...

475
00:38:47,516 --> 00:38:49,501
hat dann prima hingehauen.

476
00:39:16,021 --> 00:39:17,974
(narrator) The cost was high.

477
00:39:18,092 --> 00:39:21,966
But ball-bearing production
was disrupted for six weeks.

478
00:39:22,044 --> 00:39:26,955
(Speer) When you hit Schweinfurt first,

479
00:39:27,031 --> 00:39:31,472
it was a nightmare getting true.

480
00:39:31,558 --> 00:39:35,541
But then, I had
a very good representative, Kessler,

481
00:39:35,625 --> 00:39:40,295
and he did with all means,
not only the repair,

482
00:39:40,382 --> 00:39:46,209
but also the replacement
of ball bearings with other devices

483
00:39:46,291 --> 00:39:49,357
which could do the job,

484
00:39:49,436 --> 00:39:52,459
not as good as a ball bearing,
but it could be done.

485
00:39:57,033 --> 00:39:59,641
(narrator) In the two-wave attack,

486
00:39:59,757 --> 00:40:03,281
over 120 aircraft
were lost or damaged beyond repair.

487
00:40:03,363 --> 00:40:07,880
To prove their point at Schweinfurt,
the Americans would have to go back.

488
00:40:07,967 --> 00:40:10,880
Naturally, I was keenly disappointed,

489
00:40:10,959 --> 00:40:14,058
largely because
in sending my crews back,

490
00:40:14,143 --> 00:40:17,242
I knew they would sustain
additional losses.

491
00:40:17,328 --> 00:40:19,891
If we had done the job right
in the first place,

492
00:40:19,975 --> 00:40:22,430
we could have avoided these losses.

493
00:40:22,507 --> 00:40:27,832
But nobody who fires a gun
hits his target every time.

494
00:40:27,916 --> 00:40:30,447
We went back
because we got good weather

495
00:40:30,525 --> 00:40:33,395
and it was our highest priority target.

496
00:40:33,479 --> 00:40:35,355
That's why we returned.

497
00:40:37,047 --> 00:40:41,761
On 14th October, some 300 bombers
were marshalled over England.

498
00:40:42,457 --> 00:40:45,785
(Rogan) There were aeroplanes
climbing all over England.

499
00:40:45,871 --> 00:40:47,551
England was just an airport.

500
00:40:47,636 --> 00:40:52,230
And this, I think, was real difficult.

501
00:40:54,081 --> 00:40:55,532
(narrator) It took some time

502
00:40:55,616 --> 00:41:00,286
to group a large number
of heavy bombers into a tight formation.

503
00:41:00,373 --> 00:41:03,669
These complicated manoeuvres
gave warning to the Luftwaffe

504
00:41:03,749 --> 00:41:06,815
of the strength and direction
of an attacking force.

505
00:41:06,895 --> 00:41:09,383
Two thirds of all German fighters

506
00:41:09,465 --> 00:41:12,684
were now concentrated
against the Eighth Air Force.

507
00:41:12,765 --> 00:41:15,024
(Stewart)
The fighter was the boogie man.

508
00:41:15,143 --> 00:41:22,509
The fighter had eyes
and, in a great many instances,

509
00:41:22,586 --> 00:41:28,260
the fighter had a pretty competent fella
at the controls.

510
00:41:28,341 --> 00:41:35,466
And when he latched on to you,
you were in trouble lots of times.

511
00:41:35,554 --> 00:41:39,994
I was that close
that I could really see the rear gunner.

512
00:41:40,081 --> 00:41:44,675
I saw him as frightened as I was.

513
00:41:48,713 --> 00:41:52,772
(Rogan) They'd call the positions
of the fighters out over their intercom.

514
00:41:52,856 --> 00:41:54,809
Sometimes they'd get so frightened

515
00:41:54,889 --> 00:41:57,682
that they'd continue
to hold the microphone down,

516
00:41:57,805 --> 00:42:01,438
and keep hollering into the microphone.

517
00:42:03,675 --> 00:42:09,152
And they started
at 1,000 metres, almost,

518
00:42:09,238 --> 00:42:12,609
with their tracing ammunition,
in order to frighten us.

519
00:42:12,691 --> 00:42:17,099
And I told my younger pilots,
who had no experience,

520
00:42:17,179 --> 00:42:21,206
to close their eyes,
attacking from behind.

521
00:42:25,466 --> 00:42:30,213
(Rogan) There wasn't much time
to think. You just put that gun sight on

522
00:42:30,300 --> 00:42:34,021
and kept waving your head around
looking for enemy fighters

523
00:42:34,098 --> 00:42:36,465
and kept the gun sight on 'em.

524
00:42:37,628 --> 00:42:40,617
Pilot to navigator, what's the word?

525
00:42:40,697 --> 00:42:42,268
We're making the run.

526
00:42:42,347 --> 00:42:45,521
(Rogan) Right before we hit the target
was the worst part.

527
00:42:45,646 --> 00:42:49,171
We got picked up by fighters, were
taken into the target and they left,

528
00:42:49,252 --> 00:42:53,388
and we dropped the bombs
and they picked us up after the target.

529
00:42:56,733 --> 00:43:00,062
(narrator) More than 60%
of all ball-bearing production

530
00:43:00,148 --> 00:43:02,287
at Schweinfurt was destroyed.

531
00:43:02,373 --> 00:43:06,476
The Americans had lost
more than 60 Flying Fortresses.

532
00:43:07,706 --> 00:43:11,001
If you would have repeated those raids
shortly afterwards,

533
00:43:11,082 --> 00:43:14,453
it wouldn't have given us
the time to rebuild.

534
00:43:14,535 --> 00:43:17,786
Then it would have been
a disastrous result.

535
00:43:17,949 --> 00:43:20,054
Could you take the losses
the forces took

536
00:43:20,136 --> 00:43:22,427
when you didn't know
if you'd accomplish it?

537
00:43:22,553 --> 00:43:26,579
When you thought ball bearings were
coming in from Sweden and Switzerland?

538
00:43:26,658 --> 00:43:29,298
You didn't know.
You don't go on with those things.

539
00:43:29,382 --> 00:43:34,478
(narrator) So the strategy swung back
from pinpoint targets like Schweinfurt

540
00:43:34,599 --> 00:43:38,888
to another night area offensive: Berlin.

541
00:43:39,472 --> 00:43:43,803
With American support, Harris believed
he could wreck Berlin in six months

542
00:43:43,884 --> 00:43:45,760
and win the war.

543
00:43:45,840 --> 00:43:50,019
But the depleted Eighth Air Force
were not now able to join him.

544
00:43:50,137 --> 00:43:54,698
He sent the most amazing signals.
And one that I'll always remember -

545
00:43:54,779 --> 00:44:00,072
and this is the sort of thing
you read out to your crews at briefing -

546
00:44:00,150 --> 00:44:02,714
this one went on to say:

547
00:44:02,836 --> 00:44:06,055
"Tonight you go to the big city."
That's Berlin.

548
00:44:06,135 --> 00:44:10,314
"You have the opportunity to light
a fire in the belly of the enemy

549
00:44:10,394 --> 00:44:12,653
and burn his black heart out."

550
00:44:12,734 --> 00:44:14,719
(cheering)

551
00:44:19,563 --> 00:44:23,164
Well, crews, after they stopped
cheering a thing like that,

552
00:44:23,246 --> 00:44:25,122
they didn't want aircraft.

553
00:44:25,203 --> 00:44:27,734
You could just fill their pockets
with bombs

554
00:44:27,811 --> 00:44:31,947
and point them towards Berlin
and they'd take off on their own.

555
00:44:35,216 --> 00:44:38,391
(narrator) Bomber Command
had to go on on its own.

556
00:44:38,477 --> 00:44:43,845
It was a long way, and the weather
at the end of 1943 was particularly bad.

557
00:44:43,963 --> 00:44:47,870
But each night, the bombers
fought their way to Berlin

558
00:44:47,953 --> 00:44:50,364
and other cities deep in Germany.

559
00:44:55,166 --> 00:44:59,148
Harris' crews wrought terrible damage.

560
00:45:03,567 --> 00:45:06,405
(newsreel) Berlin is getting
a real taste of total war.

561
00:45:06,522 --> 00:45:09,696
The terrific weight of RAF assaults
on the capital of Naziland

562
00:45:09,783 --> 00:45:11,004
has set the Hun reeling.

563
00:45:11,087 --> 00:45:14,612
How he must regret the ruthless attacks
he made on Warsaw, Rotterdam,

564
00:45:14,693 --> 00:45:17,257
Belgrade, London,
Coventry and the rest.

565
00:45:17,340 --> 00:45:19,479
The day and night of reckoning is here.

566
00:45:19,566 --> 00:45:21,595
And what do you think of it, Keith?

567
00:45:21,676 --> 00:45:25,625
Jerry definitely had it this time.
It certainly was a wizard prang.

568
00:45:34,374 --> 00:45:41,041
(narrator) Yet many of Berlin's offices
and factories managed to go on working.

569
00:45:41,740 --> 00:45:47,600
(Speer) In my experience,
people rather got numb.

570
00:45:47,725 --> 00:45:52,472
They were going through the streets
like shadows.

571
00:45:52,559 --> 00:45:56,084
But they were still working
like automats.

572
00:46:23,213 --> 00:46:24,936
(siren)

573
00:46:31,883 --> 00:46:34,447
We had very little trouble
in getting there,

574
00:46:34,569 --> 00:46:36,020
but one thing I did notice

575
00:46:36,142 --> 00:46:39,088
was the vicious way
in which every German town

576
00:46:39,173 --> 00:46:43,308
now seems
to throw up flak indiscriminately.

577
00:46:43,393 --> 00:46:46,153
(narrator) The technological advantages

578
00:46:46,232 --> 00:46:49,025
which prevailed over Hamburg
no longer applied.

579
00:46:49,109 --> 00:46:53,594
The German air defence
had leapfrogged ahead once more.

580
00:47:00,120 --> 00:47:03,840
Berlin looked as if
it would indeed remain Berlin.

581
00:47:03,918 --> 00:47:06,601
("Berlin bleibt doch Berlin")

582
00:47:21,911 --> 00:47:27,388
By early spring, 1944, Harris
had not totally destroyed the city.

583
00:47:58,588 --> 00:48:01,992
Bomber Command had been
savagely mauled by the Germans.

584
00:48:02,079 --> 00:48:06,258
In those four months, in raids
against Berlin and other targets,

585
00:48:06,376 --> 00:48:11,515
1,000 aircraft, the Command's
first-line strength, were lost.

586
00:48:12,322 --> 00:48:15,726
But Harris did not,
and does not, concede defeat.

587
00:48:15,813 --> 00:48:18,225
(Harris)
The casualties in the Battle of Berlin

588
00:48:18,307 --> 00:48:21,449
were no more than we would have suffered

589
00:48:21,530 --> 00:48:26,277
if we'd gone anywhere else in Germany,
deep into Germany.

590
00:48:26,364 --> 00:48:28,895
People seem to forget
that Bomber Command

591
00:48:28,973 --> 00:48:31,842
fought 1,000 battles during the war.

592
00:48:31,927 --> 00:48:33,727
You can't succeed in every one.

593
00:48:33,807 --> 00:48:37,910
I'm not saying the Battle of Berlin
was a defeat or anything like a defeat.

594
00:48:37,988 --> 00:48:42,735
I think it was a major contribution
towards the defeat of Germany.

595
00:48:42,822 --> 00:48:47,078
There were thousands
of heavy anti-aircraft guns,

596
00:48:47,196 --> 00:48:51,604
millions of ammunition for them,

597
00:48:51,685 --> 00:48:54,783
and hundreds of thousands of soldiers,

598
00:48:54,907 --> 00:48:59,392
which were torn away
from our fight in the Eastern Front.

599
00:48:59,473 --> 00:49:03,990
So I should say,
with air attacks on Germany,

600
00:49:04,076 --> 00:49:07,754
you had, in an early stage, from '43 on,

601
00:49:07,836 --> 00:49:10,291
really a so-called second front.

602
00:49:14,588 --> 00:49:18,266
(narrator) Despite all the devastation,
the Germans carried on.

603
00:49:18,348 --> 00:49:20,487
German industry was still supplying

604
00:49:20,573 --> 00:49:23,640
the armies fighting fiercely
in the east and in Italy.

605
00:49:23,719 --> 00:49:28,433
The strategic bombing thesis
remained as yet unproven.

606
00:49:33,579 --> 00:49:37,104
The lessons of Schweinfurt
had been well learnt by the Americans.

607
00:49:37,224 --> 00:49:40,977
Re-equipped, they joined the RAF
over Berlin in March 1944.

608
00:49:41,060 --> 00:49:43,242
But now they were escorted
by the Mustang,

609
00:49:43,324 --> 00:49:46,390
a remarkable aeroplane
which was to change everything.

610
00:49:46,469 --> 00:49:49,416
It had a bomber's range
and a fighter's performance.

611
00:49:49,500 --> 00:49:52,981
The German day fighter
had now met its match.

612
00:49:58,478 --> 00:50:02,002
By the end of spring 1944,
the German day fighter had lost

613
00:50:02,084 --> 00:50:04,877
where the Spitfire and Hurricane
had won.

614
00:50:04,961 --> 00:50:08,442
The Americans had finally beaten
the Luftwaffe over daylight Europe

615
00:50:08,529 --> 00:50:10,559
with their long-range fighters.

616
00:50:11,752 --> 00:50:17,120
We had nothing of the same effort.

617
00:50:17,200 --> 00:50:21,226
And I think
they frightened us quite a bit.

618
00:50:21,305 --> 00:50:23,138
I think the main concern

619
00:50:23,223 --> 00:50:27,053
was the quantities
in which they were showing up.

620
00:50:31,970 --> 00:50:35,952
(narrator) The Germans had lost control
of their air space in daylight.

621
00:50:36,037 --> 00:50:42,442
From now on, the Allies would be able to
launch day raids over Germany at will.

622
00:50:51,191 --> 00:50:55,217
But, in March 1944,

623
00:50:55,296 --> 00:50:58,896
both bomber forces were placed
under Eisenhower's overall command

624
00:50:58,979 --> 00:51:01,118
to prepare for D-day.

625
00:51:01,204 --> 00:51:03,037
There would be six months' respite

626
00:51:03,122 --> 00:51:05,883
before the Allied bombers
could set out once more,

627
00:51:05,961 --> 00:51:09,365
to break the will of the German people.
