1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:08,000
== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==

2
00:00:06,191 --> 00:00:08,984
(narrator) Monsoon in Burma.

3
00:00:10,680 --> 00:00:14,706
(man) If you can imagine the heaviest
rain you'd ever get in this country

4
00:00:14,784 --> 00:00:20,305
going on for six to eight weeks without
a break, this was monsoon period.

5
00:00:20,385 --> 00:00:23,484
(narrator) Five months in every year.

6
00:00:24,144 --> 00:00:29,055
(man #2) Squashing through mud, living
in mud, lying in mud and sleeping in mud

7
00:00:29,131 --> 00:00:31,390
and drinking in mud and eating in mud.

8
00:00:31,471 --> 00:00:34,919
That was the monsoon in Burma,
and it's just a nightmare.

9
00:00:36,650 --> 00:00:41,822
(narrator) War in Burma made up
in ferocity what it lacked in scale.

10
00:00:42,711 --> 00:00:46,814
Here, in 1944, in these conditions,

11
00:00:46,893 --> 00:00:52,752
the British were defending the frontiers
of India against the Japanese.

12
00:01:48,041 --> 00:01:49,951
(bird calls)

13
00:01:59,818 --> 00:02:05,339
(narrator) The Burmese jungle -
a steam bath, closing out the sky.

14
00:02:05,994 --> 00:02:11,472
Dense, imprisoning...
and a long way from home.

15
00:02:12,324 --> 00:02:15,881
I'd never seen a jungle. I'd seen
a forest, but I hadn't seen a jungle.

16
00:02:15,968 --> 00:02:21,446
We went in there,
it was dark, dirty, damp, rain,

17
00:02:21,531 --> 00:02:25,437
there were all sorts of animal noises
that we'd never heard before...

18
00:02:25,521 --> 00:02:27,506
In fact, it was really scary.

19
00:02:27,592 --> 00:02:29,240
I liked the jungle.

20
00:02:29,318 --> 00:02:34,872
It did not have the fear it seems
to have had for some Allied soldiers.

21
00:02:34,957 --> 00:02:38,831
It was a friendly place - dark,
where you could camouflage yourself.

22
00:02:41,978 --> 00:02:45,774
(narrator) Burma:
jagged mountain and fetid swamp,

23
00:02:45,852 --> 00:02:50,489
clothed in jungle
and scored by steep river valleys.

24
00:02:53,870 --> 00:02:59,424
Burma: endless green growth
spawning every kind of disease -

25
00:02:59,509 --> 00:03:03,764
malaria, dysentery, scrub typhus,

26
00:03:03,844 --> 00:03:07,596
dengue fever, prickly heat -

27
00:03:07,680 --> 00:03:10,854
particularly in monsoon.

28
00:03:14,470 --> 00:03:18,835
Mud. It might have been Flanders
in the First World War.

29
00:03:19,994 --> 00:03:26,049
The monsoon in Burma turned camps
into swamps, roads into quagmires.

30
00:03:29,239 --> 00:03:35,720
After the rains, the country
was just one great bowl of mud.

31
00:03:40,633 --> 00:03:43,502
For the British,
Burma was a shield and barrier

32
00:03:43,586 --> 00:03:46,728
protecting their Indian empire.

33
00:03:46,809 --> 00:03:49,297
The Japanese saw they could use Burma

34
00:03:49,417 --> 00:03:51,479
to screen their new territorial gains

35
00:03:51,566 --> 00:03:53,136
in Southeast Asia,

36
00:03:53,215 --> 00:03:55,823
to cut the Allied supply route
to China,

37
00:03:55,939 --> 00:03:59,736
and to secure new sources
of oil and rice.

38
00:03:59,813 --> 00:04:02,912
In December 1941, they invaded.

39
00:04:02,997 --> 00:04:05,179
They had the advantage of surprise,

40
00:04:05,299 --> 00:04:09,893
and, for this jungle war,
they were thoroughly prepared.

41
00:04:10,670 --> 00:04:12,088
I don't think any country

42
00:04:12,166 --> 00:04:15,995
could have been more unprepared for war

43
00:04:16,079 --> 00:04:18,839
than Burma was at this particular time.

44
00:04:18,917 --> 00:04:20,947
The government was unprepared,

45
00:04:21,027 --> 00:04:25,544
the civil organisation
and the people were unprepared,

46
00:04:25,631 --> 00:04:30,497
and the defence forces
practically didn't exist.

47
00:04:30,963 --> 00:04:36,364
Some of the Gurkha who came along had
400 recruits straight from the depot,

48
00:04:36,449 --> 00:04:42,428
and the British had been milked
of reinforcements and officers to Europe

49
00:04:42,510 --> 00:04:46,110
and, you might say,
only the dull left behind.

50
00:04:52,714 --> 00:04:56,740
(narrator) The Japanese from the start
swept all before them.

51
00:05:01,422 --> 00:05:04,411
They used the jungle
to outmarch and outmanoeuvre

52
00:05:04,491 --> 00:05:07,513
Britain's weak Burma army.

53
00:05:13,583 --> 00:05:16,649
The British retreated in confusion.

54
00:05:21,600 --> 00:05:27,962
It was a crashing disadvantage to me
in the 1942 campaign

55
00:05:28,045 --> 00:05:30,762
in that I hadn't got a wireless set

56
00:05:30,845 --> 00:05:35,984
which would contact
my air support in Rangoon,

57
00:05:36,063 --> 00:05:38,354
and, therefore, believe it or not,

58
00:05:38,441 --> 00:05:41,998
the only thing I could do was to tap in

59
00:05:42,085 --> 00:05:46,526
onto the railway telephone line,

60
00:05:46,612 --> 00:05:51,206
get the babu
in the post office in Rangoon,

61
00:05:51,292 --> 00:05:55,166
and try and persuade him
that it was vitally important

62
00:05:55,243 --> 00:05:59,880
for me to be put on
to air force headquarters.

63
00:05:59,962 --> 00:06:03,410
And that was really
one of the reasons why,

64
00:06:03,491 --> 00:06:07,517
in our withdrawal to the Sittang,

65
00:06:07,634 --> 00:06:10,885
we were
terribly badly bombed by the RAF

66
00:06:10,972 --> 00:06:14,300
as well as by the Japanese air force.

67
00:06:18,222 --> 00:06:21,396
(narrator) The Japanese
had heavy air superiority.

68
00:06:21,483 --> 00:06:23,938
They bombed and strafed almost at will,

69
00:06:24,015 --> 00:06:28,193
spreading terror
among raw troops and civilians.

70
00:06:33,758 --> 00:06:36,705
Only a small force
of American volunteers

71
00:06:36,789 --> 00:06:39,244
and the few RAF planes
that were in Burma

72
00:06:39,321 --> 00:06:42,921
challenged their dominance
and rose to battle with them.

73
00:06:52,134 --> 00:06:56,465
The damage the Japanese bombers dealt
was, as much as anything, psychological.

74
00:06:56,545 --> 00:07:00,571
People couldn't believe
this was happening to peaceful Burma.

75
00:07:15,074 --> 00:07:19,362
Resistance, valiant at times,
was swept aside.

76
00:07:24,166 --> 00:07:26,424
I was discharged from hospital
at Mandalay

77
00:07:26,506 --> 00:07:31,983
having broken three ribs - left
absolutely stranded on the roadside.

78
00:07:32,068 --> 00:07:33,901
And a civilian picked me up,

79
00:07:33,986 --> 00:07:35,742
took me home to his house,

80
00:07:35,828 --> 00:07:39,580
and said what did I do?
And I said, "I'm catering."

81
00:07:39,664 --> 00:07:40,841
He said, "If you like,

82
00:07:40,930 --> 00:07:42,805
come to our house and cook for us."

83
00:07:42,886 --> 00:07:44,490
We were there two hours,

84
00:07:44,574 --> 00:07:45,719
no more than that,

85
00:07:45,802 --> 00:07:47,711
when the message came through:

86
00:07:47,796 --> 00:07:50,131
"Evacuate, the Japanese are here."

87
00:07:57,272 --> 00:07:59,989
(narrator)
The Japanese march north continued,

88
00:08:00,072 --> 00:08:04,512
leaving a trail of chaos and destruction
the length of Burma.

89
00:08:06,939 --> 00:08:09,350
The British retreated.

90
00:08:09,432 --> 00:08:12,072
(Bowers) I had nothing,
only what I stood up in.

91
00:08:12,156 --> 00:08:18,015
I raided someone's kit, found a stout
pair of boots, and we began to walk.

92
00:08:32,756 --> 00:08:37,470
(narrator) In the mounting confusion,
the wounded were a problem.

93
00:08:37,551 --> 00:08:40,922
(man) We had to leave giving treatment
and just bandage up,

94
00:08:41,004 --> 00:08:43,721
do the best we could.
Some we had to leave behind.

95
00:08:43,843 --> 00:08:48,480
Others we put on transport to get them
on the roads - this was all we could do.

96
00:08:48,561 --> 00:08:51,660
And eventually we had
to finally give it up as a bad job

97
00:08:51,745 --> 00:08:53,272
and make our own way out,

98
00:08:53,356 --> 00:08:56,575
as we were only 24 hours
in front of the Japanese

99
00:08:56,655 --> 00:08:58,870
through the length and breadth of Burma.

100
00:09:07,895 --> 00:09:11,070
(narrator) The Japanese
took everything in their stride.

101
00:09:11,156 --> 00:09:16,601
Ahead of them, the last recourse
of a retreating army: scorched earth.

102
00:09:23,393 --> 00:09:27,375
The invaders seemed
to have made the jungle their friend.

103
00:09:27,498 --> 00:09:30,902
They were racing
to win the rich prize of Burma's oil -

104
00:09:30,989 --> 00:09:33,706
but found instead a blazing inferno.

105
00:09:33,789 --> 00:09:40,226
At one installation, £11 million worth
of oil and plant went up in 70 minutes.

106
00:09:47,906 --> 00:09:52,085
Refugees: Eurasians, Chinese, Indians.

107
00:09:53,661 --> 00:09:57,458
(Bowers) Indians we saw die on the
roadside - we could do nothing about it.

108
00:09:57,535 --> 00:10:01,485
We just had to
think about ourselves and go on.

109
00:10:05,975 --> 00:10:08,463
(man) The Japanese
were driving Burma people -

110
00:10:08,545 --> 00:10:12,374
in their thousands they came through.
There were some terrible sights.

111
00:10:12,496 --> 00:10:13,990
Men were left behind,

112
00:10:14,069 --> 00:10:18,128
and it was heart-breaking to see them
being separated from their people,

113
00:10:18,212 --> 00:10:22,271
wondering whether they'd meet up again.
They were dying in their hundreds.

114
00:10:22,394 --> 00:10:24,423
All you used to do was pile 'em up,

115
00:10:24,503 --> 00:10:26,991
throw petrol over them
and set fire to them

116
00:10:27,074 --> 00:10:29,681
and that was the end of those.

117
00:10:37,585 --> 00:10:40,377
(man) We had to hack
through virgin jungle practically

118
00:10:40,462 --> 00:10:46,212
to get out of that country,
and we had to find our own way to India.

119
00:10:46,293 --> 00:10:50,046
I think the overall impression I had
of that horrible trek out of Burma

120
00:10:50,129 --> 00:10:53,271
was that it seemed to bring the best
and worst out of people.

121
00:10:53,351 --> 00:10:55,610
Some people who I'd looked up to

122
00:10:55,730 --> 00:10:56,722
and respected

123
00:10:56,804 --> 00:10:58,680
I found I couldn't respect any more

124
00:10:58,760 --> 00:11:03,627
because they became
entirely different on that march.

125
00:11:03,709 --> 00:11:05,313
In fact, I felt that it was

126
00:11:05,435 --> 00:11:07,966
a question of survival of the fittest.

127
00:11:09,732 --> 00:11:15,558
(narrator) British prisoners -
5,000 in one engagement alone.

128
00:11:15,639 --> 00:11:18,629
The Japanese despised
those who surrendered.

129
00:11:18,708 --> 00:11:22,156
They believed
soldiers should fight to the death.

130
00:11:23,465 --> 00:11:26,487
(Okada) We felt the British officer
was a very good fighter -

131
00:11:26,573 --> 00:11:31,974
all of the ones we captured, they always
said to me, "We will win the war."

132
00:11:32,097 --> 00:11:36,308
Now this I couldn't understand, because
here is a man who has surrendered

133
00:11:36,393 --> 00:11:39,263
and he still says,
"We will win the war."

134
00:11:52,927 --> 00:11:54,650
(triumphal music)

135
00:11:55,842 --> 00:11:57,948
Through the deserted cities of Burma,

136
00:11:58,029 --> 00:12:00,593
the conquering Japanese
marched in triumph.

137
00:12:08,617 --> 00:12:12,948
The Burmese people were now exchanging
one set of imperial masters for another.

138
00:12:13,028 --> 00:12:14,861
(shouting in Japanese)

139
00:12:20,432 --> 00:12:23,225
In five months, by May 1942,

140
00:12:23,309 --> 00:12:26,222
the Japanese
chased the British up past Rangoon,

141
00:12:26,302 --> 00:12:28,713
through the Irrawaddy
and Chindwin valleys,

142
00:12:28,795 --> 00:12:30,246
to the frontiers of India

143
00:12:30,368 --> 00:12:32,582
and out of Burma altogether.

144
00:12:32,670 --> 00:12:36,576
It was the longest retreat
in British history.

145
00:12:36,698 --> 00:12:39,567
The Japanese also drove another army,
the Chinese,

146
00:12:39,651 --> 00:12:41,910
up to Mandalay towards China.

147
00:12:41,991 --> 00:12:44,632
The Chinese,
at war with Japan since 1931,

148
00:12:44,715 --> 00:12:46,668
were protecting their supply line,

149
00:12:46,748 --> 00:12:48,733
the Burma Road.

150
00:12:49,664 --> 00:12:52,610
China was allied to the western powers.

151
00:12:52,694 --> 00:12:57,637
In command of Chinese forces in Burma
was the American, General Stilwell.

152
00:12:57,758 --> 00:13:02,089
Stilwell, chief of staff to the Chinese
supreme commander Chiang Kai-shek,

153
00:13:02,170 --> 00:13:05,116
watched America's interests.

154
00:13:06,121 --> 00:13:09,645
The commander-in-chief, India,
was General Wavell.

155
00:13:09,727 --> 00:13:11,603
Transferred from the Middle East,

156
00:13:11,683 --> 00:13:15,633
he now faced a formidable foe
with scanty resources.

157
00:13:15,711 --> 00:13:19,508
But while his Burma army licked
its wounds, he planned a comeback,

158
00:13:19,586 --> 00:13:22,989
a limited offensive for late in 1942.

159
00:13:24,803 --> 00:13:27,749
Wavell chose to mount this offensive
in the Arakan,

160
00:13:27,834 --> 00:13:30,626
on the Bay of Bengal,
near the Indian Border.

161
00:13:30,711 --> 00:13:34,540
After a hopeful beginning,
everything went wrong.

162
00:13:34,624 --> 00:13:37,493
The British were outmanoeuvred
and outfought again,

163
00:13:37,616 --> 00:13:40,103
and pushed back to their starting point.

164
00:13:40,186 --> 00:13:42,674
They still had not learned
to adapt to the jungle.

165
00:13:44,291 --> 00:13:50,466
In the Burmese jungle, fortunately,
there are many bamboo growths,

166
00:13:50,544 --> 00:13:53,718
and in Japan we all eat bamboo shoots,

167
00:13:53,804 --> 00:13:57,711
so there was a lot of natural food
in the form of bamboo shoots

168
00:13:57,794 --> 00:13:59,288
all over the place.

169
00:13:59,367 --> 00:14:04,768
Apart from that, we all know that
what a monkey can eat, we can eat too.

170
00:14:04,852 --> 00:14:08,300
So if you watch the monkeys
and avoid what the monkeys avoid,

171
00:14:08,382 --> 00:14:10,334
you are fairly safe.

172
00:14:10,415 --> 00:14:15,237
Apart from that there are such creatures
as bandicoots - a type of rat, you see -

173
00:14:15,325 --> 00:14:18,925
snakes, jungle lizards and tokay -
small lizards -

174
00:14:19,008 --> 00:14:21,691
you cut off the head, chop them up
and make into curry,

175
00:14:21,770 --> 00:14:24,530
mixed with pepper, can make good curry.

176
00:14:24,647 --> 00:14:27,866
We have our meats
and Yorkshire puddings and so forth -

177
00:14:27,946 --> 00:14:29,702
they lived on rice.

178
00:14:29,788 --> 00:14:33,769
You can't get meat and Yorkshire pudding
and greens and potatoes out there,

179
00:14:33,854 --> 00:14:36,309
so we had to reorganise ourselves

180
00:14:36,386 --> 00:14:39,637
and lived on the things
that the army could produce for us,

181
00:14:39,723 --> 00:14:41,174
Iike corned beef.

182
00:14:41,296 --> 00:14:43,435
And this is the only place I know

183
00:14:43,521 --> 00:14:47,001
where you could open a tin of corned
beef and pour it out like a liquid.

184
00:14:47,933 --> 00:14:50,650
(narrator) One man
who was going to use the jungle:

185
00:14:50,733 --> 00:14:53,264
Orde Wingate,
an experienced guerrilla fighter,

186
00:14:53,342 --> 00:14:57,019
supremely unorthodox,
with a touch of the fanatic.

187
00:14:57,101 --> 00:15:03,081
Now he planned a raid deep in enemy
territory, to be supplied from the air.

188
00:15:03,162 --> 00:15:06,413
He commanded the Chindits,
ordinary British and Gurkha troops,

189
00:15:06,538 --> 00:15:09,789
but intensively trained.

190
00:15:10,566 --> 00:15:13,174
(Calvert) The first operation
was initially

191
00:15:13,251 --> 00:15:18,041
to accompany
a general advance into Burma,

192
00:15:18,123 --> 00:15:20,763
but the general advance was cancelled.

193
00:15:20,847 --> 00:15:26,062
However, Wavell wanted
the expedition to go forward.

194
00:15:26,985 --> 00:15:31,392
(narrator) February 1943:
the first Chindit expedition.

195
00:15:31,473 --> 00:15:33,732
The going could not have been worse -

196
00:15:33,813 --> 00:15:40,327
long distances in dense, hilly jungle,
and always one more river to cross.

197
00:15:49,810 --> 00:15:53,290
The heat was extreme,
drinking water was short,

198
00:15:53,454 --> 00:15:55,788
and malaria was rampant.

199
00:15:55,871 --> 00:15:59,013
But at last the British were fighting
as the enemy did,

200
00:15:59,093 --> 00:16:03,687
learning to turn the jungle to their
own advantage - but still hating it.

201
00:16:10,487 --> 00:16:16,313
(man) The heat and the smell
of the jungle was vile. Very vile.

202
00:16:16,394 --> 00:16:23,061
You couldn't live in the jungle for an
eternity - you'd never stand the smell.

203
00:16:26,023 --> 00:16:29,351
(man #2) Even when you went downhill,
you knew you had to go up again,

204
00:16:29,437 --> 00:16:32,045
and we were carrying
60 to 70 pounds on our back,

205
00:16:32,123 --> 00:16:34,915
five days' rations
plus arms, ammunition.

206
00:16:35,000 --> 00:16:37,989
You'd think, "Oh, will it ever end?"

207
00:16:38,069 --> 00:16:40,251
It just went on and on and on,

208
00:16:40,370 --> 00:16:46,732
and the rain - and, of course, the fear
that you would be ambushed or attacked.

209
00:16:52,684 --> 00:16:56,743
It was absolute hell
in the first Wingate expedition,

210
00:16:56,866 --> 00:17:02,234
where the jungle was the friend
of the Japanese, but our enemy.

211
00:17:02,965 --> 00:17:04,951
(man #1) We were wet all the time,

212
00:17:05,037 --> 00:17:08,757
and while we were wet
we got the leech onto our bodies.

213
00:17:08,835 --> 00:17:12,512
They were there all the time
because of the dampness of it.

214
00:17:12,594 --> 00:17:15,693
They got onto your body,
sucked the blood from your body,

215
00:17:15,817 --> 00:17:19,068
and unless you burnt them the right way
with the cigarette end,

216
00:17:19,154 --> 00:17:22,754
they fell off and left black spots
all over your body.

217
00:17:22,837 --> 00:17:26,666
Once they had their fill of blood,
they dropped from your body

218
00:17:26,750 --> 00:17:31,965
and burst inside your clothes,
and you were smothered in blood.

219
00:17:40,713 --> 00:17:44,041
(man #2) The thought that
you'd get wounded and be left behind,

220
00:17:44,127 --> 00:17:48,109
that was always in our minds, I think -
I'm sure it was in most people's minds.

221
00:17:48,194 --> 00:17:50,485
I saw chaps having to be left behind -

222
00:17:50,572 --> 00:17:54,937
hand grenade, pistol, flask of water,

223
00:17:55,022 --> 00:17:57,782
water bottle, rations -

224
00:17:57,861 --> 00:18:01,264
and propped up against a tree, left.

225
00:18:03,385 --> 00:18:05,916
(narrator) 450 died.

226
00:18:07,758 --> 00:18:12,013
For some, a simple cross
in a jungle clearing.

227
00:18:14,280 --> 00:18:18,535
In June, after four months,
the first Chindits returned from Burma.

228
00:18:18,614 --> 00:18:23,601
Out of the 3,000 men who had gone in,
less than 2,000 came back.

229
00:18:23,678 --> 00:18:29,461
Weary and emaciated, most
had marched a thousand jungle miles.

230
00:18:31,159 --> 00:18:34,377
Whatever the expedition's
military results,

231
00:18:34,535 --> 00:18:37,481
it did teach valuable lessons
in jungle operations,

232
00:18:37,603 --> 00:18:40,211
in air supply, and in morale.

233
00:18:42,667 --> 00:18:49,181
(Calvert) This was a raid. Its tactical
and strategical effect was not great.

234
00:18:49,265 --> 00:18:54,404
Its main effect was on the morale
of the British and Indian troops.

235
00:18:54,483 --> 00:18:57,046
Our forces were not picked men,

236
00:18:57,130 --> 00:19:00,577
they were ordinary
British and Gurkha battalions,

237
00:19:00,697 --> 00:19:03,185
and the rest of the army said, "My God,

238
00:19:03,267 --> 00:19:05,482
if those people can do it, we can."

239
00:19:06,375 --> 00:19:10,357
(narrator) Very slowly, the British
were getting the measure of the jungle.

240
00:19:10,441 --> 00:19:13,769
They loathed its stench,
its sticky heat.

241
00:19:13,855 --> 00:19:17,183
It was hard for them to realise
that the jungle was neutral.

242
00:19:17,269 --> 00:19:21,480
(Japanese man, calling out in English)
Hello, Tommy! Where are you?

243
00:19:25,364 --> 00:19:28,386
Hello, Tommy! Where are you?

244
00:19:31,156 --> 00:19:33,371
I have been hit. Come and help me.

245
00:19:33,496 --> 00:19:37,599
(narrator) The enemy carried on
a crude but effective war of nerves.

246
00:19:37,678 --> 00:19:41,780
The troops still thought of the Japanese
soldier as master of the jungle,

247
00:19:41,936 --> 00:19:44,303
a man who could go for days
on a handful of rice,

248
00:19:44,391 --> 00:19:47,074
didn't seem to know the meaning of fear,

249
00:19:47,153 --> 00:19:52,096
would never surrender,
was perhaps unbeatable.

250
00:19:54,710 --> 00:19:57,580
(mocking laughter)

251
00:19:58,546 --> 00:20:00,608
A sort of superman.

252
00:20:01,155 --> 00:20:04,908
The Japanese was a good soldier.
He was a good soldier.

253
00:20:04,991 --> 00:20:08,668
If he was told to do a job,
he would stop there until he died.

254
00:20:09,364 --> 00:20:11,274
Animals.

255
00:20:11,359 --> 00:20:14,687
But great soldiers,
great fighting soldiers.

256
00:20:15,349 --> 00:20:19,943
Their battle drill was fantastic.
You couldn't help but admire them.

257
00:20:20,029 --> 00:20:23,509
If they were ambushed,
they were at you -

258
00:20:23,597 --> 00:20:27,044
in 20 or 30 seconds they were
pounding you with their mortars,

259
00:20:27,126 --> 00:20:29,581
and in frontal attacks
nobody could beat them.

260
00:20:29,696 --> 00:20:31,987
They would just come on and on and on.

261
00:20:32,074 --> 00:20:35,141
He hadn't the mentality, I suppose,
to think for himself.

262
00:20:35,220 --> 00:20:36,639
He just obeyed orders.

263
00:20:36,716 --> 00:20:42,084
And he came at you with everything he
had, even if it meant losing his life.

264
00:20:42,164 --> 00:20:44,422
He just... he didn't care about life.

265
00:20:45,232 --> 00:20:47,763
We were taught from the very beginning

266
00:20:47,841 --> 00:20:52,172
that we must...
our life is the emperor's.

267
00:20:52,291 --> 00:20:57,157
For instance, when I left for war duty,

268
00:20:57,240 --> 00:20:59,269
I had to clip my nails and hair

269
00:20:59,350 --> 00:21:01,335
and write a last will and testament,

270
00:21:01,421 --> 00:21:02,872
because from that moment

271
00:21:02,994 --> 00:21:05,634
our lives are in the emperor's hands.

272
00:21:05,718 --> 00:21:07,136
In other words,

273
00:21:07,214 --> 00:21:10,083
my family will put that in the urn

274
00:21:10,168 --> 00:21:12,731
in case my body is not recovered.

275
00:21:12,814 --> 00:21:16,142
So our training
is to die for the emperor, you see.

276
00:21:33,146 --> 00:21:35,710
(mournful Japanese song)

277
00:22:03,759 --> 00:22:09,509
We had what we called officers' clubs,
where there were Japanese geishas.

278
00:22:09,590 --> 00:22:12,121
These were mostly for officer grade.

279
00:22:12,198 --> 00:22:19,639
For the other ranks, we had
what you might call "comfort girls".

280
00:22:20,715 --> 00:22:26,344
And, of course,
in the officers' parties you all drank -

281
00:22:27,236 --> 00:22:30,989
the thing was to get drunk
very quickly, sing songs,

282
00:22:31,072 --> 00:22:33,363
and because of
the limitation of the girls,

283
00:22:33,451 --> 00:22:36,134
only the high officers got them later.

284
00:22:36,213 --> 00:22:38,122
But the songs would be like...

285
00:22:38,207 --> 00:22:41,732
I think the English have a song
called "Roll Me Over in the Clover",

286
00:22:41,813 --> 00:22:43,918
and you go "One, two, three, four..."

287
00:22:44,000 --> 00:22:47,753
Our songs are very similar - it's always
"One, two, three," like this.

288
00:22:47,836 --> 00:22:50,825
And similar in content, too.

289
00:22:50,905 --> 00:22:56,153
For the enlisted men,
our entertainment...

290
00:22:56,237 --> 00:23:01,682
Because you're entertaining only
between battles or on one day's leave,

291
00:23:01,761 --> 00:23:06,398
and you may die next day, we don't have
much time for any lengthy entertainment,

292
00:23:06,480 --> 00:23:09,546
we go straight to the comfort girls.

293
00:23:09,626 --> 00:23:15,332
You pay your money and you come out
feeling refreshed and like a new man.

294
00:23:17,183 --> 00:23:19,746
Most of the comfort girls
for the enlisted men,

295
00:23:19,830 --> 00:23:21,127
many were Koreans,

296
00:23:21,211 --> 00:23:23,349
and I must say
I respect all of them very much,

297
00:23:23,436 --> 00:23:25,847
because who else
would come to the front line

298
00:23:25,929 --> 00:23:29,879
to give us the last entertainment

299
00:23:29,957 --> 00:23:33,252
for many of us on this earth?

300
00:23:33,371 --> 00:23:37,201
(narrator) The British had their own,
very different, entertainment.

301
00:23:37,284 --> 00:23:39,346
(Vera Lynn)
Burma was the furthest point

302
00:23:39,433 --> 00:23:41,888
and very few artists were going there,

303
00:23:41,964 --> 00:23:43,994
so I said, "Right, that's for me."

304
00:23:44,113 --> 00:23:48,139
They thought they were the forgotten
army and I think they probably were.

305
00:23:48,256 --> 00:23:53,078
In fact, just for them to see me
was quite a lot to them,

306
00:23:53,166 --> 00:23:58,185
because that I had gone
to all the trouble

307
00:23:58,268 --> 00:24:01,487
and travelled so far just to see them

308
00:24:01,567 --> 00:24:05,932
made them feel that they weren't
a long way from home, you know.

309
00:24:06,055 --> 00:24:08,511
If I could pop on a plane
and nip out there,

310
00:24:08,587 --> 00:24:12,068
they weren't too far away
and not forgotten.

311
00:24:12,155 --> 00:24:16,486
(narrator) In this jungle stalemate,
the message was certainly welcome.

312
00:24:16,567 --> 00:24:19,665
( "It's a Lovely Day Tomorrow")

313
00:24:31,911 --> 00:24:39,352
It's a lovely day tomorrow

314
00:24:39,430 --> 00:24:45,715
Tomorrow is a lovely day

315
00:24:45,798 --> 00:24:52,508
Come and feast
your tear-dimmed eyes

316
00:24:52,588 --> 00:24:59,179
On tomorrow's clear blue skies

317
00:24:59,301 --> 00:25:06,317
If today your heart is weary

318
00:25:06,398 --> 00:25:12,334
If every little thing looks grey

319
00:25:12,421 --> 00:25:16,403
Just forget your troubles

320
00:25:16,487 --> 00:25:22,346
And learn to say

321
00:25:22,970 --> 00:25:34,853
Tomorrow is a lovely day

322
00:25:40,770 --> 00:25:43,716
(narrator) October 1943.
Things are looking up.

323
00:25:43,801 --> 00:25:46,638
Lord Louis Mountbatten arrives
as supreme commander

324
00:25:46,716 --> 00:25:49,400
of a newly created
Southeast Asia Command.

325
00:25:49,478 --> 00:25:54,541
His mission: to end the stalemate
and knock out the Japanese.

326
00:25:56,614 --> 00:26:00,094
Mountbatten's immediate aim
was to rebuild morale

327
00:26:00,181 --> 00:26:05,277
in an army that felt itself forgotten
and wondered why it was there.

328
00:26:05,360 --> 00:26:11,110
"We shall march, fight and fly
through the monsoon," he declared.

329
00:26:12,380 --> 00:26:16,100
Another new appointment:
General Bill Slim,

330
00:26:16,216 --> 00:26:19,435
commander
of the newly formed 14th Army.

331
00:26:19,515 --> 00:26:23,345
He knew Burma,
and he knew the Japanese.

332
00:26:29,605 --> 00:26:33,969
Bill Slim was essentially
a soldier's general.

333
00:26:35,014 --> 00:26:37,272
Watchful of his troops' well-being,

334
00:26:37,354 --> 00:26:40,954
he wanted them fit
and ready to go over to the attack.

335
00:26:44,566 --> 00:26:48,701
Bless 'em all, bless 'em all

336
00:26:48,785 --> 00:26:52,888
The long and the short
and the tall...

337
00:26:52,967 --> 00:26:56,447
(narrator) "The long and the short
and the tall" were, in this case,

338
00:26:56,534 --> 00:26:58,673
two-thirds of them Indian troops.

339
00:27:00,562 --> 00:27:04,469
Cos we're saying goodbye to them all

340
00:27:04,552 --> 00:27:08,272
As back to their billets they crawl

341
00:27:08,350 --> 00:27:12,376
You 'll get no promotion
this side of the ocean

342
00:27:12,454 --> 00:27:16,361
So cheer up, my lads
Bless 'em all

343
00:27:17,096 --> 00:27:18,972
(narrator) Malaria.

344
00:27:19,053 --> 00:27:21,420
At the First Arakan
th is, and other diseases,

345
00:27:21,508 --> 00:27:25,839
had claimed 120 victims
to every battle casualty.

346
00:27:25,919 --> 00:27:28,024
(man) I had malaria 17 times.

347
00:27:28,106 --> 00:27:30,714
The last time they thought
I had spinal malaria -

348
00:27:30,791 --> 00:27:33,432
I couldn't walk
and I couldn't even move my arms.

349
00:27:33,553 --> 00:27:38,616
And I was getting inoculations all day
and every day, three times a day.

350
00:27:39,269 --> 00:27:41,680
(narrator)
To stamp out the scourge at source,

351
00:27:41,763 --> 00:27:44,446
clouds of a new insecticide, DDT,

352
00:27:44,525 --> 00:27:47,699
were sprayed over
the swampy breeding grounds.

353
00:27:58,105 --> 00:28:02,469
December 1943:
a second offensive at Arakan.

354
00:28:03,399 --> 00:28:05,690
The Japanese counter-attacked.

355
00:28:05,815 --> 00:28:07,801
One enemy force advanced north,

356
00:28:07,887 --> 00:28:09,381
wheeled behind the British,

357
00:28:09,460 --> 00:28:11,915
and turned west to capture Ngakyedauk -

358
00:28:11,992 --> 00:28:14,632
or "Okedoke" - Pass.

359
00:28:14,715 --> 00:28:19,309
Another split the British divisions
and encircled one of them.

360
00:28:26,147 --> 00:28:31,930
British and Indian units, trapped in
a small enclave, fought for their lives.

361
00:28:35,546 --> 00:28:38,458
Isolated groups fought on, surrounded.

362
00:28:41,223 --> 00:28:44,943
The skeleton force held out
against an entire Japanese division

363
00:28:45,021 --> 00:28:48,621
in what came to be known
as "The Admin Box".

364
00:28:48,742 --> 00:28:53,456
Clerks, mechanics, drivers,
even a general, joined in.

365
00:28:54,727 --> 00:28:58,600
In the first Arakan operation,
the troops had withdrawn.

366
00:28:58,678 --> 00:29:03,467
Now, on Slim's express orders,
there was no withdrawal.

367
00:29:04,509 --> 00:29:07,378
They were supplied from the air.

368
00:29:11,069 --> 00:29:15,586
By day and night, the planes
of Troop Carrier Command flew in

369
00:29:15,672 --> 00:29:18,280
to drop essential stores.

370
00:29:25,684 --> 00:29:31,510
What seemed certain defeat was
averted by this tactic of air supply.

371
00:29:40,032 --> 00:29:41,329
Casualties were heavy.

372
00:29:41,451 --> 00:29:45,510
The wounded were tended
in improvised dressing stations.

373
00:29:45,594 --> 00:29:51,191
Surgeons performed major operations
in sweating heat, plagued by flies.

374
00:29:51,272 --> 00:29:53,410
(flies buzzing)

375
00:30:11,335 --> 00:30:15,131
At one field hospital, doctors,
medical orderlies and wounded alike

376
00:30:15,209 --> 00:30:17,926
were butchered by Japanese.

377
00:30:24,186 --> 00:30:26,749
The sufferings of prisoners
taken by the Japanese

378
00:30:26,833 --> 00:30:29,047
also stirred the troops to fury.

379
00:30:36,461 --> 00:30:39,865
Thousands of Allied prisoners of war
slaved and died

380
00:30:39,952 --> 00:30:41,938
building the Burma Railway.

381
00:30:42,753 --> 00:30:47,390
(man) They captured us,
and from then on we were no longer men.

382
00:30:48,891 --> 00:30:53,680
(man #2) They literally
despised us for giving in.

383
00:30:55,450 --> 00:30:57,665
(man #1) We didn't have the food.

384
00:30:57,752 --> 00:31:01,963
We had to work
anything up to 16, 18 hours a day.

385
00:31:06,997 --> 00:31:09,408
(man #2) If you argued with one,
if you hit one,

386
00:31:09,491 --> 00:31:13,855
you automatically got six set about you.

387
00:31:15,590 --> 00:31:19,147
And they thought nothing of beating you
until your arm was broke

388
00:31:19,235 --> 00:31:22,104
or your leg was broke.

389
00:31:22,188 --> 00:31:26,749
(man #1) They'd stand him outside
the guard room in the blazing sun,

390
00:31:26,869 --> 00:31:30,043
take a great delight in pricking him
with a bayonet point

391
00:31:30,129 --> 00:31:32,388
to make him stand upright.

392
00:31:37,380 --> 00:31:39,747
(man #3) There were men
with terrible ulcers,

393
00:31:39,835 --> 00:31:43,632
and the only treatment they had
was dropping maggots onto the ulcers

394
00:31:43,709 --> 00:31:47,386
and letting the maggots eat out the pus
and clean the ulcers out.

395
00:31:47,469 --> 00:31:50,643
That's the only treatment
we had for them.

396
00:31:50,730 --> 00:31:55,748
(man #1) To find a chap that was
12 stone down to about five stone

397
00:31:55,832 --> 00:31:59,628
and crawling about trying to beg
for food or scrambling for food...

398
00:31:59,706 --> 00:32:02,848
I mean, it took some living with.

399
00:32:03,504 --> 00:32:07,486
(man #4) At that time
I was going to the toilet on all fours

400
00:32:07,570 --> 00:32:10,254
cos my bowels had dropped.

401
00:32:10,332 --> 00:32:13,322
(man #2) The latrines were concrete -

402
00:32:13,401 --> 00:32:17,612
the top was just
one absolute sea of maggots.

403
00:32:17,736 --> 00:32:20,758
This chap in particular
was in such a bad way -

404
00:32:20,843 --> 00:32:22,873
I think it was cerebral malaria -

405
00:32:22,953 --> 00:32:28,627
that they found him with his head
down there. He'd committed suicide.

406
00:32:32,889 --> 00:32:35,955
(man #1) A very close friend of mine,
in my own regiment,

407
00:32:36,035 --> 00:32:40,704
he'd suffered from everything
from beriberi, cholera...

408
00:32:41,328 --> 00:32:47,766
When he died, he was just skin -
skin over a skeleton and nothing else.

409
00:32:47,888 --> 00:32:50,834
His legs had been eaten away
with ulcers.

410
00:32:50,919 --> 00:32:54,868
And there was just nothing of him.
I only just recognised him.

411
00:32:59,972 --> 00:33:03,692
And there were 16,000 died
just on the railway.

412
00:33:03,770 --> 00:33:07,490
For every sleeper that was laid,
there was a human life given up.

413
00:33:07,568 --> 00:33:11,321
With the proper food, proper treatment,
we could have carried on,

414
00:33:11,442 --> 00:33:14,967
built their blasted railway
and thought nothing of it.

415
00:33:20,649 --> 00:33:25,974
(man #2) I could never understand
people being like that -

416
00:33:26,749 --> 00:33:31,036
so terrible in things that they'd done,

417
00:33:32,043 --> 00:33:34,835
and the sadistic nature of them.

418
00:33:34,920 --> 00:33:40,364
Thinking of this, I felt sorry for 'em
as much as anything.

419
00:33:47,080 --> 00:33:48,345
(gunshots)

420
00:33:57,783 --> 00:34:01,765
(narrator) Japanese troops
would die rather than surrender,

421
00:34:01,849 --> 00:34:04,839
dig themselves in, resist to the end.

422
00:34:05,455 --> 00:34:07,714
But now, a change.

423
00:34:08,831 --> 00:34:13,010
At Arakan, some Japanese
gave themselves up. They'd had enough.

424
00:34:13,089 --> 00:34:18,611
The superman myth was exploded -
these troops were not unbeatable.

425
00:34:18,690 --> 00:34:23,098
But many Japanese wounded
still took the traditional way out.

426
00:34:23,217 --> 00:34:27,014
(Okada) It was almost impossible
to take care of the wounded,

427
00:34:27,091 --> 00:34:28,618
and the wounded, knowing this,

428
00:34:28,703 --> 00:34:32,958
would ask their comrades to give them
a grenade so they can commit suicide,

429
00:34:33,037 --> 00:34:35,601
and maybe three or four wounded
who could not walk

430
00:34:35,684 --> 00:34:39,012
could commit suicide that way.

431
00:34:45,352 --> 00:34:48,876
(man) We picked up a number of Japanese
who'd been badly shot up.

432
00:34:48,996 --> 00:34:52,869
It was quite necessary in our field
hospitals to tie their hands down,

433
00:34:52,947 --> 00:34:54,595
because if you didn't do that,

434
00:34:54,673 --> 00:34:58,274
they merely tore at their bandages,
opened their wounds

435
00:34:58,356 --> 00:35:01,836
and literally tried to commit suicide.

436
00:35:08,445 --> 00:35:09,939
(narrator) Late in 1943,

437
00:35:10,056 --> 00:35:12,238
from Ledo on the India-Burma border,

438
00:35:12,320 --> 00:35:14,502
Stilwell and the Chinese advanced

439
00:35:14,583 --> 00:35:16,722
to open the way for a new route,

440
00:35:16,808 --> 00:35:17,833
the Ledo Road,

441
00:35:17,921 --> 00:35:20,987
joining the old Burma Road at Bhamo.

442
00:35:22,946 --> 00:35:25,357
The Chinese had to fight
to clear the path

443
00:35:25,439 --> 00:35:28,810
which would lead them back to China.

444
00:35:30,465 --> 00:35:35,757
Stilwell's two divisions went ahead,
seeking out the enemy.

445
00:35:55,438 --> 00:36:01,297
Edging southeastwards, in three hard
months they killed 4,000 Japanese.

446
00:36:05,873 --> 00:36:09,975
Behind them came the engineers,
blasting as they went...

447
00:36:14,274 --> 00:36:19,795
and, in their thousands, the labourers
who would build the highway.

448
00:36:27,624 --> 00:36:31,104
The Ledo Road, driven hundreds of miles
through atrocious country,

449
00:36:31,191 --> 00:36:35,021
was to ensure continued supplies
to China.

450
00:36:38,326 --> 00:36:42,767
For Stilwell's troops, conditions
were as hard as anywhere in Burma.

451
00:36:51,791 --> 00:36:54,628
From Wingate, too, a new offensive.

452
00:36:54,707 --> 00:36:56,540
Promoted general, he was to lead,

453
00:36:56,625 --> 00:36:59,538
despite opposition
from more orthodox colleagues,

454
00:36:59,655 --> 00:37:03,213
a second Chindit expedition
to the interior.

455
00:37:03,300 --> 00:37:07,969
They flew in
and were again supplied from the air.

456
00:37:09,323 --> 00:37:12,726
March 1944: Operation Thursday.

457
00:37:13,197 --> 00:37:19,285
Air transport for 10,000 men
and 1,000 pack animals, with stores,

458
00:37:19,412 --> 00:37:23,438
to jungle sites deep in enemy territory.

459
00:37:50,216 --> 00:37:54,930
Landing so many gliders in rough,
hostile country was a formidable hazard.

460
00:37:55,894 --> 00:37:58,960
Guerrilla fighting was new
to most of them.

461
00:37:59,039 --> 00:38:03,142
In spite of their training,
this was a venture into the unknown.

462
00:38:35,905 --> 00:38:41,611
(Calvert) The second Wingate operation
was ten times the size of the first.

463
00:38:41,736 --> 00:38:48,064
The object was, in effect, to cut the
lines of communication of the Japanese.

464
00:38:48,180 --> 00:38:53,702
North Burma's like a great bowl
with mountains all the way round

465
00:38:53,781 --> 00:38:59,226
and communications
running to the rim of the bowl.

466
00:38:59,305 --> 00:39:03,790
We fanned out
to cut these lines of communication.

467
00:39:08,359 --> 00:39:12,079
(narrator) The Chindits were
on their own, marooned in mid-Burma,

468
00:39:12,156 --> 00:39:14,687
hundreds of miles from their base.

469
00:39:14,765 --> 00:39:20,515
But now it wasn't hit and run.
This time they fought pitched battles.

470
00:39:46,030 --> 00:39:48,593
(aircraft overhead)

471
00:39:50,096 --> 00:39:55,039
Bombers were called in time and
time again to save a tricky situation.

472
00:39:56,924 --> 00:40:01,835
Early on, the leader, Wingate,
was killed in an air crash.

473
00:40:02,832 --> 00:40:05,091
The operation went on.

474
00:40:06,476 --> 00:40:10,077
(man) We just marched
on our own two feet with muleteers.

475
00:40:10,198 --> 00:40:14,179
If we was taken ill, we were just
sort of slung across the pony

476
00:40:14,264 --> 00:40:17,057
till such time
as your temperature went down,

477
00:40:17,141 --> 00:40:19,705
and after about two days
you was slung off the pony

478
00:40:19,788 --> 00:40:23,737
and another unfortunate got put on.

479
00:40:25,734 --> 00:40:28,876
(man #2) Any units
operating in those circumstances

480
00:40:28,956 --> 00:40:30,832
have to be mobile all the time,

481
00:40:30,913 --> 00:40:34,862
and wounded, of course,
immediately bring you to a halt.

482
00:40:34,941 --> 00:40:39,349
Fortunately, Wingate was able to obtain
assistance from the United States

483
00:40:39,467 --> 00:40:42,260
and we were given
some remarkable aircraft,

484
00:40:42,345 --> 00:40:45,214
which was
a very short take-off/landing aircraft

485
00:40:45,337 --> 00:40:50,738
and could get into any little valley
or bit of paddy field and so on,

486
00:40:50,822 --> 00:40:53,081
and evacuate our wounded for us.

487
00:40:54,735 --> 00:40:56,797
(narrator) Long weeks in the jungle -

488
00:40:56,884 --> 00:41:02,285
weeks of dysentery, jaundice,
jungle sores and malaria.

489
00:41:02,369 --> 00:41:08,043
Aircraft like this meant rescue
for thousands, sick as well as wounded.

490
00:41:11,192 --> 00:41:15,099
The Chindits killed Japanese
where they thought they were safe,

491
00:41:15,182 --> 00:41:19,896
and forced them
to divert troops from other purposes.

492
00:41:20,016 --> 00:41:24,762
Fighting without respite in these
conditions told on the toughest.

493
00:41:24,849 --> 00:41:28,569
(Calvert) Most of the brigades,
through casualties and disease -

494
00:41:28,647 --> 00:41:33,012
they'd been behind the lines
for four to five months - were finished.

495
00:41:33,174 --> 00:41:39,732
My own brigade had only 300 fit men
out of the 4,000 who originally came in.

496
00:41:46,984 --> 00:41:52,308
(narrator) Meanwhile, pushing down
from the north were Merrill's Marauders.

497
00:41:55,577 --> 00:41:58,337
Named after their leader,
Brigadier General Merrill,

498
00:41:58,454 --> 00:42:01,825
the Marauders were American volunteers.

499
00:42:05,091 --> 00:42:09,498
Among their targets,
the important airfield of Myitkyina.

500
00:42:09,579 --> 00:42:13,605
But the Japanese again
had launched an offensive themselves.

501
00:42:13,684 --> 00:42:17,316
In March 1944,
three divisions crossed the Chindwin

502
00:42:17,405 --> 00:42:21,540
to attack Kohima and Imphal
inside India itself.

503
00:42:21,624 --> 00:42:23,806
One division struck towards Kohima,

504
00:42:23,888 --> 00:42:25,153
two towards Imphal.

505
00:42:25,230 --> 00:42:26,681
They advanced rapidly,

506
00:42:26,765 --> 00:42:29,482
threatening to isolate both objectives.

507
00:42:29,565 --> 00:42:32,053
(man speaking Japanese)

508
00:42:32,174 --> 00:42:34,662
(interpreter)
From the Chindwin river to Michan

509
00:42:34,782 --> 00:42:36,844
there are many precipitous mountains

510
00:42:36,931 --> 00:42:39,145
sticking out
like the fingers of the hand.

511
00:42:39,232 --> 00:42:44,862
We advanced, climbing up and down
these steep mountains.

512
00:42:45,293 --> 00:42:49,046
On the map, the distance
is only about 150 kilometres,

513
00:42:49,130 --> 00:42:52,501
but when the mountains and valleys
were taken into consideration

514
00:42:52,582 --> 00:42:55,648
it was about 300 km.

515
00:42:55,728 --> 00:42:59,787
Without rest or sleep,
it took us 13 days to reach Michan,

516
00:42:59,871 --> 00:43:02,326
where we cut the road.

517
00:43:03,669 --> 00:43:07,193
(narrator) For the Japanese,
Kohima was a tempting prize.

518
00:43:07,275 --> 00:43:12,064
Its capture would cut the Allies'
supply line to the great base at Imphal.

519
00:43:18,745 --> 00:43:24,113
The British air crews flew dangerous
sorties to prevent their advance.

520
00:43:33,706 --> 00:43:36,073
(bombs explode)

521
00:43:43,143 --> 00:43:45,783
But the columns came on.

522
00:43:56,838 --> 00:44:00,973
Steadily, the enemy
tightened their circle round Kohima.

523
00:44:01,096 --> 00:44:06,006
They squeezed the small garrison
into a tiny central area.

524
00:44:06,083 --> 00:44:10,338
Losses were heavy,
reinforcements desperately needed.

525
00:44:10,495 --> 00:44:13,866
I sent the 2nd British Division
down to support

526
00:44:13,947 --> 00:44:17,395
the fighting at Kohima,
and they went into Kohima.

527
00:44:17,476 --> 00:44:19,843
The front line was on either side

528
00:44:19,932 --> 00:44:23,379
of the district commissioner's
tennis court.

529
00:44:23,461 --> 00:44:25,643
They stood shoulder to shoulder.

530
00:44:25,724 --> 00:44:28,823
Where they were killed,
they were buried.

531
00:44:28,947 --> 00:44:32,928
Out of three British infantry brigades,

532
00:44:33,013 --> 00:44:37,879
two brigadiers killed, two brigadiers'
replacements seriously wounded.

533
00:44:37,962 --> 00:44:40,525
That's what the fighting was like
in Kohima.

534
00:44:40,608 --> 00:44:43,860
They attacked us at the tennis courts,

535
00:44:43,946 --> 00:44:48,234
and it was just like playing tennis -

536
00:44:48,319 --> 00:44:50,501
so much so that I believe that the area

537
00:44:50,582 --> 00:44:53,113
from one side of a tennis court
to the other

538
00:44:53,191 --> 00:44:57,905
was the positions between the Japanese
and the platoon I was with.

539
00:44:57,986 --> 00:45:02,045
The fighting I saw was literally
hundreds at a time coming towards us.

540
00:45:02,168 --> 00:45:05,037
The manpower strength
just pushed us back

541
00:45:05,160 --> 00:45:08,684
from one trench
to a trench ten foot behind us.

542
00:45:08,766 --> 00:45:12,563
Eventually they kept overrunning us
due to the manpower.

543
00:45:13,791 --> 00:45:16,628
(narrator) Kohima was
the ordinary soldier's battle.

544
00:45:16,707 --> 00:45:21,147
Small groups of Japanese and British
fought hand to hand.

545
00:45:25,376 --> 00:45:27,743
(Brown) Every one of us was frightened.

546
00:45:27,832 --> 00:45:32,927
If we put our hands up and surrendered,
our battalion would have been finished.

547
00:45:33,010 --> 00:45:37,298
We knew that if the Japs had got us,
they would have shot us and tortured us,

548
00:45:37,384 --> 00:45:40,373
Iike they did do to some of our boys.

549
00:45:40,453 --> 00:45:44,249
So we stayed in the holes
and prayed to God.

550
00:45:44,327 --> 00:45:47,164
After the first seven or eight days

551
00:45:47,243 --> 00:45:50,646
the ammunition, the food,
was running out.

552
00:45:50,733 --> 00:45:53,144
Water was almost non-existent.

553
00:45:53,227 --> 00:45:57,667
Then we was told the 2nd All-British
was on their way to get us out.

554
00:46:03,891 --> 00:46:07,873
(narrator) At last they got there.
The British were now struggling

555
00:46:07,958 --> 00:46:11,286
to force the Japanese
back from the ridge they had seized,

556
00:46:11,372 --> 00:46:14,743
and a continuous artillery duel went on.

557
00:46:18,162 --> 00:46:23,716
The Japanese had started with a force
of 15,000 against a garrison of 3,500.

558
00:46:39,645 --> 00:46:41,554
When the British supplies dwindled,

559
00:46:41,639 --> 00:46:44,399
they were replenished
entirely from the air.

560
00:46:48,046 --> 00:46:49,998
(man) I think everyone on the ground

561
00:46:50,079 --> 00:46:54,214
felt just how much they owed
to these aircrews

562
00:46:54,299 --> 00:46:58,128
who were going flat throughout the day
and sometimes during the night.

563
00:46:58,212 --> 00:47:00,578
And at that time of the war

564
00:47:00,667 --> 00:47:03,885
there weren't that number
of spare crews around,

565
00:47:03,966 --> 00:47:09,258
so that each crew had its aircraft
and that aircraft had to be kept flying,

566
00:47:09,375 --> 00:47:12,822
and they were going absolutely flat out.

567
00:47:18,390 --> 00:47:21,761
(narrator) Kohima was relieved
after seven weeks.

568
00:47:21,881 --> 00:47:25,055
The troops could now see
the suicidal price

569
00:47:25,141 --> 00:47:28,622
the Japanese had paid
in their bid to capture it.

570
00:47:28,709 --> 00:47:30,662
(man) They were fanatics.

571
00:47:30,742 --> 00:47:33,382
When I say fanatics,
you could be holding a position

572
00:47:33,504 --> 00:47:35,992
and they're about
30 yards away from you,

573
00:47:36,074 --> 00:47:39,599
and all of a sudden they'd come
flying at you, shouting and yelling.

574
00:47:39,680 --> 00:47:43,161
It always amazed us -
or amazed me, rather -

575
00:47:43,248 --> 00:47:46,881
how anybody could come flying
out of the jungle expecting to kill you

576
00:47:46,969 --> 00:47:48,879
who was shouting at you.

577
00:47:48,964 --> 00:47:53,372
I know it unnerves you and all that,
but you can get used to this eventually.

578
00:47:53,452 --> 00:47:57,631
And when we did get used to it,
we took a great toll of the Japanese.

579
00:47:57,710 --> 00:48:01,235
We just held fire and got aim and said,
"You shout on, lad, you come on."

580
00:48:01,316 --> 00:48:04,797
And they came on and
they filled up in front of our trenches,

581
00:48:04,884 --> 00:48:07,797
our little weapon pits.

582
00:48:10,255 --> 00:48:14,051
(man #2) Fighting the Japanese
was totally committed war.

583
00:48:14,129 --> 00:48:19,072
There was no question of heroics,
mock-heroics or chivalry

584
00:48:19,154 --> 00:48:24,632
in the sense that one read about
prior to the war with Biggles.

585
00:48:24,717 --> 00:48:30,161
We were totally committed
to killing as many Japanese as possible,

586
00:48:30,241 --> 00:48:34,190
probably prompted by the fact
that we knew from bitter experience

587
00:48:34,269 --> 00:48:36,102
that there had been atrocities,

588
00:48:36,187 --> 00:48:38,216
and we were always fearful of the fact

589
00:48:38,335 --> 00:48:41,325
that we didn't wish
to be taken prisoner.

590
00:48:43,476 --> 00:48:46,847
(Brown) I seen one of my lads
tied up with Dannert wire.

591
00:48:46,928 --> 00:48:49,416
I don't want to see it no more.

592
00:48:50,342 --> 00:48:55,744
It was impossible
to feel sorry or pitiful for'em,

593
00:48:55,828 --> 00:48:59,276
because we knew what they done
to our boys.

594
00:49:01,314 --> 00:49:06,868
They didn't give us a chance,
and we didn't give them a chance.

595
00:49:21,262 --> 00:49:25,473
(narrator) After Kohima,
the relief of Imphal.

596
00:49:25,558 --> 00:49:30,883
Fighting there had been as bloody
as at Kohima - and as heroic.

597
00:49:30,967 --> 00:49:35,953
The Japanese now had to be cleared
from the Kohima-Imphal road.

598
00:49:40,711 --> 00:49:45,501
In July 1944,
the Japanese broke off the offensive.

599
00:49:46,696 --> 00:49:51,758
Kohima and Imphal had been
the high point of the Japanese effort.

600
00:49:52,949 --> 00:49:56,506
"They will never come back,"
said General Slim.

601
00:50:06,414 --> 00:50:10,014
On Stilwell's front,
the Chinese, with Merrill's Marauders,

602
00:50:10,135 --> 00:50:12,316
had taken Myitkyina airfield -

603
00:50:12,398 --> 00:50:15,267
but with heavy casualties.

604
00:50:15,352 --> 00:50:19,607
Under monsoon skies,
more wounds to be dressed.

605
00:50:22,832 --> 00:50:24,742
(thunder)

606
00:50:35,645 --> 00:50:40,391
Mountbatten had said the troops
would fight through the monsoon.

607
00:50:40,479 --> 00:50:42,005
Now, in the deluge,

608
00:50:42,090 --> 00:50:45,493
they were driving the Japanese back
across the Burmese frontier.

609
00:50:45,581 --> 00:50:49,105
Ahead, the long road
they had come two years before:

610
00:50:49,187 --> 00:50:53,398
Mandalay, Rangoon,
and much bitter fighting.

611
00:50:54,711 --> 00:50:56,663
There would be no rest

612
00:50:56,744 --> 00:51:02,418
till all the Japanese in Burma
were defeated and destroyed.
