1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,672
== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==

2
00:01:31,626 --> 00:01:34,615
(narrator) The Atlantic.
Britain's lifeline.

3
00:01:36,958 --> 00:01:39,097
Treacherous enough in peacetime,

4
00:01:39,183 --> 00:01:42,205
in war, black with menace.

5
00:01:46,012 --> 00:01:48,117
U-boat packs stalk through the night.

6
00:01:48,198 --> 00:01:52,639
Knowing the danger,
their victims still plough on.

7
00:01:55,027 --> 00:01:57,012
(speaking German)

8
00:02:25,601 --> 00:02:27,783
(narrator) Ships and cargoes go down.

9
00:02:27,864 --> 00:02:30,581
Their crews - some of them - survive,

10
00:02:30,665 --> 00:02:33,611
but early in 1943
it is Britain's survival

11
00:02:33,695 --> 00:02:37,983
and the Allied hopes for victory
over Germany which are in doubt.

12
00:03:36,186 --> 00:03:39,099
When war began,
Britain saw Germany's big ships

13
00:03:39,217 --> 00:03:41,202
as the main threat to her sea trade.

14
00:03:42,861 --> 00:03:44,923
So did the Germans.

15
00:03:57,784 --> 00:04:00,850
Germany's surface raiders
savaged the merchant fleet

16
00:04:00,930 --> 00:04:03,951
on which Britain depended
for much of her food,

17
00:04:04,037 --> 00:04:06,906
most of her raw materials,
and all of her oil.

18
00:04:15,469 --> 00:04:18,687
Germany's U-boats
were to operate in coastal waters,

19
00:04:18,768 --> 00:04:21,942
sweeping up anything left
by the battleships.

20
00:04:23,985 --> 00:04:26,745
Both Britain and Germany were wrong.

21
00:04:26,824 --> 00:04:30,195
The real naval menace
was to be the U-boat.

22
00:04:30,276 --> 00:04:34,870
At least one man knew this -
Karl Doenitz, chief of the U-boat arm.

23
00:04:34,956 --> 00:04:39,516
He could've been wrong too, if Hitler
had delayed his war with Britain

24
00:04:39,598 --> 00:04:44,082
until all the battleships planned
for the German Navy had been built.

25
00:04:44,278 --> 00:04:46,809
As it was, Doenitz was certain

26
00:04:46,887 --> 00:04:51,830
that with enough submarines,
he could win the war at sea.

27
00:04:51,912 --> 00:04:54,246
He had proved it to himself
20 years before.

28
00:04:54,329 --> 00:04:57,547
In October 1918,

29
00:04:57,628 --> 00:05:01,993
(Doenitz) I was captain of a submarine

30
00:05:02,078 --> 00:05:05,329
in the Mediterranean near Malta.

31
00:05:05,415 --> 00:05:10,401
In a dark night I met a British convoy

32
00:05:10,479 --> 00:05:13,807
with cruisers and destroyers

33
00:05:13,893 --> 00:05:15,955
and I attacked

34
00:05:16,042 --> 00:05:18,834
and I sank a ship,

35
00:05:18,919 --> 00:05:23,174
but the chance would have been
very much greater

36
00:05:23,254 --> 00:05:26,014
if there had been a lot of submarines.

37
00:05:26,092 --> 00:05:32,878
That's why the idea of a wolf pack,

38
00:05:32,959 --> 00:05:38,327
to put the submarines together
that they could attack together,

39
00:05:38,406 --> 00:05:41,472
was very impressive,

40
00:05:41,552 --> 00:05:47,607
and that's why in all the years
from 1918

41
00:05:47,690 --> 00:05:51,825
until the year 1935

42
00:05:51,910 --> 00:05:55,936
when we had the first submarines again
in the German Navy

43
00:05:56,014 --> 00:05:58,153
I never had forgotten this idea.

44
00:05:59,850 --> 00:06:04,029
(narrator) Underwater,
the 1939 U-boat was slow.

45
00:06:06,947 --> 00:06:11,541
On the surface, it was faster
than any convoy of merchant ships.

46
00:06:11,627 --> 00:06:16,875
With its low silhouette it could not
be seen easily, especially at night.

47
00:06:23,328 --> 00:06:27,965
But its targets were outlined clearly
against the sky...

48
00:06:30,233 --> 00:06:34,827
and with radio, the U-boats could
quickly assemble into hunting packs.

49
00:06:43,736 --> 00:06:47,685
Doenitz knew Britain would try
to protect essential Atlantic trade

50
00:06:47,764 --> 00:06:51,638
by a system of convoys
escorted by warships.

51
00:06:51,715 --> 00:06:55,043
To attack these convoys,
Doenitz wanted 300 U-boats.

52
00:06:55,168 --> 00:06:57,382
When the war started he had only 26.

53
00:06:57,470 --> 00:07:00,721
And these boats had long,
dangerous voyages from base

54
00:07:00,807 --> 00:07:03,338
before they could reach their targets.

55
00:07:04,298 --> 00:07:06,021
When France fell,

56
00:07:06,139 --> 00:07:09,620
Doenitz gained new bases
much nearer the shipping routes.

57
00:07:14,387 --> 00:07:19,057
His Sea Wolves returned
to these French ports as heroes.

58
00:07:20,755 --> 00:07:23,319
One especial hero was Otto Kretschmer.

59
00:07:23,402 --> 00:07:27,537
In all, Kretschmer sank over a quarter
of a million tons of British shipping.

60
00:07:27,622 --> 00:07:31,833
In October 1940,
he joined the first real wolf pack.

61
00:07:31,918 --> 00:07:37,395
I remember that there was a signal
that a convoy was coming in

62
00:07:37,481 --> 00:07:39,543
from America to England

63
00:07:40,128 --> 00:07:44,263
and that its position was not known

64
00:07:44,347 --> 00:07:49,017
and that Doenitz ordered
all the submarines there,

65
00:07:49,104 --> 00:07:51,243
to the west of Ireland,

66
00:07:51,329 --> 00:07:56,806
to form a sort of recce line,
a stationary recce line,

67
00:07:56,892 --> 00:08:00,066
to let the convoy pass through.

68
00:08:00,152 --> 00:08:03,829
And when the first submarine was sighted

69
00:08:03,912 --> 00:08:07,054
the convoy made a signal,
its contact signal,

70
00:08:07,134 --> 00:08:10,385
and this recce line
was dissolved automatically,

71
00:08:10,472 --> 00:08:13,690
and every boat was free
to go in for the attack.

72
00:08:14,845 --> 00:08:19,253
(narrator) Convoy SC-7,
on the night of 17 October 1940,

73
00:08:19,333 --> 00:08:21,318
was passing Rockall.

74
00:08:22,325 --> 00:08:25,926
34 merchantmen, four small escort ships.

75
00:08:26,047 --> 00:08:28,108
Seven U-boats attacked on the surface.

76
00:08:28,195 --> 00:08:32,864
The attack took the same form
as that we were used to,

77
00:08:32,952 --> 00:08:36,934
which was a single ship being struck.

78
00:08:37,747 --> 00:08:41,424
Very shortly after
that a second one was struck,

79
00:08:41,506 --> 00:08:46,678
and then, within a matter
of five to ten minutes,

80
00:08:46,762 --> 00:08:49,674
further ships were struck.

81
00:08:49,946 --> 00:08:54,615
I tried to get through the escorts
into the convoy,

82
00:08:54,703 --> 00:08:58,958
which was my own peculiarity
of attacking,

83
00:09:00,035 --> 00:09:03,253
and failed the first time.

84
00:09:03,334 --> 00:09:08,473
They saw me and shot star shells
so that I had to draw away again.

85
00:09:09,203 --> 00:09:13,153
But the second time I succeeded
and was inside the convoy

86
00:09:13,231 --> 00:09:19,167
going up and down the lanes looking
for the most important, valuable ships

87
00:09:19,254 --> 00:09:22,887
and had the opportunity
to expend all torpedoes.

88
00:09:22,975 --> 00:09:24,851
I had 12 in all.

89
00:09:26,389 --> 00:09:32,292
(Sherwood) I could see ships
in various stages of sinking.

90
00:09:32,412 --> 00:09:35,249
A Dutch ship had stopped

91
00:09:35,366 --> 00:09:38,388
and was attempting to pick up survivors,

92
00:09:38,473 --> 00:09:41,266
and whilst I actually
watched her doing this

93
00:09:41,350 --> 00:09:43,761
and was considering what to do about it,

94
00:09:43,844 --> 00:09:47,139
she also herself was torpedoed.

95
00:09:47,258 --> 00:09:51,055
This, along with another torpedoing,

96
00:09:52,360 --> 00:09:54,815
set the whole place ablaze.

97
00:09:55,813 --> 00:10:00,756
(narrator) That night 17 merchantmen,
exactly half the convoy, were sunk.

98
00:10:00,838 --> 00:10:03,784
The escorts had not been able
to damage a single U-boat.

99
00:10:03,869 --> 00:10:08,658
I don't think I had ever seen more
than one ship sunk at a time before,

100
00:10:08,779 --> 00:10:12,030
and this was something
very different indeed.

101
00:10:12,116 --> 00:10:15,836
This really was the first time

102
00:10:15,914 --> 00:10:21,162
that these tactics could be
experienced by all of us

103
00:10:21,246 --> 00:10:23,505
and also by Doenitz himself,

104
00:10:23,586 --> 00:10:27,219
who, of course, knew it
only from our peacetime training.

105
00:10:27,308 --> 00:10:30,177
And the whole night, I think,
was a success.

106
00:10:30,261 --> 00:10:33,208
It was called
the Night of the Long Knives

107
00:10:33,292 --> 00:10:35,626
because so many ships were sunk.

108
00:10:39,315 --> 00:10:41,922
(narrator)
In the first nine months of the war,

109
00:10:42,000 --> 00:10:46,059
the Allies lost over 2 million tons
of merchant shipping.

110
00:10:47,486 --> 00:10:50,857
In the next six months,
with the U-boats operating from France,

111
00:10:50,977 --> 00:10:54,228
nearly 2.5 million tons more went down.

112
00:11:02,102 --> 00:11:04,894
There were medals galore.

113
00:11:17,868 --> 00:11:21,119
U-boat crews called this
"the happy time".

114
00:11:21,666 --> 00:11:24,459
(man) I saw the ship going up,
the stern going underwater.

115
00:11:24,543 --> 00:11:26,910
She went right up on end,
then backwards.

116
00:11:26,998 --> 00:11:29,944
And I went down with her.
After a bit I came to the surface,

117
00:11:30,029 --> 00:11:33,203
and I was still sitting
on the overturned bridge boat,

118
00:11:33,289 --> 00:11:35,471
when I saw the submarine surfacing.

119
00:11:35,553 --> 00:11:39,077
He went round and started picking up
cases out of the water -

120
00:11:39,159 --> 00:11:44,603
general cargo, possibly spirits,
foodstuff and so forth.

121
00:11:45,105 --> 00:11:47,439
They looked at us,
circled round for a bit,

122
00:11:47,522 --> 00:11:50,085
laughed at us
and went away to the northeast.

123
00:11:50,169 --> 00:11:54,075
They never asked if we had any water,
if we had any damages or anything else.

124
00:11:54,158 --> 00:11:57,639
And we were left
floating amongst wreckage in one boat.

125
00:11:57,726 --> 00:12:01,054
We were halfway
between Brazil and North Africa.

126
00:12:01,178 --> 00:12:03,393
The only thing I could think about

127
00:12:03,480 --> 00:12:06,808
was trying to get to the land
as near as possible,

128
00:12:06,894 --> 00:12:10,375
so I set the course
as near as I could to the northeast.

129
00:12:10,539 --> 00:12:14,488
All we had was the one lifeboat,
which was made for 48 people.

130
00:12:14,567 --> 00:12:16,978
We picked up 58.

131
00:12:17,098 --> 00:12:21,124
There wasn't really room enough
for anybody to sit down.

132
00:12:21,203 --> 00:12:26,800
The boat was leaking badly through
being on the chocks for some time.

133
00:12:26,881 --> 00:12:30,601
You had quite a bit of trouble getting
the crew to move so you could bail,

134
00:12:30,678 --> 00:12:33,209
and you bailed for nearly two days

135
00:12:33,287 --> 00:12:38,382
until the wood of the boat
started to swell and to tighten up.

136
00:12:38,466 --> 00:12:41,029
After that it wasn't so bad.

137
00:12:41,113 --> 00:12:43,720
The worst days, of course,

138
00:12:43,798 --> 00:12:46,132
were when there was no wind.

139
00:12:46,215 --> 00:12:49,052
Absolutely becalmed.

140
00:12:49,130 --> 00:12:50,930
The sun was terrific.

141
00:12:51,010 --> 00:12:54,381
So we started off
by giving 4oz of water -

142
00:12:54,501 --> 00:12:58,450
2oz in the morning and 2oz at night -
and one biscuit.

143
00:12:58,529 --> 00:13:01,442
There was a lot of noise in the boat.
There were Chinese.

144
00:13:01,521 --> 00:13:03,397
I said, "What's all the bobbery?"

145
00:13:03,478 --> 00:13:06,238
Which is a lot of talky-talky,
you know.

146
00:13:06,316 --> 00:13:09,612
He said, "I think number one
fireman go crazy."

147
00:13:10,536 --> 00:13:14,901
So he eventually jumped over the side
with a lifejacket on.

148
00:13:14,986 --> 00:13:18,466
And after a wee while
we got him back again.

149
00:13:20,357 --> 00:13:24,797
And later that night in the darkness
he jumped again.

150
00:13:24,883 --> 00:13:28,986
We didn't get him back
because the sharks got him.

151
00:13:29,065 --> 00:13:30,712
On the morning of the 13th -

152
00:13:30,791 --> 00:13:34,773
I'd sit on the water barrel
to make sure nobody helped themselves -

153
00:13:34,896 --> 00:13:39,107
and somebody shook me and said, "Hey,
Captain, we see lights, green lights."

154
00:13:39,192 --> 00:13:42,105
"Oh," I said,
"you're dreaming, you're dreaming."

155
00:13:42,184 --> 00:13:44,792
And I looked round
and I saw some green lights.

156
00:13:44,870 --> 00:13:48,318
It looked to me like New Brighton pier.
I couldn't make it out.

157
00:13:48,399 --> 00:13:50,581
So I said, "Well, burn a flare."

158
00:13:50,662 --> 00:13:54,536
They burned a flare. Jimmy said,
"Burn another flare."

159
00:13:54,614 --> 00:13:56,523
They burned another flare.

160
00:13:56,608 --> 00:14:01,671
And after a bit I saw the green lights
getting closer. More visible.

161
00:14:01,749 --> 00:14:04,815
Then after a bit
I saw a red light above the green,

162
00:14:04,895 --> 00:14:08,113
and then it dawned on me
that it was a hospital ship.

163
00:14:10,304 --> 00:14:12,791
(narrator)
The U-boats had eyes in the air.

164
00:14:12,874 --> 00:14:17,238
Focke-Wulf Condor aircraft
could range 1,000 miles out to sea

165
00:14:17,324 --> 00:14:18,895
to scout for convoys.

166
00:14:23,423 --> 00:14:28,060
When used to bomb shipping,
the Condors sank 30 ships in two months.

167
00:14:28,142 --> 00:14:29,439
Luckily for Britain,

168
00:14:29,523 --> 00:14:33,396
this partnership with the U-boat
was never properly exploited.

169
00:14:36,811 --> 00:14:40,292
But Doenitz did exploit the fact
that German naval intelligence

170
00:14:40,417 --> 00:14:43,210
had broken the British codes.

171
00:14:44,982 --> 00:14:48,583
We were aware that the intelligence
for some reason was good,

172
00:14:48,665 --> 00:14:54,186
but I myself put this down
to very superior hydrophone equipment

173
00:14:54,266 --> 00:14:56,142
that the submarines had,

174
00:14:56,222 --> 00:14:58,982
that the U-boats had in their boats,

175
00:14:59,061 --> 00:15:03,087
probably being able to pick up
the noise of a convoy's propellers

176
00:15:03,166 --> 00:15:06,417
up to 80 or even 100 miles.

177
00:15:06,503 --> 00:15:08,533
But in addition,

178
00:15:08,613 --> 00:15:11,984
I know that they would place
their U-boats

179
00:15:12,066 --> 00:15:17,390
in a line across, at right angles
to the expected line of the convoy.

180
00:15:17,475 --> 00:15:23,727
And this line for, say, five U-boats,
could be 100 miles from end to end.

181
00:15:23,804 --> 00:15:25,909
And so with good hydrophones,

182
00:15:25,991 --> 00:15:31,054
very little disguise of the position
of a convoy could be effected.

183
00:15:31,131 --> 00:15:35,081
It was only after the war that we knew
that they were breaking the codes

184
00:15:35,159 --> 00:15:37,298
and that they knew very well

185
00:15:37,384 --> 00:15:40,406
the time of leaving port
that the convoys had

186
00:15:40,530 --> 00:15:42,635
and how many escorts there were

187
00:15:42,717 --> 00:15:45,629
and how many merchant ships
in each convoy.

188
00:15:45,709 --> 00:15:47,618
(ticking)

189
00:15:49,315 --> 00:15:50,995
(explosion)

190
00:15:57,371 --> 00:16:00,774
(narrator) The Royal Navy,
searching for U-boats underwater,

191
00:16:00,862 --> 00:16:04,964
had pinned its faith on asdic,
an echo-sounding device.

192
00:16:26,602 --> 00:16:29,668
But U-boats were attacking convoys
on the surface.

193
00:16:29,748 --> 00:16:31,733
The navy was not prepared for this.

194
00:16:31,858 --> 00:16:34,040
(man) Convoy defence
is not very glamorous

195
00:16:34,121 --> 00:16:36,652
and between the wars,
I think rather naturally,

196
00:16:36,730 --> 00:16:40,985
the navy were inclined to concentrate
on more glamorous activities

197
00:16:41,065 --> 00:16:43,552
Iike great mass torpedo attacks

198
00:16:43,635 --> 00:16:45,435
and that sort of thing.

199
00:16:45,515 --> 00:16:48,384
All the information about the lessons

200
00:16:48,468 --> 00:16:50,760
of World War I were available.

201
00:16:50,885 --> 00:16:54,256
For those who wanted to read them,
the lessons were there.

202
00:16:54,376 --> 00:16:56,252
But I'm afraid no one bothered.

203
00:16:56,333 --> 00:17:00,740
And as a result trade defence
as a whole, was very badly neglected.

204
00:17:00,821 --> 00:17:03,188
(narrator) The neglect continued.

205
00:17:03,276 --> 00:17:06,800
In the early days,
convoys could only be escorted

206
00:17:06,882 --> 00:17:10,133
for about 300 miles
from each Atlantic coast.

207
00:17:14,439 --> 00:17:17,385
There just weren't enough escort ships.

208
00:17:17,470 --> 00:17:21,801
Those available lacked endurance and
their crews were virtually untrained.

209
00:17:21,881 --> 00:17:25,252
(Sherwood)
My officers were RNVR officers.

210
00:17:25,334 --> 00:17:29,087
One was a civil engineer by profession.

211
00:17:29,170 --> 00:17:33,959
The other two were
Canadian sublieutenants,

212
00:17:35,001 --> 00:17:39,911
both of the age of between 20 and 21,

213
00:17:39,988 --> 00:17:43,130
who had come from Canada as passengers

214
00:17:43,210 --> 00:17:47,269
and that was their seagoing experience.

215
00:17:47,353 --> 00:17:51,641
The heads of department were regulars -

216
00:17:51,727 --> 00:17:54,673
some of them had retired
and called back -

217
00:17:54,757 --> 00:17:59,394
and there were two or three seamen
who were of the pukka service,

218
00:17:59,476 --> 00:18:02,694
and the rest were straight in.

219
00:18:10,409 --> 00:18:14,315
(narrator)
Air cover was to prove all-important,

220
00:18:14,398 --> 00:18:17,923
but surprisingly the navy's carriers
did not at first supply it.

221
00:18:18,004 --> 00:18:21,757
That task went to the RAF, although
Coastal Command was ill prepared.

222
00:18:21,841 --> 00:18:26,205
(man) With the exception of Sunderland
flying boats, a very small number,

223
00:18:26,290 --> 00:18:29,586
all the other aircraft
except the Anson were lash-ups.

224
00:18:29,666 --> 00:18:33,648
They were borrowed
from entirely dissimilar functions

225
00:18:33,733 --> 00:18:35,947
in order to do this job
in Coastal Command.

226
00:18:36,034 --> 00:18:39,133
Secondly, the navigation aids
were not there.

227
00:18:39,295 --> 00:18:41,586
It was entirely dead-reckoning
navigation.

228
00:18:41,673 --> 00:18:44,740
And whereas an experienced navigator
can look at the sea,

229
00:18:44,857 --> 00:18:48,153
estimate the wind and where
he's likely to be in an hour's time,

230
00:18:48,233 --> 00:18:51,026
this is very difficult for a new boy.

231
00:18:51,110 --> 00:18:56,893
And since the point to be navigated to,
the convoy, was often equally at error,

232
00:18:57,018 --> 00:18:59,735
it was no wonder that we failed
to meet many convoys.

233
00:18:59,857 --> 00:19:04,451
So lack of equipment,
lack of training and unsuitable aircraft

234
00:19:04,575 --> 00:19:07,794
were certainly severe handicaps
at the beginning of the war.

235
00:19:07,874 --> 00:19:11,704
What is more, cooperation between
the navy and the air force in the field,

236
00:19:11,787 --> 00:19:15,846
while they're at sea,
was very bad indeed,

237
00:19:15,930 --> 00:19:20,218
mainly due to stupid quarrels
between senior officers in Whitehall.

238
00:19:22,529 --> 00:19:26,784
It took nearly two years before we had
anything like the right cooperation

239
00:19:26,863 --> 00:19:29,078
between ships and aircraft.

240
00:19:29,165 --> 00:19:31,194
It was a disgrace and a tragedy.

241
00:19:31,275 --> 00:19:34,723
So many ships were sunk
and so many lives lost unnecessarily

242
00:19:34,804 --> 00:19:36,560
during those first few years.

243
00:19:37,068 --> 00:19:38,868
(narrator) So seamen suffer

244
00:19:38,947 --> 00:19:43,858
from quarrels in Whitehall,
from the U-boats and from the sea.

245
00:19:43,934 --> 00:19:48,145
(man) Now by popular request,
the Western Approaches signature tune.

246
00:19:48,768 --> 00:19:53,678
Someone's rocking my dream boat

247
00:19:53,755 --> 00:19:58,195
Someone's invading my dream

248
00:19:58,282 --> 00:20:03,377
We were sailing along
so peaceful and calm

249
00:20:03,460 --> 00:20:08,207
Suddenly something went wrong

250
00:20:08,294 --> 00:20:14,197
It's very hard to describe to someone
on the land after a tough convoy -

251
00:20:14,278 --> 00:20:16,383
by tough I mean bad weather,

252
00:20:16,465 --> 00:20:18,953
especially in the wintertime -

253
00:20:19,035 --> 00:20:21,402
what just over two weeks at sea is,

254
00:20:21,490 --> 00:20:24,021
living on corned beef and hard tack.

255
00:20:24,137 --> 00:20:27,203
And this is not a fallacy.

256
00:20:27,283 --> 00:20:28,963
We used to do this quite often

257
00:20:29,048 --> 00:20:31,917
when the seas came in
and put the galley fires out.

258
00:20:32,001 --> 00:20:34,838
You couldn't just cook anything hot.

259
00:20:34,917 --> 00:20:36,565
The lucky ones had hammocks

260
00:20:36,643 --> 00:20:39,589
and the unfortunate ones
had to lie on the lockers,

261
00:20:39,674 --> 00:20:41,506
and it was very discomforting.

262
00:20:41,592 --> 00:20:46,032
You used to get chaps coming down
from the middle watch, four o'clock,

263
00:20:46,118 --> 00:20:48,835
wet through,
just clambering on a locker

264
00:20:48,919 --> 00:20:52,247
and the poor chap already
trying to sleep would get soaked.

265
00:20:52,333 --> 00:20:54,209
There was no hygiene there.

266
00:20:54,290 --> 00:20:59,308
We really started smelling after
about a week if you didn't watch it.

267
00:20:59,392 --> 00:21:01,683
We had a feeling
that it was a necessary job.

268
00:21:01,770 --> 00:21:04,869
I'm not sure we realised
that it was all that important.

269
00:21:04,954 --> 00:21:07,136
To us it was a very boring job.

270
00:21:07,256 --> 00:21:13,191
We were on lookout for anything that
might come up and it was bitterly cold.

271
00:21:13,279 --> 00:21:16,497
It was an open bridge,
open to all weathers,

272
00:21:16,616 --> 00:21:20,981
and we were more, really,
trying to keep warm,

273
00:21:21,066 --> 00:21:24,895
trying to keep the cold out,
trying to keep dry,

274
00:21:25,017 --> 00:21:28,617
rather than realise
that we were doing an important job.

275
00:21:28,738 --> 00:21:32,263
(narrator) But they were
doing an important job.

276
00:21:34,991 --> 00:21:41,003
They brought the cargoes, without which
Britain could not have kept going.

277
00:21:45,426 --> 00:21:48,295
(man) You sit down in the cabin.
That's when you think:

278
00:21:48,418 --> 00:21:51,210
"We're in the open sea,
we can catch a pack at any moment."

279
00:21:56,320 --> 00:21:59,004
(Butler) Many times
we saw little lights in the water

280
00:21:59,082 --> 00:22:04,603
and we assumed these were survivors,
but we couldn't stop and pick them up.

281
00:22:06,218 --> 00:22:09,665
(man) The normal comparison
that seamen made with their wage

282
00:22:09,747 --> 00:22:13,773
for the hours that they worked
was with the ammunition workers,

283
00:22:13,851 --> 00:22:16,535
who were making
a fabulous amount of money,

284
00:22:16,614 --> 00:22:20,138
with no more risks
than our housewives left at home.

285
00:22:24,938 --> 00:22:28,571
(Eyton-Jones) We lost one out of every
three men, and without them

286
00:22:28,697 --> 00:22:32,494
this nation wouldn't have survived
more than three or four months.

287
00:22:34,298 --> 00:22:36,982
(narrator)
But the Germans were still celebrating.

288
00:22:38,096 --> 00:22:43,464
In the first half of 1941 they sank
nearly three million tons of shipping.

289
00:22:43,543 --> 00:22:46,533
Ships were harder to replace than cargo.

290
00:22:46,612 --> 00:22:52,286
If they could be sunk faster than they
could be built, Britain would starve.

291
00:22:58,926 --> 00:23:02,101
But now the Canadian navy,
tiny at the outbreak of war,

292
00:23:02,187 --> 00:23:04,751
was expanding to 50 times
its original size.

293
00:23:04,834 --> 00:23:10,889
It would take on nearly half the burden
of convoy escort in the north Atlantic.

294
00:23:22,749 --> 00:23:25,204
More and more convoys
were leaving Canada,

295
00:23:25,281 --> 00:23:28,227
decks laden with tanks,
holds full of supplies

296
00:23:28,350 --> 00:23:31,568
from the neutral United States
under lease-lend.

297
00:23:39,206 --> 00:23:42,272
Alarmed at continuing losses,
the British war cabinet

298
00:23:42,352 --> 00:23:46,607
set up a new Western Approaches
Command to reorganise convoy defence.

299
00:23:46,687 --> 00:23:52,666
For the first time, the RAF and the navy
worked closely together.

300
00:23:57,773 --> 00:24:02,181
And in March 1941,
Doenitz lost three of his ablest men.

301
00:24:07,555 --> 00:24:12,574
Günther Prien, who had sunk
the Royal Oak at Scapa Flow...

302
00:24:13,194 --> 00:24:16,260
depth-charged and killed.

303
00:24:16,340 --> 00:24:19,514
Joachim Schepke, rammed and drowned.

304
00:24:23,284 --> 00:24:27,113
And Kretschmer,
depth-charged to the surface...

305
00:24:32,644 --> 00:24:34,858
and taken prisoner.

306
00:24:39,012 --> 00:24:43,343
Only one third of Doenitz's fleet
could be on patrol at any one time.

307
00:24:43,423 --> 00:24:46,293
His best captains had suddenly gone.

308
00:24:46,416 --> 00:24:49,590
Now he could only keep
some half dozen U-boats at sea.

309
00:24:49,676 --> 00:24:52,164
With this small number of U-boats,

310
00:24:52,247 --> 00:24:55,879
of course any decisive success

311
00:24:55,968 --> 00:24:59,339
in the battle of the Atlantic
was not possible.

312
00:25:00,149 --> 00:25:05,670
That's why it was necessary
for the building of submarines

313
00:25:05,750 --> 00:25:11,576
to get first place
in the German armament plan.

314
00:25:11,696 --> 00:25:14,107
But this was not done,

315
00:25:14,189 --> 00:25:17,790
in spite of all the requests

316
00:25:17,872 --> 00:25:20,589
made by Admiral Raeder,

317
00:25:20,672 --> 00:25:24,043
who then was chief of the German navy.

318
00:25:25,046 --> 00:25:27,304
(narrator) Worse was to come for him.

319
00:25:27,424 --> 00:25:30,643
The United States
was still officially neutral.

320
00:25:30,723 --> 00:25:34,127
(PA) General quarters,
general quarters. On the double.

321
00:25:34,790 --> 00:25:38,542
(narrator) But after Churchill's
Atlantic meeting with Roosevelt,

322
00:25:38,626 --> 00:25:42,684
September 1941, America announced she
would protect ships of any nationality

323
00:25:42,769 --> 00:25:45,791
plying between her shores and Iceland.

324
00:25:51,438 --> 00:25:53,086
There were now enough warships

325
00:25:53,165 --> 00:25:55,925
to provide continuous escort
across the Atlantic.

326
00:25:56,003 --> 00:25:57,804
It was time to counterattack.

327
00:25:57,883 --> 00:26:02,749
I got hold of
a number of escort commanders,

328
00:26:02,832 --> 00:26:05,701
who I asked the question:

329
00:26:05,786 --> 00:26:09,768
"When a U-boat is known
to be attacking a convoy,

330
00:26:09,852 --> 00:26:11,837
as they do now by night",

331
00:26:11,924 --> 00:26:14,836
I asked them what they did,

332
00:26:14,916 --> 00:26:19,510
and the answer in most cases was,
"Well, what can you do?"

333
00:26:19,596 --> 00:26:22,891
"It's a very tiny little thing
and we can't see them."

334
00:26:22,972 --> 00:26:29,060
Radar, of course, in those days was very
elementary and we had very few sets.

335
00:26:29,148 --> 00:26:33,665
But in fact there was
one escort commander

336
00:26:33,751 --> 00:26:36,282
who had the idea,

337
00:26:36,360 --> 00:26:38,618
which is still absolutely relevant,

338
00:26:38,700 --> 00:26:44,712
that when an attack, of which
there is no warning, takes place,

339
00:26:44,799 --> 00:26:49,130
that all of the escort
should do the same sort of thing

340
00:26:49,211 --> 00:26:51,666
on a planned line

341
00:26:51,743 --> 00:26:54,077
at exactly the same time

342
00:26:54,160 --> 00:27:00,444
so that it has the maximum effect
over the broad ocean around that convoy.

343
00:27:00,528 --> 00:27:04,401
And this, of course,
was the then Commander Walker.

344
00:27:04,479 --> 00:27:06,967
(narrator)
Although he did not survive the war,

345
00:27:07,088 --> 00:27:09,957
Walker was to sink more U-boats
than anyone else.

346
00:27:10,080 --> 00:27:14,029
At the end of 1941
he set a new style for convoy defence.

347
00:27:14,108 --> 00:27:16,900
The convoy was HG-76.

348
00:27:16,985 --> 00:27:20,280
In it were 36 merchantmen
from all parts of the world.

349
00:27:20,361 --> 00:27:24,801
They assembled in Gibraltar
for the trudge to Britain.

350
00:27:31,754 --> 00:27:35,234
The navy knew there were at least
six U-boats on the convoy's route -

351
00:27:35,322 --> 00:27:38,725
their signals had been picked up
by the admiralty.

352
00:27:41,114 --> 00:27:45,370
When HG-76 sailed
on 14 December 1941,

353
00:27:45,449 --> 00:27:50,392
it had an exceptionally large escort -
17 ships commanded by Walker.

354
00:27:50,475 --> 00:27:55,111
Among them, for the first time,
an auxiliary aircraft carrier,

355
00:27:55,193 --> 00:27:56,186
the Audacity.

356
00:27:58,454 --> 00:28:02,556
Three days out,
Audacity's plane spotted U-131.

357
00:28:07,929 --> 00:28:10,068
The escorts quickly sank her.

358
00:28:18,709 --> 00:28:22,505
Doenitz homed five more U-boats
on the convoy.

359
00:28:25,307 --> 00:28:27,762
Walker's team soon sank one.

360
00:28:29,181 --> 00:28:31,745
But that night
the U-boats attacked again.

361
00:28:33,861 --> 00:28:38,379
An escort and a merchant ship were sunk.
Walker counterattacked.

362
00:28:50,664 --> 00:28:54,613
Walker's own ship
rammed and sank U-574.

363
00:28:55,689 --> 00:28:59,748
In the air, Audacity's fighters
harried the German Condors.

364
00:29:00,983 --> 00:29:04,431
One was destroyed. Others were damaged.

365
00:29:07,044 --> 00:29:10,918
But some escorts were running
out of fuel. They had to leave.

366
00:29:10,996 --> 00:29:14,137
A U-boat penetrated the gap.

367
00:29:14,256 --> 00:29:16,667
Audacity was the next victim.

368
00:29:21,775 --> 00:29:25,910
Another hectic night followed.
The convoy lost one more ship.

369
00:29:25,995 --> 00:29:30,250
But Endrass, another U-boat ace
was sunk in U-567.

370
00:29:30,330 --> 00:29:33,581
Next day, for the first time,
a long-range Liberator

371
00:29:33,667 --> 00:29:35,161
appeared and attacked.

372
00:29:38,156 --> 00:29:40,948
Doenitz decided he must withdraw.

373
00:29:44,140 --> 00:29:46,551
Walker had justified his tactics.

374
00:29:46,633 --> 00:29:49,426
Aircraft had proved their worth.

375
00:29:51,467 --> 00:29:54,413
Four U-boats had been sunk.

376
00:29:54,536 --> 00:29:59,402
But Doenitz was about to be given
his greatest opportunity.

377
00:30:00,559 --> 00:30:03,887
("Moonlight Serenade")

378
00:30:03,973 --> 00:30:08,261
In December 1941, the United States
came fully into the war -

379
00:30:08,346 --> 00:30:10,408
but left her peacetime lights on.

380
00:30:21,849 --> 00:30:23,027
(explosion)

381
00:30:23,883 --> 00:30:27,057
Doenitz's U-boats never had it so good.

382
00:30:29,714 --> 00:30:32,506
This was the second "happy time".

383
00:30:36,235 --> 00:30:40,109
The Americans did not have enough
warships available for offshore escort

384
00:30:40,186 --> 00:30:42,445
so there were no convoys there.

385
00:30:42,526 --> 00:30:45,548
Many ships were convoyed
safely across the ocean

386
00:30:45,634 --> 00:30:49,616
to be torpedoed
alone and unescorted offshore.

387
00:30:55,186 --> 00:30:57,171
The slaughter went on.

388
00:30:57,296 --> 00:30:58,976
In the second half of 1941

389
00:30:59,060 --> 00:31:02,279
nearly 1.5 million tons of shipping
were lost.

390
00:31:02,359 --> 00:31:07,913
In the first half of 1942 over
4 million tons of shipping were lost -

391
00:31:07,998 --> 00:31:10,682
1,000 ships.

392
00:31:12,487 --> 00:31:15,738
At this rate,
the Allies would lose the war.

393
00:31:15,824 --> 00:31:20,646
We had to sink as many ships as possible

394
00:31:20,734 --> 00:31:24,913
before our Anglo-American opponent

395
00:31:24,993 --> 00:31:31,474
could develop
an effective antisubmarine defence

396
00:31:31,552 --> 00:31:37,106
and could replace the merchant ships
which had been sunk.

397
00:31:39,877 --> 00:31:43,706
(narrator) But most of Germany's
U-boats were not in the Atlantic.

398
00:31:43,790 --> 00:31:47,893
They were patrolling off Norway,
defending Germany's supply lines,

399
00:31:47,971 --> 00:31:49,881
or confined in the Mediterranean.

400
00:31:49,966 --> 00:31:52,879
These dispositions infuriated Doenitz.

401
00:31:54,301 --> 00:31:57,247
He had no doubts
where the U-boats ought to be.

402
00:31:57,331 --> 00:32:03,419
(Doenitz) The German submarines
must not be used for any other purposes.

403
00:32:03,508 --> 00:32:09,411
Their main strategic purpose
was to sink as many ships as possible

404
00:32:09,492 --> 00:32:11,477
in the Atlantic.

405
00:32:13,865 --> 00:32:17,815
But Hitler and the high command
would not listen.

406
00:32:18,507 --> 00:32:21,300
(speaks German)

407
00:32:31,588 --> 00:32:34,305
(narrator)
Although preoccupied with the Pacific,

408
00:32:34,389 --> 00:32:37,717
the US naval staff were now willing
to rethink Atlantic tactics.

409
00:32:39,261 --> 00:32:42,632
They finally established
a system of offshore convoys.

410
00:32:48,506 --> 00:32:51,069
Sinkings of merchantmen dropped off.

411
00:32:51,153 --> 00:32:53,564
Sinkings of U-boats began.

412
00:33:02,009 --> 00:33:04,617
Doenitz now switched his boats
to the Caribbean,

413
00:33:04,694 --> 00:33:08,644
where many ships
were still sailing independently.

414
00:33:27,750 --> 00:33:32,114
(narrator) In two months,
78 ships were sunk,

415
00:33:32,200 --> 00:33:35,189
more than half of them oil tankers.

416
00:33:35,269 --> 00:33:38,716
(man) It was a very long time ago,
but I can see it now -

417
00:33:38,798 --> 00:33:42,551
the people that lived aft
running around on fire

418
00:33:42,672 --> 00:33:46,349
and throwing themselves
straight over the side into the oil

419
00:33:46,432 --> 00:33:48,308
which was on fire all round.

420
00:33:48,388 --> 00:33:52,108
In the meantime, I shouted
to the remaining people in the boat

421
00:33:52,186 --> 00:33:55,023
to get the oars out
and push her off from the ship's side

422
00:33:55,102 --> 00:33:58,931
because the rivets of the ship's side
had burst out and they were on fire.

423
00:33:59,014 --> 00:34:02,767
We rowed around for a wee while
and we heard some screams for help,

424
00:34:02,851 --> 00:34:09,179
and we pulled out of the water
a fireman, or greaser as we call them,

425
00:34:09,295 --> 00:34:13,780
and he was terribly burned,
so much so that when we pulled him in

426
00:34:13,937 --> 00:34:18,345
the skin of his body and arms
came off in our hands like gloves.

427
00:34:18,425 --> 00:34:24,438
We set sail and course for Trinidad.
I had a rough idea where it might be.

428
00:34:24,525 --> 00:34:27,591
And so we tidied up the boat
and set off.

429
00:34:27,671 --> 00:34:30,692
But shortly after that the greaser,

430
00:34:30,816 --> 00:34:34,416
who'd been in terrible agony all night,
he died,

431
00:34:34,537 --> 00:34:37,177
and we laid him on the thwart
for a wee while.

432
00:34:37,338 --> 00:34:43,164
And then shortly after that they told me
that the third steward had died too,

433
00:34:43,245 --> 00:34:48,493
so I went to have a look at him,
and he was wrapped up in a blanket,

434
00:34:48,616 --> 00:34:50,339
and I took the blanket away

435
00:34:50,457 --> 00:34:54,974
and the whole of his stomach was
severely damaged and hanging out.

436
00:34:55,061 --> 00:34:57,166
He'd been very patient during the night

437
00:34:57,247 --> 00:34:59,855
and the only thing
he'd complained of was cold.

438
00:34:59,933 --> 00:35:05,530
So we laid him on the thwart and covered
him with a blanket for about an hour,

439
00:35:05,648 --> 00:35:08,747
because I wanted to really make sure
that they were dead,

440
00:35:09,139 --> 00:35:11,595
because we had nothing to indicate...

441
00:35:11,671 --> 00:35:14,661
Everything I did indicated
that they were so.

442
00:35:14,740 --> 00:35:19,225
Eventually, after about an hour,
we committed them to the deep.

443
00:35:19,842 --> 00:35:22,559
Morale in the boat at this time
was very low

444
00:35:22,643 --> 00:35:28,731
because these were all young boys -
17, 18, 19, 22.

445
00:35:28,857 --> 00:35:34,837
And by this time it was a boat-load
of miseries, pain and death.

446
00:35:36,031 --> 00:35:40,515
(narrator) Only eight men survived
from the San Emiliano's crew of 40.

447
00:35:45,928 --> 00:35:51,024
To Allied seamen
the U-boat crews were heartless killers,

448
00:35:51,107 --> 00:35:53,518
but the Germans were brave men too.

449
00:35:53,600 --> 00:35:56,972
They needed courage when depth charges
exploded around them,

450
00:35:57,053 --> 00:36:00,119
sometimes for 12 hours at a stretch.

451
00:36:03,344 --> 00:36:08,255
Eight of every ten U-boat crewmen
were to die in action.

452
00:36:08,331 --> 00:36:10,317
(explosion)

453
00:36:12,666 --> 00:36:14,651
(man shouts in German)

454
00:36:29,430 --> 00:36:32,529
They called their U-boats iron coffins.

455
00:36:32,921 --> 00:36:36,827
(German man)
The destroyer I met had radar

456
00:36:36,911 --> 00:36:40,053
so he had me on his screen

457
00:36:40,133 --> 00:36:44,388
and with full speed ahead

458
00:36:44,468 --> 00:36:48,145
he rammed me for the first time.

459
00:36:48,227 --> 00:36:51,555
And when I saw him
it was too late to dive.

460
00:36:51,642 --> 00:36:54,205
I tried to torpedo him,

461
00:36:54,289 --> 00:37:00,464
but the distance, 150 yards round about,

462
00:37:00,541 --> 00:37:05,986
was too close,
so the torpedo wouldn't explode.

463
00:37:06,066 --> 00:37:10,932
So I tried to get a bigger distance

464
00:37:11,014 --> 00:37:13,305
between the destroyer and the boat.

465
00:37:13,393 --> 00:37:18,760
And he was shooting during one hour
or two hours with machine guns.

466
00:37:18,840 --> 00:37:22,789
An officer next to me was dead

467
00:37:22,868 --> 00:37:27,352
and another officer,
he had got a bullet through his throat

468
00:37:27,433 --> 00:37:30,041
and I had got a bullet in my chest

469
00:37:30,157 --> 00:37:36,060
and I had some 30 shell splinters
in arm and leg

470
00:37:36,141 --> 00:37:38,280
and a bullet in my head.

471
00:37:38,366 --> 00:37:41,126
After one hour of stress

472
00:37:41,205 --> 00:37:43,660
the sailors were very anxious

473
00:37:43,813 --> 00:37:47,217
and one of the petty officers,
he lost his nerves

474
00:37:47,304 --> 00:37:52,290
and said, "Oh, this madman!"
and, "Why don't we surrender?"

475
00:37:52,368 --> 00:37:54,244
But this was the only one.

476
00:37:54,324 --> 00:37:58,503
(narrator) But the time was coming
when courage was no longer enough.

477
00:37:58,583 --> 00:38:00,612
(speaks German)

478
00:38:03,455 --> 00:38:06,521
Radio had remained essential
to wolf-pack operations.

479
00:38:06,600 --> 00:38:10,506
But new Allied direction-finding
equipment could pick up German signals

480
00:38:10,590 --> 00:38:13,273
and plot where they came from.

481
00:38:32,456 --> 00:38:38,511
With short-wave radar, escorts could now
locate a U-boat on the surface...

482
00:38:39,936 --> 00:38:44,453
often sighting the U-boat
before her crew could see them.

483
00:38:45,806 --> 00:38:49,101
The low silhouette
was no longer such an advantage.

484
00:38:49,220 --> 00:38:50,714
(rings)

485
00:38:50,793 --> 00:38:52,702
(speaking German)

486
00:39:00,728 --> 00:39:03,412
(narrator)
Asdic equipment too was improving.

487
00:39:03,490 --> 00:39:06,021
Escort ships
could track a submerged U-boat

488
00:39:06,137 --> 00:39:10,273
as she twisted and turned
at low underwater speed.

489
00:39:16,150 --> 00:39:20,361
There were new weapons,
like the hedgehog, for the kill.

490
00:39:38,169 --> 00:39:42,272
The Germans did not realise the extent
of British and US technical advances,

491
00:39:42,351 --> 00:39:44,074
nor did they match them.

492
00:39:44,154 --> 00:39:46,761
The Germans had some very
high-class scientists

493
00:39:46,877 --> 00:39:48,558
and some excellent engineers,

494
00:39:48,642 --> 00:39:51,937
but they didn't achieve the results
they ought to have done.

495
00:39:52,056 --> 00:39:54,664
Firstly, I think,
because they were mucked around,

496
00:39:54,742 --> 00:39:57,153
and the Germans kept
altering the priorities,

497
00:39:57,235 --> 00:40:00,606
and secondly because
I don't believe they were ever allowed

498
00:40:00,688 --> 00:40:04,288
to take any interest
in the operational side,

499
00:40:04,370 --> 00:40:07,240
as opposed to what happened with us,

500
00:40:07,362 --> 00:40:12,032
where the scientists were made to feel
full members of the operational team.

501
00:40:12,119 --> 00:40:15,993
I believe this, much more than
the question of weapons and devices,

502
00:40:16,071 --> 00:40:21,166
was the reason why the Germans fell
so far astern in technological matters.

503
00:40:21,710 --> 00:40:24,579
(narrator) And the Allies
were still behind in using

504
00:40:24,664 --> 00:40:27,730
what would be the most effective
counter to the U-boat -

505
00:40:27,809 --> 00:40:29,685
aircraft with radar.

506
00:40:38,589 --> 00:40:43,957
Convoys could seldom be given
continuous long-range air cover.

507
00:40:45,225 --> 00:40:49,556
When they were, losses were reduced
and U-boat kills increased.

508
00:41:00,608 --> 00:41:05,519
The problem was range. Planes now flew
to the convoys from North America,

509
00:41:05,595 --> 00:41:09,076
from Iceland, from the United Kingdom.

510
00:41:09,163 --> 00:41:12,076
But there was a vast gap
in mid-Atlantic

511
00:41:12,155 --> 00:41:15,406
which these escort planes
could not reach.

512
00:41:15,493 --> 00:41:17,860
The U-boats could and did.

513
00:41:20,863 --> 00:41:25,194
In the second half of 1942
over 3.5 million tons went down,

514
00:41:25,275 --> 00:41:29,104
nearly 700 ships,
many of them in the Atlantic gap.

515
00:41:30,761 --> 00:41:34,590
To close this gap,
escort carriers were needed

516
00:41:34,673 --> 00:41:36,735
to sail with the convoys.

517
00:41:39,430 --> 00:41:41,841
But few were yet available.

518
00:41:43,305 --> 00:41:46,447
Or very long-range planes
like the Liberator.

519
00:41:46,527 --> 00:41:51,121
But in 1942 the Americans needed
most of these in the Pacific.

520
00:41:51,936 --> 00:41:55,155
Or Lancaster bombers,
but despite admiralty appeals

521
00:41:55,235 --> 00:41:58,410
the RAF kept them all bombing Germany -

522
00:41:58,534 --> 00:42:02,441
although they did release
other aircraft.

523
00:42:02,524 --> 00:42:06,430
Bomber Command diverted
six squadrons to Coastal Command,

524
00:42:06,514 --> 00:42:10,234
and if you'd said it would've been
better if they'd made that ten, yes,

525
00:42:10,311 --> 00:42:12,842
but the line had to be drawn somewhere.

526
00:42:12,920 --> 00:42:17,786
As a Coastal type I would've liked to
see a few more squadrons in Coastal,

527
00:42:17,869 --> 00:42:21,164
but Bomber Command were pitifully short
of aeroplanes, too,

528
00:42:21,283 --> 00:42:22,625
for the job they had to do.

529
00:42:22,702 --> 00:42:27,187
Surely, if there had been
more Liberators allocated from America

530
00:42:27,267 --> 00:42:30,060
we could have improved
the situation much earlier

531
00:42:30,144 --> 00:42:33,166
and have saved the lives
of a lot of seamen.

532
00:42:37,433 --> 00:42:42,834
(narrator) More and more, the war
effort depended on the United States.

533
00:42:50,783 --> 00:42:53,271
Merchant ships and escorts
were mass-produced

534
00:42:53,391 --> 00:42:57,144
to carry the material and men
for the invasion of Europe.

535
00:42:57,228 --> 00:43:01,363
Unless the Atlantic was secured,
all else could fall apart.

536
00:43:01,447 --> 00:43:05,004
In January 1943,
Roosevelt and Churchill decreed

537
00:43:05,130 --> 00:43:08,425
that the defeat of the U-boat
be given top priority.

538
00:43:12,112 --> 00:43:14,720
Improved escort vessels were built.

539
00:43:19,439 --> 00:43:23,313
There were now enough of these
to go over to the attack.

540
00:43:24,771 --> 00:43:29,561
But also in January 1943, Doenitz
took over as chief of the German navy.

541
00:43:29,643 --> 00:43:31,748
He paid off most of the big ships

542
00:43:31,830 --> 00:43:35,627
and released their crews
for the submarine service.

543
00:43:41,804 --> 00:43:44,870
At last he could have U-boats
mass-produced.

544
00:43:44,949 --> 00:43:48,746
17 new U-boats
were commissioned each month.

545
00:43:57,148 --> 00:44:02,931
By early spring 1943,
Doenitz had over 400 U-boats in service.

546
00:44:06,087 --> 00:44:08,727
Once again,
the convoys might be overwhelmed.

547
00:44:14,334 --> 00:44:17,892
In May came what was to prove
the decisive battle,

548
00:44:17,979 --> 00:44:19,582
around convoy ONS-5.

549
00:44:19,667 --> 00:44:24,762
ONS-5 was a rather small, very slow

550
00:44:24,846 --> 00:44:28,478
and, of course, unladen, empty convoy.

551
00:44:28,567 --> 00:44:30,672
And we had a lot of trouble.

552
00:44:30,753 --> 00:44:35,161
The weather was very bad,
the ships got disorganised,

553
00:44:35,242 --> 00:44:38,722
and south of Iceland
after three or four days

554
00:44:38,809 --> 00:44:41,908
we had several attacks by submarines,

555
00:44:41,993 --> 00:44:47,394
most of which we drove off successfully,
and only had one ship sunk.

556
00:44:47,479 --> 00:44:53,382
Then after a spell we had a long series
of very bad gales indeed,

557
00:44:53,502 --> 00:44:58,826
combined with a little nip
into the ice pack off Greenland,

558
00:44:58,911 --> 00:45:03,700
and at this stage
my ship was running short of fuel,

559
00:45:03,783 --> 00:45:07,764
I couldn't fuel from the tanker because
of the weather, and I had to leave.

560
00:45:07,887 --> 00:45:09,763
I got the signal from Gretton

561
00:45:09,844 --> 00:45:15,168
that he had to push off
to Newfoundland to get fuel

562
00:45:15,253 --> 00:45:18,548
and would I come back
and take over the escort?

563
00:45:18,628 --> 00:45:21,650
Well, he didn't say "would I?",
he said, "You're in charge."

564
00:45:22,656 --> 00:45:26,137
(narrator) May 3.
Four escort ships have left to refuel.

565
00:45:26,224 --> 00:45:29,213
In bad weather
ten merchant ships have lost contact.

566
00:45:29,293 --> 00:45:31,748
A line of U-boats is waiting.

567
00:45:31,825 --> 00:45:33,352
As they move in on 4 May,

568
00:45:33,436 --> 00:45:36,807
aircraft from Canada
sink one and damage another.

569
00:45:36,889 --> 00:45:41,220
At about half past four to five o'clock
in the afternoon

570
00:45:41,377 --> 00:45:44,214
the torpedoing started.

571
00:45:44,331 --> 00:45:46,786
Well, I torpedoed two ships,

572
00:45:46,863 --> 00:45:49,121
each with two torpedoes,

573
00:45:49,203 --> 00:45:51,963
and one of these ships...

574
00:45:53,844 --> 00:45:55,720
Well, it didn't explode,

575
00:45:55,801 --> 00:46:01,278
but after the explosion of the torpedoes
another big explosion happened.

576
00:46:01,363 --> 00:46:03,273
I looked back and I saw the captain.

577
00:46:03,665 --> 00:46:06,611
I would suggest the bridge
was probably...

578
00:46:06,772 --> 00:46:09,991
oh, 10 or 15 feet,
might be a little more, off the water

579
00:46:10,071 --> 00:46:12,788
when he jumped off
the wing of the bridge into the sea.

580
00:46:12,872 --> 00:46:15,206
There was a life raft nearby,
I know that.

581
00:46:15,289 --> 00:46:17,852
Well, I couldn't stop and pick him up.

582
00:46:17,974 --> 00:46:20,767
And, well, it was in...

583
00:46:22,155 --> 00:46:25,297
I suppose a matter of half a minute
that I got one myself.

584
00:46:25,416 --> 00:46:29,442
Once more I was lucky
by slipping through into a gap

585
00:46:29,521 --> 00:46:32,281
between two of the escort vessels

586
00:46:32,359 --> 00:46:37,182
and closing into the port column
of the convoy,

587
00:46:37,270 --> 00:46:40,292
and I fired the two torpedoes

588
00:46:40,415 --> 00:46:44,212
and both torpedoes hit the target ship.

589
00:46:45,556 --> 00:46:50,924
(narrator) May 5. The U-boats
make 25 attacks in eight hours.

590
00:46:51,003 --> 00:46:52,836
More ships are sunk.

591
00:46:52,921 --> 00:46:58,780
The outlook for the convoy is grim
as Doenitz orders in still more U-boats.

592
00:46:58,867 --> 00:47:03,046
We picked up quite a lot of signals
from other submarines

593
00:47:03,125 --> 00:47:06,650
also getting contact with this convoy.

594
00:47:06,731 --> 00:47:11,554
And so we thought that this convoy
would be absolutely dead

595
00:47:11,642 --> 00:47:13,551
during the next night.

596
00:47:13,637 --> 00:47:19,266
Somewhere in the region of 10 o'clock
the attack started

597
00:47:19,352 --> 00:47:23,302
and they became fast and furious.

598
00:47:23,380 --> 00:47:26,599
(Looks) Suddenly dense fog came up

599
00:47:26,680 --> 00:47:31,775
and so it was nearly impossible
to find the convoy again.

600
00:47:31,897 --> 00:47:36,381
I tried to do it,
but we couldn't find the ships again.

601
00:47:36,462 --> 00:47:41,600
(Sherwood) Escorts were reporting
submarines coming in,

602
00:47:41,679 --> 00:47:45,312
not ships being torpedoed,

603
00:47:45,438 --> 00:47:49,803
and this, of course, was absolutely...

604
00:47:49,888 --> 00:47:52,572
It was the first time it happened,
certainly to me.

605
00:47:52,650 --> 00:47:58,630
Staying on the surface during
the dark time, now in the dense fog,

606
00:47:58,711 --> 00:48:01,319
of course it was very dangerous.

607
00:48:01,397 --> 00:48:03,426
They were coming up
all the time saying

608
00:48:03,507 --> 00:48:06,070
that a submarine
was bearing so-and-so on radar

609
00:48:06,154 --> 00:48:10,103
and then the next thing you'd get:
"Submarine close alongside."

610
00:48:10,182 --> 00:48:15,124
Another one: "Submarine
just ahead of me. I'm ramming."

611
00:48:15,207 --> 00:48:17,007
And this went on all night.

612
00:48:17,087 --> 00:48:20,611
I got a very firm asdic contact

613
00:48:20,693 --> 00:48:21,914
about 800 yards

614
00:48:21,997 --> 00:48:24,866
from the nearest ship in the convoy.

615
00:48:24,951 --> 00:48:26,248
My immediate reaction,

616
00:48:26,332 --> 00:48:28,132
which I think was the correct one -

617
00:48:28,212 --> 00:48:30,087
in fact I know was the correct one -

618
00:48:30,168 --> 00:48:35,340
was to increase speed and give it
a five-charge pattern straight away

619
00:48:35,423 --> 00:48:37,299
to keep the chap's head down

620
00:48:37,380 --> 00:48:41,439
so that it would put him off his stroke
if he was going to fire torpedoes.

621
00:48:41,523 --> 00:48:44,512
But I was short of depth charges
at that stage

622
00:48:44,592 --> 00:48:47,996
and I thought the conditions
were perfect -

623
00:48:48,083 --> 00:48:51,607
the night was relatively calm,
a bit of fog -

624
00:48:51,689 --> 00:48:54,023
perfect for a deliberate attack.

625
00:48:54,106 --> 00:48:59,430
And so I decided on a deliberate attack
with our forward-throwing weapon,

626
00:48:59,515 --> 00:49:00,780
the hedgehog.

627
00:49:00,896 --> 00:49:03,688
We saw two distinct flashes

628
00:49:03,773 --> 00:49:07,373
a few seconds
after the hedgehog bombs hit the water,

629
00:49:07,494 --> 00:49:10,516
and as we passed over the position

630
00:49:10,601 --> 00:49:13,776
where our hedgehog bombs
had hit the water,

631
00:49:13,862 --> 00:49:19,416
we were virtually... our bow
was virtually lifted from the water

632
00:49:19,501 --> 00:49:25,175
as a result of the U-boat breaking apart
and escaping air.

633
00:49:25,294 --> 00:49:28,163
And there was great exhilaration
on the bridge

634
00:49:28,247 --> 00:49:31,160
because this was our first kill.

635
00:49:31,240 --> 00:49:36,378
We had no feelings at the time,
I'm afraid, of destroying 70-odd people.

636
00:49:36,495 --> 00:49:43,664
One had control of one's emotions
by then, after three years of war

637
00:49:43,746 --> 00:49:46,462
and it was just the thought
that it's us or them,

638
00:49:46,584 --> 00:49:48,537
and on that occasion it was them.

639
00:49:49,385 --> 00:49:52,713
(narrator) May 6.
Although 11 merchantmen have been lost,

640
00:49:52,799 --> 00:49:57,665
the escorts have beaten off the largest
wolf pack Doenitz can send against them.

641
00:49:57,747 --> 00:50:00,464
Seven U-boats have been sunk,
others damaged.

642
00:50:00,548 --> 00:50:03,570
Demoralised by their failure
to destroy the convoy

643
00:50:03,694 --> 00:50:07,294
with the odds so much on their side,
the U-boats withdraw.

644
00:50:07,415 --> 00:50:12,892
I think we really felt that at last
our training and technology

645
00:50:13,015 --> 00:50:15,546
had got on top of the U-boats.

646
00:50:15,624 --> 00:50:21,756
We sailed for the next convoy, SC-130,
on the top of the wave,

647
00:50:21,839 --> 00:50:26,017
and despite the fact that we had
a very heavy battle

648
00:50:26,135 --> 00:50:31,885
with about 20 U-boats, we sank three of
them and didn't lose one single ship.

649
00:50:39,869 --> 00:50:44,462
(narrator) That month, May 1943,
41 U-boats were sunk.

650
00:50:48,462 --> 00:50:52,138
In one of them,
Doenitz lost his younger son.

651
00:50:52,221 --> 00:50:54,326
(Doenitz) In May 1943,

652
00:50:54,408 --> 00:50:57,779
the German submarines had lost

653
00:50:57,860 --> 00:51:01,340
the operational and tactical quality

654
00:51:01,428 --> 00:51:05,377
of surface manoeuvrability.

655
00:51:05,494 --> 00:51:07,523
(narrator) They never regained it.

656
00:51:07,604 --> 00:51:13,158
Unable to range freely on the surface,
the wolf packs were beaten.

657
00:51:13,243 --> 00:51:18,491
It was time to celebrate a victory
in North Africa and in the Atlantic.

658
00:51:18,614 --> 00:51:24,058
More than 30 U-boats were certainly
destroyed in the month of May,

659
00:51:24,215 --> 00:51:29,811
foundering in many cases with their
crews into the dark depths of the sea.

660
00:51:29,892 --> 00:51:34,911
Staggered by these deadly losses,
the U-boats have recoiled

661
00:51:34,994 --> 00:51:38,551
to lick their wounds
and mourn their dead.

662
00:51:38,638 --> 00:51:42,435
Our Atlantic convoys
came safely through.

663
00:51:42,513 --> 00:51:45,350
And now,
as the result of the May victory

664
00:51:45,429 --> 00:51:48,221
and the massacre of U-boats,

665
00:51:48,306 --> 00:51:52,713
we have had in June the best month
from every point of view

666
00:51:52,794 --> 00:51:57,202
we have ever known
in the whole 46 months of the war.

667
00:51:59,929 --> 00:52:04,108
(narrator) The Atlantic lifeline
was, at last, secure.
