1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:08,000
== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==

2
00:00:02,434 --> 00:00:03,732
(cheering)

3
00:00:03,815 --> 00:00:08,987
(narrator) Berlin in the summer of 1940
welcomed victory beyond belief.

4
00:00:14,250 --> 00:00:19,160
The soldiers of the Third Reich
came home after only a year of war.

5
00:00:19,237 --> 00:00:21,189
They had conquered France.

6
00:00:21,270 --> 00:00:24,063
Central and northern Europe
had fallen, too.

7
00:00:24,147 --> 00:00:28,250
These crowds were delirious
with exultation and relief.

8
00:00:30,477 --> 00:00:34,884
They turned to their Führer
in a frenzy of gratitude.

9
00:00:45,668 --> 00:00:49,072
They had not fancied war.
They had feared defeat.

10
00:00:49,159 --> 00:00:52,148
Now they thought the war was over

11
00:00:52,228 --> 00:00:54,595
and they rejoiced.

12
00:01:52,302 --> 00:01:54,058
(narrator) The men came home.

13
00:01:54,143 --> 00:01:57,514
They were brown and fit
and only a few of them had died.

14
00:02:04,731 --> 00:02:06,411
(woman) I just went shopping

15
00:02:06,496 --> 00:02:09,824
when somebody told me,
"Don't you hear the noise?"

16
00:02:09,910 --> 00:02:14,241
And there I saw this part of the army
coming back just near us.

17
00:02:14,322 --> 00:02:19,035
So I bought a bowl of cherries
and ran there.

18
00:02:21,994 --> 00:02:24,405
We all were so glad.

19
00:02:24,487 --> 00:02:28,972
We heard so much of the First World War
with those dreadful battles

20
00:02:29,052 --> 00:02:31,311
and those many dead.

21
00:02:31,392 --> 00:02:37,099
I felt a sort of national pride
we ended the war so quick.

22
00:02:40,676 --> 00:02:42,781
(narrator) In cities untouched by war,

23
00:02:42,863 --> 00:02:46,343
the German people had hardly begun
to give up the ways of peace.

24
00:02:46,430 --> 00:02:48,569
There was rationing, even shortages,

25
00:02:48,655 --> 00:02:52,866
but to make up for it,
the regime preached enjoyment, luxury.

26
00:02:52,952 --> 00:02:56,093
( "Rosamunde")

27
00:03:06,302 --> 00:03:09,171
While the British had declared
frivolous things immoral,

28
00:03:09,255 --> 00:03:12,245
the Nazis tried to show
that luxury flourished.

29
00:03:12,324 --> 00:03:14,234
Promises were their propaganda.

30
00:03:14,319 --> 00:03:17,844
Those who ran the war effort
came to believe their own promises.

31
00:03:17,925 --> 00:03:19,954
Only a few saw further.

32
00:03:20,035 --> 00:03:23,134
Just about August it was ordered

33
00:03:23,257 --> 00:03:25,941
that a lot of production was stopped

34
00:03:26,058 --> 00:03:29,778
or minimised or things like that.

35
00:03:29,856 --> 00:03:36,063
And there was a kind of euphoria
that the war was, so to say, over.

36
00:03:36,147 --> 00:03:38,132
I didn't believe in that at all.

37
00:03:38,257 --> 00:03:41,399
No, I thought I knew the British

38
00:03:41,479 --> 00:03:46,422
and I had the opinion
that they would see this thing through

39
00:03:46,504 --> 00:03:49,112
and that the United States
would join the war,

40
00:03:49,190 --> 00:03:53,248
and therefore
every effort should be made

41
00:03:53,333 --> 00:03:56,399
to prepare for a long blockade.

42
00:03:56,478 --> 00:03:58,464
(crowd cheers)

43
00:04:00,161 --> 00:04:02,998
(narrator) Hitler had no plans
for a long struggle,

44
00:04:03,499 --> 00:04:07,601
no preparations for the total
mobilisation of all productive capacity.

45
00:04:07,680 --> 00:04:11,008
German industry had been geared
to a blitzkrieg war.

46
00:04:11,094 --> 00:04:16,190
The regime still let the factories
turn out peacetime goods.

47
00:04:18,076 --> 00:04:21,371
The workers, subjugated
but not fully converted,

48
00:04:21,452 --> 00:04:26,198
watched the comings and goings
of the Nazi princes without enthusiasm.

49
00:04:32,078 --> 00:04:35,678
Wanting to be loved,
the Nazis gave and gave.

50
00:04:35,761 --> 00:04:40,125
For 1940, propaganda minister
Dr Goebbels was Father Christmas.

51
00:04:41,784 --> 00:04:44,467
He gave to children. He gave to mothers.

52
00:04:44,546 --> 00:04:48,604
(newsreel) In Berlin wurde der neue Film
"Mutterliebe" uraufgefürht.

53
00:04:48,689 --> 00:04:51,406
Auf Veranlassung
von Reichsminister Dr. Goebbels

54
00:04:51,489 --> 00:04:53,289
Iud die NSV 1.200 Trägerinnen...

55
00:04:53,369 --> 00:04:55,321
(narrator) Ladies with larger broods

56
00:04:55,402 --> 00:04:58,468
were invited to the film premiere
of Mother Love,

57
00:04:58,548 --> 00:05:02,988
the regime's hymn to family
and folk community.

58
00:05:03,113 --> 00:05:07,553
Das heißt, er wird uns ja vom Himmel
aus helfen, so gut er kann.

59
00:05:07,639 --> 00:05:09,701
Er wird mit dem lieben Gott sprechen.

60
00:05:09,787 --> 00:05:13,312
Und weil er so lustig ist
und alle Engel lachen macht...

61
00:05:13,393 --> 00:05:17,496
(narrator) On their breasts
they wore the Nazi Mother Cross.

62
00:05:20,107 --> 00:05:22,824
The pram was the tank of the home front.

63
00:05:22,907 --> 00:05:26,388
The government hoped
for a breakthrough on the birth rate.

64
00:05:26,513 --> 00:05:28,498
Happy babies, happy future mothers

65
00:05:28,585 --> 00:05:32,218
and very specially happy music
soused the nation.

66
00:05:32,344 --> 00:05:38,280
( march)

67
00:05:38,367 --> 00:05:40,930
The big smile glued across the face
of the people,

68
00:05:41,014 --> 00:05:45,149
still often dubious and nervous,
was stretched even wider.

69
00:05:47,842 --> 00:05:49,872
(singing in German)

70
00:06:01,537 --> 00:06:07,550
Everybody must learn to enjoy the happy
teamwork of Hitler's folk community.

71
00:06:13,007 --> 00:06:17,033
Vierzehn Uhr und eine Minute.
Der Wehrmachtsbericht.

72
00:06:17,112 --> 00:06:19,174
(narrator) Radio was the instrument

73
00:06:19,299 --> 00:06:22,245
which the Nazis made their own
from the beginning.

74
00:06:22,329 --> 00:06:24,391
Their foreign-language broadcasts,

75
00:06:24,478 --> 00:06:27,729
technically marvellous
but grotesquely unconvincing,

76
00:06:27,815 --> 00:06:31,339
reached greedily out to minds abroad.

77
00:06:31,421 --> 00:06:34,563
Today's official German war communiqué
reads as follows.

78
00:06:35,641 --> 00:06:39,318
(narrator) But listening
to foreign radio was forbidden.

79
00:06:39,400 --> 00:06:42,466
Many, like the propaganda comics
Tran and Helle,

80
00:06:42,546 --> 00:06:46,070
argued the toss between getting
a glimpse of the outside world

81
00:06:46,152 --> 00:06:49,064
and the risk of a jail sentence.

82
00:07:35,868 --> 00:07:40,429
(woman) If we listened to foreign radio,
which we always did,

83
00:07:40,510 --> 00:07:46,140
we turned it very low and we used
to sit right up close against it.

84
00:07:46,226 --> 00:07:51,441
And I remember one particular moment
when my son,

85
00:07:51,520 --> 00:07:54,542
who was a little schoolboy,

86
00:07:54,627 --> 00:07:58,763
told me that he had
a very funny story to tell me,

87
00:07:58,885 --> 00:08:02,181
that his friend's mother
also listened to the radio

88
00:08:02,261 --> 00:08:05,283
with her ear right up against it
the same as we did.

89
00:08:05,369 --> 00:08:08,467
I suddenly realised
that I could have her imprisoned

90
00:08:08,591 --> 00:08:10,500
and she could have me imprisoned,

91
00:08:10,586 --> 00:08:14,492
because these two children
had been talking about it.

92
00:08:16,110 --> 00:08:18,598
(narrator)
As well as geography and the rest,

93
00:08:18,680 --> 00:08:21,549
Nazi schools were obliged
to add a special subject.

94
00:08:21,634 --> 00:08:24,656
Children were taught
with pictures and measurements

95
00:08:24,741 --> 00:08:28,189
the dimensions of a healthy Aryan race.

96
00:08:28,270 --> 00:08:30,332
Official films prepared the Germans

97
00:08:30,457 --> 00:08:32,868
for the consequences
of keeping the race pure.

98
00:08:32,989 --> 00:08:36,240
The mentally incurable,
condemned as the bad seed,

99
00:08:36,326 --> 00:08:39,654
went to experimental gas chambers.

100
00:08:40,469 --> 00:08:42,455
(man speaks German)

101
00:09:23,127 --> 00:09:24,883
(narrator) But now, for once,

102
00:09:24,969 --> 00:09:27,838
the Germans learnt what was going on
and protested.

103
00:09:27,923 --> 00:09:32,101
Bishop Galen of Münster
attacked euthanasia from the pulpit.

104
00:09:32,181 --> 00:09:35,432
For a time, the programme was stopped.

105
00:09:36,094 --> 00:09:39,814
A controlled press
avoided such misgivings.

106
00:09:39,892 --> 00:09:43,612
Some newspapers were
mere party sheets of hate and lies.

107
00:09:43,689 --> 00:09:46,635
Some slipped criticism
between the lines.

108
00:09:46,720 --> 00:09:51,739
None of them satisfied a people
which was still highly educated.

109
00:09:51,822 --> 00:09:54,233
(man) It was terribly frustrating

110
00:09:54,315 --> 00:09:58,876
never to be allowed
to say your opinion openly.

111
00:09:58,996 --> 00:10:00,981
I myself was quite happy

112
00:10:01,067 --> 00:10:02,715
when I was called up,

113
00:10:02,832 --> 00:10:05,701
early 1940, to the army,

114
00:10:05,824 --> 00:10:10,538
and that suddenly left behind

115
00:10:10,696 --> 00:10:13,227
all the oppression I had every day.

116
00:10:13,304 --> 00:10:16,752
Being a soldier,
you don't read newspapers.

117
00:10:16,834 --> 00:10:19,168
You don't listen to the radio.

118
00:10:19,251 --> 00:10:24,040
You're not always under the stress
of the propaganda

119
00:10:24,122 --> 00:10:26,686
which was pointed at you every hour.

120
00:10:31,450 --> 00:10:34,821
(narrator) European war
became world war in June 1941.

121
00:10:34,902 --> 00:10:39,267
The Nazi leaders had secretly resolved
that the conquest of Russia must come.

122
00:10:39,352 --> 00:10:43,334
(newsreel) Reichsminister Dr. Goebbels
verliest die Proklamation des Führers.

123
00:10:43,457 --> 00:10:45,213
Deutsches Volk.

124
00:10:45,336 --> 00:10:49,973
In diesem Augenblick vollzieht sich
ein Aufmarsch, der...

125
00:10:50,400 --> 00:10:53,313
(narrator) For many, the attack
on the Soviet Union

126
00:10:53,392 --> 00:10:56,643
brought fear and bewilderment.

127
00:10:56,730 --> 00:11:02,905
Of course I'd heard
of certain preparations

128
00:11:02,983 --> 00:11:07,696
but it was all... well, hushed up,

129
00:11:07,816 --> 00:11:11,919
and till the last moment,

130
00:11:11,998 --> 00:11:14,867
I didn't think that the war
would come about.

131
00:11:17,330 --> 00:11:19,130
(narrator) For a long war,

132
00:11:19,210 --> 00:11:22,887
Germany would need to have the south
Russian oil fields for her own.

133
00:11:23,928 --> 00:11:27,070
Russia had delivered
a million tons of oil the previous year

134
00:11:27,151 --> 00:11:30,751
under the Nazi-Soviet Pact,
now flung away.

135
00:11:30,833 --> 00:11:32,360
(Kehrl) As a matter of fact

136
00:11:32,444 --> 00:11:35,925
we had the greatest trade agreements
with them that we ever had

137
00:11:36,012 --> 00:11:38,041
and they delivered promptly,

138
00:11:38,122 --> 00:11:45,137
and from an economic point of view
everything seemed to be in order.

139
00:11:45,257 --> 00:11:51,662
I personally had, through my men,

140
00:11:51,779 --> 00:11:58,412
negotiations with them of putting up
a synthetic fibre mill in Russia

141
00:11:58,492 --> 00:12:04,275
and the treaty was signed
on 15 June, 1941,

142
00:12:04,361 --> 00:12:08,387
and the first ten million marks in gold

143
00:12:08,466 --> 00:12:12,415
should be shipped on July 1, 1941.

144
00:12:12,494 --> 00:12:14,479
(woman sings in German)

145
00:12:19,936 --> 00:12:24,267
(narrator) The Germans drove eastwards
over disintegrating Russian armies.

146
00:12:28,107 --> 00:12:31,282
Victory looked like a matter of weeks,
another blitzkrieg,

147
00:12:31,406 --> 00:12:34,396
and morale at home revived.

148
00:12:44,603 --> 00:12:48,050
Göring inspected what was now
the German colony of Ukraine,

149
00:12:48,132 --> 00:12:51,350
intended to be a serf region
of agriculture.

150
00:12:51,431 --> 00:12:54,802
Nazi experts on the Slavs hoped
that this simple folk

151
00:12:54,884 --> 00:12:59,215
with simple customs
would enjoy this prospect.

152
00:12:59,295 --> 00:13:03,092
Six months later,
in the blinding snow before Moscow,

153
00:13:03,170 --> 00:13:04,970
the Germans were stopped.

154
00:13:11,072 --> 00:13:12,676
They lacked winter clothing

155
00:13:12,760 --> 00:13:15,979
and the government appealed
for furs and warm coats.

156
00:13:17,172 --> 00:13:19,277
An den letzten Tagen
der Sammlung drängen

157
00:13:19,358 --> 00:13:22,195
drängen sich vor den Annahmestellen
die Gebefreudigen,

158
00:13:22,274 --> 00:13:23,692
um ihre Spenden abzuliefern.

159
00:13:23,770 --> 00:13:27,873
Tut Ihnen das nicht leid? So einen
schönen Pelz? Oh, ist das warm da drin.

160
00:13:27,990 --> 00:13:30,445
(narrator) No amount
of rehearsed enthusiasm

161
00:13:30,521 --> 00:13:35,235
could conceal that this was
the Reich's first military reverse.

162
00:13:42,183 --> 00:13:45,816
The minister of munitions
and head of the war effort Fritz Todt

163
00:13:45,904 --> 00:13:50,083
flew to inspect the construction work
on the Eastern Front.

164
00:13:50,163 --> 00:13:53,883
One of the men who should have been
on the plane was Hitler's architect,

165
00:13:53,960 --> 00:13:57,790
the producer of the Nuremberg rallies,
Albert Speer.

166
00:13:57,873 --> 00:14:02,936
I heard in the headquarters
that Todt's plane crashed.

167
00:14:03,014 --> 00:14:08,611
He was dead. And half an hour afterwards
I was asked to come to Hitler

168
00:14:08,691 --> 00:14:11,375
and to my great surprise he told me,

169
00:14:11,453 --> 00:14:15,173
"You shall be
his successor in all his offices."

170
00:14:19,279 --> 00:14:22,345
Todt got the funeral
of a National Socialist hero.

171
00:14:38,038 --> 00:14:41,595
By now nearly 250,000 Germans
had been killed on the battle fronts,

172
00:14:41,682 --> 00:14:46,013
but Todt was the first of Hitler's
close comrades to meet death in the war.

173
00:14:46,132 --> 00:14:50,387
Hitler was shaken.
The war had reached him personally.

174
00:15:02,052 --> 00:15:05,118
Speer had already seen the chaotic,
disconnected way

175
00:15:05,198 --> 00:15:07,031
that Nazi war industry worked.

176
00:15:07,116 --> 00:15:13,171
Transport, munitions - all had to be
brought under a single control.

177
00:15:17,780 --> 00:15:21,501
One of his first targets
was the labour supply.

178
00:15:21,617 --> 00:15:25,446
Nazi Germany had never mobilised
its full workforce.

179
00:15:25,530 --> 00:15:30,276
(Speer) I tried to get the women
in the war production machinery,

180
00:15:30,363 --> 00:15:35,273
but it was opposed by Sauckel
who was in charge of all the labour.

181
00:15:35,350 --> 00:15:38,721
And the thing came to Göring
and Göring flatly denied, too.

182
00:15:38,803 --> 00:15:40,941
Then it came to the decision of Hitler,

183
00:15:41,028 --> 00:15:44,475
and Hitler also said,
"No, the women must be preserved."

184
00:15:44,557 --> 00:15:49,226
"They have other tasks. They are for
the family. They have to bear children

185
00:15:49,314 --> 00:15:54,606
and it would spoil their health
and their morale

186
00:15:54,684 --> 00:15:56,714
if they are working in the factories."

187
00:15:58,751 --> 00:16:02,122
(narrator) But Ukrainian women
were being imported as maids -

188
00:16:02,203 --> 00:16:05,345
foreign conscripts for slave labour.

189
00:16:05,426 --> 00:16:07,837
Under Speer,
a great irony was fulfilled,

190
00:16:07,919 --> 00:16:12,513
for Germany was becoming exactly what
the Nazis said it would not become.

191
00:16:12,599 --> 00:16:17,007
They had promised a return to the land,
an end to great capitalism.

192
00:16:17,088 --> 00:16:19,269
Instead, the armaments drive

193
00:16:19,351 --> 00:16:22,144
was strengthening
the vast industrial monopolies

194
00:16:22,228 --> 00:16:27,017
and swelling the cities
with German and foreign labour.

195
00:16:27,138 --> 00:16:28,513
In two and a half years,

196
00:16:28,596 --> 00:16:32,349
Speer multiplied armament production
nearly four times.

197
00:16:32,432 --> 00:16:35,803
80% of industry came under his control.

198
00:16:35,885 --> 00:16:41,023
He brushed aside bureaucracies
and worked through his own experts.

199
00:16:41,102 --> 00:16:46,656
(Kehrl) He had ideas
and he put all his energy

200
00:16:46,741 --> 00:16:48,846
behind these ideas

201
00:16:48,928 --> 00:16:52,648
and put them through
with very much success.

202
00:16:52,725 --> 00:16:54,907
He didn't know how things

203
00:16:55,027 --> 00:16:57,166
had been done in the past.

204
00:16:57,252 --> 00:16:59,391
He hadn't anything to do with it,

205
00:16:59,477 --> 00:17:03,459
so he didn't know what was impossible
and what was possible,

206
00:17:03,543 --> 00:17:07,296
and he succeeded sometimes
in doing the impossible, too.

207
00:17:08,722 --> 00:17:11,559
(Speer) It is astounding for everybody

208
00:17:11,676 --> 00:17:14,622
who didn't live
in our authoritarian system

209
00:17:14,707 --> 00:17:20,108
to hear that it was difficult
to get through with orders.

210
00:17:20,192 --> 00:17:21,687
But it was difficult

211
00:17:21,765 --> 00:17:27,439
because Germany was divided
into many districts, 32 districts.

212
00:17:27,519 --> 00:17:30,127
At the head of every district
was a Gauleiter.

213
00:17:30,243 --> 00:17:35,153
He was strong political man
and had absolute power in his district.

214
00:17:35,230 --> 00:17:39,179
He was only subordinated
to Hitler himself.

215
00:17:39,296 --> 00:17:43,432
So when my orders didn't please
one of the Gauleiters,

216
00:17:43,516 --> 00:17:46,506
possibly they weren't carried out.

217
00:17:48,925 --> 00:17:54,097
(narrator) Tank production showed how
even Speer failed to get all of his way.

218
00:17:54,181 --> 00:17:57,050
He could not slice through
the competing hierarchies

219
00:17:57,135 --> 00:17:59,349
in Hitler's chosen style of government.

220
00:17:59,436 --> 00:18:02,502
There were too many types of tanks.
Too few tanks in all.

221
00:18:02,582 --> 00:18:05,953
Too many calibres of gun
and different sizes of ammunition.

222
00:18:06,456 --> 00:18:09,937
(Speer) Hitler thought he was
far superior to such problems

223
00:18:10,024 --> 00:18:13,744
and what for others would have been
discussions of weeks and weeks

224
00:18:13,822 --> 00:18:17,881
for him was a decision
of just a fraction of a minute.

225
00:18:17,965 --> 00:18:19,721
Of course, there was a change, too.

226
00:18:19,806 --> 00:18:22,981
One can never say
that a man is always the same person,

227
00:18:23,067 --> 00:18:26,362
and Hitler changed a lot
from '42 to '43.

228
00:18:26,443 --> 00:18:29,465
In '43 he was more and more convinced

229
00:18:29,550 --> 00:18:32,114
that he didn't need
any more advice of anybody

230
00:18:32,197 --> 00:18:36,223
and he made the decisions
by himself without listening.

231
00:18:38,335 --> 00:18:41,706
(narrator) Hitler spent
more and more time at the Wolf's Lair,

232
00:18:41,787 --> 00:18:44,504
his melancholy, remote encampment
at Rastenburg

233
00:18:44,588 --> 00:18:47,076
in the East Prussian forest.

234
00:18:47,158 --> 00:18:50,028
Those around him were obsequious.

235
00:18:50,112 --> 00:18:52,795
The better advisers lost touch.

236
00:18:56,096 --> 00:19:01,192
Hitler's personal SS adjutant
was Richard Schulze-Kossens.

237
00:19:01,275 --> 00:19:05,530
(Schulze-Kossens) Nearly all ministers
were stationed at Berlin

238
00:19:05,610 --> 00:19:11,622
and some of them had contact officers
in the headquarters.

239
00:19:11,748 --> 00:19:16,308
Only Ribbentrop, Himmler and sometimes
Göring had their own headquarters,

240
00:19:16,390 --> 00:19:19,259
not so far from our headquarters.

241
00:19:20,418 --> 00:19:23,058
Speer was very often in the headquarters

242
00:19:23,141 --> 00:19:27,963
because his ministry
was very important for the war.

243
00:19:28,052 --> 00:19:31,848
Only Bormann
was always in the headquarters

244
00:19:31,926 --> 00:19:36,716
where there was
the only direct contact to Hitler.

245
00:19:36,798 --> 00:19:40,017
(Speer) Bormann, as the secretary,
was the most powerful man -

246
00:19:40,174 --> 00:19:44,888
more powerful, I think, than Hitler,
because when the power was divided,

247
00:19:45,007 --> 00:19:50,452
all those men who were in power
had to go via him to Hitler.

248
00:19:50,531 --> 00:19:55,278
Except me.
I had direct access to Hitler.

249
00:19:55,365 --> 00:19:57,427
There wasn't much cooperation.

250
00:19:57,513 --> 00:20:02,499
The cooperation was in the lower levels
of the smaller technocrats.

251
00:20:02,654 --> 00:20:05,566
We didn't have anything like a cabinet.

252
00:20:05,646 --> 00:20:09,519
Ministers met, if at all, very seldom

253
00:20:09,597 --> 00:20:12,739
and didn't talk about
very important matters -

254
00:20:12,858 --> 00:20:15,269
so was my impression.

255
00:20:15,351 --> 00:20:18,570
Every ministry worked for itself

256
00:20:18,651 --> 00:20:24,204
and sometimes they got orders
from Hitler, but very, very seldom.

257
00:20:25,594 --> 00:20:29,118
(narrator) Foreign visitors
like Mannerheim, the Finnish leader,

258
00:20:29,200 --> 00:20:32,069
could see that Hitler was living
in a world of illusion.

259
00:20:32,154 --> 00:20:36,103
He still trusted the reassurances
of Göring, head of the Luftwaffe.

260
00:20:36,182 --> 00:20:37,785
Göring, a few months later,

261
00:20:37,870 --> 00:20:40,968
claimed that his aircraft
could supply the Eastern Front

262
00:20:41,054 --> 00:20:43,966
even when a whole army
was cut off at Stalingrad.

263
00:20:44,506 --> 00:20:47,834
(man #1) Achtung,
ich rufe noch einmal Stalingrad.

264
00:20:47,920 --> 00:20:51,673
(man #2) Hier Stalingrad.
Hier ist die Front an der Wolga.

265
00:20:52,140 --> 00:20:55,206
(man #1) Achtung,
die U-Bootfahrer im Atlantik.

266
00:20:55,324 --> 00:20:57,691
(narrator) Christmas 1942.

267
00:20:59,160 --> 00:21:01,571
(man #1) Achtung, Catania.

268
00:21:01,654 --> 00:21:04,217
(man #3) Hier ist die Mittelmeerfront
und Afrika.

269
00:21:04,301 --> 00:21:06,057
(narrator) The man at Stalingrad

270
00:21:06,142 --> 00:21:08,750
had come th rough
on the radio link-up loud and clear,

271
00:21:08,827 --> 00:21:13,235
but the brave words
were faked in a Berlin studio.

272
00:21:15,157 --> 00:21:17,142
( "Stille Nacht")

273
00:21:25,054 --> 00:21:28,196
For the last time
the cathedral stood undamaged

274
00:21:28,277 --> 00:21:30,535
as the Christmas fair
took place in Berlin.

275
00:21:31,269 --> 00:21:34,182
But Stalingrad was still cut off

276
00:21:34,261 --> 00:21:37,709
and deep down the nation sensed
what was to happen.

277
00:21:37,790 --> 00:21:40,246
(man) Dritter Februar.

278
00:21:40,322 --> 00:21:44,304
Das Oberkommando
der Wehrmacht gibt bekannt:

279
00:21:44,389 --> 00:21:46,996
Der Kampf um Stalingrad ist zu Ende.

280
00:21:47,112 --> 00:21:51,597
(narrator) "The Battle of Stalingrad
has come to an end."

281
00:21:51,677 --> 00:21:55,703
For once the radio spoke the truth,
and with some dignity.

282
00:21:55,782 --> 00:21:59,612
91,000 survivors surrendered.

283
00:21:59,695 --> 00:22:03,798
Only a few thousand
ever saw Germany again.

284
00:22:03,876 --> 00:22:06,713
I was not long in the headquarters

285
00:22:06,792 --> 00:22:12,040
but I felt very significant
the atmosphere on this day.

286
00:22:13,275 --> 00:22:16,494
All people were depressed

287
00:22:16,574 --> 00:22:20,905
and Hitler himself was very serious

288
00:22:20,986 --> 00:22:25,350
and he started on his soup

289
00:22:25,436 --> 00:22:29,614
without saying any word, and...

290
00:22:30,653 --> 00:22:34,711
He was... He was very depressed.

291
00:22:44,003 --> 00:22:45,803
(narrator) The world realised

292
00:22:45,882 --> 00:22:50,061
and the Germans realised
that this was the turning point.

293
00:22:50,140 --> 00:22:54,047
This was the tragedy
which could not be hidden.

294
00:23:00,536 --> 00:23:04,366
And Stalingrad did not come alone.
A week before the city fell,

295
00:23:04,449 --> 00:23:10,429
the Germans learned that the Allies
would demand unconditional surrender.

296
00:23:12,505 --> 00:23:15,571
There was, then,
to be no mercy for the Germans.

297
00:23:15,651 --> 00:23:19,022
Nazi and non-Nazi
both lost some illusions

298
00:23:19,103 --> 00:23:21,318
and drew a little closer together.

299
00:23:21,405 --> 00:23:23,664
The escape hatches had been bolted.

300
00:23:23,784 --> 00:23:27,461
This was to be a total war,
fought to the finish.

301
00:23:29,461 --> 00:23:32,909
(Bielenberg) The general feeling was,
well, we can do nothing.

302
00:23:32,990 --> 00:23:36,710
It doesn't matter what we do.
We'd better stick it out.

303
00:23:36,788 --> 00:23:40,967
Ausharren was the word,
I remember, on everyone's lips.

304
00:23:41,046 --> 00:23:45,836
There's no alternative.
We've got to fight to the bitter end.

305
00:23:45,918 --> 00:23:50,981
And this Goebbels used to the uttermost
in his propaganda.

306
00:23:54,665 --> 00:23:56,694
(cheering)

307
00:23:57,235 --> 00:23:59,340
(narrator) Two weeks after Stalingrad,

308
00:23:59,422 --> 00:24:02,825
Goebbels brought a picked
Nazi audience to a last mass frenzy.

309
00:24:20,405 --> 00:24:23,930
(narrator) It was his supreme moment,
the proclaiming of total war

310
00:24:24,011 --> 00:24:27,885
and the invoking
of the nation's hidden power.

311
00:24:50,404 --> 00:24:54,430
(narrator) "Now, folk, rise up
and storm, break loose."

312
00:24:54,509 --> 00:24:57,040
They were the words of 1812,

313
00:24:57,117 --> 00:25:01,176
of the national uprising
against Napoleon.

314
00:25:01,260 --> 00:25:02,941
They were empty now.

315
00:25:06,401 --> 00:25:08,540
( fanfare)

316
00:25:16,106 --> 00:25:20,285
In 1943 it was better
listening to music than to news.

317
00:25:23,740 --> 00:25:25,802
(sings in German)

318
00:25:32,257 --> 00:25:35,355
(narrator) It was total war
and retreat on all fronts.

319
00:25:35,441 --> 00:25:39,270
Total war meant that even
German women must work.

320
00:25:43,727 --> 00:25:46,094
It brought its own sour humour.

321
00:25:46,182 --> 00:25:51,354
(Tucking) There was a slogan,
"Do enjoy war. Peace will be dreadful."

322
00:25:53,240 --> 00:25:55,193
(narrator) There was a new equality

323
00:25:55,274 --> 00:25:57,881
among the boys drafted
to the mines and factories.

324
00:25:57,959 --> 00:26:03,174
The Hitler Youth was mobilised into
production and eventually into battle.

325
00:26:03,253 --> 00:26:08,316
The barriers between people crumbled as
they had crumbled in the London Blitz.

326
00:26:10,273 --> 00:26:14,255
People wanted to huddle together,
to sing and forget.

327
00:26:14,378 --> 00:26:16,909
By the morning, they might be dead.

328
00:26:22,050 --> 00:26:24,232
(gunfire)

329
00:26:27,996 --> 00:26:31,520
By day the American bomber fleets
ranged over the Reich.

330
00:26:31,602 --> 00:26:33,631
At night came the British.

331
00:26:33,712 --> 00:26:35,970
In the shelters
the people waited for dawn

332
00:26:36,052 --> 00:26:38,615
and wondered if their cities
would still be there.

333
00:26:40,118 --> 00:26:44,374
(Tucking) When we had the first bombs,
we were shocked.

334
00:26:44,453 --> 00:26:49,275
We saw all the sky
lighted up from the fire.

335
00:26:49,363 --> 00:26:53,160
It was an enormous and a dreadful sight.

336
00:26:54,274 --> 00:26:56,608
We were very angry when we saw

337
00:26:56,729 --> 00:27:01,639
that so many residential areas
were destroyed.

338
00:27:01,716 --> 00:27:04,323
There were so few men left

339
00:27:04,401 --> 00:27:09,147
that everybody who had
the strength was firefighting.

340
00:27:19,324 --> 00:27:23,612
(narrator) One by one the German cities
were incinerated by firestorms.

341
00:27:23,735 --> 00:27:27,717
Ten days' raids on Hamburg
left 40,000 dead.

342
00:27:33,518 --> 00:27:36,201
Goebbels noted, "The people in the west

343
00:27:36,280 --> 00:27:38,843
are gradually beginning
to lose courage."

344
00:27:38,927 --> 00:27:42,068
"Hell like that is hard to bear."

345
00:27:46,177 --> 00:27:48,282
(Bielenberg) I think that the bombing

346
00:27:48,364 --> 00:27:50,730
hadn't the effect
one would have thought.

347
00:27:50,857 --> 00:27:54,414
It had the effect
of bringing people together.

348
00:27:54,501 --> 00:27:56,760
If you were all under the same bombs,

349
00:27:56,841 --> 00:27:59,558
it didn't matter whether your neighbour
was a Nazi

350
00:27:59,642 --> 00:28:01,475
or what they were.

351
00:28:07,084 --> 00:28:09,189
(narrator) To avoid seeing the ruins,

352
00:28:09,271 --> 00:28:12,063
Hitler's rare visits to Berlin
were made by night.

353
00:28:12,148 --> 00:28:15,900
And yet banners were ordered
for his birthday.

354
00:28:15,984 --> 00:28:21,122
They read, "Our walls have broken,
but not our hearts."

355
00:28:21,930 --> 00:28:27,025
(Junge) Hitler lost more and more
his sense of reality.

356
00:28:27,109 --> 00:28:29,792
He never, never had the will

357
00:28:29,871 --> 00:28:34,934
that he must see with his own eyes
what the war was.

358
00:28:37,159 --> 00:28:40,640
We had no information from outside

359
00:28:40,727 --> 00:28:46,324
and so I had the feeling
to live in a monastery,

360
00:28:46,405 --> 00:28:51,151
in a concentration camp.

361
00:28:51,238 --> 00:28:55,646
One of the generals once said,
"I feel like a concentration camp."

362
00:28:55,727 --> 00:28:58,410
"We are included

363
00:28:58,489 --> 00:29:02,896
and we all use the same phrases."

364
00:29:03,015 --> 00:29:06,266
"We are all thinking the same.
We are all hearing the same."

365
00:29:06,353 --> 00:29:10,837
"We are all led in our thoughts

366
00:29:10,918 --> 00:29:13,481
and our feelings by Hitler."

367
00:29:14,524 --> 00:29:18,888
We all were playing in a play,
each his role

368
00:29:18,974 --> 00:29:22,726
and he was the only one
who knew the script.

369
00:29:22,810 --> 00:29:27,447
He made us all do our play
and speak our text.

370
00:29:27,528 --> 00:29:31,161
Nobody else knew how it would end.

371
00:29:35,507 --> 00:29:41,366
Neither Hitler nor Göring nor Himmler
were seen in public. Only Goebbels.

372
00:29:43,487 --> 00:29:46,553
Whenever there was
a very heavy bombing,

373
00:29:46,671 --> 00:29:51,308
Goebbels stood there on the marketplace
and held his speeches

374
00:29:51,389 --> 00:29:55,339
and tried to say ausharren.

375
00:29:56,069 --> 00:29:58,939
I personally had respect,

376
00:29:59,023 --> 00:30:02,929
because there was a sort of inspiring.

377
00:30:03,435 --> 00:30:05,998
You were sort of in a trance.

378
00:30:08,307 --> 00:30:11,448
( "The Mastersingers of Nuremberg" -
Wagner)

379
00:30:16,861 --> 00:30:21,727
(narrator) A strained, exhausted nation
could still lose itself in music.

380
00:30:25,915 --> 00:30:29,210
The orchestras still gave
what was great and true

381
00:30:29,290 --> 00:30:31,014
in the tradition of German art.

382
00:30:33,165 --> 00:30:35,925
In the galleries there was only
the empty grimacing

383
00:30:36,004 --> 00:30:39,146
of Nazi painting, Nazi sculpture.

384
00:30:47,512 --> 00:30:49,651
True Aryan models simpered and scowled,

385
00:30:49,776 --> 00:30:54,565
their features carefully designed
to portray the victorious Nordic race.

386
00:31:01,629 --> 00:31:04,880
Race was the empire
of Himmler and the SS.

387
00:31:06,309 --> 00:31:08,568
But now the SS was itself an empire.

388
00:31:08,649 --> 00:31:10,755
Himmler, the ex-chicken-farmer,

389
00:31:10,836 --> 00:31:13,935
ruled the death camps
and the concentration camps.

390
00:31:14,634 --> 00:31:18,965
The SS had its own schools
and factories and courts.

391
00:31:19,045 --> 00:31:22,603
It administered huge tracts
of the occupied east.

392
00:31:22,690 --> 00:31:27,098
It was the instrument of German dominion
over Europe. It was even an army.

393
00:31:27,255 --> 00:31:29,011
The generals had little control

394
00:31:29,173 --> 00:31:33,690
over the hundreds of thousands
of elite troops in the Waffen-SS.

395
00:31:34,237 --> 00:31:37,869
Into the SS training schools were drawn
Aryan-looking volunteers

396
00:31:37,958 --> 00:31:39,638
from the occupied countries,

397
00:31:39,722 --> 00:31:43,978
for the SS state was to be
not merely German but European.

398
00:31:44,096 --> 00:31:48,460
(Schulze-Kossens) All had volunteered
for active service in the Waffen-SS

399
00:31:48,546 --> 00:31:52,681
because they regarded
the fight against Bolshevism

400
00:31:52,765 --> 00:31:55,558
as the most important task in Europe.

401
00:31:55,681 --> 00:32:01,693
New was the point of European education

402
00:32:01,780 --> 00:32:04,770
because we were of the opinion

403
00:32:04,849 --> 00:32:09,563
that only an imaginary contrast

404
00:32:09,644 --> 00:32:13,092
existed between the nations

405
00:32:13,212 --> 00:32:17,772
who had the same
or were from the same origin, yes.

406
00:32:21,306 --> 00:32:24,754
(narrator) For those of different
race origin, there was no place.

407
00:32:24,874 --> 00:32:28,092
For the Jews there was deportation
to eastern ghettos

408
00:32:28,173 --> 00:32:31,392
and then the gas chambers of the SS.

409
00:32:31,472 --> 00:32:34,112
The official word was "resettlement".

410
00:32:34,196 --> 00:32:38,680
Most Germans preferred to believe
that it meant no more than that.

411
00:32:38,761 --> 00:32:43,671
(Speer) Hitler often mentioned
that he is hating the Jews

412
00:32:43,748 --> 00:32:49,269
and he gave many examples already
in an early time when I was with him,

413
00:32:49,349 --> 00:32:54,641
and I should have been warned
that he is serious about it

414
00:32:54,719 --> 00:32:59,160
because he proved to be serious
about other things he predicted too.

415
00:32:59,284 --> 00:33:01,346
(speaks German)

416
00:33:03,466 --> 00:33:08,026
(translator) One night, it must have
been around midnight, the doorbell rang.

417
00:33:08,107 --> 00:33:10,137
I opened it and in front of me

418
00:33:10,256 --> 00:33:12,438
there stood a Jewish couple.

419
00:33:12,519 --> 00:33:16,348
This was how I began
to help persecuted Jews.

420
00:33:16,432 --> 00:33:20,152
All of a sudden I'd entered
into an invisible circle

421
00:33:20,230 --> 00:33:23,067
of people who smuggled Jews about.

422
00:33:23,145 --> 00:33:26,135
As soon as one hiding place
had been detected,

423
00:33:26,214 --> 00:33:28,047
they were quickly passed on.

424
00:33:28,132 --> 00:33:30,925
They'd always move about at night.

425
00:33:31,009 --> 00:33:34,686
That's how I came to belong to a group
who had to put up Jews

426
00:33:34,769 --> 00:33:37,180
when they were passed on like this.

427
00:33:37,262 --> 00:33:42,173
I've never found out who it was who'd
sent them to me in the first place.

428
00:33:42,249 --> 00:33:44,660
Decent people, I'm sure.

429
00:33:44,743 --> 00:33:48,420
The problems started
with the feeding of the Jewish people.

430
00:33:48,502 --> 00:33:53,096
They neither had food rationing cards
nor did they have any money,

431
00:33:53,182 --> 00:33:56,586
so we in our turn made use of friends

432
00:33:56,712 --> 00:33:59,079
who exchanged
their cigarette ration cards

433
00:33:59,167 --> 00:34:02,724
for the odd potato or some bread.

434
00:34:07,683 --> 00:34:13,586
One day a friend of ours who used
to collect food cards for these Jews

435
00:34:13,667 --> 00:34:19,264
came to me and she came
with another woman

436
00:34:19,345 --> 00:34:21,876
with dyed blonde hair.

437
00:34:22,529 --> 00:34:27,046
I can see her sitting there now
twisting her wedding ring

438
00:34:27,132 --> 00:34:30,929
and telling me
that it wouldn't be for long,

439
00:34:31,007 --> 00:34:36,561
that she would help me in the house
and her husband need never go out.

440
00:34:36,646 --> 00:34:39,668
He could live in the cellar or wherever.

441
00:34:39,753 --> 00:34:42,743
(narrator) But Christabel Bielenberg's
husband was away

442
00:34:42,822 --> 00:34:45,539
and was involved
in a plot to overthrow Hitler.

443
00:34:45,623 --> 00:34:49,300
She consulted her trusted neighbour
and friend Carl Langbehn,

444
00:34:49,382 --> 00:34:50,756
another conspirator.

445
00:34:50,840 --> 00:34:53,633
Langbehn told her
compassionately but firmly

446
00:34:53,717 --> 00:34:59,620
that the risks to herself and her family
and to the conspiracy were too great.

447
00:34:59,701 --> 00:35:02,876
I was astonished - overcome, really -

448
00:35:02,962 --> 00:35:05,755
at the response
that I got from my neighbour

449
00:35:05,839 --> 00:35:11,207
who told me that under no circumstances
whatsoever could I house these people,

450
00:35:11,287 --> 00:35:14,079
that housing of Jews
meant concentration camp

451
00:35:14,164 --> 00:35:18,910
not only for myself but for my husband,
possibly also for my children.

452
00:35:19,995 --> 00:35:23,475
I can remember going through
and out into the road

453
00:35:23,601 --> 00:35:29,580
and out of the darkness came a voice -
I knew there was somebody there -

454
00:35:29,662 --> 00:35:31,691
came a voice saying:

455
00:35:31,772 --> 00:35:35,645
"Frau Doktor... Frau Bielenberg,

456
00:35:35,723 --> 00:35:37,862
haben Sie einen Schluss gefasst?"

457
00:35:37,948 --> 00:35:40,741
which means, "Have you decided?"

458
00:35:41,746 --> 00:35:45,619
And I simply couldn't say no.

459
00:35:45,735 --> 00:35:51,518
I just said, "Well, I can't
for longer than two days."

460
00:35:54,482 --> 00:35:59,806
And I let him into the cellar.

461
00:36:01,348 --> 00:36:05,374
They stayed for two days

462
00:36:05,453 --> 00:36:10,123
and on the second day

463
00:36:10,210 --> 00:36:12,698
or rather in the evening,
they must have left

464
00:36:12,780 --> 00:36:16,031
because in the morning she was gone,

465
00:36:16,118 --> 00:36:18,147
the cellar was empty,

466
00:36:18,228 --> 00:36:22,286
the little bed I'd put up
all tidily arranged

467
00:36:22,371 --> 00:36:24,509
and they had gone.

468
00:36:26,015 --> 00:36:29,889
I knew later that they were caught

469
00:36:29,966 --> 00:36:33,447
buying a ticket at a railway station

470
00:36:33,534 --> 00:36:36,523
and were transported to Auschwitz.

471
00:36:37,523 --> 00:36:41,702
And why I say this is
the most painful and terrible story

472
00:36:41,782 --> 00:36:43,233
for me to have to tell

473
00:36:43,316 --> 00:36:45,924
is because after they left

474
00:36:46,001 --> 00:36:51,828
I realised that Hitler
had turned me into a murderer.

475
00:36:53,942 --> 00:36:57,193
One day in '44,

476
00:36:57,280 --> 00:37:01,720
Gauleiter Hanke came in my office
and told me

477
00:37:01,806 --> 00:37:07,403
that he was visiting
a concentration camp in Upper Silesia

478
00:37:07,484 --> 00:37:12,230
and warned me never to go
in a concentration camp there

479
00:37:12,317 --> 00:37:15,264
because horrible things would happen.

480
00:37:15,348 --> 00:37:19,407
This together with other hints I got

481
00:37:19,491 --> 00:37:24,859
should have made my decision

482
00:37:24,977 --> 00:37:27,966
to go to Hitler immediately
or to Himmler

483
00:37:28,046 --> 00:37:30,729
and to ask them what is going on

484
00:37:30,808 --> 00:37:34,560
and to take my own steps.

485
00:37:34,644 --> 00:37:40,088
But I didn't do it and not doing it
was, I think nowadays,

486
00:37:40,168 --> 00:37:43,419
the biggest fault in my life.

487
00:37:43,505 --> 00:37:46,909
We felt that people should know

488
00:37:46,996 --> 00:37:49,451
what was going on,

489
00:37:49,528 --> 00:37:52,365
and maybe typical
is this little experience

490
00:37:52,444 --> 00:37:54,200
which I had one day

491
00:37:54,285 --> 00:37:58,234
standing in the line for vegetables
or something like that.

492
00:37:58,313 --> 00:38:01,487
I told my neighbours standing around me

493
00:38:01,574 --> 00:38:07,247
that now they start to kill the Jews
in the concentration camps,

494
00:38:07,328 --> 00:38:10,274
that it is not true
that they only are brought there

495
00:38:10,359 --> 00:38:14,111
and can live there as they live here,
as it was told them.

496
00:38:14,195 --> 00:38:18,068
They are killed
and they even make soap out of them.

497
00:38:18,146 --> 00:38:21,092
I know that.

498
00:38:21,215 --> 00:38:26,201
And they said, "Frau Bonhoeffer, if you
don't stop telling such horror stories

499
00:38:26,279 --> 00:38:29,999
you will end in a concentration camp too
and nobody of us can help you."

500
00:38:30,076 --> 00:38:31,986
"It's not true what you're telling."

501
00:38:32,110 --> 00:38:36,594
"You shouldn't believe these things.
You heard them from foreign broadcasts."

502
00:38:36,675 --> 00:38:40,352
"They tell these things
to make enemies against Germany."

503
00:38:40,434 --> 00:38:45,104
I said, "No, that's not from broadcasts.
I know that directly from first hand."

504
00:38:45,191 --> 00:38:48,180
"You can be sure it is that way."

505
00:38:48,260 --> 00:38:52,012
And coming home
I told my husband in the evening

506
00:38:52,134 --> 00:38:56,924
and he was not at all applauding to me -
on the very contrary.

507
00:38:57,006 --> 00:39:00,531
He said, "My dear, sorry to say,

508
00:39:00,612 --> 00:39:04,332
but you are absolutely idiotic,
what you are doing."

509
00:39:04,448 --> 00:39:06,859
"Please understand,

510
00:39:06,942 --> 00:39:11,350
a dictatorship is like a snake."

511
00:39:11,430 --> 00:39:14,300
"If you put your foot on its tail,

512
00:39:14,384 --> 00:39:17,984
as you do it, it will just bite you

513
00:39:18,067 --> 00:39:20,859
and nobody will be helped."

514
00:39:20,944 --> 00:39:22,820
"You have to strike the head."

515
00:39:24,972 --> 00:39:27,230
(narrator)
Only the commanders of the army

516
00:39:27,312 --> 00:39:29,570
could strike effectively at the head.

517
00:39:29,652 --> 00:39:33,525
Others had struck bravely
at the tail and perished.

518
00:39:33,642 --> 00:39:36,969
In Munich, a few students around
the Scholl brother and sister

519
00:39:37,094 --> 00:39:39,734
had protested with leaflets
and been slaughtered.

520
00:39:39,856 --> 00:39:41,918
In Berlin a communist spy team

521
00:39:42,004 --> 00:39:47,023
led by Harro Schulze-Boysen
and the Harnacks had been crushed.

522
00:39:47,106 --> 00:39:50,587
Communists, socialists, Christians,
anonymous men and women

523
00:39:50,674 --> 00:39:53,162
defied the dictator in tiny groups.

524
00:39:53,283 --> 00:39:59,295
150,000 Germans suffered prison or worse
for political resistance.

525
00:39:59,382 --> 00:40:02,175
The plot against the snake's head
was a federation.

526
00:40:02,259 --> 00:40:05,936
There were conservatives like Goerdeler,
aristocrats like Moltke,

527
00:40:06,057 --> 00:40:10,192
churchmen like Bonhoeffer,
diplomats like Trott.

528
00:40:10,277 --> 00:40:14,488
Faced with defeat,
many staff officers joined in.

529
00:40:14,573 --> 00:40:17,825
All were slow to accept
that to strike at the head

530
00:40:17,911 --> 00:40:20,628
demanded the physical murder of Hitler.

531
00:40:21,133 --> 00:40:24,886
But in 1944, there appeared
a man for action -

532
00:40:24,969 --> 00:40:28,570
Colonel Count Claus von Stauffenberg.

533
00:40:28,652 --> 00:40:31,292
(man) All the difference was brought in,
of course,

534
00:40:31,414 --> 00:40:33,247
when Stauffenberg came to Berlin.

535
00:40:33,332 --> 00:40:36,202
He had lost his left eye,

536
00:40:36,286 --> 00:40:38,042
his left hand,

537
00:40:38,166 --> 00:40:40,195
or three fingers of his left hand,

538
00:40:40,276 --> 00:40:42,959
and his right hand altogether.

539
00:40:43,038 --> 00:40:46,441
Originally he was only
the planner of the coup d'état,

540
00:40:46,529 --> 00:40:49,475
but he had to report
to Hitler's headquarters

541
00:40:49,559 --> 00:40:51,392
and to attend conferences there.

542
00:40:51,477 --> 00:40:55,077
This enabled him to get near to Hitler
and then to make an attempt,

543
00:40:55,160 --> 00:40:57,920
which he did on July 20, '44.

544
00:40:57,999 --> 00:40:59,984
(explosion)

545
00:41:00,914 --> 00:41:06,544
(Junge) Suddenly there was
a very alarming bang.

546
00:41:06,630 --> 00:41:09,652
We heard voices crying for a doctor

547
00:41:09,776 --> 00:41:14,838
and we saw some generals
with bloodstained uniforms.

548
00:41:15,837 --> 00:41:17,670
Then came one of the adjutants

549
00:41:17,755 --> 00:41:22,469
and said, "There was a bomb explosion,
but the Führer is not hurt."

550
00:41:22,550 --> 00:41:24,426
"He's still alive."

551
00:41:24,507 --> 00:41:27,605
We went towards Hitler's bunker

552
00:41:27,691 --> 00:41:29,949
and we met him.

553
00:41:30,031 --> 00:41:34,548
Maybe it was an hour
after this explosion.

554
00:41:34,634 --> 00:41:38,769
He looked funny

555
00:41:38,854 --> 00:41:44,637
because his hair stood up like a brush

556
00:41:44,723 --> 00:41:48,171
and his trousers were slit

557
00:41:48,252 --> 00:41:50,860
in small stripes.

558
00:41:50,976 --> 00:41:56,421
He said, "You see,
fate has saved me for my mission."

559
00:41:56,500 --> 00:41:59,675
"I am to do what I must do."

560
00:42:01,794 --> 00:42:04,205
(narrator) At the War Ministry
in Berlin,

561
00:42:04,288 --> 00:42:08,390
the plotting generals
believed that Hitler was dead.

562
00:42:08,853 --> 00:42:13,217
(John) When I came to the headquarters,
Stauffenberg was busy with telephoning

563
00:42:13,303 --> 00:42:18,245
the various army commands, and Haeften
informed me of what had happened,

564
00:42:18,328 --> 00:42:23,074
how they'd thrown the bomb,
and then he said, "Hitler's dead."

565
00:42:23,161 --> 00:42:26,074
We did believe it
because Stauffenberg then came in.

566
00:42:26,154 --> 00:42:29,372
We had a short talk with him -
he was much too busy to give details.

567
00:42:29,453 --> 00:42:32,170
He said, "Hitler's dead.
Leave everything alone."

568
00:42:32,253 --> 00:42:33,901
"We'll see what can be done."

569
00:42:35,591 --> 00:42:39,726
(narrator) The man the plotters ordered
to occupy the city was Major Otto Remer,

570
00:42:39,810 --> 00:42:43,258
a fanatical soldier programmed
to obey any superior order.

571
00:42:43,340 --> 00:42:48,162
At first he obeyed the plotters,
then Goebbels got hold of him.

572
00:42:48,250 --> 00:42:50,203
(Remer speaks German)

573
00:42:55,232 --> 00:42:59,639
(translator) Goebbels was really
very pleased to see me. He was beaming.

574
00:42:59,720 --> 00:43:03,245
He said, "Remer,
what do you know about all this?"

575
00:43:03,326 --> 00:43:07,003
"What's going on here?
What orders have you got?"

576
00:43:07,085 --> 00:43:12,944
I said, "Minister, I have come to you
so that you can clarify the situation."

577
00:43:13,032 --> 00:43:16,708
Goebbels replied, "They're trying
to pull the wool over your eyes."

578
00:43:16,791 --> 00:43:20,620
"Hitler's alive.
I've just spoken to him."

579
00:43:20,704 --> 00:43:25,264
I was so astonished that I said,
"Please, let me speak to the Führer,"

580
00:43:25,346 --> 00:43:27,986
and this was done.

581
00:43:28,108 --> 00:43:33,203
On the other end of the line Hitler
said, "Herr Remer, you see I am alive."

582
00:43:33,286 --> 00:43:37,651
"I am Adolf Hitler.
You recognise my voice."

583
00:43:37,775 --> 00:43:40,142
"Now do you believe I'm alive?"

584
00:43:51,777 --> 00:43:54,111
(narrator) Now Remer was reprogrammed.

585
00:43:54,194 --> 00:43:57,794
He marched back to the War Ministry
and arrested everyone he found.

586
00:43:57,876 --> 00:44:03,201
The plot collapsed.
The wavering army returned to its oath.

587
00:44:03,861 --> 00:44:05,846
(man) Der Angeklagte von Witzleben.

588
00:44:05,932 --> 00:44:09,260
(narrator) Many of the plotters,
after prison and torture,

589
00:44:09,346 --> 00:44:11,222
were to face a ghastly sham trial

590
00:44:11,303 --> 00:44:16,704
conducted by Roland Freisler,
the star judge of Nazi Germany.

591
00:44:16,789 --> 00:44:21,425
Their families were seized
and their children sent to orphanages.

592
00:44:21,507 --> 00:44:24,344
The luckier conspirators,
among them Stauffenberg,

593
00:44:24,422 --> 00:44:27,412
had been shot out of hand
in the War Ministry courtyard.

594
00:44:27,491 --> 00:44:30,361
Some attempted
to explain their motives in court.

595
00:44:30,445 --> 00:44:34,165
Count von Schwerin was an officer
who had served in Poland.

596
00:44:54,076 --> 00:44:56,564
(judge)

597
00:45:03,244 --> 00:45:05,306
(judge)

598
00:45:16,364 --> 00:45:20,772
(narrator) The condemned were hanged
slowly on meat hooks.

599
00:45:20,852 --> 00:45:25,064
A film of their agony was made
and shown later to Hitler.

600
00:45:25,149 --> 00:45:28,673
But the plot left Hitler
a frightened, damaged man.

601
00:45:29,484 --> 00:45:33,619
The repression after 20 July
broke the power of the aristocracy

602
00:45:33,704 --> 00:45:36,387
and of the Prussian tradition forever.

603
00:45:36,466 --> 00:45:40,568
But there was no ruling class
to take their place.

604
00:45:42,143 --> 00:45:46,322
To Hitler, all generals
now seemed suspect.

605
00:45:46,401 --> 00:45:51,267
Only Goebbels, Bormann and Himmler
could get close to him.

606
00:45:56,951 --> 00:46:02,013
(Junge) Slowly but steadily
he became weak.

607
00:46:02,091 --> 00:46:07,797
The doctors went in and out
and he became totally apathetic.

608
00:46:07,884 --> 00:46:10,251
Not interested in anything.

609
00:46:10,339 --> 00:46:15,249
It was a very critical situation
on the West Front

610
00:46:15,326 --> 00:46:17,508
and on the East Front, too.

611
00:46:19,315 --> 00:46:24,607
And some days
it was like Hitler didn't exist.

612
00:46:25,492 --> 00:46:29,823
He was deteriorating suddenly
in his health,

613
00:46:29,903 --> 00:46:32,467
but I wouldn't go so far as to say

614
00:46:32,550 --> 00:46:36,380
that he was no more responsible
for what he was doing.

615
00:46:37,729 --> 00:46:39,911
In some ways he was...

616
00:46:39,992 --> 00:46:42,556
I have the experience
of a prisoner of 20 years.

617
00:46:42,639 --> 00:46:45,247
In some ways he was behaving
like a prisoner.

618
00:46:54,915 --> 00:46:59,704
(narrator) Through the devastation
the Germans somehow kept going.

619
00:47:01,436 --> 00:47:05,386
Down ruined streets, the workers
made their way to ruined factories

620
00:47:05,464 --> 00:47:08,486
where a few machines
could still be made to turn.

621
00:47:19,888 --> 00:47:22,529
Life retreated to the cellars.

622
00:47:23,955 --> 00:47:28,549
People learned that eight bombs fell
in a row and then you were safe.

623
00:47:28,635 --> 00:47:31,504
They learned to live a day at a time.

624
00:47:45,092 --> 00:47:48,114
(Tucking) It was really dreadful
to endure it.

625
00:47:48,890 --> 00:47:51,181
We were so tired.

626
00:47:51,268 --> 00:47:53,559
You were always in a hurry.

627
00:47:54,644 --> 00:47:59,554
All the railways were destroyed
and the lorries had no petrol.

628
00:47:59,631 --> 00:48:02,653
We had rations from the beginning

629
00:48:02,777 --> 00:48:06,803
and step by step it was worse and worse.

630
00:48:08,224 --> 00:48:11,901
(narrator) Germany itself
was near the end of its tether.

631
00:48:11,983 --> 00:48:15,965
Seven million foreign forced labourers
were not enough.

632
00:48:16,050 --> 00:48:20,458
Everything - oil, metal, food -
was running out.

633
00:48:20,576 --> 00:48:25,672
Everything from clothes to planes
was patched and made to serve again.

634
00:48:25,755 --> 00:48:27,740
Men, too.

635
00:48:30,819 --> 00:48:33,961
The war cripples were recycled
for the factories.

636
00:48:34,041 --> 00:48:37,522
The brain-damaged soldiers
were taught to speak again.

637
00:48:37,609 --> 00:48:40,980
Nun wollen wir einmal das hauchen.

638
00:48:41,062 --> 00:48:44,313
Was ist das für ein Laut?

639
00:48:44,399 --> 00:48:45,544
A.

640
00:48:45,627 --> 00:48:51,028
Hauchen wir das A, dann heißt es?

641
00:48:51,112 --> 00:48:52,531
Ha.

642
00:48:52,608 --> 00:48:56,590
Nun werde ich Ihnen
dieses Buch hier zeigen.

643
00:48:56,675 --> 00:49:00,046
Was sollen wir hauchen?

644
00:49:00,127 --> 00:49:03,073
Ha, ha, ha.

645
00:49:03,158 --> 00:49:06,070
- Schnell hintereinander.
- Ha, ha, ha.

646
00:49:07,416 --> 00:49:11,519
(narrator) Now the enemy was approaching
the very frontiers of the Reich.

647
00:49:11,597 --> 00:49:13,507
The Volkssturm, the home guard

648
00:49:13,592 --> 00:49:17,880
of the elderly, the underaged
and the unfit, was sworn in.

649
00:49:32,082 --> 00:49:34,068
(men repeat oath)

650
00:49:55,368 --> 00:50:00,583
Männer des Berliner Volkssturms,
ihr habt soeben...

651
00:50:00,700 --> 00:50:04,333
(narrator) They listened with
closed faces to oratory from Goebbels

652
00:50:04,421 --> 00:50:07,214
about fighting to the bitter end.

653
00:50:07,759 --> 00:50:14,317
(Goebbels)..wehrbereiter
und wehrentschlossener Männer verfügt,

654
00:50:15,047 --> 00:50:19,455
die den festen und unerschütterlichen
Willen haben...

655
00:50:49,074 --> 00:50:53,439
(narrator) The Volkssturm trudged out
through that same Brandenburg Gate

656
00:50:53,524 --> 00:50:57,124
which had seen the soldiers march
back from Paris four years before.

657
00:51:03,767 --> 00:51:06,222
They went towards the Russians,

658
00:51:06,299 --> 00:51:09,550
keeping their thoughts to themselves.
