1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:07,673
== Ripped & corrected by <font color="#00ff00">Kaitian</font> ==
== for <font color="#00ffff">www.addic7ed.com</font> ==

2
00:00:14,272 --> 00:00:17,371
(narrator) This land was made for war.

3
00:00:17,456 --> 00:00:20,096
As glass resists the bite of vitriol,

4
00:00:20,218 --> 00:00:26,623
so this hard and calcined earth rejects
the battle's hot, corrosive impact.

5
00:00:33,608 --> 00:00:36,859
Here is no nubile, girlish land,

6
00:00:36,945 --> 00:00:41,124
no green and virginal countryside
for war to violate.

7
00:00:42,355 --> 00:00:46,075
This land is hard, inviolable.

8
00:01:43,662 --> 00:01:45,189
(narrator) Benito Mussolini

9
00:01:45,273 --> 00:01:47,532
declares war on France and Britain.

10
00:01:47,613 --> 00:01:54,477
Combattenti di terra, di mare,
dell'aria.

11
00:01:59,353 --> 00:02:02,572
(crowd cheering)

12
00:02:20,722 --> 00:02:22,861
(narrator) Like some Roman consul,

13
00:02:22,947 --> 00:02:25,358
Mussolini longed for an African empire.

14
00:02:25,441 --> 00:02:29,041
Already he had massacred the
Abyssinians and subjugated the Libyans.

15
00:02:29,124 --> 00:02:31,579
Now he wanted more.

16
00:02:36,030 --> 00:02:41,322
(man) We were certainly not ready
to go to war in 1940.

17
00:02:41,439 --> 00:02:44,658
It was purely a political move
from Mussolini

18
00:02:44,738 --> 00:02:47,805
who felt that Hitler
was winning too much too quickly

19
00:02:47,884 --> 00:02:53,023
and that if he didn't make some sort of
gesture, take some sort of initiative,

20
00:02:53,140 --> 00:02:57,735
he would not be able to sit
at the conference table.

21
00:03:08,870 --> 00:03:12,198
(narrator) Mussolini's eyes
were on Egypt -

22
00:03:12,284 --> 00:03:15,688
the Egypt of the Nile
and the Suez Canal.

23
00:03:17,694 --> 00:03:23,630
In autumn 1940, he poured 250,000 troops
into Egypt's neighbour, Libya,

24
00:03:23,755 --> 00:03:27,007
and another 300,000 into Ethiopia.

25
00:03:27,093 --> 00:03:30,159
Facing them in Egypt
were just 30,000 British soldiers

26
00:03:30,316 --> 00:03:32,345
of the Western Desert Force.

27
00:03:57,325 --> 00:04:01,809
September 13, 1940, when the battle
for Britain was at its height,

28
00:04:01,890 --> 00:04:05,032
Mussolini's men
set out to conquer Egypt.

29
00:04:13,515 --> 00:04:17,344
Completely outnumbered,
the British troops simply fell back.

30
00:04:23,374 --> 00:04:26,670
After four days, Mussolini's men
were to reach Sidi Barrani,

31
00:04:26,750 --> 00:04:28,583
60 miles inside Egypt.

32
00:04:28,669 --> 00:04:32,957
There they would stop,
still 300 miles short of Cairo.

33
00:04:35,805 --> 00:04:38,412
(Colacicchi) Looking back,
it seems extraordinary

34
00:04:38,490 --> 00:04:43,858
how we moved into Egypt by sending out
these enormous columns -

35
00:04:43,938 --> 00:04:47,571
not very well protected
because we didn't have many tanks.

36
00:04:47,659 --> 00:04:53,289
And then each one of them settling down
in a sort of fortified camp.

37
00:04:59,284 --> 00:05:02,732
This helped, of course,
General O'Connor, I think, a lot.

38
00:05:02,813 --> 00:05:05,225
(narrator) O'Connor,
the British commander,

39
00:05:05,307 --> 00:05:08,329
had used the pause
to plan a counterattack.

40
00:05:08,415 --> 00:05:13,237
The Italians had a series
of these fortified perimeter camps,

41
00:05:13,364 --> 00:05:16,768
and we decided
that, as they were so far apart,

42
00:05:16,855 --> 00:05:19,114
they would be unable
to support each other,

43
00:05:19,195 --> 00:05:23,222
and we moved our troops round
to attack them from the rear,

44
00:05:23,300 --> 00:05:26,093
the way that their rations would come.

45
00:05:35,385 --> 00:05:39,335
(man) O'Connor undertook an operation
which was due to last about four days,

46
00:05:39,413 --> 00:05:43,047
which was the limit for the available
tanks, which were nearly worn out,

47
00:05:43,135 --> 00:05:49,387
and for our administration, in terms of
supplying water and fuel and ammunition.

48
00:05:49,465 --> 00:05:51,494
He achieved complete surprise,

49
00:05:51,575 --> 00:05:55,252
got behind the Italian positions
at Sidi Barrani, and, in the morning,

50
00:05:55,335 --> 00:05:57,790
the Italian resistance collapsed.

51
00:05:57,867 --> 00:05:59,852
(cheering)

52
00:06:18,699 --> 00:06:21,339
(Belchem) O'Connor's
great achievement was

53
00:06:21,423 --> 00:06:27,599
that, by using captured vehicles
and captured dumps of water and fuel,

54
00:06:27,676 --> 00:06:31,855
he was able to maintain
this four-day battle

55
00:06:31,935 --> 00:06:35,809
into what became an offensive
lasting over a period of weeks

56
00:06:35,886 --> 00:06:38,298
and resulted in taking him
as far as Benghazi

57
00:06:38,380 --> 00:06:41,173
and indeed, beyond, to El Agheila.

58
00:06:43,022 --> 00:06:46,547
(narrator) An area the size of England
and France had been captured.

59
00:06:46,629 --> 00:06:50,458
For the British, it was an unbelievable
victory and marvellously opportune

60
00:06:50,542 --> 00:06:53,455
for, back home,
the Blitz was mounting in ferocity.

61
00:06:53,573 --> 00:06:57,370
For Mussolini, a mere six months
after entering the war,

62
00:06:57,447 --> 00:07:01,397
the defeat meant the pricking
of his imperial pretensions.

63
00:07:01,476 --> 00:07:04,575
(Colacicchi) Mussolini had said,
"I want 1,000 Italian dead

64
00:07:04,660 --> 00:07:07,835
to be able to sit
at the conference table."

65
00:07:07,921 --> 00:07:10,834
And, of course,
it cost many more than that.

66
00:07:20,044 --> 00:07:23,765
(narrator) 200,000 Italians
were taken prisoner.

67
00:07:32,781 --> 00:07:35,040
(man) They'd had enough.

68
00:07:35,122 --> 00:07:39,487
In many cases they were
very, very happy to surrender.

69
00:07:39,572 --> 00:07:42,594
To think that we were
vastly outnumbered,

70
00:07:42,679 --> 00:07:48,855
and to see one Tommy taking literally
thousands back to the POW cage

71
00:07:48,933 --> 00:07:51,803
was a great joy for us to see.

72
00:07:51,887 --> 00:07:55,761
We used to call them "gentlemen".
"There go the gentlemen."

73
00:07:57,565 --> 00:08:01,166
(narrator) Tripoli, Libya's capital,
was in O'Connor's grasp.

74
00:08:01,248 --> 00:08:04,008
But Churchill withdrew
the cream of O'Connor's forces

75
00:08:04,087 --> 00:08:06,378
to meet the Nazi threat in Greece.

76
00:08:06,466 --> 00:08:09,640
(O'Connor) We couldn't do
Greece and Tripoli at the same time.

77
00:08:09,727 --> 00:08:11,068
That was clear.

78
00:08:11,875 --> 00:08:15,203
I say we could have done Tripoli
immediately

79
00:08:15,290 --> 00:08:18,541
and still left the options open
for Greece.

80
00:08:19,011 --> 00:08:20,921
We lost an enormous opportunity

81
00:08:21,006 --> 00:08:22,916
to finish up North Africa,

82
00:08:23,001 --> 00:08:24,452
and it was a fatal error

83
00:08:24,535 --> 00:08:25,954
to go to Greece.

84
00:08:26,032 --> 00:08:31,968
If we had advanced immediately,
we could have pushed him out.

85
00:08:32,055 --> 00:08:34,422
I entirely blame myself
for not having done it.

86
00:08:34,510 --> 00:08:38,231
I think it was quite inexcusable.
I ought to have.

87
00:08:40,112 --> 00:08:44,749
(narrator) February 12, 1941.
Hitler comes to Mussolini's rescue.

88
00:08:48,168 --> 00:08:51,572
A small mobile force
that had been hurriedly put together

89
00:08:51,659 --> 00:08:53,001
set sail to Tripoli.

90
00:08:57,299 --> 00:09:00,518
A force that was soon to be renowned
as the Afrika Korps.

91
00:09:09,039 --> 00:09:14,516
The task of the German Africa army
was only

92
00:09:14,602 --> 00:09:19,272
to tie down
as many British troops as possible

93
00:09:19,359 --> 00:09:23,156
and to cover the southern flank
of Europe.

94
00:09:23,963 --> 00:09:30,521
We had never the intention to conquer
Egypt or to cross the Suez Canal.

95
00:09:35,395 --> 00:09:38,647
(narrator) The man Hitler chose
to save Mussolini from disaster

96
00:09:38,733 --> 00:09:41,341
had made his name in France
the summer before -

97
00:09:42,416 --> 00:09:44,521
Erwin Rommel.

98
00:09:50,127 --> 00:09:55,376
In the port of Tripoli
in February / March '41,

99
00:09:56,151 --> 00:10:02,937
Rommel told my friend Lieutenant Hunt,
an engineer:

100
00:10:04,054 --> 00:10:07,928
"Hunt, here you can build me 150 tanks."

101
00:10:08,005 --> 00:10:11,453
The man looked stupefied,
and Rommel told him:

102
00:10:11,535 --> 00:10:16,325
"Don't you have timber
here in the harbour and canvas of sails

103
00:10:16,446 --> 00:10:20,079
to make 150 covers for Volkswagen?"

104
00:10:20,167 --> 00:10:22,120
"So you can give me 150 tanks."

105
00:10:22,200 --> 00:10:25,037
And those tanks misled the British.

106
00:10:26,842 --> 00:10:31,786
(narrator) Rommel knew nothing about
desert warfare, but was bold and daring.

107
00:10:32,252 --> 00:10:37,163
(man) Rommel was perhaps the ideal
commander for this war theatre.

108
00:10:37,239 --> 00:10:40,262
It was very wide in area,

109
00:10:40,347 --> 00:10:44,329
but very limited in numbers of soldiers,

110
00:10:44,414 --> 00:10:48,167
and so he could apply
practically naval tactics.

111
00:10:49,094 --> 00:10:52,116
(Westphal) Towns and cities
were very few

112
00:10:52,202 --> 00:10:57,603
and, therefore, we had no difficulties
with the Arabian population.

113
00:10:57,688 --> 00:10:59,902
They didn't disturb us.

114
00:11:03,251 --> 00:11:08,073
(narrator) The evening the Afrika Korps
arrived, they were ordered to the front.

115
00:11:10,041 --> 00:11:12,954
Rommel believed in attack, and quickly.

116
00:11:21,819 --> 00:11:25,540
On the last day of March, when not all
the troops promised had even landed,

117
00:11:25,617 --> 00:11:27,450
he took on the British at El Agheila,

118
00:11:27,536 --> 00:11:33,013
and in just 12 days pushed them back
the 500 miles to Egypt.

119
00:11:33,943 --> 00:11:36,965
(man) It was as if the bogeyman
was just round the corner.

120
00:11:37,050 --> 00:11:39,461
It was "Here comes Rommel,"

121
00:11:39,544 --> 00:11:43,570
or "Rommel's coming down the desert
fast. Get the hell out of it."

122
00:11:44,953 --> 00:11:50,278
(narrator) Now it was the British turn
to be taken prisoner in their thousands.

123
00:12:00,491 --> 00:12:04,856
(man) Rommel told me to go ahead
and we reached Derna,

124
00:12:04,941 --> 00:12:10,768
picking up on our way English soldiers
and generals who came in one by one.

125
00:12:10,849 --> 00:12:14,024
Amongst them,
the famous General O'Connor.

126
00:12:14,954 --> 00:12:17,486
(O'Connor) It was miles behind
our own front.

127
00:12:17,563 --> 00:12:19,287
We drove into the one bit of desert

128
00:12:19,366 --> 00:12:22,465
in which the Germans had sent
a reconnaissance group.

129
00:12:22,551 --> 00:12:27,341
It was a great shock, and I never
thought it would happen to me.

130
00:12:27,423 --> 00:12:28,950
Very conceited, perhaps.

131
00:12:29,878 --> 00:12:32,366
(narrator) And so the Rommel legend
took shape.

132
00:12:32,449 --> 00:12:36,475
By mid-April, he had driven
the British back where they had started.

133
00:12:36,554 --> 00:12:39,773
But one pinprick remained - Tobruk.

134
00:12:44,879 --> 00:12:48,982
100 miles behind the front,
its Australian garrison held out,

135
00:12:49,061 --> 00:12:53,655
denying Rommel a precious forward port
for his supplies.

136
00:12:56,235 --> 00:13:00,141
While Tobruk remained in British hands,
it threatened Rommel's supply lines

137
00:13:00,225 --> 00:13:03,902
and deterred him
from advancing any further into Egypt.

138
00:13:06,900 --> 00:13:11,570
Unable to take Tobruk by direct assault,
Rommel prepared to besiege it.

139
00:13:13,231 --> 00:13:15,336
The Luftwaffe, too, were called in.

140
00:13:34,370 --> 00:13:38,276
Over 1,000 raids
were mounted against Tobruk.

141
00:13:48,066 --> 00:13:49,288
Under Rommel's nose,

142
00:13:49,370 --> 00:13:52,392
the Royal Navy replaced their garrison
with fresh troops -

143
00:13:52,478 --> 00:13:56,003
Poles, South Africans, Indians, British.

144
00:13:56,851 --> 00:13:59,721
(man) It was bare rations in Tobruk.

145
00:13:59,805 --> 00:14:05,021
Although one must thank the navy.
They did a wonderful job.

146
00:14:10,548 --> 00:14:13,919
(narrator) In 1941
the Royal Navy ruled the Mediterranean.

147
00:14:14,000 --> 00:14:16,838
They had done so since
giving the powerful Italian fleet

148
00:14:16,916 --> 00:14:19,447
a bloody nose at Taranto
the previous autumn.

149
00:14:19,525 --> 00:14:22,744
And so British convoys made their way
through the Mediterranean

150
00:14:22,824 --> 00:14:25,116
relatively unmolested.

151
00:14:25,203 --> 00:14:27,767
More importantly, operating from Malta,

152
00:14:27,889 --> 00:14:30,300
the Royal Navy could harass
Rommel's own convoys

153
00:14:30,421 --> 00:14:32,984
passing from Italy to Tripoli.

154
00:15:04,565 --> 00:15:07,707
The British supplies got through,
while Rommel's didn't.

155
00:15:09,131 --> 00:15:11,619
Denied the petrol
necessary for his panzers,

156
00:15:11,701 --> 00:15:16,295
Rommel couldn't advance
any further into Egypt that summer.

157
00:15:16,382 --> 00:15:19,065
And, worse, no matter how hard he tried,

158
00:15:19,144 --> 00:15:21,206
Rommel couldn't take Tobruk.

159
00:15:21,714 --> 00:15:25,392
It remained a thorn in his side, and
became a symbol of British doggedness

160
00:15:25,474 --> 00:15:28,005
every bit as much
as Churchill's bulldog face.

161
00:15:28,083 --> 00:15:32,830
(man) We were pestered with
blaring loudspeakers on the perimeter.

162
00:15:32,917 --> 00:15:35,787
We were called
the self-imposed prisoners of Tobruk

163
00:15:35,871 --> 00:15:42,276
and Rommel's propaganda machine
bellowed at us to give up.

164
00:15:42,355 --> 00:15:45,758
Well, we just took no notice.
We said, "We'll stick it out."

165
00:15:45,846 --> 00:15:48,486
We knew that they couldn't get in.

166
00:15:56,856 --> 00:15:59,879
(man #2) There had been no light
at the end of the tunnel at all

167
00:15:59,964 --> 00:16:02,331
since the withdrawal from Dunkirk.

168
00:16:02,458 --> 00:16:06,288
I think for political
and, above all, for morale reasons -

169
00:16:06,371 --> 00:16:08,738
the morale
of the people of this country -

170
00:16:08,826 --> 00:16:13,234
it was terribly important
to show that we could hold the Germans.

171
00:16:13,315 --> 00:16:15,923
(narrator) The Desert War
was in stalemate,

172
00:16:16,001 --> 00:16:18,870
a time for taking stock of tactics
as well as supplies.

173
00:16:18,955 --> 00:16:21,944
Rommel's tactics had more effect
than those of the British,

174
00:16:22,024 --> 00:16:24,163
especially in his use of tank.

175
00:16:25,400 --> 00:16:28,848
(Belchem) We had been trained
to fire on the move,

176
00:16:28,929 --> 00:16:32,563
to execute the sort of cavalry charge
on tracks,

177
00:16:32,651 --> 00:16:35,291
and handle armour in that way.

178
00:16:35,375 --> 00:16:39,783
The Germans had studied this problem
much more than we between the wars

179
00:16:39,902 --> 00:16:43,535
and also, of course, Rommel had
experience from northern France

180
00:16:43,662 --> 00:16:46,149
and so had many of his tank crews.

181
00:16:46,232 --> 00:16:50,411
And they appreciated that
the tank's best action against his enemy

182
00:16:50,490 --> 00:16:54,320
is to wait for him to come on,
sitting in a hull-hidden position.

183
00:16:54,404 --> 00:16:55,975
If they're caught in the open,

184
00:16:56,053 --> 00:17:00,571
to decoy the enemy
onto their own antitank gun lines.

185
00:17:08,944 --> 00:17:14,083
(narrator) Rommel's main antitank
weapon was the Krupp-made 88mm.

186
00:17:14,162 --> 00:17:16,999
It had decimated the French tanks
in May 1940

187
00:17:17,077 --> 00:17:19,565
and was doing the same now
to the British tanks.

188
00:17:20,722 --> 00:17:24,170
(man) It was effective
at 1,000 yards and over.

189
00:17:25,287 --> 00:17:29,576
It could pinpoint you, zero into you
and it would brew a tank up easily.

190
00:17:33,919 --> 00:17:37,749
(man #2) They could shoot at us before
we were even within striking distance.

191
00:17:37,833 --> 00:17:43,005
We couldn't hope to hit them with
the two-pounders or the six-pounders.

192
00:17:44,815 --> 00:17:48,372
(narrator) Rommel not only had the edge
in tactics and equipment,

193
00:17:48,498 --> 00:17:52,372
he also enjoyed the confidence
of his political chief, Hitler.

194
00:17:52,450 --> 00:17:53,944
Wavell, his opposite number,

195
00:17:54,023 --> 00:17:56,816
was pressured by Churchill
to provide a victory.

196
00:17:56,900 --> 00:18:01,308
When he didn't, he was replaced
by General Sir Claude Auchinleck.

197
00:18:01,427 --> 00:18:04,569
"The Auk", in turn, appointed
as his commander in the field

198
00:18:04,650 --> 00:18:07,138
Lieutenant General Cunningham.

199
00:18:07,220 --> 00:18:09,861
Cunningham had defeated
the Italians in East Africa

200
00:18:09,982 --> 00:18:13,735
and put back Haile Selassie
on the throne of Abyssinia.

201
00:18:13,819 --> 00:18:16,808
But he was an infantryman
and knew nothing about tanks.

202
00:18:17,233 --> 00:18:20,146
The tank held the key to success
in the desert,

203
00:18:20,226 --> 00:18:22,943
but British tanks
left much to be desired.

204
00:18:23,026 --> 00:18:26,093
(man) They were very poor,
mechanically.

205
00:18:26,172 --> 00:18:31,039
There were parts missing,
parts not connected properly.

206
00:18:31,543 --> 00:18:35,101
(narrator) Unlike the Germans,
the British had few tank transporters,

207
00:18:35,188 --> 00:18:38,101
so their tanks had to move
long distances as well as fight

208
00:18:38,180 --> 00:18:40,286
on their tracks.

209
00:18:41,288 --> 00:18:44,387
(man) Every track is connected
to the next track by a pin -

210
00:18:44,511 --> 00:18:45,656
a lot of moving parts -

211
00:18:45,738 --> 00:18:51,794
which, in the desert, was sometimes
powdery but hard, gritty sand.

212
00:18:52,414 --> 00:18:55,588
Well, water is a lubricant

213
00:18:55,713 --> 00:18:59,587
and a tank track
is best suited to muddy conditions.

214
00:19:01,621 --> 00:19:05,255
(narrator) To Churchill, the Desert War
had been too long in stalemate.

215
00:19:05,343 --> 00:19:06,335
He needed victory,

216
00:19:06,417 --> 00:19:09,974
especially after the humiliating
failures in Greece and Crete.

217
00:19:10,062 --> 00:19:12,702
No sooner were Cunningham
and Auchinleck appointed

218
00:19:12,786 --> 00:19:16,157
then they, too,
were pressured into an offensive.

219
00:19:30,510 --> 00:19:35,497
The British now had more equipment,
but their tactics hadn't changed.

220
00:19:35,574 --> 00:19:38,291
Rommel might have been tempted
to echo Wellington:

221
00:19:38,375 --> 00:19:42,740
"They came on in the same old way and
we stopped them in the same old way."

222
00:19:46,815 --> 00:19:48,615
In just five days that November,

223
00:19:48,695 --> 00:19:51,837
Cunningham lost 300 tanks -
two-thirds of his force -

224
00:19:51,956 --> 00:19:54,247
many through mechanical failure.

225
00:19:54,335 --> 00:19:57,434
(man) Say the track came off
and jammed,

226
00:19:57,557 --> 00:19:59,313
well, if you were in action,

227
00:19:59,437 --> 00:20:02,427
you couldn't do anything about it
but bail out.

228
00:20:02,506 --> 00:20:04,962
And then you couldn't recover the tank.

229
00:20:05,077 --> 00:20:09,288
At that time in the desert
we had no means of recovery of tanks.

230
00:20:09,374 --> 00:20:13,171
(man #2) You'd always
leave the battleground.

231
00:20:13,248 --> 00:20:17,155
Jerrys, they used to seem to stay there.

232
00:20:17,277 --> 00:20:19,186
We might have had a successful day

233
00:20:19,272 --> 00:20:22,523
but the Jerrys always seemed
to deny us the battlefield.

234
00:20:22,993 --> 00:20:26,364
(man) Their equipment had to come
equally as far as ours,

235
00:20:26,446 --> 00:20:28,705
but they seemed to value it more

236
00:20:28,786 --> 00:20:33,729
and did every effort to recover
their tanks as soon as it got dusk.

237
00:20:34,311 --> 00:20:35,838
(narrator) By bluff and guile,

238
00:20:35,960 --> 00:20:38,753
Rommel convinced Cunningham
he had lost the battle,

239
00:20:38,838 --> 00:20:41,369
but Auchinleck
was determined to stay put.

240
00:20:41,447 --> 00:20:45,429
He sacked Cunningham, who wanted
to withdraw, and appointed Ritchie.

241
00:20:45,513 --> 00:20:48,580
The gamble to stay and fight came off.

242
00:20:56,831 --> 00:20:59,045
When defeat
stared the British in the face,

243
00:20:59,133 --> 00:21:01,773
the battle's balance
swung dramatically their way,

244
00:21:01,895 --> 00:21:04,808
as Rommel's panzers ran out of fuel.

245
00:21:05,501 --> 00:21:06,952
Tobruk was relieved.

246
00:21:07,036 --> 00:21:10,669
Rommel was forced to withdraw
500 miles back to his starting point,

247
00:21:10,757 --> 00:21:16,050
and, on Christmas Eve 1941, Benghazi
changed hands for the third time.

248
00:21:17,164 --> 00:21:20,841
But with Commonwealth forces again
poised to push the Axis out of Africa,

249
00:21:20,962 --> 00:21:24,869
they were again denuded of troops and
equipment, this time for the Far East,

250
00:21:24,952 --> 00:21:26,600
where Japan's entry into the war

251
00:21:26,679 --> 00:21:29,548
threatened British bases
in Burma and Malaya.

252
00:21:29,633 --> 00:21:36,376
An opportunity of gaining something
which was real and important

253
00:21:36,462 --> 00:21:38,796
in the Middle Eastern theatre

254
00:21:38,879 --> 00:21:45,437
was lost for the sake of something
which was very doubtful

255
00:21:45,516 --> 00:21:50,382
and unlikely to pay off
in the Far East.

256
00:21:51,386 --> 00:21:55,980
(narrator) Within a couple of weeks,
Rommel counterattacked.

257
00:22:01,667 --> 00:22:05,420
Against the weakened British forces,
he recaptured Benghazi

258
00:22:05,504 --> 00:22:07,566
and once more threatened Tobruk.

259
00:22:07,652 --> 00:22:09,834
He was stopped at Gazala.

260
00:22:09,916 --> 00:22:12,829
Once again, it was stalemate.

261
00:22:32,244 --> 00:22:36,118
The peculiar conditions of the desert
bred a comradeship that was unique.

262
00:22:36,196 --> 00:22:39,109
To many, the Desert War
was a private war,

263
00:22:39,188 --> 00:22:42,789
the last to retain
any pretence of chivalry.

264
00:22:48,434 --> 00:22:51,915
(man) As soon as we stopped anywhere
and there was a lull and a rest,

265
00:22:52,002 --> 00:22:54,217
you'd clear off a patch of the desert
and say:

266
00:22:54,304 --> 00:22:57,174
"Right. Now we'll have
a game of football."

267
00:22:57,258 --> 00:23:01,011
(man #2) The sportsmanship showed
in both sides.

268
00:23:01,133 --> 00:23:07,189
Football games were not interrupted by
artillery fire during certain periods.

269
00:23:09,189 --> 00:23:12,910
(Belchem) The staple diet
was biscuits and bully beef.

270
00:23:12,988 --> 00:23:17,123
(man #3) We had bully beef fried,
bully beef boiled,

271
00:23:17,208 --> 00:23:19,542
bully beef with dog biscuits.

272
00:23:19,625 --> 00:23:23,804
(man #4) Oh, and dog biscuits.
Dogs would refuse to eat them.

273
00:23:24,996 --> 00:23:27,559
(narrator) With food a problem
and water scarce,

274
00:23:27,643 --> 00:23:30,403
dysentery was a constant danger.

275
00:23:33,513 --> 00:23:36,731
The Germans invented a water can
which the envious English,

276
00:23:36,812 --> 00:23:40,489
after seeing theirs burst countless
times on the bumpy desert surfaces,

277
00:23:40,572 --> 00:23:43,638
copied and christened the "jerry can".

278
00:23:44,447 --> 00:23:47,851
(man) We were rationed at one stage
there on a cup of water a day

279
00:23:47,976 --> 00:23:50,235
to bath and shave.

280
00:23:50,316 --> 00:23:53,797
What often happened was
the sections collected their ration,

281
00:23:53,884 --> 00:23:57,867
put it into a helmet
and each would shave out of that.

282
00:23:57,951 --> 00:24:00,439
(narrator) Above all, it was hot.

283
00:24:00,560 --> 00:24:04,041
Very, very, very hot.

284
00:24:04,128 --> 00:24:08,231
(man) It was so hot
you could fry an egg on the mudguard.

285
00:24:08,310 --> 00:24:11,713
It's literally true.
You could break an egg on the outside.

286
00:24:11,801 --> 00:24:14,484
It was so hot it would sizzle.

287
00:24:17,862 --> 00:24:21,463
(narrator) The fly was perhaps
the desert soldier's greatest scourge -

288
00:24:21,545 --> 00:24:24,874
not just as a nuisance
but as a carrier of disease.

289
00:24:24,960 --> 00:24:28,102
The flies were indifferent
as to which side they plagued.

290
00:24:28,183 --> 00:24:32,777
(man) There were competitions
as to who killed the most flies.

291
00:24:32,863 --> 00:24:38,079
The flies were that fattened
with living on the dead

292
00:24:38,157 --> 00:24:40,296
that any time you killed them,

293
00:24:40,421 --> 00:24:43,029
the smell got into you
and caused stomach upsets.

294
00:24:43,106 --> 00:24:45,670
And we had orders
from division headquarters

295
00:24:45,754 --> 00:24:48,165
to cut out this business
of killing the flies.

296
00:24:48,286 --> 00:24:50,391
We just had to let them go.

297
00:24:52,276 --> 00:24:59,445
(Westphal) I think one fly has,
within one year, nine million children.

298
00:25:01,406 --> 00:25:04,625
(narrator) There was, too,
the occasional scorpion and viper.

299
00:25:04,706 --> 00:25:09,300
And when the wind blew,
the sand and dust got in everywhere.

300
00:25:13,837 --> 00:25:17,011
(man) The fine dust
used to clog up everything.

301
00:25:17,098 --> 00:25:20,164
The jets would clog up
in the carburettors.

302
00:25:20,244 --> 00:25:22,076
Your watches would stop.

303
00:25:22,162 --> 00:25:26,417
(man #2) We had great problems with our
intestines that gave a form of diarrhoea

304
00:25:26,535 --> 00:25:30,562
which was very severe
because of the sand passing through.

305
00:25:30,640 --> 00:25:34,744
(man #3) You had, for instance,
to go from your quarters to the latrine,

306
00:25:34,822 --> 00:25:38,652
and you had literally to do it
with a march compass.

307
00:25:38,735 --> 00:25:41,910
There are cases
where soldiers did not return

308
00:25:42,035 --> 00:25:44,490
when they had forgotten
their march compass.

309
00:25:46,332 --> 00:25:49,506
In the sandstorm, of course,
the fighting stopped,

310
00:25:49,593 --> 00:25:51,731
which was enjoyed at the beginning.

311
00:25:51,856 --> 00:25:54,540
Then after three days you think:

312
00:25:54,618 --> 00:25:57,717
"Better the sandstorm stops
and the fighting starts again."

313
00:26:00,296 --> 00:26:04,891
(narrator) Ritchie planned an offensive
for May with Grant tanks from America.

314
00:26:04,977 --> 00:26:08,534
But Rommel, as usual, got in first.

315
00:26:08,622 --> 00:26:11,305
Ritchie had learnt little
from previous mistakes.

316
00:26:11,422 --> 00:26:12,993
Like the Italians, he had set up

317
00:26:13,072 --> 00:26:14,566
a series of fortified camps

318
00:26:14,645 --> 00:26:16,478
and laid mines galore.

319
00:26:16,563 --> 00:26:17,905
But as O'Connor had done

320
00:26:17,983 --> 00:26:19,085
with the Italians

321
00:26:19,210 --> 00:26:22,123
Rommel simply went round
the open flank.

322
00:26:23,123 --> 00:26:26,572
(man) We were down south,
just in front of Bir Hakeim

323
00:26:26,653 --> 00:26:32,829
and, during the morning, we saw
this dust going up from where Jerry was.

324
00:26:32,906 --> 00:26:36,278
He was coming up through
where the Seventh Armoured Div were.

325
00:26:36,359 --> 00:26:38,651
And it was like a fox in a hen coop -

326
00:26:38,738 --> 00:26:41,880
everybody dashing about
all over the place.

327
00:27:02,332 --> 00:27:06,085
(narrator) Ritchie's new tanks
were proving a disappointment.

328
00:27:06,169 --> 00:27:09,268
Once again, the British armour
was out-manoeuvred.

329
00:27:09,391 --> 00:27:12,184
The Battle of Gazala was Rommel's.

330
00:27:24,430 --> 00:27:28,151
The way was open to the prize that had
eluded Rommel the previous summer,

331
00:27:28,229 --> 00:27:33,597
the prize that Churchill, for one, had
determined ever to deny him - Tobruk.

332
00:27:40,851 --> 00:27:43,611
Tobruk's fortifications
had been neglected.

333
00:27:43,690 --> 00:27:47,978
They were no longer as formidable
as they had been the previous summer.

334
00:28:07,437 --> 00:28:12,260
(newsreel) 27 Juni. Das Oberkommando
der Wehrmacht gibt bekannt.

335
00:28:12,386 --> 00:28:16,064
Berlin Radio broadcast
news of Tobruk's surrender.

336
00:28:16,146 --> 00:28:18,677
For Churchill
it was a particularly dark moment.

337
00:28:18,755 --> 00:28:20,511
For Rommel, the peak of his career,

338
00:28:20,596 --> 00:28:23,771
and a grateful Führer
made him field marshal.

339
00:28:30,725 --> 00:28:36,017
The British now fell back into Egypt,
further than ever before.

340
00:28:36,096 --> 00:28:40,843
(De Guingand) I've never seen such
chaos. You couldn't save the situation.

341
00:28:40,930 --> 00:28:45,295
I've never seen a desert road
crammed with every sort of vehicle,

342
00:28:45,380 --> 00:28:49,057
every unit muddled up higgledy-piggledy.

343
00:28:49,140 --> 00:28:52,010
No one knew what was going on and...

344
00:28:52,094 --> 00:28:55,193
Luckily our air force
was stronger than the enemy's,

345
00:28:55,278 --> 00:28:58,497
otherwise I think
we would have been routed.

346
00:29:00,381 --> 00:29:04,255
(man) The state of despair
had to be masked,

347
00:29:04,332 --> 00:29:08,773
and it was masked in a typically
British way - by nonchalance.

348
00:29:08,859 --> 00:29:12,384
When Rommel was expected in Cairo
that evening,

349
00:29:12,466 --> 00:29:14,189
Lord Killearn, my ambassador,

350
00:29:14,269 --> 00:29:18,754
instantly gave a dinner for 80 people
at the Mohammed Ali Club

351
00:29:18,873 --> 00:29:22,015
and said, "When he comes down,
he'll know where to find us."

352
00:29:23,937 --> 00:29:28,923
(narrator) Past Mersa Matruh, past
Maaten Bagush, past Fuka, past Daba,

353
00:29:29,001 --> 00:29:34,173
the British fell back,
until, on June 30, 1942,

354
00:29:34,257 --> 00:29:38,207
they reached a railway halt
just 60 miles from Alexandria -

355
00:29:38,362 --> 00:29:40,347
El Alamein.

356
00:29:53,094 --> 00:29:55,124
It was no chance choice of Auchinleck's

357
00:29:55,204 --> 00:29:59,994
that the decisive battle for Egypt
should be fought here at El Alamein.

358
00:30:06,982 --> 00:30:08,967
This bit of desert
was not like any other

359
00:30:09,054 --> 00:30:11,268
over which the war had been fought.

360
00:30:11,356 --> 00:30:13,647
As always, the sea was to the north,

361
00:30:13,734 --> 00:30:17,946
but, here, just 40 miles inland,
was another sea -

362
00:30:18,952 --> 00:30:22,629
a sunken sea of quicksand
and salt marsh,

363
00:30:22,712 --> 00:30:24,697
impassable to tanks.

364
00:30:25,589 --> 00:30:27,651
The Qattara Depression.

365
00:30:30,001 --> 00:30:32,412
Until now the fluid strategy
of desert warfare

366
00:30:32,495 --> 00:30:35,713
had sprung from there being
always an open flank.

367
00:30:35,794 --> 00:30:40,082
But at Alamein, Rommel would have
to think of something different.

368
00:30:43,467 --> 00:30:46,489
Auchinleck prepared
for the final battle for Egypt,

369
00:30:46,651 --> 00:30:49,018
for, after Tobruk,
he had sacked Ritchie

370
00:30:49,107 --> 00:30:52,402
and taken command
of the Eighth Army himself.

371
00:30:55,667 --> 00:30:59,420
But Churchill was already planning
to sack him too.

372
00:30:59,503 --> 00:31:01,871
Rommel didn't wait
for Churchill's decision.

373
00:31:01,959 --> 00:31:07,480
He threw his tired troops into
a last, desperate attempt to take Egypt.

374
00:31:12,816 --> 00:31:16,341
In July, in perhaps the most decisive
battle of the Desert War,

375
00:31:16,422 --> 00:31:18,757
Auchinleck halted him.

376
00:31:19,683 --> 00:31:22,979
(De Guingand) It was
a frightfully important battle,

377
00:31:23,059 --> 00:31:27,391
and it was touch and go that we might
have lost our whole Middle East base.

378
00:31:38,175 --> 00:31:42,660
(narrator) Churchill went to see for
himself in August the troops' morale.

379
00:31:42,741 --> 00:31:44,541
Tobruk's fall had exasperated him,

380
00:31:44,620 --> 00:31:48,374
but he was heartened by the reception
he got from the Eighth Army.

381
00:31:48,495 --> 00:31:52,860
He'd already decided to appoint
Alexander in place of Auchinleck.

382
00:31:52,946 --> 00:31:55,554
The new Eighth Army commander
was to be Montgomery,

383
00:31:55,631 --> 00:31:59,189
although Montgomery had not set foot
in the desert during the war.

384
00:31:59,276 --> 00:32:02,527
(man) When Montgomery came
we were a bit apprehensive about him

385
00:32:02,614 --> 00:32:07,600
because we'd never seen this man
who had white knees and what have you.

386
00:32:07,678 --> 00:32:11,933
(Durrell) The presence of your PM
suddenly was a very tonic thing.

387
00:32:12,013 --> 00:32:14,773
He was wearing a siren suit,
smoking an immense cigar,

388
00:32:14,852 --> 00:32:16,500
but he had "WC" on his slippers -

389
00:32:16,617 --> 00:32:18,799
he was wearing
old-fashioned dancing pumps

390
00:32:18,880 --> 00:32:21,444
that you used to wear
with dinner jackets,

391
00:32:21,527 --> 00:32:24,091
with W on one foot and C on the other.

392
00:32:25,172 --> 00:32:28,119
And he gave us a very good pep talk.

393
00:32:42,398 --> 00:32:45,038
(narrator) For Rommel,
the laws of desert warfare

394
00:32:45,122 --> 00:32:46,922
now began to work against him.

395
00:32:47,002 --> 00:32:49,991
The further the advance,
the longer the supply line.

396
00:32:51,068 --> 00:32:56,623
(Westphal) I think we had
crossed the Rubicon, like Caesar,

397
00:32:56,708 --> 00:33:00,308
when we went to Egypt.

398
00:33:00,429 --> 00:33:06,485
The eyes of Hitler were directed
every day to the Russian front -

399
00:33:06,568 --> 00:33:08,673
the deciding front -

400
00:33:08,755 --> 00:33:12,508
and our role was not so important.

401
00:33:12,591 --> 00:33:16,847
He was content
if we had no difficulties,

402
00:33:16,926 --> 00:33:20,953
but he was not able to guarantee

403
00:33:21,031 --> 00:33:26,324
the supplies came
to the North African force.

404
00:33:33,538 --> 00:33:37,063
(narrator) Only one in four of Rommel's
supply ships ever got through.

405
00:33:37,183 --> 00:33:41,242
His solution - late in the day -
crush Malta.

406
00:33:52,721 --> 00:33:57,587
Göring's Luftwaffe believed it could
annihilate the island single-handed.

407
00:34:01,314 --> 00:34:03,147
(siren)

408
00:34:18,655 --> 00:34:22,682
Stukas, Heinkels, Junkers,
Dorniers, Messerschmitts

409
00:34:22,760 --> 00:34:27,201
day in, day out, hundreds at a time,
were ordered against the island.

410
00:34:27,287 --> 00:34:29,654
Malta became
the most bombed place on earth.

411
00:34:57,941 --> 00:35:00,003
Malta held out.

412
00:35:10,639 --> 00:35:11,861
Equally bad for Rommel,

413
00:35:11,944 --> 00:35:15,577
the Desert Air Force could now operate
from its home bases along the Nile,

414
00:35:15,665 --> 00:35:18,032
just 100 miles behind the line.

415
00:35:18,965 --> 00:35:23,176
(man) In the desert,
fighting is characterised

416
00:35:23,261 --> 00:35:28,477
by the opposition of tanks
in large quantities,

417
00:35:28,594 --> 00:35:32,468
of artillery, of air support.

418
00:35:34,042 --> 00:35:38,712
Air support, for instance, didn't play
a considerable role in Russia,

419
00:35:38,799 --> 00:35:42,749
where troops had enough cover.

420
00:35:42,828 --> 00:35:48,764
In Africa, air superiority
was all decisive.

421
00:35:52,035 --> 00:35:54,326
(narrator) Montgomery
had air superiority.

422
00:35:54,414 --> 00:35:57,938
Desperately short of fuel, Rommel's
convoys had to run the gauntlet,

423
00:35:58,020 --> 00:36:00,354
the 1,400 miles
from his main base at Tripoli,

424
00:36:00,475 --> 00:36:05,222
whereas Montgomery was only
60 miles from his at Alexandria.

425
00:36:05,309 --> 00:36:08,376
(Westphal)
The distance from the ports -

426
00:36:08,455 --> 00:36:11,597
Benghazi, Tripoli
and, perhaps, Tobruk -

427
00:36:11,716 --> 00:36:14,357
had become too big.

428
00:36:15,514 --> 00:36:18,537
(man) During the jigsaws
up and down the desert,

429
00:36:18,660 --> 00:36:20,875
when we pushed Rommel back

430
00:36:20,962 --> 00:36:23,875
we used to accuse him
of putting oil in the wells,

431
00:36:23,955 --> 00:36:26,213
which we thought
was really a dirty trick.

432
00:36:26,295 --> 00:36:28,018
Then when we came back down,

433
00:36:28,098 --> 00:36:30,782
he would blame us
for putting oil in the water.

434
00:36:30,860 --> 00:36:34,613
And now it seems that, all the time,
it was the oil wells below the ground

435
00:36:34,697 --> 00:36:36,606
seeping through into the water well.

436
00:36:38,994 --> 00:36:42,322
(narrator) In September the Afrika
Korps' morale was dealt a blow

437
00:36:42,408 --> 00:36:45,550
when Rommel fell ill.
Hitler ordered him home.

438
00:36:46,551 --> 00:36:52,073
But his men were left behind
under the desert sun for a second year.

439
00:36:54,608 --> 00:36:58,285
(man) When you are in the desert, you
feel like a man on the moon would feel.

440
00:36:58,368 --> 00:37:01,314
You are alone with the universe.

441
00:37:03,010 --> 00:37:06,763
(narrator) For the men of the Afrika
Korps, there was no question of leave,

442
00:37:06,846 --> 00:37:11,441
only the certainty that, sooner or
later, the British would attack them.

443
00:37:11,527 --> 00:37:13,556
(man) The homesickness of the soldier

444
00:37:13,637 --> 00:37:16,933
who would have preferred
to be at home and not at war.

445
00:37:17,013 --> 00:37:21,378
(woman) Vor der Kaserne
Vor dem großen Tor

446
00:37:21,463 --> 00:37:25,828
Stand eine Laterne
Und steht sie noch davor

447
00:37:25,914 --> 00:37:28,674
(narrator) It was no accident
that the desert campaign

448
00:37:28,753 --> 00:37:31,622
produced the most memorable song
of the Second World War.

449
00:37:31,707 --> 00:37:34,118
(woman sings "Lili Marlene" in German)

450
00:37:34,201 --> 00:37:38,336
(man) Lili Marlene
was a piece of our home.

451
00:37:44,252 --> 00:37:47,504
(narrator) Lili Marlene
was equally popular with the British.

452
00:37:48,204 --> 00:37:51,073
(men sing "Lili Marlene" in English)

453
00:37:51,158 --> 00:37:54,224
(man) We were always
in touch with home.

454
00:37:54,342 --> 00:37:59,089
We heard the news and, of course,
we heard the opposition's news -

455
00:37:59,176 --> 00:38:03,584
witness "Underneath the lamppost
by the barrack gate".

456
00:38:04,585 --> 00:38:07,914
For you, Lili Marlene

457
00:38:08,038 --> 00:38:12,708
My own Lili Marlene

458
00:38:13,524 --> 00:38:17,082
(narrator) For the British, home
comforts were close at hand in Cairo,

459
00:38:17,207 --> 00:38:20,230
just the place for a spot of leave
with its bars, bazaars

460
00:38:20,315 --> 00:38:23,381
and, um... other distractions.

461
00:38:37,809 --> 00:38:40,646
(man) They used to take your money,
yes.

462
00:38:43,065 --> 00:38:44,822
(lively music)

463
00:38:47,784 --> 00:38:52,149
I should say 75% of them

464
00:38:52,235 --> 00:38:55,486
if they could find another woman,
they'd have her.

465
00:38:58,718 --> 00:39:00,322
(Durrell) It really was weird

466
00:39:00,406 --> 00:39:04,039
when you think of the whole of Europe
blacked out and in darkness.

467
00:39:04,128 --> 00:39:06,004
In despair, you know?

468
00:39:06,084 --> 00:39:09,226
In Cairo, seething with light,
you rang up people,

469
00:39:09,307 --> 00:39:12,253
you went out to dinner,
you had a hot bath and a whisky,

470
00:39:12,338 --> 00:39:14,477
and on Monday
you'd be back on the line.

471
00:39:17,172 --> 00:39:20,729
(narrator) Montgomery saw his main task
as raising the troops' morale.

472
00:39:20,816 --> 00:39:25,148
He was the first commander to project
himself like an American politician.

473
00:39:25,228 --> 00:39:30,051
Press men and photographers kept at
arm's length by Wavell and Auchinleck

474
00:39:30,139 --> 00:39:32,594
now found themselves welcome.

475
00:39:32,671 --> 00:39:38,039
(Belchem) He immediately went round
all the formations of the Eighth Army,

476
00:39:38,119 --> 00:39:40,453
gathering people round to talk to them.

477
00:39:40,574 --> 00:39:47,208
He used also the press, the radio
and gimmicks, such as his hats.

478
00:39:48,401 --> 00:39:52,766
(man) They wanted something to be able
to identify themselves with and look at,

479
00:39:52,851 --> 00:39:56,877
something other
than the strict uniform.

480
00:40:02,481 --> 00:40:07,195
(De Guingand) It was remarkable. In
days, there was a different atmosphere,

481
00:40:07,276 --> 00:40:08,727
a feeling of confidence.

482
00:40:08,811 --> 00:40:12,717
He told us that
the bad old days were over

483
00:40:12,801 --> 00:40:15,943
and he was now determined
there was going to be success.

484
00:40:16,023 --> 00:40:18,238
He said, "Now the only order

485
00:40:18,325 --> 00:40:22,504
is everyone stays where they are, fights
where they are and dies where they are."

486
00:40:32,367 --> 00:40:35,618
(narrator) Montgomery saw to it
his army had the latest weapons.

487
00:40:35,704 --> 00:40:38,160
Pressed by Churchill
to take the offensive,

488
00:40:38,236 --> 00:40:42,143
"Monty", as he was soon known,
was not going to be rushed.

489
00:40:42,226 --> 00:40:44,136
He was determined, as he put it,

490
00:40:44,298 --> 00:40:47,473
to have everyone tough and hard
for the coming battle.

491
00:40:49,784 --> 00:40:53,232
Because its first few hours
were going to be dominated by the mine -

492
00:40:53,314 --> 00:40:55,681
the Germans had laid
over half a million of them -

493
00:40:55,769 --> 00:40:58,639
the offensive had the codename
Operation Lightfoot,

494
00:40:58,723 --> 00:41:01,331
a sick joke if ever there was one.

495
00:41:02,445 --> 00:41:05,314
A mine detector
had been devised for use at Alamein,

496
00:41:05,399 --> 00:41:07,232
but many were found to be faulty,

497
00:41:07,317 --> 00:41:10,307
so most of the detecting
had to be done in the old way -

498
00:41:10,386 --> 00:41:16,595
by men prodding the ground with
bayonets and lifting the mines by hand.

499
00:41:26,308 --> 00:41:30,214
The German minefields at Alamein
were five miles deep.

500
00:41:30,298 --> 00:41:31,443
To assault them,

501
00:41:31,525 --> 00:41:34,547
Montgomery had assembled
a quarter of a million troops -

502
00:41:34,633 --> 00:41:37,393
British, Australians, New Zealanders,

503
00:41:37,472 --> 00:41:39,425
Indians, South Africans,

504
00:41:39,543 --> 00:41:43,602
Greeks, Poles, Czechs and Free French.

505
00:41:43,687 --> 00:41:45,672
Twice as many men as Rommel had.

506
00:41:46,142 --> 00:41:49,012
Nothing was being left to chance.

507
00:41:49,096 --> 00:41:53,385
(man) We were fully trained.
We were really confident.

508
00:41:53,892 --> 00:41:59,905
(man #2) Every single solitary man
knew exactly what he had to do.

509
00:41:59,992 --> 00:42:02,206
(man) Everything was in your favour.

510
00:42:02,332 --> 00:42:05,092
We had no fear as such.

511
00:42:05,171 --> 00:42:06,590
It's an old adage, you know,

512
00:42:06,706 --> 00:42:10,655
that it'll never happen to you
personally, you think.

513
00:42:11,808 --> 00:42:14,983
(narrator) October 23, 1942.

514
00:42:15,146 --> 00:42:20,165
In the darkening desert, 1,100 tanks
and 1,000 guns moved into position.

515
00:42:21,093 --> 00:42:24,082
(man) I was with my battalion,

516
00:42:24,162 --> 00:42:27,991
laying mines
in front of our own positions,

517
00:42:28,075 --> 00:42:31,326
and the Battle of Alamein started

518
00:42:31,413 --> 00:42:36,323
by seeing the whole horizon on fire.

519
00:42:48,869 --> 00:42:54,466
(man #2) A lot of people think
that Alamein was a big barrage

520
00:42:54,547 --> 00:42:56,532
and everybody waiting behind,

521
00:42:56,618 --> 00:42:59,182
queuing up ready to go
once the barrage finished.

522
00:42:59,266 --> 00:43:04,404
But it wasn't like that. There was some
bloody fighting there, believe me.

523
00:43:04,483 --> 00:43:07,276
(man #3) We moved off
before the barrage

524
00:43:07,360 --> 00:43:09,848
and we were allowed a walking pace -

525
00:43:09,931 --> 00:43:13,761
that was so the artillery
fell in front of us.

526
00:43:16,798 --> 00:43:21,054
(man #4) In the morning
we were disappointed, to say the least.

527
00:43:21,133 --> 00:43:27,725
When the tanks should've passed us,
they hadn't arrived. Nobody had arrived.

528
00:43:31,070 --> 00:43:35,892
By the time the sappers got the mines up
and there was a road made,

529
00:43:35,981 --> 00:43:40,498
the Germans realised the reason,
and they pinpointed that opening.

530
00:43:45,265 --> 00:43:49,630
(man #3) There was uncertainty that
the ground would erupt underneath you,

531
00:43:49,792 --> 00:43:54,233
but you forget about running through a
minefield when a shell suddenly drops

532
00:43:54,319 --> 00:43:57,265
and machine-gun fire opens up
and mortar fire.

533
00:43:57,350 --> 00:43:58,998
There were squeals, shouts.

534
00:43:59,115 --> 00:44:01,722
(Harding) It was a battle of attrition.

535
00:44:01,800 --> 00:44:05,936
It was fought in a way,
and rightly in a way,

536
00:44:06,020 --> 00:44:10,385
in which you had to continue
the offensive

537
00:44:10,471 --> 00:44:13,340
until you had broken
the enemy's power of resistance.

538
00:44:13,425 --> 00:44:14,996
And this does take time.

539
00:44:15,918 --> 00:44:19,170
(man #3)
If infantry destroys the antitank gun

540
00:44:19,256 --> 00:44:20,936
and the minefields are clear,

541
00:44:21,059 --> 00:44:23,896
then the tank can come forward
and exploit the situation.

542
00:44:24,013 --> 00:44:27,887
But until that happens,
no success, no tanks.

543
00:44:28,655 --> 00:44:31,951
(narrator) Montgomery lost 200 tanks
in the first two days,

544
00:44:32,032 --> 00:44:35,098
as many as the Germans had started with.

545
00:44:35,178 --> 00:44:38,429
Rommel, now back in Africa,
though clearly far from well,

546
00:44:38,554 --> 00:44:42,187
immediately counterattacked,
angry his panzers had not done so

547
00:44:42,275 --> 00:44:45,188
when the British had been bogged down
in the minefields.

548
00:44:45,267 --> 00:44:47,755
It was too late.

549
00:44:50,754 --> 00:44:53,666
Rommel was thrown back,
with losses he could ill afford.

550
00:44:53,746 --> 00:44:56,965
Casualties were heavy on both sides.

551
00:45:06,713 --> 00:45:11,427
(man) They really hung on, see.
It was really stubborn.

552
00:45:11,509 --> 00:45:16,954
When we'd finished, then we realised
the casualties we'd left behind.

553
00:45:17,878 --> 00:45:21,937
You kept saying to yourself, "It won't
happen to me. He'll catch it, I won't."

554
00:45:22,021 --> 00:45:23,625
All of a sudden it dawns on you,

555
00:45:23,709 --> 00:45:27,429
"One day you won't always
get away with it, lad."

556
00:45:34,489 --> 00:45:37,556
(narrator) It was a killing match,
as Monty had predicted.

557
00:45:37,635 --> 00:45:40,505
A messy, horrid killing match.

558
00:45:41,088 --> 00:45:46,107
A First World War battle
fought with Second World War weapons.

559
00:45:52,214 --> 00:45:54,854
The battle of attrition
was going Montgomery's way.

560
00:45:54,938 --> 00:45:58,157
The moment had come
for him to let loose his armour.

561
00:46:15,079 --> 00:46:19,564
800 tanks, mostly Shermans,
the latest and best tank from America,

562
00:46:19,645 --> 00:46:21,979
were thrown against
the Germans and Italians.

563
00:46:22,062 --> 00:46:24,396
And Rommel had less than 100 tanks.

564
00:46:33,303 --> 00:46:35,255
Again, the fighting was bitter.

565
00:46:35,336 --> 00:46:37,518
Rommel began to yield a little.

566
00:46:51,986 --> 00:46:54,398
For two days more the battle raged.

567
00:46:54,480 --> 00:46:57,808
It was the biggest tank battle
of the Desert War.

568
00:46:59,659 --> 00:47:04,952
Rommel was now down to only 35 tanks,
compared with Montgomery's 600.

569
00:47:06,527 --> 00:47:10,051
Just when he was thinking of slipping
away to hold a line 60 miles back,

570
00:47:10,171 --> 00:47:12,583
Hitler ordered him to stay.

571
00:47:16,348 --> 00:47:21,018
(man) It's a particularly nasty form
of ending one's days

572
00:47:21,105 --> 00:47:23,561
if one is trapped in a tank

573
00:47:23,637 --> 00:47:27,238
and the tank brews up and is on fire.

574
00:47:27,320 --> 00:47:32,231
You will never lose the awfulness

575
00:47:32,346 --> 00:47:34,834
of screams of men trying to get out.

576
00:47:50,109 --> 00:47:52,291
(narrator)
The British armour was through

577
00:47:52,373 --> 00:47:55,668
and by the afternoon of November 4,
the 12th day of the battle,

578
00:47:55,749 --> 00:47:58,662
Rommel was in full retreat.

579
00:48:03,844 --> 00:48:08,666
Thousands of Italians were left behind.
The Germans had pinched their transport.

580
00:48:08,754 --> 00:48:11,777
Rommel's deputy, Von Thoma,
was captured too.

581
00:48:18,844 --> 00:48:22,292
Alexander signalled Churchill
to ring out the victory bell,

582
00:48:22,374 --> 00:48:23,596
which Winston did -

583
00:48:23,678 --> 00:48:28,665
the first time church bells had been
rung in Britain since Dunkirk.

584
00:48:30,315 --> 00:48:32,345
(thunder)

585
00:48:32,425 --> 00:48:37,063
Heavy rain fell on November 6
to impede both pursued and pursuer.

586
00:48:37,144 --> 00:48:40,134
Montgomery's corps commanders
were all for rushing ahead

587
00:48:40,213 --> 00:48:42,669
to trap Rommel
before he could reorganise.

588
00:48:42,746 --> 00:48:46,303
Monty was not going to risk
being trapped himself.

589
00:48:47,234 --> 00:48:50,638
(Harding) Montgomery was very conscious

590
00:48:50,725 --> 00:48:54,403
that we had already been twice up
and twice back,

591
00:48:54,485 --> 00:48:59,046
and he was determined
not to push back for a third time.

592
00:49:01,966 --> 00:49:03,570
(narrator) The air force saw to it

593
00:49:03,654 --> 00:49:06,796
that Rommel's retreat
was not without incident.

594
00:49:09,332 --> 00:49:12,890
(man) He had nowhere to run.
All he could was run into the sand.

595
00:49:12,977 --> 00:49:16,228
(man #2) This is where desert warfare
was something on its own.

596
00:49:16,315 --> 00:49:18,878
You just sat out there
or moved out there

597
00:49:18,962 --> 00:49:20,872
and you were exposed to everything.

598
00:49:20,957 --> 00:49:22,528
(gunfire)

599
00:49:40,446 --> 00:49:43,971
(narrator) Past Mersa Matruh,
Sidi Barrani, through Halfaya Pass,

600
00:49:44,053 --> 00:49:48,647
Rommel was pushed back,
turning to fight a little every day.

601
00:49:50,997 --> 00:49:54,292
On November 13,
to Churchill's great joy,

602
00:49:54,373 --> 00:49:56,587
Tobruk was retaken.

603
00:49:56,675 --> 00:49:59,282
A week later it was Benghazi's turn
to change hands

604
00:49:59,360 --> 00:50:02,885
for the fifth and positively final time.

605
00:50:10,639 --> 00:50:14,775
In mid-January 1943, Tripoli fell -

606
00:50:14,859 --> 00:50:19,268
the prize that had eluded O'Connor
two years before.

607
00:50:24,489 --> 00:50:28,515
At last the British people
had something really to cheer about.

608
00:50:28,594 --> 00:50:32,119
And Churchill?
The big victory he had been hoping for

609
00:50:32,200 --> 00:50:35,604
before America would dominate the war.

610
00:50:37,993 --> 00:50:42,707
(Churchill) You have altered the face
of the war in the most remarkable way.

611
00:50:42,827 --> 00:50:47,650
I must tell you that your fame,

612
00:50:47,738 --> 00:50:52,146
the fame of the Desert Army,
has spread throughout the world.

613
00:50:52,227 --> 00:50:54,136
(bagpipes playing)

614
00:50:57,559 --> 00:51:00,200
Now, this is not the end.

615
00:51:00,283 --> 00:51:04,691
It is not even the beginning of the end.

616
00:51:04,772 --> 00:51:08,722
But it is, perhaps,
the end of the beginning.
