1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:08,000
== Ripped & corrected by Kaitian ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==

2
00:00:02,587 --> 00:00:04,496
(tea dance)

3
00:00:10,374 --> 00:00:13,320
(narrator) For the wartime
newsreel cameras,

4
00:00:13,404 --> 00:00:15,160
the dancers wore gas masks.

5
00:00:15,246 --> 00:00:19,806
But the Germans never used gas
against British civilians.

6
00:00:20,923 --> 00:00:25,408
Hitler's weapon
against British civilians was bombs.

7
00:00:25,488 --> 00:00:29,853
Over two million homes
were damaged, blasted, gutted.

8
00:00:29,938 --> 00:00:34,575
And beginning with London,
whole cities were hammered.

9
00:00:34,657 --> 00:00:37,145
Fire and high explosives

10
00:00:37,265 --> 00:00:41,630
probed and tested the strength
of the British way of life.

11
00:01:38,260 --> 00:01:40,213
(air-raid siren)

12
00:01:49,117 --> 00:01:53,983
In November 1940, the Germans
shifted their attack from London.

13
00:01:54,065 --> 00:01:58,550
The first provincial city they hit hard
was Coventry.

14
00:02:01,891 --> 00:02:03,876
(church organ)

15
00:02:09,141 --> 00:02:13,735
The heart was torn out of the cathedral,
out of the city.

16
00:02:18,809 --> 00:02:20,489
People were bewildered,

17
00:02:20,573 --> 00:02:24,479
and their leaders were bewildered, too,
by the huge fires.

18
00:02:27,862 --> 00:02:31,266
(man) On paper, Birmingham, Nuneaton,

19
00:02:31,353 --> 00:02:34,681
Rugby, should've come
to the aid of Coventry,

20
00:02:34,767 --> 00:02:37,134
which they did, in fact.

21
00:02:37,222 --> 00:02:39,251
But on arrival here, they found

22
00:02:39,332 --> 00:02:43,161
that the couplings
on the fire engines were dissimilar,

23
00:02:43,245 --> 00:02:45,962
didn't marry up,
and it meant, therefore,

24
00:02:46,045 --> 00:02:49,570
that cooperation broke down completely.

25
00:02:49,651 --> 00:02:54,943
Of course, in addition to that,
you've got 360 fractures on the gas main

26
00:02:55,022 --> 00:02:58,121
and all the other services went.

27
00:02:58,206 --> 00:03:00,923
All the water supplies
were disconnected.

28
00:03:01,006 --> 00:03:06,865
If the firemen wanted to find sources,
they simply were not there.

29
00:03:07,873 --> 00:03:12,313
(narrator) The king visited Coventry.
With him, the Home Secretary.

30
00:03:12,438 --> 00:03:14,697
(Hodgkinson) Herbert Morrison came in.

31
00:03:14,778 --> 00:03:17,691
The military folk
wanted to establish martial law.

32
00:03:17,770 --> 00:03:21,295
We had a stand-up fight on this.

33
00:03:21,376 --> 00:03:27,813
Alderman Bill Halliwell and myself said,
"No, this must be a civic exercise."

34
00:03:27,898 --> 00:03:33,648
The pressure was taken off
and virtually he and I,

35
00:03:33,729 --> 00:03:38,977
plus the regional officers,
conducted operations from then on.

36
00:03:39,061 --> 00:03:42,509
There were virtually
seven weeks of dictatorship.

37
00:03:43,818 --> 00:03:48,073
You see, there was nothing
in the textbooks of civilian defence

38
00:03:48,153 --> 00:03:50,836
to indicate to local authorities

39
00:03:50,915 --> 00:03:55,093
how to behave in an emergency,
calamity situation,

40
00:03:55,173 --> 00:04:00,039
such as we found
on the morning of November 15th.

41
00:04:00,122 --> 00:04:03,111
(narrator)
While Morrison strove to correct this

42
00:04:03,190 --> 00:04:06,332
by creating Britain's
first national fire service,

43
00:04:06,413 --> 00:04:09,587
volunteers shored up
the crumbling home front.

44
00:04:09,674 --> 00:04:12,008
Fresh evacuation
hurried the children away,

45
00:04:12,090 --> 00:04:14,698
as city after city
passed through crisis.

46
00:04:17,154 --> 00:04:19,336
Portsmouth, Southampton,

47
00:04:19,417 --> 00:04:23,018
Sheffield, Bristol, Glasgow.

48
00:04:23,100 --> 00:04:25,708
Then Plymouth became the worst-hit city

49
00:04:25,785 --> 00:04:29,418
with seven big raids
in March and April 1941.

50
00:04:29,507 --> 00:04:31,721
A quarter of its people,
50,000 trekkers,

51
00:04:31,808 --> 00:04:34,372
fled the city at night
and slept out in the hills.

52
00:04:34,455 --> 00:04:37,936
This film was not shown
in wartime Britain.

53
00:04:38,943 --> 00:04:42,468
The censored press
could only hint at chaos.

54
00:04:42,549 --> 00:04:47,416
30,000 people lost their homes
and many lost much more.

55
00:04:49,455 --> 00:04:51,407
(alarm)

56
00:04:51,488 --> 00:04:56,474
And when the sirens went, it was
somewhere around nine o'clock, I think,

57
00:04:56,551 --> 00:04:59,955
I called my mother
and she came down the stairs.

58
00:05:00,042 --> 00:05:03,599
She said, "I'll take Raymond."
I said, "All right, I'll take Sheila."

59
00:05:03,687 --> 00:05:06,753
And we called Mrs Todd,
that was the lady upstairs,

60
00:05:06,832 --> 00:05:09,320
and she came down
with her three children.

61
00:05:09,403 --> 00:05:13,429
And we went in our respective cupboards,

62
00:05:13,507 --> 00:05:17,992
and I sat on a little tiny chair,
I put Raymond at my side,

63
00:05:18,072 --> 00:05:21,018
and I held Sheila in my arms.

64
00:05:22,599 --> 00:05:25,850
And after that, I didn't know anything.

65
00:05:26,972 --> 00:05:31,227
I must've come to in the cupboard,
because I heard my father say:

66
00:05:31,307 --> 00:05:34,678
"Oh, I'm afraid your mother's had it."

67
00:05:34,798 --> 00:05:40,973
And then I said, "Oh,
Sheila's all right. She's in my arms."

68
00:05:41,051 --> 00:05:47,031
And I went to touch my other child
and I couldn't feel him.

69
00:05:47,112 --> 00:05:51,858
And I must've lost consciousness again
because I was buried, I believe.

70
00:05:53,710 --> 00:05:59,307
Later, I learned that my mother was dead
and the two children were.

71
00:05:59,426 --> 00:06:03,757
And Mrs Todd was killed,
and her two children.

72
00:06:03,876 --> 00:06:06,331
She was expecting a baby any hour.

73
00:06:06,408 --> 00:06:08,547
(narrator)
Mrs Bunt's husband, a sailor,

74
00:06:08,633 --> 00:06:10,509
came home on leave the next morning.

75
00:06:10,589 --> 00:06:14,692
(man) There was her mother
laying on the bed in the front room.

76
00:06:14,771 --> 00:06:18,218
We went across the road
to her brother's place.

77
00:06:18,300 --> 00:06:22,129
He told me about the two children.

78
00:06:22,213 --> 00:06:26,316
I went up, there they were... cold.

79
00:06:26,394 --> 00:06:28,380
Not a blemish on them.

80
00:06:31,458 --> 00:06:33,792
That's when I lost my temper.

81
00:06:33,875 --> 00:06:37,278
I said,
"Instead of us dropping bloody paper,

82
00:06:37,366 --> 00:06:40,388
we ought to be hitting them
the same as they're hitting us."

83
00:06:40,511 --> 00:06:43,882
Mr Magee, after all this,
what do you think about us

84
00:06:43,964 --> 00:06:46,953
going over to Berlin and doing the same?

85
00:06:47,033 --> 00:06:48,298
I should think so, too.

86
00:06:48,376 --> 00:06:51,703
Bit worse than this, I hope,
with a wicked bugger like he is.

87
00:06:51,790 --> 00:06:54,779
I definitely do, sir.
Bomb them tenfold.

88
00:06:54,859 --> 00:06:57,314
I'm sorry
for the women and children of Berlin,

89
00:06:57,390 --> 00:06:59,572
but what about
the people of this country?

90
00:06:59,654 --> 00:07:01,639
(cheering)

91
00:07:03,912 --> 00:07:09,389
(narrator) This is what the authorised
newsreels did show of Plymouth.

92
00:07:09,474 --> 00:07:13,577
Churchill's voice and presence
did sustain morale.

93
00:07:13,694 --> 00:07:16,913
And in cabinet,
he knew how to get his way.

94
00:07:18,835 --> 00:07:22,086
And if Henry V said,
"Now, gentlemen,

95
00:07:22,172 --> 00:07:28,108
I've been into all this thing and the
Channel is very tricky at the moment."

96
00:07:28,195 --> 00:07:34,250
"We can't get the reinforcements,
the rate of sickness can't be replaced."

97
00:07:34,333 --> 00:07:40,999
"The bridgehead, according to Hamley's
infantry tactics, is too small."

98
00:07:41,084 --> 00:07:45,372
"And, in short, I feel there's
nothing else but to launch an attack."

99
00:07:45,458 --> 00:07:47,258
But he didn't say that.

100
00:07:47,337 --> 00:07:51,440
He said, "Once more
unto the breach, dear friends."

101
00:07:51,557 --> 00:07:54,656
Winston had that extraordinary power.

102
00:07:54,741 --> 00:07:57,534
(narrator) Churchill's speeches
rang less true now.

103
00:07:57,657 --> 00:07:58,954
Almost worse than bombing,

104
00:07:59,076 --> 00:08:01,945
U-boat attacks on shipping
cut Britain's food supplies.

105
00:08:02,030 --> 00:08:05,707
The Germans
were on the rampage everywhere.

106
00:08:07,017 --> 00:08:13,301
(Churchill) We cannot tell what
the course of this fell war will be,

107
00:08:13,385 --> 00:08:18,098
as it spreads, remorseless,
through ever-wider regions.

108
00:08:18,180 --> 00:08:21,857
We know it will be hard.
We expect it will be long,

109
00:08:22,822 --> 00:08:28,528
We cannot yet see how deliverance
will come or when it will come,

110
00:08:28,614 --> 00:08:34,790
but nothing is more certain than
that every trace of Hitler's footsteps,

111
00:08:34,867 --> 00:08:40,159
every stain
of his infected and corroding fingers,

112
00:08:40,276 --> 00:08:42,960
will be sponged and purged

113
00:08:43,077 --> 00:08:47,790
and, if need be,
blasted from the surface of the earth.

114
00:08:47,872 --> 00:08:52,312
He may spread his course far and wide

115
00:08:52,437 --> 00:08:55,350
and carry his curse with him.

116
00:08:55,429 --> 00:09:00,099
He may break into Africa or into Asia.

117
00:09:00,186 --> 00:09:05,630
But it is with us,
here in this island fortress,

118
00:09:05,710 --> 00:09:10,925
that he will have to reckon
and settle in the end.

119
00:09:13,804 --> 00:09:16,259
Now behold in me an LDV

120
00:09:16,336 --> 00:09:18,212
For battle I'm just yearning

121
00:09:18,293 --> 00:09:20,627
Doing my best like all the rest

122
00:09:20,709 --> 00:09:22,739
To keep the home fires burning

123
00:09:22,819 --> 00:09:25,186
Each evening stiff and starched

124
00:09:25,274 --> 00:09:27,030
Up and down the street I march

125
00:09:27,116 --> 00:09:29,571
I'm guarding
the home of the Home Guard

126
00:09:29,648 --> 00:09:31,786
Guarding the Home Guard's home

127
00:09:31,873 --> 00:09:33,978
All day long, steady and strong

128
00:09:34,059 --> 00:09:36,121
Doing what I'm told
and I can't go wrong

129
00:09:36,246 --> 00:09:40,152
All the ladies are fond of me
but last night one of them gave a shout

130
00:09:40,235 --> 00:09:42,374
When she saw me
pulling my bayonet out

131
00:09:42,460 --> 00:09:44,719
While guarding the Home Guard's home

132
00:09:46,412 --> 00:09:49,434
(narrator) The Home Guard
had been founded a year before.

133
00:09:49,557 --> 00:09:52,623
On exercises,
its members played at fighting.

134
00:09:52,703 --> 00:09:57,569
You are a new corps,
a corps with its traditions to make.

135
00:09:57,652 --> 00:10:03,827
But you have already got your motto,
and your motto is: "Kill the Boche!"

136
00:10:03,905 --> 00:10:07,385
In the course of your duty,

137
00:10:07,511 --> 00:10:11,875
you may have the luck
to come in contact with the enemy.

138
00:10:11,999 --> 00:10:14,061
If you do, one of your duties

139
00:10:14,147 --> 00:10:17,747
is to shoot when you see a sitter,
and shoot to kill.

140
00:10:19,288 --> 00:10:21,622
(narrator)
The British still lived in fear,

141
00:10:21,704 --> 00:10:26,571
not just of invasion,
but of the foe at home -

142
00:10:26,653 --> 00:10:28,715
fear of listening spies.

143
00:10:33,251 --> 00:10:35,782
And fear of enemy aliens.

144
00:10:37,164 --> 00:10:41,572
In the summer of 1940, the press
had screamed, "Intern the lot."

145
00:10:41,691 --> 00:10:44,222
And almost all of them -
Germans, Austrians,

146
00:10:44,299 --> 00:10:46,285
refugee Jews, left-wing exiles -

147
00:10:46,371 --> 00:10:51,815
had passed through verminous
transit camps, interned without trial.

148
00:10:51,895 --> 00:10:54,458
I was interned just like that, you know?

149
00:10:54,542 --> 00:11:00,368
Fetched by the police
without knowing anything beforehand.

150
00:11:00,450 --> 00:11:02,784
Two policemen came and fetched me.

151
00:11:04,132 --> 00:11:06,391
(narrator)
Although they did not know it,

152
00:11:06,472 --> 00:11:09,156
they were bound for Liverpool,
for embarkation.

153
00:11:09,234 --> 00:11:13,293
People standing lining the streets,
you know?

154
00:11:13,377 --> 00:11:20,197
Throwing stones at you, spitting at you,
shouting "spies", you know?

155
00:11:20,283 --> 00:11:23,043
And that was horrible.

156
00:11:24,042 --> 00:11:28,864
Everyone thought it will be a
concentration camp like it is in Austria

157
00:11:28,952 --> 00:11:31,898
or in Germany.

158
00:11:31,983 --> 00:11:35,463
And we were brought on that boat.

159
00:11:35,550 --> 00:11:38,540
Several of them
wanted to jump into the water

160
00:11:38,619 --> 00:11:43,136
because they didn't know
what is in front of them.

161
00:11:43,261 --> 00:11:45,716
When we arrived on the Isle of Man,

162
00:11:45,793 --> 00:11:48,859
we had pictures taken
with our number on.

163
00:11:48,939 --> 00:11:53,379
So we had already the feeling,
"Well, we are criminals."

164
00:11:53,465 --> 00:11:58,212
But from that moment on,
it was much, much better.

165
00:11:58,299 --> 00:12:02,402
We had quite nice people
to look after us,

166
00:12:02,519 --> 00:12:05,159
and we had more security.

167
00:12:05,242 --> 00:12:10,032
We had so much security
that we were fenced in, even.

168
00:12:10,114 --> 00:12:13,518
(narrator) Aliens had the right
of appeal to tribunals,

169
00:12:13,605 --> 00:12:15,864
and by 1941 many were free.

170
00:12:15,945 --> 00:12:18,815
But a new threat to civil liberty
had loomed:

171
00:12:18,899 --> 00:12:21,354
Regulation 2D.

172
00:12:23,694 --> 00:12:26,149
Because Stalin
was in alliance with Hitler,

173
00:12:26,226 --> 00:12:29,597
the British Communist Party
opposed the war effort.

174
00:12:29,717 --> 00:12:34,201
Under 2D, its paper,
the Daily Worker, had been banned.

175
00:12:34,282 --> 00:12:36,770
Five months later
when Hitler struck at Russia,

176
00:12:36,891 --> 00:12:40,523
Churchill himself
seized the chance to be Stalin's ally.

177
00:12:40,612 --> 00:12:42,030
Germany's new thrust east

178
00:12:42,108 --> 00:12:44,748
took the pressure
off Churchill's battered island.

179
00:12:44,831 --> 00:12:50,156
There was time now to perfect
the new and truly total war economy.

180
00:12:51,813 --> 00:12:54,344
But at its head,
in the coalition government,

181
00:12:54,422 --> 00:12:55,840
were two jealous rivals -

182
00:12:55,956 --> 00:12:58,564
big men brought in
from outside Parliament.

183
00:12:58,642 --> 00:13:02,853
Max Beaverbrook, the newspaper baron,
now Minister of Supply,

184
00:13:02,938 --> 00:13:05,698
and Ernest Bevin,
the strong man of the TUC.

185
00:13:08,232 --> 00:13:11,298
For Bevin,
the industrial workers were his people.

186
00:13:12,145 --> 00:13:16,323
Well, mates, ever since we took office,

187
00:13:16,403 --> 00:13:19,883
we have been exhorting you
to work harder.

188
00:13:19,971 --> 00:13:24,881
I've never done so much exhortation
to work hard in my life.

189
00:13:24,996 --> 00:13:28,215
But we've got to do it
to win this victory.

190
00:13:29,024 --> 00:13:34,196
We'll all go along together
with a mighty effort,

191
00:13:34,318 --> 00:13:37,384
and show to the Hitlers and Mussolinis

192
00:13:37,502 --> 00:13:40,448
that we do not only work and fight,

193
00:13:40,533 --> 00:13:43,369
but we can be cheerful
in doing it as well.

194
00:13:43,448 --> 00:13:45,433
(cheering)

195
00:13:50,622 --> 00:13:54,374
(Chandos) Ernie Bevin, you see,
is an Englishman to the fingertips,

196
00:13:54,458 --> 00:13:57,447
and with a great hold
over the trade unions

197
00:13:57,527 --> 00:14:00,058
and the labour movement as a whole.

198
00:14:00,135 --> 00:14:04,117
I think he's the most conceited man
that I've ever known.

199
00:14:04,202 --> 00:14:07,343
It happens to self-made men very often.

200
00:14:07,424 --> 00:14:09,377
But the great thing about Ernie

201
00:14:09,457 --> 00:14:12,065
is that he never
went back on what he said.

202
00:14:12,142 --> 00:14:15,743
He'd say to me,
"Well, I said it, didn't I?"

203
00:14:15,825 --> 00:14:19,731
That is a tremendous thing.
He was very loyal in those ways.

204
00:14:19,815 --> 00:14:21,615
A very likeable man.

205
00:14:21,695 --> 00:14:24,946
And one day, we were fighting for,
a rather technical point,

206
00:14:25,032 --> 00:14:27,715
the extraction of wheat in the loaf.

207
00:14:27,794 --> 00:14:31,514
And they were trying to get it
up to 88% extraction.

208
00:14:31,592 --> 00:14:36,305
And Ernie suddenly said
in the committee, he said:

209
00:14:36,387 --> 00:14:38,995
"I say the middle of this loaf
is indigestible."

210
00:14:39,072 --> 00:14:41,909
"I can't eat it.
(hiccups) What did I tell you?"

211
00:14:41,988 --> 00:14:45,086
Churchill grew in admiration

212
00:14:45,172 --> 00:14:49,001
of the great fundamental qualities
of Bevin -

213
00:14:49,085 --> 00:14:50,961
his single-purposeness

214
00:14:51,041 --> 00:14:56,977
and the obvious desire,
determination, on the part of Bevin,

215
00:14:57,064 --> 00:15:01,319
to suppress
all party-political considerations.

216
00:15:01,476 --> 00:15:03,581
Imagine the power he had.

217
00:15:03,662 --> 00:15:09,292
He was in charge
of the possibilities of service

218
00:15:09,378 --> 00:15:13,175
for everybody
in the civilian life of this country.

219
00:15:14,212 --> 00:15:18,652
(narrator) He had total powers over
every man working, and over every woman.

220
00:15:18,738 --> 00:15:23,910
From March 1941, Bevin began
to direct women into vital work,

221
00:15:23,994 --> 00:15:28,631
and into vital work the pretty girls
went, but not enough of them.

222
00:15:28,712 --> 00:15:32,465
So in December, Britain went further
than any fighting land had ever done

223
00:15:32,548 --> 00:15:34,730
and further than
the Germans could ever go.

224
00:15:34,812 --> 00:15:38,107
Conscription of women was announced.

225
00:15:38,188 --> 00:15:42,137
Girls called up could choose between
the women's services

226
00:15:42,216 --> 00:15:45,467
or war work in the fields or factories.

227
00:15:48,046 --> 00:15:49,922
(radio) "Music While You Work"

228
00:15:50,003 --> 00:15:53,876
will be played to you this morning
on Rhythmic Records.

229
00:15:53,954 --> 00:15:56,485
(sings along)

230
00:15:56,563 --> 00:15:59,126
("Yes, My Darling Daughter)

231
00:16:13,979 --> 00:16:18,310
- You'll be leaving us shortly?
- Y es, I th ink I will.

232
00:16:18,391 --> 00:16:20,452
I think I'll give the Land Army a try.

233
00:16:20,577 --> 00:16:24,788
- Do you think you'll like that?
- Yes. The life rather appeals to me.

234
00:16:24,874 --> 00:16:27,863
I don't think any of us
want to starve, though.

235
00:16:27,943 --> 00:16:32,853
What will I do about my hair? I can't
possibly come down to the country.

236
00:16:32,930 --> 00:16:37,065
Oh, well then, madam, I suggest
you wear it straight, like Hitler's.

237
00:16:37,188 --> 00:16:39,522
I'd like to help to build Spitfires.

238
00:16:39,604 --> 00:16:44,241
My boy's in the RAF, well,
and I feel I'm helping him.

239
00:16:44,323 --> 00:16:47,389
The sooner we all pull together,
the sooner it'll be over.

240
00:16:47,469 --> 00:16:50,796
I would like to go in the services
because the uniform appeals.

241
00:16:50,883 --> 00:16:52,912
("Fall In")

242
00:16:57,212 --> 00:17:00,583
(woman) Changing step
at the march in quick time.

243
00:17:00,665 --> 00:17:02,618
Change step!

244
00:17:03,657 --> 00:17:05,031
Change step!

245
00:17:05,499 --> 00:17:09,557
Move to the right in threes.
About... turn!

246
00:17:12,442 --> 00:17:14,242
Slow...

247
00:17:14,322 --> 00:17:15,619
march!

248
00:17:15,703 --> 00:17:18,158
About...

249
00:17:18,657 --> 00:17:20,642
turn!

250
00:17:22,761 --> 00:17:25,325
(narrator) Bevin's concern
was long-term efficiency,

251
00:17:25,408 --> 00:17:28,659
but Beaverbrook revelled
in short-term frenzies.

252
00:17:28,746 --> 00:17:30,698
Now he was calling for tanks.

253
00:17:30,817 --> 00:17:33,348
We want tanks.

254
00:17:33,426 --> 00:17:36,109
We want very many tanks.

255
00:17:36,188 --> 00:17:40,628
We want them
for the defence of our island

256
00:17:40,714 --> 00:17:44,664
and also for offensive operations.

257
00:17:44,742 --> 00:17:48,572
(narrator) Beaverbrook's methods
outraged his colleagues.

258
00:17:48,655 --> 00:17:50,411
Even his loyal friend Churchill

259
00:17:50,497 --> 00:17:53,180
was troubled by his moods,
his resignations,

260
00:17:53,297 --> 00:17:56,363
and his quarrels with Bevin.

261
00:17:56,443 --> 00:18:01,037
(Chandos) Max Beaverbrook
did a very good crash job.

262
00:18:01,622 --> 00:18:04,534
But in my opinion, and I am biased,

263
00:18:04,614 --> 00:18:10,593
he left behind an enormous quantity
of wreckage - administrative wreckage.

264
00:18:11,442 --> 00:18:16,767
And he said,
"War is a matter of improvisation."

265
00:18:16,851 --> 00:18:19,873
"Organisation
is the enemy of improvisation."

266
00:18:20,956 --> 00:18:22,985
(man) Ernie Bevin...

267
00:18:23,066 --> 00:18:25,171
domineering, dogmatic,

268
00:18:25,252 --> 00:18:27,619
even tyrannical, could be ruthless.

269
00:18:27,707 --> 00:18:31,504
"Don't stand in my way.
Don't criticise me."

270
00:18:31,582 --> 00:18:35,531
"I will tolerate no interrogation
from any source."

271
00:18:36,300 --> 00:18:39,290
Beaverbrook the same. The same.

272
00:18:39,369 --> 00:18:44,694
Two strong personalities,
domineering and ruthless.

273
00:18:45,584 --> 00:18:47,002
(narrator) Early in 1942,

274
00:18:47,118 --> 00:18:50,108
Beaverbrook flounced out
after two weeks in a new job -

275
00:18:50,187 --> 00:18:53,483
boss of war industry,
Minister of Production.

276
00:18:54,484 --> 00:18:58,390
For convincing reasons,
Bevin had finally won.

277
00:18:58,473 --> 00:19:04,103
Well, I think he won because Churchill
had the sense, the common sense,

278
00:19:04,189 --> 00:19:09,328
to realise it was good to have
the trade union movement on his side.

279
00:19:09,445 --> 00:19:12,467
He didn't throw Beaverbrook overboard.

280
00:19:12,552 --> 00:19:16,840
Don't forget, Beaverbrook
was out and in, and out and in.

281
00:19:16,925 --> 00:19:20,646
(narrator) And finally out.
This time he stayed out.

282
00:19:20,723 --> 00:19:22,905
A visit to Russia,
where he'd been welcomed

283
00:19:22,987 --> 00:19:25,353
by Britain's ambassador,
Sir Stafford Cripps,

284
00:19:25,442 --> 00:19:30,919
had convinced him that the delightful
Stalin was a great man.

285
00:19:31,004 --> 00:19:34,103
Russia had been pressing
a reluctant British government

286
00:19:34,188 --> 00:19:36,021
to start a second front in Europe.

287
00:19:36,106 --> 00:19:40,012
Out of office, Beaverbrook flung himself
into a campaign for the second front,

288
00:19:40,096 --> 00:19:44,504
building on Britain's almost
mystical admiration for the Red Army.

289
00:19:44,622 --> 00:19:48,758
We believe in the skill
of the Russian generals.

290
00:19:48,842 --> 00:19:52,792
We believe in the equipment
of the Russian divisions.

291
00:19:52,870 --> 00:19:58,424
And we believe in the fighting power
and the courage of the Russian soldiers.

292
00:20:01,041 --> 00:20:05,907
And this is the day
to proclaim our faith!

293
00:20:05,990 --> 00:20:08,204
(cheering)

294
00:20:08,752 --> 00:20:11,010
Weapons we must give,

295
00:20:11,092 --> 00:20:13,929
and raw materials.

296
00:20:14,007 --> 00:20:15,993
Bread we must give,

297
00:20:16,117 --> 00:20:18,758
and sugar, too.

298
00:20:18,841 --> 00:20:21,754
Men we must give,

299
00:20:21,833 --> 00:20:25,630
equipped with tanks and with airplanes.

300
00:20:27,626 --> 00:20:30,844
That is a pledge of the second front.

301
00:20:30,925 --> 00:20:33,608
(cheering)

302
00:20:33,687 --> 00:20:36,250
(narrator)
Also cheering Beaverbrook on,

303
00:20:36,334 --> 00:20:39,171
Britain's Communist Party
now backed the war.

304
00:20:39,288 --> 00:20:41,470
Their leaders
were calling on the workers

305
00:20:41,551 --> 00:20:43,842
to make their war production
mightier yet.

306
00:20:43,929 --> 00:20:48,948
No one calls for the second front
without being personally prepared

307
00:20:49,070 --> 00:20:54,776
to place their being, their energy,
and every ounce of fight they possess

308
00:20:54,901 --> 00:20:57,541
at the disposal of the government.

309
00:20:57,625 --> 00:21:01,072
There is a full understanding
of what is meant,

310
00:21:01,154 --> 00:21:03,445
and the people of this country

311
00:21:03,532 --> 00:21:08,202
are quite rightly beginning to resent
this war on the cheap,

312
00:21:08,289 --> 00:21:11,006
this one-way war that's going on,

313
00:21:11,090 --> 00:21:13,620
where it's the Russians
that do the dying

314
00:21:13,698 --> 00:21:15,913
and the fighting and the sacrifice,

315
00:21:16,038 --> 00:21:17,762
while we pay tribute to them

316
00:21:17,841 --> 00:21:20,481
from the benches
of the House of Commons.

317
00:21:20,565 --> 00:21:22,856
(applause)

318
00:21:22,943 --> 00:21:26,085
(narrator) But one left-winger
on those benches, Cripps,

319
00:21:26,204 --> 00:21:28,887
had just returned
from his stint in Moscow.

320
00:21:28,966 --> 00:21:32,566
Many people saw him
as a possible rival for Churchill.

321
00:21:32,649 --> 00:21:35,638
His views on Russia had vast appeal.

322
00:21:37,022 --> 00:21:41,888
(Cripps) We've got to try and help
the Russians in every way that we can

323
00:21:41,971 --> 00:21:46,226
to make ready,
to meet the spring offensive of Hitler.

324
00:21:46,305 --> 00:21:49,218
I appreciate there are
some people in this country

325
00:21:49,298 --> 00:21:53,629
who are still afraid
of the spread of the Russian ideology.

326
00:21:53,709 --> 00:21:58,499
But what they've got to recollect
is that if we are friendly with Russia

327
00:21:58,581 --> 00:22:01,374
and have an arrangement
of cooperation with them,

328
00:22:01,458 --> 00:22:05,288
any dangers which they fear
will be very much less.

329
00:22:05,371 --> 00:22:11,230
As a matter of fact, the Soviet Union
have no idea and no wish

330
00:22:11,356 --> 00:22:15,720
to interfere with the internal affairs
of any other country.

331
00:22:15,806 --> 00:22:18,872
I know that
from the lips of Stalin himself.

332
00:22:28,005 --> 00:22:32,369
(narrator) Again, in the headlines,
disaster was stacked on defeat.

333
00:22:32,454 --> 00:22:33,873
The press was critical,

334
00:22:33,951 --> 00:22:38,238
especially the Daily Mirror's
scalding campaign against profiteers.

335
00:22:38,362 --> 00:22:40,729
One cartoon was too much for Churchill:

336
00:22:40,817 --> 00:22:46,262
"The price of petrol has been increased
by one penny - Official".

337
00:22:48,950 --> 00:22:51,164
Churchill told Morrison
to stop the paper,

338
00:22:51,252 --> 00:22:53,707
but the press
rallied to the Mirror's support,

339
00:22:53,784 --> 00:22:59,567
led by the young editor of Beaverbrook's
Evening Standard, Michael Foot.

340
00:22:59,653 --> 00:23:02,370
The liberty of press in this country

341
00:23:02,453 --> 00:23:06,556
can only be maintained
by the vigilance of the people,

342
00:23:06,635 --> 00:23:10,508
the vigilance of Parliament, and the
courage of the newspapers themselves.

343
00:23:10,624 --> 00:23:17,105
That's the only way. Therefore, we must
fight, fight to retain those liberties.

344
00:23:17,184 --> 00:23:21,701
The ministers come along and tell us,
they've told us in the last few weeks,

345
00:23:21,787 --> 00:23:24,886
it's only the Daily Mirror
they were trying to get at.

346
00:23:24,971 --> 00:23:27,993
"The attack is over," they say.

347
00:23:28,117 --> 00:23:30,648
"No more demands
on any other newspapers."

348
00:23:30,726 --> 00:23:34,904
"All other newspapers
may continue to live in tranquillity

349
00:23:34,984 --> 00:23:38,006
and in freedom and in peace."

350
00:23:38,091 --> 00:23:41,997
There's something rather familiar
about those words.

351
00:23:42,081 --> 00:23:46,184
- I have no more territorial demands.
- (laughter)

352
00:23:47,528 --> 00:23:50,899
I can picture in my mind's eye now

353
00:23:50,981 --> 00:23:55,421
Mr Morrison himself
muttering those words.

354
00:23:55,546 --> 00:23:59,026
"I have no more territorial demands."

355
00:23:59,113 --> 00:24:05,704
Coming down Shoe Lane with a firm look
on his jaw and a hot gun in his pocket,

356
00:24:05,788 --> 00:24:08,701
with the Evening Standard
safely suppressed under 2D,

357
00:24:08,780 --> 00:24:13,188
and its proprietors
safely looked after under 18B.

358
00:24:13,269 --> 00:24:16,902
The only man who thought it was
going to be shut down was Churchill.

359
00:24:17,028 --> 00:24:19,319
When it was brought up in the Commons,

360
00:24:19,407 --> 00:24:23,738
the House of Commons came out
on the side of the Mirror, more or less.

361
00:24:23,857 --> 00:24:28,767
They didn't like the Mirror, but they
weren't going to have it suppressed.

362
00:24:28,844 --> 00:24:31,833
And after that,
we trimmed ourselves a bit

363
00:24:31,912 --> 00:24:34,902
and the government
forgot their foolishness.

364
00:24:34,981 --> 00:24:40,000
(narrator) Since democratic life did
go on, there were still by-elections.

365
00:24:40,084 --> 00:24:43,957
The coalition government
lost a string of them to independents.

366
00:24:44,035 --> 00:24:47,635
Tom Driberg stood at Maldon
as an independent Socialist.

367
00:24:47,756 --> 00:24:50,930
Maldon was a very safe Tory seat.

368
00:24:51,017 --> 00:24:54,038
(man) I hadn't the faintest idea
how to be a candidate.

369
00:24:54,162 --> 00:24:59,683
I didn't belong to any party, I didn't
know the electoral law or anything.

370
00:24:59,763 --> 00:25:03,243
First I went to see my employer,
Lord Beaverbrook,

371
00:25:03,331 --> 00:25:07,815
whom I was working for at the time
on the Daily Express.

372
00:25:07,896 --> 00:25:10,656
And he was a bit sceptical.

373
00:25:10,773 --> 00:25:15,333
He said the only advice he would give me
was that I must wear a hat.

374
00:25:15,415 --> 00:25:16,985
He said, "The British people

375
00:25:17,064 --> 00:25:19,595
will never vote for a man
who doesn't wear a hat."

376
00:25:19,673 --> 00:25:23,775
(narrator) Then in June
came a fresh shock from Africa.

377
00:25:23,854 --> 00:25:26,494
(Driberg) Tobruk fell
about three or four days

378
00:25:26,578 --> 00:25:29,338
before polling day in the election.

379
00:25:29,417 --> 00:25:33,628
We rushed out a leaflet
headed "Tragedy at Tobruk".

380
00:25:33,713 --> 00:25:36,506
And it was a tragedy,
and we felt it as such,

381
00:25:36,590 --> 00:25:39,230
but, nonetheless,
I'm bound to admit that

382
00:25:39,314 --> 00:25:44,452
that did probably greatly add
to the number of votes which we got.

383
00:25:44,531 --> 00:25:47,171
(narrator)
Driberg won by a huge majority.

384
00:25:47,255 --> 00:25:52,547
Meanwhile, the rebel MPs of all parties
wanted a showdown with Churchill.

385
00:25:53,546 --> 00:25:57,179
(man) And when Tobruk fell in 1942,

386
00:25:57,267 --> 00:26:00,867
Churchill was in Washington.

387
00:26:00,950 --> 00:26:04,856
The American press
carried alarmist reports

388
00:26:04,939 --> 00:26:08,158
of the state of the government at home

389
00:26:08,315 --> 00:26:11,108
and the possible votes of censure,
and so on.

390
00:26:11,192 --> 00:26:13,723
So much so, that Winston rang me up.

391
00:26:13,801 --> 00:26:18,241
It was about 5am our time,
I suppose about midnight his time,

392
00:26:18,328 --> 00:26:22,430
to ask what was happening -

393
00:26:22,509 --> 00:26:26,186
was the government still in office
and what was going on, and so forth.

394
00:26:26,268 --> 00:26:28,952
And I was able to tell him,
so far as I knew,

395
00:26:29,030 --> 00:26:33,166
nothing had happened expect this motion
had been tabled that he'd have to take.

396
00:26:33,250 --> 00:26:35,235
(narrator) Churchill came back

397
00:26:35,322 --> 00:26:39,425
to a motion expressing no confidence
in his leadership.

398
00:26:39,503 --> 00:26:43,911
It even seemed to the rebels
that they might win, but they muffed it.

399
00:26:45,066 --> 00:26:48,895
As so often with these
great parliamentary debates,

400
00:26:48,978 --> 00:26:52,852
there's a bit of an anticlimax
when you get there.

401
00:26:52,930 --> 00:26:58,942
And in this case, the anticlimax
came instantly in the opening speech

402
00:26:59,029 --> 00:27:02,979
by this ineffable old Tory,
Sir John Wardlaw-Milne,

403
00:27:03,096 --> 00:27:06,314
because he made
this fantastic suggestion

404
00:27:06,395 --> 00:27:08,653
that there should be
a supreme commander

405
00:27:08,735 --> 00:27:10,949
of all the armed forces
who should be...

406
00:27:11,075 --> 00:27:16,781
And he named him none other than the
Duke of Gloucester, whom God preserve.

407
00:27:16,867 --> 00:27:23,196
But there was a roar of laughter
and a howl of disappointment.

408
00:27:23,274 --> 00:27:27,562
(narrator) And in gales of derision,
the motion was swept away.

409
00:27:27,647 --> 00:27:30,746
There were only 25 votes
against Churchill.

410
00:27:31,790 --> 00:27:35,390
And now the war news
began to grow brighter.

411
00:27:35,473 --> 00:27:38,571
The Germans were held up at Stalingrad.

412
00:27:38,657 --> 00:27:42,137
Britain won in November at El Alamein.

413
00:27:42,224 --> 00:27:46,250
Churchill went north to Bradford
in sprightly spirits.

414
00:27:47,173 --> 00:27:53,228
Now, we have just passed through
the month of November,

415
00:27:53,311 --> 00:27:56,257
usually a month of fogs and gloom,

416
00:27:56,341 --> 00:27:59,516
but, on the whole,
a month I've liked a good deal better

417
00:27:59,602 --> 00:28:01,936
than some other months we've seen

418
00:28:02,019 --> 00:28:05,619
during the course
of this present unpleasantness.

419
00:28:05,702 --> 00:28:08,189
- (applause)
- And so I say to you,

420
00:28:08,272 --> 00:28:14,447
let us go forward together and put
these grave matters to the proof.

421
00:28:14,525 --> 00:28:16,859
(cheering)

422
00:28:16,942 --> 00:28:20,313
(narrator) Churchill was safe
in power while the war lasted,

423
00:28:20,394 --> 00:28:23,842
but the hopes of the British people
were swinging away from him.

424
00:28:23,923 --> 00:28:27,556
Beyond victory,
what could Churchill offer them?

425
00:28:28,987 --> 00:28:33,242
Roll out the barrel

426
00:28:33,322 --> 00:28:37,916
We'll have a barrel of fun

427
00:28:38,002 --> 00:28:42,716
Roll out the barrel

428
00:28:42,836 --> 00:28:46,665
We've got the blues on the run

429
00:28:46,749 --> 00:28:50,884
(narrator) But by the middle of the war,
there weren't so many barrels.

430
00:28:50,968 --> 00:28:55,147
If you wanted beer,
you might have to bring your own bottle.

431
00:28:55,227 --> 00:28:59,329
And many other things which people
had relied on were now in short supply.

432
00:28:59,408 --> 00:29:05,005
Apples and razors, prams and potatoes,
bread and offal were all unrationed.

433
00:29:05,124 --> 00:29:07,153
But you had to queue.

434
00:29:12,873 --> 00:29:16,931
And because they hated queuing,
people welcomed rationing.

435
00:29:17,016 --> 00:29:21,653
Soap and clothes were rationed,
as well as most essential foodstuffs.

436
00:29:21,734 --> 00:29:25,990
You knew you could get the ration
and the British system seemed fair -

437
00:29:26,069 --> 00:29:28,753
the same for everyone, rich or poor.

438
00:29:28,831 --> 00:29:32,127
Each person got
up to eight ounces of sugar a week,

439
00:29:32,207 --> 00:29:35,077
every two months a packet of dried eggs,

440
00:29:35,161 --> 00:29:39,264
eight ounces of cheese a week, eight
ounces of fats, four ounces of bacon,

441
00:29:39,342 --> 00:29:41,677
and about a pound of meat.

442
00:29:51,158 --> 00:29:55,413
(man) Are you helping to win the war
on the kitchen front?

443
00:29:56,720 --> 00:30:03,463
If you're saving our shipping by
making the most of what we grow at home,

444
00:30:03,549 --> 00:30:09,953
if you're growing vegetables on every
bit of ground that you can get hold of,

445
00:30:10,032 --> 00:30:13,359
if you're only eating what you need

446
00:30:13,484 --> 00:30:17,433
and not what you like
and as much as you like,

447
00:30:17,512 --> 00:30:20,076
then you are helping to win the war.

448
00:30:20,197 --> 00:30:25,904
And my advice to you
is cook potatoes in their jackets,

449
00:30:25,990 --> 00:30:28,172
and grow your own onions.

450
00:30:28,253 --> 00:30:33,545
(narrator) And they did, assailed
by a barrage of films and posters.

451
00:30:33,624 --> 00:30:37,224
After war work, before fire watching,
between spells of training,

452
00:30:37,307 --> 00:30:40,144
townsmen toiled on their allotments.

453
00:30:40,222 --> 00:30:42,939
Britain was under blockade.

454
00:30:43,023 --> 00:30:45,128
By 1943, farmers had brought

455
00:30:45,209 --> 00:30:49,388
nearly four and a half million
extra acres under the plough,

456
00:30:49,467 --> 00:30:53,341
and allotments were chewing up
scraps of good land left over.

457
00:30:53,457 --> 00:30:57,439
Vegetables flourished
round the Albert Memorial.

458
00:31:02,932 --> 00:31:07,220
Good, plain food was still cheap
and unrationed in factory canteens

459
00:31:07,305 --> 00:31:09,761
and in new publicly-owned
British restaurants,

460
00:31:09,876 --> 00:31:15,200
but many people complained that the
rich could still find fancier titbits.

461
00:31:15,285 --> 00:31:19,267
The black market
snaked silently through Britain.

462
00:31:19,351 --> 00:31:22,755
"Poor fella.
Now, what can I sell his mother?"

463
00:31:27,292 --> 00:31:32,311
I want to talk to you
about what is called racketeering,

464
00:31:32,394 --> 00:31:34,925
or the black market.

465
00:31:35,003 --> 00:31:37,795
It is being stopped.

466
00:31:37,880 --> 00:31:41,677
These food cheats
are the enemies of the people.

467
00:31:41,754 --> 00:31:46,348
There must be no dirty fingers
in the people's food.

468
00:31:49,196 --> 00:31:53,561
(narrator) The ugly Squanderbug,
symbol of waste, was outlawed.

469
00:31:53,646 --> 00:31:56,287
Women were reminded
not to waste old clothes

470
00:31:56,370 --> 00:31:59,469
and not to ask for glamorous new ones.

471
00:32:05,807 --> 00:32:09,058
Every scrap
of manufactured matter counted.

472
00:32:09,681 --> 00:32:11,863
(newsreel) Fashion is rationed.

473
00:32:14,131 --> 00:32:16,117
The rot set in when silk stockings

474
00:32:16,203 --> 00:32:19,269
had to be sacrificed
in the early stages of the war.

475
00:32:19,349 --> 00:32:21,411
That was pre-Austerity.

476
00:32:21,497 --> 00:32:25,054
Did you realise the difference
between Austerity and Utility?

477
00:32:25,141 --> 00:32:29,320
Austerity, on the left, is the elder
sister of Utility, in the checked suit.

478
00:32:29,438 --> 00:32:30,889
And Austerity was allowed

479
00:32:30,972 --> 00:32:33,765
many fashionable privileges
denied to Utility.

480
00:32:33,849 --> 00:32:35,453
For instance, pleats.

481
00:32:35,537 --> 00:32:38,297
Utility, as you know,
is confined to four,

482
00:32:38,376 --> 00:32:41,365
whereas Austerity
was lavish with pleats.

483
00:32:43,631 --> 00:32:47,035
(narrator) Strict petrol al location
d rove cars off the road,

484
00:32:47,122 --> 00:32:50,188
though some drivers ran on coal gas.

485
00:32:52,800 --> 00:32:55,363
Trains and buses were scarce now, too.

486
00:32:55,447 --> 00:32:57,814
(newsreel)
You wonder why we make a fuss

487
00:32:57,902 --> 00:32:59,658
if George decides to take a bus.

488
00:32:59,743 --> 00:33:04,413
But look again and you will see that
George ain't all that George should be.

489
00:33:04,500 --> 00:33:08,941
He 's only got a step to go -
a couple of hundred yards or so.

490
00:33:09,027 --> 00:33:13,282
Whilst others, further down the queue,
have far to go and lots to do.

491
00:33:15,894 --> 00:33:21,032
When George gets on we often find
that other folk get left behind.

492
00:33:21,111 --> 00:33:25,246
He pays his fare and rides a stage,

493
00:33:25,331 --> 00:33:27,742
then off he hops...

494
00:33:27,824 --> 00:33:30,038
and see the rage.

495
00:33:30,126 --> 00:33:33,224
And seeing this gives George a jog.

496
00:33:33,310 --> 00:33:37,062
(George)
Perhaps I'm just a transport hog.

497
00:33:37,146 --> 00:33:41,586
Hello, Forces. Once again, this is
Joan Griffiths saying thank you for...

498
00:33:41,673 --> 00:33:44,280
(narrator) The BBC,
official voice of Britain,

499
00:33:44,435 --> 00:33:48,308
was more high-minded than ever,
but the public didn't mind.

500
00:33:48,386 --> 00:33:51,069
The Brains Trust,
a weekly intellectual forum,

501
00:33:51,186 --> 00:33:53,641
was one of radio's
most popular programmes,

502
00:33:53,756 --> 00:33:58,121
and the voice of the novelist
JB Priestley made him a major star.

503
00:33:58,206 --> 00:34:03,302
The British were absolutely
at their best in the Second World War.

504
00:34:03,385 --> 00:34:09,211
They were never as good,
certainly in my lifetime before it.

505
00:34:09,293 --> 00:34:13,853
And, I'm sorry to say, that they've
never been quite as good after it.

506
00:34:14,855 --> 00:34:17,190
Because a large number of people

507
00:34:17,272 --> 00:34:22,182
were living more intensely
than they'd ever done before,

508
00:34:22,259 --> 00:34:28,271
a large number of people equally
felt they needed some of the arts.

509
00:34:31,965 --> 00:34:36,067
(narrator) Dame Myra Hess
played in the National Gallery.

510
00:34:39,944 --> 00:34:44,461
(Priestley) There was a greater demand,
I think, for good books,

511
00:34:44,547 --> 00:34:49,107
good plays, music,
the sight of some good pictures,

512
00:34:49,189 --> 00:34:52,255
than I'd ever known before
in this country.

513
00:35:04,342 --> 00:35:06,797
(narrator)
Still more people loved Hi, Gang!

514
00:35:06,874 --> 00:35:08,521
and "That Man", Tommy Handley.

515
00:35:08,600 --> 00:35:11,546
- (man) ITMA!
- (fanfare)

516
00:35:15,467 --> 00:35:18,914
(chorus)  It's that man again,
yes, that man again

517
00:35:19,034 --> 00:35:21,096
Can I do you now, sir?

518
00:35:21,183 --> 00:35:23,474
(applause)

519
00:35:30,543 --> 00:35:35,212
Well, well, if it isn't Canteen Clara,
the rissole-smacking bomber.

520
00:35:35,300 --> 00:35:38,780
I say, you look a bit tousled.
Have you flown off the handle?

521
00:35:38,867 --> 00:35:42,587
No, sir. I've been fire watching
for the first time.

522
00:35:42,665 --> 00:35:45,076
(laughter)

523
00:35:45,197 --> 00:35:47,990
- Did you have a chaperone?
- Oh, yes, sir.

524
00:35:48,074 --> 00:35:51,140
And a very nice polite chap he was, too.

525
00:35:51,220 --> 00:35:54,089
Always said "pardon"
before he took his boots off.

526
00:35:54,174 --> 00:35:56,203
(laughter)

527
00:35:58,355 --> 00:36:02,152
I'd hate to hear what he said
before he took his socks off.

528
00:36:03,073 --> 00:36:05,986
(narrator) And Gracie Fields was back.

529
00:36:06,066 --> 00:36:08,018
I'm the girl that makes the thing

530
00:36:08,099 --> 00:36:10,204
That drills the hole
that holds the spring

531
00:36:10,285 --> 00:36:14,726
That drives the rod that turns
the knob that works the thingamabob

532
00:36:14,812 --> 00:36:18,718
I'm the girl that makes the thing
that holds the oil that oils the ring

533
00:36:18,802 --> 00:36:22,554
That takes the shank that moves
the crank that works the thingamabob

534
00:36:22,676 --> 00:36:26,887
It's a ticklish sort of job
making a thing for a thingamabob

535
00:36:26,973 --> 00:36:30,497
Especially when you don't know
what it's for

536
00:36:30,579 --> 00:36:32,150
And I don't know!

537
00:36:32,228 --> 00:36:34,595
But I'm the girl that makes the thing

538
00:36:34,683 --> 00:36:36,593
That drills the hole
that holds the spring

539
00:36:36,717 --> 00:36:40,666
That makes the thingamabob
that makes the engines roar

540
00:36:40,745 --> 00:36:45,185
And I'm the girl that makes the thing
that holds the oil that oils the ring

541
00:36:45,271 --> 00:36:48,522
That makes the thingamabob
that's going to win the war

542
00:36:49,606 --> 00:36:51,024
'Tis true!

543
00:36:55,514 --> 00:36:58,612
(narrator) Aircraft production
had trebled in two years.

544
00:36:58,698 --> 00:37:00,378
In the next two, it doubled again.

545
00:37:00,462 --> 00:37:03,332
Britain's war economy
was much more widely based

546
00:37:03,416 --> 00:37:06,024
and thoroughly organised than Germany's.

547
00:37:06,102 --> 00:37:09,505
But the cost of such
concentrated effort was high.

548
00:37:09,592 --> 00:37:12,156
Familiar customs in industry
were swept aside.

549
00:37:12,239 --> 00:37:17,106
Workers put in massive overtime which
stretched mind and body to the limit.

550
00:37:17,226 --> 00:37:20,947
Then, sometimes, their patience snapped.

551
00:37:21,791 --> 00:37:26,352
This is Betteshanger, Kent,
scene of a famous dispute in 1942.

552
00:37:26,433 --> 00:37:30,721
Industry cried out for coal,
but output fell and went on falling.

553
00:37:30,806 --> 00:37:34,603
Many miners had joined up
or had found better-paid work.

554
00:37:34,681 --> 00:37:38,936
Older men worked longer hours
and had to guard the mine, as well.

555
00:37:39,016 --> 00:37:43,227
But when they could stand
these conditions no more, they struck.

556
00:37:43,312 --> 00:37:49,248
(man) We all marched down into Deal
and then onto the Canterbury Road.

557
00:37:49,335 --> 00:37:54,736
There were several local residents
and particularly some of the troops,

558
00:37:54,821 --> 00:37:58,421
they were jeering and sneering at us.

559
00:37:58,503 --> 00:38:01,678
But little did they know at the time

560
00:38:01,764 --> 00:38:05,823
that we were manning this pit
24 hours a day,

561
00:38:05,907 --> 00:38:08,667
with the Home Guard troops, ourselves,

562
00:38:08,746 --> 00:38:13,612
and many of us worked and stopped
at the pit here 24 hours a day.

563
00:38:13,695 --> 00:38:16,913
(narrator) The miners knew
strikes were forbidden by Bevin

564
00:38:16,994 --> 00:38:20,245
by a wartime regulation, order 1305.

565
00:38:22,019 --> 00:38:24,124
But faced
with a solid body of 1,000 men,

566
00:38:24,206 --> 00:38:26,889
you couldn't jail them all
or even collect fines,

567
00:38:26,968 --> 00:38:29,608
and Bevin and Churchill knew it.

568
00:38:31,993 --> 00:38:35,059
(Roberts) I don't think Churchill
wanted us to go to prison.

569
00:38:35,139 --> 00:38:37,822
He wanted us to stay here
and guard his property.

570
00:38:37,901 --> 00:38:41,883
Because it was his property, after all.
It wasn't ours.

571
00:38:42,888 --> 00:38:44,873
(narrator) The government gave in.

572
00:38:44,959 --> 00:38:49,945
Desperate for labour, late in 1943,
Bevin called up boys.

573
00:38:50,061 --> 00:38:52,931
Not for the forces, for the mines.

574
00:38:53,015 --> 00:38:54,891
You'll be here four weeks.

575
00:38:54,972 --> 00:38:58,605
Is there any district you'd like to go
to at the end of your training?

576
00:38:58,731 --> 00:39:03,216
- Bolsover, Derby.
- Pass down to the billeting section.

577
00:39:04,140 --> 00:39:07,435
- Good old steel toecaps.
- Thank you.

578
00:39:07,593 --> 00:39:10,767
- What size is your hat?
- Seven and a quarter, please.

579
00:39:10,853 --> 00:39:14,181
(narrator) One new national serviceman
in ten became a Bevin Boy.

580
00:39:14,268 --> 00:39:16,985
You couldn't escape,
whoever your dad was.

581
00:39:17,068 --> 00:39:18,901
You're a public schoolboy.

582
00:39:18,986 --> 00:39:21,899
It'll be a change for you
going in the mine, won't it?

583
00:39:21,978 --> 00:39:25,229
Yes, but it's a necessity
that someone's got to do the job,

584
00:39:25,354 --> 00:39:30,264
so I think I'm doing my part in...
in helping.

585
00:39:31,569 --> 00:39:33,980
I was expecting to go into the army.

586
00:39:34,062 --> 00:39:37,619
I was very shocked when I heard
on the news on Christmas Day

587
00:39:37,707 --> 00:39:40,118
that I was to be
directed into the mines.

588
00:39:40,200 --> 00:39:41,694
It was a ballot, actually,

589
00:39:41,811 --> 00:39:44,724
and they drew out numbers
ending in nought or nine.

590
00:39:44,803 --> 00:39:49,822
My registration number ended in nought,
so there was no ducking away from that.

591
00:39:49,906 --> 00:39:52,742
I had to go in the mines
regardless of anything.

592
00:39:52,821 --> 00:39:55,614
(narrator) His parents hoped
he'd be an army officer.

593
00:39:55,698 --> 00:39:57,040
They were flabbergasted.

594
00:39:57,156 --> 00:39:59,523
If somebody'd said,
"You'll go into the mines",

595
00:39:59,611 --> 00:40:01,487
I'd have thought they were joking.

596
00:40:03,524 --> 00:40:04,822
(narrator) But lads of 17

597
00:40:04,905 --> 00:40:07,774
without a mining background
couldn't solve the problem.

598
00:40:07,859 --> 00:40:10,925
Output went on falling and falling.

599
00:40:11,043 --> 00:40:13,531
And in 1944,
in Yorkshire and South Wales,

600
00:40:13,613 --> 00:40:17,672
over 200,000 miners
came out on unofficial strike.

601
00:40:18,753 --> 00:40:24,460
The men have worked continuously
for a period of nearly five years,

602
00:40:24,546 --> 00:40:26,957
under war conditions,

603
00:40:27,040 --> 00:40:29,832
suffering from a deep sense of grievance

604
00:40:29,955 --> 00:40:33,435
because they have not been rewarded
by the state equally

605
00:40:33,523 --> 00:40:37,156
with ex-mine workers
employed in government factories.

606
00:40:41,195 --> 00:40:44,294
(narrator) In bustling Tyneside
shipyards, as in mines,

607
00:40:44,379 --> 00:40:48,744
men who remembered
mass unemployment feared the peace.

608
00:40:48,829 --> 00:40:54,655
Their doubts and wishes spoke out even
in government-made documentary films.

609
00:40:54,737 --> 00:40:57,497
(man) Tyneside's busy enough today.

610
00:40:57,575 --> 00:41:01,557
Old 'uns and young 'uns
hard at work making good ships.

611
00:41:01,642 --> 00:41:07,119
But just remember what the yards
looked like five years ago.

612
00:41:07,204 --> 00:41:10,499
Idle, empty,

613
00:41:10,580 --> 00:41:12,719
some of them derelict,

614
00:41:12,805 --> 00:41:17,551
and the skilled men that worked in them
scattered and forgotten.

615
00:41:17,677 --> 00:41:22,543
Will it be the same again
five years from now?

616
00:41:23,853 --> 00:41:26,035
Other films echoed the same question,

617
00:41:26,155 --> 00:41:30,410
Iike this early effort by the Boulting
brothers, starring Bernard Miles.

618
00:41:30,490 --> 00:41:35,127
I reckon Hitler's made a lot of us
change our minds a bit lately.

619
00:41:35,208 --> 00:41:37,008
We made a fine big war effort,

620
00:41:37,088 --> 00:41:40,416
but when it's all over, we've
got to make a fine big peace effort.

621
00:41:40,502 --> 00:41:45,368
There's no two ways about it.
We can't go back now we've made a start.

622
00:41:45,451 --> 00:41:48,625
Cor, look at that Dunkirk.

623
00:41:48,750 --> 00:41:50,888
Weren't no unemployed there.

624
00:41:50,975 --> 00:41:54,041
Every man had a job to do
and he done it.

625
00:41:54,120 --> 00:41:58,942
That's what we've got to see
they have in peacetime - a job.

626
00:41:59,031 --> 00:42:02,434
And there'll be work enough, too,
when this lot's over -

627
00:42:02,522 --> 00:42:07,235
building up something new
and better than what's been destroyed.

628
00:42:07,355 --> 00:42:12,298
There mustn't be no more chaps
hanging around for work what don't come.

629
00:42:12,381 --> 00:42:14,672
No more slums, neither.

630
00:42:14,759 --> 00:42:17,442
No more dirty, filthy backstreets

631
00:42:17,521 --> 00:42:22,540
and no more half-starved kids
with no room to play in.

632
00:42:22,623 --> 00:42:27,566
We can't go back to the old way
of living. Leastways, not all of it.

633
00:42:28,224 --> 00:42:30,787
That's gone forever.

634
00:42:30,871 --> 00:42:35,311
And the sooner we all make up our minds
about that, the better.

635
00:42:35,436 --> 00:42:37,999
We've gotta all pull together.

636
00:42:38,735 --> 00:42:42,335
There was a great community spirit
during the war.

637
00:42:42,456 --> 00:42:45,555
It is the nearest thing that I've seen,
in my lifetime,

638
00:42:45,640 --> 00:42:48,400
to the operation
of a kind of socialist state,

639
00:42:48,479 --> 00:42:51,774
that is of a democratic
socialist state of citizens

640
00:42:51,855 --> 00:42:55,258
believing they could influence
by their actions,

641
00:42:55,346 --> 00:42:57,757
speedily, what was going to be done,

642
00:42:57,839 --> 00:43:01,287
and that the world could be changed
by the way they operated.

643
00:43:01,368 --> 00:43:04,739
They saw that the world was changed
by their actions in the war

644
00:43:04,859 --> 00:43:08,918
and thought that could be translated
into political action as well.

645
00:43:09,002 --> 00:43:13,672
It was extremely exciting,
but some of the political leaders,

646
00:43:13,759 --> 00:43:16,858
because they were so involved
in their own pursuits,

647
00:43:16,943 --> 00:43:19,234
didn't appreciate what was happening.

648
00:43:19,322 --> 00:43:22,879
(narrator) And so,
the people's hopes for a better peace

649
00:43:22,966 --> 00:43:25,803
fixed themselves
on Sir William Beveridge,

650
00:43:25,881 --> 00:43:28,598
who'd been commissioned
by the government

651
00:43:28,682 --> 00:43:32,130
to draw up plans for a welfare state.

652
00:43:32,211 --> 00:43:37,154
When his report was published in 1942,
it was a best seller.

653
00:43:37,275 --> 00:43:40,221
The report proposes, first,

654
00:43:40,305 --> 00:43:44,713
an all-in scheme of social insurance,

655
00:43:44,794 --> 00:43:48,667
providing for all citizens
and their families

656
00:43:48,783 --> 00:43:52,994
all the cash benefits
needed for security,

657
00:43:53,080 --> 00:43:57,138
in return for
a single weekly contribution

658
00:43:57,223 --> 00:44:00,518
by one insurance stamp.

659
00:44:01,404 --> 00:44:08,453
It preserves the maximum of individual
freedom and responsibility

660
00:44:08,539 --> 00:44:12,642
that is consistent
with the abolition of want.

661
00:44:12,721 --> 00:44:17,435
(narrator) The government
first blew hot, then cold, very cold.

662
00:44:17,554 --> 00:44:19,584
Churchill wouldn't act.

663
00:44:19,664 --> 00:44:22,534
Churchill got very worried
and his two chancellors,

664
00:44:22,618 --> 00:44:26,797
Sir Kingsley Wood and Anderson,
were equally critical.

665
00:44:26,953 --> 00:44:30,204
That's why the Beveridge plan
was delayed after my bill.

666
00:44:30,290 --> 00:44:32,320
That's why education came first.

667
00:44:33,014 --> 00:44:36,963
(narrator) A major reform of education
would tread on fewer big toes.

668
00:44:37,042 --> 00:44:39,147
It had other uses, too.

669
00:44:39,229 --> 00:44:43,135
(Butler) It wasn't very controversial.
It was very long.

670
00:44:43,218 --> 00:44:46,088
Churchill realised
here was a wonderful way

671
00:44:46,172 --> 00:44:48,539
of exercising the troops, you see?

672
00:44:48,627 --> 00:44:52,347
(narrator) Churchill was,
first and foremost, a war leader.

673
00:44:52,425 --> 00:44:54,684
He kept the brakes on reconstruction.

674
00:44:54,765 --> 00:44:57,558
(Butler)
Churchill didn't take much interest.

675
00:44:57,642 --> 00:45:01,821
He wanted to know whether we were
going to go in for nationalisation.

676
00:45:01,900 --> 00:45:06,919
We had a proposal by Herbert Morrison
to nationalise the electricity industry,

677
00:45:07,003 --> 00:45:09,686
and that's where
the coalition government stopped.

678
00:45:09,803 --> 00:45:11,865
We couldn't get agreement on that.

679
00:45:11,951 --> 00:45:14,090
(narrator) A new party, Common Wealth,

680
00:45:14,176 --> 00:45:17,165
called for Beveridge now,
and won two by-elections.

681
00:45:17,245 --> 00:45:20,616
Other independents took up the cry.

682
00:45:20,698 --> 00:45:22,879
The Beveridge bandwagon rolled on.

683
00:45:22,961 --> 00:45:25,721
Early in 1944,
West Derbyshire had its say.

684
00:45:25,800 --> 00:45:28,091
One candidate was wholly independent.

685
00:45:28,178 --> 00:45:30,895
Indeed, he had no programme at all.

686
00:45:31,439 --> 00:45:33,894
I have no animosity...

687
00:45:33,971 --> 00:45:36,458
to the other two candidates.

688
00:45:38,075 --> 00:45:44,360
If I am not elected, I am the only one
that has anything to lose.

689
00:45:45,786 --> 00:45:48,961
I am very proud...

690
00:45:49,047 --> 00:45:51,654
that what I consider

691
00:45:51,732 --> 00:45:56,020
to be the foundation stone
of true democracy

692
00:45:56,105 --> 00:46:01,277
has been well and truly laid
in the village of Kniveton,

693
00:46:01,361 --> 00:46:04,274
Derbyshire, England.

694
00:46:07,614 --> 00:46:10,407
(narrator) Goodall then fled
to his father's cottage.

695
00:46:10,491 --> 00:46:14,211
The real fight was between
an independent socialist, Charlie White,

696
00:46:14,327 --> 00:46:16,891
who had Common Wealth support,

697
00:46:16,974 --> 00:46:20,040
and the youthful Conservative
Lord Hartington,

698
00:46:20,196 --> 00:46:22,607
who had official Labour backing.

699
00:46:23,994 --> 00:46:27,169
Hartington's family
had always found a seat here,

700
00:46:27,255 --> 00:46:30,168
and to reject him
would be most untraditional.

701
00:46:35,810 --> 00:46:38,177
But White won by a landslide.

702
00:46:38,265 --> 00:46:41,363
Conservatives were not pleased.

703
00:46:41,449 --> 00:46:43,554
Democracy, however, was safe enough

704
00:46:43,712 --> 00:46:46,429
for the Fascist leader, Mosley,
to be released.

705
00:46:46,551 --> 00:46:48,842
He had been interned since 1940.

706
00:46:50,540 --> 00:46:55,177
The government said that he was ill,
but very few people believed it.

707
00:46:55,297 --> 00:46:59,247
This caused the greatest public uproar
of the war years.

708
00:47:08,801 --> 00:47:11,364
Fear and hatred
had changed their targets.

709
00:47:11,448 --> 00:47:14,165
Released aliens
served in the Pioneer Corps.

710
00:47:14,248 --> 00:47:16,931
On newsreels,
they now appeared as lovable allies.

711
00:47:17,010 --> 00:47:19,377
(man) This is Corporal Gruker.

712
00:47:19,465 --> 00:47:21,832
His scars and his glass eye

713
00:47:21,920 --> 00:47:24,135
are the legacy
of being kicked by a horse

714
00:47:24,222 --> 00:47:27,015
when he was in a crack
Austrian cavalry regiment.

715
00:47:27,099 --> 00:47:31,125
- The Dragoons, wasn't it, Gruker?
- Yes, sir. I was kicked twice.

716
00:47:31,204 --> 00:47:36,147
Once by the horse and once
by Shickelgruber. I prefer the horse.

717
00:47:36,881 --> 00:47:39,980
(narrator) Alien troops
were welcomed now in Britain

718
00:47:40,065 --> 00:47:44,201
where they gathered to prepare
for the D-day invasion.

719
00:47:44,285 --> 00:47:47,002
The Free Poles
conquered many Scottish hearts.

720
00:47:49,848 --> 00:47:52,488
And the GIs were everywhere.

721
00:47:54,182 --> 00:47:57,979
(all chant) One! Two! Three! Four!

722
00:47:58,057 --> 00:48:00,774
(narrator)
They were well-equipped, well-paid,

723
00:48:00,857 --> 00:48:04,763
and gave the girls fine new things
like nylons and the jitterbug.

724
00:48:10,640 --> 00:48:14,927
Churchill could now inspect an army
which knew that it would win.

725
00:48:16,125 --> 00:48:20,456
The hour of our greatest effort
and action is approaching.

726
00:48:20,537 --> 00:48:25,447
We march with valiant allies
who count on us as we count on them.

727
00:48:25,524 --> 00:48:31,459
The only homeward road for all of us
lies through the arch of victory.

728
00:48:34,309 --> 00:48:37,375
(narrator) At last, the day came.

729
00:48:37,454 --> 00:48:39,439
And it was sweet.

730
00:48:43,247 --> 00:48:46,618
Wally Hammond's cover drive
delighted crowds

731
00:48:46,699 --> 00:48:50,103
who basked serenely
in the fine summer weather.

732
00:49:00,816 --> 00:49:04,341
Britain seemed close
to the winning post.

733
00:49:04,422 --> 00:49:06,953
Wasn't it all over, bar the killing?

734
00:49:07,031 --> 00:49:10,359
(newsreel) Thanks to the very fine
weather in the Straits of Dover,

735
00:49:10,445 --> 00:49:15,235
all holiday crowds had a good time,
except those rash enough to travel.

736
00:49:15,356 --> 00:49:18,607
Is the favourite winning?
Ah, who cares anyway?

737
00:49:29,971 --> 00:49:31,652
(droning)

738
00:49:45,354 --> 00:49:47,689
(narrator) The V -1.

739
00:49:56,556 --> 00:49:58,618
A plane with no pilot.

740
00:50:01,389 --> 00:50:02,884
(droning ceases)

741
00:50:12,092 --> 00:50:14,078
(explosion)

742
00:50:15,660 --> 00:50:17,645
A new kind of weapon.

743
00:50:29,930 --> 00:50:32,386
A new kind of war.

744
00:50:54,827 --> 00:50:56,966
It was time to hide again.

745
00:50:59,162 --> 00:51:01,191
(droning)
