HITLER'S RISE TO POWER
Berlin 1945, Europe has been freed
from the Nazi reign of terror.
The Red Army is waging its final battles.
Captain Joseph Prautof, a Russian officer:
The hate ran so deep.
We wanted to end the war.
Annihilate that force that wanted to kill us.
Finish it off, once and for all.
Hitler's days are numbered.
He leaves his bunker
for one final bit of showmanship,
as seen in this propaganda film.
Is there still a soldier or a child,
willing to die for him?
The war left some 50 million dead.
Most of them, innocent civilians.
For the women of Germany,
the ordeal would continue
even after the cannons had gone silent.
The book "A Woman in Berlin"
is a deeply disturbing account
of the Russians' rape
of German women in 1945.
They grab me and throw me down.
I'm lying with my head on the steps.
I see one of the soldiers keeping watch,
while the other rips off my under clothes.
And brutally forces himself on me.
But then we'd say, better to
have a Russian on your belly,
than an American over your head.
This German woman was referring
to the Allied bombers
that pounded her city into ruins.
The Kurfurstendam,
Berlin's most fashionable avenue.
13 years earlier, the showcase of Germany.
A nation still plagued by crises.
A monument commemorating the millions
of victims of the First World War.
Marlene Dietrich is singing "The Blue Angel"
in Berlin, Alexanderplatz.
Thomas Mann is savoring
his Noble Prize for Literature.
In the shade of the linden trees,
of Avenue Unter den Linden.
Berlin is major cultural center of Europe.
One of the most open and tolerant cities
in the world.
Then, in 1933, all that changes.
Through intimidation, demagoguery
and exploiting the bitterness
of the German veterans,
Hitler and his armed militias,
like the SA with their hymn,
the "Horst Wessel Lied",
seized control of Germany.
The Nazis take advantage of the fact
that the German Left is splinted.
And it even seems like Hitler
with his raised fist,
revolutionary salute,
wants to get on their good side.
German Communists take their orders
from Moscow,
which views the social democrats
as the true enemy.
No alliance is possible between them.
So, for the last time, German Communists
sing "De Internazionale".
Hitler comes to power legally
on January 30th, 1933.
Within a few months, his dictatorship
is firmly in place.
He becomes "Die Führer", the Leader.
His supporters rise and chant, "Heil Hitler!"
However, not all Germans are
totally convinced, so again and again,
Hitler hammers home his simplistic,
nationalist slogans:
Before us lies Germany
Within us Germany is stirring
Behind us, all Germany is following!
And he eventually wins more
and more people over,
for he has a remarkable power
of persuasion over the masses.
But what does Hitler want?
In his book "Mein Kampf", My Struggle,
he clearly states what he calls his missions.
Being one of the embittered veterans
of the First World War,
his first mission will be to destroy France.
To wipe out the humiliation
of the Versaille Treaty of 1919
that stripped Germany of its army,
and part of its territory.
Then, he wants to conquer what he calls
"Lebensraum", living space.
Germany has a population of 80 million,
twice that of France.
He wants to make Germany
"The World Power" that it deserves to be.
A pathological anti-Semite,
Hitler has also taken on
the mission of asserting the superiority
of the Germanic Aryan race,
menaced by the Jews.
For him, the Jews were
the cause of the Great War,
Germany's defeat, inflation, unemployment.
The next war will be a war on the Jews.
They will be sent to Dachau,
the first concentration camp
where Hitler locks up the anti-Nazis,
the communists, social-democrats,
and all those opposed to the Nazi regime.
Lastly, Hitler takes on the mission
of bringing all German speaking peoples
into the Reich's fold,
beginning with those of his homeland.
The Anschluss, Austria is annexed,
and immediately submitted to
the same reign of terror as Germany.
With the opening of one of
the most infamous concentration camps
at Mauthausen, near Linz.
Which country will be his next victim?
Neighboring Czechoslovakia, where there is
a German population, the Sudeten Germans.
But the country is recognized as
an independent state, by England and France.
The clouds of war gather.
In Munich, temple of Nazism,
an 11th hour peace conference is organized.
On one side, Adolf Hitler who is becoming
more and more frightening.
And his ally, the Italian dictator,
Benito Mussolini.
Mussolini, the founder of fascism,
an indoctrination of an entire nation.
From childhood on.
On the other side, the Western democracies,
victorious but exhausted from the Great War.
Neville Chamberlain,
the conservative British Prime Minister.
And the radical socialist French Premier,
Edouard Daladier,
want to save the peace.
They end up accepting the unacceptable.
They give up the Czech province
of Sudetenland to Hitler,
in exchange for his solemn promise
to make no more claims
on another European territory.
But what is Hitler's promise worth?
Just six months later,
he invades the rest of Czechoslovakia.
And enters Prague, accompanied
by Marshall Hermann Göring.
Göring, a former First World War fighter pilot,
one of the founders of the Nazi party,
is now the Air Minister.
And an ogre, trying to charm
the Czech children.
Hitler no longer needs the excuse
of reuniting German speaking people.
The powerful Czech industry
will be working for him.
Why shouldn't he take advantage of it?
The Allies let him get away with it.
The USSR is the last major
neighboring power left to counter Hitler.
It had signed a mutual assistance treaty
with France.
The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics
is the official name of communist Russia
and its satellite republics.
Manipulation of the masses in Red Square,
masks the ironfisted dictatorship of Stalin
who has also thrown millions of poor
wretches into his labor camps, the Gulag.
Industrialization and forced militarization
have made the USSR a major power.
Despite their fear of communism,
the Western powers rely on the U.S.S.R.
Hitler is going to beat them to the punch.
In the summer of 1939,
in his Berchtesgarden chalet,
with his Minister of Foreign Affairs,
Joachim von Ribbentrop,
he prepares a blocking maneuver.
Hitler, who swore to destroy communism,
sends von Robbentrop, the Nazi, to Moscow
to sign a history-making treaty
with his worst enemy.
When Stalin's foreign affairs minister,
Molotov, signs the German-Soviet Pact,
communists are totally taken aback,
like these French Party Members.
It's August, 1939, and people in France
are enjoying their first paid holidays.
One of the major victories
of the Socialist Popular Front.
What are the reasons behind
this non-aggression pact.
The Soviets answer that Stalin
is playing for time.
Letting Hitler and the Western powers
kill each other off.
Perhaps, Stalin, who intends to grab
the Baltic countries and part of Poland
even has the illusion that he could share
Europe with Hitler on a permanent basis.
In 1936, the US Congress had passed
the Neutrality Act,
to avoid being dragged
into a European war once again.
So, with nothing to fear either from
the United States or from Russia,
Hitler decides to wipe out what he calls
"The worst monstrosity
of The Versaille Treaty", the Danzig Corridor.
In 1919, German territory was cut in two,
in order to give Poland access to the sea.
Hitler decides to launch his invasion
of Poland and recover Danzig
on September 1, 1939, at 5:35 AM.
The first cannon shot of
the Second World War, is fired on Danzig.
Hitler is convinced that the French
and the British will not take action.
Yet the two governments meet immediately,
and send him an ultimatum
demanding that he halt all military action
against Poland.
Hitler declares, "Our enemies are little worms."
And he adds, "Who wants to get bogged down
in a world war for Danzig?"
September 3, 1939
at 11 AM, The Ambassador of Great Britain
in Berlin delivers a declaration of war.
At 5 PM, France declares war on Germany.
Hitler can hardly believe it.
German generals find themselves facing
their worst case scenario: War on two fronts.
But the die is cast.
Hitler unleashes the Wehrmacht,The Armed
Forces of Nazi Germany, onto Poland.
Entering battle as if in a bygone age,
the Polish cavalry charges the German tanks,
and is slaughtered.
Paris, the Gare de l'Est train station.
Many of these men had shipped out from
these same platforms 25 years ago,
in a totally different atmosphere.
In August 1914, they marched off
to war in high spirits
with flowers in their rifles.
But there are no flowers this time.
And no rifles.
Nobody wants to fight this war.
4 million men are mobilized.
Many of them are farmers.
France is still a largely rural country.
They head for the German border on foot,
with their officers following on horseback.
Armies still rely heavily on horses and these
are requisitioned throughout the country.
Motorization has not kept up.
Gaston Chirac, a driver of one
of these outdated trucks,
with solid rubber tires, recalls:
There was such a shortage of equipment.
We had one rifle for two per truck.
We had one box of 10 bullets,
which we weren't allowed to open.
It was pathetic. If we'd had what
we needed, we'd have fought,
because we're no great friend
of the "Bosche".
The "Bosche" was a pejorative term for
the German soldiers during the previous war.
They were also called "vert-de-gris",
which in French means "field gray",
the color of their uniform, which enabled them
to blend in with their surroundings.
But just who are these soldiers?
Let's take for example, one of these
young Germans, marching as he sings:
Our flag is waving before us,
Our flag is a new age.
Our flag is stronger than death.
His name is August von Kageneck,
he writes:
I thought that a military career was the right
choice. My parents thought so as well.
My father would tell me:
At least there, you can still open
your mouth and say what you like.
And you don't have to do that Nazi salute.
In September 1939, August von Kageneck
is still training to become a tank commander.
He writes: My father who was a general
was telling me:
The French have 40 divisions on the border,
we have 15.
All the rest are in Poland.
500,000 men against 200,000.
They outnumber us 2 to 1.
French Forces attack on September 7, 1939,
4 days after declaring war.
This offensive launched to show public opinion
that Poland has not been abandoned,
advances 8 km into the Saar region.
The French army's cinema department
shows off the spoils of war, bicycles.
"...as we can see with these happy peddlers
who've recuperated
the bicycles that were abandoned in the
German villages."
The Saar offensive stops there,
and degenerates into a series of skirmishes,
raids by elite commandos,
led by the hero, Joseph Darnand,
who receives the citation of
"Premier Soldier of France".
Later, he will become one of the most rabid
collaborators with the Germans.
And eventually,
he'll be executed after the war.
The French army, in spite of its heroes and its
superiority in numbers, takes no further action.
General Maurice Gamelin, 67 years old,
is Commander-in-Chief of
the Allied-Franco British Land Forces.
For the French outnumber the British,
who also think that this war isn't for real,
and that it'll all be settled soon.
Gamelin himself has no desire
to re-fight the war of 1914.
He wants to avoid another bloodbath,
at any cost.
He considers that he needs 2 years
safe behind the Maginot Line,
in order to re-arm the country.
The Maginot line is the work of a former
Minister of War, Andre Maginot.
This complex of fortifications was meant
to stop the German enemy, once and for all.
It took nearly 10 years to construct,
and swallowed up 1,5 million cubic meters
of concrete, and 150,000 tons of steel.
All these gun turrets are linked together
by a labyrinth of tunnels, 100 km of them.
The line itself, stretched for 720 km,
from the Swiss to the Belgian borders.
The Maginot Line ends
at the foot of the Ardennes Forrest.
The French military command
thought that German tanks
could never cross this extremely rough terrain.
The French didn't extend
the line all the way to the sea,
because Belgium,
before declaring its neutrality,
was an ally of France, and opposed it.
This northern part of the front is manned
by a French army
and the British Expeditionary Forces.
Later reinforced by Canadians, and troops
from the far-flung British Empire.
In Britain a popular song of the day was
"The Washing on the Siegfried Line".
We're gonna to hang out the washing
on the Siegfried Line.
Have you any dirty washing, mother dear?
We're gonna hang out the washing
on the Siegfried Line.
'Cause the washing day is here.
The Siegfried line is the string of fortifications
constructed by Hitler, facing the Maginot Line.
The Germans don't attack,
they're still trying to avoid a second front.
The French, nevertheless,
take some precautions.
They evacuate the population
of Alsace and Lorraine
to the regions of Perigord and Charentes
in the southwest.
Strasbourg, a ghost town.
Abandoned by its population,
emptied of its soul.
Especially that of the synagogues.
On 25th of September,
Hitler orders the bombing of Warsaw.
The city is surrounded, but still holding out.
The Führer wants to strike terror into
the hearts and minds, not only of the Poles,
but of the French and British as well.
"This is what is in store for you."
The world is horrified.
In New York, the bombing of Warsaw
is up in lights in Time Square,
and on the front page of all the newspapers.
Franklin Roosevelt, the President
of The United States addresses the nation:
This nation will remain a neutral nation,
But I cannot ask that every American
remain neutral in thought as well.
Even a neutral has a right
to take account of facts.
Even a neutral cannot be asked
to close his mind, or to close his conscience.
The bombing of Warsaw shows how vulnerable
the cities are.
Paris sets about protecting its monuments
and hides its museum's masterpieces
out in the provinces.
The Champ de Mars, at the foot of
the Eiffel Tower, is dug full of bomb shelters.
And there are frequent air raid drills.
Gas masks are compulsory.
Poison gases were used in the First World War,
and now, everyone is afraid of them.
Even the horses.
Meanwhile, Poland, is being ruthlessly
carved up.
As previously agreed with Hitler, the Soviets
have invaded the eastern half of Poland.
Here, German and Soviet soldiers
are fraternizing,
an incongruent site, to say the least.
The Nazis hand out flyers that read:
The German Army salutes the Red Army
of workers and farmers
which it has always held in the highest respect.
The Polish Army surrenders to the Germans,
and in the east, to the Soviets.
Stalin then orders the execution
of 20,000 Polish prisoners.
He wants to eliminate the elite
of this country he intends to annex.
4,500 Polish officers are executed
with a bullet in the head,
in the Katyn forest, near Smolensk, in Russia.
2 years later, at the Kremlin, Stalin meets with
the head of the Polish Government in exile,
General Sikorski,
who delivers a list of missing Polish officers.
The Soviets deny any wrong-doing.
In 1992, the president of post-Soviet Russia,
Boris Yeltsin
will present the Polish president, Lech Walesa,
with the original order of execution,
signed by Stalin himself.
Stalin, by occupying half of Poland,
is in fact, playing into the hands of Hitler,
who needs a common border
with the USSR to facilitate his plans,
to invade Russia.
Hitler and Himmler, the head of the SS,
will now take care of Poland
by naming the Nazi, Hans Frank, Governor
General of the Occupied Polish Provinces,
who proclaims, "I have the power of life
and death over the Polish people."
After the war, he will be tried at Nuremberg
and hanged for crimes against humanity.
These gypsies, held in a pen, are filmed
by a German.
For the Nazis, they are "Non-persons".
The women will be forced
to undergo sterilization,
because they do not deserve to reproduce.
The Nazis declare "Open season" on gypsies.
Hundreds of thousands will be interned
in concentration camps.
The ordeal of the Jewish people, begins.
The Nazis now have 3 million Polish Jews
at their mercy.
Hitler is still uncertain about
what to do with them.
As long as the war is going well for him,
he considers deporting them to the east
or even shipping them to Madagascar.
It's only when the outcome of the war
becomes less certain
that Hitler and his accomplices unleash
a frenzy of hate and murder.
"The Final Solution".
For the time being,
the Jews have to be identified,
marked with a yellow star,
and herded into ghettos.
Some of which, are completely walled-off.
From the diary of one of these
unfortunate souls:
It's heart-rending to see the shameful scenes
of violence that take place before our eyes.
Women and the elderly, beaten right out
in the streets by petty thugs.
Tears come to my eyes.
All our powerlessness, all our isolation
is there to see right in the open
where not a single person takes our defense.
We are so weak.
All the major cities of Poland
will have their ghetto prisons
where German, Austrian, and Czech Jews
will also be interned.
The Jews here still feel confident
that perhaps someday,
they'll be able to return to their homes.
They don't know that they will die
of hunger and cold.
They don't know that the Shoah
is about to begin.
Inhabited by Jews
No Entrance
Warsaw is in ruins.
Hitler comes to be filmed
by a propaganda crew,
seen here traveling in
a car in the background.
These victorious German soldiers
march their goose step
to the sound of the grenadier's march.
But they weren't too efficient
during the Polish campaign.
Poor preparation, a lack of fighting spirit,
and even cases of indiscipline
are the points that the commander-in-chief,
general von Brauchitsch,
dares report to the Führer.
Hitler is furious, but he is immune to doubt
and orders the attack on the West
to be prepared.
An attack on the Netherlands,
Belgium, and France.
Some of his generals think its madness.
Some of them begin plotting
to overthrow the Führer.
This is a crucial moment, the course of history
lies in the balance.
November 8, 1939, Hitler narrowly escapes
an assassination attempt.
It seems as if he enjoys some kind of
divine protection.
When he attends the funeral for the victims,
he's no longer the same man.
His power over the army and
the German people has grown even stronger.
He tells his generals:
My decision is irrevocable.
I will attack France when the time is right.
I will be victorious, or die in the attempt.
Yet, Hitler is still uncertain about
attacking the West, for he also says:
War is like opening the door on a dark room.
You never know what will happen.
Eventually, he postpones the order to attack,
and goes back to his chalet in the Alps
to join his mistress, Eva Braun.
She shot this footage of Hitler's entourage
of the Reich's architect, Albert Speer,
who goes for long walks with Hitler.
Speer recalls: Hitler wanted
to re-christen Berlin, Germania.
We already had a mock-up of the future,
Adolf Hitler's Square
with a dome, inspired by St. Peter's in Rome,
but 17 times bigger.
I said to him, "My Führer, wouldn't that
make an ideal target for bombers?"
He answered:
Not at all. Göring has assured me that
no enemy aircraft will ever fly over the Reich.
From his barracks, the future German officer,
August von Kageneck, writes to his mother:
We are all eager to fight.
We are ready for battle.
His mother answers:
This war is a crime, and we are going
to have to pay for it.
The war then enters a new, bizarre phase.
The Germans call it the "Sitzkrieg",
"The sitting war".
The British call it the "Phoney war".
And for the French, it's the "Drole de Guerre",
"The funny war".
A long, strange waiting period,
especially hard on the women.
For them there's not only the anguish of war,
but also the survival of their families
to worry about.
As in the last war, the soldiers dig in
and try to make the best of things.
The French soldier, Gaston Chirac,
writes to his wife:
It's 30 degrees below zero, the bread is frozen.
I'm one of the lucky ones.
They gave us some straw,
and with that, we can sleep better.
The winter of 1939-1940 is indeed
one of the coldest of the century.
To make a bad situation worse, all the winters
of this war, will be brutally cold.
The commander-in-chief, General Gamelin,
is expecting the Germans to attack
through Belgium
and move towards Paris across
this open plain, like in 1914.
Gamelin plans to make his stand against
the Germans, on Belgian soil.
In France, Colonel de Gaulle, a tank officer,
who is beginning to make a name for himself
criticizes this strategy.
He calls it the "Maginot Line Mentality"
which consists in waiting for the other side
to make a move.
In his book "Towards a Professional Army"
he argues in favor of taking the offensive,
making massive use of tanks.
France is producing 300 tanks a month,
but they're being dispersed in all the sections
to back up the infantry.
French aviation has also fallen behind.
France ordered 4,000 planes
from the United States,
in spite of the ever growing isolationist trend
championed by Charles Lindbergh.
The hero who made the first
Trans-Atlantic solo flight
and now a leading proponent of
the "America First" movement.
If you believe in an independent destiny
for America.
If you believe that this country
should not enter the war in Europe.
We ask you to join
the America First Committee in its stand.
It's the isolationist voice of America
and of public personalities like Henry Ford,
the anti-Semitic car maker,
Or like Joseph Kennedy, America's ambassador
in London, who is anti-war.
Whereas his son, John, the future president,
Kennedy, supports European democracies.
Nazi sympathizers in America also
contribute to the impassioned climate
that reigns at the beginning of 1940.
In Europe, The British Union of Fascists
are also quite active
up to the moment they're banned.
Oswald Mosley, "The English Führer",
challenges the government,
right in the center of London.
He'll spend the next several years in prison.
Mosley's speeches urge people to get out
on the streets, and stop the war.
But Winston Churchill has taken the reins
of the British government.
Here, we see him with the French general
Gamelin, and Admiral Darlan
who were on an official visit to London.
A Franco-British Expeditionary Corps,
is formed to help Finland
which has been invaded by the Soviet Union.
France is preparing to send its elite soldiers,
The French Foreign Legion.
The Foreign Legion, for a century it has been
taking in the world's reprobates,
no matter what their past,
as long as it's not too "Shady".
Their headquarters, in Sidi Bel Abbes,
in Algeria
now signs up a good number
of Spanish Republicans,
having fled from their country,
after Franco's fascists' victory.
They're now eager to fight the Nazis,
who supported Franco.
They'll all make the long trip to France.
The Legionnaires embark at Brest, along with
the well equipped "Chasseurs Alpins".
A mountain corp, trained for action
in the snow.
But Finland and the Soviet Union
sign a peace treaty.
A few days later, Hitler launches an offensive
against Denmark and Norway.
The "Blitzkrieg", the Lightning War.
The Wehrmacht takes Oslo in 2 days.
Hitler is seeking to protect "The Iron Route".
Iron is indispensable to the German war effort,
and 50 percent of its Swedish iron ore
is shipped out of the Norwegian port of Narvik.
The Franco-British Expedition Recon
lands in the Fjord of Narvik.
After a month of fighting,
the Allies take Narvik.
The Iron Route is temporarily cut.
This victory is good for French morale
and adds credence to their motto:
We will win because we are the strongest.
But the expeditionary corps will have
to abandon Narvik,
and for the rest of the war, train load after
train load of Swedish iron ore
will feed the German war machine.
The French are brought back home,
for the Germans have just launched
their offensive in the West.
The 9th of May 1940, Hitler left Berlin
on his private train, code named "Amerika".
Heading west towards new headquarters
near the French border.
Hitler announces:
Gentlemen, the offensive has just begun.
His generals had submitted him
their battle plan during the winter.
It looks similar to that of 1914,
attack through Belgium.
But Hitler preferred
general von Manstein's idea.
Cutting straight through the Ardenne forest,
and swinging up and driving towards the sea,
encircling the allies
with a sickle cut movement.
But this sickle-cut movement is, in fact,
a huge gamble,
because the Allies could turn back
and counter attack.
However, Hitler is confident. He notes,
"The main thing is to have good weather."
Leftenant August von Kageneck claims,
"We are the Wehrmacht,
the armed forces of greater Germany.
Victory is certain."
For the German soldiers,
their homeland is in danger.
After all it was the French
who declared war on Germany.
The 10th of May, 1940, at dawn, German parachutists
make a jump over Holland.
Their mission is to capture the air fields
and bridges around Rotterdam.
At the same time, Hitler unleashes
his war machine on Belgium.
Hitler waits.
Will the Allies fall into the trap?