Old people in Florida,
they drive slow...
...and they sit low.
Right? That is their motto.
The state flag of Florida should be...
...a steering wheel with a hat
and two knuckles on it.
And that left-turn signal on...
...from when they left the house
that morning.
Right? That's a legal turn in Florida.
It's known as an eventual left.
And old people
get to a certain age...
...where, when they back out
of the driveway...
...they don't look.
You know what I mean?
They just feel like:
"Well, I'm old, and I'm coming back.
I survived. Let's see if you can."
- Hey, you're back!
- Oh, I'm back, baby.
- How was it?
- One of the best jobs I ever had.
- Good for you.
- I killed.
- You killed.
- Wiped the floor with them.
And not only that,
the money was unbelievable.
- Unbelievable.
- Yeah, highest-paying job I ever had.
How much?
- I'd rather not.
- Oh, come on.
It's not good to talk about money.
It can affect the friendship.
I tell you how much I make.
And I'm always impressed.
Just show me the check. Come on.
- You wanna see it?
- I wanna see it.
Okay.
Check that out.
- This is unbelievable.
- I told you.
My God, you're rich.
Oh, yeah.
I didn't know you made
that kind of money.
- Gee.
- What?
I just don't think
I can talk to you anymore.
I feel inferior.
I never should have told you.
You know, Jerry, I think
this changes the relationship.
I mean, I feel it. Do you feel it?
No, I can't feel anything.
What are you gonna do with all that?
I was thinking of donating
a large portion of it to charity.
- Really?
- No.
Well, you should, Jerry.
To tell you the truth, I was thinking
of buying my father a car.
- You see, that's nice.
- Yeah, maybe a Cadillac.
Cadillac.
Yeah.
That would blow his mind.
He's always wanted one...
...his whole life. He's never
been able to afford it.
- I'll do it.
- You're gonna score big points...
...with the man upstairs.
Oh, isn't that what it's all about?
Who was Pippi Longstocking?
Pippi Longstocking? I don't know.
Did she have anything
to do with Hitler?
Hitler? Maybe.
- Hey.
- Hey, George.
Have you seen Jerry?
I told him 2:00.
You remember Katy?
Oh, hi.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We met skiing that time.
You're married to the eye guy.
Also ear, nose and throat.
Nose.
What's the worst
that could happen to a nose?
What does it get, stuffed?
- He's funny.
- You don't have to tell me.
Ladies, please, please.
Oh, you know what?
He got engaged.
Oh, you did?
What, is that bad?
I actually would have set you up
with a friend of mine.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
You'd be perfect for her.
She loves quirky, funny guys.
- Bald?
- Loves bald.
Loves bald.
Who...?
- Who is she?
- Marisa Tomei.
- The actress?
- Yeah.
You're friends with Marisa Tomei?
That's right.
That's incredible. My Cousin Vinny...
I love her. She was fantastic.
Yeah, I know.
You were gonna fix me up with her?
She's just been sitting home.
Marisa Tomei's sitting home, Elaine.
Why didn't you tell me
Katy was friends with Marisa?
Oh, I don't know
what I was thinking.
I want this baby fully loaded.
Well, how soon can you get it there?
Oh, that's terrific.
Okay, thanks, bye.
Hey, guess what.
- I just bought my father a Cadillac.
- Really?
- Wow, you are quite the good son.
- Yeah.
I'm a very good boy.
I'm flying down there
and surprising them.
- You gonna sleep on the foldout?
- Yeah.
I guess.
Let me ask you something.
You ever hear of Marisa Tomei?
- The actress?
- Yeah.
- She's... She's something, isn't she?
- Oh, yeah.
- Well, you know Katy, Elaine's friend?
- Yeah.
She happens to be
good friends with her.
Marisa Tomei?
- How does she know Marisa Tomei?
- I don't know. I didn't ask.
You didn't ask
how she knows Marisa Tomei?
- Not the point. Can I finish?
- All right.
Go ahead.
Seems like a reasonable question.
That's all I'm saying.
I would have asked her.
All right!
So she said that she could have
fixed me up with her.
What do you mean, "could have"?
Well, you know, if I wasn't engaged.
Could have fixed me up
with Marisa Tomei.
She said I was just her type.
- Really?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Do you know the odds
of me being anyone's type?
I have never been anyone's type.
But, apparently, this Marisa Tomei
loves funny, quirky bald men.
You know, she won
an Academy Award.
Like I don't know that.
My Cousin Vinny, I loved it.
I, George Costanza, could be
on a date with an Oscar winner.
An Oscar winner, Jerry.
Do you know what that's like?
If 50 years ago someone had fixed
me up with Katharine Hepburn.
Same thing.
Now there's a match,
you and Katharine Hepburn.
- I mean, you've seen her?
- Katharine Hepburn? Yeah.
- Marisa Tomei!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I mean, she's beautiful, right.
She's just my type.
The dark hair, the full lips.
- You like full lips.
- Oh, I love full lips.
Something you can really
put the lipstick on.
Too bad you're engaged.
Yeah, too bad, too bad.
This is no good.
- Hi.
Excuse me, I'm with Plaza Cable.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I'm looking for the guy
who lives over here.
Been waiting about two hours.
You happen to know where he is?
No.
Could you tell him
the cable company was here?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Nice people.
- Yeah.
Listen, let me ask you a question.
What if I got a cup of coffee
with her?
Well, what about Susan?
I can't have a coffee with a person?
I'm not allowed to have coffee?
Would you tell Susan about it?
Not necessarily.
If you can't tell Susan about it,
then there's something wrong.
Of course there's something wrong.
We had a pact.
- Hey, cable guy's looking for you.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah, I've been getting HBO
for free.
They found out about it.
Now they wanna come and take it out.
Well, said he was waiting two hours.
Seemed a little put out.
Oh, was he?
Well, I guess the cable man
doesn't like to be kept waiting.
You don't seem too bothered by it.
Do you remember what they did to me
10 years ago?
"Oh, we'll be there in the morning
between 9 and 1...
...or we'll be there between 2 and 6."
And I sat there, hour after hour...
...without so much as a phone call.
Finally, they show up.
No apology.
Tracking mud all over
my nice, clean floors.
And now they want me
to accommodate them.
Well...
...looks like the shoe
is on the other foot, doesn't it?
- I've never seen you like this.
- You don't wanna get on my bad side.
- Marks without Positraction...
...which was not available
on the '64 Buick Skylark.
Hey.
Hey, what are you watching?
What is that, My Cousin Vinny?
- Yeah.
- I thought you saw that before.
How come you're watching
that again?
I don't know.
Did you know Marisa Tomei
won an Oscar for that?
Boy, she's beautiful, don't you think?
I wish I looked like that.
Turn it off.
You're making me jealous.
I'm gonna think you like her
more than you like me.
- Hello?
- Elaine, it's me, George.
- How come you're whispering?
- Never mind.
Never mind.
I need you to do me a favour.
Remember what we were talking
about at the coffee shop?
No.
Think a second.
You know, your friend was talking
about me and, you know...
George, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- The actress.
- What?
Marisa Tomei!
- Nothing. Nothing.
Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, what about her?
- Well...
...I think I'd like to do it.
- What?
What?
George, no way. You're engaged.
A coffee.
That doesn't mean anything.
- No, George.
- Elaine.
- Forget it.
Elaine! Don't!
The judge! I hate this guy.
I can't believe you're buying
your father a car.
And best of all, it's a Cadillac.
A Cadillac?
I had no idea you had
this kind of money.
I don't like to talk about it.
Yeah, I mean,
I thought you were doing okay.
I just didn't think you were
in this kind of, you know...
...position.
It's just money.
So when are you getting back
from Florida?
Oh, I don't know.
I'll play it by ear. Why?
I don't know, just...
Things seem a little more exciting
when you're around.
That's all.
Are you okay?
Sure, sure.
- What was that?
- Quiet, quiet.
Hey, you know the guy
who lives here?
- Yeah.
- All morning I've been waiting here.
- All morning.
- Oh, this is...
The guy says he's gonna be home.
I show up, and all I do is wait.
I'm getting pretty sick and tired of it.
I'm not gonna put up with it
much longer.
I'm loving this.
Hey, there's a guy out here that...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know, I know.
Thanks very much for yesterday,
by the way.
Jerry, he wants me to fix him up
with Marisa Tomei.
I am not gonna be a part of this.
"Fixed up"? A cup of coffee.
A cup of coffee is not a fix-up.
You wanna meet her.
You wanna see if she likes you?
- So what? So what if I do?
- You're engaged!
I'm aware! I'm aware!
But this is Marisa Tomei, Elaine.
An Oscar winner.
How can I live the rest of my life...
...knowing I could have been
with her?
She said I was just her type.
She loves short, stocky,
balding funnymen.
I notice you threw "stocky" in.
Yeah, what the hell.
George, it's cheating.
It's not cheating if there's no sex.
Yes, it is. Jerry.
Hundred. Hold on a second.
I'm sorry.
I didn't hear what you said.
Elaine, come on.
Would you make the call?
Please, make the call.
Yeah. Yeah, fine. I'll call.
- Eight fifty.
- Oh, right.
So...
...how are you getting to the airport?
Do you need a ride, or?
- Don't be silly. I've arranged a car.
- You sure? You sure?
Because, you know...
- Maybe I'll let you pick me up.
- Okay.
Oh, hi.
Is Katy there?
What?
Oh, really?
Well, could you tell her
Elaine called?
Yeah, thanks.
She's in the hospital.
She has an arrhythmia.
What about Marisa Tomei?
Morty, what do you have to open
this box for?
There's already
a box of cookies open.
I wanted a Chip Ahoy.
I don't want all these open boxes.
Look, I got a few good years left.
If I want a Chip Ahoy, I'm having it.
Surprise!
- Jerry!
- Oh, my God!
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I'm a good son.
Just like that? No call?
- Just like that.
- Oh, you are really something.
To what do we owe this honour?
You wanna know, come on outside.
Outside? What's going on?
Whenever Jerry comes,
something exciting happens.
Come on, come on.
- Well, what do you think?
- Look at this.
Look at this.
You bought a Cadillac?
I bought it for you. It's yours.
You what?
You bought me a Cadillac?
I bought you a Cadillac.
Here you go.
Are you out of your mind?
- What?
- We can't take this.
You don't want it? Are you kidding?
- He's not buying us a Cadillac.
- What are you, nuts?
This is a very nice gesture, Jerry,
but take it back.
Can you believe this?
I'm not letting him buy us a Cadillac.
He hasn't got the money.
- How do you know?
- Oh, get out of here, Mr. Big Shot.
Why can't I buy my father a car?
- Your father doesn't need a car.
- Yes, I do.
- Oh, Morty.
- We're keeping it.
Over my dead body.
Give me those. Give me...
Well, this worked out
just as I had hoped.
- Giddyup.
- Yeah, this is Nick Stevens...
...from Plaza Cable.
Well, I waited all morning again.
You said you were gonna be there
from 9 to 1.
I was there. Where were you?
I got nothing better to do...
...than stand outside all morning
waiting for you to show up?
You're not gonna
get away with this.
Hey, Jerry, look at this.
My seat's got a memory,
in case somebody moves it.
I could be in prison for years.
I come out, my seat goes back
to where I like it.
That's what I was thinking.
Hello, Jerry.
Hiya, Jack.
So...
...how do you like this?
- Whose car?
- It's mine.
- Yours?
- That's right.
- My son bought it for me.
- He what?
My son bought me the car.
It's a present.
- You bought it?
- That's right. I bought it.
You ever see one so nice?
Some car.
- You wanna take a ride?
- No, thank you.
- Come on, take a ride.
- I don't wanna ride.
- Why not?
- I don't feel like taking a ride.
Do I have to take a ride?
He doesn't wanna take a ride.
What do you think,
I've never ridden in a Cadillac?
Believe me, I have ridden
in a Cadillac hundreds of times.
- Thousands.
- Thousands?
You think you're such a big shot now
because you got a Cadillac?
Did you believe that guy?
Anyway, I was thinking
about what you said...
...about me and Marisa, you know,
the two of us getting together.
And I know that I said
that I was engaged...
...but, you know, it's really just
something you say, you know.
It's like going steady, you know.
Going steady, engaged.
It's all just stuff you say.
Anyway, I was watching
My Cousin Vinny...
...on the tape the other day
and I was thinking that...
...you know, the two of us
might take a meeting, as they say.
So, what do you think?
Move a pinkie if it's yes.
Can you move a pinkie?
- Hello.
- Hi, Mr. Kramer.
This is McNab
down at the phone company.
We got a report
about some trouble on your line.
Well, I haven't had any trouble.
Thing is, we happen to have a man
right in your neighbourhood.
Is that right? Well, I have been having
a little trouble with my call waiting.
We can fix that. We can fix that.
Oh, can you?
Well, that's funny.
Because as it happens...
...I don't have call waiting.
Seems to me that the phone company
would know that.
Oh, right, I'm sorry.
I was looking at the wrong
work order.
Could you hold on for a second?
I've got something on the stove.
Hey, McNab!
Chunnel's on HBO tonight!
Why don't you stop by!
All right. Next thing on the agenda:
The restoration of the fence
at the Broward Gate.
At the present time,
we are still accepting bids.
It's been broken
for six months already.
What the hell are you doing?
Well, I, as your president,
have to find the best price.
And right now, I, for one,
do not think it's cost-feasible.
I'll bet you don't.
What's that?
Come on, Morty. The jig is up.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm sorry.
I'm sitting here the whole meeting
holding my tongue.
I know you a long time, Morty,
but I cannot hold it in any longer.
- What's going on, Jack?
- I'll tell you what's going on.
Morty Seinfeld has been
stealing funds from the treasury.
- Stealing?
- What proof do you have?
Proof? You want proof?
He's driving around
in a brand-new Cadillac.
What more proof do you want?
My son bought me that car.
Your son? Your son could never
afford that car.
We all saw his act
last year at the playhouse.
He's lucky he can pay his rent.
Jack's right. He stinks.
It's his material.
I tell you, he bought it for me.
- I move for a full investigation.
- I second.
- Impeachment?
- That's right.
Have you ever heard anything
like that?
- Can they do that?
- Lf they get the votes.
Told you we shouldn't have let him
give us the car.
Didn't you tell them I got the bill?
That proves I paid for it.
It doesn't make a difference.
They think we're in cahoots.
You could put a fence around these
condos and call it an insane asylum.
Nobody would know the difference.
No one's ever
been impeached before.
I couldn't live here.
We'd have to move to Boca.
Hello?
- Oh, hi, Evelyn.
- Hello, Jerry.
I just got off the phone
with Sol Brandes.
- What did he say?
- He's voting to impeach.
Not because he thinks
you stole the money...
...but mainly because you never
thanked him...
...for giving you his aisle seat
at Freddy Roman's show.
I did so thank him.
No, he never heard you.
I told you he didn't hear you.
He's deaf anyway.
Now, my sources tell me...
...there's three votes
for impeachment...
...three votes
against impeachment...
...and one undecided.
- Who's that?
- Mrs. Choate.
- Who's she?
- Oh, that one?
She's been a member of the board
longer than anybody.
She's very tough to deal with.
Maybe we should have her over
for coffee and explain our side of it.
- That's a good idea.
- Okay.
I'll see you
at the Lichtenbergs' tonight.
- The Lichtenbergs'?
- Yes, they're having a party.
We weren't invited.
Well.
Probably they think
you're too good for them.
You know, because of the car.
We're losing all our friends.
- Hello?
- Hello, Mr. Kramer?
This is John Hanaran from Con Ed.
- Oh, it's Hanaran now, is it?
- Yes.
We've had some reports
of power surges in your building.
It seems some jok ers
were up on the roof.
They must have damaged
some of the wires.
Oh, you don't say.
Either way, we need to get
into your apartment...
...and do a safety check.
Oh, you're good.
You are really good.
What are you talking about?
I guess I should just
go introduce myself, huh?
Hey, what are you watching?
Only You?