I love when the car place
puts that paper mat on the floor.
Like they're so obsessed
with cleanliness.
They don't even want their shoes
to touch the carpet.
The mechanic comes out,
he looks like Al Jolson.
He's covered in goo from head to toe.
You can't even see him.
I prefer that to when they have the
lab coat, the clipboard, the glasses.
Now you know
you're getting screwed.
"Can I see it?"
"You better not.
It's idling quietly right now.
I think it should stay overnight.
We want to keep an eye on it,
and want to keep the bill running up."
Tell the players that
I reimbursed the trainer...
...for the cigarettes and shakes.
- The players will be reimbursed?
- The trainer.
Tell the players
I reimbursed the trainer.
This is the third time
I've had to repeat myself.
- Sorry.
- Sorry doesn't cut it.
We're running
a ball club here, George.
You've got to pay attention.
I know. It won't happen again.
Let me see.
I had an assignment for you.
Let me... Let me think here.
Elaine.
Hi, Mr. Peterman.
You know what a huge fan
I am of John F. Kennedy.
I do.
The Peace Corps gave me
my start in this business.
Clothing the naked natives
of Bangtubesh.
The Pygmy pullover.
Sotheby's is having an auction
of JFK's memorabilia.
One item in particular
has caught my eye.
The presidential golf clubs.
To me, they capture that indefinable
romance that was Camelot.
Whatever.
Unfortunately, I will be
out of town with my lady...
...and therefore unable
to bid on the lot.
I was hoping you would go
in my stead.
Oh, yeah. I'd be happy to.
How much do you want this thing?
How high are you willing to go?
I would see no trouble in spending
up to, say, $10,000.
Have my secretary give you a check.
- When you're done, George,
and bring it directly to me.
Mr. Steinbrenner is
very interested in this.
- Yes, sir.
- Yes, George.
I want you to make this project
a top priority.
I will, sir. Top priority.
- Top priority, George.
- Top priority.
So he walks out of the stall.
He's been talking the whole time.
- He pulled an LBJ on you.
- LBJ?
Lyndon Johnson used to do that
to his staffers.
- No kidding?
- Oh, yeah.
He'd hold national security
meetings in there.
He planned the Hanoi bombing
after a bad Thai meal.
I don't know what
I'm supposed to do.
I don't even know
what my assignment is.
Ask him to repeat it.
Tell him there was an echo.
I can't. He's been on me
about not paying attention.
It's too late.
I already told him I heard him.
You know what you do?
Ask him a follow-up question.
Tell him you're having trouble getting
started, and you want his advice.
Yeah, follow-up question.
That'll work.
- Hey, bud.
- Hey.
- Can I have my keys...
- Yeah.
- Back please.
- You should have come, Jerry.
- We made quite a haul.
- Where did you go?
- Price Club.
- Why didn't you take your car?
- Oh, the steering wheel fell off.
I don't know where it is.
What are you doing?
Don't throw that away.
Well, I'm not paying the 5 cents
for that stupid recycling thing.
You don't pay 5 cents.
You get 5 cents back.
Read the label.
"Vermont, Connecticut,
Massachusetts, New York.
Refund, 5 cents."
- Refund?
- Yeah.
Well, what do you think
the hobos are doing?
I don't know. They're deranged.
Listen. Can you give me
a lift back to my place?
No, I can't. I've gotta pick up Elaine.
I'm taking her to this Kennedy auction.
- All right. I'll see you later.
- All right.
- What is this "MI, 10 cents"?
- That's Michigan.
In Michigan you get 10 cents.
- Ten cents?
- Yeah.
Wait a minute, you mean you get
5 cents here and 10 cents there?
You could round up bottles
and run them to Michigan.
- No, it doesn't work.
- What do you mean?
You get enough bottles...
You overload your inventory, and you
blow your margins on gasoline.
Trust me. It doesn't work.
You're not talking that Michigan
deposit-bottle scam?
- No, I'm off that.
- You tried it?
Oh, yeah. Every which way.
Couldn't crunch the numbers.
It drove me crazy.
You keep an eye on each other?
- No problem.
- You bet.
Are you sure you didn't hear
my car making a funny noise?
I know those two idiots did
something to it.
No, I didn't hear anything.
Oh, my God. Look who's here.
Sue Ellen Mischke, the braless,
Oh Henry! Candy bar heiress.
Well, hello, Elaine, Jerry.
- Hi, Sue Ellen.
I'm surprised to see you here.
Come to catch a glimpse
of high society?
No, no, I'm actually here to bid,
Sue Ellen.
I mean,
that is if anything's to my liking.
I'm here to catch
a glimpse of high society.
Well, I hope you find something
that fits your budget.
I hate that woman.
I don't understand.
You fill an 18-wheeler.
No, an 18-wheeler's no good.
Too much overhead.
You got permits,
weigh stations, tolls.
Look, you're way out of your league.
I wanna learn.
I want to know why.
Oh, those are handsome.
Look at that set.
Yeah, think I might bid on those.
Lot number 745.
We have a full set of golf clubs...
...that were owned
by President John F. Kennedy...
...as seen in the famous photo of the
president chipping at Burning Tree...
...on the morning
of the Bay of Pigs Invasion.
The set is in perfect condition,
and we will start the biding at $4000.
Four thousand dollars?
Do I have $4000? I have $4000.
Do I have 5? Five thousand dollars?
I have $5000. Do I have 6?
Six thousand dollars
for this set of beautiful clubs.
Six? I have $6000.
Can I have 6500?
Sixty-five hundred
to the dark-haired person on the right.
We are at 6500.
Do I hear 6600?
The president's own golf clubs.
Leisure life at Camelot.
Sixty-five hundred going once.
Eight thousand.
Eight thousand. We have 8000.
The bid is now $8000.
What is she doing?
She's starting in on the biding now?
Eighty-five hundred.
- We have 85.
- Nine thousand.
Nine thousand dollars.
I think she wants those clubs.
Do I hear 95?
Ninety-five hundred.
- Ninety-five hundred.
- Ten thousand.
Ten thousand
to the shapely woman on the left.
Ten thousand going once.
- That's you're ceiling.
- Ten thousand going twice.
- Eleven thousand.
- Twelve thousand.
- Thirteen thousand.
- Fourteen thousand.
Fifteen thousand.
Peterman is gonna kill me.
I really thought
you had her there at 17,000.
Why didn't you stop me?
Do you hear this clunking?
A little.
Oh, you know what?
I'm gonna grab these from you later.
You'll take care of them.
Okay? Okay.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Alrighty. Bye.
- Bye.
What is going on here?
Oh, my God.
Oh, you idiots!
So we could put the bottles
in a U-Haul.
- Go lean and mean.
- Newman, it's a dead end. Come on.
- Hey, there he is.
- Hey.
You put your groceries under
the hood of my car?
Oh, that's right.
We forgot about those.
That's where my missing soda is.
And your crab legs?
And a thing of cheese?
The AAA guy said I was close to
sucking a muffin down the carburettor.
- What were you thinking?
- We ran out of space.
Now I gotta take the car to Tony
and get it checked out.
- He's good.
- He's real good.
But he's so obsessive
about the car.
He makes me feel guilty about
everything wrong with it.
I gotta get it washed before
I take it down or he'll yell at me.
- Choke?
- No, thank you.
Oh, yeah.
I remember this car. Beautiful car.
Yeah, so anyway, the engine's been
idling a little rough.
I thought it might be time
for a check-up.
There's nothing wrong on the inside.
The shift knob is loose.
You know about that?
- No, I hadn't noticed.
- Have you been picking at it?
Have I been picking at it?
No, you know,
it's just wear and tear.
Wear and tear, I see.
The engine's the only thing
that needs checking.
- You been rotating the tires?
- Try to.
You don't try to. You do it.
Fifty-one percent of all turns
are right turns.
That's right.
Twenty thousand dollars?
Elaine, that's twice the amount
I authorized you to spend.
I know, Mr. Peterman,
but once I saw them...
...I just couldn't stand to let anyone
else have them, you know.
Certainly not some
stuck-up candy-bar heiress...
...who flaunts herself in public
without regard...
Well, where are they?
They should be here today.
- Mr. Wilhelm.
- Yes, George.
Hi, I was just...
I just had one little question
about my assignment.
Well, I trust things are
moving smoothly.
Mr. Steinbrenner's counting on you.
Yes, yes, very smooth,
super smooth.
But I really want to attack this thing.
You know, sink my teeth into it.
So I was just wondering...
...what do you think would be
the very best way to get started?
Get started?
I don't understand, George.
- I was wondering...
- You haven't been to Payroll?
- No, I haven't done that.
- What's the problem?
Now, come on, George. I told
the big man you were moving on this.
Now, don't let him down!
Payroll!
Hello there.
I'm George Costanza.
Yes.
Assistant to the travelling secretary.
I'm working on the project.
- What project?
- The payroll project.
Wilhelm?
Big, big payroll project.
You're gonna have to fill me in.
You know what?
I'll look around for awhile.
- I'll just browse around.
- Hey, wait. Excuse me.
You can't come back here.
I'm under direct orders
from Mr. Wilhelm.
If you have a problem,
you just take it up with him.
Well, maybe I will.
You know what?
I urge you to take it up with him.
Go ahead. Give him a call.
He'll tell you what I'm doing here.
Then you can tell me.
Mr. Wilhelm,
this is Lafarge in Payroll.
There's a Costanza here,
says he's working on some project.
Oh, I see. Interesting.
Well, that's quite a project.
All right. Thank you.
I'm sorry that I doubted you.
Whatever you need,
just make yourself at home.
So he explained it all to you?
Yes, he explained it all very clearly.
- What did he tell you?
- Look, you were right, I was wrong.
You don't have
to humiliate me about it.
Damn.
Oh, Mother's Day.
Wait a second.
Mother's Day.
Yes!
Come on, Kramer!
- What?
- It's the truck, Kramer, the truck.
Look, Newman,
I told you to let this thing go.
No, no, no, listen to me.
Most days, the post office sends
one truckload of mail...
...to the second domestic regional
sorting facility in Saginaw, Michigan.
But on the week before holidays,
we see a surge.
On Valentine's Day,
we send two trucks.
On Christmas, four,
packed to the brim.
And tomorrow,
if history is any guide...
...we'll see some spillover
into a fifth truck.
- Mother's Day.
- The mother of all mail days.
And guess who's signed up
for the truck?
A free truck?
Oh, boy, that completely changes
our cost structure.
Our G and A goes down 50 percent.
We carry a couple of bags of mail,
the rest is ours!
Newman, you magnificent bastard,
you did it!
Let the collecting begin!
So did you go down to Payroll?
Yes, Payroll. Yes, I did.
Very productive. Payroll paid off.
Then I guess
you'll be heading downtown, huh?
Oh, yeah. Downtown, definitely.
I'm very interested
to see how this thing turns out.
You said it. Excuse me, Mr. Wilhelm,
do you really think...?
Well...
Is this downtown trip really necessary,
you know, for the project?
Oh, no, you've got
to go downtown, George.
It's all downtown.
- Just like the song says.
- The song?
There's your answer, "Downtown."
The song "Downtown"?
The Petula Clark song?
Yeah.
You're sure he didn't mention it
because you were going downtown?
I think he was trying to tell me
something, like it had some meaning.
Okay, so how does it go?
When you're alone
And life is making you lonely
You can always go
Downtown
Maybe you know
Some little places to go to
Where they never close
- Downtown
- Wait a second.
Little places to go that never close.
What little place never closes?
- 7-Eleven.
- Maybe.
Just listen to the music
Of the traffic in the city
Linger on the sidewalk
Where the neon lights are pretty
Where the neon lights are pretty.
The Broadway area?
No, that's midtown.
Midtown.
The lights are much brighter there
You can forget all your troubles
Forget all your cares
Just go
Downtown
Things will be great
When you're
Downtown
I got nothing, Jerry, nothing.
Well, don't hang around
and let your troubles surround you.
There are movie shows.
You think I should come clean?
What do you think?
You think I should confess?
How can you lose?
Yeah, Jerry,
it's Tony Abado at the shop.
Look, we gotta talk.
You better come down.
Anytime after 4.
- Hello.
- Hi, it's me.
- Oh, hi.
- Listen, I need to come over...
...and pick up the clubs.
- Oh, you know what?
- Oh, no. What?
No, it's no big deal.
I left the clubs in the car.
You left them in the car?
- How could you leave them in the car?
- I forgot.
Oh, go down and get them.
I can't.
The car's at the mechanic's.
Oh, this is great.
All right. Where's the mechanic?
I'll just go and pick them up myself.
No, no, you can't.
He's working on the car right now.
You cannot disturb him
while he's working.
I'm going there in an hour
if you wanna meet me there.
You know the place.
It's on 56th Street.
Oh, okay. All right. Fine.
Hey, Tony.
- Thanks for coming in, Jerry.
- Sure.
I think I know what's going on here,
and I just want to hear it from you.
But I want you
to be straight with me.
Don't lie to me, Jerry.
You know that motor oil
you're putting in there?
It's from those
quickie-lube places, isn't it?
- Well, I change it so often. I mean...
- Motor oil is the lifeblood of a car.
You put in a low-grade oil,
you can damage vital engine parts.
Okay, see this gasket?
I have no confidence in that gasket.
- Tony, I really don't...
- Here's what I wanna do.
I wanna overhaul the entire engine.
But it's gonna take
a major commitment from you.
You're gonna have to keep it under
60 miles an hour for awhile.
You gotta come in, and you gotta get
the oil changed every 1000 miles.
How much money is
this gonna cost me?
I don't understand you.
It's your own car
we're talking about.
You know, you wrote
the wrong mileage down on the form.
You barely know the car.
Don't know the mileage,
the tire pressure.
When's the last time you checked
the washer fluid?
- But the washer fluid is fine.
- The washer fluid is not fine!
You know what...
...I just wanna take my car and
I'm gonna bring it someplace else.
- What do you mean?
- Just can I have my car.
I'm gonna to pay my bill
and be on my way.
- Well, the car's on a lift.
- Well, just get it down.
All right.
Okay. Well, wait here and I'll...
I'll bring it around.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Hey, where's the car?
- He's bringing it.
- Good.
Okay. Thank you.
So, what did they say?
They're sending
a detective tomorrow.
What the hell were you thinking
leaving my clubs in that car?
Well, I didn't count on my mechanic
pulling a Mary Beth Whitehead, did I?
Well, what kind of maniac
is this guy?
He's a very special maniac.
- What do I tell Mr. Peterman?
- I don't know.
Why couldn't
you take better care of that car?
- Well, are they here?
- Mr. Peterman...
...there seems to be a bit of a snag.
Snag?
It seems that
a psychotic mechanic...
...has absconded
with my friend's car.
What does that have
to do with my clubs?
They happened to be
in the back seat at the time.
What was the suspect wearing
at the time of the incident?
You know, like mechanic's pants,
a shirt that said "Tony."
Let me ask you,
have you ever seen a case like this?
All the time. The mechanic forms
an emotional attachment...
...thinks he's gonna lose the car.
He panics and does something rash.
I'm gonna ask you
some personal questions.
I'm sorry if I touch a nerve,
but I think it will help with the case.
Had you been
taking good care of the car?
- Had I been taking...?
- Did you leave the AC on?
Do you zip over speed bumps?
Ride the clutch? Things like that?
What does it matter? It's my car.
I can do whatever I want with it.
Not that I would think
of doing such things.
All right, Mr. Seinfeld,
we'll let you know if we find anything.
I gotta be honest with you.
These cases never end up well.
Well, whatever you can do.
Thanks.
Mr. Wilhelm, about the project, sir.
That's what I came to talk about.
Great job, George.
You really nailed it.
- I did?
- Yes, I read through it this morning.
I couldn't have done it better myself.
I turned it over to Mr. Steinbrenner.
Good work, George.
I don't get it.
He assigns it to you,
you don't do it...
...somehow it gets done...
...and now he's telling you
what a great job you did.
Maybe somebody did it
and didn't take credit for it.
Maybe it was already done and
didn't need doing in the first place.
I have no idea who did it...
...what they did,
or how they did it so well.
And you know what?
Jimmy crack corn and I don't care.
The gardener did a nice job planting
the rose bushes, didn't he, dear?
You planted the rose bushes, dear.
- I did?
- Yesterday. You remember.
That's right.
- Oh, what's for dinner?
- We just ate.
Did you forget
to take your medicine?
The point is,
however it got done, it's done.
So any luck with the car?
No, the police have no leads.
And I just found out today
my insurance doesn't cover it.
- Why not?
- They don't consider it stolen...
...if you wilfully
give the guy the keys.
- Hey.
What did the detective say?
They're looking.
I gotta go.
- Hello.
- Mr. Seinfeld?
- Yeah.
- It's Detective McMahon.
I'm at the warehouse on pier 38.
I think you'd better get down here.
Yeah, okay.
They may have found the car.
Are the clubs in it? Ask him.
Are there golf clubs in the back?
We really can't tell.
You better bring
your service records.
Watch where you step.
There's quite a bit of grease.
Detective, Jerry Seinfeld is here.
How do you do?
Thanks for coming down.
This is Elaine Benes.
We used to date
but now we're just friends.
- I see.
- You know.
I'm sorry to make you go through this,
but we need to make sure.
What's going on?
What is this thing?
One of our patrolmen
stumbled over this.
Oh, my God.
The block is nearly split apart.
We found the overhead cams
30 feet away.
We can only hope
the body's sold for scrap.
Oh, my God.
And we know it's a Saab.
The angle on the V6
is definitely a '92.
The model is hard to determine
because the drive train is all burnt out.
What is that smell?
Look at the clutch.
Excuse me.
Whoever did this
didn't just dismantle it.
I mean, they took their time,
they had fun...
...they were very systematic.
They went out of the way
to gouge the sides of every piston.
And the turbo was separated
from the housing...
...and shoved right up
the exhaust pipe.
Wait a second. Turbo?
- I didn't have a turbo.
- Your car is not a turbo?
No, it's a 900 S.
It's a turbo, Elaine. A turbo.
It's a turbo!
Excuse me.
Did you say "Turbo"?
Saab Turbo 9000?
Is it midnight blue?
Yes, ma'am.
9999 bottles and cans in the truck
9999 bottles and cans
At $0. 10 a bottle and $0. 10 a can
We're pulling in $500 a man
9998 bottles and cans in the truck
9998 bottles and cans
We fill up with gas
We count up our cash
9997 bottles and cans in the truck
- Hello.
- Hey, Jerry. It's Tony.
Tony, where are you?
Oh, look, I just want you to know
that the car is fine.
Got her all fixed up.
We're in a nice area,
no potholes, no traffic.
So there's nothing
to worry about, okay?
In fact, here.
Somebody wants to talk to you.
Tony, you better
bring that car back.
Nobody's giving anything back.
You tried to take it from me.
I don't forget that.
Tony, it is my car,
and I want it back.
Oh, your car?
You want your car back?
- Tony...
- Listen.
That registration may have
your name on it, Jerry...
...but this engine's running
on my sweat and my blood.
Where do I find these guys?
- How much gas we got?
- Three quarters of a tank.
Better than we estimated.
- Seven dollars and 22 cents better.
- Oh, baby.
- Maybe we could stop for a snack.
- No, that's not in the budget.
Well, the budget changed, you know.
I mean, it might be a good investment.
That's not a good investment.
That's a loss.
Hey, you see that car?
It looks like Jerry's.
I'm gonna check out
that license plate.
Yeah, those are New York plates.
- Is that Jerry's number?
- I don't know.
But that's New York and we're in Ohio.
Those are pretty good odds.
- What are you doing?
- Calling Jerry.
- On what?
- I brought my phone.
- Hello.
- Hey, Jerry.
- What's your license plate number?
- What's up?
Yeah, well,
I think I spotted your car.
Oh, my God, you're kidding.
Hang on a second.
- It's JVN728.
- Hey, that's it.
That's it.
Hey, look, we got him.
We're driving behind him
in a truck.
Oh, my God. Yeah.
He said he brought it to the country.
We're in the country,
and we're right on his tail.
Good work, Kramer.
This is incredible.
Yeah, don't worry, Jerry.
We're right on this guy
like stink on a monkey.
I'll check back with you.
Elaine Benes.
Yeah, it's me.
Kramer found the car.
Oh, my God. Where is it?
Somewhere in the country.
They're following him.
- The clubs there?
- I don't know. They're tailing him.
- I'm waiting for them to call me back.
- All right. I'm heading over right now.
- What's the status?
- Last check-in, they were still on him.
Have they called the police yet?
- They won't call the police.
- What? Why not?
They'll get in trouble
for using the truck.
- Kramer doesn't want a record.
- Kramer has one.
Not a federal record.
- Kramer?
- What's going on?
- Yeah, nothing.
We're still following him.
Wait a second. He's getting off.
Yeah, he's gonna be going south
on the 135.
- Keep following him.
- All right. I'll follow him.
We can't.
We're going north to Michigan.
Yeah, hey, listen, I can't.
It's gonna be taking us out of our way.
- I need those clubs.
- Kramer, I want my car.
- Well, I don't know what to do!
- We got 10,000 deposit bottles here.
This guy could be going
to Arkansas.
Keep following.
Don't let me down.
We can't afford a detour.
Our budget won't hold it.
I don't know what to do, man!
Stay left! Stay left!
Left, left, left. Stay left!
- Right! Go right!
- Go south!
All right, all right. I'm getting off.
I'm gonna go on the ramp.
I hope you realize
what you've done.
You've destroyed
our whole venture.
This ramp is steep.
All my work, my planning, my genius,
all for naught.
We're pulling too much weight.
- He's getting away. Take the wheel.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- I'm gonna get something.
- Are you crazy?
Keep your foot on the gas.
Hey, you're not dumping those
bottles back there, are you?
Kramer, those have wholesale value.
We can cut our losses.
Bottles below!
I love this magnifying glass.
I feel like a scientist.
- Oh, yeah.
- You wanted to see me, sir?
Come in, George. Come in.
Wilhelm gave me
this project you worked on.
- Yes, sir.
- Let me ask you something.
Having any personal problems?
Girl trouble? Love trouble?
- No, sir.
- What about drugs?
Doing some of that crack cocaine?
You on the pipe?
- No, sir.
- Are you seeing a psychiatrist?
I got a flash for you, young man.
You're non compos mentis.
You got some bats in the belfry.
What are you talking about?
George, I read this report.
It's troubling. Very troubling indeed.
It's a sick mind at work here.
Okay, come on, boys.
Come in here.
George, this is Herb and Dan.
They're gonna take you
to where you can get some help.
Very friendly people there.
My brother-in-law was there.
Man was obsessed
with lactating women.
They cured him.
Although he eats a lot of cheese.
But you see... You see, I didn't
write that report. That's not mine.
Of course you didn't.
You didn't write it.
I didn't do it! It just got done!
I don't know how it got done
but it did!
Of course, it got done.
Things get done all the time.
I understand.
Your job will be waiting for you
when you get back.
Get better, George!
Get better!
Man, I don't understand this.
I ditched every bottle and can,
and we still can't gain.
It's like we're...
...sluggish.
We collected all those bottles and
all those cans for what? What a waste.
I'm really gonna catch hell
for those missing mailbags.
Hey, wasn't that a pie stand
back there?
- A pie stand?
- Oh, yeah.
Homemade pies, 200 yards back.
Oh, come on, pull over.
Pull over, will you?
Where? I don't see it.
Well, open the door.
You'll get a better look.
I don't see any pie.
Kramer!
I'm sorry, Newman,
you were holding us back.
Kramer!
Jerry, we've lost the fat man
and we're running lean.
We're back on track, buddy.
Federal employee.
I hate corn.
- Hello, stranger.
- Look, I'm sorry to bother you...
...but I'm a U.S. Postal worker...
...and my mail truck
was just ambushed...
...by a band of backwoods,
mail-hating survivalists.
You just calm down now.
Calm down.
Don't worry. We'll take care of you.
This farm ain't much,
but you're welcome to what we have.
- Hot bath, hearty meal, clean bed.
- Oh, thank you, sir.
I just have one rule.
Keep your hands off my daughter.
Jerry, we got him.
I'm riding his tail.
There's no escape.
He's running scared, buddy.
- How's the gas situation?
- I got enough to get to Memphis.
He's reaching in back.
Keeps grabbing at something.
He's pulling out a gun.
- He's got a gun, Jerry!
- Duck, Kramer, duck.
It's a golf club. There's no gun.
He threw a golf club at me!
Those are JFK's golf clubs.
Hey, I'm under fire.
I'm under heavy fire here.
Jeez, there goes a five-iron.
Stop the truck, Kramer.
Pick up the clubs.
No, don't stop, Kramer.
Keep going. Don't let him get away.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I think he's done.
Oh, no, he's taking out the woods!
You'll have to do
a lot better than that!
What's happening?
This truck is dying.
We're losing him.
- I think we lost him.
- Damn it.
Can you stop
and pick up those clubs, Kramer?
Yeah, yeah, I'll get them.
Enjoying that mutton?
It's delicious mutton.
This is... This is out of sight.
I would... I would love to get the recipe.
It's very good.
That cider too strong for you?
No, no, I love strong cider.
I'm a big strong-cider guy.
Gonna milk the Holsteins
in the morning, if you'd lend a hand.
You know, I don't know much about...
I don't have any...
- I don't think I know much about that.
- Susie will teach you.
Just gotta pull on the teets a little.
It's nice having
a big, strong man around.
You know, those mailbags,
they get mighty heavy.
I...
I Nautilus, of course.
Can I have some gravy?
Steinbrenner had me committed!
I'm in the nuthouse.
I'll be back
same time next week, Pop.
They took my belt, Jerry.
I got nothing to hold my pants up.
You gotta come over here now!
Just tell him what we talked about,
how I didn't do the project.
George?
I see you're finally
getting some help.
Oh, Deena, thank God.
Thank God, you're here.
Listen, you gotta help me.
You gotta tell these people
that I'm okay.
You know
that I don't belong in here.
George, this is
the best thing for you.
What? No, no, Deena.
Deena, wait! Deena, help!
It's not what it looks like.
Is that little Georgie C?
How's the folks?
You still got that nice little car?
- What are you doing?
- Kramer, help me, help me!
I told you to keep away
from my daughter.
No, Daddy, you'll hurt him.
I love him.
Goodbye, Norman! Goodbye!
Elaine, you found the clubs.
That's wonderful news.
- Where are they?
- Yep.
Let me get them for you,
Mr. Peterman.
I'll be inaugurating them this weekend
with none other than Ethel Kennedy.
A woman whose triumph
in the face of tragedy...
...is exceeded only
by her proclivity to procreate.
The...
The letter of authenticity
is in the side pocket there.
Elaine.
I never knew Kennedy
had such a temper.
Oh, yeah.
The only thing worse was his slice.
- See you on Monday.
- Have a good game.