That's another Marisa Tomei movie.
And you've seen that one too.
What, do you have a thing for her?
Yeah. Yeah, I have a thing
for Marisa Tomei.
Like she would ever go out
with a short, stocky, bald man.
Like that's her type.
She's an Oscar winner.
Besides, I don't even know her.
It's not like anyone's
trying to fix us up.
Who would try and fix me up
with Marisa Tomei?
What are you talking about?
Have I told you
how much I love you today?
Not in the last 15 minutes.
Well, I do love you very much.
And I love you, Marisa.
Well, then. Come on, get dressed.
We're going to be late
for the premiere.
Stupid foldout.
Why do they put the bar
in the middle of the bed?
- Hello?
- Hi, Jerry.
Elaine? What's going on?
I was thinking. I mean, I'm not really
doing that much this weekend...
...and I thought, "Well, what the hell.
Maybe I'll come down there
and hang out a little."
You wanna hang out here...
...at Phase Two
in the Pines of Mar Gables?
Well...
...it's just two hours by plane.
Gee, I don't know what to tell you.
Damn it. I got another call.
Hang on. Don't hang up, Jerry.
- Yeah?
- Elaine...
...you have got to get me
Marisa Tomei's number.
Okay, George, I'm on the other line.
I promise you, I'll get you her number.
- Yeah.
- Goodbye.
Hi.
So, what do you think?
I don't think so.
I'll be back on Monday.
Well, if you need that ride...
...just give me a call.
I can meet you at the gate, Jerr.
Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
- All right, I'll see you.
- Jerr, Jerry?
- Yeah?
- Bye.
Bye.
Yeah, sure. No, that's fantastic.
I'll... I'll see you then.
Okay.
I just got off the phone
with Marisa Tomei.
I just spoke to Marisa Tomei.
And I wasn't even that nervous.
I can't remember calling
a woman without being nervous.
Usually I'm pacing all over the room.
I write down things to say.
Okay, well, that's all the time
we have for today.
Why don't we pick up
with this next week?
- Where are you going?
- I got stuff to do.
- What? You can't leave yet.
- Why not?
- We have to discuss my alibi.
- Alibi?
- What does that have to do with me?
- I spend Saturday...
...with Susan. She'll wanna know
what I'm doing.
I can't use Jerry.
He's in Florida.
- So you wanna say you were with me?
- Yes.
Okay, fine. You were with me.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
What were we doing?
Where were we?
Why are we together?
- What is the difference?
- Because if you ever see her...
...and it comes up,
we have to be in sync.
Okay. Now...
Why do I have to see you?
Because I'm going to the dentist...
...and I'm afraid...
...and I want you to go with me.
That's no good.
Okay, fine.
What?
I don't like the way you
just rejected my suggestion.
Hey, let's not get so defensive here.
This is a give-and-take process.
I thought that
my suggestion was good.
I think you could have
been a little more tactful.
Okay, look, we've never
worked together on a lie.
You don't understand how I work.
I have a certain way of working.
Jerry and I have worked together
a few times. He knows how I work.
Not a personal thing. We're just trying
to come up with the best possible lie.
- That's what this is about.
- Okay.
- Okay. Fine.
- Okay?
- Good.
- Fine, fine, fine.
Okay.
Okay, how about this?
- What?
- You are having problems...
...with your boyfriend, and I am
meeting you to discuss the situation.
I don't have a boyfriend.
She doesn't know that.
We say that you do.
It's good. Believe me.
I thought my idea was just as good.
- The dentist thing?
- Yeah, right. The dentist thing.
- The dentist thing was not good.
- Okay, all right.
What is his name? Who is he?
Art Vandelay.
Art Vandelay?
- This is my boyfriend?
- That's your boyfriend.
What does he do?
- He's an importer.
- Just imports? No exports?
He's an importer-exporter.
Okay?
So I'm dating Art Vandelay.
What is the problem
we're discussing?
Yes, yes.
How about this?
How about he's thinking
of quitting the exporting...
...and just focusing in
on the importing.
And this is causing a problem.
Because why not do both?
Oh, what? You don't like
that suggestion either?
It's very complicated.
You know, it seems to me
that it's all you...
...and none of my ideas
are getting in.
You know, I mean, you just know it all.
And I am Miss Stupid, right?
What are you doing?
Are you making coffee?
- Yeah.
- You better make a pot of tea too.
Morty, you're driving me crazy.
Look, I don't want anything
to go wrong.
If this woman votes to impeach me,
I'll be a laughingstock.
You wanna drive a Cadillac,
expect to pay the consequences.
There she is.
Hello. Hello, Mrs. Choate.
- Hello.
- Oh, come in. May I take your coat?
No, no. I prefer to wear it.
Nobody's taking my coat.
How about a cup
of coffee or something?
Coffee?
I'll take hot water
with lemon if you have it.
Please, have a seat.
That's a lovely scarf you're wearing.
Where did you get it?
They're a dime a dozen.
Oh, hi, Jerry. Mrs. Choate,
this is my son, Jerry.
- Give me that rye.
- Stop it.
Help! Someone help!
- Shut up, you old bag.
- Thief!
Stop him! Stop him,
he's got my rye!
- Nice to meet you.
- Hello.
Jerry lives in New York.
You just came from New York?
Yeah, I was visiting my daughter.
And I'll never go back.
The crime there is just terrible.
Do you know I got mugged
for a marble rye right on the street?
Oh, that's terrible. They stole a rye?
Why would they steal a rye?
That's what the city's turning into.
They'll steal anything.
They're like savages.
Yeah, there are some sickos
out there.
You look very familiar.
Have we ever met?
You ever go to Camp Tioga?
Maybe you've seen him
on television.
- Jerry's a comedian.
- No, I don't watch TV.
- It was nice meeting you.
- Jerry, don't go.
No, I think I'll go.
So, Morty, what's this all about?
What do you want?
Hey, where are you going?
Oh, l... I didn't tell you?
I gotta go meet Elaine.
Elaine? What for?
I don't know. She's having some
problems with this guy she's seeing.
I didn't know
she was dating anyone.
Yeah, yeah. She's seeing
this guy, Art Vandelay.
- So, what does he do?
- He's an importer-exporter.
What kind of problems
are they having?
Well, he...
He wants to quit
the exporting and...
...focus just on the importing.
And it's a problem because
she thinks the exporting...
...is as important as the importing.
Are you having
an affair with Elaine?
Right. Come on.
I'm having an affair with Elaine?
If I was having an affair with Elaine...
...I wouldn't tell you
I'm seeing Elaine.
I would make up another person
to tell you I would see...
...and then I would go see Elaine.
I'll get you! I'll get you, Kramer!
You won't get away with this.
All right, are you ready to eat?
Oh, right, let's go. Jerry, let's go.
It's time to eat. We're going to dinner.
- Dinner? Well, what time is it?
- It's 4:30.
Four thirty?
Who eats dinner at 4:30?
By the time we sit down,
it'll be quarter to 5.
I don't understand
why we have to eat now.
We gotta catch the early-bird.
It's only between 4:30 and 6.
Yeah, they give you a tenderloin,
a salad and a baked potato for $4.95.
You know what that
costs you after 6?
Can't we eat at a decent hour?
I'll treat. Okay?
You're not buying us dinner.
I'm not force-feeding
myself a steak at 4:30...
...to save a couple bucks.
I'll tell you that.
All right.
We'll wait.
But it's unheard of.
So anyway, if you think about it...
..."manure" is not really
that bad a word.
I mean, it's "newer," which is good.
And a "ma" in front of it,
which is also good.
"Manure." It's really not that bad.
You're so right.
I never thought of it like that.
"Manure." "Ma" and the "newer."
Did you just make that up?
What, you think I'm doing material?
No, no.
It's hard to believe anyone
could be so spontaneously funny.
And I'm a little tired.
So tell me:
How is it that a man like you...
...so bald and so quirky
and funny?
How is it you're not taken?
Well, Marisa...
...you see, the thing is...
...l'm sort of engaged.
What?
I'm, you know, "engaged."
- Hey, look, there's a spot right in front.
- Always, Jerry. Always.
Was that delicious or what?
Where you gonna get
a better meal?
It's better than Danny's.
Danny's? Come on.
- Hello, Jack.
- Doris.
- Hi, Jack. Hi, Doris.
- Jerry.
Hello, Morty.
Well, you missed the early-bird.
Yeah? So?
Must be nice to have
that kind of money.
Bernie.
Look who's eating at 6:00.
Your suddenly well-to-do president.
Stop it, Jack.
You enjoy your last meal in office.
Tomorrow, when they kick you out...
...you'll have plenty of time
to drive around in your Cadillac.
They're not kicking me out.
You don't have the votes.
That's what you think.
- We'll see.
- Yes, we will.
All right, let's eat already.
- Hi, Susan.
- Hi.
Hi. Come in. Come in.
- Have a seat.
- Elaine, I have to ask you a question.
- Oh, sure.
- Are you having an affair with George?
What?
Don't be ridiculous.
I mean, why would
anyone wanna sleep...?
Well, obviously...
You know... Of... Of...
Why would you think I was
having an affair with George?
Oh, because he said that he had to
talk with you earlier about some...
...problem that you were having.
Yeah. Yeah, I did have
to talk with him.
I definitely had to talk with him.
I was having a problem
with my boyfriend.
- Art Vandelay?
- Yeah, Art Vandelay.
I'm sorry.
L... I feel like an idiot.
No, no.
That's okay.
- Forget that we ever talked.
- It is so forgotten.
- All right.
- Okay.
Okay. It's no problem.
So was George helpful at all?
Yeah. Oh, yes.
Yes, he was very helpful.
Because Art and I were
getting into this whole thing...
...about his business.
- You know he's an importer-exporter?
- Yeah.
George felt that I was too
adamant in my stand...
...that Art should focus
on the exporting...
...and forget about the importing.
Wait a minute. I thought that Art
wanted to give up the exporting.
- What did I say?
- The importing.
I did?
So, what does he import?
Chips.
- What kind of chips?
- Potato.
- Some corn.
- And what does he export?
Diapers.
- I'm sorry to bother you.
- Oh, no, it's okay.
Okay.
Come on, George, pick up.
Oh, pick up. Oh, pick up.
- Hi.
- Hi. So, George...
...what does Art Vandelay import?
Matches. Really long matches.
There she is. Okay, if I could have
your attention for a minute here.
We're calling this emergency meeting
of the board of Phase Two...
...to consider a motion of impeachment
of our president, Morty Seinfeld.
- Nervous, Jack?
- What for?
Because I have the votes.
- Nice to see you, Mrs. Choate.
- Hello, Morty.
Building A, are you for or against
the motion to impeach?
- What does that mean?
- It means if you're for the motion...
...you're against Morty.
So why don't you say that?
Hey. I'm running the meeting.
If you think so.
- Building A.
- For impeachment.
- Building B.
- Against impeachment.
- Building C.
- For impeachment.
- Building D.
- Against impeachment.
I can't believe you got that old bag.
Help! Someone help!
Shut up, you old bag.
Thief! Thief!
It's him.
It's your son.
Now I know where I saw him.
He stole my marble rye.
My son never stole anything.
He's a good boy.
They should lock him up.
Like father, like son.
I change my vote.
I vote to impeach.
Me too. I change my vote.
- All those in favour say aye.
- Aye!
All opposed?
The ayes have it.
The motion passes.
Morty Seinfeld, you are officially
dismissed as condo president.
As vice president, Jack Klompus...
...in accordance with
the Phase Two constitution...
...is hereby installed as president.
Hear, hear, Jack.
Good for you, honey.
All right, I know you're in there.
I know you can hear me.
You win, okay? You win.
I can't do it anymore.
What do you want from me,
an apology?
All right.
I'm sorry.
There, I said it.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I see now how we made you feel
when we made you sit home waiting.
I don't know why we do it.
I guess maybe we just kind of enjoy...
...taking advantage of people.
But all that's gonna change.
From now on, no more 9 to 12,
no more 1 to 5.
We'll kind of have appointments.
Eleven o'clock is gonna
mean 11:00...
...and if we can't make it,
I'm gonna call you, tell you why.
For God's sakes, if a doctor can do it,
why can't we?
Anyway...
...that's it.
I'm sorry, bub.
The bags are in the car.
And I guess we'd better go.