You know, like mechanic's pants,
a shirt that said "Tony."
Let me ask you,
have you ever seen a case like this?
All the time. The mechanic forms
an emotional attachment...
...thinks he's gonna lose the car.
He panics and does something rash.
I'm gonna ask you
some personal questions.
I'm sorry if I touch a nerve,
but I think it will help with the case.
Had you been
taking good care of the car?
- Had I been taking...?
- Did you leave the AC on?
Do you zip over speed bumps?
Ride the clutch? Things like that?
What does it matter? It's my car.
I can do whatever I want with it.
Not that I would think
of doing such things.
All right, Mr. Seinfeld,
we'll let you know if we find anything.
I gotta be honest with you.
These cases never end up well.
Well, whatever you can do.
Thanks.
Mr. Wilhelm, about the project, sir.
That's what I came to talk about.
Great job, George.
You really nailed it.
- I did?
- Yes, I read through it this morning.
I couldn't have done it better myself.
I turned it over to Mr. Steinbrenner.
Good work, George.
I don't get it.
He assigns it to you,
you don't do it...
...somehow it gets done...
...and now he's telling you
what a great job you did.
Maybe somebody did it
and didn't take credit for it.
Maybe it was already done and
didn't need doing in the first place.
I have no idea who did it...
...what they did,
or how they did it so well.
And you know what?
Jimmy crack corn and I don't care.
The gardener did a nice job planting
the rose bushes, didn't he, dear?
You planted the rose bushes, dear.
- I did?
- Yesterday. You remember.
That's right.
- Oh, what's for dinner?
- We just ate.
Did you forget
to take your medicine?
The point is,
however it got done, it's done.
So any luck with the car?
No, the police have no leads.
And I just found out today
my insurance doesn't cover it.
- Why not?
- They don't consider it stolen...
...if you wilfully
give the guy the keys.
- Hey.
What did the detective say?
They're looking.
I gotta go.
- Hello.
- Mr. Seinfeld?
- Yeah.
- It's Detective McMahon.
I'm at the warehouse on pier 38.
I think you'd better get down here.
Yeah, okay.
They may have found the car.
Are the clubs in it? Ask him.
Are there golf clubs in the back?
We really can't tell.
You better bring
your service records.
Watch where you step.
There's quite a bit of grease.
Detective, Jerry Seinfeld is here.
How do you do?
Thanks for coming down.
This is Elaine Benes.
We used to date
but now we're just friends.
- I see.
- You know.
I'm sorry to make you go through this,
but we need to make sure.
What's going on?
What is this thing?
One of our patrolmen
stumbled over this.
Oh, my God.
The block is nearly split apart.
We found the overhead cams
30 feet away.
We can only hope
the body's sold for scrap.
Oh, my God.
And we know it's a Saab.
The angle on the V6
is definitely a '92.
The model is hard to determine
because the drive train is all burnt out.
What is that smell?
Look at the clutch.
Excuse me.
Whoever did this
didn't just dismantle it.
I mean, they took their time,
they had fun...
...they were very systematic.
They went out of the way
to gouge the sides of every piston.
And the turbo was separated
from the housing...
...and shoved right up
the exhaust pipe.
Wait a second. Turbo?
- I didn't have a turbo.
- Your car is not a turbo?
No, it's a 900 S.
It's a turbo, Elaine. A turbo.
It's a turbo!
Excuse me.
Did you say "Turbo"?
Saab Turbo 9000?
Is it midnight blue?
Yes, ma'am.
9999 bottles and cans in the truck
9999 bottles and cans
At $0. 10 a bottle and $0. 10 a can
We're pulling in $500 a man
9998 bottles and cans in the truck
9998 bottles and cans
We fill up with gas
We count up our cash
9997 bottles and cans in the truck
- Hello.
- Hey, Jerry. It's Tony.
Tony, where are you?
Oh, look, I just want you to know
that the car is fine.
Got her all fixed up.
We're in a nice area,
no potholes, no traffic.
So there's nothing
to worry about, okay?
In fact, here.
Somebody wants to talk to you.
Tony, you better
bring that car back.
Nobody's giving anything back.
You tried to take it from me.
I don't forget that.
Tony, it is my car,
and I want it back.
Oh, your car?
You want your car back?
- Tony...
- Listen.
That registration may have
your name on it, Jerry...
...but this engine's running
on my sweat and my blood.
Where do I find these guys?
- How much gas we got?
- Three quarters of a tank.
Better than we estimated.
- Seven dollars and 22 cents better.
- Oh, baby.
- Maybe we could stop for a snack.
- No, that's not in the budget.
Well, the budget changed, you know.
I mean, it might be a good investment.
That's not a good investment.
That's a loss.
Hey, you see that car?
It looks like Jerry's.
I'm gonna check out
that license plate.
Yeah, those are New York plates.
- Is that Jerry's number?
- I don't know.
But that's New York and we're in Ohio.
Those are pretty good odds.
- What are you doing?
- Calling Jerry.
- On what?
- I brought my phone.
- Hello.
- Hey, Jerry.
- What's your license plate number?
- What's up?
Yeah, well,
I think I spotted your car.
Oh, my God, you're kidding.
Hang on a second.
- It's JVN728.
- Hey, that's it.
That's it.
Hey, look, we got him.
We're driving behind him
in a truck.
Oh, my God. Yeah.
He said he brought it to the country.
We're in the country,
and we're right on his tail.
Good work, Kramer.
This is incredible.
Yeah, don't worry, Jerry.
We're right on this guy
like stink on a monkey.
I'll check back with you.
Elaine Benes.
Yeah, it's me.
Kramer found the car.
Oh, my God. Where is it?
Somewhere in the country.
They're following him.
- The clubs there?
- I don't know. They're tailing him.
- I'm waiting for them to call me back.
- All right. I'm heading over right now.
- What's the status?
- Last check-in, they were still on him.
Have they called the police yet?
- They won't call the police.
- What? Why not?
They'll get in trouble
for using the truck.
- Kramer doesn't want a record.
- Kramer has one.
Not a federal record.
- Kramer?
- What's going on?
- Yeah, nothing.
We're still following him.
Wait a second. He's getting off.
Yeah, he's gonna be going south
on the 135.
- Keep following him.
- All right. I'll follow him.
We can't.
We're going north to Michigan.
Yeah, hey, listen, I can't.
It's gonna be taking us out of our way.
- I need those clubs.
- Kramer, I want my car.
- Well, I don't know what to do!
- We got 10,000 deposit bottles here.
This guy could be going
to Arkansas.
Keep following.
Don't let me down.
We can't afford a detour.
Our budget won't hold it.
I don't know what to do, man!
Stay left! Stay left!
Left, left, left. Stay left!
- Right! Go right!
- Go south!
All right, all right. I'm getting off.
I'm gonna go on the ramp.
I hope you realize
what you've done.
You've destroyed
our whole venture.
This ramp is steep.
All my work, my planning, my genius,
all for naught.
We're pulling too much weight.
- He's getting away. Take the wheel.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- I'm gonna get something.
- Are you crazy?
Keep your foot on the gas.
Hey, you're not dumping those
bottles back there, are you?
Kramer, those have wholesale value.
We can cut our losses.
Bottles below!
I love this magnifying glass.
I feel like a scientist.
- Oh, yeah.
- You wanted to see me, sir?
Come in, George. Come in.
Wilhelm gave me
this project you worked on.
- Yes, sir.
- Let me ask you something.
Having any personal problems?
Girl trouble? Love trouble?
- No, sir.
- What about drugs?
Doing some of that crack cocaine?
You on the pipe?
- No, sir.
- Are you seeing a psychiatrist?
I got a flash for you, young man.
You're non compos mentis.
You got some bats in the belfry.
What are you talking about?
George, I read this report.
It's troubling. Very troubling indeed.
It's a sick mind at work here.
Okay, come on, boys.
Come in here.
George, this is Herb and Dan.
They're gonna take you
to where you can get some help.
Very friendly people there.
My brother-in-law was there.
Man was obsessed
with lactating women.
They cured him.
Although he eats a lot of cheese.
But you see... You see, I didn't
write that report. That's not mine.
Of course you didn't.
You didn't write it.
I didn't do it! It just got done!
I don't know how it got done
but it did!
Of course, it got done.
Things get done all the time.
I understand.
Your job will be waiting for you
when you get back.
Get better, George!
Get better!
Man, I don't understand this.
I ditched every bottle and can,
and we still can't gain.
It's like we're...
...sluggish.
We collected all those bottles and
all those cans for what? What a waste.
I'm really gonna catch hell
for those missing mailbags.
Hey, wasn't that a pie stand
back there?
- A pie stand?
- Oh, yeah.
Homemade pies, 200 yards back.
Oh, come on, pull over.
Pull over, will you?
Where? I don't see it.
Well, open the door.
You'll get a better look.
I don't see any pie.
Kramer!
I'm sorry, Newman,
you were holding us back.
Kramer!
Jerry, we've lost the fat man
and we're running lean.
We're back on track, buddy.
Federal employee.
I hate corn.
- Hello, stranger.
- Look, I'm sorry to bother you...
...but I'm a U.S. Postal worker...
...and my mail truck
was just ambushed...
...by a band of backwoods,
mail-hating survivalists.
You just calm down now.
Calm down.
Don't worry. We'll take care of you.
This farm ain't much,
but you're welcome to what we have.
- Hot bath, hearty meal, clean bed.
- Oh, thank you, sir.
I just have one rule.
Keep your hands off my daughter.
Jerry, we got him.
I'm riding his tail.
There's no escape.
He's running scared, buddy.
- How's the gas situation?
- I got enough to get to Memphis.
He's reaching in back.
Keeps grabbing at something.
He's pulling out a gun.
- He's got a gun, Jerry!
- Duck, Kramer, duck.
It's a golf club. There's no gun.
He threw a golf club at me!
Those are JFK's golf clubs.
Hey, I'm under fire.
I'm under heavy fire here.
Jeez, there goes a five-iron.
Stop the truck, Kramer.
Pick up the clubs.
No, don't stop, Kramer.
Keep going. Don't let him get away.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I think he's done.
Oh, no, he's taking out the woods!
You'll have to do
a lot better than that!
What's happening?
This truck is dying.
We're losing him.
- I think we lost him.
- Damn it.
Can you stop
and pick up those clubs, Kramer?
Yeah, yeah, I'll get them.
Enjoying that mutton?
It's delicious mutton.
This is... This is out of sight.
I would... I would love to get the recipe.
It's very good.
That cider too strong for you?
No, no, I love strong cider.
I'm a big strong-cider guy.
Gonna milk the Holsteins
in the morning, if you'd lend a hand.
You know, I don't know much about...
I don't have any...
- I don't think I know much about that.
- Susie will teach you.
Just gotta pull on the teets a little.
It's nice having
a big, strong man around.
You know, those mailbags,
they get mighty heavy.
I...
I Nautilus, of course.
Can I have some gravy?
Steinbrenner had me committed!
I'm in the nuthouse.
I'll be back
same time next week, Pop.
They took my belt, Jerry.
I got nothing to hold my pants up.
You gotta come over here now!
Just tell him what we talked about,
how I didn't do the project.
George?
I see you're finally
getting some help.
Oh, Deena, thank God.
Thank God, you're here.
Listen, you gotta help me.
You gotta tell these people
that I'm okay.
You know
that I don't belong in here.
George, this is
the best thing for you.
What? No, no, Deena.
Deena, wait! Deena, help!
It's not what it looks like.
Is that little Georgie C?
How's the folks?
You still got that nice little car?
- What are you doing?
- Kramer, help me, help me!
I told you to keep away
from my daughter.
No, Daddy, you'll hurt him.
I love him.
Goodbye, Norman! Goodbye!
Elaine, you found the clubs.
That's wonderful news.
- Where are they?
- Yep.
Let me get them for you,
Mr. Peterman.
I'll be inaugurating them this weekend
with none other than Ethel Kennedy.
A woman whose triumph
in the face of tragedy...
...is exceeded only
by her proclivity to procreate.
The...
The letter of authenticity
is in the side pocket there.
Elaine.
I never knew Kennedy
had such a temper.
Oh, yeah.
The only thing worse was his slice.
- See you on Monday.
- Have a good game.