1
00:00:29,880 --> 00:00:32,590
Vast open plains.

2
00:00:33,880 --> 00:00:35,790
Immense spaces.

3
00:00:37,160 --> 00:00:38,630
Eerie silence.

4
00:00:41,760 --> 00:00:44,830
But any feeling of emptiness is an illusion.

5
00:00:48,640 --> 00:00:53,950
The plains of our planet support
the greatest gatherings of wildlife on Earth.

6
00:00:58,920 --> 00:01:03,590
At the heart of all that happens here
is a single living thing.

7
00:01:05,400 --> 00:01:06,590
Grass.

8
00:01:10,320 --> 00:01:15,750
This miraculous plant covers
a quarter of all the lands of the Earth.

9
00:01:30,720 --> 00:01:37,070
Grasslands exist wherever there is a little rain,
but not enough to sustain a forest.

10
00:01:38,000 --> 00:01:40,190
Some are huge.

11
00:01:40,320 --> 00:01:46,150
The Central Asian Steppe alone
extends one third of the way around our planet.

12
00:01:52,040 --> 00:01:56,230
It's summer,
and eagles effortlessly cruise the thermals,

13
00:01:56,320 --> 00:01:59,350
scanning the ground beneath for signs of prey.

14
00:02:02,240 --> 00:02:04,910
In the distant reaches of outer Mongolia,

15
00:02:05,000 --> 00:02:08,390
one of the planet's great migrations is underway.

16
00:02:15,040 --> 00:02:19,190
Few people ever see
this extraordinary annual event.

17
00:02:27,360 --> 00:02:29,590
Mongolian gazelle.

18
00:02:29,680 --> 00:02:33,870
Two million are thought to live here,
but no one really knows.

19
00:02:36,880 --> 00:02:40,750
For much of the time,
they're scattered through this vast landscape,

20
00:02:40,840 --> 00:02:44,310
but once a year they come together
to have their young.

21
00:02:46,080 --> 00:02:50,230
Nearly all will give birth within the next 10 days.

22
00:02:55,160 --> 00:02:59,710
Out in the open,
communal calving is the safest way to have young.

23
00:03:00,080 --> 00:03:02,350
With so many pairs of eyes keeping watch,

24
00:03:02,440 --> 00:03:05,510
it's almost impossible for predators to sneak up.

25
00:03:12,040 --> 00:03:16,670
There are no bushes, no trees.
There's only one thing to hide behind.

26
00:03:17,440 --> 00:03:18,630
Grass.

27
00:03:20,760 --> 00:03:22,950
And it's not very effective.

28
00:03:30,720 --> 00:03:35,310
Predators also have a hard time
raising their young on open grassland.

29
00:03:35,840 --> 00:03:39,950
Without trees,
eagles have to nest directly on the ground.

30
00:03:43,240 --> 00:03:47,350
All the inhabitants of the Great Plains
are exposed to the elements.

31
00:04:05,360 --> 00:04:08,470
Fire sparks panic in the herd.

32
00:04:15,160 --> 00:04:16,990
Gazelles are born to run

33
00:04:17,080 --> 00:04:20,670
and even young calves easily outpace the flames,

34
00:04:20,760 --> 00:04:23,150
if they can avoid being trampled.

35
00:04:56,680 --> 00:04:58,710
With nothing to stand in its way,

36
00:04:58,800 --> 00:05:01,870
the blaze consumes anything that can't flee.

37
00:05:03,360 --> 00:05:07,870
Huge quantities of grass, valuable food,
have been lost.

38
00:05:12,160 --> 00:05:14,590
And with it, the old and the weak.

39
00:05:20,560 --> 00:05:25,830
The gazelles move on to new pastures
and leave the desolation behind them.

40
00:05:29,560 --> 00:05:32,710
From the ashes rises the phoenix.

41
00:05:33,360 --> 00:05:36,590
Grass, the incredible survivor.

42
00:05:39,480 --> 00:05:43,590
Because it grows from a protected part
at the base of its stems,

43
00:05:43,680 --> 00:05:46,030
grass is almost indestructible.

44
00:05:57,680 --> 00:06:00,710
Able to repair and reproduce itself rapidly,

45
00:06:00,800 --> 00:06:04,590
it covers more of the Earth's land
than any other plant

46
00:06:04,680 --> 00:06:07,390
and feeds more wildlife than any other.

47
00:06:27,840 --> 00:06:29,710
Red-billed quelea.

48
00:06:30,120 --> 00:06:33,870
One and a half billion
swarm across the savannahs of Africa.

49
00:06:34,440 --> 00:06:38,390
These are the most numerous birds on Earth.

50
00:06:42,560 --> 00:06:44,830
Some flocks are so vast

51
00:06:44,920 --> 00:06:48,430
that they can take five hours to pass overhead.

52
00:07:20,920 --> 00:07:24,870
Only grass can feed plagues of these proportions.

53
00:07:25,760 --> 00:07:28,750
The ravenous hordes devour the seeds.

54
00:07:29,920 --> 00:07:34,350
And the leaves and stems are cropped
by great herds of antelope.

55
00:07:45,480 --> 00:07:50,670
The East African savannahs alone
sustain nearly two million wildebeest.

56
00:08:03,280 --> 00:08:07,630
They trim the grass down to its roots,
leaving little in their wake,

57
00:08:07,720 --> 00:08:10,670
but within days the plant will recover

58
00:08:10,760 --> 00:08:14,190
and continue to sustain
the biggest herds on Earth.

59
00:08:25,880 --> 00:08:28,910
Grass is not confined to the tropics.

60
00:08:33,600 --> 00:08:38,070
It manages to grow
even in the bitter conditions of the Arctic.

61
00:08:46,040 --> 00:08:51,590
Beyond the limits of the last tree,
the planet is barren and ice-locked.

62
00:08:52,160 --> 00:08:55,550
A frozen no-man's land at the end of the Earth.

63
00:08:56,560 --> 00:09:02,710
But for a short time each year,
the long, dark winter releases its grip.

64
00:09:14,160 --> 00:09:15,710
Temperatures rise

65
00:09:15,840 --> 00:09:21,030
and grass that has lain dormant and frozen
throughout the winter sprouts once more.

66
00:09:26,520 --> 00:09:28,990
Green returns to the Arctic.

67
00:09:30,760 --> 00:09:35,990
The receding ice reveals
an immense flat plain the size of Australia.

68
00:09:36,440 --> 00:09:39,030
This is the Arctic tundra.

69
00:09:45,720 --> 00:09:48,470
It's a desolate, silent wilderness.

70
00:09:49,080 --> 00:09:51,070
But it's about to change.

71
00:10:07,840 --> 00:10:09,390
Snow geese.

72
00:10:11,640 --> 00:10:14,190
They winter along the Gulf of Mexico,

73
00:10:14,280 --> 00:10:17,870
and in spring they fly
the entire length of North America

74
00:10:17,960 --> 00:10:20,070
to reach the Arctic tundra.

75
00:10:21,720 --> 00:10:25,350
Five million birds make this journey every year.

76
00:10:41,920 --> 00:10:46,230
Their marathon migration
is almost 3, 000 miles long

77
00:10:46,320 --> 00:10:48,430
and has taken them three months.

78
00:10:55,320 --> 00:11:00,310
Exhausted and starving,
they touch down inside the Arctic Circle,

79
00:11:00,400 --> 00:11:03,990
back at their traditional breeding grounds at last.

80
00:11:06,000 --> 00:11:07,990
Snow geese pair for life.

81
00:11:08,400 --> 00:11:13,150
As soon as couples arrive,
they must stake a claim to a nesting patch.

82
00:11:17,200 --> 00:11:22,470
Ideal sites are in short supply
and quarrelsome neighbours are all around.

83
00:11:26,320 --> 00:11:28,270
Disputes can be vicious.

84
00:12:01,840 --> 00:12:03,430
Point taken!

85
00:12:05,760 --> 00:12:12,230
It's a long way to travel, but for a short period,
the tundra is the ideal place for a grazer.

86
00:12:12,320 --> 00:12:15,910
The grass grows vigorously
during the short, intense summer

87
00:12:16,000 --> 00:12:19,190
and there are fewer predators than further south.

88
00:12:23,160 --> 00:12:26,870
Here, geese can nest on the ground
in relative safety.

89
00:12:27,400 --> 00:12:31,470
Nonetheless, this female must incubate
her eggs for three weeks

90
00:12:31,560 --> 00:12:34,910
and throughout this time
she will be very vulnerable.

91
00:12:48,880 --> 00:12:51,750
An Arctic fox surveys the colony.

92
00:12:51,840 --> 00:12:54,790
She's been waiting for the geese all winter.

93
00:13:00,120 --> 00:13:02,830
Sneaking up unnoticed is impossible.

94
00:13:12,920 --> 00:13:15,630
Perhaps fortune will favour the bold.

95
00:13:30,520 --> 00:13:34,790
The colony is well-defended.
There are no easy pickings here.

96
00:13:46,080 --> 00:13:50,950
She's driven away from every nest,
but hunger compels her to continue.

97
00:14:18,880 --> 00:14:22,630
There are more eggs here
than she can possibly eat now.

98
00:14:22,720 --> 00:14:25,030
But the nesting season is short.

99
00:14:25,120 --> 00:14:28,470
So she stashes much of her plunder
for later in the year

100
00:14:28,560 --> 00:14:30,750
when all the geese have gone.

101
00:14:42,400 --> 00:14:46,590
Further south,
other bigger predators prowl the tundra.

102
00:14:49,240 --> 00:14:50,470
Wolves.

103
00:14:50,560 --> 00:14:54,750
For them, finding food on the plains
is an even greater challenge.

104
00:14:55,200 --> 00:14:58,910
Not only is their prey seasonal,
it's also hard to find.

105
00:14:59,000 --> 00:15:02,110
They've been searching for days without a sign.

106
00:15:09,040 --> 00:15:13,590
Somewhere in this immense landscape
there is food for them.

107
00:15:20,600 --> 00:15:22,870
This is it. Caribou.

108
00:15:25,280 --> 00:15:27,390
Travelling 30 miles a day,

109
00:15:27,480 --> 00:15:31,750
they can cover nearly 2, 000 miles
during the summer months.

110
00:15:39,720 --> 00:15:43,270
The wolves will starve
if they don't find the caribou.

111
00:15:43,360 --> 00:15:47,750
But it's no easy task to locate prey
that never stops travelling.

112
00:16:08,320 --> 00:16:14,030
Biting flies and the quest for new pasture
drives the migration ever onwards.

113
00:16:49,800 --> 00:16:52,510
A wolf has finally picked up the trail.

114
00:16:54,560 --> 00:16:56,430
The caribou are close.

115
00:17:01,160 --> 00:17:02,910
At last, a chance.

116
00:17:06,480 --> 00:17:07,990
The hunt is on.

117
00:17:19,240 --> 00:17:23,350
The wolf panics the herd,
and the weak and young are singled out.

118
00:17:32,280 --> 00:17:34,790
A calf is separated from its mother.

119
00:18:11,600 --> 00:18:15,950
At the goose colony,
it's high summer and eggs are hatching.

120
00:18:18,600 --> 00:18:22,790
The young all emerge within a day or two,
a marvel of timing.

121
00:18:23,080 --> 00:18:26,590
The colony is now home to a million goslings.

122
00:18:42,840 --> 00:18:45,790
The fox is still gathering all she can get.

123
00:18:50,880 --> 00:18:54,550
Sometimes one mouth simply isn't enough.

124
00:19:28,960 --> 00:19:30,830
One will have to do.

125
00:19:37,200 --> 00:19:41,190
Not all food is stored. Some is needed right now.

126
00:19:43,280 --> 00:19:45,990
She has seven hungry cubs to feed.

127
00:19:52,640 --> 00:19:57,430
As their appetites grow, the mother
must work tirelessly to raise her family.

128
00:19:57,520 --> 00:20:01,190
Only fat, healthy cubs
will survive the Arctic winter.

129
00:20:17,160 --> 00:20:20,670
The vast majority of the goslings
are still flourishing.

130
00:20:21,160 --> 00:20:24,030
Their parents lead them
down to the safety of the water

131
00:20:24,120 --> 00:20:27,470
as soon as they're strong enough
to make the journey.

132
00:20:32,720 --> 00:20:36,310
For the foxes, boom time has come to an end.

133
00:20:36,760 --> 00:20:41,150
But the mother has given her cubs
the best possible start in life.

134
00:20:43,880 --> 00:20:46,270
The geese will continue grazing the tundra

135
00:20:46,400 --> 00:20:50,710
until the summer ends
and they're forced to head south for the winter.

136
00:20:58,920 --> 00:21:01,870
At these latitudes, the sun's rays are weak

137
00:21:01,960 --> 00:21:05,350
and grass can only grow here
for a few months a year.

138
00:21:05,480 --> 00:21:10,350
But further south,
summers are longer and the grasslands flourish.

139
00:21:24,920 --> 00:21:27,150
The prairies of North America.

140
00:21:29,560 --> 00:21:35,190
This rich pasture once supported
the greatest herds ever seen on our planet.

141
00:21:45,240 --> 00:21:48,030
There were once 60 million bison,

142
00:21:48,120 --> 00:21:51,590
but no animal is immune
to intensive hunting by man

143
00:21:51,680 --> 00:21:54,230
or the destruction of its habitat.

144
00:21:54,320 --> 00:21:58,790
And a century ago,
the bison were reduced to barely 1, 000.

145
00:21:59,800 --> 00:22:04,510
Now, thanks to rigorous protection,
the species is recovering.

146
00:22:09,720 --> 00:22:11,670
The growing season is long,

147
00:22:11,760 --> 00:22:15,110
and the grass here
can support herds all year round.

148
00:22:21,320 --> 00:22:24,710
Male bison weigh in at one ton.

149
00:22:40,360 --> 00:22:43,670
In high summer,
the bulls are fat from the rich grazing

150
00:22:43,760 --> 00:22:47,270
and in prime condition, but only a few will mate.

151
00:22:47,360 --> 00:22:50,590
Exactly which few is about to be decided.

152
00:23:21,880 --> 00:23:27,990
On temperate plains around the world,
summer is a time for growth and reproduction.

153
00:23:31,040 --> 00:23:33,990
Now the grass produces its flowers.

154
00:23:46,680 --> 00:23:49,950
New colours also come to the plains.

155
00:24:26,280 --> 00:24:31,950
The northern flowering is mirrored
by the grasslands of the southern hemisphere,

156
00:24:32,040 --> 00:24:36,630
and nowhere is more impressive
than on the veldt of South Africa.

157
00:25:23,400 --> 00:25:28,670
Not all temperate plains
are so rich and colourful in the summer.

158
00:25:35,920 --> 00:25:39,550
This is midsummer on the Tibetan plateau,

159
00:25:39,640 --> 00:25:42,310
the highest great plain in the world.

160
00:25:43,920 --> 00:25:46,550
Despite the conditions, grass survives

161
00:25:46,680 --> 00:25:51,910
and in sufficient quantities
to support the highest of all grazing herds,

162
00:25:52,000 --> 00:25:53,910
those of the wild yak.

163
00:25:57,320 --> 00:25:59,550
Even in summer, life is hard.

164
00:26:00,080 --> 00:26:04,230
Temperatures rarely rise above freezing
and the air is thin.

165
00:26:11,240 --> 00:26:15,950
It's also exceptionally dry for one very big reason,

166
00:26:19,560 --> 00:26:21,030
the Himalayas.

167
00:26:23,520 --> 00:26:29,350
The great mountain range acts as a barrier,
preventing clouds moving in from the south,

168
00:26:29,440 --> 00:26:34,790
and this casts a giant rain shadow
that leaves Tibet high and dry.

169
00:26:53,280 --> 00:26:55,430
Grass clings to life

170
00:26:55,520 --> 00:27:00,710
even as desiccating winds remove
what little moisture remains in the soil.

171
00:27:10,240 --> 00:27:14,150
So long as grass can survive, so can grazers.

172
00:27:19,600 --> 00:27:20,910
Wild ass.

173
00:27:30,000 --> 00:27:32,750
The males are fighting to win territories.

174
00:27:32,880 --> 00:27:37,350
Those that hold the best
are more likely to attract a herd of females.

175
00:27:53,480 --> 00:27:55,910
It's a frisky business.

176
00:28:00,720 --> 00:28:02,590
That counts as a victory,

177
00:28:02,680 --> 00:28:06,110
but he can't assume
the females will actually turn up.

178
00:28:11,080 --> 00:28:14,390
Female asses are mysterious creatures.

179
00:28:17,120 --> 00:28:18,910
They come and go as they please

180
00:28:19,000 --> 00:28:23,590
and much of their behaviour
seems unfathomable to an outsider.

181
00:28:35,280 --> 00:28:37,870
They're the great nomads of the plateau

182
00:28:37,960 --> 00:28:42,070
and will often trek vast distances
across these parched plains

183
00:28:42,160 --> 00:28:44,110
in search of oases.

184
00:28:45,800 --> 00:28:48,070
But when they do find paradise,

185
00:28:48,160 --> 00:28:51,470
they are liable to feed and drink
for just a few hours

186
00:28:51,560 --> 00:28:55,190
and then head back to the dust
for no apparent reason.

187
00:29:00,240 --> 00:29:05,270
Wild ass are the most conspicuous pioneers
of this high frontier,

188
00:29:05,360 --> 00:29:09,430
but the most numerous grazer in Tibet
lives underground.

189
00:29:13,280 --> 00:29:18,030
Pika, a relative of the rabbit.
It, too, feeds on grass.

190
00:29:24,040 --> 00:29:28,910
On the exposed plateau,
pikas never stray far from their burrows.

191
00:29:29,000 --> 00:29:33,550
But even so, squatters will move in
given half a chance.

192
00:29:46,600 --> 00:29:50,350
While ground peckers and snow finches
can be a nuisance,

193
00:29:50,480 --> 00:29:55,190
they're worth tolerating because they provide
a valuable early warning system.

194
00:30:09,000 --> 00:30:13,070
The bizarre Tibetan fox. The pika's nemesis.

195
00:30:36,840 --> 00:30:40,590
When stalking, it keeps below the skyline,

196
00:30:40,680 --> 00:30:43,670
perhaps helped by its curious body shape.

197
00:30:44,880 --> 00:30:46,870
But why the square head?

198
00:31:38,720 --> 00:31:42,030
In summer, the Tibetan plateau heats up,

199
00:31:42,120 --> 00:31:45,270
drawing in warm, wet air from the south.

200
00:31:45,360 --> 00:31:47,990
But the water never arrives.

201
00:31:48,080 --> 00:31:52,270
As the moist air approaches,
it's forced upwards by the Himalayas

202
00:31:52,360 --> 00:31:55,510
and condenses into huge rain clouds.

203
00:32:10,080 --> 00:32:15,230
These clouds drop all their water
on the southern side of the mountains.

204
00:32:15,320 --> 00:32:17,910
The very peaks that keep Tibet dry

205
00:32:18,000 --> 00:32:21,750
are responsible for the monsoon rains
falling farther south

206
00:32:21,840 --> 00:32:23,870
and the greening of India.

207
00:32:34,080 --> 00:32:37,710
Here, soaked by rain and bathed in tropical sun,

208
00:32:37,800 --> 00:32:40,590
grass reaches its full potential.

209
00:32:43,280 --> 00:32:46,470
Elephant grass is the tallest in the world.

210
00:32:59,000 --> 00:33:04,310
Grass that towers over an elephant
can conceal all sorts of surprises.

211
00:33:13,400 --> 00:33:15,390
The male Lesser Florican.

212
00:33:15,880 --> 00:33:20,870
It's hard work getting noticed
when you go courting in high grass.

213
00:33:34,280 --> 00:33:36,750
The long-grass plains of tropical India

214
00:33:36,840 --> 00:33:40,990
are home to some of the largest
grass-eating mammals on our planet.

215
00:33:41,480 --> 00:33:43,750
And some of the smallest.

216
00:33:45,920 --> 00:33:48,750
Pygmy hogs are no bigger than rabbits.

217
00:33:48,840 --> 00:33:52,510
They're the tiniest and rarest of all wild pigs.

218
00:33:57,600 --> 00:34:01,950
The female is busy collecting grass,
but not for eating.

219
00:34:10,080 --> 00:34:11,910
She's building a nest.

220
00:34:26,320 --> 00:34:30,590
Each piglet may be small enough
to fit in the palm of a hand,

221
00:34:30,680 --> 00:34:32,590
but she does have 10.

222
00:34:46,480 --> 00:34:51,510
This is how grass can grow,
given unlimited sunshine and water.

223
00:34:52,400 --> 00:34:55,390
But on most tropical plains across our planet,

224
00:34:55,480 --> 00:34:58,350
the wet season is followed by a dry one.

225
00:35:08,360 --> 00:35:10,190
On the African savannahs,

226
00:35:10,280 --> 00:35:13,950
grazers are marching in search of grass and water.

227
00:35:35,160 --> 00:35:39,110
Without rain, these plains can become dust bowls.

228
00:35:39,200 --> 00:35:41,670
Grass can now lose its hold.

229
00:35:51,680 --> 00:35:54,430
Elephants are in immediate danger.

230
00:35:54,520 --> 00:35:57,150
They must drink almost daily.

231
00:36:02,680 --> 00:36:04,150
Driven on by thirst,

232
00:36:04,240 --> 00:36:08,030
they march hundreds of miles
across the parched plains.

233
00:36:26,280 --> 00:36:30,390
Relying on memory,
the matriarchs lead their families

234
00:36:30,480 --> 00:36:34,950
to those special water holes
that saved them in previous years.

235
00:36:41,800 --> 00:36:46,070
This one still has water,
but they must share what remains

236
00:36:46,160 --> 00:36:49,870
with desperately thirsty animals of all kinds.

237
00:37:07,040 --> 00:37:09,630
These are tense times.

238
00:37:25,760 --> 00:37:28,510
The elephants dominate the water hole,

239
00:37:28,600 --> 00:37:32,150
but as night falls the balance of power will shift.

240
00:37:45,760 --> 00:37:49,910
Thirsty herds continue to arrive
throughout the night.

241
00:37:50,000 --> 00:37:52,230
It's a cooler time to travel.

242
00:38:12,680 --> 00:38:15,270
In the darkness, the tables turn.

243
00:38:19,440 --> 00:38:23,070
The elephant's night vision
is little better than our own.

244
00:38:26,440 --> 00:38:29,990
But lions have much more sensitive eyes.

245
00:38:43,120 --> 00:38:46,630
The cats are hungry
and the elephants seem to sense it.

246
00:39:26,840 --> 00:39:29,790
Lions don't usually hunt elephants,

247
00:39:29,880 --> 00:39:33,630
but desperate times require desperate measures.

248
00:39:34,720 --> 00:39:38,670
This herd contains calves, easier targets.

249
00:39:43,240 --> 00:39:45,470
But how to reach them?

250
00:40:00,360 --> 00:40:02,830
The adults encircle their young.

251
00:40:02,920 --> 00:40:05,790
It's an impenetrable wall of grey.

252
00:40:33,520 --> 00:40:37,670
A few exhausted stragglers are still arriving.

253
00:40:41,160 --> 00:40:43,270
One of them is alone.

254
00:41:03,320 --> 00:41:06,790
But it's too big for the lions to tackle.

255
00:41:11,880 --> 00:41:14,510
This one looks a little smaller.

256
00:41:27,440 --> 00:41:31,270
A solitary lion stands no chance,

257
00:41:31,360 --> 00:41:33,310
but the whole pride is here.

258
00:41:37,360 --> 00:41:41,310
There are 30 of them
and they are specialist elephant hunters.

259
00:42:47,200 --> 00:42:52,150
This elephant will feed the whole pride
for at least a week.

260
00:43:01,840 --> 00:43:05,590
Elephants know
these drinking holes are dangerous,

261
00:43:05,680 --> 00:43:08,110
but they have no choice.

262
00:43:08,200 --> 00:43:12,070
The dramas that play out here
are a savage reminder

263
00:43:12,160 --> 00:43:16,670
of how important water is
for all life on these plains.

264
00:43:25,600 --> 00:43:28,870
As the dry season finally draws to a close,

265
00:43:28,960 --> 00:43:33,270
Africa's baked savannahs
undergo a radical change.

266
00:43:35,600 --> 00:43:38,470
Rain sweeps across the continent

267
00:43:38,560 --> 00:43:41,910
and grass, the great survivor, rises again.

268
00:43:42,840 --> 00:43:44,670
And the herds return.

269
00:43:47,680 --> 00:43:50,870
For months they've been scattered
over huge areas,

270
00:43:50,960 --> 00:43:54,470
clinging to existence around tiny water holes.

271
00:43:55,120 --> 00:43:57,990
Now, the good times are back.

272
00:44:03,880 --> 00:44:07,150
A few African savannahs are very special.

273
00:44:07,880 --> 00:44:13,190
Here, rainwater from far and wide
flows across the flat plains.

274
00:44:14,000 --> 00:44:17,750
Grass is submerged, but still it grows.

275
00:44:38,120 --> 00:44:44,390
Flooded, burnt, baked and frozen,
grass can withstand it all.

276
00:44:49,720 --> 00:44:51,790
After six months of drought,

277
00:44:51,880 --> 00:44:55,310
grass replaces dust over great areas.

278
00:45:06,120 --> 00:45:10,070
Fresh new shoots draw animals
from great distances.

279
00:45:22,040 --> 00:45:26,510
Many undertake epic migrations
to catch the boom time.

280
00:45:34,560 --> 00:45:38,790
Some resourceful animals live here
all the year round.

281
00:45:46,480 --> 00:45:50,990
Baboons are permanent residents,
but they have to change their behaviour

282
00:45:51,080 --> 00:45:55,110
if they are to gather what they need
on the newly flooded plains.

283
00:46:00,160 --> 00:46:01,830
There's plenty to eat,

284
00:46:01,920 --> 00:46:05,510
but getting to it can be a little uncomfortable.

285
00:46:54,520 --> 00:46:58,390
New water poses problems for the youngsters,

286
00:46:58,480 --> 00:47:01,150
but they know where to find a dry seat.

287
00:47:10,880 --> 00:47:15,670
A juicy snail is ample recompense
for sodden paws.

288
00:47:26,920 --> 00:47:30,030
Having survived the dry, barren times,

289
00:47:30,120 --> 00:47:32,990
animals can now reap the rewards.

290
00:47:39,400 --> 00:47:41,230
On this seasonal planet,

291
00:47:41,320 --> 00:47:44,910
the great plains are lands of feast and famine.

292
00:47:46,320 --> 00:47:52,510
At their peak, they support the greatest
gatherings of wildlife found anywhere on Earth.

