1
00:00:33,880 --> 00:00:39,350
This is our planet's hothouse,
the jungle, the tropical rainforest.

2
00:00:42,040 --> 00:00:45,710
Forests like these occupy only 3% of the land

3
00:00:45,800 --> 00:00:49,590
yet they're home
to over half of the world's species.

4
00:00:51,200 --> 00:00:54,750
But how do so many different kinds
of plants and animals

5
00:00:54,840 --> 00:00:58,110
find the space here to live alongside one another?

6
00:01:10,400 --> 00:01:15,230
On the dark, humid forest floor,
the jungle appears to be lifeless.

7
00:01:17,200 --> 00:01:20,710
Often, the only signs of life are what you hear.

8
00:01:27,400 --> 00:01:31,550
A male Blue Bird of Paradise
is advertising for a mate.

9
00:01:33,920 --> 00:01:35,350
It's quite a performance.

10
00:01:35,480 --> 00:01:40,190
But he's not the only bird of paradise here
keen to make an impression.

11
00:01:41,680 --> 00:01:45,350
There are nearly 40 different kinds
on the island of New Guinea,

12
00:01:45,440 --> 00:01:49,390
each with a display
seemingly more bizarre than the rest.

13
00:01:58,000 --> 00:02:00,590
A Rifle Bird of Paradise.

14
00:02:10,360 --> 00:02:15,310
Like many jungle animals, birds of paradise
avoid competing with each other.

15
00:02:15,440 --> 00:02:20,270
And these do so by living in different parts
of this jungle-covered island.

16
00:02:26,160 --> 00:02:32,030
The Six-Plumed Bird of Paradise
displays in his special clearing on the forest floor.

17
00:02:39,200 --> 00:02:44,110
The Magnificent Bird of Paradise
favours the low branches of bushes.

18
00:02:47,920 --> 00:02:51,030
His female is modestly dressed.

19
00:03:02,880 --> 00:03:05,190
The male has a good set of lungs,

20
00:03:05,320 --> 00:03:10,070
but he'll have to do more than flutter his eyelids
if he wants to impress her.

21
00:03:16,520 --> 00:03:19,150
It'll all depend on his performance.

22
00:03:23,960 --> 00:03:27,510
The females may be dull-looking
but they're very picky.

23
00:03:29,600 --> 00:03:32,550
And it's time for a really close inspection.

24
00:03:38,360 --> 00:03:41,830
His right side looks fine, but what about his left?

25
00:03:46,840 --> 00:03:50,750
Pretty impressive, but is he magnificent enough?

26
00:03:53,080 --> 00:03:56,030
Oh, dear! Her departure says it all.

27
00:03:56,920 --> 00:04:03,310
Generations of choosy females have driven
the evolution of these remarkable displays.

28
00:04:04,240 --> 00:04:08,510
The more extravagant a male is,
the more likely he will be noticed.

29
00:04:33,560 --> 00:04:39,470
New Guinea lies in a warm tropical belt
that girdles our planet around the equator.

30
00:04:40,200 --> 00:04:45,790
With abundant rainfall
and 12 hours of daylight 365 days a year,

31
00:04:45,880 --> 00:04:48,990
it's here that rainforests flourish.

32
00:04:54,400 --> 00:05:00,110
Surprisingly, only 2% of the sunlight
filters down to the forest floor.

33
00:05:02,320 --> 00:05:05,710
Down here, seedlings struggle to grow.

34
00:05:06,720 --> 00:05:09,150
But the gloom is not eternal.

35
00:05:41,840 --> 00:05:45,830
The death of a forest giant is always saddening.

36
00:05:45,920 --> 00:05:49,870
But it has to happen
if the forest is to remain healthy.

37
00:05:51,760 --> 00:05:56,790
The sudden blaze of sunlight
will bring life to the forest floor.

38
00:06:00,720 --> 00:06:06,790
A single hectare of rainforest
may contain as many as 250 species of tree.

39
00:06:06,880 --> 00:06:10,230
That's nearly 10 times the number
that grow in Britain.

40
00:06:10,320 --> 00:06:14,830
And the thirst for light triggers a race
for a place in the sun.

41
00:06:30,440 --> 00:06:32,190
There's no time to waste.

42
00:06:32,320 --> 00:06:38,030
A seed that may have fallen only a few days ago
now bursts through the leaf litter.

43
00:06:52,240 --> 00:06:57,030
With so many competitors,
getting a good start is critical.

44
00:06:59,280 --> 00:07:06,270
But each plant has its own particular strategy
for making the most of this rare opportunity.

45
00:07:07,480 --> 00:07:10,190
The seeds of hardwoods are quick to germinate.

46
00:07:10,280 --> 00:07:15,190
But like the fabled tortoise,
their strategy is to be slow and steady.

47
00:07:19,960 --> 00:07:27,110
Vines and other climbers put all their energy
into rapid vertical growth rather than girth,

48
00:07:27,200 --> 00:07:30,110
though they'll need to be well-supported.

49
00:07:35,800 --> 00:07:40,270
The climber's strategy looks chaotic
but there's method in their madness.

50
00:07:40,400 --> 00:07:46,270
Their growing tips circle like lassoes
searching out anchors for their spindly stems.

51
00:07:53,160 --> 00:07:55,350
They put coils in their tendrils

52
00:07:55,440 --> 00:07:59,670
so that if their support moves,
they will stretch and not snap.

53
00:08:02,240 --> 00:08:06,230
But the frontrunners at this stage,
the first to fill the clearing,

54
00:08:06,320 --> 00:08:08,950
are pioneers like the Macarangas.

55
00:08:10,280 --> 00:08:13,910
Their immense leaves
capture huge amounts of sunlight,

56
00:08:14,000 --> 00:08:16,070
so fuelling their growth.

57
00:08:22,280 --> 00:08:26,590
As a result, the Macarangas
grow a remarkable eight metres a year,

58
00:08:26,680 --> 00:08:29,670
surging ahead of almost all their rivals.

59
00:08:42,400 --> 00:08:46,070
In the race for the top spot, hundreds will start

60
00:08:46,160 --> 00:08:48,710
yet few will ever reach the finishing line,

61
00:08:48,800 --> 00:08:52,230
their growth cut short by the diminishing light.

62
00:08:55,240 --> 00:08:59,190
In less than four years the gap will have gone,

63
00:08:59,280 --> 00:09:01,990
but that's not the end of the race.

64
00:09:10,840 --> 00:09:16,470
The ultimate winners are the tortoises,
the slow and steady hardwoods.

65
00:09:18,760 --> 00:09:25,030
When the short-lived pioneers have fallen,
it's the hardwoods that take their place.

66
00:09:25,120 --> 00:09:27,750
And a 50-metre giant like this one

67
00:09:27,840 --> 00:09:32,350
may keep its place in the sun
for another 200 years.

68
00:10:08,480 --> 00:10:12,830
At the top is the canopy,
the engine room of the jungle.

69
00:10:12,920 --> 00:10:17,790
It's up here that most of the animal life
in a rainforest can be found.

70
00:10:19,240 --> 00:10:23,430
But despite the apparent abundance
of vegetable food,

71
00:10:23,520 --> 00:10:26,030
gathering it is seldom easy.

72
00:10:39,520 --> 00:10:45,830
With no real seasons, each tree flowers or fruits
at a different time of the year,

73
00:10:45,920 --> 00:10:49,390
which means that food is very widely spaced.

74
00:10:54,880 --> 00:10:56,870
Monkeys, like these tamarins,

75
00:10:57,000 --> 00:11:01,510
must search the canopy for all kinds of food
if they're to survive.

76
00:11:04,600 --> 00:11:07,270
But across the world's rainforests,

77
00:11:07,360 --> 00:11:11,350
there's one type of fruiting tree
that always delivers.

78
00:11:11,840 --> 00:11:13,070
The fig.

79
00:11:22,320 --> 00:11:28,190
Wherever they grow, figs are a magnet
for a great diversity of animals.

80
00:11:30,640 --> 00:11:34,910
In the Amazon,
the first to appear are the spider monkeys.

81
00:11:36,520 --> 00:11:39,670
These large primates are big fig-eaters.

82
00:11:39,760 --> 00:11:42,470
But they won't have the tree
to themselves for long.

83
00:11:42,560 --> 00:11:44,550
Others will want a share.

84
00:11:46,040 --> 00:11:48,870
Like the diminutive Emperor tamarins.

85
00:11:52,480 --> 00:11:57,950
The tamarins love figs, too,
but being petite means they're easily scared off.

86
00:12:08,280 --> 00:12:12,710
Squirrel monkeys are also small,
but they have strength in numbers.

87
00:12:15,560 --> 00:12:21,070
Their time-share on the tree may be short
so their tactics are more smash-and-grab.

88
00:12:30,120 --> 00:12:33,430
Capuchin Monkeys are the bully boys
in these forests

89
00:12:33,520 --> 00:12:36,190
and they want the ripe figs for themselves.

90
00:12:53,640 --> 00:12:57,990
Figs are one of the few trees
that fruit the year round.

91
00:12:58,080 --> 00:13:00,390
So when other food is scarce,

92
00:13:00,480 --> 00:13:04,070
these fruits are always available
somewhere or other.

93
00:13:08,400 --> 00:13:14,030
Even for leaf-eaters like howler monkeys,
the ripe figs are just too good to miss.

94
00:13:20,000 --> 00:13:24,270
And howlers are too big
for the capuchins to chase off.

95
00:13:28,280 --> 00:13:33,670
Figs are so popular that as many as
44 different kinds of bird and monkey

96
00:13:33,760 --> 00:13:37,790
have been seen working a shift system
on a single tree.

97
00:13:46,840 --> 00:13:52,470
Because fruiting trees are so valuable,
many monkeys are territorial.

98
00:13:52,600 --> 00:13:54,430
And if you live in the treetops,

99
00:13:54,560 --> 00:13:58,950
there's perhaps no better way
of staking your claim to a territory than this.

100
00:14:05,400 --> 00:14:11,510
The calls of the Siamang gibbons begin as a duet
between the dominant male and female.

101
00:14:24,000 --> 00:14:29,270
The rest of their family soon join in
and it results in a frenzy of activity.

102
00:14:38,280 --> 00:14:43,070
The calls can carry over a mile
and their message is clear.

103
00:14:48,240 --> 00:14:53,350
They tell any neighbouring Siamangs,
"This is our territory, keep out."

104
00:15:03,320 --> 00:15:08,190
Up here, the calls of Siamang gibbons
seem to dominate the airwaves.

105
00:15:08,760 --> 00:15:14,510
But with the jungle's incredible diversity,
there are countless others trying to be heard, too.

106
00:15:20,760 --> 00:15:24,670
Every layer seems to beat to a different tune.

107
00:15:41,920 --> 00:15:46,510
In the early morning,
the forest's chorus is particularly rich.

108
00:15:46,600 --> 00:15:49,230
Sounds travel further in the cooler air.

109
00:15:53,920 --> 00:16:00,030
But few calls can penetrate
as far through the dense vegetation as this one,

110
00:16:00,120 --> 00:16:04,030
the deep bass solo of a male orang-utan.

111
00:16:19,360 --> 00:16:22,750
In the middle of the day, little stirs in the jungle

112
00:16:22,840 --> 00:16:26,110
and the hot, dense air muffles the sound.

113
00:16:29,680 --> 00:16:34,590
As the afternoon wears on,
a different set of players begin to warm up.

114
00:16:37,160 --> 00:16:42,310
Insects work in harmony, timing their calls
to fall between the notes of others.

115
00:16:50,720 --> 00:16:53,870
Many singers stick to precise schedules.

116
00:16:53,960 --> 00:16:57,110
And right on cue, the 6:00 cicada.

117
00:17:09,560 --> 00:17:13,230
Night brings out a whole new orchestra.

118
00:17:36,960 --> 00:17:41,510
The cacophony of competing calls
seems deafening to us,

119
00:17:41,600 --> 00:17:46,590
but frogs' ears are tuned to hear
only the calls of their own kind.

120
00:17:54,240 --> 00:17:58,030
The songs of courtship echo from all around.

121
00:18:10,640 --> 00:18:15,510
Male gliding leaf frogs leap from the treetops.

122
00:18:49,520 --> 00:18:55,310
To slow their descent,
they use their huge webbed feet as parachutes.

123
00:19:00,280 --> 00:19:05,070
These large tree frogs spend most of their lives
in the high canopy

124
00:19:05,160 --> 00:19:08,190
and only come down when it's time to breed.

125
00:19:13,840 --> 00:19:18,750
Once settled,
they begin to serenade their unseen females.

126
00:19:30,200 --> 00:19:34,310
Now it's time for the females to make their move.

127
00:19:38,720 --> 00:19:43,630
There's no shortage of suitors,
but this female has already made her choice.

128
00:19:43,720 --> 00:19:49,710
She's heading towards the loudest call
because loud calls come from big frogs,

129
00:19:49,800 --> 00:19:51,630
and big is best.

130
00:19:52,560 --> 00:19:57,790
But to reach him she must run the gauntlet
of a gang of smaller suitors.

131
00:19:57,880 --> 00:20:02,190
Their only chance of mating
is to make a sneaky interception.

132
00:20:07,760 --> 00:20:09,270
He scored.

133
00:20:09,400 --> 00:20:15,550
But with more females arriving all the time,
it's not over until the fat frog stops singing.

134
00:20:22,400 --> 00:20:27,110
Feet, so vital for gliding,
are now put to other uses.

135
00:20:32,520 --> 00:20:36,950
Two's company, three is inconvenient.

136
00:20:37,080 --> 00:20:41,630
But in any case,
all male frogs are equipped with dry thumbs,

137
00:20:41,720 --> 00:20:46,190
which enable them to get a vice-like grip
on their moist partners.

138
00:20:47,600 --> 00:20:51,230
It's a case of first come, first served.

139
00:20:59,240 --> 00:21:05,870
Living in such a humid environment means
jungle frogs are less tied to puddles and pools.

140
00:21:05,960 --> 00:21:09,110
And these even lay their eggs out of water.

141
00:21:18,840 --> 00:21:24,430
There's little chance of them drying out,
and up here they're safer from predators.

142
00:21:32,360 --> 00:21:36,510
Surprisingly, it doesn't rain every day
in a rainforest,

143
00:21:37,640 --> 00:21:41,590
but more still falls here
than anywhere else on Earth.

144
00:21:41,680 --> 00:21:44,670
On average, over two metres a year.

145
00:21:54,400 --> 00:21:59,470
A single tree can suck up
hundreds of tons of water each year.

146
00:22:02,480 --> 00:22:04,870
But the trees can't use all this water,

147
00:22:04,960 --> 00:22:10,590
so much of it returns to the air as vapour,
forming mist and clouds.

148
00:22:16,320 --> 00:22:21,150
In the Amazon, the largest unbroken stretch
of rainforest in the world,

149
00:22:21,240 --> 00:22:23,910
half of all the rainwater that falls

150
00:22:24,000 --> 00:22:27,470
comes from clouds
produced by the trees themselves.

151
00:22:59,240 --> 00:23:01,030
With so much rain,

152
00:23:01,160 --> 00:23:06,630
it's not surprising that many of the world's
largest rivers are found in rainforests.

153
00:23:22,040 --> 00:23:27,150
Inside the forest, the high humidity
creates the perfect conditions

154
00:23:27,240 --> 00:23:31,630
for a strange world where life is built on decay.

155
00:23:44,280 --> 00:23:48,510
Amoeba-like slime moulds cruise the surface,

156
00:23:48,600 --> 00:23:52,070
feeding on bacteria and rotting vegetation.

157
00:24:08,000 --> 00:24:11,510
Fungi also flourish on decay.

158
00:24:13,280 --> 00:24:16,470
These are the fruiting bodies of the fungi,

159
00:24:16,600 --> 00:24:22,710
the only visible sign of a vast underground
network of fungal filaments.

160
00:24:53,520 --> 00:24:59,150
In temperate forests, the build-up of leaf litter
creates rich stores of nutrients.

161
00:24:59,280 --> 00:25:02,030
That, however, doesn't happen here.

162
00:25:05,760 --> 00:25:09,670
Nutrients that reach the soil
are leeched out by the rain,

163
00:25:09,760 --> 00:25:14,270
but fungi are connected to tree roots
by their underground filaments,

164
00:25:14,360 --> 00:25:16,430
and by quickly consuming the dead,

165
00:25:16,520 --> 00:25:21,470
they help to recycle crucial minerals
straight back into the trees.

166
00:25:28,080 --> 00:25:33,870
And this recycling happens faster here
than anywhere else on the planet.

167
00:25:53,480 --> 00:25:58,550
There are thought to be nearly a million
different types of fungi in the tropics,

168
00:25:58,640 --> 00:26:02,190
the vast majority still unknown to science.

169
00:26:08,880 --> 00:26:11,350
But one thing's for certain.

170
00:26:11,440 --> 00:26:15,590
Without fungi, rainforests could not exist.

171
00:26:26,840 --> 00:26:29,870
Nothing goes to waste in a rainforest.

172
00:26:29,960 --> 00:26:33,950
The fungi become food for others,
like these beetle larvae.

173
00:26:38,800 --> 00:26:41,710
Finding the fungus isn't a problem for the grubs

174
00:26:41,800 --> 00:26:45,190
since their caring parents
actually show them the way.

175
00:26:59,000 --> 00:27:03,470
Incredibly, 80% of all insects live in jungles.

176
00:27:04,400 --> 00:27:06,830
Few are more successful than the ants.

177
00:27:06,920 --> 00:27:10,670
There can be eight million individuals
in a single hectare.

178
00:27:12,320 --> 00:27:15,710
But jungle ants don't have it all their own way.

179
00:27:22,720 --> 00:27:27,150
These bullet ants are showing
some worrying symptoms.

180
00:27:28,360 --> 00:27:31,990
Spores from a parasitic fungus called Cordyceps

181
00:27:32,080 --> 00:27:35,710
have infiltrated their bodies and their minds.

182
00:27:42,280 --> 00:27:46,830
Its infected brain directs this ant upwards.

183
00:27:48,440 --> 00:27:53,110
Then, utterly disoriented,
it grips a stem with its mandibles.

184
00:27:54,040 --> 00:27:56,990
Those afflicted that are discovered by the workers

185
00:27:57,080 --> 00:28:00,990
are quickly taken away
and dumped far away from the colony.

186
00:28:02,760 --> 00:28:06,870
It seems extreme, but this is the reason why.

187
00:28:09,000 --> 00:28:11,710
Like something out of science fiction,

188
00:28:11,800 --> 00:28:16,590
the fruiting body of the Cordyceps
erupts from the ant's head.

189
00:28:31,360 --> 00:28:33,950
It can take three weeks to grow,

190
00:28:34,040 --> 00:28:38,670
and when finished,
the deadly spores will burst from its tip.

191
00:28:38,760 --> 00:28:43,310
Then any ant in the vicinity
will be in serious risk of death.

192
00:28:46,200 --> 00:28:50,390
The fungus is so virulent
it can wipe out whole colonies of ants.

193
00:28:51,000 --> 00:28:54,550
And it's not just ants that fall victim to this killer.

194
00:28:56,800 --> 00:29:01,470
There are literally thousands
of different types of Cordyceps fungi

195
00:29:01,600 --> 00:29:06,630
and, remarkably,
each specialises on just one species.

196
00:29:41,840 --> 00:29:46,710
But these attacks do have a positive effect
on the jungle's diversity,

197
00:29:46,800 --> 00:29:51,030
since parasites like these
stop any one group of animal

198
00:29:51,120 --> 00:29:53,070
getting the upper hand.

199
00:29:53,560 --> 00:29:55,710
The more numerous a species becomes,

200
00:29:55,840 --> 00:30:00,990
the more likely it will be attacked by its nemesis,
a Cordyceps fungus.

201
00:30:24,480 --> 00:30:29,670
With so much competition,
jungles have become the home of the specialist.

202
00:30:30,480 --> 00:30:34,790
And this animal, in the island of Borneo,
is one of the most unusual.

203
00:30:36,160 --> 00:30:38,950
It's a colugo, or flying lemur,

204
00:30:39,040 --> 00:30:42,670
though this is something of a misnomer
as it doesn't actually fly,

205
00:30:42,760 --> 00:30:45,150
and it certainly isn't a lemur.

206
00:30:45,240 --> 00:30:49,470
In fact, nobody's quite sure
who its closest relative is.

207
00:31:08,840 --> 00:31:12,670
The colugo depends on a diet of young leaves,

208
00:31:12,760 --> 00:31:16,750
and to find enough of them,
it must move from tree to tree.

209
00:31:18,840 --> 00:31:24,710
The leaves are not very nutritious,
but then getting around doesn't use much energy.

210
00:31:30,760 --> 00:31:35,630
In a single night, a colugo might have to travel
as far as two miles.

211
00:31:35,720 --> 00:31:40,550
But that task is made easier
by its superior gliding skills.

212
00:32:11,760 --> 00:32:16,230
The secret of success in the competitive jungle
is specialising,

213
00:32:16,320 --> 00:32:20,590
and this has led to the evolution
of some very intimate relationships

214
00:32:20,680 --> 00:32:22,950
between plants and animals.

215
00:32:24,840 --> 00:32:28,590
These are pitcher plants, also from Borneo.

216
00:32:33,920 --> 00:32:37,910
Adapted to living in very low-nutrient soils,

217
00:32:38,040 --> 00:32:43,150
the pitcher plant gets most of its nourishment
from insects lured to nectar glands

218
00:32:43,280 --> 00:32:45,670
on the underside of the lids.

219
00:32:47,080 --> 00:32:52,510
Once on board, the waxy sides of the pitcher
ensure there's little chance of escape.

220
00:32:56,360 --> 00:32:59,390
Most slip to a watery grave.

221
00:33:07,200 --> 00:33:11,310
At the bottom of the pitcher,
glands secrete enzymes

222
00:33:11,400 --> 00:33:15,830
which help to digest the corpses,
so feeding the plant.

223
00:33:17,000 --> 00:33:20,830
But not all visitors have a fatal attraction
to the pitchers.

224
00:33:22,240 --> 00:33:26,270
The Red Crab Spider
spends its entire life in the pitchers,

225
00:33:26,360 --> 00:33:28,710
hanging on with threads of silk.

226
00:33:38,280 --> 00:33:43,990
Instead of building a web,
it relies on the water-filled pitcher to trap its food.

227
00:33:46,760 --> 00:33:51,550
When an ant falls in,
the spider simply waits for it to drown

228
00:33:51,640 --> 00:33:55,190
and then abseils down for a spot of fishing.

229
00:34:02,400 --> 00:34:06,550
Alive, this ant would be far too dangerous
for the spider to tackle,

230
00:34:06,640 --> 00:34:12,070
so using the pitchers as traps
means it can get bigger meals.

231
00:34:14,320 --> 00:34:17,270
And the spider
doesn't rob the pitcher of everything.

232
00:34:17,360 --> 00:34:21,230
The digested remains of its booty
will end up in the water,

233
00:34:21,320 --> 00:34:24,310
providing instant food for the plant.

234
00:34:28,600 --> 00:34:33,070
Other food, like mosquito larvae,
seems to be out of reach,

235
00:34:33,160 --> 00:34:36,310
but the spider has another surprising trick.

236
00:34:36,400 --> 00:34:39,590
By taking its own air supply trapped in a bubble,

237
00:34:39,680 --> 00:34:44,030
the crab spider can actually dive
to the very bottom of the pitcher.

238
00:34:47,680 --> 00:34:49,470
Once the prey is captured,

239
00:34:49,560 --> 00:34:53,990
the spider hauls itself back up
its silken safety line.

240
00:35:01,360 --> 00:35:07,070
The pitcher is a one-stop shop for this spider,
but it's not alone.

241
00:35:07,200 --> 00:35:12,630
In the jungle there's competition for everything,
even a small water-filled pitcher plant.

242
00:35:28,560 --> 00:35:33,190
Such specialists create
the jungle's remarkable diversity.

243
00:35:33,680 --> 00:35:36,870
But finding enough food to survive
is so challenging

244
00:35:36,960 --> 00:35:40,150
that most animals living here tend to be small,

245
00:35:40,240 --> 00:35:42,550
though there are exceptions.

246
00:35:50,000 --> 00:35:53,510
This is the Congo, in Africa.

247
00:35:53,600 --> 00:35:58,750
It's a vast wilderness
and the least explored of alljungles.

248
00:36:01,360 --> 00:36:07,750
From up here, the forest looks similar to the ones
that grow in the Amazon or Southeast Asia.

249
00:36:07,880 --> 00:36:11,870
But down below,
there are some unexpected sights.

250
00:36:29,120 --> 00:36:34,070
Crisscrossing this forest
are countless miles of highways.

251
00:36:34,160 --> 00:36:37,470
And they were made by something big.

252
00:36:46,600 --> 00:36:51,670
Forest elephants roam great distances
in their search for food,

253
00:36:51,760 --> 00:36:56,270
but to survive they must emerge
from the gloom of the forest.

254
00:36:58,320 --> 00:37:03,790
And clearings like this one are a magnet
for elephants from far and wide.

255
00:37:58,280 --> 00:38:03,270
These elephants live in much smaller groups
than their savannah cousins.

256
00:38:04,080 --> 00:38:09,350
This might be the first time that one group
will have seen another for a month.

257
00:38:18,960 --> 00:38:25,470
For the adult males, it's a welcome break
in an otherwise largely solitary existence.

258
00:38:33,560 --> 00:38:37,390
And they're not the only animals
attracted to the clearing.

259
00:38:39,960 --> 00:38:45,270
Forest buffalos and red river hogs
are also regular visitors.

260
00:38:45,880 --> 00:38:50,310
As are bongos, which are very difficult to see
outside these clearings.

261
00:38:51,560 --> 00:38:57,430
All these large forest animals have come here
to collect an essential element of their diet

262
00:38:57,520 --> 00:39:00,310
that lies buried beneath the mud.

263
00:39:04,880 --> 00:39:09,110
And the elephant's trunk
is the perfect tool for reaching it.

264
00:39:23,320 --> 00:39:29,510
To get what they seek, the prospecting elephants
must first blow away the covering layer of silt.

265
00:39:51,400 --> 00:39:54,030
Satisfaction at last.

266
00:39:58,960 --> 00:40:01,870
They're collecting a particular kind of clay

267
00:40:01,960 --> 00:40:06,270
that contains vital minerals
scarce in their natural diet.

268
00:40:06,360 --> 00:40:12,350
It may be mud but there's just nothing
quite like it for enriching the blood.

269
00:40:13,400 --> 00:40:19,710
The clay also helps to absorb the toxins
found in many leaves that the elephants eat.

270
00:40:25,120 --> 00:40:27,990
There are other benefits to coming here.

271
00:40:28,880 --> 00:40:30,870
These clearings are the only places

272
00:40:30,960 --> 00:40:34,910
where the forest elephants
can get together in such numbers.

273
00:40:35,000 --> 00:40:37,110
When they return to the forest,

274
00:40:37,200 --> 00:40:40,670
they will have to go
their separate ways once more.

275
00:41:00,760 --> 00:41:03,990
If large animals are rare in jungles,

276
00:41:04,080 --> 00:41:09,030
then groups of large animals
actually living together are even rarer.

277
00:41:27,520 --> 00:41:33,910
This posse of hunters is not only formidable,
it's also very large.

278
00:41:52,840 --> 00:41:54,750
In their search for food,

279
00:41:54,840 --> 00:42:00,030
chimpanzees move effortlessly
between the forest floor and the canopy.

280
00:42:00,120 --> 00:42:03,750
They're one of the few jungle animals
able to do so.

281
00:42:18,160 --> 00:42:22,350
Figs are a vital part of a chimpanzee's diet

282
00:42:22,440 --> 00:42:25,590
and some just can't seem to get enough of them.

283
00:42:35,520 --> 00:42:39,710
But there's something special
about this stretch of forest in Uganda.

284
00:42:39,800 --> 00:42:42,270
Fruit is actually abundant.

285
00:42:47,960 --> 00:42:52,310
And a lot of food supports lots of chimps.

286
00:43:08,560 --> 00:43:10,710
At 150 strong,

287
00:43:10,800 --> 00:43:15,110
this community of chimps
is the biggest yet found in Africa.

288
00:43:15,240 --> 00:43:20,550
Their numbers are so large
that they need a big territory, lots of fig trees,

289
00:43:20,640 --> 00:43:22,990
and they're willing to fight for it.

290
00:43:32,040 --> 00:43:38,110
These calls announce the start of a raid
into land controlled by their neighbours.

291
00:43:44,080 --> 00:43:48,110
As they leave their core zone,
the patrol goes silent,

292
00:43:48,200 --> 00:43:50,470
occasionally stopping to listen.

293
00:43:55,000 --> 00:43:59,750
Signs of the enemy are detected
and examined closely.

294
00:44:14,040 --> 00:44:18,750
The chimp militia are now
at the very edge of their territory.

295
00:44:19,760 --> 00:44:23,150
All need to be on maximum alert.

296
00:44:31,440 --> 00:44:34,190
They must wait and listen.

297
00:44:55,120 --> 00:44:58,990
An unfamiliar chimp call raises the tension.

298
00:44:59,120 --> 00:45:05,230
It's an uncertain time,
the size of the rival group is as yet unknown.

299
00:45:08,600 --> 00:45:12,390
Not far away,
their neighbours are feeding in a fig tree,

300
00:45:12,480 --> 00:45:15,230
oblivious to the approaching dangers.

301
00:45:16,960 --> 00:45:20,550
The patrol moves off with a sense of purpose.

302
00:45:20,640 --> 00:45:24,630
They must remain silent
until they close in on their rivals.

303
00:45:36,440 --> 00:45:38,070
The attack is on!

304
00:45:40,600 --> 00:45:42,470
To intimidate their opponents,

305
00:45:42,560 --> 00:45:45,990
the aggressors scream
and drum on buttress roots.

306
00:46:05,840 --> 00:46:08,830
Several males corner an enemy female.

307
00:46:08,920 --> 00:46:12,990
It's a ferocious attack
and she's lucky to escape with her life.

308
00:46:30,240 --> 00:46:32,590
Others are not so fortunate.

309
00:46:39,040 --> 00:46:43,110
The battle won, a grizzly scene unfolds.

310
00:46:44,040 --> 00:46:47,310
An enemy youngster has been caught and killed.

311
00:46:47,400 --> 00:46:51,870
The carcass is shared between members
of the group and eaten.

312
00:46:55,920 --> 00:47:00,350
Killing a competitor makes sense
if you want to protect your food supply.

313
00:47:04,120 --> 00:47:08,670
But exactly why they cannibalise
the dead chimp is not fully understood.

314
00:47:10,000 --> 00:47:14,310
It may simply be a chance for some extra protein.

315
00:47:25,920 --> 00:47:29,950
Teamwork has brought
this group of chimps great success,

316
00:47:30,040 --> 00:47:33,390
but they'll soon reach the limits of their power.

317
00:47:34,600 --> 00:47:40,990
The competition for resources ensures
that no one species dominates the jungle.

318
00:47:47,640 --> 00:47:51,670
The rainforests' great diversity has come at a cost.

319
00:47:51,800 --> 00:47:55,950
It has made them the most finely balanced
ecosystems in the world,

320
00:47:56,040 --> 00:48:00,910
only too easily upset and destroyed
by that other great ape,

321
00:48:01,000 --> 00:48:04,070
the chimpanzee's closest relative,

322
00:48:04,160 --> 00:48:05,670
ourselves.

