1
00:00:38,720 --> 00:00:40,430
A hundred years ago,

2
00:00:40,520 --> 00:00:44,310
there were one-and-a-half billion people on Earth.

3
00:00:46,200 --> 00:00:50,750
Now, over six billion crowd our fragile planet.

4
00:00:52,520 --> 00:00:57,470
But even so, there are still places
barely touched by humanity.

5
00:01:03,120 --> 00:01:07,150
This series will take you to the last wildernesses

6
00:01:07,240 --> 00:01:12,510
and show you the planet and its wildlife
as you have never seen them before.

7
00:02:01,640 --> 00:02:04,990
Imagine our world without sun.

8
00:02:06,440 --> 00:02:11,390
Male emperor penguins are facing the nearest
that exists on planet Earth,

9
00:02:11,960 --> 00:02:14,350
winter in Antarctica.

10
00:02:16,240 --> 00:02:22,230
It's continuously dark and temperatures drop
to minus 70 degrees centigrade.

11
00:02:33,000 --> 00:02:36,550
The penguins stay
when all other creatures have fled

12
00:02:36,640 --> 00:02:39,110
because each guards a treasure,

13
00:02:39,200 --> 00:02:41,990
a single egg resting on the top of its feet

14
00:02:42,120 --> 00:02:45,430
and kept warm
beneath the downy bulge of its stomach.

15
00:02:50,920 --> 00:02:53,590
There is no food and no water for them

16
00:02:53,680 --> 00:02:56,950
and they will not see the sun again
for four months.

17
00:02:57,040 --> 00:03:01,590
Surely, no greater ordeal is faced by any animal.

18
00:03:11,840 --> 00:03:17,750
As the sun departs from the Antarctic,
it lightens the skies in the far north.

19
00:03:26,640 --> 00:03:31,070
It's March, and light returns to the high Arctic,

20
00:03:31,200 --> 00:03:34,110
sweeping away four months of darkness.

21
00:03:47,120 --> 00:03:49,470
A polar bear stirs.

22
00:03:49,800 --> 00:03:52,670
She has been in her den the whole winter.

23
00:03:53,200 --> 00:03:57,110
Her emergence marks the beginning of spring.

24
00:03:59,800 --> 00:04:04,350
After months of confinement underground,
she toboggans down the slope,

25
00:04:04,520 --> 00:04:09,150
perhaps to clean her fur, perhaps for sheer joy.

26
00:04:24,120 --> 00:04:29,350
Her cubs gaze out at their bright new world
for the very first time.

27
00:04:32,040 --> 00:04:33,750
The female calls them,

28
00:04:33,880 --> 00:04:38,870
but this steep slope is not the easiest place
to take your first steps.

29
00:04:52,280 --> 00:04:55,630
But they are hungry
and eager to reach their mother,

30
00:04:55,720 --> 00:04:58,710
who's delayed feeding them on this special day.

31
00:04:59,280 --> 00:05:01,790
Now she lures them with the promise of milk,

32
00:05:01,880 --> 00:05:05,990
the only food the cubs have known
since they were born, deaf and blind,

33
00:05:06,080 --> 00:05:09,030
beneath the snow some two months ago.

34
00:05:25,520 --> 00:05:28,790
Their mother has not eaten for five months

35
00:05:28,880 --> 00:05:31,750
and has lost half her body weight.

36
00:05:31,840 --> 00:05:36,750
Now she converts the last of her fat reserves
into milk for her cubs.

37
00:05:55,840 --> 00:06:01,030
The spring sun brings warmth,
but also a problem for the mother.

38
00:06:01,600 --> 00:06:04,310
It starts to melt the sea ice.

39
00:06:04,760 --> 00:06:08,710
That is where she hunts for the seals she needs
to feed her cubs

40
00:06:08,800 --> 00:06:11,870
and she must get there before the ice breaks up.

41
00:06:15,960 --> 00:06:19,270
For now, though, it's still minus 30 degrees,

42
00:06:19,360 --> 00:06:22,390
and the cubs must have the shelter of the den.

43
00:06:35,880 --> 00:06:38,990
It's six days since the bears emerged

44
00:06:39,120 --> 00:06:41,710
and spring is advancing rapidly.

45
00:06:41,880 --> 00:06:45,510
But even now,
blizzards can strike without warning.

46
00:06:48,480 --> 00:06:51,510
Being so small, the cubs are easily chilled

47
00:06:51,640 --> 00:06:54,430
and they would be more comfortable
resting in the den,

48
00:06:54,520 --> 00:06:57,550
but their mother must keep them out and active.

49
00:06:59,160 --> 00:07:03,430
She's becoming weak from hunger
and there's no food on these nursery slopes.

50
00:07:10,200 --> 00:07:14,470
The sea ice still holds firm,
but it won't last much longer.

51
00:07:18,320 --> 00:07:22,750
Day 10, and the mother
has led her cubs a mile from the den.

52
00:07:23,040 --> 00:07:25,470
It's time to put them to the test.

53
00:07:28,200 --> 00:07:30,750
They've grown enormously in confidence,

54
00:07:30,880 --> 00:07:34,190
but they don't have
their mother's sense of urgency.

55
00:07:49,720 --> 00:07:53,270
At last it seems that
they're ready for their journey

56
00:07:53,360 --> 00:07:55,230
and only just in time

57
00:07:55,320 --> 00:07:59,590
for, a few miles from the coast,
the ice is already splitting.

58
00:08:05,560 --> 00:08:09,270
Now the mother can start hunting
for the seals they must have,

59
00:08:09,360 --> 00:08:13,430
but she's leading her cubs
into a dangerous new world.

60
00:08:14,400 --> 00:08:18,950
Nearly half of all cubs die in their first year
out on the ice.

61
00:08:29,320 --> 00:08:35,310
Summer brings 24 hours of sunlight
and a thawing, shifting landscape.

62
00:08:38,720 --> 00:08:43,390
Further south, the winter snows
have almost cleared from the arctic tundra.

63
00:08:51,720 --> 00:08:54,830
Northern Canada's wild frontier.

64
00:08:54,960 --> 00:08:59,190
Here, nature stages one of her greatest dramas.

65
00:09:06,640 --> 00:09:12,510
Every year, three million caribou
migrate across the arctic tundra.

66
00:09:25,280 --> 00:09:30,750
The immensity of the herd
can only be properly appreciated from the air.

67
00:09:38,520 --> 00:09:43,910
Some herds travel over two thousand miles a year
in search of fresh pastures.

68
00:09:44,280 --> 00:09:49,510
This is the longest overland migration
made by any animal.

69
00:10:00,920 --> 00:10:03,230
They're constantly on the move.

70
00:10:03,360 --> 00:10:07,270
Newborn calves have to be up and running
the day they're born.

71
00:10:27,480 --> 00:10:31,590
But the vast herds do not travel alone.

72
00:10:34,600 --> 00:10:36,070
Wolves.

73
00:10:38,000 --> 00:10:42,350
Packs of them, eight to ten strong,
shadow the migration.

74
00:10:44,640 --> 00:10:46,630
And they're hungry.

75
00:10:51,520 --> 00:10:55,030
It's the newly-born calves that they are after.

76
00:11:02,160 --> 00:11:06,150
Running directly at the herd
is a ploy to generate panic.

77
00:11:17,120 --> 00:11:21,790
The herd breaks up and now it's easier
to target an individual.

78
00:11:32,360 --> 00:11:35,950
In the chaos, a calf is separated from its mother.

79
00:11:42,840 --> 00:11:48,230
The calf is young, but it can outrun the wolf
if only it manages to keep its footing.

80
00:12:00,840 --> 00:12:03,670
At this stage the odds are even.

81
00:12:03,760 --> 00:12:06,030
Either the caribou will make a mistake

82
00:12:06,120 --> 00:12:08,790
or, after a mile, the wolf will give up.

83
00:12:56,280 --> 00:13:00,790
Midsummer on the tundra
and the sun does not set.

84
00:13:04,040 --> 00:13:07,670
At these latitudes, the sun's rays are glancing

85
00:13:07,800 --> 00:13:12,550
and not enough of their energy
reaches the ground to enable trees to grow.

86
00:13:15,360 --> 00:13:19,990
You need to travel five hundred miles
south from here before that is possible.

87
00:13:26,360 --> 00:13:33,150
These stunted shrubs mark the tree line,
the beginning of the Boreal forest,

88
00:13:33,240 --> 00:13:34,950
the taiga.

89
00:13:43,520 --> 00:13:47,390
The needle-shaped leaves of the conifers
are virtually inedible,

90
00:13:47,560 --> 00:13:50,630
so this forest supports very little animal life.

91
00:13:57,640 --> 00:14:02,550
It's a silent place where the snow
is unmarked by footprints.

92
00:14:11,840 --> 00:14:17,470
In the arctic winter,
snow forms a continuous blanket across the land.

93
00:14:18,040 --> 00:14:23,310
But as spring creeps up from the south,
the taiga is unveiled.

94
00:14:28,840 --> 00:14:32,030
This vast forest circling the globe

95
00:14:32,120 --> 00:14:35,390
contains a third of all the trees on Earth

96
00:14:35,520 --> 00:14:40,710
and produces so much oxygen,
it changes the composition of the atmosphere.

97
00:14:43,720 --> 00:14:48,510
As we travel south,
so the sun's influence grows stronger

98
00:14:48,600 --> 00:14:53,750
and at 50 degrees of latitude,
a radical transformation begins.

99
00:15:04,160 --> 00:15:09,590
Summers here are long enough
for broad-leaved trees to replace conifers.

100
00:15:10,560 --> 00:15:13,630
Broad leaves are much easier to eat and digest

101
00:15:14,400 --> 00:15:17,670
so now animals can collect
their share of the energy

102
00:15:17,760 --> 00:15:19,870
that has come from the sun.

103
00:15:20,960 --> 00:15:24,950
It's summer and these forests
are bustling with life.

104
00:15:50,680 --> 00:15:53,350
But the good times will not last.

105
00:15:55,520 --> 00:15:59,550
Broad leaves must be shed in winter
for they're damaged by frost.

106
00:16:00,120 --> 00:16:05,750
As they disappear, so the land becomes barren
with little for animals to eat.

107
00:16:14,320 --> 00:16:20,590
The inhabitants must migrate, hibernate
or face months of near-starvation.

108
00:16:38,960 --> 00:16:43,150
The Amur leopard, the rarest cat in the world.

109
00:16:46,760 --> 00:16:52,070
Here, in the deciduous forests of eastern Russia,
the winter makes hunting very difficult.

110
00:16:52,520 --> 00:16:56,470
Prey animals are scarce
and there's no concealing vegetation.

111
00:17:00,040 --> 00:17:03,470
The cub is a year old
and still dependent on its mother.

112
00:17:12,000 --> 00:17:15,550
Deer are frequent casualties of the harsh winter

113
00:17:15,640 --> 00:17:19,190
and these leopards are not above
scavenging from a corpse.

114
00:17:20,080 --> 00:17:23,110
African leopards could never survive here

115
00:17:23,640 --> 00:17:27,630
but the Russian cats have thick fur
to shield them from the cold.

116
00:17:34,120 --> 00:17:39,590
There are only 40 Amur leopards left in the wild,
and that number is falling.

117
00:17:41,600 --> 00:17:46,070
Like so many creatures, the cats
have been pushed to the very edge of extinction

118
00:17:46,160 --> 00:17:49,350
by hunting and the destruction of their habitat.

119
00:17:51,520 --> 00:17:56,510
The Amur leopard symbolises the fragility
of our natural heritage.

120
00:17:57,600 --> 00:18:01,750
The future of an entire species
hangs on the survival

121
00:18:01,880 --> 00:18:04,910
of a tiny number of mothers like this one.

122
00:18:10,840 --> 00:18:16,590
All animals, rare or common,
ultimately depend for their energy on the sun.

123
00:18:24,640 --> 00:18:29,750
In Japan, the arrival of the cherry blossom
announces the beginning of spring.

124
00:18:51,000 --> 00:18:54,550
The sun's energy brings colour to the landscape.

125
00:19:04,720 --> 00:19:10,470
The Earth, as it makes its annualjourney
round the sun, spins on a tilted axis

126
00:19:10,840 --> 00:19:14,230
and it's this tilt that creates the seasons.

127
00:19:39,360 --> 00:19:43,070
The advance of the seasons
brings constant change.

128
00:19:44,680 --> 00:19:47,550
As the sun's influence diminishes in the north,

129
00:19:47,640 --> 00:19:52,030
so the deciduous forests of America
begin to shut down,

130
00:19:52,120 --> 00:19:56,670
losing their leaves in preparation
for the dark, cold months ahead.

131
00:20:10,960 --> 00:20:13,750
One season hands over to another.

132
00:20:13,840 --> 00:20:16,630
Some organisms thrive on decay,

133
00:20:16,760 --> 00:20:22,230
but most must make special preparations
for winter and a life with little sun.

134
00:20:37,200 --> 00:20:41,950
Whole populations of animals
are now forced to travel great distances

135
00:20:42,040 --> 00:20:45,110
in pursuit of food and warmth.

136
00:20:50,640 --> 00:20:56,590
Three hundred thousand Baikal Teal
gather to escape from the Siberian winter

137
00:20:56,680 --> 00:20:59,230
by migrating south to Korea.

138
00:21:02,680 --> 00:21:06,910
The world's entire population in a single flock.

139
00:21:11,040 --> 00:21:14,950
But there are parts of the world
that have no seasons.

140
00:21:18,680 --> 00:21:22,550
In the tropics,
the sun's rays strike the Earth head-on

141
00:21:22,640 --> 00:21:26,390
and their strength
is more or less constant all year round.

142
00:21:29,400 --> 00:21:34,270
That is why the jungle grows so vigorously
and supports so much life.

143
00:21:36,360 --> 00:21:40,110
This forest covers only 3% of the planet's surface

144
00:21:40,200 --> 00:21:44,750
but it contains more than 50%
of all its plants and animals.

145
00:21:48,800 --> 00:21:51,350
The canopy is particularly rich.

146
00:21:51,960 --> 00:21:56,230
There are monkeys, birds
and millions of species of insects.

147
00:21:56,320 --> 00:21:59,070
Exactly how many, we have no idea.

148
00:22:01,600 --> 00:22:04,750
The character of the forest changes
as you descend,

149
00:22:04,880 --> 00:22:10,710
becoming ever darker and damper,
favouring different kinds of animals and plants.

150
00:22:16,920 --> 00:22:20,070
Less than 2% of the sunlight reaches the floor.

151
00:22:20,200 --> 00:22:23,310
But even here, there is extraordinary variety.

152
00:22:32,560 --> 00:22:34,750
In the great island of New Guinea,

153
00:22:34,880 --> 00:22:40,510
there are 42 different species of birds of paradise,
each more bizarre than the last.

154
00:23:06,680 --> 00:23:11,390
This forest is so rich
that nourishing food can be gathered very quickly.

155
00:23:11,880 --> 00:23:17,470
That leaves the male Six-plumed bird of paradise
with time to concentrate on other matters,

156
00:23:17,560 --> 00:23:20,230
like tidying up his display area.

157
00:23:29,960 --> 00:23:32,590
Everything must be spick and span.

158
00:23:40,680 --> 00:23:42,150
All is ready.

159
00:24:02,800 --> 00:24:05,590
Very impressive. But no one is watching.

160
00:24:08,280 --> 00:24:12,310
The Superb bird of paradise
calls to attract a female.

161
00:24:15,080 --> 00:24:17,230
And he has more luck.

162
00:24:18,280 --> 00:24:21,790
But what does he have to do to really impress her?

163
00:24:47,200 --> 00:24:49,550
She retires to consider her verdict.

164
00:24:56,640 --> 00:25:01,390
It's hard not to feel deflated
when even your best isn't good enough.

165
00:25:21,760 --> 00:25:26,750
The sun influences life in the oceans
just as it does on land.

166
00:26:12,400 --> 00:26:16,070
Its richest parts are those
where waves and currents

167
00:26:16,200 --> 00:26:20,950
bring fertilising nutrients to surface waters
that are bathed in sunlight.

168
00:26:21,320 --> 00:26:23,870
The seas off the Cape in South Africa

169
00:26:24,000 --> 00:26:27,710
have this magic recipe and are hugely productive.

170
00:26:31,880 --> 00:26:37,310
Summer is a time of plenty,
and it's now that the seals start to breed.

171
00:27:01,200 --> 00:27:05,750
The strike of a great white shark
lasts a mere second.

172
00:27:05,880 --> 00:27:10,910
Slowing it down 40 times
reveals the technique and immense strength

173
00:27:11,000 --> 00:27:13,030
of this massive predator.

174
00:27:50,120 --> 00:27:53,830
If surprise fails, there will be a chase.

175
00:28:04,120 --> 00:28:07,150
The shark is faster on a straight course,

176
00:28:07,240 --> 00:28:09,950
but it can't turn as sharply as a seal.

177
00:28:12,800 --> 00:28:15,230
It's agility versus power.

178
00:29:09,000 --> 00:29:13,550
Once the seals have finished breeding,
the giant sharks will move on.

179
00:29:16,240 --> 00:29:21,670
It's now becoming clear that great whites
migrate thousands of miles across the oceans

180
00:29:21,840 --> 00:29:26,030
to harvest seasonal abundances in different seas.

181
00:29:52,120 --> 00:29:57,870
The sun, beating down on tropical waters,
powers the weather systems of the globe.

182
00:29:58,320 --> 00:30:04,030
Moisture evaporates from the warming ocean
and rises to create great storms.

183
00:30:24,600 --> 00:30:30,190
The winds generated out at sea
sweep inland across the continents.

184
00:30:41,880 --> 00:30:47,270
As they travel across the Sahara,
they create the biggest of all sandstorms,

185
00:30:47,360 --> 00:30:52,350
blowing sand halfway round the world,
to fertilise the Amazon jungle.

186
00:30:57,480 --> 00:31:00,630
Winds blowing across the Indian Ocean

187
00:31:00,720 --> 00:31:04,990
collect moisture and sweep northwards
towards the Himalayas.

188
00:31:06,440 --> 00:31:09,710
As the air rises, so it cools.

189
00:31:13,800 --> 00:31:17,630
The water it carries condenses into clouds

190
00:31:17,720 --> 00:31:21,590
and then falls
as the life-giving rains of the monsoon.

191
00:31:27,200 --> 00:31:30,550
So air currents, powered by the sun,

192
00:31:30,640 --> 00:31:33,750
carry wet air to the middle of continents.

193
00:31:52,640 --> 00:31:55,710
Without water there can be no life.

194
00:31:55,880 --> 00:32:00,030
But its distribution over the land is far from even.

195
00:32:06,480 --> 00:32:12,750
Deserts cover one third of the land's surface
and they're growing bigger every year.

196
00:32:23,360 --> 00:32:26,990
This is the Kalahari desert in southern Africa.

197
00:32:27,720 --> 00:32:29,590
It's the dry season

198
00:32:29,720 --> 00:32:35,070
and thousands of elephants have started to travel
in a desperate search for water.

199
00:32:45,040 --> 00:32:49,950
All across southern Africa,
animals are journeying for the same reason.

200
00:32:53,320 --> 00:32:55,870
Buffalo join the great trek.

201
00:32:56,000 --> 00:33:01,430
Nowhere else on Earth are so many animals
on the move with the same urgent purpose.

202
00:33:06,320 --> 00:33:10,070
They are all heading for the swamps of
the Okavango,

203
00:33:10,160 --> 00:33:12,630
a vast inland delta.

204
00:33:14,080 --> 00:33:18,310
At the moment it is dry, but water is coming.

205
00:33:20,840 --> 00:33:24,830
The travellers are hampered by
dangerous dust storms.

206
00:33:28,920 --> 00:33:32,910
Females and calves can easily get separated
from the main herd.

207
00:33:49,120 --> 00:33:53,870
For this pair, sanctuary lies
in a patch of woodland a few miles ahead.

208
00:33:53,960 --> 00:33:56,470
They can't rest until they reach it.

209
00:34:12,280 --> 00:34:15,510
The main herd has already got there safely.

210
00:34:20,760 --> 00:34:24,430
Finally, the stragglers emerge from the dust.

211
00:34:29,080 --> 00:34:33,230
The exhausted calf is still blinded by sand.

212
00:34:35,960 --> 00:34:38,990
Its mother does everything possible to help it.

213
00:34:52,120 --> 00:34:55,150
The storm is now subsiding.

214
00:34:55,240 --> 00:34:58,550
But not all the elephants have been so lucky.

215
00:34:58,640 --> 00:35:01,310
One youngster has got lost.

216
00:35:03,040 --> 00:35:07,230
Thirsty and exhausted,
it follows the tracks of its mother,

217
00:35:08,000 --> 00:35:11,230
but, sadly, in the wrong direction.

218
00:35:34,720 --> 00:35:40,590
At the peak of the dry season in the Kalahari,
water arrives in the Okavango.

219
00:35:40,680 --> 00:35:44,550
It fell as rain a thousand miles away
in the highlands of Angola

220
00:35:44,680 --> 00:35:47,790
and has taken nearly five months to reach here.

221
00:35:54,160 --> 00:35:58,230
The water drives out insects
from the parched ground,

222
00:35:58,360 --> 00:36:00,430
which are snapped up by plovers.

223
00:36:04,080 --> 00:36:06,270
Catfish, travelling with the flood,

224
00:36:06,360 --> 00:36:09,670
collect any drowning creatures
the birds have missed.

225
00:36:20,360 --> 00:36:24,270
It's a seasonal feast for animals of all kinds.

226
00:36:35,960 --> 00:36:38,950
Birds are the first to arrive in any numbers.

227
00:36:39,200 --> 00:36:40,750
Wattled cranes,

228
00:36:42,160 --> 00:36:44,550
then black storks.

229
00:36:46,560 --> 00:36:49,590
Behind the birds come buffalo.

230
00:36:49,680 --> 00:36:53,310
After weeks of marching,
their trek is coming to an end.

231
00:37:12,240 --> 00:37:14,830
As the water sweeps into the Okavango,

232
00:37:14,920 --> 00:37:20,630
a vast area of the Kalahari
is transformed into a fertile paradise.

233
00:37:24,320 --> 00:37:30,070
Nowhere on our planet is the life-giving power
of water so clearly demonstrated.

234
00:37:34,760 --> 00:37:39,830
The Okavango becomes criss-crossed with trails
as animals move into its heart.

235
00:37:40,640 --> 00:37:45,350
The new arrivals open up paths like arteries,
along which water flows,

236
00:37:45,440 --> 00:37:47,790
extending the reach of the flood.

237
00:38:07,480 --> 00:38:10,070
This is an Africa rarely seen.

238
00:38:11,360 --> 00:38:13,230
A lush water-world.

239
00:38:30,800 --> 00:38:33,630
Some creatures are completely at home here.

240
00:38:33,760 --> 00:38:38,230
These are lechwe, antelope with hooves
that splay widely,

241
00:38:38,320 --> 00:38:41,110
enabling them
to move at speed through the water.

242
00:38:42,520 --> 00:38:45,670
For others, the change is far less welcome.

243
00:38:51,880 --> 00:38:55,470
Baboons are somewhat apprehensive bathers.

244
00:39:26,960 --> 00:39:32,150
The water brings a season of plenty
for all animals.

245
00:39:46,160 --> 00:39:47,870
Hunting dogs.

246
00:40:07,040 --> 00:40:10,830
These are now among the rarest
of Africa's mammals

247
00:40:11,000 --> 00:40:14,550
but they're, nonetheless,
the continent's most efficient predators.

248
00:40:17,080 --> 00:40:19,470
Their secret is teamwork.

249
00:40:23,440 --> 00:40:26,230
Impala are their favourite prey.

250
00:40:27,480 --> 00:40:30,510
They start to hunt and the pack splits up.

251
00:40:31,720 --> 00:40:35,270
An aerial viewpoint gives a new insight
into their strategy.

252
00:40:36,800 --> 00:40:42,670
As the dogs approach their prey, they peel off
to take up separate positions around their target.

253
00:40:54,640 --> 00:40:58,150
They seem to form a cordon around the impala.

254
00:41:06,880 --> 00:41:10,750
Moving in total silence,
they take up their positions.

255
00:41:15,560 --> 00:41:18,750
Those ears can detect the slightest rustle.

256
00:41:39,760 --> 00:41:41,750
The hunt is on.

257
00:41:45,280 --> 00:41:48,550
Three dogs close in on one impala.

258
00:41:57,000 --> 00:41:58,110
Missed!

259
00:42:02,560 --> 00:42:06,310
The lead dog drives the impala
towards the hidden flankers.

260
00:42:16,600 --> 00:42:22,430
Anticipating their line, the leader cuts the corner
and joins a flanker for the final assault.

261
00:42:25,040 --> 00:42:27,670
It's all or nothing. One on one.

262
00:42:32,120 --> 00:42:35,630
The dog has stamina, the impala has speed.

263
00:42:49,080 --> 00:42:52,470
Leaping into the lake is an act of desperation.

264
00:42:52,560 --> 00:42:54,910
Impala can barely swim.

265
00:42:58,120 --> 00:43:01,550
The dogs know their prey must come out or drown.

266
00:43:01,640 --> 00:43:03,870
Now it's a waiting game.

267
00:43:11,960 --> 00:43:14,510
The rest of the pack are calling.

268
00:43:15,640 --> 00:43:20,710
They've made a kill in the forest
and this is an invitation to join in the meal.

269
00:43:24,680 --> 00:43:26,910
The impala is in luck.

270
00:43:34,720 --> 00:43:39,470
A pack this size kills once a day,
and everything is shared.

271
00:43:48,800 --> 00:43:51,870
And this impala is reprieved.

272
00:44:00,280 --> 00:44:04,030
The elephants are nearing the end
of their long journey.

273
00:44:06,120 --> 00:44:10,150
After weeks of marching, they're desperately tired.

274
00:44:17,880 --> 00:44:23,150
The matriarch can smell water
and encourages the herd to make one last effort.

275
00:44:33,680 --> 00:44:37,550
The youngsters are exhausted,
but their mothers have made this journey before

276
00:44:37,640 --> 00:44:40,270
and they know that they're close to water.

277
00:44:56,920 --> 00:45:00,430
After many hundreds of miles, they've arrived.

278
00:46:09,080 --> 00:46:14,950
The lives of these elephants are dominated
by the annual rhythm of wet and dry,

279
00:46:15,080 --> 00:46:18,310
a seasonal cycle created by the sun.

280
00:46:48,280 --> 00:46:52,630
At the southern end of the Earth,
after four months of total darkness,

281
00:46:52,720 --> 00:46:56,470
the sun once more rises over Antarctica.

282
00:47:10,440 --> 00:47:14,830
Now at last the emperor penguins
abandon their huddle.

283
00:47:14,920 --> 00:47:17,910
The males are still carrying the precious eggs

284
00:47:18,000 --> 00:47:21,030
that they've cherished
throughout the Antarctic winter.

285
00:47:29,120 --> 00:47:32,510
With the returning sun, the eggs hatch.

286
00:47:34,120 --> 00:47:36,910
Other birds have not even arrived

287
00:47:37,000 --> 00:47:41,070
but the emperors,
by enduring the long black winter,

288
00:47:41,160 --> 00:47:44,230
have given their chicks a head start.

289
00:47:53,360 --> 00:47:56,590
These youngsters are now ready and eager

290
00:47:56,680 --> 00:48:00,110
to make the most of the brief Antarctic summer.

