Yo, Renaldo!
- Renaldo!
- ¿Qué?
Next time you finish up the box,
you need to holler on it, yo.
Sí, sí.
Mamma mia.
Hey, y'all, it's Omar.
- Omar.
- There he is.
- Omar step, yo.
- Omar, yo.
Y'all ain't got no Honey Nut?
Whatever you see.
And a carton of Newports.
Omar comin'.
Hey, y'all, here he come.
Omar, Omar.
Omar strollin'.
They don't have the Honey Nut?
I don't even want this, dawg.
Why not?
It ain't what you're taking,
it's who you taking it from, you feel me?
How you expect to run
with the wolves come night
when you spend all day
sporting with the puppies?
When you walk through the garden
Watch your back
Well I beg your pardon
Walk the straight and narrow track
If you walk with Jesus
He'll save your soul
Gotta keep the devil down in the hole
He's got fire and the fury
At his command
Well, you don't got to worry
Hold on to Jesus' hand
We'll be safe from Satan
When the thunder rolls
But you gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
Oh yeah, mm
We'll be safe from Satan
Gotta keep the devil
Down in the hole
- Keep him in the hole
- In the hole
- Down in the hole
- Keep him in the hole
- Keep him in the...
- Down in the hole
- Keep him in the hole
- Keep him in the...
- Down in the hole
- So you staying with Royce, I see?
- What you mean?
Oh, man.
Makes sense since I know
you got your fill of Carcetti.
They've been puttin' up
a crop of these things
on every lawn on the block.
And as fast as I take 'em down,
they bring more.
That's what they do this time of year.
I see you're at your leisure.
I work two nights a week,
three day shifts and no weekends.
I'm off till this afternoon.
You're good with it?
It ain't the Hopkins gig, but it'll do.
Pullin' 52, good bennies,
got a take-home car.
I mean the hotel manager's
a pain in the ass, but still.
Well, if you was a bit free,
I heard something.
This thing over at University
of Maryland School of Social Work -
- they got a grant. Big money.
- Just stop.
Half a million to look at
repeat violent offenders.
Clinical intervention, all that mess.
So they gonna study some shit, huh?
Melvin, I had me a good helping
of them downtown, tie-wearing,
come-to-do-good, stay-to-do-well
college types last year.
You sure? Cos I sold 'em on it,
should you want it.
Bunny, you're a big man
down on the campus.
You the police that legalized it.
The college boys loved that mess.
Nobody else did, though.
Well, I tried.
You did.
Yo, blacktops, pandemic.
Pandemic, got that pandemic.
Pandemic.
My mack, pandemic,
blacktops right here.
That's my boy, right?
Ain't taking no handouts,
but he workin' for it.
See what I mean?
This nigger's made
a little something out of this corner.
Now hold on, son.
We're just talking now.
- All right?
- Man, y'all did good with this spot.
You a rightful hustler.
What's your name again, man?
Boney? Biddy?
- What's it now?
- You know my name.
Yeah, but now here's the thing.
With this spot all built up and shit,
we need it, yo. Yeah.
- What?
- Two choices -
you can start taking our packages
or you can step off.
My man Chris
is gonna holler at you, all right?
You tell him what it need to be.
Don't wait for the pandemic.
It's right here, y'all.
Don't sleep on the pandemic.
I want to know more
about that boy right there.
Got good signs on him.
Big paws on a puppy, huh?
Yeah, big paws on a puppy.
To a T.
Get that blacktop before you flop.
Get that pandemic.
The truth is we don't know why he was killed.
It could have had to do
with him being a witness
or it could be unrelated.
Now, whoever leaked that shit
to Carcetti's camp,
- they lied on us.
- Yeah, well, that's it.
Eight points -
close as Carcetti gets.
He wants to go big dick with me?
I'll show him one he can't handle.
We put it out there,
anyone contributing to both sides
gets frozen out of my next term.
- No one rides the middle anymore.
- Done.
Next, I want DPW and HCD out there today
tearing down all Carcetti's signs.
Any lamppost, median,
any city-owned buildings,
unless the homeowner's
out there arguing, tear it down.
- Done.
- Third, I want Transport
camped outside of
Carcetti's headquarters.
Any car, any violation,
the meter flag goes up,
- inspection sticker - tow it.
- Done.
Next, you two, slow it down.
Nothing else comes out about that murder
until after the primary.
And I want both of you
to go to the press
and talk down that witness angle.
Take the full weight either way it goes.
Clarence, I'm running dead even
with Bond right now.
How are you gonna be running,
I drop you from the ticket?
OK, that's it. Thank you, gentlemen.
Go to it. Now.
Mr. Mayor.
- What?
- Carcetti has a point.
I went down to Annapolis,
got matching funds for witness protection.
You didn't earmark a dime
to put 'em into play.
- Next fiscal year.
- Don't claim poverty on this.
We're only talking a quarter of a million.
I match those funds now and that
motherfucker's got a campaign highlight -
"Tommy Carcetti expands
witness protection program.
"Fought for and won extra funds."
Hell with that!
I go after that state-match funds
after the election.
Nah, I paid for three pills.
Look, blue shirt gets two.
- Nah, I get two.
- White shirt gets one.
- Cheatin' motherfucker.
- I get four.
Look, blue shirt gets two,
white one, no shirt one.
Y'all can take
what y'all paid for and walk away
or just walk away with nothing.
Motherfuck a refund.
No, nigger, I paid for three.
You need to rethink what putting
a hand on me's gonna get you.
You can thank your friend here
for snatching away y'all highs.
Yo, yo, hold up, hold up.
Can I get my two?
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
You don't rattle. Yo, you come up
under my wing, young'un,
you ain't gonna do nothin' but rise.
- I don't know why you thinkin' about quittin'.
- Look, man, like I already told you,
I'm all the way repaid,
and tomorrow's school.
Come on, man, what the fuck
do you want to go to school for?
What do you want to be?
An astronaut?
A dentist? A pay lawyer, nigger?
Look, check it out.
Why don't you just come
down here after school
and just work these rush hours for me?
How about that?
Hey, hey!
Thank you. I know that kind of money...
I said I know that kind of money
doesn't come easy to anyone.
No, it's just something on my end,
some construction or something... Right.
Yeah, right. Thanks again.
Two hours, 30 grand.
Am I getting the hang of this or what?
What the fuck is that?
DPW's tearing up the sidewalk
right outside our door.
You really pissed him off.
Yes, I did, didn't I?
Come on.
Door-to-door in Irvington.
- Right.
- And we got that dead witness tonight.
Yeah. Federal?
Nah, she ain't no federal.
That there a city girl.
I like shorty too. She all right...
long as she don't get in my way.
Re-up right there.
Por qué?
School ain't starting till tomorrow, right?
The little one'll be all dressed up
with nowhere to go.
You know it too, don't you, girl?
The camera.
If you go in front, they...
They're supposed to know it's me.
I'm my own trademark. You feel me?
But if they know it's you...
What, you scared on bein' made, huh?
Claro que sí.
How 'bout I put you
in a full-body bunny suit?
You'd be like a six-foot rabbit
putting a pistol in their face.
Let me get a pack of Juicy Fruit.
You look like one of them
half-soul, half-Chinese types
from Vietnam and shit.
Come again now, Mama-san.
Patience, girl.
More patience.
The guy drives a shit box.
He's got a two-bit minimart
but the back door in there is reinforced steel
and the security camera
on the street is high-end.
Not only that, but I think
I made the re-up today.
- Schoolgirl with a heavy backpack.
- Mm.
Well, I pulled Andre's phone history
trying to find Marlo's organization,
cross-referencing DNRs to other cells.
This is Fruit, this is Monk, and there's
three or four other good probables.
Not likely to find a direct line
to Marlo that way.
Andre had to go through Monk
to get to him.
No, but we might get
a cell on Chris Partlow,
or for Toad, or for one of the top lieutenants.
We're gettin' close.
Deputy pulled me downtown.
You guys aren't into any shit, are you?
No, sir.
Good he wasn't down at the ocean today.
And the subpoenas?
You won't see a page of anything
until after the primary.
After that, if a document lands
and there's no one there to read it,
will the mayor and his people
honestly give a shit?
Other than that, what can I tell you
except to get that unit back on the street?
Lieutenant, you are relieved
from command of Major Crimes.
You've done exceptional work,
and in light of that,
we want you to improve
another vital aspect of our mission.
- Sir?
- Telephone Reporting Unit.
You report there tomorrow, 0800.
Have I done something wrong?
Lieutenant Marimow
will be taking over Major Crimes.
If you need to brief him, do so promptly.
Yes, sir.
Jimmy, how's that
beach house coming?
Beach...
Um, fine, sir...
Great. Sounds great.
Hand me the colander, will you?
He's early.
You get the door, I'll do that.
- Hey!
Come in.
- Ooh, smells good.
- Spaghetti, nothing fancy.
- Côtes du Rhône?
- Yeah.
The sommelier
behind the Plexi said it was dry.
- Hey, Beadie!
- Hey, Bunk, how you doing?
Whoa, look at you!
Blonde and all.
- You like it?
- I do, I do.
- Hey, kids.
- This is Jack, that's Cary.
- This is Detective Moreland.
- Hi!
- Call me Bunk.
- Let me open this wine.
Yeah, that's right.
Let that shit breathe.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- That's all right. They hear worse.
- Yeah, no doubt.
So, you want ice in yours?
No, man, that's a double-digit vino.
- Even has a cork.
- Swell.
- I like your binders.
- Thanks!
McNulty gave them to us.
- McNulty?
- Yeah.
- Not Jimmy?
- No.
Uncle Jimmy? Jim?
- No?
Daddy? Pops?
McNulty.
Oh, just plain McNulty.
And if I take his weak-ass product,
that means I'll be makin' less money.
I only brought life to this strip because
of the good shit that y'all gave me.
I'm standing here holding my Charles Dickens
cos I ain't got no muscle, no backup.
Shit, man. Yo, if this was the old days...
Yeah, now, well,
the thing about the old days,
they the old days.
People I'm working with now...
So you want to bump with Marlo
over real estate?
You're on your own.
But if you want my advice...
I don't, man. I don't.
Bodie. Yo, Bodie.
Me? I lost the wholesale
to every crew in Winchester, homes.
Them horses takin' Marlo's shit now.
He pushin' the independents over Hilltop, too.
I lost three crews there this month.
What about the East Side?
There we got a much bigger problem,
all those ugly-ass bitches in Yankee hats
chasin' all the locals away.
I heard them New York boys
ran off most of Delroy's people,
and those that stay
gotta take they package.
Man, all this theorizing
about how it be product, not territory?
You can't talk that shit
if a nigger snatchin' all the territory
an' won't take your product.
See, the thing is
Marlo's only takin' a little bite.
Them New York cats
is like Wal-Mart comin' to town.
Me, personally,
I think it's time Wal-Mart went home.
If we gonna bump with 'em,
it's got to be all of us.
I tell you what, I'd like to see
Marlo with us in on that one.
You know what I mean?
One big Baltimore team.
Yeah, Marlo can make an inconvenient
nigger disappear, can't he?
I heard he got some kinda hookup
at this funeral home in Westport.
Coffin goes in there
needs two pallbearers.
Come out, you need eight
to carry that bitch,
you know what I mean?
Nah. He usin' them shut-up rowhouses.
Dump a body in there,
no one can tell one smell from another.
Well, whatever he doin',
he cold but he ain't stupid.
Think it's time to try again
to talk to the boy.
I hope you got better shit to say than Stringer
cos young'un ain't given
no one an ear yet.
Jimmy, you're a domesticated motherfucker.
- Yeah, guess I am.
- Ah, we're good.
How's everything at the port?
- Quiet.
- It's quiet everywhere.
- Even the Western.
- Yeah.
I'm having a hard time with it,
somethin' ain't right.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
- You working something?
- Yeah, I got this one case.
I know who the shooter is
but can't find him.
He'll turn up.
Maybe.
More?
- Oh, mercy. No, ma'am.
- Dessert?
I was thinking
we might go out for a little taste.
Unless you got to tuck in the kids.
- I don't know.
- Oh, it's fine, Jimmy. You go.
I'll tuck 'em in.
She trusts you.
Yeah.
Can't go to dinner without
catching a page, huh? What now?
Her john jumps in the shower.
She rummages his wallet.
He figures it out and beats on her
till the people next door call the front desk.
Sir, if she doesn't have the money on her,
I don't know what I can do.
Did you beat that woman in there?
I just want my money back.
Excuse me, Mr. Gergen, I need a moment
with my director of security.
If she presses charges,
I'm cuffin' that motherfucker.
This is a delicate matter.
Delicate shit.
Mr. Gergen represents a national
consortium of convention planners,
and he's been a friend of the hotel...
Mr. Colvin? Mr. Colvin?
Now, you took his cash
and he beat you good, huh?
How much he beat you for?
How much?
Give me the cuffs.
No, Mr. Colvin. I...
What the fuck is this?
She steals my money
and you're gonna lock me up?
You're gettin' charged with assault.
You charge her with the theft,
I'll put the cuffs on her too.
- But you in the wagon, shitbird.
- This is not acceptable...
- No. He's goin' in a wagon.
- Mr. Colvin, I have to insist.
30 years a police officer,
I never took cuffs off a right charge.
- Ain't about to start now.
- You're not a police officer, Mr. Colvin.
You work for us.
Nah, I'm good.
You nursin' that thing like a baby bird.
You know those little corner joints
in the ghetto
that sell subs,
and fried chicken, lake trout?
Lake trout?
Like egg creams in New York.
No eggs, no cream.
Exactly.
No lake, no trout.
They're pogies. Whitefish, trash fish.
Exactly. White trash fish.
"Lake trout." That's all marketing.
It's just all dressed up like something it ain't.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Sometimes it is what it is.
It really is.
That's deep.
- I like the way you think.
- Yeah, you too.
Hold on.
Dang, Bug, if you can tie one shoe,
you can tie the other one.
You hear me?
Cookies all on your face.
Come on.
What up, shorty? Ready for the first day?
Yeah, he can't wait to be
in the third grade. Ain't that right, Bug?
What's up?
Dukie.
Cool.
Look at all these big-ass
eighth graders out here.
Look like some sixth graders
gonna get banked.
Come in here.
I wanna show y'all somethin'.
Go ahead, Bug.
Yo, what up, boy?
That jersey's crazy, son.
Where you get that at?
Yo, check it. This dude in the joint
with my father drew these.
- I'm about to get one on my arm.
- Is this you?
Why would you get yourself?
In case you forget what you look like?
Yo, what do these mean, man?
A'ight, this one means "heart",
like, you know, "He got heart".
- That means "lion."
- How you know?
Word, the dude could be playing you.
Like, this one, instead of heart,
it could mean like bitch or somethin'.
And like this one,
it could mean, like, pussy or clown.
Come on, man.
Fuck y'all motherfuckers.
- They probably do, too.
- Get outta my house.
Understand something about me -
I may be wearing these bars
but I worked the bricks to earn 'em,
and I am stone-cold police
first, last, and always.
Froze my balls off in the winter,
sweated 'em in the summer,
ran, jumped,
rolled in the dirt
with the bad guys 24/7/365.
Now, I'm a great admirer of this unit.
Avon Barksdale.
That was a 14-point buck you bagged.
However, we are gonna do better.
And if there's a case to be made out there,
we'll make it together
with good work
and good supervision of that work.
I want to be briefed every step of the way.
Questions?
No?
Good.
Yo, who you got?
I got...Prez... Prez-what?
I got Mrs. Scott.
Fuckin' hate that foul bitch, man.
She ain't that bad.
At least you ain't got Sampson.
- Yeah, I know.
- Yo, Michael, who you got?
Man?
Presborowski... Pres...
Yo, he new and white.
We got it made.
Uh-oh, look at this.
Where is your fine take-home car?
Got took home.
We need to talk.
Sixth grade is on the first floor!
Seventh grade is on the second.
Eighth-grade homeroom
is on the third floor!
Don't go up the down staircase.
Quickly and quietly, people.
I see you, Quantell.
I see you too.
School's getting ready to start. Come on.
Hi, dear. Good to see you back.
Yo, what up, Turner.
You back for more?
Aw, damn, man.
I love the first day, son.
Everybody all friendly an' shit.
Namond Brice.
Already, we're starting?
Damn, man.
Next time, they stay in my drawer.
Yo, whatever, man.
I know, right? Already, son.
Yo, what up?
Damn, man. These kids is crazy, son.
- I know, right?
- We're seventh graders.
Yo, dang. You see Neesy?
Yo, them bitches is on steroids, word.
Word, son.
Send them bitches to Iran.
That shit'd be over in a heartbeat.
OK, check the chart
to see where you're sitting.
Check the chart.
Hi, I'm Randy.
How are you doing, Randy?
Check the chart.
Bunny! Bunny!
OK. Good morning.
OK, good morning.
Yo! Shut up!
Good morning.
I'm your homeroom teacher, obviously.
My name is Mr. Pryzbylewski.
But you can call me Mr. Pryzbylewski.
OK. Let's find out who you are.
This is Ms. Donnelly.
We had trouble with first bells, so expect
the class change to ring in one minute.
Students will walk, not run,
to classes in an orderly manner.
OK...um...
We'll, uh...
We'll get to know each other
a little later.
Sorry. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Latifah.
All right. Sorry.
Where my bus passes at?
- Crystal Judkins, you're not listed.
- Crystal? I look like Crystal to you?
I'm Charlene.
- Ronald Parker?
- Heh.
Karim Williams.
Ronald over there.
- Oh, Jeez.
- Um, yo, Mr. Prez,
I need a hall pass for the bathroom.
It's an emergency.
Everyone, I need those bus passes back.
Hold on. Whoa.
Everyone, stay where you are.
Stay where...
I need those passes back.
It's an emergency.
Mr. Prez...
Everyone, I need those bus passes back.
The kids that need them...
- Mr. Prez...
- What? Just take one.
- I need those bus passes back!
- No one leaves this room
until Mr. Pryzbylewski
gets those bus passes back.
Do I need to say that twice?
Thank you. Thank you.
You'll get the hang of it.
Come in.
Are you coming in or what?
I'm coming in, OK?
You asked to see me, sir?
I did.
Seeing as how
I like to know my boys in depth...
why'd you want this unit?
Honestly?
I took the sergeant's test,
scored pretty high but not high enough.
And Lieutenant Hoskins -
we went through the academy together -
he said that this is a good detail
for going up the ladder.
I know you have to do it for a while
but maybe next year,
if I do good here,
they'll reach down for me.
Next year, huh?
For some things, that's a long time to wait.
Excuse me?
I hear you're a good cop.
I also hear you recognize
who your friends are
and that you're loyal to them.
Did I hear all that right?
Absolutely.
Where are you on the list?
32.
They took 15, but...
Man, I thought you were gonna say
something like 60, or, you know, 95.
Hey, let me call my man Burrell.
No need in wasting good police like you
chauffeuring around politicians.
I don't even know what to say,
Mr. Mayor. This...
This is unexpected.
Don't mention it.
Today being the first day,
let's have some fun.
I'm gonna throw you a little math puzzle,
see if I can get you thinking on your feet.
Andre is leaving Baltimore...
Mr. Prezbo, I need to change my seat
cos this boy here
smells like a garbage can.
You need to work a little
on your compassion skills.
Yeah, and he needs to work a little
on his soap-and-water skills.
All right, like I was saying,
my friend Andre is leaving Baltimore.
He's going 60 miles an hour...
Hey, what side of Baltimore,
east or west?
- It doesn't make any difference.
- That's what you think.
OK, east.
West, OK?
OK. Uh...
And he's going to Philadelphia...
- Man, Philly's ass.
- You think Allen Iverson is ass?
- OK, stop.
- He only play for them, he ain't from there.
I'd never play for the Sixers
no matter how much they pay.
Nigger, they'd pay yo' ass to go away.
Enough!
OK, Andre's leaving Baltimore,
West Baltimore, traveling 60 miles per hour.
He's going to Philadelphia,
which is 80 miles away.
- What kind of car?
- He drivin' on I-95,
he need to watch out for the state police.
They be profilin' niggers.
He ain't say Andre was black, yo.
C'mon, Randy.
Andre from the West Side?
- He ain't say he was black.
- Yo, you know he black.
OK.
I said OK!
Mr. Prezbo.
You say he travellin' in a car.
Is he driving or is he, like, in the back seat?
All right, you know what?
Fun is fun...
Hey!
Take your seats! Everybody sit down!
Everything OK in here?
Why isn't Officer Massey present?
Working overnight on the wire.
Attendance at all office meetings
is now mandatory. Inform her.
And this Marlo Stanfield?
This the best we can do?
- Sir?
- This is the guy
we're wasting months chasing with a wiretap?
We could be out doing
a dozen other different things.
Stanfield is a comer.
He's got a lot of West Side real estate.
How many bodies on him?
He fought a war against
the Barksdales last year but nothing recent.
Nothing recent?
He owns West Baltimore
but with no bodies?
Maybe it's just me,
but in 18 years out there,
I have never seen
a carnivore eat a carrot.
He's been quiet for a time...
"For a time"?
This city's up to its hips in blood
and you are sitting on one guy with a history?
OK, here's the new world order, guys.
I want good, quick rips.
Six, ten, twelve felony cases a month.
That means no more long-ass wiretaps,
no more subpoenas,
no more mincing around on shit.
We get out on the street
and come back with stats.
The Barksdale case is closed
and when the Stanfield wire comes up,
we close that as well. Understood?
The hell with this.
We got a wiretap up, and a judge
decides when it comes down.
Well, Detective,
the Deputy Ops is gonna
talk to you about that.
Table B. Put those cards away.
Kareem Myers. Sit down.
Yo, yo, listen, listen.
Kit Kats a dollar,
Snicker bars a dollar,
Warheads a dollar,
Twizzlers a dollar.
Sour Patch 50 cent, and gum 50 cent.
Anything you can get at the store,
I can get in here for y'all.
Gummy bears?
Ain't a problem.
I got Snickers, M&Ms.
Check the price and come holler at me.
I'm doing a three-for-two discount
and I'm taking orders for tomorrow.
So, if you want something special,
just come holler at me.
There it is, yo.
Qué pila de mierda.
Why not give me a water pistol?
You just worry about
how we gonna do. It'll play.
Oye, gordo! The package.
Avanza, cabrón.
With that raggedy-ass piece?
Nigger, is you crazy?
Loco or something?
Don't you know the shit is bulletproof?
You don't understand...
You heard what the boy said.
An' a box of Newports.
Where my change, yo?
Don't wild me.
Hey, yo, you see the look on his mug?
That's the reason
why we get up every morning.
OK.
OK, OK.
Now, Andre's friend Yvonne
is supposed to meet him in Philadelphia.
Yeah. Andre gonna bone that skank.
Can you shut up? Mr. Prezbo
is tryin' to teach us somethin'.
You shut up, bitch.
He ain't teachin' me nothin'.
Yvonne, though, is coming from New York.
So...my question for you is -
A, who arrived in Philly first,
Andre or Yvonne?
And B, by how much time?
Prezbo!
And C...
who gives a rat's ass?
With this grant the mandate is not only
to rethink how we utilize institutions
but to help us start getting past
having to rely on jail
and drug rehab as our only responses.
We're looking for a specific target group
to inoculate, epidemiologically speaking...
Doctor, pardon me, I'm not an academic.
Not by a long shot, but...
what exactly are you saying here?
He's sayin' he's got a lot of money
to come up with some way
to go at those boys out there
bangin' on the corners.
That's what I mean, yes.
So where do I come in?
If the salary is suitable, your duties
would be to perform as a field researcher,
a liaison operating
in the urban environment.
You go out in the 'hood
and get him some corner boys to mess with.
This is why I need somebody
like you to be paired up with me.
I go out there on my own...
They sell your tenured ass for parts.
In so many words.
Anyway, um, we're looking
for 18 to 21 -year-olds.
This is where we see
the demographic peak in violent behavior.
You excuse us for a minute?
What happens
when you ain't around to translate?
Don't play ignorant on me, Bunny.
You can back-and-forth with any
of these guys. I've seen you work.
Besides, it's clear,
you ain't cut out for the private sector.
18 to 21?
By that age they're deep in the game.
He's fucked on that.
So show him.
50,000, 80-20 health plan
and a take-home vehicle.
I'd be amazed if they
give you 30, an HMO
and a bus pass.
OK. See you later.
I go in there now,
you know what that makes me?
Some asshole politician
who's running for office.
Watkins. 40th District.
- You call the reporters?
- All three channels and The Sun.
My condolences.
- I'm Thomas...
- I know who you are.
Thanks for your respects.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
We shouldn't be here today
just because...
your son came forward as a witness.
What do you mean?
I know it's...
I'm just sorry for your loss, that's all.
A parent's worst nightmare. I don't know
how anybody can go on after this.
Yeah, me neither.
Ms. Daniels.
Councilman.
How's things over in the 11th District?
Harder than I'd hoped for.
Even on the mayor's ticket.
Yeah. Eunetta's pretty well entrenched.
Good luck with it, though.
The council sure could use you.
Councilman Carcetti,
can you give us a minute?
Look, guys, I'm sorry, you know.
Now's not the time.
I don't really have anything to say.
I'm sorry.
You don't want coverage?
Are you insane?
We'll get time on the 11:00 from the visual
but I start making speeches right here? Now?
- How's that gonna look?
- This is pretty fucking lame political theater.
Yeah, well, you know,
that depends on the audience.
This is Shawn Williams.
Lieutenant Mello,
please call shift commander.
Boss, you want me to stay?
No. We're good.
So, Shawn...
You police.
He ain't.
Shawn, how old are you?
18. How old are you,
you shiny-head motherfucker?
- You got a sister, Shawn?
- What the fuck you want with my sister?
What the fuck's this Chuck E. Cheese
lookin' motherfucker writing?
Let's say you hear that
your sister was assaulted.
- Who fuckin' with my sister?
- She wasn't. I'm just saying...
Sayin' what? Why you
fuckin' with my head, motherfucker?
And this bitch is writing again.
- It's a habit.
- Now, what would you do
if you heard your sister
got beat up by some guy?
Which sister? Cos if it's Cherise,
she probably had it coming.
All right, another sister then.
Danielle? I'd fuck that guy up.
I'd fuck his ass shut.
- With you in jail.
- I'd get my boy to do it.
What if you didn't have no boy?
I'd get the nigger myself when I get out.
- What if you had a life sentence?
- Then I'll fuckin' escape.
And put that fuckin' pen down
before I shove it up
your motherfuckin' ass.
What if you couldn't escape, Shawn?
Fuck you.
Would you go to the police?
Just a question.
Son, thanks for being you.
Thanks.
Look, I'm ready to acknowledge that...
18-to-21 might be too seasoned.
How you fixed for juveniles?
Right now? Fresh out.
The van to baby booking just left.
Are you looking for kids in the system
or just kids?
If it's just kids,
you got Douglass around the corner.
High school?
That's what, 15 to 18, right?
Yeah, but I would...
I'd go younger even.
- Kima. What's up, girl?
- Are you sure?
Come on. I'm the one
who took you out of the Eastern,
sent you to the show.
You can't come back here,
you too good for a district.
I need a home, Major.
If you need to make a move,
move up or at least lateral.
But a district is you going backwards.
And you don't need to be
under my wing, either.
You're gonna be valued
no matter where you land.
Let me talk to people.
I especially liked the timing
for when you flew your paper.
Shrewd.
I couldn't see anybody shutting us down,
not with the elections.
What asshole would risk the headline?
But to gut us from the inside out...
Charlie Marimow. My Trojan horse.
And now, let me guess,
to save your wire,
you're prepared to go to Judge Davis.
If my memory serves,
this isn't the first time
a Deputy Ops felt the need to bury you.
You have a gift for martyrdom.
I wonder, though,
are your disciples as keen for the cross?
In your final court report,
it would be prudent to tell the judge
the investigation hit a dead end.
I doubt you'll believe it, but...
I respect the effort.
You're a hell of an investigator.
It would be too much to expect you
to serve under Lieutenant Marimow?
The man's a virus.
Homicide, then.
That's you, right?
Yeah.
I know it's hard right now, Detective, but...
try to think on this as a favor.
This seems right.
Yeah.
So, I understand my old unit's gone
to Lieutenant Marimow.
Yes, it has.
So that unit is...
- Yes, it is.
- That's a shame.
I need to ask if you can
take care of my girl Greggs.
She's a good cop looking for a home,
- and I think she'd be a natural homicide.
- Hm.
Well, there was an opening.
Oops. Just filled that last night.
Another fugitive from Major Crimes.
But...
for you, Major...
let me see who I don't love no more.
OK, so, if a rocket travels, say,
1,000 miles an hour,
how far does it go in an hour?
Darnell.
Chiquan?
As far as it wants.
I mean, it's a rocket ship, right?
- Randy?
- Is this a trick question?
No.
1,000 miles?
On the money.
Oh, Mr. Prezbo, I was gonna say that.
Go ahead, bitch.
Laugh at me now.
Please, please, please!
What? You want some?
You on the fucking floor, bitch.
Laugh at me now.
Hey!
I don't hear shit.
Crystal, have the office call 911
and get the nurse.
Everybody in your seats.
Just lay still. Just lay still.
Just keep putting pressure on it.
You're doing fine.
Chiquan, you're doing fine.
Just hold on for a couple more minutes.
It's gonna be OK. It's gonna be OK.
You're gonna be all right.