(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Miss, can I help you?
I think it belongs
to that woman who came in early.
Maybe there's a reward for finding it.
You wouldn't think
a lock that good would just pop.
No I.D. on any of this stuff.
Weird, huh.
What should we do with it?
Eh, we'll worry about it tomorrow.
It's late.
- Pizza?
- Sounds good.
Whoa there, Mr. Wayne. Anything wrong?
No, just trying to get out
before they set the night alarms.
No problem, sir.
I'll walk you to your car.
Thanks.
The alarm system makes me nervous.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Did we set it off by accident?
No, sir. It's from upstairs.
What the heck is that thing?
Better not take any chances.
Right this way, sir.
Now, for your own safety
you stay put, Mr. Wayne.
Stay put?
I don't think so.
(BOTH COUGHING)
(STRAINING)
(SCRAPING)
Home.
(BEEPING)
Intruder rectifier. Now.
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
I do wish you wouldn't be so rough
with your toys, Master Bruce.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Wayne Manor. Moment, please.
Mr. Lucius Fox, Master Bruce.
Shall I out him on the speaker phone?
Thank you, Alfred.
Lucius, what's up?
Bad news, my friend.
They got away with all the prototype
protein silicon wafer chips from R&D.
The design specs?
Still safe in the computer,
thank heaven.
The thieves won't be able
to duplicate the chips without them.
Maybe we should discuss
tightening security
in case they come back.
You're right.
10 minutes, Lucius. Thanks.
Protein silicon what, Master Bruce?
I's called Wetware.
The cutting edge of computer research.
Sounds more like a line of swimsuits.
I'm talking about AI.
Artificial intelligence.
The missing link
between computers and human thought.
You mean machines that think?
Yes, and with a will of their own.
They could process raw data
a million times faster than we.
It'll still be able
to make the leaps of intuition
that inspired our greatest minds.
Sounds as if the human race
will become quite expendable.
Except for butlers, of course.
Of course.
GORDON: When I told the mayor
about the nature of the theft,
he insisted I oversee the investigation.
Question is, where could
the thieves hope to sell this stuff?
Beats me.
Only other group
researching AI on this coast
is Karl Rossum's team at Cybertron.
I thought Rossum was retired.
BRUCE: Karl went into semi-seclusion
after the loss of his daughter.
He taught me
everything I know about electronics.
But he's been
more active in business lately.
I'll talk to him.
Dad, you in here?
Oops, bad timing.
Barbara, come in. You've grown.
It's been, what, four years?
Home from college for a visit.
Made the dean's list.
BRUCE: And who's your little friend?
(CHUCKLES) This is Wubby.
My best friend since 3rd grade.
Dad can't seem to pick me up at
the airport without bringing him along.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Yes, well, he knows
the way better than I.
So you go talk to Rossum
and I'll start things moving on my end.
Barbara forgot her bear.
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRUMPET PLAYING)
Bruce Wayne. I'm so glad you called.
It's been years.
I heard about the theft
of those chips, my boy.
You need better security.
Just curious if anyone's
tried to sell you any Wetware.
Afraid not. If anyone does,
of course, you'll be the first to know.
- Cappuccino?
- Yes, thanks.
I was wondering
about your own AI research.
Uh... Thank you.
Nothing like a hot Cappuccino
and a foot massage.
Now, let me show you my pride and joy.
This is my greatest achievement.
My prototype AI.
This is HARDAC.
Who?
Holographic analytical
reciprocating digital computer.
HARDAC.
HARDAC. Okay.
And you?
How rude of me. Bruce,
this is Randa Duane, my assistant.
Your hand is like ice.
Sorry, I've been in the cold room.
So tell me. What does HARDAC do?
Now, Bruce, I can't tell you
all of my secrets, can I?
Let's just say that certain...
That certain projects
are under his control.
Well, since you won't tell me
what you're working on, Karl,
maybe I can charm the details
out of your lovely assistant?
Well, you can try.
Dinner? Tomorrow night at my house?
Love to. After 8:00 though.
I'm working late.
Good. Well, I better get going.
I'll walk you out.
Randa, you did not bring me
the design specifics I needed.
There wasn't time to get them
from the Wayne Enterprises' databanks.
I'll try again tomorrow night.
Some people in high places
are becoming too curious
about this operation.
They must be dealt with.
The next duplicant is ready.
See to his placement. Tonight.
Of course.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
I'll get it, princess.
You keep hitting those books.
Yes. What is it?
What the devil?
(GROANS)
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(BODY THUDS)
Dad, you okay?
I'm fine.
Who was at the door?
Were you outside? Your hand is like ice.
I'm fine.
- Dad, are you sure you're...
- I said I'm fine.
As of last night, Karl Rossum
hadn't been approached
to receive any stolen goods.
But he knew what was stolen.
So you'll try to squeeze some info
from his assistant tonight.
Well, "squeeze" may not be
the best word.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
BRUCE: Not at all.
We're just installing
some new computer safeguards.
Well, I'll stay out of your way.
Shall we go?
After you.
(CHIMING)
Don't you like the roast, Dad?
It's fine.
That's practically
all you've said since last night.
Are you mad at me?
No, you're...
I know. I'm fine.
(CHIMING)
But the best one was the dishwasher
that turned into a Jacuzzi.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Yeah, Karl's a genius, all right.
He'd have to be to know
it was Wetware chips
that were stolen from my company.
Care to tell me about that, Randa?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Wayne here.
I'm on my way.
I have to go out.
Call Alfred if you need anything.
I'll be back soon.
They get the Wetware specs?
I don't know yet.
They dust the keys for prints?
Yeah. Nothing.
They got the file, all right.
How are these guys getting in here?
Don't worry. I uploaded
a decoy file here last night.
The real design specs file
is at my house.
- Randa.
- Yes?
The information I need
was not in that file.
Search the house.
My databanks of Rossum's memories
indicate that Bruce Wayne
always kept important backups at home.
I'll do it right now.
I heard your voice, Ms. Duane,
and thought Master Bruce had returned.
I thought you might enjoy a spot of tea.
(GROANS)
I think it's time Ms. Duane
answered some questions.
(RINGING)
Something wrong?
No answer at the house.
I better get back there.
See you later, Lucius.
HARDAC, I've definitely found something.
Bruce Wayne is Batman.
Intriguing. This data
may be useful later.
There must be a central computer.
It will have the data I need.
I see it. Prepare for interface
in one minute.
I will take it from here, Randa.
You come home.
Alfred? Randa?
Alfred!
Alfred?
Master Bruce.
Alfred, what happened?
Where's Ms. Duane?
Forgive me, Master Bruce.
I can't imagine how would I...
I must've dozed off.
I assume Ms. Duane has left.
I assume nothing at this point.
Computer, scan Batcave for...
What?
(SCREAMS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)