The mob war in Gotham continues tonight.
Rival crime families led by
Rupert Thorne and Arnold Stromwell
continue to battle
for control of the city's underworld.
- That's a nice picture of you, boss.
- Pipe down!
According to Police Commissioner Gordon,
mob violence is intensifying.
What we have here is a battle
between an older crime boss
and his younger rival
for control of the rackets in Gotham.
And in this case,
it looks like youth has the edge.
I'd say Stromwell
is about to be retired.
We'll see about that!
But the struggle
may now be taking a tragic twist
with the reported disappearance
of Arnold Stromwell's only son, Joseph.
Calm down, boss.
Remember your blood pressure.
I want my son back.
I know, Arnie. I know.
This war has to stop.
I want a meeting with Thorne,
and I want it tonight!
I'll set it up, Mr. Stromwell.
It's Thorne. He's got my son. I know it!
I know it!
Come on, buddy, you're out of here.
Huh?
Let's go.
Stromwell wants the meeting tonight.
We'll put out a sign that says
"private party."
Yeah. A going-away party.
When Arnie gets here,
we're all going to act nice-nice,
make him feel we want a truce.
All everybody has to do
is follow my instructions.
And you get the first cue, Pete.
It's got to go like clockwork.
After Pete leaves, the lights go out.
We have to the count of five
to get clear,
and it'll be all over
for Arnold Stromwell.
I'll teach Thorne to muscle in on me.
This is my town.
I made it what it is.
You got to swear
you won't squeal on me, Mike.
Gee, Arnie, you keep stealing junk,
you're gonna get caught.
Nah. Someday I'm gonna own this town.
Arnie? What are you doing?
Get off the tracks!
Arnie!
- Excuse me, Father.
- What can I help you with?
You!
It's coming down tonight, Father.
He's going to need you.
Arnold?
That's one soul
I wish I could give up on.
I don't believe
you'd give up on anyone, Father.
Please be there.
Hi, Arnie.
I'm glad we could get together.
We'll see, Thorne. It's time to talk.
I think we should talk alone.
Man to man.
Let the boys get some air.
We made the news today.
I saw. It's making things difficult.
You're making things difficult.
Come on, Arnie. This town's big enough
for the two of us.
- Where's my son?
- What?
My son! Where is he?
What have you done to him?
I don't know anything about it.
You lowlife.
You'd do anything to take over my city.
I didn't touch your kid.
I swear it, Arnie.
You know I don't mess with family.
Hey, come on.
We're getting off
on the wrong foot here.
It's a shame about your kid.
Maybe I can help.
- How?
- Well, I've got connections you don't.
Good.
Now, we can't talk on an empty stomach.
Pete, I want to see an antipasto
out here that'll knock our socks off.
No!
The boss!
- You can't go in there.
- It was a setup!
We can't do nothing now.
We've got to regroup.
Come on, before the cops get here.
Consider yourself replaced, Arnie.
It's party time.
Oh. What...
No! Where am I?
I'm alive.
You! What are you doing?
Saving your hide.
Whoa. Heavy barbecue action, man.
Wow! He's really out there.
Let me go, you caped freak!
The media's going to nail us
on this one.
What are you looking at?
Your hair. It looked better on TV.
Definitely arson, Commissioner Gordon.
A bomb.
Darn shame. They make the best cannolis.
- Anybody in there?
- There's no evidence anyone was inside.
There was somebody in there!
Batman saved his butt! I seen them, man.
He was just leaping on the rooftops,
carrying somebody on his shoulders.
I seen it!
Like a dark angel snatching the guy
from the fires of Hades, man.
Your news puts a crimp
in our celebration, Simon.
Sorry, Mr. Thorne.
But why would Batman
want to save a guy like Stromwell?
To get him to spill his guts
about the organization.
Get everyone on the street!
Check the train yards.
Find Stromwell and the Batman
and get rid of them!
All right. Why the heroics?
You've got something I want.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
Information. About the gangs.
Well, I appreciate
your saving my life and all,
but you're gonna have to come up with
a better reason for me to turn stoolie.
I'll try and deliver.
Whoa.
You're gonna pay for this!
Hey, I know this place.
I started out here.
Selling drugs.
Prove it.
- And now you manufacture them.
- Prove that, too.
Nobody twists anybody's arm
to take them, you know.
And for the record, I make candy.
Hey, what are you doing?
"Sunrise Foundation."
Means nothing to me.
What is this place?
A drug rehab center.
No. I ain't going in.
Your 10-cent tour of the city's over.
So what could it hurt?
One little look, right?
Joey!
Yes, and he's lucky. He'll pull through.
Connie! Why didn't you call me?
I didn't know until today.
I'd never have known
if it weren't for Batman.
Don't get any closer.
The nurse said not to disturb him.
I'll find the guy who got him hooked.
Just look in the mirror.
It was your drugs
and your people who sell them.
I left you to get away
from what you were doing.
Our son wasn't so lucky.
Help stop it, Stromwell.
All your power and money has bought you
is an empire of misery.
- What do you want me to do?
- Close down the organization.
Talk to the D.A.
Turn in all the records.
It has to stop, Stromwell.
It has to stop now!
Here are the records. Look them over.
These are dummy books.
Yeah. And you're the dummy.
They're both up there, all right.
Let's smoke 'em out!
You think I'd go down that easy? Ha!
I got scores to settle.
I'm big bad news.
- Always have been, always will be.
- What about Joey?
I'm getting him out of that freak ward,
so I know he'll get better.
You're fooling yourself
again, Stromwell.
You're the fool, Batman.
Now, if you just stay nice and quiet...
Tear gas!
Look out!
Stash, Freddy, get up there.
Stay here. Don't move.
Stash? That you?
Where's Batman?
Huh?
You blew it, you jerks!
Over there! It's Stromwell!
He ain't here.
He's got to be here somewhere.
Arnie, it's time to come home.
No! Get away from me.
You can't run anymore, Arnie!
Go ahead, take some.
No! You stole that candy, Arnie.
- I don't want it.
- Oh, what a mama's boy!
No! Not again!
Someday, I'm gonna own this town.
Get off!
Arnie? What are you doing?
Get off the tracks!
Arnie! Arnie!
Jump, Arnie. Jump!
Michael? Michael!
Michael! Michael!
- I'm here, Arnie.
- What are you doing here, Michael?
- I came to help you, Arnie.
- I don't need your help.
Is that a fact?
An empire crumbling.
A marriage shattered. A son lost.
Sure, you're doing fine.
Stay away, Michael.
Last time you helped me,
it cost you your leg.
Oh, I get by. Knock on wood.
You knew I was no good, Mike.
Why did you save me?
Arnie, what else could I do?
But now, you've got a chance
to save yourself.
Come on, Arnie. Do the right thing.
For yourself, for your son.
For me, your little brother.
Michael.
Your family reunion
touches me, Stromwell.
Now say goodbye.
Commissioner Gordon,
I have a statement to give you.