- How we doing for time?
- Bullock's meeting us at 2300 hours.
We'll be there
with time to spare. Relax.
Sorry. I've never worked a sting before.
It ought to be a hot one.
Hot is right. What happened?
Where's Bullock?
I don't know, but we're in deep trouble.
We've got to find Bullock.
- Detective Bullock. Are you all right?
- I'm okay.
Do you realize what this means?
Why didn't you wait for us?
- Let's go.
- Wait. More inside.
Wilkes, go after those two.
I'll check out the warehouse.
Batman!
When I'm done with you clowns,
you won't qualify as security guards!
The department works months
to nail that drug lord.
We lay out $2 million in cash
for the sting.
And in five stinking minutes,
you idiots blow it!
- Hey, I didn't blow anything.
- Well, one of you did!
Or maybe what we've got here
is three cops on the take.
- That's uncalled for.
- What? You can't be serious.
Where does he get off?
Hey, I'll tell you who's to blame.
Batman!
- You saw the Batman, too?
- Come on, Harvey, Batman's fault?
Then whose fault is it, Officer?
I don't know, but I'm sure
it wasn't Batman. He was...
Either you start coming up with
some answers or hand over your badges.
I'm telling you, Lieutenant,
Batman blew the bust.
Montoya and Wilkes were late,
so I had to go in alone.
We weren't late!
You had your chance.
All right, Bullock, let's have it.
Like I said, I had to go in alone.
I was waiting for Wilkes and Montoya
when I saw that blasted Batman
enter the warehouse.
I couldn't wait for backup any longer.
I was afraid he'd screw up the bust,
so I followed him.
Got it.
The boss was right.
Must be a couple of mil in here.
I was closing in
when this loud noise tipped them.
Must have been Batman.
What was that?
Freeze, maggots!
You're all under arrest!
- Jeez!
- Over there. Get him!
Fry, copper!
In spite of the fire,
I had everything under control
and then Batman showed up
and bungled everything.
Lucky I was there to save his butt.
It took my last bit of strength
to get us out.
- So you went in because of Batman.
- I told you. They were late.
Were you trying to beat them out
of the collar or beat them to the cash?
- Ease up, Lieutenant.
- No. You back off, Commissioner!
Gordon, this is my investigation,
so pipe down or get out!
He knows they were
supposed to go in as a team.
Bullock, I demand to know
the real reason you didn't wait
for the rest of your team.
- Bullock!
- Give me a break.
Why don't you ask them
why they were late?
But we weren't late, Detective.
All right, let's hear from the rookie.
Maybe he knows who's to blame
for this screw-up.
Well, like Officer Montoya said,
we weren't late.
When we arrived,
Detective Bullock was down.
Then the two suspects
came out of the building.
I pursued them while Officer Montoya
went into the warehouse.
When I looked into the alley...
The suspects completely vanished.
I thought I'd bought it.
Then he came flying out of nowhere.
I'd heard of him,
but I'd never seen him before.
It was incredible,
the Batman threw out his hand
and sparks flew from his fingertips.
Then he pointed his fingers...
And some kind of ray
shot out at the van.
It blew the door open.
One of the suspects staggered out.
The other must've escaped
through the loading dock.
The guy tried to bolt
and the Batman just pointed at him.
Wham! He dropped!
It was unbelievable!
Batman's on the guy in a flash.
Then the Batman says something to him.
What did he say?
I couldn't hear.
But the guy looked plenty scared
- and blurted out "Doc" something.
- Doc who?
I don't know. He just said "Doc."
We're interrogating the suspect now,
but it doesn't look like he'll crack.
Well, I think the rookie's
holding something back.
Take it easy!
He told you everything he knows!
How touching. I hope you're as good
at defending yourself
since the detective here
is calling you a liar.
Wait a minute.
Nobody's calling anyone a liar.
There's obviously a
communication problem here.
- But my officers are not liars.
- Well, someone in here is lying.
Why don't you reserve judgment
until you've heard
what Officer Montoya has to say.
All right, let's have your version.
Like I said before,
we got there on time.
Bullock was down.
He said there were still
suspects inside, so I entered.
We'll take it down
to Hathcock.
And then I heard the name "Hathcock."
Freeze! Police!
Get her.
My pleasure.
I guess Batman must have
gotten a second wind
after Detective Bullock dragged him out.
Because he was in rare form.
Behind you!
I was just about to cuff them when
the whole place started to come down.
Before I knew what happened,
Batman pushed me out of the way.
He was buried alive.
- There was nothing I could do.
- Poor Batman.
But don't feel too bad.
One of you is going to burn, too.
What we've got here is three cops
with two stories.
- I'm telling you, they were late!
- Commissioner, it's just not true.
Bullock went in early.
So you're accusing the detective
of trying to hog the collar?
He may have had good reason
for going in.
But we were not late.
So it's my word against theirs.
Now what, Commissioner?
You're all suspended
until I make my decision.
- Suspended?
- Hey, you can't...
But no, I...
I'll take your badges and your weapons.
You too, Officer.
Doc. Doc.
Dr. Hathcock. Dock!
Dock. Gotham Harbor! The dock!
I'd better tell...
No.
Hathcock. Yes!
Now it all comes together.
I wonder what the boss is gonna do
with pointy-ears up there.
Well, he's already been charbroiled.
How about we skewer him?
No. The boss figures
he's worth more in one piece.
Where is your boss?
Is he gonna keep me
hanging around all day?
Keep your cape on. He's right up there.
That's all I wanted to know.
- I thought you were...
- Not while there's unfinished business.
Come on.
Argh! Give me another clip.
Oh, boy!
Are you all right?
- Dandy.
- Then don't go away.
Count on it.
What?
I have to hand it to you, Montoya.
You and the Batman
really turned this thing around.
Yeah. What a collar.
You didn't just bust them,
you put the whole gang
out of commission.
What collar? She's suspended!
This farce has gone far enough, Hackle.
We've nailed the suspects
and recovered our money.
The investigation is closed.
Officer Montoya earned this collar.
The collar belongs to all three of us.
It was a team effort.
Gee, thanks, partner.
What was that, Bullock?
I said...
Thanks a lot, Montoya.