(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Bruce? Bruce Wayne?
MAN: Over here, Lucius.
Bruce, it's 3:00 in the morning.
Couldn't this wait?
I could've given you this stuff
in the office.
(SHUSHING)
Not out here.
Come on.
My phones are bugged.
The office, the house, everywhere.
He knows we're on to him.
LUCIUS: Daggett?
Who else? You were the one who said
he was trying to take over the company.
Yes. Insider trading.
But once you give these papers
to the DA, he'll be under indictment
before he can change his socks.
If I turn in the evidence. But I won't.
(GASPS)
You see, Lucius, the reason I want
those papers is to destroy them.
(GUN COCKS)
And now, that you've brought them,
we won't be needing you anymore.
Bruce, what's going on here?
Let's just say
I'm accepting your resignation, Mr. Fox.
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
VOICE ON POLICE RADIO:
Two-Baker-six. Two-Baker-six.
204 at Gotham Island Tramway,
south-side terminal. Respond, code 2.
Let's finish this.
Fast.
Before we have the law on our necks.
BATMAN: Too late, dirtbag.
Huh?
Who said that?
The Batman! Not him!
Where is he?
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
(GASPING)
Wayne. Bruce Wayne.
He set me up.
Cover me!
COP: Stay where you are! Don't move!
Ready on the set.
I'll go get Matt.
Come on, come on. Where are you?
TEDDY: Matt, uh, you okay in there?
(GRUNTING)
Matt?
HAGEN: Close the door!
It's Teddy, Matt.
Help me look.
It's gotta be in here somewhere.
The face cream?
You used up your last jar yesterday.
No!
I gotta have more! Now, see.
It wore off.
Look! I can't fix it anymore!
Relax, Matt.
Don't tell me to relax, you idiot!
I can't go out there like this!
Here.
Give it to me!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Huh? That's all?
I was lucky I could
hang on to that much.
(PANTING)
You were holding out on me?
I had to, Matt. If I didn't,
you wouldn't have any now.
(SIGHS)
You can't go on like this, Matt.
You hurt all the time now.
You're just my stand-in.
Nobody promoted you to nursemaid.
That stuff
makes your face like putty, Matt.
It can't be good for you.
It probably ain't good for me.
But unless I only wanna do
horror pictures,
it ain't bad for me either.
Gone!
Empty!
Only 24 hours,
then it starts all over again.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN: Mr. Hagen, we're waiting!
Keep your shirt on!
That's what ain't good for you.
Having to keep going back
to Daggett for more of that stuff,
and do whatever lousy thing
he wants to get it.
You're right, Teddy. I can't.
I'll have to find a way
to get lots of this stuff on my own.
DAGGETT: You're sure, Bell?
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER ON HEADPHONES)
You're sure that the man you hired
knows nothing about our operation?
Bell! I asked you a question.
Bell! Bell!
Germs, take off his headphones.
Pay attention.
Mr. Daggett is talking to you.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
Now, then.
Relax, Mr. Daggett.
The guy was just a hired gun.
He don't even know our names.
Thank heaven for small favors.
But Hagen has disappointed me
once too often lately.
He botched this assignment completely.
To wit, once Fox is able to talk,
he might very well incriminate us,
if the police can't figure out
what we're up to from those papers
Hagen was supposed to retrieve.
Frankly,
I think our Mr. Hagen
has outlived his usefulness.
I want him dealt with.
But, Mr. Daggett,
the man's a master of disguise.
He was even before he had his accident,
and you gave him this stuff.
Yeah. It's not easy finding somebody
who can change the way he looks.
(CHUCKLES)
You needn't bother searching for him.
This is the only place in the world
where he can get what he needs.
And when his supply runs out,
he'll come to us.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SNORING)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
BELL: Hold it right there.
Turn around, real slow.
Step into the light
where we can see you.
I'm looking for Mr. Daggett.
I don't believe we've met.
My name is Wayne. Bruce Wayne.
Wayne, huh? Yeah, right. Sure.
(GRUNTING)
Can the garbage, Hagen. We ain't stupid.
(GRUNTS)
- No!
- You're Hagen, all right.
Broke in for more of that stuff,
didn't you?
Yeah, once they're hooked,
they stay hooked.
Come on, Hagen,
we're going for a little ride.
Forget it! I know what that means!
Wait! I got an idea.
Hold him.
(GRUNTING)
Pretty boy wanted more of this stuff?
Then let's give it to him.
HAGEN: No! Not that way!
Please!
BELL: Let's give him
all he'll ever need.
HAGEN: No!
No! Don't!
Sweet dreams, slimeball.
(HAGEN GROANING)
BATMAN: I know my fist has landed
on that jaw once before.
Bell. Raymond Bell.
Of course! Now I remember him.
Carries a pocket radio,
tuned to police band at all times.
Master Bruce,
what am I to do about the police?
They shall be back, you know.
I can't keep telling them you're out.
Police? What police?
What are you talking about?
I suggest you consult
the morning paper, sir.
BATMAN: "Bruce Wayne
sought for questioning"
"in attempt on executive's life"?
But that's impossible!
VOICE ON POLICE RADIO: Two-Baker-10,
code 7 in progress, 500 North Main.
Twenty-two, code 4
at 1900 Roth Avenue, apartment B, "boy."
All units, a warrant has been issued
for the arrest of Bell Raymond.
White male,
approximately 5 feet 10 inches.
Age, mid-30s.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
All available units
divert to suspect's last known address,
3720 Burnley Boulevard.
Suspect is believed...
Armed and dangerous.
Proceed with extreme caution. Over.
BELL: (CHUCKLES) Yeah, go ahead.
Stake out my place.
It'll be a long wait, jerks.
That's it, Bell. Keep it up.
You're reacting true to form so far.
(GASPS) The Batman?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Made it! I am out of here!
Huh?
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(YELLS) No!
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (SCREECHING)
Oh, no!
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
No! For the love of mercy, Batman,
don't let me fall!
(SCREAMING)
What are you doing? Are you crazy?
Listen up, scumwad.
(AMPLIFIED)
Because I'm only gonna ask you once.
(SCREAMING)
Who was Lucius Fox meeting at the tram?
Wayne! Bruce Wayne!
You lying sleaze!
You wanna rethink that answer?
No! No!
Okay, okay, it wasn't Wayne!
Then who was it?
(SCREAMING)
Last chance.
Who was impersonating Wayne?
(PANTING)
Who, Bell? Who?
Fainted. He fainted.
This is GCPD airborne unit
six-Able-12 to Batwing.
Descend in the name of the law
and remand your prisoner
to police custody.
This should wake you up, Mr. Bell.
This is the police!
You are under arrest!
No.
Please,
leave me alone.
Lucius, it's okay. It's me, Bruce.
I have to speak to you.
Only you can give me
the answers I need now.
Lucius, take it easy.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
You know I'd never do anything
to hurt you.
(BEEPING)
Ah, there's his car. Stop here.
Matt?
Matt, are you in there?
SUMMER: And we'll have continuing
updates on this late-breaking story.
The arrest of millionaire industrialist
Bruce Wayne
at the scene of an attempt on the life
of Wayne executive Lucius Fox.
This is Summer Gleeson, WGBS News
at 11:00, live at Gotham County Jail.
Matt?
Matt, it's me, Teddy.
(BREATHING HOARSELY)
Matt? Matt?
Oh, Matt, is that you?
What in heaven's name
did they do to you?
(SCREAMING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)