Your help means a lot to us, Bruce.
And what you do
means a lot to this city.
I wish we could do more.
Lately, things haven't been going well.
Thanks. What do you mean?
I can't prove it, but I'm positive,
people are disappearing.
Transients, regulars,
old faces I miss seeing.
Then a month ago, a volunteer,
Dan Riley, disappeared.
I'm telling you, something's very wrong.
- You've talked to the police?
- Of course.
But the police have their hands full.
And homeless people disappearing
is not big news.
Hey, buddy, you looking for a job?
Maybe. What kind of job?
Oh, you'll like it.
It's long-term employment.
Hey, Riley.
Oh, boy.
- Hey, stranger.
- You okay?
I think so. Where am I?
Well, opinions differ, but we all agree.
It ain't Miami.
Don't mind him.
Every chain gang has a comedian.
I'm Dan Riley, and he's Salvo Smith.
So, what's your name, pal?
I don't know.
What is this?
If it's moving, it's a rat.
If not, it's a cooked rat.
Why aren't these lowlifes working?
They have to eat, sir.
I have to eat. They have to work.
From now on, they'll bring me
twice the gold ore.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes, sir.
We recruited some new men.
You bums better start busting butt
or you'll all end up like him.
No! Please!
I ain't done nothing! No! Please!
Please!
Now get to work, or you'll all roast.
Rise and shine.
It's a beautiful...
That's odd.
Only vampires loathe daylight
more than Batman.
I wonder what's keeping him.
- How you holding up?
- Okay, I guess.
Remember anything yet?
I'm beginning to wonder if I ever will.
Hey, you can't give up hope.
Down here it's all we've got
to hang on to.
I guess you're right.
So, what brought you guys here?
I was one of Gotham City's unemployed.
Now I got a job. Lucky me.
I was a steamfitter
at the Gotham Navy Yard.
Two nights a week, I did volunteer work
at the Dock Street Rescue Mission.
One night I was getting into my car,
and three guys jumped me.
I wound up here.
My family must be
going out of their minds.
Rescue Mission.
Cave-in!
Ah, are you okay?
Where's Salvo?
I'm over here, taking five.
Hang on, man. We'll get you out.
Take your time.
It's the first break I've had all day.
Does this sort of thing happen often?
Too often.
No, I'm sorry, sir.
Mr. Wayne was called out of town.
If you call back on Friday...
The Studebaker's gone.
I'd better activate the tracking device.
The Bowery.
Dock Street Rescue Mission.
I've never seen such lazy scum.
Now that was real funny.
Throw him in the box!
You can't. It'll kill him.
That's the idea. Now do it!
I got him! Come on!
We'll see how they like the oven.
Hey, you really cleaned their clocks.
You did pretty good yourself.
Well, maybe you used to be
some kind of fighter.
I don't know.
I just don't know.
My son, he's gonna be six on April 7th.
Or seven on April 6.
Oh, what's it matter?
I'll never see him again.
Hang on, Riley.
We'll make it.
Remember what you told me?
You can't lose hope.
I can't take it anymore!
I lost my family! My family!
My family! My family! My family!
My family!
Riley, you've got to pull it together.
We're getting out of here.
Yeah, right.
You're the one who's losing it.
Stop him!
Stop him,
or you'll all rot in the mines!
There he is.
We got him now.
He's gone into Box Canyon.
There's no way out.
Look! Up there!
Whoa!
Oh! Whoa!
This must be the place. Bring us down.
Negative.
But Master Bruce is down here.
We have to land.
Impossible. Area too confined.
Land, you bucket of bolts.
Your funeral.
Oh, dear.
Get us down!
Caution. Rocks.
Son of a gun.
Watch your step.
I... I... I claim this land for Spain.
Master Bruce.
Hurry up with that gravy!
If those fools let that prisoner escape,
I'll eat them alive.
A bat! A giant bat!
Horrible!
What are you babbling about?
What bat?
Right here.
There it is!
Batman!
Shoot him!
After him, you fools!
After him!
$1,000 to the man who bags that bat.
There he is!
Split up and fan out.
Huh?
Kill the lights!
We'll find out if this bat
can see in the dark.
Look out!
I think he went this way.
Pete, where are...
Help!
Hodges, Kurt, Howard! Are you okay?
Not exactly.
Stop him!
No! Leave me alone!
We've got to get out of here.
Stop. We'll be killed.
Stop, and we will be.
Don't let me drown!
When you taste the prison food,
you'll wish I had.
It's no palace,
but you're welcome to stay at our place
until you get back on your feet.
Thanks, Riley. Maybe this time,
we can find some work that pays.
You know, pal, it'll be tight,
but you're welcome too.
Thanks, but I...
Are we ready, Master Bruce?
Master Bruce?
Bruce Wayne. WayneTech Enterprises.
If you'd like a job,
I can probably help.
Hit me, Riley.
Hit you? Why?
Maybe I'll lose my memory
and wake up a millionaire too.