(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
BATMAN: Previously on Batman...
Who are you? How did you get in here?
I am he who is called Ra's al Ghul.
Your ward was abducted
on the same night as my daughter.
You're Talia's father?
My time is short.
I need a man to assume my position
when I am gone.
BATMAN: But why me?
RA'S: Because you are most worthy.
And because my precious daughter
loves you.
- Forget it.
- Then this means we must be enemies!
You will regret this insult, Detective.
You will... (COUGHING)
We must take him to the Lazarus Pit.
(RA'S LAUGHING EVILLY)
(TALIA GRUNTS)
Put her down, Ra's. Now!
No, Father! Ah!
We must stop him.
The chemicals can revive the dying
but will kill a healthy person.
I get it, I get it.
TALIA: No!
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH GASP)
(GRUNTS)
Stay back.
TALIA: I can handle this myself.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(YELLS)
RA'S: Thank you, daughter.
And thank you, Detective,
for my daughter's life.
You look refreshed, Father.
Renewed.
But even a miracle such as
the Lazarus Pit has its terrible price.
Yes. It offers physical rejuvenation
but the stress of the transformation
leaves one temporarily insane.
And no man may reap
its blessings indefinitely.
Which is why I must ask you
again, Detective,
will you wed my daughter
and carry on for me when I am gone?
The answer is still no.
A pity. You leave me no choice.
- (SNAPS FINGERS)
- (GUNS COCKING)
RA'S: You see, if you are not
with me, Detective,
you are against me.
Father, no!
He has seen too many of our secrets.
He knows too much
to be permitted to leave here.
But you would
destroy this place, our home?
Only a minor loss.
There is nothing here that cannot be
found in our desert stronghold.
And we must leave nothing behind
that might be later used against us.
(RUMBLING)
Farewell, Detective.
Goodbye, beloved.
(BOTH YELL)
Robin! The rope!
(ROBIN GRUNTS)
Come on!
(ROBIN YELLS)
- (EXHALES) You okay?
- Sure.
I wish I'd worn the thermal tights,
but other than that...
By the time we get down this mountain,
he could be halfway to his
desert stronghold, wherever that is.
Then we've gotta find out where.
(WIND HOWLING)
He's going to realize his dream of
a green and balanced Earth at any cost.
Even if that means destroying
half the planet's population to do it.
ROBIN: But where do we
even start looking?
BATMAN: You were his prisoner
for a week.
You must have overheard something.
Well, there was one thing.
A word I heard several times.
It was, uh... (STUTTERS)
Orpheus. Yeah, that's it.
Orpheus. From Greek mythology.
He descended into the netherworld
to bring his beloved back from the dead.
But according to the database,
Orpheus is also the name of
a privately-owned satellite
launched into synchronous orbit
over a year ago.
- Coincidence?
- Yeah, right.
DICK: What's it orbiting over?
BRUCE: What else? A desert.
The Sahara desert.
And the exact coordinates have to
be Ra's al Ghul's desert stronghold.
We're within 100 kilometers
of the target area, Bruce.
Gotta hold her steady at 500 feet
to stay under their radar,
but you can still
eject at this altitude.
Then let's do it.
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
(CHUCKLES) Huh?
(YELPS)
So you have finally arrived.
Hitch your mounts and follow me.
We must not keep the master waiting.
- Quickly. Our time grows short.
- (CAMELS GRUNTING)
You there! Did you not hear me?
What is the matter with...
Huh?
(BATMAN GRUNTS)
So my eyes did not deceive me.
You will pay for this trespass.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(GROWLS)
For this indignity,
I will see you suffer.
RA'S: Enough!
What is the meaning
of this disturbance, Ubu?
Forgive me, master, but I discovered
this most unworthy one spying.
Oh? I believe I would have a closer look
at one so foolish.
Or so brave.
(GRUNTING)
- You.
- My admiration for you
was well-founded, Detective.
Too bad I can't say the same.
- Shall I dispatch him, master?
- No.
For now, merely relieve him
of that cumbersome belt.
Oh, and search him. Make certain
that he conceals no surprises
which might enable him to escape.
(BATMAN GRUNTS)
You have nothing to lose by telling me
what you're doing here.
Yes, I suppose I do owe you
that much, Detective,
since, in many ways,
you are responsible for it.
You see, I had hoped
to achieve my vision
of an earthly utopia
gradually over time,
with my heir carrying on my work
after I was gone.
But your refusal to become my heir
has left me no other choice.
- His mask, master?
- No, leave it.
It is a mark of honor.
Even though because of him, I must
now use what I call the Lazarus effect
to achieve my utopia in one bold stroke.
BATMAN: How?
(HUMMING)
RA'S: The material of the pit
is an unknown chemical stew
that bubbles to the Earth's surface
only at certain key places.
Even now my people are placing bombs,
such as that one,
over the various Lazarus Pits
around the world.
These bombs are electronically linked
to a private satellite
already in Earth orbit.
- Orpheus.
- Precisely.
And at the moment when
sun and moon are in proper alignment
to cause the greatest upheaval
in Earth's geomagnetic field,
I shall send a signal to that satellite
beginning a countdown.
Five minutes thereafter,
one bomb will be lowered
deep into the heart of each pit.
The satellite will, in turn,
relay a microwave signal
that will detonate
all the bombs simultaneously.
The multiple explosions will result
in a global chain reaction.
All the Lazarus Pits throughout
the world will overflow.
The globe will be saturated
with their chemical solution.
And when the resultant cataclysm
has abated,
there will come a blessed peace.
And this poor, defiled planet
shall find itself restored
to its former pristine glory.
But that will cost countless lives.
Actually, Detective, we have counted.
Two billion, fifty-six million, nine
hundred and eighty-six thousand.
A most impressive plan,
would you not agree?
Yes, I can see it clearly now
for the first time.
You are completely out of your mind.
Infidel dog.
(GRUNTS)
This time I shall attend
to you personally.
RA'S: Ubu.
I would prefer the detective live
to witness the realization of my dream.
Take him to the tower
to await my moment of triumph.
As you wish, master.
TALIA: Wait.
To remember me, beloved.
Not so dangerous without
your precious belt, are you?
One can only wonder
why the master thought
it would require two of us to guard him.
(BOTH YELL)
My children, we stand
on the threshold of a great adventure.
Even now, the satellite Orpheus
is moving into proper alignment
and the moment of destiny
is finally upon us.
(ALL CHEERING)
Father, it is not too late.
Surely there must be some other way.
No, daughter.
The decision has been made.
(BEEPS)
In five minutes,
the world will be forever changed.
(ALL CHEERING)
(MUFFLED SHOUT)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
UBU: Master.
Stop him! He'll ruin everything!
(GRUNTS)
Infidel.
If you only knew how sick I am
of you calling me that.
(UBU GRUNTS)
Perhaps, Detective, it is time
that you and I finally finish this.
It is the only chance you will have
to stop that satellite.
Well?
- Are you man enough to face your better?
- If you insist.
(YELLS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SWORDS CLANGING)
Give it up, Ra's.
You'll destroy yourself.
(RA'S GROANS)
It appears that we will both
perish together, Detective.
Accept it. You have no choice.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(BEEPS)
(YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
Give me your hand.
(GRUNTS)
Victory is yours, Detective.
Perhaps it is time I am finally one
with the planet I so love.
You must understand, beloved,
I share my father's vision
and seek the same ends
but I do not choose his means
to those ends.
I know.
What's to become of me, then?
Am I to be your prisoner?
So it's finally over?
We've seen the last of Ra's al Ghul?
Looks that way.
(RA'S LAUGHING EVILLY)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)