This is how
I'll always remember you.
Surrounded by winter,
forever young,
forever beautiful.
Rest well, my love.
The monster who took you
from me
will soon learn
that revenge is a dish
best served cold.
In the midst of the hottest August
on record,
a rash of bizarre cold-related crimes
have chilled Gotham to the bone.
Once again,
the target is a GothCorp facility
attacked by an assailant
wielding what witnesses called
a "freezing gun."
The attacker's motives
remain unclear.
We spoke earlier
with GothCorp CEO
Ferris Boyle,
who offered these comments.
I don't know
what this person has against GothCorp
But we've always looked upon ourselves
as the people company.
If this man has a problem,
we're willing to listen.
A heartfelt plea from the chairman
of GothCorp,
the people company.
This is Summer Gleeson
for Gotham Insider.
Hey, get out of here!
Taking up video games,
are we, sir?
I've accessed police files
on the GothCorp raids.
These are the stolen objects.
They don't look like much alone,
but in this configuration...
My word.
They combine
into a massive weapon
able to generate intense cold.
There's still one component missing,
and only one GothCorp plant makes it.
Halt.
Stay where you are.
Look out!
We got company.
Keep your mind
on your business.
I'll handle this.
Load those canisters.
Hurry.
Are you done?
All set.
The Batman!
Put me down!
Freeze.
That's "Mr. Freeze" to you.
This is a personal vendetta.
It doesn't concern you.
It's my concern now.
Since you ally yourself
with my enemies,
you leave me no choice.
Ahhh!
Johnny!
Take it easy, man.
I got you.
Leave him.
He should have been more careful.
Now he's paid the price
for his incompetence.
But he's one of us.
Then perhaps
you'd like to share his fate.
Don't leave me.
Please!
Come back!
Help! Please!
Cold...
So cold.
I must say,
you're showing
a surprising amount
of compassion for that man
considering he would surely
have left you
to die in his place.
With all the compartments
on your belt,
you'd think
there'd be one for tissues.
Thanks.
He's pulling through.
The hot chemical bath
did the trick.
You could use a hot bath yourself.
I can't worry about a cold now.
After Batman drops
our unconscious guest
at police headquarters...
Bruce Wayne has got a meeting
with Mr. Ferris Boyle.
Bruce Wayne.
It's been forever.
How have you been?
Still the terror
of the Gotham night scene?
I get around.
Speaking of terror,
what's this about
someone causing trouble for GothCorp?
You got me.
Some fruitcake has it out
for my company.
I don't know why.
Maybe it's an investor
who lost money.
Or an angry ex-employee.
There's only one man
who'd hate
GothCorp that much,
if he were alive.
- Who?
- One of our scientists.
An obsessed wacko.
He was caught
using company equipment
for personal reasons.
I had to send my security men in.
There was a fight,
an explosion.
We lost him.
What was he doing?
Wasting company money.
My money!
Look, Bruce.
That "people company" line is great PR.
But when the wage-slaves
start acting like they own the place,
it's time to pull the plug.
Know what I mean?
Sir,
the humanitarian committee is here.
I'll be right out.
We're hosting a ceremony tonight
for Gotham's Humanitarian Industrialist
of the Year.
Guess who's winning?
I feel ill.
Hmm?
Excuse me, Ferris. My cold.
Congratulations on your award.
I'm sure it's well-deserved.
And I want to say
that these
unwarranted attacks against GothCorp
have in no way changed
our personal commitment
to the community.
Inspirational words
from Gotham's
Humanitarian Industrialist of the Year.
Humanity.
Compassion.
Charity.
Where were those pretty words
when she needed to hear them?
Faster.
The cannon must be completed tonight.
I have my own warm wishes
to bestow on Mr. Boyle.
When Ferris
mentioned that explosion,
I remembered this headline
from last year
Does it say
what caused the accident?
No.
And I suspect
that's the reason for the cover-up.
I won't know for sure until I check
GothCorp's classified files.
If you're going
to go sneaking around
a crowded office building,
you'll need this.
Knockout gas?
Chicken soup.
The only way to fight a cold.
Mr. Boyle sent me to fill in.
Enjoy yourself at the party,
with his compliments.
Hey, great.
- You okay?
- I'm fine. Take off.
My name is Dr. Victor Fries.
I am recording
what I pray
will be mankind's first step
toward immortality.
Behind me
you see the CC-100...
A cryogenic
freezing chamber of my own design.
I created it for the express purpose
of freezing subjects
stricken with inoperable ailments.
Subjects like
my own beloved wife, Nora.
Once a remedy
has been found...
Open this door!
Open it now!
Get away from that equipment!
Shut this stuff down.
Stop! This is my experiment!
Your unauthorized experiment.
I ordered
funding suspended weeks ago.
I'm already three million in debt,
thanks to you.
You can't stop it now.
My wife is in there.
So bring her out.
You can't interrupt the process now.
Open it.
It's her only chance.
This is my equipment!
Mine!
I have every legal right
to use it
or not use it as I see fit.
I say this project ends now!
No!
Stay away from her, murderer.
Victor...
I'm sorry.
I lost my temper.
It doesn't have to come to this.
We can talk.
Get out! Get out!
Nora!
My God.
Yes...
It would move me to tears
if I still had tears to shed.
The snow is beautiful,
don't you think?
Clean, uncompromising...
And cold.
Like the swift hand
of vengeance.
I saw what happened to your wife.
I'm sorry.
I'm beyond emotions.
They've been frozen dead in me.
That suit you wear...
A result of the coolant?
Very good.
A detective to the last.
I can no longer survive
out of a sub-zero environment.
Tonight, I mean to pay back
the man who ruined my life.
Our lives.
Even if you have to kill
everyone in the building to do it?
Think of it, Batman.
To never again
walk on a summer's day
with a hot wind in your face
and a warm hand to hold.
Oh, yes.
I'd kill for that.
Let's go.
Huh?
Keys?
Seal the building.
Higher. Higher.
Let the evil that walks inside
be cleansed
by pure, unforgiving ice.
And so it gives me great pleasure
to present this well-deserved award to...
Double the power.
Huh?
I will finish this.
The cold eyes of vengeance
are upon you, Boyle.
Who...
Who are you?
Come, now.
Surely you remember
your old colleague
Victor Fries.
No!
Stop. Please.
I beg you.
You beg?
In my nightmares,
I see my Nora behind the glass,
begging to me
with frozen eyes.
How I've longed to see
that look frozen on you.
The advanced circuitry
that powers my suit
also triples my strength.
Sooner or later,
all who stand in my way
must feel the icy touch of death.
Ugh. What was that stuff?
The only way to fight a cold.
It can't end this way.
Vengeance...
No.
Justice.
A year ago,
Ferris Boyle interrupted an experiment,
and in the process
destroyed two lives.
Here's the evidence.
Good night, humanitarian.
I failed you.
I wish there were another way
for me to say it.
But I cannot.
I can only beg your forgiveness
and pray you hear me somehow...
Someplace...
Someplace where a warm hand
waits for mine.