By the end of October 1942,
the city on the Volga still has not fallen.
The Führer announces to the German people,
"We have taken Stalingrad.
A few pockets of resistance remain.
We will take them one by one.
It is just a question of time."
For Hitler, Stalingrad has come
to represent his victory over Russia.
ALLIES STRIKE BACK
After 2 years of fighting in Russia,
the Germans have threatened to vanquish
the "Eastern Giant".
In the north,
Leningrad is surrounded by the Germans.
It has been a year since the Germans entered
this northern city.
In the center, Moscow, the target city,
remains just within reach for the Germans.
In the south, the drive towards
the Baku oil fields
has come to a halt in the Caucasus mountains.
In Stalingrad,
the Soviets are holding their ground.
Contrary to Hitler's declarations,
Soviet boats continue to cross the Volga,
bringing over reinforcements.
Everyday, thousands of young Russian men,
sometimes without any weapons
or military training
are disembarked on the riverbanks.
Those who back away from the German shells
are ruthlessly executed
by the political commissars.
On the 7th of November,
the anniversary of the revolution,
the beleaguered soldiers holding Stalingrad
and the Soviet troops all along the front,
listen to their commander-in-chief, Stalin,
make this astonishing declaration:
Tomorrow, there will be celebrations
in our streets.
And indeed, general Zhukov,
the man who saved Moscow
has a plan to keep those pockets of resistance
fighting to the very end
in order to retain the German troops
of general Paulus inside Stalingrad.
On the other side of the Volga, Zhukov is
secretly putting together an entire army.
The country has been ravaged,
one-fourth of its territory lost.
But the entire Soviet Union is toiling away
to provide this new army with huge amounts
of equipment.
Factories that were moved out
and rebuilt behind the Ural mountains
are operating 24 hours a day.
In this endeavor, lives will be sacrificed.
It is the winter of 1942.
The women working in these unheated,
sometimes ruthless workshops,
are cold and hungry.
Many will die of exhaustion.
But the country's industrial production
will increase tenfold.
The United States is now providing
massive amounts of aid to the Soviet Union.
The Allies are able to reduce the threat,posed by
the German submarines in the North Atlantic
by forming protective convoys to Soviet ports,
such as Murmansk.
Anti-communism is put on hold.
For the Americans,
Joseph Stalin is now, "Uncle Joe"
and for the British, "Good Old Joe".
The Russians receive huge shipments
of jeeps, tanks, planes, and trucks.
And cans of corned beef.
When they open the tins of meat,
the Russian soldiers joke,
"We're opening the second front."
Along with Stalin, everyone expects the Allies
to do more to alleviate their plight.
In Egypt however, the British are being
threatened by the Germans.
Rommel, whom Hitler just promoted to
Field Marshall after his victories in the desert,
and his tank army, the Afrika korps,
are getting dangerously close
to the Suez Canal.
They have reached El Alamein.
The British Empire is in peril.
The British Prime Minister, Winston Churchill
comes to encourage his army in the desert.
The situation is grim,
but he retains his sense of humor
and shares cheerful moments with his men.
He meets with the newly appointed
general Montgomery.
Montgomery wasn't Churchill's first choice.
And all of these soldiers in the desert
are a little worried.
The British, the Australians, the New Zealanders,
the South Africans and the Free French.
As soon as he arrived, Montgomery,
the son of a clergyman,
ordered a new program of strict rules
and discipline to be imposed.
He is cautious,
he waits until his army is superior
in terms of both men and equipment.
The new American Sherman tanks
for example, built for speed and power.
Montgomery launches his offensive
with a preliminary artillery barrage,
followed by a massive tank assault.
But the German 88 flak guns
cause tremendous losses.
Rommel's soldiers counterattack relentlessly.
The battle turns into a bayonet charge
just like in the Battle of the Somme in 1916,
with heavy casualties on both sides.
In this deadly game, it is the side
with the most men that wins.
In a letter to his wife, Rommel writes:
We're simply being crushed
by the enemy's weight.
He receives a message from Hitler:
There can be no other thought than
to stand fast, yield not a yard of ground.
Rommel writes back to his wife:
I wracked my brains for a way
of this plight for my poor troops.
We are facing, perhaps the most
difficult days that a man can undergo.
And he adds: The dead are lucky.
It's all over for them.
Rommel retreats.
In London, Churchill announces
to his fellow citizens
what is really the first good news of the war.
Now this is not the end.
It is not even the beginning of the end.
But it is, perhaps, the end of the beginning.
Churchill's words ring out around the world.
The old British lion has stood up to Hitler.
Back in his headquarters, the Wolf's Lair,
Hitler is scornful.
He says, "It is just a set-back.
The war will go on."
And indeed it does.
The Allies open up a new front in North Africa.
A first step towards controlling
the Mediterranean.
As in 1917, American troops sail across
the Atlantic.
The French writer, Antoine de Saint Exupery,
who is exiled in New York,
will return from the US with one
of these military convoys.
The author of the "Little Prince" writes:
Friends in America,
I'd like to do you complete justice.
50,000 soldiers were going to war
not only for the United States
but for humanity, for human respect,
for human freedom and human greatness.
Off the coast of Casablanca and Oran,
the British and Americans are greeted
with cannon fire from the Vichy French.
They counterattack.
North Africa is still controlled
by the Vichy regime
which collaborates with the Germans.
The fighting is violent and the Vichy forces
suffer extensive damage.
The Free France Leader, general de Gaulle,
makes a speech over the radio in London:
To the French leaders, soldiers, sailors,
airmen, civil servants.
French colonials on North Africa,
I say, rise up!
Help our Allies!
Join them without hesitation.
After 2 days of fighting against the liberators,
the guns are silenced.
The Allies secure their landing.
In Algiers, the pragmatic
US commander-in-chief, general Eisenhower,
negotiates with the Vichy regime's
military commander, admiral Darlan.
Darlan is one of
France's most die-hard collaborators
who had even met Hitler.
He decides to switch sides.
And the French forces in Algeria and Morocco
join the Allies.
A few weeks later, Darlan will be assassinated
by a French resistance fighter.
Many of the French in North Africa
greet the Americans warmly.
The "Zouaves" in the French army of Africa
are also relieved.
They never really want to shoot
the Americans.
In fact, they will soon be fighting
side-by-side with them.
Like almost all of the others French colonials.
As will the "indigenous soldiers",
as they are called at the time
who will form the Moroccan and Algerian
"Tirailleur Units".
The Axis Power has anticipated the Allies
by moving into Tunisia,
a territory still controlled by Vichy regime,
which allows Germans to stay.
Rommel is retreating towards Tunisia.
Two days later, in order to secure
the Mediterranean coast,
Hitler invades southern France,
the hitherto unoccupied free zone.
Hitler's orders are to take the port of Toulon
where most of the Vichy navy is based.
With their shaky autonomy now at risk,
the Vichy admirals decide to scuttle their fleet.
They proceed to sink their own ships,
in order to keep them from falling
into the hands of the Germans or the Allies.
That is the tragic result
of the politics of the Vichy regime.
But it's not good news for Hitler.
With the arrival of the Germans, those Jews
hiding in the remaining pockets
of French tolerance
have little chance of survival.
Amidst the increasingly sinister atmosphere
of round-ups
and denunciations all over Europe,
children are saved by courageous families.
Like Carl de Brouwer's family.
He is a Belgian banker.
He films his 4 children, while he and his wife,
Denise, hide 2 Jewish children.
Monique Mogoulsky,
the 12 year-old daughter of an engineer
who is hiding somewhere himself.
And 6 year-old, Adrien Sapcaru.
Adrien's mother was arrested and deported
to a work camp in eastern Europe.
She will never return from Auschwitz.
By now, many people suspect that when
the occupiers use words like "Work camp",
its true meaning is death.
Carl and Denise du Brouwer
are everyday heroes
who will one day be awarded the title of
"Righteous among the Nations"
along with more than 20,000 other men
and women from all over occupied Europe.
3.000 km away, outside of Stalingrad,
the Germans have been enjoying
a brief respite behind the lines
before returning to fight the Russians
in order to eliminate their remaining pockets
of resistance.
The German army's flanks are defended
by units from the Reich's satellite countries.
Romanians, Hungarians and Italians
who are totally unaware of the danger
looming just around the corner.
A few km away, the Soviet troops
are preparing to attack.
They are ready to fight
and there are over a million of them.
They are going to storm
the enemy's weakest units
in order to surround the German army
occupying Stalingrad.
At 7 AM,
the Soviets obliterate the enemy's lines.
Pounding them with the rocket launchers
they call "Stalin's organs".
Zhukov's massive army launches the offensive.
The Hungarians
don't have enough ammunition.
The Romanians don't have any anti-tank weapons.
They, as well as the Italians,
lost a massive number of men.
The two Soviet armies from the north
and the south meet up.
Soviet filmmakers use their skills
to glorify the moment.
The Germans see the Soviet tanks
close the circle around them.
General Paulus's 6th Army is trapped
inside Stalingrad.
Hitler is in the Berghof, his retreat
in Berchtesgaden in the Bavarian Alps,
where he is informed of the Soviet offensive.
His immediate reaction is to hide this news
from the German people.
He rushes off to his headquarters
in East Prussia, declaring,
"If the 6th army withdraws from Stalingrad,
the Wehrmacht will never be able to return."
Paulus could still break out of the encirclement
but he would have to obey orders.
For when Hitler arrives at the Wolf's Lair
he sends him this message:
Stand firm, an army will come to rescue you.
But no army is able to reach them.
And the aeroplanes of the Luftwaffe,
fail to deliver sufficient supplies
in spite of the promises made by
the Head of the Air Force, Hermann Göring.
At Christmas, rations are reduced to
50 grams of bread and 12 grams of fat.
Mussolini, who has just lost an army
in Stalingrad
is looking for a way to shift German attention
back to North Africa.
He writes to Hitler: In my opinion,
Russia can never be annihilated.
She is defended by her very size,
a territory so vast,
that it can never be conquered or held.
The Russian chapter is over,
we should make peace with Stalin.
What would Hitler do?
To negotiate would be to admit that the campaign
in Russia was a huge failure.
Future events however,
would not give Hitler the choice.
Roosevelt, the President of the United States,
has arrived in Casablanca in Morocco
to attend one of the most important meetings
in modern history.
He and Churchill want to settle
the prickly question of French political power.
Roosevelt wants to exclude de Gaulle
who since 1940
has been claiming his legitimacy
as the leader
of the French resistance movement.
Roosevelt says, "General de Gaulle is a soldier.
Certainly a patriot and devoted to his country.
But on the other hand,
he is also a politician and a sectarian.
And I believe in him,
he has all the attributes of a dictator.
Roosevelt prefers to invite
another a France's great leaders
to Casablanca, general Giraud.
Taken prisoner in 1940,
he has just escaped from Germany
and arrived in North Africa.
He cuts a dashing figure.
Churchill continues to support de Gaulle
who he invites in order to reconcile
the two rival generals,
which is not an easy task.
Roosevelt and Churchill agree
that future cooperation
between the two adversaries
is necessary in order to save France.
It is obvious that Roosevelt has
warmer feelings for Giraud than for de Gaulle.
Then at the closing press conference,
Roosevelt and Churchill make a declaration
of the utmost importance.
With great vehemence,
they pronounce the words
that henceforth will become the Allies credo.
Unconditional surrender by Germany,
Japan and Italy.
There will be no more negotiating.
The Allies will keep fighting the Axis Powers
until the very end.
The price in lives will be high.
And many believe that this radical position,
who purpose is to reassure the Soviets,
will only serve to increase
the German devotion to their Führer.
Stalin is satisfied.
He feared that Hitler will conclude
a separate peace with the Allies
in order to pit all of his forces against Russia.
He launches his offensive to annihilate
the beast still lurking in the ruins of Stalingrad.
Beyond the red flag, is the Univermag store
where the commander of the 6th Army,
general Friedrich Paulus, is entrenched.
His men surrender.
The day before, Hitler had promoted him
to Field Marshall,
thinking it would compel him to commit suicide
in order to save his honor.
Paulus however, on the verge of collapse,
weakened by dysentery
and revolted by the absurdity of Hitler's orders
allows himself to be captured.
Field Marshall Paulus is an extraordinary prize
for the Soviets.
He is the man that masterminded
Operation Barbarossa.
The plan to invade the Soviet Union.
The Soviet leaders can hardly believe it.
Paulus will collaborate with the Soviets
and testify at the Nuremberg trials
against his former commanders,
such as Keitel.
When he is released in 1953,
he will settle in East Germany.
His reaction is mainly a rejection
of Hitler's outrageous policies.
Many of his men feel the same way.
Hitler can go to the devil!
The German prisoners dare to mutter
in a few words of Russian they know.
We want to go home.
We can only imagine how the people
in the occupied countries must have felt.
After the German defeat in Stalingrad,
hope is revived.
The German news broadcasts do not,
of course, show any of these images.
And Hitler says,
"We must not use the word "surrender".
We must explain that our men were unable
to receive supplies
and that is why they were beaten.
We have to use the word "sacrifice".
The Nazis want to turn this national disaster
into an opportunity for galvanizing
the German people.
The Minister of Propaganda, Goebbels,
assumes the task of mobilizing
all the nation's energy
and resources towards this end.
I ask you,
do you want total war?
Yes!
A war that is even more total
and more radical
than anything we could ever
imagine?
Yes!
People, rise up!
Let the storm break loose!
Deutschland, Deutschland über alles
Germany, Germany above everything
Above everything in the world!
Deutschland, Deutschland über alles
Germany, Germany above everything
In the audience,
seemingly ecstatic is Albert Speer.
He will furnish Hitler with the means
to implement total war.
Hitler calls him, "His only friend".
The 38 year-old architect,
builder of the Führer's megalomaniac edifices
has been appointed Minister of Armaments.
Speer gives new impetus
to the German war industry.
He is a masterful organizer,
but above all, he is an adamant Nazi.
Under his orders, millions of foreign
or Jewish civilians will be rounded up
and worked to exhaustion or to death.
After Russia and Poland, occupied France
is the country that provides the Nazis
with the greatest number of workers.
The Vichy regime institutes
a compulsory labor service
and drafts 600,000 French workers
for Germany.
Those who want to evade the service take to
the forest and join the resistance movement.
The song of this group is the "Partisan" song.
Friend, do hear the dark flight
of the crows over our plains?
Friend, do you hear the dulled cries
of our country in chains?
Partisans, laborers, farmers,
take up your arms!
Underground resistance groups had been
created in all of the occupied countries.
Tonight the enemy shall know
the price of blood and tears.
Come out of the mines,
come down from the hills, comrades!
Take the guns, munitions and grenades
from under the bay!
Hey you, hitmen,
with bullets and knives, kill swiftly!
Hey you saboteurs, watch out
for your load of dynamite!
We break open the jail bars
for our brothers.
Here, we march on, we kill and we die.
Friend, if you fall, a friend from
the shadows will take your place.
Behind the walls of the Warsaw ghetto
the Germans are confronted
by a Jewish uprising.
Before the war, this area of Warsaw
was a lively open district.
Filmed in color here by an American tourist.
In 1940, the Nazis turned
this pleasant area of Warsaw
into an over-populated prison.
This woman shrieks in grief as she carries
her dead child through the streets.
The Warsaw ghetto in 1941.
The ghetto in 1942.
The ghetto in 1943.
The Nazis deliberately starve
the people in order to kill, weaken
and prevent any kind of revolt.
But the Jews manage to acquire weapons,
and they die fighting.
The survivors are deported
to the Treblinka extermination camps
and executed.
The ghetto is razed to the ground.
At the same time,
the Allies win another victory.
They enter Tunis.
Behind these gates,
the Germans had already initiated policies
to persecute the Jews in Tunisia
during their short occupation.
The Jews immediately take the opportunity
to remove their yellow stars.
The Italian prisoners receive insulting gestures
from the crowd.
Rommel, who is still in Tunisia,
is filmed by a German officer
before boarding one of the last planes
leaving for Germany.
In March 1943, he wrote:
I have received instructions to take sick leave
and get myself back into shape.
All my efforts to save my men and get them
back to the continent have been fruitless.
Orders have been issued
by the Führer's headquarters
to maintain the utmost secrecy
concerning my recall to Germany.
My military reputation
is still to serve as a deterrent.
The Afrika korps has been captured
and is now marching in long lines
towards the American fleet's ships
to be taken away
to the other side of the Atlantic.
During the war, 380,000 Germans will be sent
over to Canada and the United States
from where escape is impossible.
These prisoners are about to embark
on a strange odyssey.
It begins on these military transport ships.
Many feel like they're in a dream.
For them, the war is over and they are safe.
However, for these German soldiers,
the dream will soon turn into a nightmare,
because even here,
the Nazis remain in control.
These men coming off the boat in Canada,
insist on making the salute.
Even those with just one arm.
Some prisoners are sent to camps
in Virginia and Texas.
They work on cotton or tobacco plantations.
In these barracks, Nazi law continues
to terrorize the prisoners.
LONG LIVE OUR FÜHRER
Within a short time, Nazi officers
have taken control of the prisons.
Using intimidation, torture and even murder
to maintain fascist ideology
among their fellow prisoners.
And this message must reach
the German soldiers,
fighting and suffering on all of the German fronts.
They have to understand
that they have nothing to gain
from turning themselves in to the Allies.
On the eastern front,
ever since the fall of Stalingrad,
the Wehrmacht is never the same.
The soldiers exchange rumors
about the Führer.
Apparently he's lost his head!
He's being secretly held in Berchtesgaden.
It's his double that we're seeing.
But no, it is Hitler himself, filmed here
in Berchtesgaden by his mistress, Eva Braun.
Since his army's defeat in Stalingrad
and El Alamein, he's changed.
His famous moustache has grayed.
One of his generals, Von Senger,
is struck by his appearance.
He says, "His skin was flaccid.
The look in his blue eyes
which had mesmerized the crowds
was reddened by insomnia."
In fact, his physician, Doctor Morrel
has concocted cocaine eye drops for him.
Morrel is filmed here on the 20th of April, 1943,
with the secretaries and close friends
who have come to wish the Führer
a happy birthday.
He is only 54.
Morell is able to make him presentable
for ceremonies.
Hitler, however, is careful to keep
his left arm under control.
It tends to tremble.
He is already showing signs
of Parkinson's disease.
As a result, the head of the SS, Himmler,
becomes even more important.
The SS, whose recruits were now
coming from the Hitler youth,
started out as the Schutzstafell,
the protection squad for the Nazi officials.
Later, it would provide the guards
for the concentration camps.
The SS has now created a veritable army
of its own, the "Waffen SS".
In the future, these elite troops,
under Himmler's orders
are expected to replace the Wehrmacht,
which is no longer considered completely loyal.
Increasingly, Himmler recruits
from the occupied countries.
Fanatics such as these Bosnian SS.
In the occupied areas of Russia,
the SS also has no problem
recruiting two divisions of Cossacks
who during the time of the Tsars
were already known
for their bloody anti-Semitic pogroms.
They will form
the fearsome 15th SS Cavalry Corps.
As for the Wehrmacht, it will enlist
as many as 1,000,000 Soviet prisoners
who have no other choice.
They can either die of hunger
or fight alongside the Germans.
Some, like former Soviet general,
Andrey Vlasov, are also against Stalin.
After the German siege of Leningrad,
Vlasov was taken prisoner and changed sides.
He will command the Russian Liberation Army
under the flag of the Wehrmacht.
The Germans outfit this veritable foreign
legion of theirs with the best equipment.
Such as the Tiger tank, designed by
the brilliant engineer, Ferdinand Porsche.
With its 88 mm gun, the Tiger was
the most dreaded of the German tanks.
As a result, back in the Wolf's Lair,
Hitler starts to feel hopeful again.
He can now renew his obsession
with destroying the Red Army.
He wants to attack at Kursk.
The Russians have pushed forward
into the frontlines
and Germany will launch
a massive summer offensive.
"Operation Citadel",
the biggest tank battle in history.
2,700 German tanks are preparing to combat
3,600 Soviet tanks.
But the technical superiority
of the German Tiger,
appears to be overwhelming.
Hitler knows the importance of this battle.
To lead his force of 900,000 soldiers,
he has chosen the man who helped him to win
the Battle of France,
Field Marshall von Manstein.
The offensive, led by the Tiger tanks,
breaks through the Soviet lines.
But encounters a brutal anti-armor defense,
set up by the Soviets
and dense concentrations of tanks.
The Wehrmacht's troops are pushed back.
Even the formidable Tiger tanks
are falling victim to the Soviets.
And the Soviets have a secret weapon.
The British have succeeded
in capturing and decoding
the German encryption machine,
called "Enigma".
And they are now able to read
all of the most secret German orders.
The powerful Soviet Secret Service
in Great Britain
had managed to pass on
the decoded operation plans to Moscow.
This war is also an espionage war.
At Kursk, the outcome is devastating
for the Germans
who have already lost 50,000 men
in this battle.
Von Manstein wants reinforcements
in order to continue his offensive.
He is waiting for Hitler.
He immediately tells him,
"We have suffered losses,
but the Russians have too. Even worse."
Hitler seems very hesitant.
He mutters a few inanities.
Von Manstein will write:
He seems to me to be quite feeble.
This impression is confirmed,
when von Manstein shows Hitler
the figures of the losses incurred at Kursk.
Since the beginning of the war,
2,000,000 German soldiers
have already been killed, wounded
or gone missing in action.
Hitler will never be able to fill that void.
Things are now a far cry from
the victories of the lightning war campaigns,
the Blitzkrieg of the Battle of France.
Kursk is the real turning point in the war
because Hitler moves over to the defensive.
Overcome by paranoia, he insists on having
stenographers present.
Von Manstein does not believe that
everything is lost, but Hitler disagrees.
Von Manstein implores him to continue
the offensive. Hitler refuses.
The Battle of Kursk is over.
For Hitler, the priority now
is to send reinforcements over to Sicily
where the Allies have just landed.
The noose is tightening.
Things are moving fast.
All Hitler can do is try to hold back
the advancing Allies.
But he is unable to prevent
the fall of Mussolini,
which leads Italy to surrender
and to change sides.
The new Italian government has
Mussolini imprisoned, up in the mountains.
Hitler sends an airborne commando unit
to rescue him.
Hitler wants Mussolini back in power.
He sends him back to Italy to reestablish
his fascist regime
with the help of the German army.
The Germans invade Italy
and have no qualms about slaughtering
their former allies who attempt to resist.
The Germans immediately start going
after the Jews in Rome, Milan,
Genoa, Florence and Trieste.
Hitler's greatest concern is to prevent
any further Allied landings in Italy,
and above all, in France.
This is the idea behind "Fortress Europe",
whose emblem is the Atlantic wall.
A staggering system of fortifications
stretching from Norway,
down to the Spanish border.
Rommel is put in charge
of defending "Fortress Europe".
He says, "It is absolutely necessary that we
push the British and Americans
back from the beaches.
Afterwards, it will be too late.
The first 24 hours of the invasion
will be decisive.
It will be, the longest day."
For Rommel and the Nazis, this is
the beginning of the twilight of the Gods.
The final months of Nazi Germany.
And yet, these German newsreel images
of Rommel
who had been invited to tea
by Magda Goebbels,
the wife of the propaganda minister,
are revealing of the moods of the Nazis
at this point of the war.
Nazi ideology puts faith in victory
and vanquishes doubt.
Magda Goebbels worshipps Hitler like a god.
Even though he is driving Germany into
a frenzy of bloodshed and death.
Magda Goebbels has given all
of her 6 children first names
that begin with the letter "H",
just like Hitler.
Helga, Hildegard, Holdine,
Helmut, Hedwig and Heidrun.
She would kill them all, one by one,
on the last day of the Reich.