The Allies have landed in Italy
which is occupied by the Germans.
In their advance towards the North
where Mussolini is still in control
the American, British, Canadian
and French armies
are held up by the solid German defense belt
along the Gustav line,
in the area of Monte Cassino.
Perched on the top of the mountain,
is historical St. Benedict's monastery.
The Allies think that the Germans have turned
this 1,400 year old monument
into a look-out post.
More than 200 Allied bombers
will drop over 500 tons of bombs
on the monastery.
In World War 2, nothing is sacred.
It turns everything into an inferno.
RETREAT AND SURRENDER
The Allies launch their attack
but the German paratroopers push them back.
The German shock troops are now firmly
entrenched in the ruined monastery.
Nothing was achieved by the bombing.
These scenes were filmed
by the American director, John Huston,
who was sent to this front in Italy.
He would later say,
"It was a massacre in the freezing cold."
And yet, Churchill had called Italy
the soft under-belly of Europe.
By moving in from the south via Italy,
Churchill's aim is to take Berlin
before the Russians could.
The Red Army continues to advance steadily
from the east. Kiev is liberated.
The German Wehrmacht army
pulls out of the Ukraine
obeying Hitler's order
to systematically destroy everything.
In Italy, several months later,
the Wehrmacht is still holding
the Gustav line and Monte Cassino.
The French general, Juin,
proposes to surprise the Germans
who have left those slopes,
thought to be too steep, undefended.
The rugged soldiers of North African
and Polish regiments, however,
manage to climb up the mountain
and put the Allies on the road to Rome.
As the Wehrmacht retreats,
it once again leaves a path of destruction
behind it.
But together with Mussolini,
and his remaining fascists,
the Germans will retain control
of Northern Italy and its industries.
They are the target of attacks
by Italian partisans
and they retaliate
with indiscriminate violence.
At the same time, in Southern England,
the Allied war machine assembled
for the Normandy landing, is gearing up.
On the evening of 5th of June,
the paratroopers get ready to leave.
Decked out in their Indian style war paint
and haircut to make themselves feel brave.
The Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces,
general Eisenhower, comes to tell them,
"You are about to embark
upon the great crusade."
The plan is to land on 5 beaches
along on 100 km stretch
of the Normandy coast.
From the Seine to the Cotentin Peninsula,
where the German Atlantic war defenses
are the weakest.
At midnight, on June the 5th,
British Gliders and Dakotas,
full of British, American
and Canadian paratroopers,
slip silently inland over the Normandy region.
The paratroopers are the first
to set foot in occupied France.
Their mission, to secure the flanks
of the landing zone.
The Allied fleet is on its way.
It is the biggest armada ever assembled.
Nearly 5,000 landing ships and assault craft.
Yet it is not detected by the Germans
who are prevented from carrying out
reconnaissance flight by the stormy weather.
Bombardment and shelling
from the battleships, pound the coast
but completely miss their targets
on the beach code named Omaha.
The German bunkers remain intact.
The first assault wave of American troops
is getting ready to tackle the German defenses
on Omaha beach.
Among them, is American writer,
Ernest Hemingway
who is a war correspondent.
He writes: As we moved in towards land
in the grey early light,
the coffin-shaped steal boats took
solid green sheets of water,
that fell on the helmeted heads of the troops,
packed shoulder to shoulder.
In the stiff, awkward, uncomfortable,
lonely companionship of men going to a battle.
Another war reporter,
the photographer Robert Capa
is also caught up in this inferno.
He says,
"It was the ugliest beach in the whole world.
Exhausted from the water and the fear,
we lay flat on a small strip of wet sand."
Over 2,000 American soldiers
will lose their lives here.
As the tide rolls in, the soldiers are trapped
between the sea and gun fire
from the German blockhouses.
Eisenhower had prepared a communique
in case the landing failed.
In a hand-written letter he said,
"My decision to attack at this place
was based on the best information available.
If there is any blame or fault attached
to the attempt, it is mine alone."
But a small group succeeds in climbing up
under enemy fire
and neutralizing the German cannons
with the help of
Royal Air Force's fighter bombers.
In the meantime, the Canadian troops
have landed on Juno Beach.
There is indeed very little resistances,
only a few shots
that do not deter the British
on the next beach along.
The few German defenders who survived
the bombardments, finally surrender.
British and French commandos
land on the fifth beach.
The Allies plan to land 326,000 men.
In just one week,
a daily average of 10,000 men,
3,200 vehicles and 15,000 tons of supplies
are ferried across.
In order to accomplish this,
a harbor is needed.
But the Allies decided to stay away
from the big ports
which were too well-defended,
and to land on the beaches of Normandy.
Instead, they brought their harbors
with them.
Gigantic construction kits called "Mulberries".
146 concrete caissons,
61 m long and weighing 6,000 tons
were assembled to create
breakwaters and piers
where the Liberty ships, as they were called,
could unload their cargo.
American shipyards had turned out
one of these ships everyday.
In less than 3 years, the war industry
has turned the United States into a super power.
The country has mobilized more
than 11,000,000 men.
Its armies are now in France, Italy,
North Africa, and Asia.
The power of the United States is such
that, just a few days after
the Normandy landings in Europe,
it's able to assemble a second fleet
on the other side of the world, in the Pacific.
In order to attack the Mariana Islands,
which are under Japanese control.
Having taken the island of Tarawa
the year before,
the Americans now want to use
the island of Saipan
as a base for bombers taking off for Japan.
Some 127,500 troops, two-thirds of them
marines, prepare for combat.
15 aircraft carriers and 900 planes
will crush the Japanese Air Force
in an air battle will come to be known
as "The Great Marianas Turkey Shoot".
A fatal blow is also dealt
to the Japanese Imperial Navy.
After which, Japan's defenses in Saipan
are battered.
But when the marines land on this tiny island,
which is only 9 km wide,
one of the bloodiest battles of the war begins.
Over 15,000 Americans and at least
27,000 Japanese will be killed or wounded.
A month and a half after D-Day,
the fighting is still fierce.
The Allies are advancing,
but Eisenhower is worried.
Hitler is determined to contain the Allies
in Normandy
in order to protect the launch ramps
for his weapon of terror, the V-1
which he fires at London
from the Northern France.
It is the first cruise missile ever to be used.
The V-1 is a flying bomb, with a pulse jet
engine and a 1 ton explosive warhead.
This small, swift, pilotless aircraft
is difficult to intercept and shoot down.
The British call them "Buzz bombs"
because they made motorcycle noise
that alert Londoners to their arrival.
By the time the V-1s reach the capital city,
their fuel is used up and their engines die out.
Londoners never know where they will fall.
Nearly 20,000 of these missiles were launched
against England and continental Europe.
Killing 11,000 people.
But even under these conditions,
the British retain their pluck
and their composure.
If the V-1s fail to demoralize the British,
their purpose was also to boost
the morale of the Germans.
For years, they have had to live
in underground shelters.
American bombers by day
and British bombers by night
demolish Germany's cities,
under a carpet of bombs.
American planes drop 1,400,000 tons of bombs.
Allied bombing led to around
600,000 casualties. 7,000,000 homeless.
Such is the outcome of
the strategic bombing campaign
whose purpose is to destroy the industrial
and human potential
behind Germany's war time effort.
In the Führer's headquarters, the Wolf's Lair,
beneath the obligatory smiles,
many of Hitler's officers are deeply troubled.
Especially those from
the old Prussian military aristocracy.
In the past year, many of them
have joined a plot to get rid of Hitler.
One of these officers,
colonel Count Claus von Stauffenberg,
places a bomb under Hitler's desk
during a conference in the Wolf's Lair.
It is this heavy table, that saves Hitler.
It deflects the blast, that would eventually
kill 4 men and wound 20 others.
Of the failed assassination attempt,
Hitler says,
"Having now escaped death,
I am more than ever convinced
that the great cause that I served
will be brought through its present perils
and that everything can be brought
to a good end.
Hitler is only slightly injured, a bruised arm,
his eardrums punctured, his hair singed.
But the incident deeply traumatizes him,
affecting his mental state.
Intensifying his cruelty and his paranoia.
He unleashes his revenge.
The main conspirators are tried.
5,000 suspects were arrested,
200 of them executed
and their families deported.
He has no second thoughts
about executing his marshals.
Because he agreed to replace Hitler
at the head of the army,
Rommel is forced to commit suicide.
Hitler hypocritically gives him a state funeral.
Henceforth, power is in the hands of the SS.
Nothing can save Germany now.
The Russians continue to advance in the East.
"The Great Patriotic War", as they call it,
has taken a new turn for them.
The Red Army is suddenly able to strike
with a force that amazes all sides.
An endless supply of men.
Even after the extremely costly battles
of Moscow and Stalingrad.
The offensive in Belarus
in the summer of 1944
is one of the biggest battles
of the second World War.
The Eastern front is 1,000 km wide.
But the Russians are able to push forward
100s of kilometers within 2 months
destroying 17 German army divisions.
The Wehrmacht retreats towards East Prussia,
leaving behind many thousands of casualties.
Some 50,000 captured Germans will be paraded
through Moscow.
In the West,
the Allies are gaining the upper hand.
For the Wehrmacht,
the situation is deteriorating.
50,000 German soldiers are taken prisoner
in the Falaise pocket,
or as the Germans call it,
"Stalingrad in Normandy".
It is a much needed victory for the Allies.
The Allies tighten their noose
with a new landing in Provence.
The reassembled French Army
plays a major part in this landing.
Africans, Moroccans,
Algerians, Tunisians, French colonials
and young Frenchmen,
who were part of the Free French Forces
aid the liberation in Provence.
It takes them just 2 weeks to liberate
the entire coast, up to Marseille.
The resistance movement comes out
of the shadows
and participates in the liberation,
as it will do in Paris.
Paris rises up.
Barricades are erected across the city.
Most of the German army has retreated
to the East,
but 20,000 men remain behind,
under the command of general von Choltitz
who is received orders from Hitler
to destroy the city.
Violent fighting breaks out.
On the fourth day of the insurrection,
a French unit,
general Lecrec's 2nd Armor Division,
arrives from Normandy.
And the capital is finally liberated
the next morning.
The Germans surrender
and General von Choltitz is taken
to Leclerc's headquarters
in the Montparnasse train station.
Hitler had just called and
asked his famous question,
"Brennt Paris?"
"Is Paris burning?"
Choltitz preferred to turn himself in.
This highly disciplined officer
from the airborne regiment,
disobeyed Hitler's order
to fight to the last man.
Then de Gaulle arrives
with eloquent words for history.
Paris has been offended,
Paris has been shattered,
Paris has been tortured,
but Paris has been liberated!
While France and Belgium
are progressively liberated,
and the Red Army waits outside Warsaw,
on the other side of the globe,
the American general MacArthur,
is returning to the Philippines.
After escaping from the Japanese siege
3 years earlier, MacArthur said, "I shall return."
His return is sumptuously staged
by his public relation staff,
complete with
his legendary Popeye corn cob pipe.
He proclaims,
"People of the Philippines, I have returned.
The hour of your redemption is here."
But it will take 4 months to liberate
the Philippines.
Manila, the capital, will be the second most
devastated city of the war, after Warsaw.
The savagery and the cruelty of these combats
can be explained
by the American troops' discovery
of the mass execution of hostages.
And the camps with the surviving US prisoners
from 1941.
Everywhere in the Pacific,
the war is marked by this type of savagery.
Everywhere, the same confusion of marines
trapped on the beaches of these inferno islands.
The same suicidal obstinacy of the Japanese.
For them, surrendering
is the ultimate disgrace.
The Americans are no longer taking any risks.
They follow the nstinct to shoot first,
and ask no questions.
Along with imperialism, another underlying
cause of World War 2 is racism.
Racism gave birth to Auschwitz,
the killing factory.
Liberated by the Russian offensive
of January 1945.
Hatred of the Jews, exterminating them,
was, as Hitler wrote in "Mein Kampf".
His mission.
He sent 1,000,000 Jews to their death
in the gas chambers of Auschwitz.
6,000,000 died of starvation,
brutal treatment,
were shot and burned in the crematoriums
in Majdanek, in Sobibor, in Treblinka.
The Russians find a few hundreds survivors,
tattooed for life.
They also intercept the trains full of deportees.
The Nazis continue to give priority
to these death trains
even over the munitions convoys.
They make their trips to
the approximately 100 concentration camps
that are still operating
at the beginning of 1945.
Millions of Jews, political activists, opponents,
Christians, homosexuals, Gypsies,
have been deported to these camps.
And 5,000,000 of them have died of hunger,
abuse and exhaustion.
Like the slaves in the Dora tunnel,
the underground factory
where the Nazis are assembling
another secret weapon, the V-2.
The first ballistic missile
with a 1 ton explosive warhead
that has a range of 300 km.
From the German coast, 1,500 of them
are launched against London.
And 2,000 against Belgium, adding to
the devastation and the civilian casualties.
The Allies' greatest fear is that
it might one day, carry a nuclear charge.
The eminent scientist Einstein himself
had warned Roosevelt
about the urgency of getting ahead
of the Germans.
Huge funds were provided
and a team of scientists
secretly went to work
on the first atomic bomb.
A bomb that uses a metal, uranium
that makes it possible to split the atom.
It is expected to have
the power of 20,000 tons of TNT.
More than 2,000 times more powerful
than the largest bomb used to date,
in addition to lethal radioactive fall out.
The designated target was Berlin.
But this first atomic bomb will not be finished
in time for Germany.
In Germany,
are there any factories that still standing
that will be capable producing such a weapon?
Even synthetic fuel is becoming scarce.
The carpet bombing, carried day and night
by the Allies,
continues to devastate German cities.
The Allied bombers will destroy Dresden.
An important center of communications
for the German armies on the Eastern Front.
And one of the biggest industrial cities
in the Reich.
Until now, it has remained untouched.
Dresden, known as the "Florence of the Elba"
was one of Europe's finest medieval cities.
Phosphorus bombs create a fire typhoon
in which an estimated 25,000 people
are burned to death.
The city continues to blaze for 7 days.
Churchill had said,
"We will make the German people taste
and gulp a sharper dose of the miseries
they have showered upon mankind.
Their cities are dying
and now Goebbels and the Nazis
want to send all Germans
from 16 to 60 years old
to their deaths as part of the "Volkssturm",
the People's Militia.
They shout, "I vow to fight courageously
for my homeland.
Swear to die for Adolf Hitler."
Hitler says, "There must be not be
any weakening of Germany."
His generals, those who survived
the massive purge
following the July 20th assassination attempt,
no longer dare to oppose the Führer.
They obeyed his order which seemed absurd,
to launch an attack in the West,
in the Ardennes during winter.
They would have preferred to devote
all their efforts to fighting the Russians.
Hitler was hoping to recapture
the Port of Antwerp,
in order to stop the Allies from unloading
their equipment,
which would enable them to move into Germany.
But the German offensive
in the Ardennes failed,
due to the extraordinary defense, put up
by the American paratroopers in Bastoigne
to the intervention of general Patton's tanks
and to the overwhelming power
of the Allied Air Forces.
As for the Russians in the east,
they are crossing the German border.
Millions of Germans flee in panic
from the approaching Soviet troops.
Especially the German women,
who fear the mass rapes
that are being perpetrated.
There is no dissension between
the Western Allies and the Russians.
Moreover, in Churchill's mind,
the problem with Germany is practically over.
He is now thinking about how to divide up
the occupation zones.
He and Roosevelt meet in the Crimea
for an important conference with Stalin.
Concerned about the increasing losses
being suffered in the Pacific,
Roosevelt has come to press Stalin
to join the war effort against Japan.
Stalin has made Roosevelt
come all the way out to Crimea
which takes a toll
on the ailing president's health.
He is drawn and emaciated.
He barely has the strength
to hold out his arm.
Roosevelt smokes cigarette after cigarette.
He is very frail.
He will pass away a few weeks later.
His main priority is Japan.
At the same time he does not have
the strength to oppose Stalin
who liberates but also occupies,
the Baltic States,
Romania, Bulgaria, Hungary,
Poland, Silesia and Prussia.
And there is no way to make him leave.
The only one who tries to negotiate is Churchill.
Finally, he gets Stalin to promise to hold
free elections in Poland.
A promise that will never be kept.
And to give up Greece
which will led to civil war.
The Greek communist partisans will rise up
and Stalin will let them be massacred.
One of the goals of this conference
is the founding of the organization
of the United Nations
which will soon be convened
in San Francisco.
The UN mission will be to seek a
peaceful settlement for all disputes
and to protect human rights.
This picture heralds
the beginning of the Cold War.
The war in the Pacific continues.
The marines raise the American flag
on top of mount Suribachi.
The volcano that dominates
the island of Iwo Jima.
The battle took the lives of 7,000 Americans
and 20,000 Japanese.
It is now possible for
the Boeing B29 Super Fortress Bombers
taking off from Iwo Jima and other islands
on the Pacific to reach Japan.
Humans have invented something
even more vicious
than the phosphorus used in Dresden,
Napalm.
Gasoline mixed with incendiary jelly.
1,700 tons dropped on little houses,
made of wood and paper.
The Japanese are victims
of their fanatical military leaders,
who plunged them into this inferno
and who wanted to pursue the war
in spite of the 80,000 victims and the 1,000,000
homeless from this air raid over Tokyo.
7 years earlier,
Hitler was at his chalet in Bavarian Alps,
along with his dog Blondi, of whom he seemed
to be fond of more than any human being.
He predicted, "The next war would not end
like the First World War.
There will be no 11th of November.
It would be either victory or annihilation.
Perhaps this vertiginous feeling of
"All or nothing"
is what kept him from marrying
his mistress, Eva Braun.
He said,
"I'm already married to Germany."
His Germany is on the verge of collapse.
The Soviet forces have surrounded Berlin.
But Hitler refuses to admit defeat.
He says,
"It will be the opposite of Stalingrad."
But his remaining soldiers overwhelmed
by the Russian rocket launchers
surrender, one after the other.
Beneath the ruins of the Chancellery,
in his underground bunker,
Hitler rants and raves and maneuvers
his imaginary armies.
The last of his faithful followers
take advantage of a lull,
to come out and celebrate his birthday
on April the 20th.
Hitler is 56 years old.
He consoles these Hitler youth
who have been chosen because their parents
have just been killed
in the bombing of Dresden.
As the Americans advance westward,
they capture thousands of this Hitler Jugend.
Sent to the front to replace the soldiers
who've been killed.
The Americans can hardly believe
their eyes.
These boy soldiers are afraid of nothing.
They have undergone years of brainwashing.
Hatred and racism have been indoctrinated
into them.
The old men in the Volkstrum
who are also captured,
have no words of comfort for them.
The Americans met up with the Russians
on the Elbe, near the Torgau bridge.
East meets West, the final act of the alliance.
The atmosphere is friendly, for the cameras.
Stalin's portrait is superbly displayed.
But Roosevelt's is draped
in black mourning crepe. He died on April the 12th.
One of America's most renowned generals,
George S. Patton is furious.
He thinks the Americans should have
entered Berlin before the Russians.
Patton, the man with a pistol in his belt
who drove his tanks through Africa
through Normandy, through the Ardennes.
He says to Eisenhower,
"The 9th Army is 60 miles from Berlin.
Not to go all the way there is a historic error
whose consequences will be very grave."
Eisenhower says nothing.
The only thing that matters to him
is to eliminate Hitler and the Nazis.
A few days earlier,
Patton had called him up urgently,
wanting him to witness the horrors
of the concentration camp at Buchenwald.
Eisenhower had the inhabitants
of the nearby city of Weimar
taken there in trucks, so that they
could no longer say that they did not know.
In order to show them
that such things did exist.
So that they would be able to testify
in Germany.
To say that they had seen the tattoos
collected from the corpses of the deported.
The lamp shades, made of human skin.
The shrunken-head paper weights.
Then, in accordance with the Yalta Agreements,
Eisenhower withdrew his troops
from Buchenwald
which was located in the Soviet zone.
Stalin immediately put the camp back to work.
It will become part of his prison system
where people suspected of hostility
towards his regime, will be imprisoned.
In Berlin, the Russians are 300 m away
from the Führer's bunker.
Hitler kills his pet dog Blondi,
after marrying Eva Braun.
She swallows a cyanide pill.
Hitler shoots himself in the head.
Goebbels and his wife also committed suicide.
Before that, Magda Goebbels had poisoned
her 6 children.
In her last letter she wrote:
That we can end our lives together
with the Führer
is a blessing for which we never dared
to hope.
The Soviets will raise their Red Flag
over the Reichstag.
The main Nazi leaders will be captured.
Like Göring,
one of Hitler's most diabolical accomplices.
In Italy, Mussolini is executed by partisans
and his body is lynched by the crowd.
Everywhere in Europe,
a wave of revenge is unleashed
against those who in one way or another,
collaborated with the devils.
In Berlin, Anna Pavlovna directs traffic
at the Brandenburg gate.
To defeat Nazi Germany,
Russia paid a very high price.
20,000,000 civilians and soldiers were killed.
Nearly 15 percent of the population
of the Soviet Union.
Soviet general Georgy Zhukov
has himself filmed in the ruins
of the Grand Chancellery of the Reich.
The very symbol of Hitler's delusions
of grandeur.
And finally, in Hitler's office,
with the famous globe that Charlie Chaplin
parodied in his movie, "The Great Dictator".
Hitler had ordered the SS to burn his body.
The Soviets will get rid of the bones
in order to prevent any kind of hero worship.
Wehrmacht commander Marshall Keitel,
signs the unconditional surrender
of Nazi Germany
in front of general Zhukov, his mortal enemy
and the Allied officers,
the British Air Marshall, Tedder,
the American general, Spaatz
and the French general, de Lattre de Tassigny.
Keitel will later be tried
at the International Nuremberg Trials.
He will be hanged,
like many other war criminals.
To stop the Nazis,
Germany had to be annihilated.
Will it also be necessary to annihilate Japan?
In the Pacific, the suicide pilots,
that the Japanese call "Kamikaze",
nose dive their planes into the American fleet.
Clutching on to their power,
the military chiefs in Tokyo
sacrifice what remains
of their country's youth and their aircraft,
in order to prevent the Americans
from landing in Japan.
In the end, the United States decides against
an invasion in Japan
which it thinks will cost the country
a million lives.
Instead, it detonates the atomic inferno.
The first 2 nuclear bombs ever exploded
kill in 1 second, over 100,000 people.
And finally enable the emperor, Hirohito
to seek peace without losing face.
The atom bomb had to be dropped
before these Japanese soldiers
and officers would finally consent
to perform this act.
Which is entirely contrary to the "Bushido",
their code of honor.
A few Japanese soldiers take to the jungle.
Some never even learn of
their country's defeat.
The last of these will come out from hiding
and turned themselves in, in 1975.
In Tokyo Bay onboard the USS Missouri,
the representatives of the Allied Nations
from China, Great Britain, Russia
and France are filled with emotions.
They have the privileges of attending
the signing of the Japanese surrender
that marks the end of World War 2.
General MacArthur represents the victors.
The Japanese Minister of Foreign Affairs,
in a top hat,
walks with a limp, having lost a leg
in a bomb attack in China,
will signing on behalf of the Emperor,
with whom he had met the day before.
He had told him,
"We must make off this day of mourning,
the first day of the birth of a new Japan.
In that way, we can go to the ceremony
with our heads held high."
MacArthur concludes with these historic words:
It is my earnest hope and indeed
the hope of all mankind
that from this solemn occasion
a better world shall emerge out of the blood
and carnage of the past.
This war took the lives of some
50,000,000 people.
Most of them innocent civilians
in an outbreak of pure violence.
Thousands of victims suffered
for many years afterwards
from the appalling after effects
of nuclear radiation.
Or from the terrible loss
of parents or children
exterminated in the Nazi's camps.
This series is dedicated to the victims
of all forms of totalitarianism.
Let us be grateful to the cameramen,
the unarmed heroes who recorded
these combats for posterity.
And to all, who filmed the war
in all of its atrocity and its familiarity.
They introduced us to Rose,
who on the last day of the apocalypse,
wrote "The End" on a bomb.