He's good ain't he? I like that!
Hope he don't do no more though!
'Ere Trigger, you coming to the do Saturday night?
Only I've only got two tickets left!
Yeah, put 'em down to me Mike!
Good boy. Now they're 2.50 each
but you can have the pair for a fiver!
You're a pal!
- Right, I'll go for a tenner on that one.
- Royal Flush! Get out of that my son!
I don't know where you're pulling 'em
from tonight, Del Boy, I really don't!
Now listen you cretinous little erks!
There is a three-yard exclusion zone around this table!
And if another one of your missiles
should fall within it,
I will personally shove it - point, shaft, feathers an' all,
right up your gear box! Do I make myself clear?
- Yeah, alright Boycie, we get yer drift.
- Well just be aware then, eh, just be aware...
Bloody peasants!
That's what I like about you Boycie,
you've always been such a good loser!
Yeah, I've had plenty of bloody
practice where you're concerned, ain't I?
Mike says no gambling.
He's frightened of losing his licence.
Trigger, Michael knows very well what he can do with his
bloody licence! I'm tryin' to win my money back here.
Alright, alright. There's plenty of time Boycie.
Listen, I'll go and get some drinks.
What do you want, scotch,
scotch, Trigger?
- Cheers Del.
- About time an' all.
- Alright Tommy?
- Hello Del.
'Ere, listen. Tell the enemy that I haven't forgotten
about her sandwich toaster,
I'll pop it round to her in the morning, alright?
Michael please, three scotches if
you don't mind.
Del, I've told you before, do
not gamble in the pub! I'll lose my licence.
Yeah why, no it's only a
friendly game.
Friendly, friendly? I've seen at least fifty quid
change hands in here tonight!
That's what I mean, it's a friendly game!
There you are, put the rest in
the bottle, will you...I'm in the mood for love.
'Ere Del, Del. D'you want tickets for the do
Saturday night, I've only got two left?
Yeah, on then, I'll have 'em.
- Maureen, give them to Del, will you. And get the money.
- That's a fiver.
Yeah, alright, go on, get the money yourself.
Help yourself. They're in my pocket.
There's no money in there!
I know, it's in me jacket
pocket! Go on help yourself.
- You're a swine, you really are.
- Take a pound for yourself.
- Yeah I will, thanks very much.
- And thank you very  much.
- Maureen...Vodka and lemonade, please.
- Vodka and lemonade.
Oi Mickey, alright? We going
down the pizza palace later on then?
Well, we're going down there!
But we're with the birds see!
Oh right. Yeah, well, I didn't
fancy a pizza to be honest!
Gotta be up early market and
all that.
'Ere Rodney, do you want tickets for the do
Saturday night, only I've only got two left?
- Well he won't want two, will he Mike?
- Why won't I want two?
- Well you won't be bringing a bird will you?
- Why shouldn't I be bringing a bird?
There's no reason Rodney, but
why break the habits of a lifetime?
- Yeah, I'll have the two Mike! How much?
- Good boy, that's a fiver.
- Who you bringing then, your Uncle Albert?
- I'm bringing a girl!
- Oh give over Rodney!
What's her name?
It's none of your business!
You'll have to find out Saturday night, won't you!
Who is it? 'Ere it's not that
sort form the fishmonger's is it?
No it ain't that sort form the fishmongers actually.
This one happens to be in showbusiness.
Showbusiness. You're a liar.
I'm telling you the truth,Mickey.
You wanna see her, an' all, she's a right bramma!
Well, I've got ten says you
won't bring a bird on Saturday night!
- Make it 20?
- Alright, 20!
Oi, oi, oi. What's all the
noise? I can't hear myself think here.
He's betting me I ain't got a
bird to bring to the do Saturday.
- Well, you ain't have you? What really?
- Yes.
Go on then Rodney, go on, take
him the mouthy git! Go on.
- I'll tell you what, make it 30.
- Make it 40 if you like!
- Go'n, go'n Rodney my son!
- I know, I know let's make it a nice round 50.
You're on! I'll see you Saturday,
and you'd better bring your money with you.
He's got more front than
Buckingham Palace ain't he?
Don't worry, come Saturday night you'll be the one
that's laughing won't you?
Yeah, that's it. Come on, come
and sit down over here and hold yer noise, right.
- Here are Dave, you can sit here, I'm going.
- Are we playing cards or what?
- Yeah come on.
- About bloody time an' all.
Right it'll be down to you then
Boycie. Here...
Keep yer money to yourself will
you, 'cos of old...
Okay, I will go a pound.
- Yeah, go on I'll have some of that. Two pound.
- Four.
- Eight.
- Sixteen.
- Thirty-two, go on.
- Sixty-four!...
It's gonna cost you 128 to see me Del Boy.
Just a minute Boycie! Just a minute.
This is supposed to be a friendly game ain't it.
Friendly? It's the start of
World War Three ain't it?
Well what can we do Del, it's
just the way the bids have gone!
I'll tell you what we can do!
We can both take our bets back, and start all over again,
and just you know try to play a little more sensibly. Alright?
- Alright Del Boy! Anything you say. Right, a pound.
- I'll see you!
I've got three tens!
Oh well that beats me out of sight Boycie.
Well played my son. Goodnight. Come on Rodney let's go!
Then I said to him, 'I'll see you!' Well you should have
seen his face Uncle, he didn't know whether to laugh or cry!
It was a picture weren't it Rodders?
Boycie's face - when I tucked
him up at cards!
Yeah, yeah, it was triffic!
- Wassamatter with you Rodney?
- Nothing!
Come on Rodders cheer up. Pay day tomorrow and then it's
Saturday when you take Mouthy Mickey to the cleaners!
Well that's what's bothering me Del.
Oh Rodney. You ain't starting
to feel sympathy for him 'ave you?
I mean, he's got far too much rabbit. It's about time
he was put in his place once and for all that boy.
Del - I ain't got a girl for Saturday night!
I ain't got a girl for any night!
You ain't got a...Well why did
you keep upping the ante?
You told me to! You were stood
behind me going 'Go on Rodney, go on my son!'
That's because you said you had
a girl and I believed you!
Yeah, well I weren't telling
the complete truth!
Telling the complete truth! You were lying
through yer back bloody teeth, you stupid little berk!
- He stands to lose fifty quid on this!
- Why d'you have to tell lies Rodney?
It was pride talking weren't it?
I mean, there was Mickey Pearce and all the others and
they was laughing at me! So I pretended! I lied!
Anyway, what's to say I won't meet a
girl by Saturday night?
That's the spirit Rodney!
There's loads of girls on this estate.
And one of 'em must be
willing to go out with you!
Well, the thing is Albert,
I've been out with most of 'em in the past.
What, didn't they like you?
Well they haven't started a fan
club yet, have they Rodney?
No Del, they ain't have they?
'Ere, I've got it! I've got it!
What about that tubby girl, who lives down by
the community hall there, she'll go out with you Rodney.
'Cos she ain't got a full deck!
I can sort this one out on my
own, thank you Derek!
Alright, alright, up to you.
- 'Ere, what about the girl from the fishmonger's
- No thank you Uncle!
Got it, cracked it. Remember a couple of months ago
when I took you out on that blind date?
Remember it?? I'm still having therapy for it!
You are not honestly suggesting I spend
another evening with Big Brenda?
Just 'cos she's taller than you! Anyway,
I heard she was a very sporting girl!
Yeah, but when you told me she was a sporting girl
I didn't realise you meant she was
Southern Areas Shot-put Champion!
Well you seemed to get on with hervery well,
you were laughing and dancing and that.
Del, I was scared of her! Anyway, if you think
I'm walking into the Nag's Head on Saturday night
with Miss Anabolic Steroids on me arm,
you've got another think coming.
I could not stand another night of:
'So I said to Zola' and 'Zola said to me!'
Oh well, you'll have to sort it out yourself Rodney,
I mean, you know I've done me best, ain't I, eh?
You wanna be careful Rodney!
Look at that little thing you took to the pictures
the other week - lucky not to get yer collar felt!
Now that's not fair! She swore
blind to me she was 18!
That's right, how did Rodney
know she was only nine?
She was 16 that month!
Anyway, I didn't suspect nothing till
she paid her fare with a school bus pass!
And she did all the chatting up! You know.
I mean she invited me to the pictures!
Well she had to didn't she,
they wouldn't let her in without an adult!
Oh get off my back you two! I'm
going to bed!
Rodney, listen you are sure you
don't want me to phone up that Big Brenda?
Oi, watch your language, these walls
are paper thin! I don't know, Uncle.
I don't know what the younger generation's coming to,
they can't even swear without effing and blinding!
Yeah, yeah, alright then darling. Yeah, no it's been
lovely hearing your voice after all these years!
Okay, see you around then. Bonjour.
Oh well. That's it. That's it.
That was the last one.
Last what?
I've been phoning round some of my old girlfriends,
see if I could pull something out of the hat for Rodney.
No luck. I tell you what Uncle, phoning round
some of your old birds don't 'alf make you feel your age!
Any phone calls for me today?
Yeah, that young Mickey Pearce called, said he had
a phone number of a lonely hearts club for Rodney!
Cor, he's a lairy little sod he is.
I'd like to tuck him up, I really would!
- Oh well, carry on. Alright Rodney?
- Yep!
Bloody hell!
That reminds me, I'm playing
dominoes down the Legion tonight!
What have you done to yourself?
Del, what you see before you is the new me!
The old Rodney Trotter is dead! Long live the King!
- You look like a liquorice all-sort!
- You ain't gotta wear it, have you?
No, that's too true, I ain't!
Look, I've still got a couple of hours left to win that bet!
I'm going out to see if I can't bump into a right bramma!
Make sure you don't bump into
her on a zebra crossing.
No, I mean it looks a bit like now you see me,
now you don't! Do you know what I mean?
Rodney, use your loaf, you're never
gonna pull a tart dressed up like Bertie Bassett!
- You ain't getting to me Del so save yer breath!
- Alright.
You know what would look good
on you Rodney, a big white stetson!
Do you know what would look
good on you Albert? A doberman pinscher!
Alright, alright, come on you two...Now pack it in.
Listen, d'you want me to come with you?
- You can if you like, I don't care.
- Alright, alright, I'll come with you.
- What you gonna wear?
- Sunglasses I should think!
Oh don't bother, I'll go on me own.
Calm down, calm down.
Come on, calm down, have a cup of tea.
- And will you stop winding him up!
- I ain't said a word!
No, well just make sure you don't then!
I don't know what it is, but I keep getting this
yearning to put my Bobby Crush LP on!
Alright, where, Rodney,
where did you get that?
I bought it off Paddy the Greek!
Paddy...the Greek! Pad...That's the rubbish
I sold him last Monday!
When I offered it to you then,
you weren't interested!
Yeah, I know, but he was
cheaper than you!
Yeah, well, I've got to cover
me overheads ain't I!
Look, there's gotta be easier ways to
win a bet than this ain't there.
There's something I don't understand!
All these young girls on the estate that you've taken out.
- What about 'em?
- How come none of 'em want to see you again?
Yeah, that is a bit of a mystery
innit, eh that?
Alright seeing as how it's
'National let's take the piss out of Rodney week'.
- I will tell you. I frighten them off! Alright?
- Frighten them off?
Yeah, well he's got this thing about
uniforms ain't he, you know what I mean.
It's got nothing to do with uniforms!
I got over that phase months ago!
Alright, look, to
morons like Mickey Pearce, and...
...some of the others, a woman
is not a person, to talk to, someone to relate to.
Oh no, a woman is just a trinket to
bolster their masculinity.
You know, something to hang on their arm
to prove their macho image! Well I'm different!
No, no, there's nothing like
that about him.
Look either I like a girl, or I don't!
If I don't like her Idon't see her no more!
But if I do like her, I...tend
to get a bit serious!
And well I think that's what's frightening 'em off!
They're young, you know, they want to see a bit of life –
perhaps they don't want a wally like me drooling round 'em!
I just fall in love too easy, that's my trouble!
It's our family trait Del!
Us Trotters wear our hearts on our sleeves!
- Leave it out...he wears his heart in his Wranglers!
- Oh, here we go again! See!
You don't know what love is Rodney,
you haven't had enough experience to know!
I bet you have though ain't yer?
I certainly have bruv!
I am covered in emotional scars me.
I was in love once!
Yeah? Triffic! You see Rodders,
I used to have this vision of love!
I used to imagine that me, me and my - sweetheart -
were running, in slow motion, through a field of buttercups!
We're both - you know, we're both like that
dressed in white, and you know like...
...I'd done a bit of weight!
And suddenly - there in the background
I can hear Semprini's orchestra
playing the theme tune from Doctor Zhivago!
- Where's he going?
- Probably gone to be sick!
Shut up and listen, listen will yer?
Then again, you see another time - another time. I
imagine us at the top of an Alpine peak.
Looking out across
the mountains and the forests,
it's just like as if we're the last two people
left alive in the world.
But suddenly behind us
you hear the sound of a lone violin.
- Semprini on a skiing holiday is it?
- Will you shut up and listen?
Oh, come on Del, that ain't a
vision of love, it's a yoghurt commercial!
Oh well, thank you very much.
There I am tryin' to give you the benefit of my
experience and what do you do, eh,
you throw it back in my face. Well thank...
- What's this?
- That's Helga!
- Helga?
- Helga who?
I was in love with her! I don't
think I ever really stopped loving her!
Yeah, well it's getting on
ain't it, if we're going down the club.
It was in 1946. We'd sailed in to Hamburg
to pick up some prisoners of war.
Helga was working in a bar near the docks.
She was the most beautiful woman I've ever seen –
I fell in love with her the moment I saw her!
The little finger on her right hand was missing!
No, she lost it when her home was bombed.
Her entire family was wiped out!
Oh! Sorry!
I asked her to marry me. She
said no! Just like that, no!
See, I mistook her gestures of
friendship as tokens of love!
I suppose it was all for the
best really.
You see theauthorities didn't like us
fraternising with the Germans,
and I was still married to yer
aunt Ada and she'd have kicked up a stink!
It's funny you know, but even after all this
time, if I'm ever watching a German war film
and I hear the word 'nein'
I always think of Helga!
What, 'cos that's how many fingers she had?
It's the German word for 'no'!
I'll put this back in the box.
Yeah, that's it. Go on, you put
it somewhere safe.
I think in her own way she loved me!
She never used to charge me as much as the other lads!
He tells a good story don't he?
It gets you right here.
Like bile. Well
come on - come on, shake a leg. Come on.
No, I don't think I'll bother Del!
Yeah come on, Rodney, come on
you've gotta make an effort!
No, I'm never gonna pull a bird, am I.
Yes you are. Come on like,
remember, he who dares wins!
Yeah, but that won't work for me Del!
I'll just have to pay Mickey the money that's all.
No you don't listen. I'll tell
you what you're gonna do.
Listen. I'll buy the bet off you. Right, now if we win,
I collect the 50. If we lose, I pay out.
- How's that grab you?
- Yeah, alright then!
Good boy, you know it makes sense!
Now, come on then, we're gonna go down
and give those dance halls a bit of an' hammering tonight!
'Come on let's twist again
like we did last summer.'
Yeah Del, this time, you know, let's not just go crashing in
there right and - kick 'em in the ankles and 'Wanna dance darling?'
You know, let's have a bit of decorum this time, eh?
Bit of sophistication!
What are you talking about?
Sophistication is my middle name!
Yeah, I know, I know, I just forgot!
Well that's alright then! Don't you worry. Listen, I'm just
gonna have a - a clean pants, splash of Brut,
- be with you in a minute, alright son.
- Triffic!
I don't know. Stone me. I right blinding night this has turned
out to be ain't it, eh, cor we've been everywhere!
Empire Leicester Square, Hammersmith
Palais, you name it we've danced there!
And the only thing I've pulled is a ligament in me back,
trying to do that bloody break dancing.
Surely to goodness Rodney,
one of them girls would have done you!
No, no, they wouldn't Del! This
one's got to be something a bit special.
I told Mickey she was in showbusiness.
You know, I made her out to be a bit of a film star!
You didn’t tell me that when I
took the bet of you did yer?
No!
No, you saucy little git!
Honestly I don't - oh come - sit - put your tookers down
there come on for heaven's sake. Take the weight of it.
Well how are we gonna find a
Bo Derek look-alike in Peckham?
If it had been Bo Diddley
we'd have been laughing!
Well, we ain't gonna find her here, are we?
What d'you bring us here for?
- Looks like a trouble place to me!
- It's not a trouble place!
- Del, there's dried blood on the door handle!
- The cleaners night off. Don't worry.
'Ere look at that - oi, down
there - those two there  - those two there.
Do I look like St George? Oh come on Del,
look at that one, she's older than the Mary Rose!
She's alright. I thought you said that this girlfriend of
yours was a bit of a film star. Bette Davis is a film star!
Yeah, well so was Rin Tin Tin
but I ain't taking a bloody alsatian to the do!
Don't know, it hasn't bothered
you other years! Has it?
- God, look at the state of her, eh.
- Eh, what?
- You can see her wrinkles from here!
- Alright, alright.
Got a face like a bulldog
chewing a wasp, ain't she?
Leave it - alright, go on, you
can have the best one!
That is the best one!!
I don't know what I'm going to do. I just bloody give up
with you. I really do. What you drinking?
Lager.
That's all your gonna get. Oi, Orlando!
- 'Ere Vonny. Vonny how are you? How you going?
- Hello presh, how are you?
Oh I'm alright. You know, I'm doing a bit here,
I'm doing a bit there. You know me.
What are you doing these days, you
still stripping are you?
I'm not a stripper Del, I'm an
exotic dancer!
Ah yeah, of course you are. Sorry.
You still take yer clothes off though, don't yer?
Well it's part of the act!
Yeah, yeah. 'Ere I heard you got into a bit
of trouble the other week. What was that?
Did you hear about that? Bloody drug-crazed tourist,
he jumped up on the stage after me!
- He tried to strangle me you know!
- Yeah I know, so I heard! How is the snake now?
- Oh he got over it.
- Oh good, good.
- I've got the sack from most of my clubs now.
- Oh yeah Orlando!
Yeah, why's that then?
Well, to be honest with you Del,
I've been hitting the bottle a bit too much.
Oh, have you?
Doctor says I've got a drink problem.
I said to him, I ain't got no problem, I like it!
Of course, my real problem is
frustration!
Perhaps I could help you out
there, couldn't I, eh?
- I shouldn't be a stripper Del!
- Oh I don't know, I think it suits you.
Deep down inside I'm a singer!
But no-one'll take me seriously!
No, I know. Gives you the 'ump
don't it, eh?
'Ere just a minute. You know my local, don't you?
The Nag's Head. Well there's a bit of a do on there
tomorrow night, do you fancy going?
- Will they let me sing there?
- Well yes, they'll insist!
- Alright then. You gonna pick me up?
- No, well you see you won't be going with me!
Who am I going with then?
It's alright, you'll be going
with my dopey little brother over there.
Where?
He's over there! Over there at
that table, there look.
Well there's no-one there,
just some geezer dressed up as a negative!
- Yeah, that's him!
- Oh Del...
- I stand to win a bet.
- Oh Gawd!
Listen Vonny. I'm on for a 50 here, alright.
I'll tell you what, come on
look there's a score in it for yourself.
- Oh ta Del.
- Alright. Go'n then!
What?
Well, you've gotta go over
there haven't you and you've gotta chat him up!
Make it look real! Go on. That's it,
use your charm girl. Go on.
- Hi!
- Oh, watcha!
- Is this anyone's seat?
- Em...No! No!
- My name's Yvonne.
- I'm Rod... Rod
I haven't seen you in here  before!
No, well that's probably something to do
with the fact that I've never actually been here before!
- So, do you work here?
- Oh no. I'm... erm... I'm in show-business!
Really? You ain't done any
films have you?
Oh well, there was a couple when I was younger,
but I'd rather not talk about it!
I just called in here tonight on the off chance,
I was hoping I might bump into some friends.
I heard someone was throwing
a party tomorrow night!
But now it looks as though I'll
have to spend the evening in on my own!
Yes, I've got absolutely
nothing to do tomorrow night!
Listen, I've got a couple of
tickets for a do! It's only a pub...
- Oh, I'd love to go with you, thank you!
- It starts about 8.30.
Oh, I'll see you there.
Well, hold on, I'd better write
the address down for you.
Oh it's alright, I know where
the Nag's Head is! Must rush.
- There you go. Don't tell me you've pulled!
- I have.
- You haven't!
Rodney, Rodney listen. Now listen to me.
Let me explain before I do something you'll regret,
I'll explain to you, you see...
- No Del, it's me Del.
- Ah! Oh it's you. Come on in where's Rodney?
He's coming up the stairs. Oh
he's after your blood, Del.
It wasn't my fault. Well not
entirely. I only did it so that he could win the bet.
I'm sure in the cold light of day Rodney will realise
that Vonny's behaviour wasn't that bad.
Oh it  was bad, Del. It was very bad.
At one point Rodney started crying.
- I am going to kill you!
- Careful, now listen, don't be a plonker all yer life!
- You set her...up to...going out with me!
- I did not set her up, I paid her!
You paid her? Well that' worse!
Come here.
Alright, now listen, I only did it
for you to win the bet. And to save your pride!
My pride!? Tonight, in front of half of Peckham,
the bird I told everyone was my girlfriend
stood on the counter and took all her clothes off!
I don't think anyone noticed Rodney!
Well you certainly noticed Uncle!
Because you stood on a chair to notice!
At one point he almost knocked you off!
That's right, he did.
No listen alright, so she has one too many gins,
I didn't know she had  drink problem.
No, I found out a couple
of new things about her as well.
I didn't know she could juggle light ale bottles.
I didn't know she couldn't sing!
And where did that snake come from??
I don't know! Nobody knows
where it went either!
That's it isn't it? I will
never ever live this evening down.
This is the sort of stuff that legends are made
of! Right?
I was telling everyone how me and Yvonne was
thinking of getting engaged.
And I turned round and there
she is stark b...with nothing on!
I had her singing in one ear
and Hissing Sid in the other!
- Yeah, but you won your bet didn't you?
- Yeah, I won my bet alright.
Ah good boy, did Mickey Pearce pay up?
Yeah, he paid up - he was
laughing but he paid up.
Alright. Come on come on, let's have the 50!
- What's this? 50p??
- Yeah.
Oh, I bet I know what you thought!
You and that Mickey Pearce,
you're like a couple of bleedin kids!
I can't wait to tell the boys down the market!
Rodney's girl did a strip and Del Boy won a 50p bet.
Uncle, stand very still!
There is a snake in the hood of your duffle coat!
God there is too. Look at it. It's a big 'un.
Quick go down and phone the vet's quickly.
Subtitles by NVL