Good morning
Is this perhaps yours, sir?
Fell out of somebody's window
No!
Oh, sorry
Want anything from me?
Yes
What is it?
I live in the upper floor
I hope you remember me
Yes, you ran my dog
over two years ago
My name is Dorota Geller
My husband's a patient of yours
I don't remember all the names
about his health?
Yes
I inform the families on
Wednesdays, 3 to 5:00:00 PM
Come to the hospital
But Wednesday's only
the day after tomorrow...?
It's Monday today
I'm sorry I didn't run you over
instead of your dog
Come on in, Barbara!
Good morning, Doctor?
There's something wrong, Barbara...
It doesn't bloom
Dorota? Are you there, Dorota?
Why don't you answer the phone?
The perhaps you're out...
This is Abka speaking...
I'm going away for a week
with the class...
I'll let you know when I'm back...
bye...
This is Janek Wierzbicki...
I must talk to you
Could I perhaps drop in tonight?
Well, what was it?
Not the cold, you know...
He's teething... He cried all night
Only went to sleep at dawn
I spent the night at his bed
She didn't sleep, either
She was worried about the
two of us getting no sleep
Father came into the room
in the morning
All dressed, he was, and laughing
He opened his mouth and showed
us a hole where a tooth had been
He extract that tooth himself
Well, I told him the little one
had just cut his first tooth
And he just laughed and said
True enough
Yeah, That's how it is, Barbara
I tie my scarf
The kid's sleeping peacefully
I can see the man
through a half-open door
Father hold his granddaughter
on his knees
She's laughing and trying his tooth
And then that lady comes
to meet me in the hall
Her eyes are black ringed
for lack of sleep
She says, I don't like it...
Too many teeth here...
I answer, Go get some sleep,
father's staying home today
She nods and says, O.K.
Well, the next episode coming to
you next week
Excuse me, Madam
Yes?
A hare fell out of somebody's window...
The caretaker was asking...
Was it perhaps yours?
No
I can see you this afternoon
if it's really urgent...
Mrs. Geller?
Money order
Your husband's sick benefit
May I see your
identification card, please?
I only have a passport
That will do
Do you know the time?
It's past ten...
Thank you
Which room is Mr. Geller in?
Geller... The one we've
operated on? Room12
I'd like to see his records
Yes, sir
Just leave it here...
Perhaps he'll feel like
eating it later
Has he had anything today?
Not much
Good-bye
May I help you?
I have an appointment
with the ward head
No families received today
But he told me to come
My name's Geller
A lady to see you, Doctor
Mrs. Geller
Is it afternoon already?
Ten past twelve
The doctor will see you
Sit down, please
Can I smoke?
I don't smoke, but if you have to...
The diagnosis, the treatment,
the operation ther belated, all of that
What do you mean?
Thing ae in a bad way
Will he live?
I don't know
But I've got to know
You've got to know it, too
No, the only thing I've got to do
is treat your husband as best I can
And I know just one thing;
that I don't know
Give me the district clinic, please
Yes, the district clinic
Shall I give you a lift?
No, thank you
I always walk
Your soup's in the fridge, I repotted
your cactus, please don't touch it
I checked on the ads
Will tell you about them when
I come on Wednesday, Barbara
Just a moment
I'm coming
I took the other staircase
Smoke if you like
How do you cope with bathing?
I warm potfuls of
water on the stove
Look here, Madam...
I really don't know
You see... I...
We're very happy together,
my husband and I...
I love him very much
I saw you together several times
You seemed happy
Madam...
Please try to understand me...
We know nothing about causes...
very little about effects...
and next to nothing
about prognosis
They tell patients the
truth in America
So they do
They usually prove right...
It's different with optimistic forecasts
I don't care, I can stand
a pessimistic prognosis
Please tell me: Is he going to die?
I have to know
I want to do everything
I can for him
There's nothing you can do
Just wait
If you let me talk
just a minute longer,
I'll tell you about my problem
Go on
You see, I couldn't get
pregnant before I'm pregnant now
three months ago. The father is
another man, not my husband
I know I won't ever have children again
if I have an abortion now, I know it
But if my husband is to live,
I can't have that baby
The man I've told you about
is avery close friend
I don't know what to do...
Do you understand?
Do you know it's possible...
to love two men at once?
It is...
Do you understand?
He has little chance to get better,
about several percent
The odds that he's
going to live,
that is just to vegetate,
are fifteen percent
That's what you can find
in scitific books
But I've seen too
many people in my life
who ought to have
died but lived on
...and too many others
who died for no reason,
I can't pass the sentence
You see, one of them...
that is, my husband - made
me feel safe and comfortable
The other one...
Ah, well...
it's wrong to want too much
It's conceit
Do you believe in God?
I have a God that's enough
for myself only, I guess...
Your private one?
Yes...
Then ask your God for absolution
Janek!
I phoned, didn't you listen to
the recordings?
Yes, yes, I did
What's the matter?
We're going away
When?
In a week's time... To Delhi
And then we're going on to
the first camp, with the Sherpas
What have you brought with you?
Andrzej's rucksack
Why should somebody else bury it...
Isn't it a bit too early
for the funeral?
We'll miss him
...up there in the mountains
Take it
Take it away
He's still member of the club,
isn't he?
Then let it stay there, damn it!
At least until he dies...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to
I know
My poor girl...
No, no
Not any more
This is 31-23-67...
Please leave a brief message
after the electronic signal
Hello, Dorota - it's me
It's afternoon here
I know it's already dark back home
I've just returned from a rehearsal
Lots of friends,
but I don't feel good here
I can't wait to see you
I'll phone again tomorrow evening
Tomorrow night, to you
I'd like to tell you
one more thing,
but perhaps the recording
will soon end
Everything's fine, wonderful
All right, you can get dressed
I must get rid of it, Doctor
Everything goes so well?
All right, if you insist
It's the last moment to do it
Have you ever been my patient?
No, this is my first visit
Let me see...
the day after tomorrow...
one o'clock
Your name, please?
Dorota Geller
Dorota... A pretty name...
It's you, isn't it?
Yes
When have you arrived?
Yesterday night
He wanted me to
tell you about himself
Please do
Well, he rehearses a lot
Had one concert already
He thought you'd be there
Can't get through to you...
Said to tell you
he'd try again tonight
I know...
Well, that's about all
Have you got the key to his flat?
He wants you to
take the scores with you
when you're going to join him
They're on the piano,
several sheets in a green cover
All right
Ah, that's your coffee...
It's cold already
Yes, it is
This is the previous segment...
And the one before that...
Just look at them
This one's a month old
and this one - just two weeks
And this is the latest one
You've always taught us, sir...
Forget it, what do you think?
Progression...
Answer it, Dorota
You're there, aren't you?
You are! Can you hear me?
Dorota?
Yes
At least! Good morning,
or is it good evening?
Good morning, I guess
Good morning, then I tried to get
hold of you the last few days
I know, I'm sorry
I was out
Have you got the passport?
Yes, but it doesn't matter anymore
Why?
How's Andrzej?
Pretty bad...
But why doesn't it matter?
What you said about the passport?
I'm going to have an
abortion, tomorrow
I don't get you
I'm having an abortion tomorrow
Do you understand?
Yes, I do
If you do it and
Andrzej dies, Dorota...
you will never want me again
I know
You'll pay a fortune for this call...
Yes, we won't be together
Do you understand?
Yes
I want to be with you, Remember
I want it very much
You'll have to ask somebody else
to bring you the score
Dorota...
I love you
Just a short story today, Barbara
I went to work, to the hospital
A man came to see me and said...
We had to make a
transfer to England, that night
I phoned home
Father answered it and said she was
asleep, he had to speak softly
I asked about the kids
They're fine, he said, the girl laughed
so much she wetted her panties
And the boy woke up ever so hungry
I fed him... And then I couldn't
hear him anymore
just ga-ga-ga... He must have put
the receiver right up to the kid's mouth
That was at eleven o'clock
Soon after twelve, I obtained
a release and went home
But there wasn't any home
Yes, it was then
it was...
Where our house use to stand,
there was just a hole in the ground
It was on that day
A few minutes past twelve
The boss said it was
only exceptionally
Yes
Andrzej?
Can you hear me, Andrzej?
I love you...
so much
Andrzej...
Will you please
excuse me, gentleman
We'd like to talk in private
No, please stay
It won't take long
You didn't want to pass a sentence
in my husband's case
But I don't wan you to
have a clean conscience
I'm having an abortion in an hour
Go out!
Didn't I tell you?
Please don't do it
What do you mean?
Don't do it
Why not?
He's going to die
How do you know?
Metastasis proceeds quicker and
is more dangerous than before
He hasn't the ghost of a chance
Can you swear?
I swear
And, Madam...
You play with the philharmonic,
don't you?
Yes
I'd like to listen to
your performance
Yes, please
Come on in
I'm sorry...
You've been sleeping
No, just dozing
Please sit down
I'd like to thank you
There's nothing to thank me for
Nothing really...
We've only just learned
once again that
it's not the X-ray pictures
that we're treating
I'm coming back...
from the other side
Yes...
You know, the world...
seemed to me
to be disintegrating,
Everything grew uglier,
more hideous
As if somebody did it on purpose
So that I wouldn't be sorry
But now...
I could know
I can touch the table
And what's more... you know...
We're going to have a baby
I'm glad to hear it
Do you know what it means,
to have a baby?
Yes, I do