To be opened after my death
Anka, stop it, damn you!
Please don't
Stop it, do you hear?
It's Easter Monday!
No...
What do you mean, no?
Open the door!
I won't
Please let me in
I'm in a hurry
No
Open the door, damn it
Easter Monday, eh?
Let me in
I won't have the time to get dry
if I'm to- Oh!
Yes, it's me... Just a moment
Would you hang up the receiver,
Dad? I'll take it from my room
O.K.
Has he hanged up?
Yes
Have you hanged up, Dad?
Well?
It's all right, false alarm
I got the curse in the morning
Thank God
Want me to come to the airport?
What is it?
My ticket, damn it
Are you scared?
You won't believe me anyway
if I say no
Right, I don't like your going away
It's wet, damn it
Bye, Dad
Bye, and take care
Anka...
I forgot to pay the rent and
the telephone bill
Where are those bills?
One of the bureau drawers
You'll find them
Dad!
To be opened after my death
Your Christian name, please?
Anna
Age?
Twenty
Are you a student?
PWST third year...
The Theatrical College
I know
I wonder...
My son wants to study there,
what exams did you have on admission?
Literature, prose, poetry, song
Let me see
Elliot's, Herbert's?
Elliot?
I see, he hasn't got a chance
Do you have problems with your sight?
Yes, yesterday I looked at a plane
from a distance
I ought to have seen it clearly
but it was just a blurred shape
And then I remembered
I only notice bus numbers
...from a very close distance
Here you are
F-A-T-H-E-R, Father
You've been guessing
At least the last letters
Yes
And you speak English
Why have you arranged the letters
like this?
I checked you I.Q., too
I see, my father was leaving on that
plane which I couldn't see yesterday
To be opened after my death
Have I done anything wrong?
Have I?
No...
You're not in the centre of everything
Bad temper?
I don't like Father to be away
If you feel sad or scared,
I can stay with you all the time
For my daughter Anna
Well, who's next?
I know it's going to be me...
And me
All right, step up to each other
Good night
We won't have any more games tonight
What a shrew, you love him, remember
You love him, you're offended
An offended princess, concentrate
Why should I love him?
Are you kidding?
Don't you get the implied meaning?
It's possible to love just anybody
We all have a silly something for which
All right, but why do I love him?
I don't know, Think of something
Let's say...
you love him because he stared at you
All right, sir, if you please
Now don't get personal
Lie down on the table
Let's imagine such a situation
Just the text
Good night
Good
We won't have any more games tonight
May the angel put his
blue wings around you...
Don't be shy
Good night
May your eyes that cried so much...
have some rest at last
Let the smile fade,
and now get closer to him
Good night
Turn your lovely eyes to me...
Look at me once more
Turn your cheek to me...
Good night
You aren't concentrating,
do you want?
Let me kiss you
Good night
Are you leaving like this?
I will touch your breasts
They are hiding under your clothes
With bonds of love
I will not let you sleep
See: You know how to look at him
Now you're concentrating
Thank you, we'll have a break now
Break...
For my daughter Anna
Hi
Sorry I haven't phoned, I just
happened to be in the neighborhood
Michal asked me to collect some drawings
I'm in a hurry
Someone's waiting for me downstairs
I say, Adam...
Yes?
You've known Father a long time,
haven't you?
We were students together
Did you know my mother?
Yes, not too well, actually
What was she like?
You resemble her
I mean, what did she look like?
You resemble her that way, too
But she also had intuition, like you
Do you think she could have had a secret?
I don't know
Something she might have
wanted to let me know
She'd have told you
She was like you
I was five days old when she died
Ah, yes
She'd have wrote you a letter or something
Sorry, I've got to go
I'll call in some day
after Michal's back, bye
Thanks
Hello, why here of all places?
Well yes, it's quite nice
Pretty, pale frame
Is anything wrong?
No
At school?
Then what is it?
My dear baby daughter...
Pardon?
My dear baby daughter
I don't know what you look like
reading this letter
You must be a grown-up woman now,
and Michal is already dead
When I'm writing this, you're just
a tiny baby, I saw you just once
They refused to show you to me anymore
because I'll be dying soon, I guess
There's an important thing
I've got to tell you
Michal is not your father
But it doesn't really matter
who your father is
Just a moment of forgetfulness
and the harm was done
I know Michal will love you like a daughter
and you'll be comfortable with him
I'm thinking about you now...
wondering what you look like
...when you're reading this letter
You have dark hair, haven't you?
And slender hand...
and neck...
I would so much like to...
Mother...
Good afternoon, is Jarek home?
No, he's out
But he'll be back, come in
Did he tell you he wanted to marry me?
I guessed it, anyway
I can marry him straight away
What about your father?
It doesn't matter
He's not my father, really
I've been looking for you
I forgot the keys
Is this our floor?
Sorry
Good evening?
Are you going down?
Yes
You knew it?
And you first...
tell me
Yes, I guessed
Oh, I'm sorry
It seems I've brought all the way down
No, we weren't going down
But this is the basement, Dad
Never mind, come on!
Do you recognize your mother?
Yes, well
One of them may be your father
Dad?
It belonged to your mother
They gave it back to me in the hospital
Sin when do you know?
I've never known for sure
I only suspected
You deceived me
It never mattered to me
You've always been my daughter
You should have told me
First, I planned to show
this letter to you,
When you were ten
But then it turned out
you were still too small
Next, I decided to wait
till you were fifteen
Then you proved too big
So I just put it into
that yellow envelope
So damn simple
I thought things would be the same
between you and me
But you're lying
Yes, you are
Look
I've got two candles
This one's mine...
and the other one - yours
The person whose candle is the first
to die out will ask a question, O.K.?
O.K.
It's a draft
Got a cigarette?
You win
You can ask, and
you'll get a honest answer
Why I read the letter?
I read it because you wanted me to
I first saw it...
during the removal, quite accidentally
Papers fell out of a briefcase of yours
I was sixteen at that time
Fifteen and a half
All right, fifteen and a half
I put the letter back to the briefcase
but I already knew it existed
It was quite exciting to begin with,
to know there was something
I could only learn after your death
I noticed you took the letter
with you when you went away
But you didn't take it with you
the last time
You did it on purpose
Well, so I took it
I carried it with me three days long
A week had passed, and I went to sit
on the Vistula and opened the letter
Quite an exhaustive answer
Have you ever read it?
No
It wasn't too exhaustive, really
Like they tell us at school,
think...
why you say the things you say,
think about the intention or the implied meaning
Don't you want to learn about
the implied meaning?
The implied meaning is that...
I sensed, or guessed, the contents
of this letter several years ago
When I had my first boy-friend
I knew I was deceiving somebody
I couldn't understand it
That somebody was you
I keep looking for a person
Another person
But when somebody touches me
I think about your hand
When I'm close with somebody,
I'm not really with him but...
How shall I call you?
I don't know
Anka...
Ah, so you're back
Hello
Well, how was it?
Not too bad
Here are your drawing, I copied and
mailed them and they wired they got them
Oh, gush...
I've heard there are drafts
Yes...
That one?
Yes
Exactly the same
Does it help?
Just look at Anka
After just a month of taking it
Don't you believe me?
Just try it
Oh, you've been drinking together?
Yes, Anka...
How are things at school?
When are you graduating
In May
And what about those dreams you had?
Then I'm...
No thanks, old boy, I'll be going
You haven't even unpacked your things
Go to him
He's gone
I know
Take a bus and go to him
Or take a taxi and go no matter
where You don't want to talk, do you?
Anka baby
I'm not listening
Leave me alone!
Who are you afraid of?
Me or yourself?
No reason to be afraid
I'm getting married
Answer it
It might be Krystyna or Marta
Or Jarek, answer it
Yes?
I don't know
No, I haven't been asleep
Phone tomorrow, O.K.?
He doesn't know he's going to
be carried, does he?
No, but I told his mother
Aren't you afraid?
Want to talk?
Really?
You can run away
Go away, get married...
But it won't help any
What I told you before Adam came
was true
I always felt guilty in bed
Now I know why
I was deceiving you
I didn't feel it
I say, let's make a deal
If you lie and I catch you out,
you will admit it, O.K.?
All right
You lied that you'd never felt it
Yes
You did feel it, then?
You live your own life
You're free to do what you like
And I pretend it's all right
Even if you really want to marry
that boy Jarek,
I won't tell you not to
No matter how much you'd like me to
I have no right to forbid you anything
If I forbid you something or
force you to do something,
I'll consider myself jealous
Not the way a father is jealous
about his daughter
That would be ordinary jealousy,
like between man and woman
Do you get my meaning?
I don't want it to be like that
I've never wanted it
But it's been like that
I don't know why
Remember three years ago,
when you caught me in bed with Marcin?
Was it because of that
that you went away?
Yes
I tried to find an excuse then, too
No father likes it when his daughter
starts sleeping with men
But I wasn't you daughter
I don't know
I often thought your mother
could have
But they say women always know
But she could have been mistaken
No, she couldn't
Women do know
How do you know that?
I just know
Have you ever been pregnant?
When was it?
Last year
Let me tell you something
I used to go away, to spend night out
I left you alone because...
because I wanted something to happen
Something irreversible
At first I thought it would with
your first man, but it didn't
And then I just dreamed that
you should have a baby, I still dream about it
That's why I had an abortion, I didn't want
you to tell me it was all right
For that same reason, I didn't tell you
I was going to have that abortion
I was afraid you'd say, Ah well,
do as you wish, my girl
It's all right
Has it never occurred to you
at I didn't want anything irreversible to happen
What do you want my baby for?
You just want everything to be settled
without you once more, just like that letter
To be opened after my death
I'm putting it back where it belongs
It's addressed to you
I don't want it
I don't
When I was a little girl,
you used to caress my back
Sometime I would cry on purpose
...to make you reach under my pyjamas and
caress me
It gave me a thrill
You wanted me to stay a little girl,
didn't you?
To be a baby
You forbade me to wear a proper bathing suit
despite the fact I already had breasts
When I was to have the curse for the first time
you took me to the mountains to stop it somehow
And you never married,
Marta or another woman
I was afraid you might...
but there was no reason
You didn't marry again
You've been waiting for me,
haven't you?
Haven't you?
Yes...
It was bound to happen
I'm not your daughter,
and I'm a woman
Do you want to touch me?
Do you?
All right
Then answer just another question
Just one
Why did you want me to read
that letter?
I wanted the impossible
I wanted...
the impossible
That's why I hit you the first time,
back at the airport
That was because you'd read the letter,
and because I'd wanted you to read it
Because of Mother...
Because she wrote things
she never told me
Because I love you...
but you're not my daughter
Because everything could have shaped
quite differently
And because of the days that won't
ever be back
When you caressed my back
whenever I cried...
Candy King
Gingerbread Page
Marzipan Princess
Dad?
Dad!
Daddy!
I lied to you, Daddy
I didn't read that letter,
I didn't even open it
Dad, I wrote it myself what you read,
what I told you at the airport
I noticed Mother's handwriting on the
envelope and forged that letter
Dad, What did Mother write?
I don't know
Where have you been?
To fetch some milk for breakfast
I know what we should do
with the letter
This is the genuine one
Will you help me?
Yes
My darling daughter...
I'd like to...
is it: Tell?
I'd like to tell you
something...
most important
Michal...
Michal is not...
the rest of it's been burnt down