Only 3% of the water on our planet is fresh.
Yet these precious waters are rich with surprise.
All life on land is ultimately
dependant upon fresh water.
The mysterious tepuis of Venezuela,
isolated mountain plateaus
rising high above the jungle.
This was the inspiration
for Arthur Conan Doyle's Lost World,
an imagined prehistoric land.
Here, strange towers of sandstone
have been sculptured over the millennia
by battering wind and torrential rain.
Moisture, rising as water vapour
from the surface of the sea,
is blown inland by wind.
On reaching mountains,
the moist air is forced upwards
and as it cools, it condenses into cloud
and finally rain, the source of all fresh water.
There is a tropical downpour here
almost every day of the year.
Fresh water's journey starts here,
high in the mountains.
Growing from humble streams to mighty rivers,
it will travel hundreds of miles to the sea.
Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world.
Its waters drop unbroken for almost 1, 000 metres.
Such is the height of these falls,
that long before the water reaches the base
in the Devil's Canyon,
it's blown away as a fine mist.
In their upper reaches,
mountain streams are full of energy.
Streams join to form rivers,
building in power, creating rapids.
The water here is cold,
low in nutrients but high in oxygen.
The few creatures that live in the torrent
have to hang on for dear life.
Invertebrates dominate these upper reaches.
The hellgrammite,
its body flattened to reduce drag,
has bushy gills to extract oxygen from the current.
Black fly larvae anchor themselves
with a ring of hooks.
But if these become unstuck,
they're still held by a silken safety line.
There are advantages to life in the fast stream.
Bamboo shrimps can just sit
and sift out passing particles
with their fan-like forearms.
Usually these mountain streams
only provide enough food
for small animals to survive,
but with the spring melt here in Japan,
monsters stir in their dens.
Giant salamanders, the world's largest amphibian,
almost two metres long.
They're the only large predator in these icy waters.
They begin their hunt at night.
These salamanders
have an exceptionally slow metabolism.
Living up to 80 years, they grow into giants.
The fish they hunt are scarce
and salamanders have poor eyesight.
But sensory nodes on their head and body
detect the slightest changes in water pressure.
Free from competition,
these giants can dine alone.
Pickings are usually thin for the salamanders,
but every year some of the world's high rivers
are crowded by millions of visitors.
The salmon have arrived.
This is the world's largest
freshwater fish migration.
Across the northern hemisphere,
salmon, returning from the ocean
to their spawning grounds,
battle their way for hundreds of miles upstream.
Up here there are fewer predators
to eat their eggs and fry.
A grizzly bear.
From famine to feast, he's spoilt for choice.
This Canadian bear is very special.
He's learnt to dive for his dinner.
But catching salmon in deep water
is not that easy,
and the cubs have lots to learn.
The annual arrival of spawning salmon brings
huge quantities of food into these high rivers
that normally struggle to support much life.
Although relatively lifeless,
the power of these upland rivers
to shape the landscape
is greater than any other stage in a river's life.
Driven by gravity,
they're the most erosive forces on the planet.
For the past five million years,
Arizona's Colorado River
has eaten away at the desert sandstone
to create a gigantic canyon.
It's over a mile deep
and at its widest, it's 17 miles across.
The Grand Canyon.
This river has cut
the world's longest canyon system,
a 1, 000 mile scar clearly visible from space.
As rivers leave the mountains behind,
they gradually warm
and begin to support more life.
Indian rivers are home
to the world's most social otter.
Smooth-coated otters
form family groups up to 17 strong.
Group rubbing not only refreshes their coats,
but strengthens social bonds.
When it comes to fishing,
there is real strength in numbers.
Fishing practice begins
when the cubs are four months old.
Only the adults have the speed and agility
needed to make a catch.
Adults share their catches
with their squabbling cubs.
Most otters are solitary,
but these rich, warm waters
can support large family groups
and even bigger predators.
Mugger crocodiles, four metres long,
could easily take a single otter.
But confident in their gangs,
the otters will actively harass these great reptiles.
Team play wins the day.
The Mara River,
snaking across the plains of East Africa.
As the land flattens out,
rivers slow down and lose their destructive power.
Now they're carrying heavy loads of sediment
that stains their waters brown.
Lines of wildebeest are on the march.
Each year, nearly two million animals migrate
across the Serengeti Plains
in search of fresh, green pastures.
For these thirsty herds,
the rivers are not only
a vital source of drinking water
but also dangerous obstacles.
This is one of the largest concentrations
of Nile crocodiles in Africa,
giants that grow over five metres long.
From memory, the crocodiles
know the wildebeest are coming
and gather in anticipation.
The crocodile's jaws snap tight like a steel trap.
Once they have a hold, they never let go.
It took over an hour to drown this full-grown bull.
To surprise their prey,
crocodiles must strike with lightning speed.
Here, only the narrowest line
separates life from death.
Most rivers drain into the sea,
but some end their journey in vast lakes.
Worldwide, lakes hold 20 times more fresh water
than all the rivers.
The East African Rift Valley
holds three of the world's largest,
Malawi, Tanganyika and Victoria.
Lake Malawi, the smallest of the three,
is still bigger than Wales.
Its tropical waters teem with more fish species
than any other lake.
There are 850 different cichlids alone,
all of which evolved from just one single ancestor
isolated here thousands of years ago.
These two-metre wide craters are fish-made.
Fastidiously maintained by the males,
these bowers are courtship arenas.
Cichlids are caring parents.
Brooding young in the mouth
is a very effective way of protecting them.
This lake can be a dangerous place.
After dark, predatory dolphin fish emerge
from their daytime lairs among the rocks.
Like packs of sharks,
they're on the prowl for sleeping cichlids.
In the darkness, these electric fish
hunt by detecting distortions
in the electric field
they create around their bodies.
Any cichlid that ventures out will be snapped up.
The floor of Lake Malawi
drops 700 metres into an abyss.
Here in this dead zone
the larvae of lake fly midges
hide out away from predators.
In the rainy season, they balloon up to the surface
and undergo a magical transformation.
At dawn, the first adult midges start to break out.
Soon, millions upon millions
of newly-hatched lake flies
are taking to the wing.
Early explorers told tales of lakes
that smoked as if on fire.
But these spiralling columns,
hundreds of metres high,
are mating flies.
Once the flies have mated,
they will all drop to the water surface,
release their eggs and die.
Malawi may look like an inland sea,
but it's dwarfed by the world's largest lake.
Baikal in eastern Siberia.
Four hundred miles long and over a mile deep,
Baikal contains one-fifth of all the fresh water
found in our planet's lakes and rivers.
For five months of the year,
it's sealed by an ice sheet over a metre thick.
Baikal is the oldest lake in the world
and despite the harsh conditions,
life flourishes here in isolation.
80% of its species are found
nowhere else on Earth,
including the world's only freshwater seal.
With this seal
and its marine-like forests of sponges,
Baikal seems more like an ocean than a lake.
There are shrimp-like crustaceans,
giant amphipods as large as mice.
They are the key scavengers in this lake.
The water here is just too cold for the bacteria
that normally decompose the dead.
Most rivers do not end in lakes
but continue their journey to the sea.
The planet's indisputable super river
is the Amazon.
It carries as much water
as the next top 10 biggest rivers combined.
Rising in the Peruvian Andes,
its main trunk flows eastwards across Brazil.
On its way,
the system drains a third of South America.
Eventually, over 4, 000 miles from its source,
it empties into the Atlantic Ocean.
The Amazon transports a billion tonnes
of sediment a year,
sediment clearly visible
at the mixing of the waters,
where one massive tributary, the Rio Negro,
flows into the main river.
Its waters are wonderfully rich.
To date, over 3, 000 species
of their fish have been described,
more than in the whole of the Atlantic Ocean.
The Amazon is so large and rich in fish
that it can support freshwater dolphins.
These botos are huge, 2.5 metres long.
In these murky waters,
they rely on sonar to navigate and hunt.
They work together to drive shoals of fish
into the shallows.
Botos are highly social
and in the breeding season,
there is stiff competition for mates.
The males hold court in a unique way.
They pick up rocks in their jaws
and flaunt them to their attending females.
Maybe each male is trying to show
how strong and dexterous he is
and that he therefore is the best father
a female could have for her young.
Successful displays lead to mating.
Even for giant rivers like the Amazon,
the journey to the sea
is not always smooth or uninterrupted.
Iguaçú Falls,
on the border of Brazil and Argentina,
is one of the widest waterfalls in the world,
1 .5 miles across.
In flood, 13 million litres of water
spill over every second.
All the world's great broad waterfalls,
Victoria, Niagara and here, Iguaçú,
are only found in the lower courses of their rivers.
In their final stages,
rivers broaden and flow wearily
across their flat flood plains.
Each wet season here in Brazil,
the Paraná river overflows its banks
and floods an area the size of England.
The Pantanal, the world's largest wetland.
In these slow-flowing waters,
aquatic plants flourish,
like the Victoria Giant Water Lily,
with leaves two-metres across.
These underwater forests
are nursery grounds for fish.
Over 300 species breed here,
including red-bellied piranha.
And other predators, like the spectacled caiman.
Ripening fig trees, overhanging the water's edge,
provide welcome food for shoals of hungry fish.
The commotion attracts dorado,
known locally as the river tiger.
They patrol the feeding shoals
looking for a chance to strike.
And waiting in the wings,
ready to pick off any injured fish,
are the piranhas.
A feeding frenzy quickly develops.
Piranha can strip a fish to the bone in minutes.
Great numbers of fish
sustain vast flocks of water birds.
The roseate spoonbill
is just one of the 650 bird species
found in the Pantanal.
They nest alongside woodstorks
in colonies thousands strong.
Spectacled caiman linger below,
waiting for a meal to fall out of the sky.
When rivers finally reach the sea,
they slow down,
release their sediment and build deltas.
In Bangladesh,
the Ganges and Brahmaputra rivers
join to form the world's biggest.
Every year, almost 2,000 million tonnes
of sediment eroded from the Himalayas
is delivered to the ocean.
At the delta's mouth,
the largest mangrove forest in the world,
the Sunderbans.
These extraordinary forests
spring up throughout the tropics
in these tidal zones where rivers meet the sea.
Crab-eating macaques are mangrove specialists.
In Indonesia, these monkeys
have adopted a unique amphibious lifestyle.
They fish out fallen food.
The troop also uses the waters to cool off
during the heat of the day.
But the channels are also the playground
for restless young macaques.
Some of the young have even taken
to underwater swimming.
They can stay down for more than 30 seconds
and appear to do this just for fun.
Yet these swimming skills acquired during play
will certainly be useful later in life
in these flooded mangrove forests.
In cooler climes, mud laid down in estuaries
is colonised by salt marsh grasses,
and form one of the most productive habitats
on the planet.
Four hundred thousand greater snow geese
flock to the estuaries
along the Atlantic coast of the United States
to rest and refuel on their long migratory journeys.
This is the end of the rivers' journey.
Collectively, they've worn down mountains
and carried them to the sea.
And all along the way,
their fresh water has brought life
in abundance to planet Earth.