Trees, surely among
the most magnificent of all living things.
Some of the largest organisms on Earth,
dwarfing all others
and these are the tallest of them all.
The deciduous and coniferous woodlands
that grow in the seasonal parts of our planet
are the most extensive forests on Earth.
Their sheer extent stuns the imagination.
The barren snows of the Arctic.
A thousand miles from the North Pole
and heading south.
This is the very first place that trees can grow.
To begin with, the conifers are sparse
but soon they dominate the land.
This is the taiga forest.
There are as many trees here
as in all the world's rainforests combined.
The taiga circles the globe
and contains a third of all the trees on Earth.
It produces so much oxygen that it refreshes
the atmosphere of the entire planet.
At the taiga's northern extent,
the growing season
can last for just one month a year.
It can take 50 years for a tree
to get bigger than a seedling.
It's a silent world where little stirs.
But there are occasional signs of life,
stories written in the snow.
The prints of an Arctic fox
and the hare it might have been stalking.
A female polar bear and her two cubs.
Some animals are so difficult to glimpse
that they're like spirits.
One could live a lifetime in these woods
and never see a lynx.
The cat must roam hundreds of miles
in search of prey
and may never visit
the same patch of forest twice.
It's the very essence of wilderness.
With so few prey animals here,
life for a hunter is particularly hard.
Creatures are scarce
because few can eat conifer needles.
The moose is an exception.
Growth is so difficult
that conifers protect their precious leaves
by filling them with resin.
That reduces water loss,
but it also make them very distasteful.
At least the conifer's seeds are edible.
But they're protected within armour-plated cones
and it takes a specialist to reach them.
The crossbill's extraordinary beak
can prise apart the scales
so that its tongue can extract the seeds.
Birds are fortunate.
When the seasonal crop is gathered,
they can fly south.
But one animal is so expert at survival
in this frozen forest
that it stays here and is active all year long.
In local folklore,
the wolverine is a link to the spirit world
and a cross between a bear and a wolf.
In reality, it's a huge weasel.
Its bulk helps to conserve body heat
and also broadens its menu.
It's so big and powerful,
it can even bring down an adult caribou.
For its size, it's said that the animal
can eat more in one sitting than any other.
Which is why it's also known as the glutton.
Being gluttonous here is a very effective strategy.
It's wise to eat all you can when you can.
And when even a glutton can't eat more,
it stores what's left for later
in the surrounding deep freeze.
Spring in the ice forest.
The capercaillie can also digest conifer needles.
But feeding is not its priority at the moment.
Like gladiators, the males square up for a battle.
Each may have just a single chance
to impress a female.
Neither can afford a lapse in concentration.
The injured loser may not survive.
The inhabitants of this great wilderness
may live and die
without ever having contact with humanity.
Long may it be that way.
The northern forests may be the largest on Earth,
but to see coniferous trees
that have reached their full potential
you must travel 1,000 miles south of here.
The Pacific coast of North America.
The land of hemlock, Douglas fir
and giant redwood.
Here water is never locked up in ice.
And even if rains fail,
the needles can extract moisture from the fogs
that roll in from the sea.
The sun's energy powers these forests,
not for one month as it does in the taiga,
but for half the year.
These conifers grow at ten times the rate
of those near the Arctic
and they live for thousands of years.
One grove of redwoods in California
contains three of the tallest trees on Earth.
This one is over 100 metres high,
the size of a 30-storey building.
These forests were growing here
long before humans walked the Earth.
They were in their prime 20 million years ago
and existed before the Swiss Alps
or the Rocky Mountains were even raised.
There is more living matter
in a forest of giant conifers
than in any tropical rainforest.
But it's all contained within the trees.
These are as inedible as those in the taiga.
So animals are still scarce, but they are present.
A pine marten.
It's spring, the best time of year
for a marten to find food.
Birds' eggs are a seasonal snack
and for a short time there's plenty of them.
Sometimes perhaps too many.
But to live here permanently,
the marten needs a more reliable food source.
Squirrels fit the bill.
They thrive here on the pine cones
and although these are also seasonal,
they can be stored and eaten throughout the year.
The squirrels are busy mating.
Good news for the hunter.
A distracted squirrel is a vulnerable squirrel.
But this time the amorous couple are safe.
There is a loner stocking his larder
who will be the easier target.
Early summer
and great grey owl chicks are fledging.
Adults can only raise young here
in years when the seasonal vole crop
is big enough to support them.
The moment has arrived for their first flight.
Leaping from the world's tallest trees
is not for the faint-hearted.
If you're going to fall here,
it's quite a good idea to do it in stages.
The ground is no place for an owl.
If he's to climb to the top of his class,
he'll need to persevere.
So now, let's have another go.
The American conifer forests
may not be the richest in animal life
but their trees are extraordinary.
This giant sequoia, a relative of the redwood,
is the largest living thing on Earth.
Known as General Sherman,
it's the weight of ten blue whales.
Higher up in the nearby mountains,
bristlecone pines.
The oldest organisms on the planet.
Some have been here for 5, 000 years.
They were alive before the pyramids were built
and were already 3, 000 years old
when Christ was born.
Across the equator in the southern hemisphere,
there are forests that mirror those of the north.
Here in South America, araucaria trees, or
monkey puzzles, are like the conifers of the taiga.
They have waterproof scales instead of needles
and their cones look a little different,
but the principles are the same.
Slender-billed parakeets rather than crossbills
extract their seeds.
Where the growing season is longer,
there are alerce trees, the redwoods of the south.
As in the frozen north,
the Valdivian forests of Chile
support very few animals.
But that is the end of the similarity.
This is a bizarre world of miniature creatures.
The pudu, the world's smallest deer,
feeds on the giant leaves of the gunnera plant.
The female is just 30 centimetres high
at the shoulder
and her infants are hardly bigger than kittens.
The male must stay alert.
There are hunters here
who would snatch his young.
Another miniature, the kodkod cat.
It's the smallest cat in all the Americas
and a young pudu would be a feast for it.
But with the male on guard,
the kodkod must lower his sights.
Moths are hatching.
They're the last of the summer.
The tiny cat should be able to score with these.
No one knows why the creatures here are so small,
but at least they can survive on meagre rations.
You might call this a game of cat and moth.
As winter approaches in Chile,
spring is arriving in the northern hemisphere.
These are the deciduous forests of home.
Dormant throughout the winter,
they now undergo one of the most
magical transformations in the natural world.
By late spring, the landscape is wrapped
in a vibrant fresh green.
Here, instead of conifers,
there are broad-leaved trees
and that makes the character of this forest
entirely different.
Being broad, these leaves trap
much more light than needles.
But they're also thin, soft and edible.
And others can eat the leaf-eaters.
It's spring in the great broad-leaved forests
of Eastern Europe and Asiatic Russia.
The mandarin ducks are calling.
The female mandarin nests in a tree hole.
And when it's time for everyone to leave,
she leads the way.
The ducklings are only 24 hours old.
It's a long drop
and a few calls of encouragement are required.
Two down, seven to go.
There are still two missing.
All present and correct.
But they won't be safe until they reach water.
And the forest pool is almost a mile away.
By June, the days are at their longest
and all across the northern hemisphere
the broadleaves are hard at work.
On the east coast of North America,
it seems like any other summer's evening.
But tonight is special.
After 17 years underground, creatures are stirring.
The nymphs of the periodical cicada
have been biding their time.
Now they march like zombies
towards the nearest tree and start to climb.
At first there are merely thousands.
But soon more than a billion
swarm all over the forest.
The biggest insect emergence on the planet
is underway.
They invade the upper branches
where they climb out of their external skeletons
and assume their adult winged form.
At first, they're white and soft.
But they have until dawn
to complete their transformation.
After an absence of 17 years,
the forest is now overrun by cicadas.
The adults are clumsy and very edible.
For turtles and other inhabitants of the forest,
this is a feast they're lucky to see
once in their lifetime
and they gorge themselves while they can.
Times have never been so good.
The cicadas have no defences
and virtually offer themselves to their attackers.
The stream of insects is so relentless
that soon all the predators
are full to the point of bursting.
And still the cicadas come.
With the predators overwhelmed,
the survivors can achieve their purpose.
After mating, the adults lay their eggs
and then their job is done.
In just a few days they will all die
and the forest will fall silent.
The cicadas here will not be heard again
for another 17 years.
Having fed the predators, the cicadas leave
one final gift for the forest itself.
The nutrients in a generation of cicadas
are returned to the soil all at once.
And the trees enjoy a marked spurt in growth.
This may be the single largest dose of fertiliser
in the natural world.
In the great broadleaf forests of Eastern Europe,
the days are beginning to shorten
and a primeval sound
heralds the onset of autumn.
Male red deer are starting their rut.
The air is heavy with the scent of females.
The rules are simple, winner takes all.
Across the northern hemisphere,
the deciduous forests are changing.
Leaves that have provided food and shelter
since the spring, are now shed.
In the broadleaf forests of Russia,
winter is particularly severe.
But there will always be some
who benefit from hardship.
Black vultures scavenge
from the carcass of a seka deer
that has died of cold or starvation.
These endangered birds are visitors,
they've come down from the north
to escape the even colder conditions in Siberia.
An Amur leopard, the rarest cat on Earth.
Winter is a difficult time for this hunter.
There are no leaves for cover
and no young prey animals.
This female has the added pressure
of having to provide for her one-year-old cub.
It will be another 12 months
before he'll be able to fend for himself.
The bickering vultures
have abandoned the carcass.
It's a valuable discovery for the leopards.
But the cub
doesn't share its mother's sense of urgency.
The vultures have left behind plenty of good meat,
but it's stiff with frost.
The mother works to open the hide
and make feeding a little easier for her cub.
There are only 40 Amur leopards left in the wild
and that number is still falling.
The harshness of the winter here,
hinders their increase in numbers.
It takes one of these females longer
to raise her young to independence
than it does a leopard in Africa.
If the mother can sustain her cub
for a few more weeks,
spring will bring an increase in prey
and her task will lighten.
For all the inhabitants of this seasonal forest,
the long, cold wait is nearly over.
Spring in a deciduous woodland is special.
With no leaves overhead,
the rays of the sun strike the forest floor directly
and their warmth rouses plants
from their winter sleep.
The ground-living plants are in a hurry.
Before long, the trees above will come into leaf
and steal their light.
Their flowers decorate the forest floor
as they advertise their sweet nectar
to the newly emerged insects.
The spring blooms of the deciduous woodlands
have no equivalent
in either the great conifer forests
or the tropicaljungles.
Within a matter of weeks, the canopy has closed
and only a few wheeling shafts of light
penetrate the woodland.
In the tree tops,
the broad leaves rapidly expand to their full size
to make the most of summer while it lasts.
Then, after a few months,
the days begin to shorten again
and the trees must shut down
and shed their leaves
in preparation for the cold, dark time ahead.
Great tracts of North America flush red
as the season progresses.
The effect is so spectacular and so extensive
that it can be seen from space.
The threat of winter frost
is not the only reason for trees to shed leaves.
These forests stand in the tropics.
Here, day length never changes.
But the dry season is so severe
that the trees can't afford to lose
the amount of water
that would evaporate from their broad leaves,
so the leaves must be shed.
The forest resembles
a European woodland in midwinter
but the heat is overpowering
and its inhabitants unfamiliar.
For the creatures of India's teak forests
these are desperate times.
But salvation is at hand.
The mahua tree is about to bloom.
Its flowers are full of liquid,
making them irresistible.
The mahua is an oasis in a hot, dry desert.
Those that fly or climb
are not the only ones to get a share.
Chital deer follow the Langur monkeys,
collecting the flowers that fall.
The monkeys welcome the deer,
for deer are unrivalled at spotting predators.
If they are relaxed,
it must be safe to come down to the ground
and gather the food that lies there.
But it's not wise to travel far from the sentinels.
Tropical Madagascar, the wet season.
It's now that the baobab trees re-grow their leaves
and collect water to store in their huge trunks
ready for the dry season ahead.
The prehistoric shape of these trees
is rightly famous
but few have ever witnessed
the baobab's real magic.
For that happens at night
and high in the tree tops.
Flush with water, the baobab prepares itself
for an unforgettable display.
Once started, the foot-long flowers
can open fully in less than a minute.
As the flowers open,
the creatures of the forest wake.
The mouse lemurs have been hibernating
throughout the dry season.
With the return of rains, it's time to get busy.
A dozen share this tree-hole,
but there's plenty of room.
The world's smallest primate
is no bigger than your hand.
High in the branches above,
the baobab's nectar is starting to flow.
A drink of this sugary, energy-packed liquid
is an ideal way for the lemurs to start their day.
Liquid oozes from the flower's centre
and trickles down the petals.
But the nectar is not intended for lemurs.
These giant hawk moths are the drinkers
the tree needs to attract.
As they sip, moving from tree to tree,
so they transfer pollen and fertilise the flowers.
Nectar was an excellent first course for lemurs,
but moths are the main dish.
The moths are very important to the lemurs
for they will replenish the fat reserves
that the lemurs need
to survive the barren dry season.
The lemurs might seem to be a pest
for the baobab,
they kill its pollinators and rob it of its nectar
but they do give something in return.
For as they wrestle with the moths,
their fur inevitably becomes dusted with pollen.
So they too become pollinators.
As the alternation of wet and dry seasons
brings change to some tropical forests,
so the progression of summer to winter
dictates life in more temperate regions.
Whether trees have needles or broad leaves,
it is their ability to survive annual change
that has enabled them to cover
such vast areas of the Earth
and made the seasonal forests
the greatest forests of all.