This is our planet's hothouse,
the jungle, the tropical rainforest.
Forests like these occupy only 3% of the land
yet they're home
to over half of the world's species.
But how do so many different kinds
of plants and animals
find the space here to live alongside one another?
On the dark, humid forest floor,
the jungle appears to be lifeless.
Often, the only signs of life are what you hear.
A male Blue Bird of Paradise
is advertising for a mate.
It's quite a performance.
But he's not the only bird of paradise here
keen to make an impression.
There are nearly 40 different kinds
on the island of New Guinea,
each with a display
seemingly more bizarre than the rest.
A Rifle Bird of Paradise.
Like many jungle animals, birds of paradise
avoid competing with each other.
And these do so by living in different parts
of this jungle-covered island.
The Six-Plumed Bird of Paradise
displays in his special clearing on the forest floor.
The Magnificent Bird of Paradise
favours the low branches of bushes.
His female is modestly dressed.
The male has a good set of lungs,
but he'll have to do more than flutter his eyelids
if he wants to impress her.
It'll all depend on his performance.
The females may be dull-looking
but they're very picky.
And it's time for a really close inspection.
His right side looks fine, but what about his left?
Pretty impressive, but is he magnificent enough?
Oh, dear! Her departure says it all.
Generations of choosy females have driven
the evolution of these remarkable displays.
The more extravagant a male is,
the more likely he will be noticed.
New Guinea lies in a warm tropical belt
that girdles our planet around the equator.
With abundant rainfall
and 12 hours of daylight 365 days a year,
it's here that rainforests flourish.
Surprisingly, only 2% of the sunlight
filters down to the forest floor.
Down here, seedlings struggle to grow.
But the gloom is not eternal.
The death of a forest giant is always saddening.
But it has to happen
if the forest is to remain healthy.
The sudden blaze of sunlight
will bring life to the forest floor.
A single hectare of rainforest
may contain as many as 250 species of tree.
That's nearly 10 times the number
that grow in Britain.
And the thirst for light triggers a race
for a place in the sun.
There's no time to waste.
A seed that may have fallen only a few days ago
now bursts through the leaf litter.
With so many competitors,
getting a good start is critical.
But each plant has its own particular strategy
for making the most of this rare opportunity.
The seeds of hardwoods are quick to germinate.
But like the fabled tortoise,
their strategy is to be slow and steady.
Vines and other climbers put all their energy
into rapid vertical growth rather than girth,
though they'll need to be well-supported.
The climber's strategy looks chaotic
but there's method in their madness.
Their growing tips circle like lassoes
searching out anchors for their spindly stems.
They put coils in their tendrils
so that if their support moves,
they will stretch and not snap.
But the frontrunners at this stage,
the first to fill the clearing,
are pioneers like the Macarangas.
Their immense leaves
capture huge amounts of sunlight,
so fuelling their growth.
As a result, the Macarangas
grow a remarkable eight metres a year,
surging ahead of almost all their rivals.
In the race for the top spot, hundreds will start
yet few will ever reach the finishing line,
their growth cut short by the diminishing light.
In less than four years the gap will have gone,
but that's not the end of the race.
The ultimate winners are the tortoises,
the slow and steady hardwoods.
When the short-lived pioneers have fallen,
it's the hardwoods that take their place.
And a 50-metre giant like this one
may keep its place in the sun
for another 200 years.
At the top is the canopy,
the engine room of the jungle.
It's up here that most of the animal life
in a rainforest can be found.
But despite the apparent abundance
of vegetable food,
gathering it is seldom easy.
With no real seasons, each tree flowers or fruits
at a different time of the year,
which means that food is very widely spaced.
Monkeys, like these tamarins,
must search the canopy for all kinds of food
if they're to survive.
But across the world's rainforests,
there's one type of fruiting tree
that always delivers.
The fig.
Wherever they grow, figs are a magnet
for a great diversity of animals.
In the Amazon,
the first to appear are the spider monkeys.
These large primates are big fig-eaters.
But they won't have the tree
to themselves for long.
Others will want a share.
Like the diminutive Emperor tamarins.
The tamarins love figs, too,
but being petite means they're easily scared off.
Squirrel monkeys are also small,
but they have strength in numbers.
Their time-share on the tree may be short
so their tactics are more smash-and-grab.
Capuchin Monkeys are the bully boys
in these forests
and they want the ripe figs for themselves.
Figs are one of the few trees
that fruit the year round.
So when other food is scarce,
these fruits are always available
somewhere or other.
Even for leaf-eaters like howler monkeys,
the ripe figs are just too good to miss.
And howlers are too big
for the capuchins to chase off.
Figs are so popular that as many as
44 different kinds of bird and monkey
have been seen working a shift system
on a single tree.
Because fruiting trees are so valuable,
many monkeys are territorial.
And if you live in the treetops,
there's perhaps no better way
of staking your claim to a territory than this.
The calls of the Siamang gibbons begin as a duet
between the dominant male and female.
The rest of their family soon join in
and it results in a frenzy of activity.
The calls can carry over a mile
and their message is clear.
They tell any neighbouring Siamangs,
"This is our territory, keep out."
Up here, the calls of Siamang gibbons
seem to dominate the airwaves.
But with the jungle's incredible diversity,
there are countless others trying to be heard, too.
Every layer seems to beat to a different tune.
In the early morning,
the forest's chorus is particularly rich.
Sounds travel further in the cooler air.
But few calls can penetrate
as far through the dense vegetation as this one,
the deep bass solo of a male orang-utan.
In the middle of the day, little stirs in the jungle
and the hot, dense air muffles the sound.
As the afternoon wears on,
a different set of players begin to warm up.
Insects work in harmony, timing their calls
to fall between the notes of others.
Many singers stick to precise schedules.
And right on cue, the 6:00 cicada.
Night brings out a whole new orchestra.
The cacophony of competing calls
seems deafening to us,
but frogs' ears are tuned to hear
only the calls of their own kind.
The songs of courtship echo from all around.
Male gliding leaf frogs leap from the treetops.
To slow their descent,
they use their huge webbed feet as parachutes.
These large tree frogs spend most of their lives
in the high canopy
and only come down when it's time to breed.
Once settled,
they begin to serenade their unseen females.
Now it's time for the females to make their move.
There's no shortage of suitors,
but this female has already made her choice.
She's heading towards the loudest call
because loud calls come from big frogs,
and big is best.
But to reach him she must run the gauntlet
of a gang of smaller suitors.
Their only chance of mating
is to make a sneaky interception.
He scored.
But with more females arriving all the time,
it's not over until the fat frog stops singing.
Feet, so vital for gliding,
are now put to other uses.
Two's company, three is inconvenient.
But in any case,
all male frogs are equipped with dry thumbs,
which enable them to get a vice-like grip
on their moist partners.
It's a case of first come, first served.
Living in such a humid environment means
jungle frogs are less tied to puddles and pools.
And these even lay their eggs out of water.
There's little chance of them drying out,
and up here they're safer from predators.
Surprisingly, it doesn't rain every day
in a rainforest,
but more still falls here
than anywhere else on Earth.
On average, over two metres a year.
A single tree can suck up
hundreds of tons of water each year.
But the trees can't use all this water,
so much of it returns to the air as vapour,
forming mist and clouds.
In the Amazon, the largest unbroken stretch
of rainforest in the world,
half of all the rainwater that falls
comes from clouds
produced by the trees themselves.
With so much rain,
it's not surprising that many of the world's
largest rivers are found in rainforests.
Inside the forest, the high humidity
creates the perfect conditions
for a strange world where life is built on decay.
Amoeba-like slime moulds cruise the surface,
feeding on bacteria and rotting vegetation.
Fungi also flourish on decay.
These are the fruiting bodies of the fungi,
the only visible sign of a vast underground
network of fungal filaments.
In temperate forests, the build-up of leaf litter
creates rich stores of nutrients.
That, however, doesn't happen here.
Nutrients that reach the soil
are leeched out by the rain,
but fungi are connected to tree roots
by their underground filaments,
and by quickly consuming the dead,
they help to recycle crucial minerals
straight back into the trees.
And this recycling happens faster here
than anywhere else on the planet.
There are thought to be nearly a million
different types of fungi in the tropics,
the vast majority still unknown to science.
But one thing's for certain.
Without fungi, rainforests could not exist.
Nothing goes to waste in a rainforest.
The fungi become food for others,
like these beetle larvae.
Finding the fungus isn't a problem for the grubs
since their caring parents
actually show them the way.
Incredibly, 80% of all insects live in jungles.
Few are more successful than the ants.
There can be eight million individuals
in a single hectare.
But jungle ants don't have it all their own way.
These bullet ants are showing
some worrying symptoms.
Spores from a parasitic fungus called Cordyceps
have infiltrated their bodies and their minds.
Its infected brain directs this ant upwards.
Then, utterly disoriented,
it grips a stem with its mandibles.
Those afflicted that are discovered by the workers
are quickly taken away
and dumped far away from the colony.
It seems extreme, but this is the reason why.
Like something out of science fiction,
the fruiting body of the Cordyceps
erupts from the ant's head.
It can take three weeks to grow,
and when finished,
the deadly spores will burst from its tip.
Then any ant in the vicinity
will be in serious risk of death.
The fungus is so virulent
it can wipe out whole colonies of ants.
And it's not just ants that fall victim to this killer.
There are literally thousands
of different types of Cordyceps fungi
and, remarkably,
each specialises on just one species.
But these attacks do have a positive effect
on the jungle's diversity,
since parasites like these
stop any one group of animal
getting the upper hand.
The more numerous a species becomes,
the more likely it will be attacked by its nemesis,
a Cordyceps fungus.
With so much competition,
jungles have become the home of the specialist.
And this animal, in the island of Borneo,
is one of the most unusual.
It's a colugo, or flying lemur,
though this is something of a misnomer
as it doesn't actually fly,
and it certainly isn't a lemur.
In fact, nobody's quite sure
who its closest relative is.
The colugo depends on a diet of young leaves,
and to find enough of them,
it must move from tree to tree.
The leaves are not very nutritious,
but then getting around doesn't use much energy.
In a single night, a colugo might have to travel
as far as two miles.
But that task is made easier
by its superior gliding skills.
The secret of success in the competitive jungle
is specialising,
and this has led to the evolution
of some very intimate relationships
between plants and animals.
These are pitcher plants, also from Borneo.
Adapted to living in very low-nutrient soils,
the pitcher plant gets most of its nourishment
from insects lured to nectar glands
on the underside of the lids.
Once on board, the waxy sides of the pitcher
ensure there's little chance of escape.
Most slip to a watery grave.
At the bottom of the pitcher,
glands secrete enzymes
which help to digest the corpses,
so feeding the plant.
But not all visitors have a fatal attraction
to the pitchers.
The Red Crab Spider
spends its entire life in the pitchers,
hanging on with threads of silk.
Instead of building a web,
it relies on the water-filled pitcher to trap its food.
When an ant falls in,
the spider simply waits for it to drown
and then abseils down for a spot of fishing.
Alive, this ant would be far too dangerous
for the spider to tackle,
so using the pitchers as traps
means it can get bigger meals.
And the spider
doesn't rob the pitcher of everything.
The digested remains of its booty
will end up in the water,
providing instant food for the plant.
Other food, like mosquito larvae,
seems to be out of reach,
but the spider has another surprising trick.
By taking its own air supply trapped in a bubble,
the crab spider can actually dive
to the very bottom of the pitcher.
Once the prey is captured,
the spider hauls itself back up
its silken safety line.
The pitcher is a one-stop shop for this spider,
but it's not alone.
In the jungle there's competition for everything,
even a small water-filled pitcher plant.
Such specialists create
the jungle's remarkable diversity.
But finding enough food to survive
is so challenging
that most animals living here tend to be small,
though there are exceptions.
This is the Congo, in Africa.
It's a vast wilderness
and the least explored of alljungles.
From up here, the forest looks similar to the ones
that grow in the Amazon or Southeast Asia.
But down below,
there are some unexpected sights.
Crisscrossing this forest
are countless miles of highways.
And they were made by something big.
Forest elephants roam great distances
in their search for food,
but to survive they must emerge
from the gloom of the forest.
And clearings like this one are a magnet
for elephants from far and wide.
These elephants live in much smaller groups
than their savannah cousins.
This might be the first time that one group
will have seen another for a month.
For the adult males, it's a welcome break
in an otherwise largely solitary existence.
And they're not the only animals
attracted to the clearing.
Forest buffalos and red river hogs
are also regular visitors.
As are bongos, which are very difficult to see
outside these clearings.
All these large forest animals have come here
to collect an essential element of their diet
that lies buried beneath the mud.
And the elephant's trunk
is the perfect tool for reaching it.
To get what they seek, the prospecting elephants
must first blow away the covering layer of silt.
Satisfaction at last.
They're collecting a particular kind of clay
that contains vital minerals
scarce in their natural diet.
It may be mud but there's just nothing
quite like it for enriching the blood.
The clay also helps to absorb the toxins
found in many leaves that the elephants eat.
There are other benefits to coming here.
These clearings are the only places
where the forest elephants
can get together in such numbers.
When they return to the forest,
they will have to go
their separate ways once more.
If large animals are rare in jungles,
then groups of large animals
actually living together are even rarer.
This posse of hunters is not only formidable,
it's also very large.
In their search for food,
chimpanzees move effortlessly
between the forest floor and the canopy.
They're one of the few jungle animals
able to do so.
Figs are a vital part of a chimpanzee's diet
and some just can't seem to get enough of them.
But there's something special
about this stretch of forest in Uganda.
Fruit is actually abundant.
And a lot of food supports lots of chimps.
At 150 strong,
this community of chimps
is the biggest yet found in Africa.
Their numbers are so large
that they need a big territory, lots of fig trees,
and they're willing to fight for it.
These calls announce the start of a raid
into land controlled by their neighbours.
As they leave their core zone,
the patrol goes silent,
occasionally stopping to listen.
Signs of the enemy are detected
and examined closely.
The chimp militia are now
at the very edge of their territory.
All need to be on maximum alert.
They must wait and listen.
An unfamiliar chimp call raises the tension.
It's an uncertain time,
the size of the rival group is as yet unknown.
Not far away,
their neighbours are feeding in a fig tree,
oblivious to the approaching dangers.
The patrol moves off with a sense of purpose.
They must remain silent
until they close in on their rivals.
The attack is on!
To intimidate their opponents,
the aggressors scream
and drum on buttress roots.
Several males corner an enemy female.
It's a ferocious attack
and she's lucky to escape with her life.
Others are not so fortunate.
The battle won, a grizzly scene unfolds.
An enemy youngster has been caught and killed.
The carcass is shared between members
of the group and eaten.
Killing a competitor makes sense
if you want to protect your food supply.
But exactly why they cannibalise
the dead chimp is not fully understood.
It may simply be a chance for some extra protein.
Teamwork has brought
this group of chimps great success,
but they'll soon reach the limits of their power.
The competition for resources ensures
that no one species dominates the jungle.
The rainforests' great diversity has come at a cost.
It has made them the most finely balanced
ecosystems in the world,
only too easily upset and destroyed
by that other great ape,
the chimpanzee's closest relative,
ourselves.