What the fuck?
Wow, hey!
Look who's here.
- Finally!
- Look at her...
...with her own business now.
I got some radio tie-ins to help
with Mondays and Tuesdays...
...plus I'm thinking about
adding some contests later on.
- Glenlivet, right, Ton?
- Yeah.
- Sil?
- Just seltzer, dear.
Christopher here?
Is he supposed to be?
- You want me to call him?
- We're gonna sit down there.
The VIP table's better.
Hello?
An FBI informant?
I must've been out of range, Carm.
Your accountant didn't reach you?
A.J. said he talked to you hours ago.
Well, Ginsberg didn't call me.
I'm gonna fuck her face up
before I kill her.
Look, I said I'll talk to him,
so I'll talk to him.
Cousin Brian is dropping the
estate papers by tomorrow.
Good, I'm anxious to look them over.
Let's give it up for No Soap Radio.
Was that a steamroller of a set?
Pick up one of their new CDs for sale,
up at the front.
Come on, Giovanni.
Jesus Christ, he's pissing his pants.
- No, no, no.
- Want me to do it again, huh?
No, no!
- I don't think he gets it.
- Hit him again.
Hey, there you go!
Pretty good.
Okay, well, that's great.
Okay, let's bring out your lover.
The weight she put on in rehab!
How could you do that to yourself?
She always had a bad can. It's genetic.
Hello? Hey, Ma. What's up?
Adriana, you got a call.
Ma, hang on a sec.
- Hello?
- Adriana, it's me.
- Why the fuck are you calling me here?
- Don't hang up, I'll just call back.
Ma, I'll call you later. I know, Ma.
Goddamn it, I'll pick up the Sensodyne.
- Norman, I gotta take this.
- Ade, I got a boliage at 11.
- Are you following me?
- We wanna talk to you.
- A & B Bakery, Route 10, East Hanover.
- I gotta drive all the way up there?
Want us talking to you
in your neighborhood?
And don't go anywhere. We got
a unit watching the beauty shop.
- I'm getting lights and a wax.
- We'll wait.
- Janice, hi.
- Hi.
Listen, I can't stay.
I just brought Bobby Jr.
a couple Xbox games...
...a friend of mine burned for him.
JoJo. Hi, wow.
What are you doing here?
Janice, look at you.
I made Bobby and the kids
some of my chicken Marsala.
Times like this, I remember
when I lost Mikey.
It's impossible to think about food...
...but like the president says,
we have to keep going.
The family's gotta eat.
I'm picking up the kids after school,
Bobby. No argument.
He's hanging in, though.
Aren't you, Bobby?
Janice, leave those.
The girl's coming today.
Then I better do these pots.
I've seen Rigoberta with those copper
Tuffies. What she's done to this Teflon!
Anytime you want to drop Sophia and
little Bobby off, don't be shy.
I mean it.
My kids would love it.
How is Michael Jr.
doing on the Ritalin, Jo?
The way they medicate kids today,
it's the answer for everything.
And then they wonder why
teenagers get hooked on drugs.
If a child had diabetes,
you'd give him insulin.
- I didn't mean it like that.
- Bobby's got to come home anyway.
Karen always made him do his homework
before dinner, or it didn't get done.
The chicken, Bobby.
Put it in a 350 oven for 20 minutes.
You just want to heat it.
And if you have some egg noodles,
it's better the first night, so enjoy.
Thank you, JoJo.
- Everybody's been so nice.
- I'll bet.
Look at all these casseroles
people brought.
Stuffed shells. Gabriella.
- Ziti.
- Karen made that.
- I'm sorry.
- That's her last ziti before she died.
I didn't know.
I loved her so much.
I thank God for every day
we had together.
- She was an angel.
- I know. She was special.
Miss La Cerva.
Agent Harris. We met.
This is Agent Sanseverino.
- Hi, Adriana.
- Eat shit, Danielle.
Or whatever the fuck your name is.
Get you a latte? Scone?
I just want you to leave me alone.
How many times do I have to tell you?
I don't know anything.
You people are just trying to scare me.
Nobody's trying to hurt Christopher.
What was he doing
in Yonkers last night?
What? I don't know.
Somebody saw him having drinks
at the Renaissance Inn...
...with an individual named Chip Zoto.
Christopher ever mention a Chip Zoto,
or just plain Chip?
- No.
- Here's what's problematic:
You don't know where he is,
so how do you know if he's in trouble?
He's into heroin, organized crime...
...he's associating with some
dangerous people.
- Not to mention Tony Soprano himself.
- See, that's where you're wrong.
Tony wouldn't let anything
happen to Christopher.
They're cousins. He loves him.
He loved Pussy Bonpensiero.
What happened to him?
- He's in the Witness Protection Program.
- Dwight, he went into the program?
- You know anything about that?
- No.
We would've heard.
And your Uncle Richie,
I suppose he's in the program too.
He is.
Isn't he?
Adriana, this is a way out for you.
You have your whole life in front of you.
We'd like to see you two have a chance.
Okay.
- I'm gonna get back.
- Where are you going?
You're gonna be working with
Agent Sanseverino here.
What?
- Why?
- It's for your own safety.
And you know what we were
talking about? About the little creatures?
- Good luck with that. I mean it.
- Fuck you.
The more you can tell us, the more
we can help you and Christopher.
He doesn't need your help.
He can take care of himself.
- You want some water?
- Yeah.
- How's Tony been lately?
- I have no fucking idea, I told you.
- Been over to the house?
- I don't go over there.
Hardly ever.
Well, that should be your area
of focus, if possible.
I don't feel so good.
Here. A little more salt?
No, it's delicious.
- I was talking to Cousin Brian.
- Carm, I'm gonna see Ginsberg, all right?
No, not that. He gave me a free tip on
a medical stock that's gonna move soon.
- He said we should put $10,000 in it.
- Oh, 10,000?
- It's not that much.
- Right.
It's not a meaningful investment.
That much of Dell Computer bought
in 1989 is worth 5 million today.
We don't have that kind of money
on hand right now.
Things are tight.
Don't you read the papers?
The economy.
Well, it sounded like
a wonderful opportunity.
What are you gonna do, huh?
Waldorf Astoria for horses back here.
Groom, trainer, three meals a day.
No, Ton, watch out for the goat.
It butts.
- My nonna Lento cooked goat.
- What's it doing here?
Horses like company. Seabiscuit had
his own horse that he traveled with.
How do you like that?
You own a horse, Tony?
Please, as his accountant...
I thought about it a couple times,
but it's an animal, it's a commitment.
Don't tell me
with the bucked shins again.
No, she's fine.
We had a great morning.
- Jesus, that's a beautiful horse.
- She's gonna be a bottle of LePage...
...if she don't win.
Bubeleh, you want a sure thing?
Buy bonds.
Lois is the best trainer here.
This chooch, he sells me a horse,
the next week it starts losing.
I don't know what happened. She ran
ahead by two lengths...
...then she stopped in the backstretch.
Stopped?
- Slowed down. Finished fourth.
- As in out of the money.
Try holding her back.
Keep something for the finish.
Horse is a front-runner.
She likes running up front.
- Well, so what, if she don't win?
- I have to agree with Lois here.
- The horse has style. Don't fuck with it.
- Her kind of track today. Fast.
- And she did draw the one-hole.
- Done, said, finished.
Tony, all due respect,
I'm inclined to defer to the experts.
- Me too.
- All right.
Wire to wire.
And tell that midget not to be shy
with the whip.
If only his mother had taken that advice.
That's what you're wearing to court?
- I'll get it.
- Now what?
It's your niece.
Morning, Uncle Jun.
Great tie!
- What's that?
- Dinner tonight.
Some delicious chicken Marsala.
Murf, 350 oven for 20 minutes,
just so it's hot.
- And if you have some egg noodles...
- Go bring the car around.
- Where you going?
- I'm getting my jacket.
I'll bring it.
Go get the car, we're late.
I gotta go upstairs,
get some change for the parking.
I been meaning to get down to the court
to show my solidarity.
But this thing with Bobby,
he needs help with those kids.
- He needs help? I'm on trial for my life.
- He's gonna get through this.
When? I'm waiting like
patience on a monument.
You really depend on him, don't you?
Well, this one, he drives like a little
old lady. Gas, brake, gas, brake.
You know, I remember Daddy said that
someday Bobby would be your linchpin.
My brother said that?
Bobby was still a headwaiter
when Johnny died.
Bobby's doing better.
We had a very healing day yesterday.
I helped him go through Karen's things
for St. Vincent de Paul.
- Psychologically, that's enormous.
- Yesterday?
- Bobby was home?
- Why?
He was supposed to take care
of something for me.
- What was it?
- Goddamn it.
Each of us is alone
in the fucking universe.
So this estate-planning shit...
Carmela wants it, and I got nothing
against getting well set up.
Half of these cetriolos
live one day to the next.
A blue-chip portfolio like your cousin's
suggesting, to keep pace with inflation...
...if it makes your wife happy,
go with God.
Thanks.
I'm supposed to make the money,
she takes care of the house.
That's the way it should be.
Carmela's a smart woman.
We start winning...
...it's gonna be Intel this
and Coca-Cola that. It'll never end.
- Tony!
- Post time is in one minute.
- Anthony!
- This other thing your cousin advised.
Life-insurance trust?
Big red flag.
What? The kid says there was
tremendous tax advantages.
To Carmela. When you die.
But present day, if something
unforeseen should arise, divorce, say...
...that type of trust is irrevocable.
That means it can't be changed.
You have to petition the court
and even then...
Don't get me wrong.
A trust per se is a good thing.
Avoids probate, prying eyes,
but there's other ways to go.
Such as an inter vivos, or living trust.
- Here they go.
- They're in the gate.
- And they're off.
- Come on, baby!
It's Vision Be Mine, Miss Rae Rae
and Zucker's Mother going for the lead.
Yeah Boy right there on the outside.
Pie-O-My settling into fifth.
Go, goddamn, go!
- Come on, move up!
- Come on, baby! Come on, girl!
I hate this fucking pygmy, I hate him.
What's he doing?
Get her out of there!
Move her up!
Vision Be Mine following by a length.
Pie-O-My behind.
No, goddamn, no.
I got five G's on her.
- He's gonna make it. Here we go.
- Come on, baby! Come on, girl!
Miss Rae Rae, Vision Be Mine
and Pie-O-My join the front-runners.
Look at her. She's coming around.
Jesus, look at her go!
Moving on the outside, it's Pie-O-My
with a tremendous push...
...Pie-O-My with tremendous speed.
Come on, girl! Come on, Pie!
It's Pie-O-My challenging
Zucker's Mother for the lead.
Pie-O-My and Zucker's Mother.
Pie-O-My and Zucker's Mother
as we head for home.
Pie-O-My pulling ahead. Pie-O-My
with speed to burn, and it's Pie-O-My.
Pie-O-My coming from behind to win it.
Pie-O-My hits the wire first.
Son of a bitch!
- And it's Pie-O-My to win.
- I won!
I'm rich. I'm rich. I'm rich!
Five grand and an 8-to-1!
Heading for the winner's circle
is Pie-O-My, owned by Inez Munoz.
- Beautiful. Fantastic.
- Whooo!
- Who is that?
- That's his girlfriend.
I'll give you a shot
in the fucking head, my girlfriend.
- It's his maid.
- Oh, right, the racing license.
Miss Munoz, as the owner of the horse...
...you'll receive an 8-by-10
glossy in two to four weeks.
You, Anthony. You, you, you.
What did you say?
"Hold her back."
You are not going unthanked.
You, I'm giving a taste of my win.
Hey, Inez.
- Come here, have some champagne.
- Mr. Ralph, I don't know if I...
Ahh.
There he is.
I wanna congratulate you.
- I asked, and she was there.
- You know, not for nothing...
...the horse won, but that was not
the agreed-upon strategy.
Nicky didn't sit on her. She was bumped
and got stuck in a speed trap.
So this coming behind, this was a fluke?
- This man here, he knew.
- We all get lucky.
No. Right is right, Anthony.
Fluke, escolar, whatever the fuck.
I'm giving you your taste.
- Your money's no good.
- I insist.
She ran your race. You called it.
End of story.
Three, four, five, 600.
And I need 150 more this week
for A.J.'s football cleats.
In my day, they were 50 bucks.
Fifty? That's what I pay to get
your suits out of the cleaners.
So you got those papers for me to sign?
- Brian's?
- Yeah, I told you I'd talk to Ginsberg.
- Got a pen?
- Anthony Soprano, that is wonderful.
That's so great.
I am so impressed.
Here.
- "Authorization to open an account."
- It's wherever there's a little red arrow.
Okay.
And there.
You need to sign the
agency papers too.
It gives Brian authorization
to buy stocks for us.
What are the little circles here, initials?
You won't regret this, Tony, truly.
This is the best thing for all of us.
It'll give us such peace of mind.
Okay.
Mmm.
Wait, there's one more.
I'm not gonna sign that one.
- Why not?
- I don't think it's a good idea.
But this is what it's about,
in case something happens to you.
- Well, I'm not gonna sign it.
- You have to.
Remember? Your children, your wife.
So they don't end up on the street.
Yeah, well, there's better ones.
In vitro or something?
- What? What's wrong with this one?
- It's irrevocable.
- And we don't wanna get locked in.
- To what?
- Float like a butterfly, sting like a bee.
- Excuse me.
It's the government.
You gotta be flexible.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
Come on, Carm, be fair.
I gave you two out of three.
You gave me?
Ade?
In here, hon.
What are you doing in bed?
We got dinner with Tony and Carmela.
I can't go. I'm sick.
- What do you mean?
- I don't know, I got chills and a fever.
I think I'm getting the flu.
I shouldn't go up there.
Come on, get dressed. Couple of drinks, it'll
kill the germs. You'll forget about it.
- You better go without me.
- But you have to go.
This is the inner sanctum here.
I'm not just a relative anymore.
You think Paulie and his goomars
ever get invited to dinner?
I'm sorry.
Maybe if I just sleep...
Nothing ever goes my way.
Is that sausage?
My mom made it with hamburger.
See?
Just a spoonful, Jan.
That's enough, thanks.
Tell Daddy what we saw
on the way home from school.
The Fuji blimp over Willowbrook Mall.
So?
Well, you kids seemed to like it
when you saw it.
You begged me to follow it.
It was nice of you
to pick them up, Janice.
- And making dinner.
- Enjoy, everybody.
It does smell good, doesn't it?
- Did you eat yet?
- I'll get something at home.
No, it's all right. Isn't it, kids?
- Can we eat in front of the TV?
- Yeah.
- That's rude.
- Oh, no, no, no, kids.
I'm the one barging in.
You go right in there.
You know how to set up the TV trays.
You want a little more?
- Okay. It's pretty good, actually.
- Thank you, Bobby.
Thanks.
Jan, I told you, I don't want them to be
spoiled because they lost their mother.
I saw my uncle today.
- Jesus.
- That's right.
Is he mad?
What's going on, Bobby?
What were you supposed to do?
- Union business.
- What's going on?
- This election coming up, that's all.
- Bobby...
I'm the one that should've
been in that car, not Karen.
And Junior's been so good to me,
and I'm letting him down.
Fuck him. He only thinks of himself,
selfish old fuck.
Now listen to me.
I know my uncle. He's a patient man.
But if you don't do your job,
he'll find somebody who will.
You know what I'm talking about?
All your effort, all the years you put in
getting your ticket punched...
...you'll be a nobody.
I don't care anymore.
That's the problem.
I don't care if I live or die.
We lose that luxury
when we have children.
I remember my son Harpo
when my husband left us.
I had both barrels
of a shotgun in my mouth.
But then just one thought of Harpo...
My little boy without his mother.
- Every day is worse than the last.
- Bobby, my uncle loves you.
He needs you.
So you're gonna get up tomorrow
morning, and you're gonna get dressed...
...and you're gonna get in that car and
you're gonna do what needs to be done.
Aren't you?
Okay, then.
Now, will you eat something?
So show me one of those trusts,
the living ones.
Okay. I can see where you'd
want more mutability, Ton.
Does mutability mean money?
Because, yeah, that's what I want.
Oh.
Carmela's cousin Brian Cammarata.
Ralphie Cifaretto.
- This is the life, huh?
- What life's that?
- I didn't mean...
- I'm kidding.
Just kidding. Any cousin of Tony's...
Lois, how's she look today?
Been clocking her best fractions yet,
21/45.
She's in some rich company, though.
Zucker's Mother again.
And this other one,
frigging Kentucky thoroughbred.
You wanted a stakes horse,
this is a stakes race. I think she's ready.
- So, Dr. Dolittle, any thoughts?
- Only six furlongs.
- She should run it head-to-head.
- Excuse me, signora...
...if I'd listened to you last time...
No, she's right.
Short race like this,
let her blow them away.
Hmm.
Well, foolish that I am,
I'm gonna place some bets.
They're all in line, and they're off.
Look at that. The five horse bumped her.
You see that? Piece of shit.
- Come on!
- Go, go, Jesus!
Zucker's Mother, Lil Camille, Pie-O-My,
Tenant's Harbor sprint out for the lead.
- Run, goddamn it!
- Go, go, go!
Coming to the top of the stretch,
Pie-O-My ahead by two lengths.
Run, you fucking nag!
Come on, Pie!
- Come on, baby, go!
- Look, she's pulling ahead!
Lil Camille challenging Pie-O-My,
Lil Camille giving it all she's got.
- He can't get you, baby.
- But she just can't beat Pie-O-My.
And Pie-O-My hits the wire first,
Lil Camille was second...
...and Tenant's Harbor third.
Beautiful.
Damn it, I bet to show!
What'd you win, 5 bucks?
My financial adviser.
This is it. This is happiness.
Winning is one thing,
but when it's your horse, right?
Yeah.
Anthony.
Once again, your horse wisdom
is not going unappreciated.
Heading to the winner's circle
is Pie-O-My.
Pie-O-My is owned by Inez Munoz
and trained by Lois Pettit.
Hey.
I see the flowers got here.
Which you like better,
the lilies or the roses?
Came into some cash.
Sold a property down on
Frelinghuysen Avenue.
- So, okay, let's buy that stock.
- It split. It's too late. We missed it.
You're Teddy Genaretti, aren't you?
The shop steward for Local 184?
Guilty. Are you a joint-fitter?
- What can I get you?
- Wild Turkey, neat.
I saw your caravan in the lot.
It's a nice car for a family.
- Do I know you?
- Jim Blake.
- What local you in?
- My bad back.
It's just that I follow these things,
this election coming up.
Dick Hoffman for president.
I heard he's got 184's vote.
I think it's a mistake.
Pension's been ripped off
the last 25 years.
Hey, I'm sure you guys got grievances,
but Dick Hoffman?
What do you owe this guy? It's all talk.
He's out of touch with reality, Dick.
You think if push came to shove,
he'd give a fuck about you?
- I know what you're trying to do.
- You look like a smart guy.
I can see why your local puts their faith
in you to do the right thing.
I'm just saying, if it was me...
I got kids that depend on me,
like yourself.
And to waste my votes on somebody
like Dick Hoffman...
...I might as well put a bullet
in my head. Here, here and here.
Affordable solutions
to all your fitness challenges.
Now, the Body by Jake design team
has used a remarkable new technology...
...to attack three of the biggest problem
areas below the waistline...
...with the Body by Jake
bun and thigh rocker.
The 3-minute hip, thigh
and bun machine.
So now you can quickly and easily
trim and tone the hips and thighs.
- What, are you up?
- Cosette, go to your basket.
- What's the matter with you?
- Because I'm glad to see you.
- I worry about you staying out so late.
- Since when?
You hungry?
Want some scrambled eggs?
Yeah, all right.
Christopher?
I was thinking, maybe we should
try someplace else.
I saw this thing on TV, a tour
of this house in Santa Barbara.
You should see the flowers they had.
And the ocean...
- I was in California. Didn't like it.
- I'm just saying, we're young.
We got our whole life in front of us.
Looks really nice out there.
- No snow.
- You're burning the butter.
Let's be honest.
What's our future here, Christopher?
You could end up in jail,
or something horrible could happen.
Fucking negative shit.
Stop with that.
Somebody could have it in for you.
- Who?
- I don't know.
- What is this? Who told you that?
- Nobody.
Fucking negative shit coming
out of your mouth.
I had that bird watching me
when I got made.
I'm already under a
what-do-you-call-it, possibly.
So stop with that.
I worry about you, that's all.
- I love you so much.
- So if you love me, stir my eggs, okay?
Excuse me.
- Is Tony here?
- Tony?
- It's all right, we'll wait in the office.
- What?
- Can I see a bar menu?
- I'll take a CC and Seven.
Nachos grande and a Diet Coke.
Where's your office, in the back?
You should play Skynyrd.
- It smells in here.
- Mold.
- Stuff can kill you, I read.
- Fuck that.
What the fuck you think cheese is?
Mold.
- Holy...!
- You okay?
It's a beautiful day in the neighborhood.
And I gotta rot in that courtroom.
I'll put the heat on under the gravy.
And my daughter's coming over
to the house for dinner, so I gotta go.
The three men were arrested
in Germany last month.
Did we miss it? Goddamn it.
In the federal courthouse in Newark,
there were few surprises in the trial...
...of Corrado "Junior" Soprano.
Hey, Murf.
- Hello, Junior.
- Shh.
The defendant listened as government
auditors detailed...
...financial irregularities
at Comley Trucking.
The prosecution outlined how...
- The fuck?!
- What?
What kind of likeness is that?
If they were great artists,
they'd be in a museum.
I'm fucking fodder for cartoonists now?
You know, Bobby, a little support
in the courtroom would be nice.
- Or are you still hanging crepe?
- I took care of the thing. Last night.
- The guy, you saw him?
- Him and 184 won't be a problem.
Good.
Hand me that weight over there.
The one in the middle.
I'm glad to see you back in the swing
of things. All that moping around...
- You just gotta put it behind you.
- That's what Janice said.
- Janice?
- She's been wonderful through all this.
Looking after Bobby Jr. and Sophia,
bringing dinner over the house.
- Janice?
- She's a pretty good cook.
Since when?
Everybody steers clear of her food.
Nah. She made lasagna
the other night. Delicious.
With sweet sausage along with the beef.
I thought Karen's was good, but...
Sweet sausage? In little pieces?
And a layer of basil leaves
underneath the cheese?
- That's right.
- That's Carmela's lasagna.
Fuck you talking about?
You always think the worst
of everybody.
Well, fine.
Enjoy your lasagna.
Just don't come running to me.
Oh, shit!
Go see if he's all right.
They were here till 1:00.
I couldn't even get into my office.
- This is a good thing, Adriana.
- Why?
They don't pay for nothing.
They ran up a $200 bar bill.
Overcharge some of those
college students.
Ralph and them wanted to know
if Tony was here. Why? Is he gonna be?
You don't know what
this guy did for me.
Yeah, I do.
Not getting my stripes.
Something I can't talk about.
Something that was ruining
my whole life, and he made it right.
I would follow that man into hell.
But why do they have to come here?
I don't understand.
This place isn't bugged. The cops
and the feds don't know about it.
Probably in time they will.
Until then...
Ow!
Oh, shit.
They broke my fucking chair!
Oh.
We're having Sunday dinner
at Tony's, and you're coming.
I don't care if your mother's dying.
Your Honor, I introduce as evidence
government exhibit 27B...
...which is a stipulation between
the parties that if called as a witness...
...Koren W. Jonic, supervisor
of the U.S. Post Office...
...located at 8721 Wayland Ave.
In Paramus...
...would testify that post office box 206
was registered to and paid for...
...by one Ira E. Barad, who resides
at 43 Bellingham Blvd., apartment 4B...
...Paramus, NJ, and was initially rented
by Ira E. Barad on September 16, 1998...
...with a payment of...
I don't care what your psychic said.
Ma, if a guy don't call back within
the first 48 hours... No, don't.
Don't call him, Ma.
Because I don't wanna hear about it.
Oh, fuck.
Nothing, Ma. I gotta go.
I'll call you later. Bye.
I can't stay.
Christopher's waiting for me.
Just checking in,
seeing how you're doing.
How I'm doing? I can't even
get my dog clipped anymore?
- Anything interesting going on?
- No.
Ralph Cifaretto was in your club.
Vito Spatafore, Gene Pontecorvo
and Patsy Parisi?
It's the law. If they got shirts
and shoes on, I gotta serve them.
Ralph Cifaretto drove down
to Philadelphia last Thursday.
Had a couple of guys with him.
- You know who was in the car?
- No.
You ever heard the name
"Cogo, Giovanni"?
Giovanni?
No.
Okay, look...
...Patsy Parisi goes to White Plains
a lot. He gets these suits.
- Suits?
- Yeah, suits.
Some guy came in, and Patsy went out
and got him a bunch of suits.
Boss and stuff, half-dozen, dozen...
...from his car.
See? How hard was that?
Finally, the woman finds the Easy-Off.
- Thanks for picking the kids up.
- No prob.
So how about you?
How was your day?
- Good.
- Oh?
- Yeah.
- I knew it.
See? I knew you would feel better.
Did you make sure that my uncle knows?
- Yeah.
- We should celebrate.
- I'll make something special for dinner.
- No. I mean...
...we should go out.
Vesuvio?
Takes too long for them.
Kids like Chinese.
MSG. I collapsed one time at
the Hunan Palace. Complete blackout.
I'll just open a can of soup.
That's crazy. There must be
something I can heat up.
Really, Janice, you do too much already.
What about this?
Karen's ziti?
I'm not ready to eat that yet.
I understand.
Hold on a minute, hon.
Sorry.
What does that mean, "basically"?
Doesn't matter how he keeps
Old Man Rictora...
He's laying out cash to us every week.
So let him write a check to one
of our shell companies.
You got it.
How's our girl?
- Our girl?
- Yeah, she had a hot tendon.
You know, it's always something
with her.
You should see the veterinarian bills.
Fucking racket.
Know what we should do,
if you don't mind my saying?
I think we should switch her shoes
to those titanium ones.
They don't weigh anything...
...so they're good for a tender hoof.
Sure. Why not?
Here you are, baby.
Shit.
- You don't have to answer it.
- See who it is.
- You want me to answer it?
- Will you answer the fucking phone?
- Hello?
- Hello, I need to speak with Mr. Ralph.
It's your maid.
What, she's gotta go to the clinic
again tomorrow?
Talk to her, tell her to get her ass
in here.
- He isn't in.
- Because the horse is very, very sick.
And he put the horse in my name,
and he say I won't get in no trouble.
But the horse doctor won't do nothing...
...because Mr. Ralph don't pay
the money he owes it to him...
...and the horse may die...
...and I don't know what it to do.
All right, wait.
Hold on.
Your horse is sick, and the vet
won't help until he gets paid.
These guys, no compassion
for the fucking animals whatsoever.
Maybe you better go down there.
Tell her to call 555-0157.
History has vindicated his part of the
British disaster that followed...
...and placed the blame...
A.J!
At the outbreak of the second
Great War in 1939...
...Sir Winston again answered his
country as first lord of the Admiralty.
- After the British...
- Churchill.
You know, you saw that TV
movie you liked about him?
- War efforts as prime minister.
- Yeah.
Three days after his appointment,
he was to make his...
Carmela, can you shut the door?
Carmela,
could you please shut the door?
- Hello?
- The horse is sick.
- And the lady says to call you.
- Who's this?
Mr. Ralph's housekeeper. The horse
is very sick, and she said to call...
...because they needed a doctor.
Slow down.
The horse is sick! The Pie-O-My.
- How bad is it?
- They said she may to die.
And the doctor, he won't do nothing
until he gets his money.
Tell them I'll take care of it.
Son of a bitch.
I am now nearing the end of my journey.
I hope I still have some
services to render.
- Where are you going?
- I gotta go out.
- It's raining.
- Ralphie Cifaretto's horse is sick.
And they can't find him, so somebody's
gotta go down there and pay the vet.
- Down where?
- The racetrack.
It's a racehorse?
So why do you have to go?
- You bought a racehorse?
- No. I didn't buy it.
- It followed you home?
- The horse is sick.
I told him you were coming
with the money.
He finally gave her something
to settle her down, so I don't know.
- Is she gonna be all right?
- Well, she stopped thrashing.
That's dangerous. The intestines
get twisted, and you have to cut.
And they're finished as racers then.
- You the vet?
- I gave her a shot. She's quieted down.
Here. Here's your fucking money.
You better hope she's gonna be all right.
Shh shh shh.
Good girl.
That's a good girl, okay?
Shh. Okay?
Trust me.
Trust me, it's okay.
Good girl.
Shh shh.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay, I know.