What do you hear? What do you say?
Welcome home.
Youngstown, my ass. Look at this guy.
You look like you were in Miami.
- Hey, you look like you were in Miami.
- Good to be home, skip.
What can I get you, Paulie?
After four months inside?
How about laid?
- It's Papillon.
- Oh, hello, Sil, how are you?
I heard you were getting laid
up there all the time.
Come here, you little prick.
Hello, Chrissy.
- Let's have a drink.
- Here you go.
Come on. Pass them back.
- Over here.
- There you go.
All you guys!
- Salute.
Just a second, just a second.
My song.
Welcome home.
Come on.
What the fuck?
Why is this his song?
Paulie, say hello to Brian Cammarata,
Carm's cousin.
The financial guy.
- How you doing, kid?
- So just back from college, huh?
Let me talk to Paulie for a sec, all right?
Nice meeting you.
Have a seat.
So how you doing? You okay?
Thank God that piece of shit from
Youngstown finally copped to that gun.
I could've been wearing
an orange jumpsuit till I'm 90.
Well, you're home now.
That's the important thing.
Here, get back on your feet.
Thanks, T.
Not that I don't appreciate it...
...but I could've used a boost
when I was gone too.
Fucking bills. Then there's Ma
with the private home care.
You know she almost lost her spot
at Green Grove?
An extra 5 G's it cost me just
to hold her place.
You been back 30 seconds,
you already got a fistful of cash...
...not to mention the no-show jobs
I got for you.
You're right, Ton. I know.
- Enjoy the party.
- I will.
All right.
Were you having dinner
at Citris last year...
...when a man threw a drink
in Richard Cross' face?
Yes.
Subsequent to that incident,
did Mr. Cross telephone Rusty Arnold?
Yes.
And the following day, were you
informed that the man in question...
...had suffered a fractured skull?
Your Honor, objection. This whole line
of questioning is irrelevant.
Overruled. You may answer,
Miss Costello.
I don't think I'm supposed to, judge.
I just made my ruling.
You are required to answer.
But isn't there some law about testifying
against your husband?
Excuse me?
Richard and I were married
night before last in Reno.
Your Honor, the defense requests
a conference in chambers.
We'll stand in recess for 15 minutes...
...while the court confers
with counsel in chambers.
- Bailiff, will you escort the jury out.
- Did Julie say anything to you about this?
What we saw in that courtroom is a
transparent attempt by Richard Cross...
...to subvert the intent
of the marital privilege.
Hey, she's his wife.
Where are my pants?
Some mouthwash and shit in the back.
We'll go get breakfast.
Oh, aspetta, I'll go with you.
Any investment advice for an ambitious
young man such as myself?
Buy land, I guess.
God ain't making any more of it.
That's what Will Rogers said.
It's true. My house is worth
nearly triple what I paid.
Well, location's the key, right?
Otherwise, you get stuck with shit.
Sometimes there's money in shit.
How do you mean?
- Nothing, I don't know.
- We're just talking here. Come on.
I don't know. Some guy I went
to school with, this black guy.
We worked one summer
for this not-for-profit housing group.
Told me about some scam his minister
was involved with up in Harlem.
I read about this. Fugazy mortgage
loans or something, right?
- Actually, you ever hear of HUD?
- Housing development, yeah.
HUD was set up to help minorities
and low-income families...
...become homeowners.
There are more programs...
...for these deadbeats, I swear.
As long as the feds guarantee the home
mortgage, the banks will loan the money.
You get a front man to buy houses
in some crummy neighborhood.
Talking about some real shit-boxes,
maybe they're worth 100 grand apiece.
Next, you tie up with some nonprofit
organization who goes to HUD...
...says they intend to buy these houses
from your stooge.
They're gonna convert them to homes
for working-class blacks.
Thing is, though...
All right, sit tight.
I'm gonna be a while.
I'll be over here.
Maurice and I met in college.
All the way to the University of Michigan
to make friends with a guy...
...who lived 20 blocks away from me.
You should've seen his Jewfro.
Out to here.
So, Maurice, Ron tells me you're
from down Roseville Street.
My father was a typesetter
for the Star-Ledger.
No shit?
Sixth and Orange.
Then we were practically neighbors.
Yeah, that's why he moved.
- Hello?
- Carmela, it's me, Furio.
I guess I missed you this morning.
I was in the bathtub.
The reason I call, I leave my sunglasses
in some place, I don't know.
Oh, you're kidding.
Oh, let me have a look around.
So how is everything? How's your dad?
Not so good.
But I get the pictures
from the housewarm finally.
Oh, good, bring them next time.
I will.
There's a pretty one of you.
Oh, that's sweet.
I don't see the glasses, Fur.
That's okay. I probably leave them home.
All right. Well, if I find them,
I'll give you a call.
Okay.
I see you soon.
The summer of '67,
we're both home on break.
I'm interning at the state Legislature,
and he... What were you doing?
East Newark Food Co-op.
Right. But come July...
The Newark riots.
What a fucking summer that was.
Later that year, Maurice and I organized
one of the first black voting drives.
Maurice, were you around
for Anthony Imperiale?
The White Knight?
Around? Who do you think
he was fighting against?
"Italian pride." "Keep Newark white."
Aspiring Klansmen, some of those boys.
So this group you got now,
the Urban Housing League.
What's the story there?
Like many nonprofits,
we've fallen on hard times.
Republican administration, plus a
proliferation of new charities post-9/11.
Sounds like you three got a lot to talk
about. I'm gonna hit the showers.
- Maurice, nice meeting you.
- Same here.
I filled Maurice in on the broad strokes.
Okay, and we got a guy, Dr. Fried.
He's a urologist.
We're gonna give him a half mil
of our money...
...have him grab up four houses
on Garside Street...
...for 125 grand apiece.
The old First Ward.
Once we own the houses,
we got an appraiser who'll play ball.
He's gonna reappraise them
in the $300,000 range.
What you do, Maurice, is you take
the phony appraisals to HUD.
Tell them your Urban Housing League
wants to buy these shit-holes...
...convert them to low-cost housing
for working families.
Once HUD guarantees the mortgage app,
you take it to the bank.
They cut a check,
and we work it up nice.
At which point I assume my organization
fails to make the mortgage payment.
Unforeseen construction delays
and repeated vandalism...
...force the project into dissolution.
We all walk away from the houses.
Your cut will be in the 10 percent
of the profit range.
My office will write a letter
in strong support of your application.
Sounds about right.
Tony, good, you're still here.
Is there a problem?
No problem. I just wanna talk to you.
You remember that time
in Atlantic City?
You brought Irina, your old girlfriend?
Yeah, the cystic fibrosis thing,
the fundraiser.
God, this is awkward.
Irina and I are seeing each other.
What? You're fucking kidding me.
I met her that night at the fundraiser.
I gave her my card. She was having
some problem with her landlord.
She called me months later, after you
broke it off. One thing led to another...
All right, all right, take it easy.
It's ancient history.
Still, I've been meaning to tell you.
I feel like I owe you an explanation.
What am I, your father?
You're both adults. Enjoy yourself.
It's more than that. I care for her.
Very deeply. Roz and I are separated.
The heart wants what the heart wants,
I guess.
The heart also wants
what the dick wants.
Okay, who's gonna scrub my back?
Ralph, you steal my water?
Man, I love this song.
The Chi-Lites, the best.
Believe it or not, the Chi-Lites
were signed to the same label...
...as Tommy James
and them damn Shondells.
See, a lot of people think that,
but they're wrong.
Chi-Lites were on Brunswick.
See you soon.
So, Tony, anyway...
Look, she's a great girl.
Beautiful girl. Little needy.
Frankly, I'm glad to have her
off my payroll.
Thanks. Thanks for understanding.
Wish you nothing but the best, Ron.
Dr. Fried, you are now the legal owner.
Eat my dust, Donald Trump.
- Hey, Adriana.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
Why don't you go haunt a house
or something.
- It's been a while, figured I'd check in.
- So you crawl up my ass?
What do you want, Robyn?
I heard Paulie Gualtieri's out of jail.
- What do I know?
- How does Christopher feel about that?
Christopher likes Paulie.
They're friends.
Is that a crime now too?
How is Christopher, anyway?
He looked tired last time I saw him.
If you're gonna turn me
into a fucking traitor, fine...
...but stop asking about him
like you give a shit how he is.
How's he doing with his drug problem?
He doesn't have a drug problem.
How are you doing, Ade?
- Really.
- I'm fine.
We're both fine.
As a matter of fact, we're thinking
of finally getting married.
You have a good time today?
Yeah, it was cool. I love the ocean.
Feel like taking a ride?
See that church?
Your great-grandfather helped build
that almost 80 years ago.
He was a stonemason, the old man.
Came over from Avellino
with $4 in his pocket.
Yeah, but I saw in a book
where you could get a hotel room...
...for, like, 10 cents a week then.
Room service must have been,
like, 1 or 2 cents a meal.
Room service? We're talking
about history here, A.J.
Your family's history.
Newark's history.
- Well, who gives a shit about Newark?
- I'm making a point.
This neighborhood used to be beautiful,
100 percent Italian.
The 1920s, most of them
right off the boat.
Most Italians couldn't even find a church
that wanted them.
So, what did they do,
did they cry?
Did they go to the government
with their hand out?
No. They took care
of their own problems.
They said, "You don't want us
in your church? Fine.
We'll build our own. A better one."
Look at all these buildings around here.
Most of them are falling
down to the ground.
But that church is still standing.
You know why?
The bricks?
Because our people give a shit,
that's why.
Every Sunday,
Italians from the old neighborhood...
...they drive miles
to come here to pray.
They keep this place alive.
So how come we never do?
Buy land, A.J., because God
ain't making any more of it.
Hey, this is advice I'm imparting
to you as your father.
Now what?
Are you afraid?
Right, like I haven't seen places
like this before.
See those houses over there?
I'm buying them.
Those crappy ones?
What for?
For an investment.
What have I been saying?
I don't know.
Real estate. Buy real estate.
Dad, the black dude's coming over.
- Hey, what's up?
- What's up? Five-O?
Yeah, I'm Starsky and this is Hutch.
Smoke, crack or crank?
No, thank you.
We're just having a look around.
- No eyeing if you ain't buying.
- This is a free country.
Unless you want something,
motherfucker, get the fuck off our street.
The language on you.
You blow your father with that mouth?
What the fuck you say to my sister?
I don't want no trouble. I'm just showing
my son the old neighborhood.
Well, this is our neighborhood now.
Guinea motherfucker.
Yeah, I can see that.
So that's a crack ho.
Keep your fucking cracker-ass off
my motherfucking block!
Come on, ease up, ease up.
She's really gonna marry him?
What is wrong with this girl?
Come on. Moltisanti's a great catch.
Tall, dark and sociopathic.
From a strategic standpoint,
do the nuptials help us or hurt us?
Well, if they do get married,
brings them closer, obviously...
...and, by extension, gets
her closer to Tony.
It could cause her to stop cooperating.
The guilt becomes overwhelming.
Remember Angel DiLetto?
I think it'll have the opposite effect.
His problems really become
her problems.
If they have kids,
that's even more pressure.
The DiLettos never had kids.
I wouldn't count on children.
She's had some issues, female trouble.
Maybe Darwin was right. Nature
really does weed out the nimrods.
So, what do we do, people?
Yea or nay?
Supportive or discouraging?
If anyone objects to this marriage,
speak now or forever hold your peace.
I say neutral or supportive.
Even if we discourage it,
she'll go through with it.
Agreed then. They have our blessing.
To the happy couple.
These doctors own so much property.
You're buying four houses
on Garside Street?
You've certainly got your work
cut out for you.
One day at a time.
Keep on keeping on.
Tony, hey, come on in.
You know, it really would've been better
if we met over at Denny's.
What are you worried about?
I was in the neighborhood.
So, what's up?
Can I get you something?
Scotch, right?
Sent some of my guys down there
to start gutting the place.
One of the houses was a crack den.
- So?
- What "so"?
We gotta get them out of there.
Why didn't your guys roust them?
Oh, nice. Bunch of white guys
setting off caps in the ghetto.
That won't attract any attention at all.
What do you want me to do?
Exert some influence.
Make some calls.
Get the doughnut squad to
go down there and roust the shit-bags.
Tony, it's not that eas...
Hello, Tony.
How you doing, hon?
I'm very good.
No, I'm very well, thanks you very much.
She's taking a class at the community
college, English as a second language.
Well, you sound great.
Ronnie, I'll go make some lunch,
some egg salad.
Great. You hungry?
No.
Go light on the mayo.
Look...
...when you're dealing
with squatters' rights...
...or anything having to do with
the homeless, it can get very tricky.
What homeless? I saw them myself.
They're crackheads.
I understand. They're gumming up
the works.
But try to see the big picture.
The HUD approval came through.
In two weeks, we're looking at
a huge windfall.
See, that's why you're a politician
and not a businessman.
Maximum value is the big picture.
There must be $7000
of copper pipe in there...
...if they haven't taken it out already.
I still don't know
what you expect me to do.
Okay, all right, well...
...we'll take the 7 K
out of your end?
- Well, no, but...
- Come on, Ronnie.
University of Michigan.
Fucking figure it out.
Good dinner, baby.
Christopher.
Let's get married.
Whoa!
Where'd this come from?
I don't know. It's gonna be two years
we're engaged.
Let's just go down to City Hall.
City Hall? What are we, shlubs?
You said you wanted
a big wedding, anyway.
I don't care about that shit.
I just want you.
It'll be cheaper anyway.
We could buy a house.
Plus...
...a wife can't testify
against her husband.
You can't have a club, stay out all night
getting high when you have a kid.
What if we didn't have kids?
Fuck that! What's the point
of being married?
I mean, what if we can't?
If I can't?
Would you still love me?
Of course I'd still love you.
Why?
There's something you should know.
A long time ago, years ago,
I had a medical procedure.
It was before we met.
My uterus got pierced.
- Both of them?
- There's only one. That's ovaries.
So, what does that mean,
you can't get pregnant?
My doctor said it might be hard.
A friend gave me the name
of a specialist in Manhattan...
You knew you were damaged goods
and you never fucking told me?
- How could you call me that?
- Jesus-fucking-Christ!
How could you lie to me like that?
I tried to tell you once.
I wanted to.
I was afraid that you wouldn't propose.
You don't get it, Adriana. I don't have a
son, the Moltisanti name ends! That's it!
- We could adopt.
- Yeah, that's great!
Some kid with Chinky eyes
called Moltisanti!
He'd get his ass kicked every day!
- You said you'd still love me.
- That doesn't mean I'll marry you!
She's a great girl, Christopher.
You don't wanna lose this one.
T's right. You could have
more kids than the Kennedys.
If you're married to some twat,
what good is it?
Gotta have balance in a relationship.
I know all that, but what
if the kid thing never happens?
Come on, medicine today,
technology?
You want my advice?
And this is nothing about Ade
or anybody else.
Stay single as long as you can.
Come on. What are you saying?
Oh, no offense, but ask me,
marriage and our thing don't jive.
Everybody we know is married.
Not everybody.
- You love her, right?
- Yeah. You know.
Then do the right thing.
When the shoe was on the other foot,
your spleen...
...she stood by you, right?
What, do you wanna end up
like my Uncle Junior?
Or worse, like Paulie?
Exactly.
Thanks. I gotta go think about it.
All right.
- Ron!
- Hi, Lenore.
- What a nice surprise.
- We're overdue for that dinner...
...the four of us.
We absolutely are.
- Here they come.
- We're late for practice.
- He's in the den.
- Okay, thanks.
The fact is, Mo, these people
are criminals.
Addicts and dealers who've been
occupying that house illegally.
What about the police? Get the seller,
what's his name, the urologist.
- Let him call.
- They're crack addicts.
They'll be back in two hours.
The deal was for me to effectuate
the purchase of these houses, period.
- I realize that.
- Nobody mentioned violence.
We renounced it, remember?
When Eldridge went in
the codpiece business.
- I'm in a bind here, Mo.
- I appreciate that...
...but what can I do?
Get your people to handle it.
- What people?
- Well, we can't send whites in there.
People of color. You run a youth gang
outreach program, don't you?
- I'm on the board, Ron.
- Fine, I understand.
How about you take the 7000
this is costing out of your end?
Oh, come on. You know what I pay
in child support to my first wife.
The chances I'm taking
with this thing.
I'm putting it all on the line.
So you get some kids, gangbangers,
whatever. You throw them some money.
From a policing standpoint, it's just one
group of recidivists beating on another.
Stop trying to justify it, Ron.
It's about the 7 grand.
Let me tell you something else.
Guys like Tony, you don't fool around
with these people.
My son.
I don't know what he understands.
I'm trying to tell him
about the immigrants.
He talks about room service.
We need to talk about
your recent behavior in here.
Your angry tirade?
You wanna talk about that now?
That was weeks ago.
It was my judgment that, at the time...
...you were in crisis
about Gloria's suicide.
Didn't you get the flowers I sent?
Your behavior was unacceptable,
Anthony.
You cannot have these outbursts
and expect to redeem yourself...
...with an FTD bouquet.
I'm sorry, all right?
It's good that you're sorry,
but no, it's not all right.
We've been down this road before.
- I know, I know.
- The fact that you're angry is fine.
And it's okay to talk about your anger.
But when it manifests itself
in physicality...
...it becomes unacceptable.
I never laid a finger on you.
You loomed.
You threw my tissue holder.
Yeah, and then I picked it up.
- I was very upset. You lied to me.
- I did not lie to you.
You withheld information
about a very sensitive subject.
All right, look.
I know what I did was wrong, okay?
And you may not believe this,
but I did exercise impulse control.
And I have been controlling my anger.
This thing with my son.
I showed him the old neighborhood,
and we got accosted by crackheads.
One of them had a gun. And
the other one threw a bottle at my car.
Now it may not sound like much,
but I let it go. I drove away.
Well, in the future I'll ask
that you extend to me...
...the same courtesy
you would a crack addict.
All right, as long as we're being
truthful here, you know, opening up...
...I've been holding a grudge against you
for recommending that Wendi Kobler.
That half-assed adolescent shrink.
That stupid bitch almost sent
my daughter to Barcelona.
You're right, it's no excuse.
It's no excuse.
I knew I hit something last night
when I turned off the road.
Up and at 'em, lieutenant.
How was your ride?
- Busted brake line.
- Yeah, what's it look like?
Like a busted brake line, man.
- Good morning, honey.
- Can you fix it, B.A?
Gonna try. Thanks, Hannibal.
- I need those.
- What do you need my tools for?
Get my hands on the tape
that'll prove Calvin Cutter's a murderer.
I'm not gonna leave the county
without proof.
The tape ain't gonna do us any good
if we can't get out the county with it.
Listen, I've been doing some thinking.
The kid thing and all.
I'm not happy that you lied to me...
...but I think I wanna try
and deal with it.
Really?
I love you, Adriana.
I want you in my life.
I love you too, Christopher.
Are you high?
You gotta start with that now?
- I just wanna be sure it's real.
- It is real.
I love you.
When can we get married?
I was thinking maybe our anniversary
we could go to Vegas.
Vegas? Wanna get married
by some Elvis impersonator?
- We would save money at least.
- No, it's a sacrament, Ade.
Why don't we have it here,
all your friends could come?
- Yeah?
- Yeah, we'll have it in the great room...
...or in the yard even, if it's nice out.
We can have Artie cater it.
Christopher's gonna ask
Tony to be his best man.
I am sure he will be honored.
- Does your mother know yet?
- You're the first person I've told.
We'll decorate the whole house
with mums.
And you will not save any money
in Vegas.
My cousin Jackie and her husband,
Tommy, 60,000 at blackjack.
- I'm getting married!
- I know!
- What's up?
- Give me some of that. One of them.
Remember, just shoot the ceiling
and shit. No 187s.
Get the fuck out my house,
motherfuckers!
Get out and stay out!
Hey, mister, mister.
I'll kill you, come around here, bitch.
- Don't come back here no more.
- Get out before we kill your asses, nigga!
Fucker's got a 9!
Yeah.
All right.
Don't come around here no more.
That's my brother.
Angelo.
Get out of here, you filthy bitch!
Go, go, go!
I told you young people that crack
is some bad shit.
Dr. Fried, 1,300,000.
Mr. Tiffen, you take possession
as of today.
Good luck now, and congratulations.
Thank you, doctor.
- It's for you.
- What's this?
It's a music box.
Holy shit! A Patek?
Yeah, me and Ralph got lucky
on a new real-estate investment.
You actually did it?
- I was just speculating. I never meant...
- Relax. Your name'll never come up.
No, it's not that. I mean,
the American taxpayers are...
The American taxpayers pay for
airport security. Look how that's going.
Give me a fucking break.
This is, like, a $15,000 watch, Tony.
I can't take this.
It's just a little thank-you, that's all.
A.J., what are you doing down there?
It's me, Carm, down here with Bri.
- I'm just borrowing some tools.
- All right.
Thank you for this, really.
I gotta get dressed.
Furio, hi, good morning.
Good morning.
Come in. What are you doing
out in the cold?
Today I'll wait in the car, I think.
Why, don't you want some coffee?
The motor is acting funny.
I need to keep my foot
on the gas pedal.
Well, okay. I was looking forward
to seeing those pictures, though.
Okay, I'll let Tony know you're here.
Furio's here.
You doing some work on the house?
Yeah, you know, sinking
some anchors for a wall mirror.
Thank you.
How's the mousse?
Fucking great.
I tell you, the shit you miss
when you're inside?
There was a week where I would've
killed for some Good & Plenties.
Should've told me.
I would've sent you some.
I know you would.
See, that's the thing, though.
What I need's not your problem.
- What do you mean?
- Fucking Tony.
Four months I'm up there like
the Man in the Iron Mask.
Not one visit, not even
a fucking phone call.
The guy didn't reach out at all?
John, when do I ever complain?
Paulie, look, the guy's a boss.
You visit a guy in the can these days...
You know the feds.
You give someone the time of day,
it's a criminal conspiracy.
So he can't phone?
You fucking did.
Even before I left, he was treating me
like the ugly girl at the dance.
I'm sucking wind, and he's rolling in it
with that fucking Christ-killer.
- Hesh?
- Fucking Zellman.
Fucking real-estate scam.
The Frelinghuysen Avenue thing.
We had some words.
- Tony made it right.
- It's a different one now.
I'm not sure what it is.
All I know is, Ralphie's going around...
...bragging about how much
they're making.
Listen, John, I know we talk sometimes.
I tell you my problems.
You tell me yours.
And I have the highest regards
for Carmine.
He thinks the world of you also.
Even still, this shit don't leave
the table, right?
I'm hurt that you even have to ask.
As far as we know, Loretta,
those transformers are safe...
...but like I said,
I'll propose an ad hoc study.
- Thank you, assemblyman.
- Okay, bye-bye.
Mr. Olmstead called regarding lunch...
...and you've got
the zoning hearing at 4.
I'll call him later.
I'm gonna make a stop.
I'll see you at the office...
...and make sure she's on the list
for the fundraiser.
What's this, go to your cousins?
No, Verrazano Salvage. Ask for Gene.
Don't forget the fireplace mantles
and the wall sconces.
Go downtown, yuppies
pay top dollar for it.
We're on it, Ton. Don't worry.
Tony, hey.
Assemblyman, what brings you
to beautiful downtown Newark?
Meeting with one of my constituents.
You gonna be at the Bing tomorrow?
I don't know yet.
Maybe I'll see you over there, then.
Maybe you will.
Is it gonna be a nice house here now?
I'm taking it. I'll put it on my card,
okay? It's with my clothes.
Of course. I'll get the seamstress.
Can't believe you're finally doing this.
So sudden too.
The best part is gonna be seeing
how much people give us.
Lisa told me at her and Ricky's wedding,
Bobby Canzoneri...
...didn't even cover his plate.
Shut up.
Forty dollars in an envelope.
Not even a card.
I'll tell you, the main thing
about getting married...
...I can never be called to testify.
What do you mean?
- A wife can't testify against a husband.
- Oh, right, right.
Actually, though, I don't think
that's actually true.
- What do you mean?
- They did a Murder, She Wrote about it.
See, this butler thought his wife
couldn't testify against her husband.
But it turns out,
legally, she actually could.
To claim marital privilege,
three conditions must be met.
First, the communication must be
made during marriage.
Anything said before you were married
is fair game.
Two, the communication
must involve only the spouses.
The presence of a third party
destroys the privilege.
Three, the communication can't
be made in furtherance of a crime.
Oh, my God, it's a simple question.
Can they make me testify or not?
The short answer? Probably.
In an organized crime, a RICO, the feds'll
spend a fortune putting on their case.
Believe me, if they want you to testify,
they're gonna find a way.
Here you go, 10 percent apiece.
Technically, it's a little less...
...but our friend rounded you up
to an even 60 G's.
And there's plenty more
where that came from.
There's a lot of poor families need
affordable housing in Newark.
Ronnie, listen...
...I been wanting to say this.
No hard feelings, huh?
No, of course not.
- You sure you're all right?
- I'm fine.
You're just being...
You're being awfully quiet.
I don't know, tired.
- You ever feel bad about any of this?
- What do you mean?
When I think about
where we started out.
I used to think what I did
made a difference.
The anti-drug programs,
the voter drives.
But over the years, it's like shoveling
shit against the tide, you know that.
I guess.
Yeah, you... You cut corners,
but you help out.
Do the best you can.
Hey, if it ain't us, it's gonna be
somebody else.
Really, I mean, what are we supposed
to be, the only honest men?
We were gonna lead a revolution,
Maurice.
Revolution.
The revolution got sold, Ronnie.
You heard the Beatles for H&R Block?
Sometimes I feel like I
should be punished.
Come on, let's get something to eat.
Well, here's something
I never thought I'd say:
To the federal government.
Depends on which department.
A cappuccino maker. This is great.
Oh, is that the Capresso?
You are gonna love that, Ade.
Cappuccino now.
He used to drink Bosco.
I got it at Fortunoff's
if you want to exchange it.
Oh, no, no, no scissors!
Bad luck.
That's from me. I can't count
how many cheese-melts...
...I've made for Silvio in that thing.
Here, open this one, Ade.
Tony?
You got anything to drink?
What's going on?
What's up?
- Why don't you just calm down and...
- I'm perfectly calm.
- We can talk about what's bothering you.
- Yeah?
Tony, this is crazy.
Tony! Tony!
Come on! Fuck!
Tony, no!
Tony!
All the girls in New Jersey,
you had to fuck this one?
Go ahead, cry like a bitch.
Ronnie, Ronnie, Ronnie.
Ronnie.