"Italy was relieved
today upon learning...
...that the country's
high court...
...had ruled that influence
peddling is not a crime.
Said Franco Ferrarotti,
an Italian sociologist:
'Essentially the judges
are saying
what everybody believes.'
He was referring to
raccomandazione,
the Italian custom...
...of seeking special treatment
from people in power.
'This is our version
of the Protestant ethic, '
Mr. Ferrarotti said.
The case concerned a clerk
of a civil court in Potenza...
...who was jailed for promising
to speed up someone's trial.
Evidence showed that he received
88 pounds of fish...
...in return for his
assistance."
Hello? Yeah, she's here.
She's on duty today.
The same, undercover.
Yeah, let me have
her call you back.
Deb, it was your mom.
You complain about your paper
on ethnicity.
Here's interesting stuff.
It's your background.
We're from Potenza? I thought we
were "Nabolidaboli" or whatever.
Napoletani. But this is
about Italy as a whole.
The squirrels eat
that bread I put out
for the ducks
or somebody sweep it up?
I do know
that Meadow stepped in
some soggy bread
in her bare feet.
You should've heard it.
What's that?
The New York Times
that your friend
here has delivered to him...
...every day at school
for social studies...
...then doesn't read.
I find them in his room.
Make a go of it
at that new school.
You got no idea what we
had to do to get you in.
There is no reason you shouldn't
pass social studies.
You passing social studies?
You just reveal
your own ignorance.
It's only been five days.
We didn't get grades yet.
I what? I reveal my own what?
Look at that.
Now he's reading.
- Hey, everybody.
- Where's Furio?
How you doing, Ton?
A.J.,
finish getting dressed.
- You want some coffee?
- No.
Has Furio got that bug again?
Tony likes
to mix it up, you know.
Different cars.
- What, the Caprice?
- No, he's turning off.
Take me to my uncle's doctor.
Furio called me. He's going
to the fucking track today?
So, what about it?
I don't know. I'm driving again
all of a sudden.
I gotta explain why I want
you with me this week?
- God forbid you explain.
- That's right.
Now you're gonna get
fresh about it.
I'm just saying,
I'm glad to do it.
Oh, I'm glad you're glad.
Your father was
like a mentor to me.
- Right.
- A standup.
You ask anybody.
Your old man was a legend.
He single-handed hunted down
that New England crew.
Brought the war home
to them up there.
Another Chevy.
It's nuns.
Might be undercover feds,
but I doubt it.
He must be colicky.
I think he likes
your hair better that way.
Mr. Soprano.
- There she is.
- You be good, now. Don't start.
You ought to see my finish.
You know, you get sued for talk
like that nowadays.
Cancel my appointment.
Let me die
if a man can't voice...
...to a beautiful woman
the zephyrs
blowing through his mind.
My God, will you listen
to him today?
Go in there now and strip down
to your shorts.
You see, now?
I'm not gonna touch that line.
Too much class. But as
for that lovely laugh line...
Come on, handsome, we're busy.
Give me that cheek, right here.
I surrender.
Do with me what you will.
Okay.
The doctor will be
with you both.
So, what'd you wanna
see me about?
My trial starts a week from
Tuesday.
You'll beat it.
Melvoin's good.
We have to change our
arrangement.
Which arrangement is that?
These lawyers are taking
my internal organs.
A million bucks
for this trial,
Melvoin and Hirshorn
are charging.
And that was bad enough.
They put this Harvard kid on,
this lackey.
I don't know
what the fuck he does.
And then they just
decided we needed
audibility experts
to testify you can't...
...definitively state
what people
are saying
on the government tapes.
I could fucking tell them that.
Yeah, well, those guys,
they got sound graphs and shit.
Fifty grand the cocksuckers
are charging.
Plus the minimization expert,
plus the fucking
monthly expenses.
Fucking Lexus fees,
the xeroxing.
An entire forest must have given
its life in Xerox paper...
...just for this
one fucking trial.
I said to Mel,
"Can't we just
at one meeting
all read
from the same paper?
- Pass it around?"
- Our split stays the same.
You kept me in place as boss
to take the heat off you.
My legal problems
let you go strutting
around like a gabavreesch
two years.
- There you go.
- Ten points.
I got medical bills too,
Anthony.
I got cash-flow problems
of my own.
A one-time hit, 50, 75 grand
to cover the audibility expert.
I got two kids
in private schools.
Goddamn it!
Get your shy running right.
That's what you should be
focused on.
Would you like to try some
kielbasa? Kentshire Farms.
- Sure.
- Nitrate free.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
I like Versace's dinnerware...
...but stamping your face
on every plate. The ego!
Look who's here.
My God,
what are you doing home?
I gotta get this out of my car.
Is that for us?
You're in a good mood.
Want me to fix you a plate?
Will you shut
that pocket rat up?
You wanna say
hello to Danielle?
Not really.
I should go, anyhow.
Enjoy your wine.
Don't listen to his bullshit.
I gotta get up early tomorrow.
No matter
how much the john offers?
Pig.
This is beautiful.
Where'd you get it?
You said
you were gonna go, go.
- I gotta get some sleep.
- I should go.
Froze to death
in that mall today.
They go crazy
with the air conditioning.
So when am I gonna
see you again?
I'll call you.
Okay, sweetie.
Some of those bags
look like Gucci.
He gets that stuff all the time.
His cousin's a liquidator.
- Bye.
- See you.
- You are so fucking rude.
- I had a horrible goddamn day.
She's over here
all the time lately.
Tony still acting all mean?
Cosette, quiet.
Fucking asshole.
Ever since
I questioned his judgment...
...on some Ralphie-Jackie Jr.
problem.
Like he's fucking infallible,
Pope Tony XXIII or some shit.
Now he starts in
with my father...
...so I can be compared all
negative.
- Jeez.
- You never know.
I could be on the endangered
species list.
- Chrissy!
- Gonna get high?
Maybe I'll just smoke some.
Stonato. That's more addictive
than shooting.
I don't do it
every fucking day now...
...like some people.
I'm just chipping.
I got it under control.
Chrissy, Tony loves you.
Why would he have you made
if he didn't depend on you?
He could depend on me.
When the fuck have I ever not
been there 100 percent.
Want some?
Can I talk to you a minute?
Turn this off?
Turn it down.
I'm worried, Tony.
- About my weight?
- About money.
So you're getting
less allowance than usual.
I told you, it's temporary.
Super Bowl last year,
we didn't lay enough off.
No, it's not just that.
I'm worried about you...
...about the future...
...me and the kids
if something happens to you.
- I don't provide for you?
- Now.
I saw Angie Bonpensiero today.
She was handing out
free Polish sausage...
...at the supermarket.
Don't start with that.
I supported her long enough.
Who is gonna support
your children and me?
If, God forbid,
something happens to you.
That's the point.
Sil? Paulie?
That is frightening.
You'll be taken care of.
Say, that was real pretty.
Go on, play some more.
Now, why don't you play
something I...
You're set in perpetuity.
There's money in
overseas accounts.
I don't have the serial numbers.
You'll have them then.
Not now. For your own benefit.
So you're not an accomplice.
Jesus, Carmela, I been busting
my pick all day...
...to bring home the money
you're concerned about.
I thought maybe
I could have a sundae...
...and zone out
in front of the TV...
...because, A, you're right,
my job is extremely stressful...
I am talking about some simple
estate planning, Tony...
...that's all.
My cousin, Brian Cammarata,
helped lots of people...
...set up
trusts for their kids...
...begin asset allocation...
I gotta
spell this out for you?
I can't declare
X amount of my income.
Your consulting fees
from Barone Sanitation you do.
We file a tax return to justify
the house, the cars.
We could be putting aside some
to start a portfolio.
Stocks?
You gotta be high
in the corporate structure...
...to make that work.
We don't have those Enron-type
connections.
Bonds, then.
There are these things
called REITs...
...that Brian told me about.
Bonds? Where's the capital
for that?
In the Caymans
or under the mattress...
...or wherever you put it
at zero growth.
The money stays.
With what's going on
in the world?
- There's always an excuse.
- There's no cash in this house.
Not since our last bust.
Check the vents.
And I provide for my children.
Yes, Tony, you do.
But I don't know
how because you won't tell me.
Let me tell you something.
Or you can
watch the fucking news.
Everything comes to an end.
Good morning, Ton.
- They over there?
- I was able to reach everybody.
What the fuck you doing?
- What, Ton?
- You're wasting fucking ice.
Oh, it's mostly melted.
- You gonna argue with me now?
- No, Ton.
You don't have to see
the monthly statement.
We're losing money.
No, Ton, you're right. I don't.
Think that shit grows on trees?
Ice? No, I don't.
What, are you getting
cute with me?
No.
I think you are. You're getting
an attitude on you.
I'm not.
Ice, Ton,
when it hangs around...
Hey, Georgie, be quiet.
But it gets watery.
It dilutes the drinks,
especially Scotch.
Jesus Christ.
Here, throw it all away now.
Waste it all,
fucking John D. Rockefeller!
Waste it all! Motherfuck, huh!
Conserve!
Where were you?
I wanna know
why there's zero growth...
...in this family's receipts.
Where's the fucking money?
You're supposed to be earners.
That's why you got
the top-tier positions.
Each of you, go to your people
on the street, crack some heads.
Create some
fucking earners out there!
The guy. We talked about this
over at the other place.
With the guy, the councilman.
What the fuck happened to that?
- It petered out.
- It petered out?
- It died on the vine.
- It died on the vine?
It died on the vine.
The guy, he moved or something.
Oh, nobody knows what the fuck
I'm talking about?
We hear you, Ton.
My uncle...
...the boss of this family,
is on trial for his life.
And what you people are kicking
up there is a fucking disgrace.
You know how much lawyers cost?
A major RICO like his?
I'm the only one supporting him.
This thing is a pyramid,
since time immemorial.
Shit runs downhill.
Money goes up.
It's that simple.
I should not have
to be coming here...
...hat in my hand...
...reminding you about
your duty to that man.
And I don't wanna hear
about the economy!
I don't wanna hear it.
Sil, break it down for them.
What two businesses
have been...
...recession-proof
since time immemorial?
Certain aspects of show business
and our thing.
Now, that's it.
That's all I gotta say.
Frankly, I'm depressed
and ashamed.
Is that what your coach laid out
for you as a training breakfast?
The shelf in the garage is
still loose.
You went down in the garage?
I'm gonna go check it out.
You said you'd get up early,
come to church with me...
...and go online and register
for your classes.
I'll miss Grandma-and-Grandpa
dinner too.
There's a back-to-school party
for Hadley.
Those boring Sunday dinners.
Can one of my
new friends eat over?
Aunt Ro and Uncle Ralph
will be here too...
...but I'm sure we can fit.
- Not gonna lay out, Dad?
- It's too cold.
Ralphie and Ro are coming
out here today?
I thought we got that...
...straightened out
months ago.
And it's not "Uncle" Ralph.
I asked you about inviting them
the other night...
...and you said, mmm.
I must've been focused
on something else.
Yeah, well, it's Ro's birthday,
and she's very down.
Anthony, I ever tell you
about the time I had a Harley?
- Whoa, cool.
- Seventy-four Shovelhead.
I could blow off Porsches
on that thing.
Not my dad's Boxster.
- What's your name?
- Matt.
Matt, no offense...
...but your dad's Boxster
is a Porsche with panties.
He knows what I'm saying.
I mean, that's for the Hamptons,
the Boxster.
I'm talking Turbo Carrera.
One time I'm alongside this...
...Turbo
with doctor plates.
We come off the line,
he's got this big Jew grin.
- You're not Jewish, are you?
- Half.
He knows it's all in fun.
We hit the intersection...
...Passaic Avenue
and New Dutch Lane.
We're doing 110.
Right through the light.
He wasn't grinning then, boy.
I look back.
He's white as false teeth.
Jason Mingelli's parents
let him get a YZ250.
You get on that bike...
...I'll cut your legs off
before the bike does.
I had the high handlebars.
Bruce Dern, don't you got
somewhere to be?
I gotta hit
the little boys' room.
You guys need some help?
In my day there was a motorcycle
called the Vincent Black Shadow.
- Boy, did that thing take off.
- The hoods all drove those.
They beat you up that time,
you remember, on City Island?
He'd just gotten
out of the Navy.
I think
he weighed 105 pounds.
Did you see any action in World
War II?
A little bit.
I was stationed in Nova
Scotia...
...but I'd caught
diverticulitis...
...the weight loss
she's talking about.
Oh, my God, you're eating.
I'm so sorry.
Don't worry, come in.
Absolutely.
You want something?
No, thank you.
I came to borrow
the samovar...
...for my cousin's baby shower.
This is my friend,
Danielle Ciccolella.
This is Christopher's cousin,
Tony.
How you doing?
His cousin, Carmela.
- This is a beautiful home.
- Thank you.
- Where you from, Danielle?
- Whippany.
- Want some anisette?
- No, thanks.
This thing needs polishing.
- There's a bathroom downstairs.
- It's me, Janice.
- There's a bathroom downstairs!
- I know.
- What?
- What are you doing?
Nothing.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- I knew it.
Go ahead, you can do that.
How's Ro doing down there?
Very quiet. You know,
it's to be expected.
They got her on medication.
I don't think it's helping.
"Ah, Bartleby! Ah, humanity!"
Danielle,
did you see the loggia?
That loggia was
my daughter's idea.
Nice, huh?
Danielle,
come check this out.
Wait, Ralphie.
Oh, come on.
- What?
- What are you doing to me here?
I was stationed in Nova Scotia.
Well, I told you that.
Anyway, there was
nothing for them to do...
...in Nova Scotia.
Great seafood,
but other than that...
It's a lot of cracked corn.
All the ducks...
...they've flown south
for the winter.
So I'll be ready
for next season.
Thanks.
Red Suburban. I'll be over
at Italianissimo.
Good news
about the Esplanade.
The legislature
voted to refund...
...the special Newark
Development District...
...along Frelinghuysen north
from the Museum of Trucking.
Because of the vote,
Omni will put up a hotel...
...with a galleria
on the first floor.
Word came down yesterday.
A galleria?
Fifty stores selling sneakers
and turnip greens.
It's a demographic imperative.
Hoboken's maxed out.
Your Prada people are already
moving to Down Neck.
Where are they gonna go next?
My old man had a piece of
the garbage transfer station...
...in lower Manhattan
in the '70s.
Now, people told him...
...start buying up the abandoned
buildings around here.
But he couldn't see it.
And now it's Tribeca.
Tell you, Tony, I'm borrowing
money myself...
...to grab up parcels along
Frelinghuysen...
...through a shell company.
A private citizen like you?
Who's gonna quibble with
patriotic entrepreneurism?
My uncle has property down
on Frelinghuysen.
Mr. Soprano.
Oh, boy.
Right there.
I'm gonna be busy the next
couple months. But after that...
...what would you say,
me and you.
Una bella giornata to that city
called Atlantic.
I have many dear friends there.
I could show you quite a time.
- Thank you, but I don't gamble.
- With me it's never a gamble.
You know,
today is my last day.
Where are you going?
Back to school.
Anyway, I'll come say goodbye
when you're done here.
Excuse me.
All the fucking luck.
So, what is it today?
It's becoming clear to me...
...Murf can't run my operations
while I'm in court.
He's starting to forget things.
His words.
Sometimes there's food on
the front of his shirt,
the poor bastard.
I'm gonna move Bobby up.
- I think it's a good choice.
- I wasn't asking. I'm telling.
- So you know who to talk to.
- Bobby know yet?
Well, I think
we should bring him in here.
He's gonna be
a very happy man.
Thought you were
at the beauty parlor.
I'm gonna get
the last of the tomatoes.
Yeah, they were good
last night.
A little late in the season
for ducks, no?
Well, not necessarily.
The ones from upper Canada...
...this is the south to them.
Speak.
I have a collect call
from Mr. Walters.
Okay, operator.
John?
- Oh, right on time.
- It's all I got, pal, time.
What the fuck happened out
there?
Didn't Tony tell you? Sil?
They just mentioned
in passing...
...you were doing the county
book in Youngstown.
They didn't have
long to talk.
Hello?
Let me first say...
...I can't tell you
how touched I was...
...when my nephew told me
you wanted me to call.
Anthony only talks to me
through middlemen.
So, what'd they pinch you for?
Gun charge. I drove out
to visit Lenny Scotise.
Don't know if you know Lenny.
We used to have that club in...
Doesn't matter.
Anyway, my first night here...
...we drive out to visit...
...Dean Martin's
birthplace in Steubenville.
Cops pull us over
for no left blinker.
Long story short? They find
a piece under the seat.
Fucking.38.
Turns out it was used...
...in an unsolved murder out
here...
...from eight years ago.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Yeah.
- So, what can I do to help?
- You're too much. Nothing.
The lawyer said
they'll keep us here...
...as long as they can...
...until they make their case
or somebody cops to it.
- Keep your dick up.
- Well, I... Leave that!
Don't touch that.
My program's coming on.
John, love you, babe.
Don't let me rot, now.
- Hello?
- I gotta work tonight.
- I see.
- You see. You see what?
You're so concerned
about our finances...
...where do you think
it comes from?
Well, be careful driving home.
There he is. Here's to Newark's
newest hotel, huh, Ton?
Anything else with the Esplanade
I should know?
No.
It's the girls
from Icelandic Air.
Oh, come on in.
Hey, how are you?
All right, let me get
the fuck out of here.
- How's Junior?
- He's gonna be all right.
Tell him he's in our prayers,
et cetera.
I'll be sure and let him know.
One other thing, though.
John said he went
to a cookout at your house.
- Yeah.
- A don doesn't wear shorts.
All right, Carmine, come on.
Elevator's here.
- So where are you girls from?
- Reykjavik.
Oh, you do,
and you'll clean it up.
- Christopher!
- Yo. Yeah.
Let's go.
What's up, T?
- You have a good time tonight?
- All right.
Learn anything?
Like what?
Anything.
You had a sit-down
with two bosses.
You got a real hard-on for me,
that's all I know.
- Oh, you think so.
- It's fucking obvious.
Take the parkway.
You know, for all the things...
...there are to eat
on this island...
...your breadfruit,
mangoes, papayas...
...not to mention
the fish in the sea...
...there's no question
about us surviving.
We could go on here for years.
And I mean years.
Where you going?
Get that.
Hello.
Who did?
Oh, they did?
I'll tell him.
Tell me what?
- That was Melvoin.
- So it was Melvoin.
The fuck is this, Mother May I?
Go ahead! Tell me!
He just had a call
from some source of his.
Dr. Schreck's office
isn't safe to talk at.
The FBI had an undercover
in there since January.
Or D-day or something.
The agent's been pulled
to testify at your trial.
All right, pull up over there.
Who's that? Bobby Bacala?
See over there?
Guy in there killed
your father.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Barry Haydu.
Detective lieutenant
in the Clifton Police Force.
Retired today.
That's his retirement party.
Everybody always told me
it was a fucking cop.
I thought he was dead.
My mother can't even
talk about it.
Did the hit for Jilly Rufalo.
He and your old man
were in the can together.
Jilly stabbed your
old man's cellmate to death.
So when your
old man got paroled...
...he tracked down Jilly.
Took out his eye so bad...
...he couldn't
even put a glass one in.
Loyal, your old man.
That's what I heard.
Some guy's eye.
They hit my dad right outside
my house, right?
He was bringing home
a crib for me?
Yeah.
Well, no, he was
outside the house...
...but he wasn't
carrying a crib.
He had a bunch of TV trays.
Could've been
a crib just as easily.
That rat fuck was
in uniform then.
Gambled like
you wouldn't believe.
He did it on contract.
Could've been
a crib just as easily.
So how come
he's still fucking walking?
Because he's been useful.
But he's outlived it...
...as of his cute little
ceremony this afternoon.
Is that him?
With the sombrero on?
No, you can't tell from here.
But maybe. Maybe it... Yeah.
Yeah, probably.
Here.
Nice house, apparently.
They say he paid cash for it.
Good luck.
Questions?
Kill the dome light.
That's the lamest plan
I ever heard.
It is not a lame plan.
We got it all worked out.
We got the time to place
everything!
It's lame.
Magnum, why are you being
so negative and hostile?
I wanted the biggest drug dealer
in the Midwest...
...and he's a dangerous
criminal...
The fuck is this?
You're cleaned out.
There's nothing
to rob in this place.
Well, there's this.
Okay.
You know I'm a police officer.
Engraving on this watch says
you retired, today.
Well...
...every little bit helps.
Rough divorce, huh?
She must be a real vile twat.
Hope she didn't pass it on
to your daughter.
Listen to me.
It's not too late
to cut your losses.
Unlock me, give me the weapons.
I promise you I will do whatever
is in my power to help you.
Maybe. Let's come back to that.
You remember Dickie Moltisanti?
- No.
- No?
Is that what you said?
- Was he a friend of yours?
- He was my father.
Steak san, Newport fries.
Scrambled eggs,
no oil, tomato slices.
So are you mentally prepared
for this promotion?
Oh, yeah.
How's that steak?
- It's okay.
- Yeah?
- Hon?
Another steak san
over here, rare.
Coming up.
No, because it's...
It's a lot of added
responsibility.
I think it should've
happened sooner.
How's your family doing,
you know...
since the tragedy
with your dad?
- Rough on my mother.
- Yeah, yeah, well...
How old is she now?
She's 69.
Mom really went downhill
after the World Trade Center.
You know, Quasimodo
predicted all this.
- Who did what?
- All these problems.
The Middle East,
the end of the world.
Nostradamus.
Quasimodo's the Hunchback
of Notre Dame.
Oh, right. Notredamus.
Nostradamus and Notre Dame.
It's two different things
completely.
It's interesting, though,
they'd be so similar, isn't it?
And I always thought,
"Okay, Hunchback of Notre Dame.
You also got
your quarterback...
...and your halfback
of Notre Dame."
One's a fucking cathedral.
Obviously, I know.
I'm just saying...
...it's interesting,
the coincidence.
What, you gonna tell me you
never pondered that?
The back thing
with Notre Dame?
No.
Look, I don't know who told you
I had anything to do...
...with the death
of your father...
...but their information
is faulty.
Or they are deliberately
not telling you the truth.
Are you inferring...
...that you didn't
take cash from Jilly Rufalo...
...to whack my father while he
was carrying a TV tray...
...for me to watch TV?
I don't know
anybody named Rufalo.
You're being set up!
He's lying to you,
whoever he is!
It wouldn't make
any difference.
What do you mean?
- He wants you dead.
- All right, look, look, look.
I got a boat.
It's a Sea Ray 230.
It's almost brand-new.
I didn't kill your father,
but you could...
You don't want
a cop-kill on your head!
And what if they won't pull
over, T.C?
I'm not gonna take
on a limo in this car.
- No problem.
- I'm sorry!
- Pull over to the side.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
What are you gonna do?
Honk the horn.
Pull over! Police!
Police? In a Ferrari?
Freeze. Don't move a muscle,
or I'll put a bullet through it.
Special Investigator Finaday,
you're under arrest.
What's the charge, officer?
Speeding, reckless driving,
endangering another vehicle.
And impersonating an officer.
How you think it's going?
Oh, it couldn't be better.
You two are terrific.
Soon as they come
through the door...
...we're gonna nail them.
Freeze!
Oh, shit.
I missed my game, again.
Fucking loser!
Now Reese'll have to lead
the guys to victory.
- Who's Reese?
- Kenneth Reese!
He was my backup quarterback at
the Academy...
...and he's been waiting...
...for a chance
like this since 1963.
He got it because of you.
More than 12 hours. Ted?
Amy, in Pennsylvania tonight,
two men were shot and killed...
...in what was described
as a brazen...
...but successful armored-car
robbery.
Three accomplices escaped
with $800,000...
...while one of the dead men...
...Denis Lynch of Freehold,
New Jersey...
...was said by police
to have ties...
...to organized crime
families...
...both in that city
and in New York.
The street where the robbery
took place...
...was littered
with bills from...
- You smell gas down here?
- It's always like that.
He had
the pipes checked?
Oh, I thought
I heard something.
Is he up?
I need to talk to him.
I brought him a steak.
You can put it with his
eggs like he likes.
Actually, your wife's here.
She's making him
something to eat.
Karen. Something happen?
We had some
bad news last night.
Are you just gonna stand there?
No, the feds had
an undercover agent...
...in Dr. Schreck's office.
Uncle Jun.
- Hey, Karen.
- Fucking Grand Central Station?
Junior, my kids, huh?
You're right. Sorry, dear.
I brought my bar of soap.
What time they call you?
We had a little scare.
Thought it was
the shunt in his heart.
He passed some gas,
and he seems better.
Why don't you go on Joe
Franklin...
...tell the whole
Tri-State area?
- Dad, Dad.
- Not now.
Look, I heard what happened.
It's bad, but it's not worth
getting yourself sick over.
- I told you just sit down.
- He doesn't have cable.
Actually, we're gonna go.
Okay, Jun, you got everything?
Thank you, dear,
you've been wonderful.
- Bye, Karen.
- I'll see you.
- Come on.
- See you, kids.
- Goodbye, Karen.
- Be good.
Must've been
that piece of tail.
Now, look, she...
She probably reported the
meetings...
...who was there,
all that shit.
As far as conversations,
what could she hear?
You better hope nothing...
...because you were involved in
every fucking one.
How could you fall
for that flirty shit?
That's the point.
Get the hell out of here.
I wanna talk to my uncle.
Forget about that for a minute.
That shit about
your legal expenses.
I been thinking, and okay...
...maybe I can give you
some relief.
What?
You got that empty garage over
on Frelinghuysen Avenue.
You been trying to sell it.
I'll take it off your hands.
The fuck you gonna do
with it?
I don't know.
I'm trying to help you out.
How much?
Hundred thousand.
- Who gives a fuck anyway?
- Hey, come on.
I was led around
by the nose, Anthony.
You're right, a young cooze
smiled at me...
...and birds started chirping.
The time was...
...my instincts would've
never failed me like that.
So, what are you now,
the Amazing Kreskin?
What did I tell her?
Did I say anything
could be used against me?
I don't know.
Bullshitting, singing.
Atlantic City, Jesus Christ.
I'll be sitting right across
from her in the courtroom.
All right, come on,
have something to eat.
I'm an old man, Anthony.
An old man
that's going to trial.
Not much else to say about me.
I'm a little depressed.
- And you were on vacation.
- Can you describe the feelings?
I mean, things are good.
Especially with Carmela.
Oh, but then she starts ragging
on me about the future.
How she's worried.
And what's gonna happen to them
if I'm dead.
And buy bonds
and all this shit.
A lot of people are feeling
vulnerable.
But on the other hand,
she's right.
Not that I'd ever
tell her that.
Why not?
Then she'd wanna know
where's the money, how much...
Don't you want Carmela
to be taken care of?
She is. Anyway, she's right.
That's the point.
Over the last couple years
I been doing a lot of thinking.
And?
My uncle snapped it into focus.
What's he, 72 years old.
What's he got?
Fucking shitty house in
Belleville...
...and a bunch of
legal bills...
...that'd make you gargle Drano
if you had them.
I've analyzed it.
There's two endings
for a guy like me...
...a high-profile guy.
Dead or in the can,
big percent of the time.
- You never talk this frankly.
- Even with this terrorism...
...the government has resources.
As far as legal bills...
Anthony.
- What?
- Why don't you give it up?
You didn't let me finish.
There's a third way
to wrap it up.
You rely only on family.
Not many men could survive...
...without the love and support
of their wife and children...
No, no, no, I'm talking
about business.
You trust only blood.
A friend of mine...
...a guy whose name
you would know...
...stayed out of the can
and in charge...
...living in Florida...
...till he was 81 years old...
...because he only gave
orders through his son.
No other conversations that
could come back in testimony.
- His son?
- No, no, not A.J.
What I've been dealt is
my nephew.
He's gotten his
act together, the kid.
And over the last
couple of months...
...I started the process...
...of bonding him to me
inseparably.
- How?
- Well, that we can't get into.
Didn't your uncle do
that with you?
You said his life is
like a desert.
I'm 42.
I'm already more successful
than my uncle ever was.
You've seen my house.
Anthony, why are you
telling me this?
I don't know.
Guess...
...I trust you.
A little.
Hey, Mom.
What the hell
are you doing here?
You scared me to death.
Just stopped by to see
how you're getting along.
You ever do anything like
a normal person?
There is a bell.
So how you been?
Fine.
- How's Connie's kid?
- He's huge.
Jesus!
That's Jason?
He has a weight problem already,
eight years old.
She never had him baptized.
She thought she knew everything.
Actually, I was hoping...
...you'd make me one of
your fluffernutters.
It's fucking mouthwash.
Leave me the fuck alone,
you come over here
for that shit.
What's that on the table?
Daddy's Navy picture?
You ever miss him?
When he was in prison?
Or since he's been dead?
I don't know.
Did I saddle you
with a stepfather?
I don't have any peanut butter.
I haven't kept it
since you left.
I can't make you
a fluffernutter.
Want French toast?
No.
I gotta go.
- Ade sends her love.
- Right. Say hello.
And you watch that Baileys.
I'll give you
a shot in the head.
- Look who's talking.
- What?
Never mind what.