Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
Looking down from two miles
above the surface of the Earth
it's impossible not to be impressed
by the sheer grandeur and splendour
and power of the natural world.
Ten years ago, in a television
series called Planet Earth,
we revealed many of those wonders,
but today, much has changed.
We can now show life on our
planet in entirely new ways.
Bring you closer to
animals than ever before.
And reveal new wildlife
dramas for the very first time.
But that's not all.
Our planet has changed too.
Never have those wildernesses
been as fragile and as precious
as they are today.
At this crucial time for the natural world,
we will journey to every
corner of the globe...
...to explore the greatest
treasures of our living planet...
...and reveal the extreme
lengths animals go to
to survive.
Finally, we will explore our cities
to see how life is adapting
to the newest habitat on Earth.
This is Planet Earth II.
There are hundreds of thousands of islands,
each one a world in miniature,
a microcosm of our living planet.
The struggles to survive
on these remote lands
reflect the challenges
faced by all life on Earth.
The tiny island of Escudo
off the coast of Panama.
Home to the pygmy three-toed sloth.
This is a male and life
here suits him well.
Mangroves provide all the leaves he can eat
and there are no predators to worry him.
Island life may seem idyllic
but it comes at a price.
There are only a few hundred
pygmy sloths in existence.
And he needs a mate.
That's an enticing call...
...from a female.
Somewhere out there.
And this, for a sloth, is a quick reaction.
The problem is, there's
deep water between them.
So what should any red-blooded sloth do?
Swim, of course.
Could this be her?
He does his best to put on a turn of speed.
But she's not the one.
She already has a baby and she
won't mate again until it leaves her
in about six months' time.
Even life on a paradise island
can have its limitations.
But at least she can't be far away.
The world's entire population
of pygmy sloths is isolated
on a speck of land no bigger
than New York's Central Park.
The size of an island has
a huge influence on the fate
of those cast away there.
The island of Komodo in Indonesia.
Home to dragons.
Ten feet long and weighing
an impressive 150 lbs,
these are the largest
living lizards on the planet.
It's unusual to find
large predators on islands.
Yet, for four million years, the
Komodo dragon has dominated here.
It might seem there wouldn't be enough food
to support such giants on
this relatively small island.
But reptiles, being cold-blooded,
need only about a tenth of the
food a carnivorous mammal would.
A single meal will last a dragon a month.
There are so successful that their
only serious competition comes from
others of their own kind.
And there are some 2,000 of them here.
This giant, however, isn't looking
for food... he's looking for a mate.
Female dragons come into
season only once a year.
She's receptive.
So far, so good.
But he's strayed into someone else's patch.
Another huge male thinks
he is the king here.
Space being limited on islands,
dragon territories overlap and
that creates continual conflict.
In dragon society, size is everything.
But if rivals are closely matched,
the outcome can be uncertain.
Muscular tails strike with
the power of sledgehammers.
And their serrated teeth
are as sharp as steak knives.
Each tries to topple his opponent.
Defeated.
Only the most powerful dragons
win the right to mate.
The limited food and space on small islands
can often lead to intense competition.
But some islands are immense.
More like miniature continents.
And these provide opportunities
for life to experiment and evolve.
Madagascar is one of the biggest
islands and also one of the oldest,
having split away from Africa
over 120 million years ago.
With time and isolation,
its animals have adapted to take
advantage of every available niche.
The island now has some
250,000 different species,
most found nowhere else on Earth.
These are not monkeys, but lemurs.
From a single ancestor, about
100 different types have evolved.
The largest, the indri, seldom
comes down from the branches.
The much smaller ringtails wander
in troops across the forest floor
searching for food.
And tiny bamboo lemurs
eat nothing except bamboo.
With few competitors, lemurs
have been free to colonise
almost every environment on the island.
Even the most extreme.
This baby sifaka has a
hard life ahead of it.
He's been born in the most
arid and hostile corner
of Madagascar's vast landscape.
If he is to survive here,
he has much to learn.
The spiny forest is like a desert.
It rarely rains, so water
and food is very hard to find.
Moving from tree to tree
is a perilous business.
Here, nearly all the plants are
covered with ferocious spines.
His mother searches the tree
tops for the youngest leaves.
They provide the only food and
water to sustain the family.
At three months old, the
youngster is starting to explore.
All too soon he will have
to fend for himself up here.
But it's altogether easier
to stay on mother's back.
If he can master the strange
ways of this forest...
...he will have a little
corner of Madagascar to himself.
Island life encourages animals
to do things differently.
And on some islands that is essential.
There are islands still forming today...
...built by volcanoes.
Some erupt explosively.
Others pour out rivers of molten rock.
Lava.
In the last 50 years,
ten new volcanic islands have been formed.
Newly created and often remote,
they're hard for colonists to reach.
Even those that do find these
are tough places to survive.
This is Fernandina, one of the
Galapagos Islands in the Pacific.
Young and still volcanically
active, it's a desolate place.
The surrounding sea, however,
is particularly rich with life.
And the frontier between these two
very different worlds is the home of
one of the strangest of reptiles.
Seagoing iguanas.
They are vegetarians,
but since there's little
food for them on the land,
marine iguanas graze on the sea floor.
A big male like this
one can dive to 30 metres
and hold his breath for half an hour.
There are more than 7,000
individuals on Fernandina alone.
And by bringing nutrients
from the sea to the land,
the iguanas help other
animals to survive here, too.
Crabs feed on dead skin
on the iguana's back
and, in turn, provide a
welcome exfoliation service.
While smaller lizards prey on
the flies that pester the colony.
But not all the relationships
on this island are so harmonious.
Marine iguanas lay their eggs in sand.
In June, when the hatchlings
emerge, they are vulnerable.
They must join the adults
at the edge of the sea.
But the journey will be a dangerous one.
Racer snakes.
The snakes miss their chance.
But more babies are hatching.
And now the snakes are on the alert.
This is the best feeding
opportunity they will get all year.
On flat ground, a baby iguana
can outrun a racer snake.
But others are waiting in ambush.
Another hatchling has its first
glimpse of a dangerous world.
A snake's eyes aren't very good,
but they can detect movement.
So if the hatchling keeps its
nerve, it may just avoid detection.
A near miraculous escape.
The lucky survivors can begin
learning the unique way of life
demanded by this hostile island.
Although marine iguanas
are expert swimmers,
they can't cross open oceans.
But even the stormiest waters
are no barrier for birds.
Gale force winds and cold
temperatures make the sub-Antarctic
islands off New Zealand
particularly unwelcoming in winter.
But, when the brief summer comes,
temperatures rise and winds slacken.
It's now that visitors arrive.
All here to breed before winter returns.
There's the Snares penguins.
Shearwaters come, too.
This is an excellent place for
them to dig their nesting burrows,
for no predators have managed to get here.
Soon the island is crowded with birds.
Every one of them eager to make the
most of the short breeding season.
But not everyone has a partner.
A male Buller's albatross
waits for his mate.
Each year they spend six months
apart, travelling the ocean.
They reunite here to breed.
But this year, she's late.
No, that's not her.
The other birds come and go.
The clock is ticking.
If she doesn't appear soon,
it could be too late for
them to breed successfully.
Every morning the shearwaters fly
off to collect food for their young.
Everybody else seems to
be getting on with it.
The shearwaters' return
marks another lost day.
There are three million birds on the
island, but only one matters to him.
Could this be her?
At last.
At first, he's a little coy.
But not for long.
They greet each other
with the special dance
they've perfected over many years.
There is much to do if they're to
raise a chick before winter returns.
But when you have been apart for six
months, some things can't be rushed.
Islands in warm tropical waters
don't experience seasonal extremes.
The Seychelles, lying off
the coast of East Africa,
provide a sanctuary for sea
birds all the year round.
Fairy terns are permanent residents.
They take a fairly relaxed view
about what constitutes a nest.
A bare branch is quite enough.
Climbing onto it to incubate
has to be done with care.
Once a year, the noddies arrive.
They do make nests,
and pisonia trees provide their young
with a rather less
precarious start in life.
Nesting on this island looks idyllic.
But behind the beauty,
there's a sinister side.
The Seychelles fody makes
quick work of an unattended egg.
She knows something's not quite right,
but her drive to incubate is strong.
The noddies too have a problem.
As their chicks grow,
so the pisonia trees
develop seeds that are sticky
and equipped with hooks.
By the time the young noddies leave,
they carry these hitchhiking
seeds away to other islands.
But sometimes the pisonia
trees are too successful.
If a fledgling, testing out
its wings, drops to the ground,
it can get covered with the seeds.
Entangled and weighed down,
if it can't free itself,
the youngster will starve.
The pisonia may have failed
to disperse these seeds...
...but it will soon have
fertiliser for its roots.
This is why some people call the
pisonia the "bird catcher tree".
The fairy tern laid another egg,
and now she has a tiny chick to feed.
This chick is lucky.
By the time it fledges, the
pisonia seeds will have dispersed,
and the danger they brought will be gone.
Even the most idyllic-looking
of islands presents challenges
for the animals living there.
But the greatest threat
they face is change.
Christmas Island in the Indian Ocean.
For millions of years,
this remote speck of land
has been ruled by crabs.
Their ancestors came from the sea,
but most have now adopted
a land-based existence.
Given there are so many of them,
they get on relatively harmoniously.
They're the gardeners and
caretakers of a tiny crab utopia.
Once a year, they must all
return to the sea to breed,
and the march of the red crabs
is one of the greatest
natural spectacles on earth.
There are 50 million of them.
It's an event that has brought
the island worldwide fame.
But in recent years,
millions of red crabs haven't
managed to reach the sea.
An invader has occupied this island.
Yellow crazy ants.
They escaped from visiting ships and
with no predators to control them,
they have now created vast
super colonies in the forest.
When migrating red crabs march into
their territory, the ants attack.
Squirting acid into the
crabs' eyes and mouths.
The crabs have no defence.
Blinded and confused...
...they're doomed.
Humans brought these ant invaders here,
and now humans are having to control them.
Isolated communities may evolve from
millions of years in relative peace.
But, when new challenges arrive,
they can struggle to cope.
Of all the species that have
become extinct in recent years,
around 80% have been islanders.
Our impact on the Earth is
greater today than ever before.
Yet some islands are so remote
that few humans have even set foot on them.
Zavodovski Island is one.
It lies in the great Southern Ocean.
It's not only surrounded
by the stormiest of seas,
it is itself an active volcano.
It's the last place on Earth
you would choose to live.
Unless you're a chinstrap penguin.
There is plenty of food in
these waters, but to exploit it,
the penguins have to risk their lives.
Life here is dangerous in the extreme.
But there are some benefits
from living on a volcano.
Its warmth melts the
snow early in the year.
And, by January, the
Antarctic's mid-summer,
the island is covered in chicks.
Parents take turns at guarding them
until they're large
enough to be left alone.
This mother's chicks are hungry, but
she has no food left to give them.
Their survival depends on their
father returning with the next meal.
But some don't make it.
Skuas harass the colony,
hoping to snatch a chick.
She can't risk leaving them.
Everything will be fine, as long
as their father comes back soon.
He's been fishing 50 miles
offshore, but now he's not far away.
For him, however, and for
all the other parents here,
the worst of the journey is still to come.
Tiny claws help him to get whatever
grip he can on the rough lava.
For these commuters, it's rush hour.
Some have had a really bad day.
The father now has a
two-mile walk to the nest,
and a stomach loaded
with food doesn't help.
This is the largest
penguin colony in the world.
But as he makes the same
journey every other day,
he should be able to do
it with his eyes closed.
It's true that there
can be safety in numbers,
but numbers can also be
something of a problem
when you're trying to find your own nest.
The mother is still waiting.
Her chicks are now desperate.
In the midst of all this deafening chorus,
he can recognise her particular cry.
At last.
Both chicks will get a meal.
With a head bob of acknowledgement,
their mother now leaves.
It's her turn to do the feeding run.
This formidable commute is the price
these penguins pay for sanctuary.
A strange vision of
paradise to us, perhaps,
but, for one and a half million
penguins, this island has it all.
Islands may seem remote and insignificant,
but they are home to some of the
most precious wildlife on Earth.
The expedition to film on
the island of Zavodovski
was the most intrepid shoot of the series.
To ensure its success,
the team have called in
Antarctic expert Jerome Poncet,
one of the few people to
have set foot on the island.
This whole region of
Antarctica is rarely visited.
And this is the planet's roughest ocean.
After seven long days and nights at sea,
they get their first glimpse
of the final destination.
It's actually quite
surreal after a whole year,
trying to put the expedition together.
And then today we wake up,
and there's the volcano.
That's Zavodovski.
The explorers who discovered this place
spoke of the stench of sulphurous gases,
treacherous waters,
and astonishing numbers of penguins.
It seems not much has changed.
Jerome's been round the whole place,
and there literally is only
one safe area to get on,
and he's telling us
it's that rock face over there.
The team must take everything
they need to survive.
There are the penguins!
Though the boat'll stay nearby,
they will need to be self-sufficient.
But that means taking a tonne
of equipment up this cliff.
Just get to that lot to help.
Many flippers make light work.
They work all day getting the gear ashore.
But the fact there are so
many penguins on the island
doesn't make it easy.
The hardest thing for us has
been finding a pathway through,
because there's absolutely
penguins everywhere you look.
Finally, it's time to make camp.
They choose a sheltered place
that won't disturb the locals.
But since most of the penguins
won't have seen a human being before,
they seem keen to pop over and visit.
Hello. Nosy neighbours.
The team set off
to start documenting the
daily lives of the penguins,
and what they find is astonishing.
As soon as you walk over that ridge,
you sort of get a tingly feeling,
because I've never seen that
many animals in one spot.
It's mind-blowing.
It's like Glastonbury Festival.
The whole landscape
is full of little black and
white penguins waddling around.
This is penguin paradise, and
that's what we're trying to show.
A promising start.
But here, fortunes can change quickly.
♪ Summertime... ♪
Every season within ten minutes.
As the snow melts, it
creates an unforeseen problem.
We purposely chose this campsite
because it was a place where
the penguins didn't seem to go.
I think we've realised why
the penguins don't nest here.
It's because of the spray
and because of some run-off,
so we are literally in a bit of a bog.
And it's not just mud.
A couple of these guys, as they
wander down to do a spot of fishing,
they tend to use my tent
as a little poop spot.
You kind of get used to it at night,
just hearing a constant
splat on top of the tent.
But, as you can see, all of the kit,
I'm afraid that's getting splat on as well.
And, when the wind changes,
it brings a noxious reminder
that they're camping on an active volcano.
It's the first time we've smelt sulphur,
which is welcome relief
from smelling penguins.
It's smoking away.
I think if they start running for the sea,
we're going to be calling
Jerome pretty quick for the boat.
Each day filming on Zavodovski
seems to present a new challenge.
Next, a huge storm hits the island.
Only now do the team realise
just how tough life
can be for the penguins.
It's hard not to be moved
by the effort they go to
to feed their chicks.
These huge waves are coming in.
The penguins are surfing here,
getting battered on these big boulders.
Now and then you just get a
penguin that gets catapulted
15 metres in the air...
it's totally ludicrous.
And really, I think there are quite
a few penguins getting killed in it.
The beach in the afternoon was just
a scene of death and destruction.
It was absolute carnage.
It was heartbreaking.
I mean, they're trying so hard to
get up the beach with broken legs
and bleeding and very,
you know, sobering, really.
After witnessing the struggles,
the penguins must endure,
the team now face the same problem.
Getting off the island.
With another storm coming in,
they decide to take their chance.
Jerome has seconds to get
in and out between the waves.
Or the Zodiac could tip...
...leaving them all stranded.
Hurray, that's the
first box off the island.
What took a day to get
ashore must be off in minutes.
And the swell is getting bigger.
Their window of opportunity is closing.
Look at this swell now,
watch out, watch out!
The equipment's off, but
now the team has to follow.
She's just leaving us now, is she?
That's the producer, she's
gone! We have to swim now.
They're gone. Yeah.
Luckily it didn't come to that.
Safely aboard, they leave with
an unforgettable experience
of how hard life is on an
island at the edge of the world.
Next time, we ascend into
the planet's highest peaks
to discover a spectacular
but hostile world,
where only the toughest animals can endure.
This is life on the roof of the world.
Mountains.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com