Freaks and Geeks S01E10 The Diary (VO)
Nice muffler!
We should definitely be getting a ride.
Right here is the best spot.
This is cool.
Hitchhiking.
It's, like, in kerouac, you know?
Kerouac?
Jack kerouac.
He wrote on the road.
Kim, we've been reading it in english class
For the last 2 weeks. where've you been?
All we ever do in that class is read.
Ooh, ooh, ooh! Stick
out your thumb, would ya?
We're so sheltered, you know?
There's this whole other america out there.
And the person who picks
us up could be an artist
Or a psychic or an escaped felon.
It's so exciting.
Ok, one thing that helps...
Point your boobs towards the road.
Redneck!
Oops...i mean...
Cool guy. come on!
Hey. Drop us as close to the corner
Of wilson and elm as you can.
Hi, i'm lindsay.
This is kim.
So, are you from around these parts?
1210 lilac terrace.
Oh.
So what do you do?
You pick up hitchhikers a lot?
Listeni know you.
I buy gear from your dad's store.
I don't think you girls
should be doin' this,
And i feel obliged to
tell him what you're up to.
This...the thumb?
Do you think i don't know what that means?
I know, lindsay.
It means, "hey, stranger,
"Please lock me in your car,
Drive me to god knows where and murder me."
Dad, you're overreacting.
Lindsay, i will not have my
daughter hopping into cars
Like some woman of the night.
You could have been picked up by ted bundy.
Dad, kim does it all the time.
Don't be so overdramatic.
What, her parents let her hitchhike?
Oh, i don't know.
I bet she doesn't even have parents.
Of course she does, dad.
Mom, you talked to her mom on the phone.
Well, maybe we should meet her.
I used to know all your friends' parents.
You know...
We should invite her over for dinner.
Get acquainted.
Yeah.
Mom, no. Please?
Yeah, well, i think she oughta know
What a bad influence her
daughter is, don't you?
All right, guys,
Let's play a little softball.
Pick your team, gents.
Oh, man, here we go.
I've got lewis.
Got humphries.
Athcliff.
Shawn! pick me.
Um, jeremy.
Pick me, pick me.
Winnington.
No...he sucks.
Mike.
I'm good. justin.
Henry.
Ok, white.
All right, divvy 'em up. Let's go.
Come on. let's go.
There is no language in our lungs
Ttell the world just how we feel
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
Bridge of thoughts
No mental link
No letting out just what you think
There is no language in our lungs
Lungs, lungs, lungs
There is no muscle in our tongues
Tongues, tongues, tongues
Hey.
Hey, nick.
How's it goin'?
It's goin'.
Great.
Yeah.
It is great.
It's never been greater.
Hey.
Hey, kim.
So...what happened with your parents?
You, like, grounded?
Oh, not exactly.
My parents wanna meet your mom.
What?
Yeah, they wanna get to know her.
Shut up.
No, i'm serious.
They're inviting her over for dinner.
Could you be quiet, please?
Class is starting.
Today...we are not in a classroom.
We are in a coffeehouse.
And you are not students.
You are beat poets.
And we're gonna be reading aloud.
Hey,
batta-batta-batta.
Swing,
Miss! Batta-
Could you be quiet, please?
Yeah, i'm really a shortstop.
Is that so?
Hey, they got a meeting on the mound.
I wonder what they're talkin' about.
Yeah...
Must be fascinating.
I hate this.
This is so unfair.
Maybe i'm good.
They don't know.
Maybe i'm unbelievably good.
But are they ever gonna find out?
Uh-uh. No.
Where i can
- 'cause they never put me in a position
Where i could catch a stupid ball.
I hate them.
Maybe they're scared of you.
Come on, ladies.
Maybe.
Hey, chuck!
Look alive out there! come on!
Let's play some ball.
Uh-huh. Wait.
All the teachers' numbers are there?
Yeah.
Ooh.
Phone.
Think we could be arrested
for making prank calls?
And we'll get sent yeah.to telephone prison.
Oh. Ha ha.
Hello?
Uh, hmm. Hello? coach fredricks?
Yes.
This is mr. Crisp.
Gordon crisp's father.
Mr. Crisp?
Uh, how are you?
Not good. I want to give
you a piece of my mind.
I think it's very unfair
The way you've been running
baseball in gym class.
You always let the jock kids run the game.
Now, some kids, like gordon my son,
Never-never get a chance
'Cause you guys think he's not very good.
For example, he may wanna play shortstop,
But, uh, yeah, you never give him a shot.
Look, i'm sorry, but, uh,
you know i always assumed
Gordon, uh, didn't have
any interest in sports.
You know what i'm sayin'?
Well, he does.
Don't judge a book by its cover.
Oh,
i-i-i, uh,
I apologize. All right?
I'll rectify the situation immediately.
Ok, then. thank you very much.
Good-bye now.
All right, bye.
Gordon crisp!
I did it.
What did he say?
He totally bought i
He called me mr. Crisp and everything.
Fellas, i just changed our lives.
Oh, great.
Now we're gonna have to
actually play baseball.
Thanks a lot.
I can't wait till tomorrow.
You have such a lovely house.
Thank you.
I had a beautiful house once.
Oh, yeah.
Up on maple drive.
Mmm.
Then kim's father left me with 2 kids,
And a huge mortgage and, well...
That's life, huh?
I can't imagine how difficult it must be
To raise children by yourself.
Ohit isn't easy.
Chip, my oldest, oh, he's a doll.
He's got water in his brain,
but, oh, he's a sweet kid.
Kim, she's another story.
Yeah, tell us about kim.
Well she ain't the
sharpest crayon in the box.
She's a big pain in the neck.
And i know she hates me for being strict...
I get worried.
Of course you do.
Becaus
E i don't know what she's doin' out there.
She lies.
These girls today, they all lie.
She says to me...
"I mm-hmm.
'M gonna go study at the library."
She goes to a party. she gets loaded.
She says she's seein' a movie...
She's foolin' around with
some guy in the back of a van.
Oh, my.
Want to know how i find out?
How?
I read her diary.
I sneak into her room, and i read it.
Oh, she won't do her homework,
But she's got a freakin' novel in there.
I have to.
It's the only way i get the truth.
And you wanna know somethin'?
The truth is very scary.
Because times have changed.
These girls today...
Oh, they run wild.
Hey.
So how was dinner?
Lindsay, your mother and i don't
want you spending any more time
With kim kelly. do you understand?
No, dad, she's my friend.
I mean, yes, she's not like millie, but-
No, she's not like millie, all right.
She's as dumb as a crayon.
Even her own mother says so.
Dad, just because kim's mother is insane-
No, she's not insane, honey,
she's practically a saint.
Lindsay, do you know what happens
When you put a rotten
banana in a fruit bowl?
All the other bananas go rotten.
And that's what a bad banana.
Mrs. Kelly had some pretty alarming
things to tell us about kim.
Like what?
That she experiments.
With drugs!
And boys!
Is that true, honey?
Enough said.
Now, no more kim kelly!
You know, maybe she needs her head shrunk.
Harold...
It's about trust, and frankly...
I don't think i trust her anymore.
Lindsay's always been very honest with us.
Yeah?
Well, she told us she didn't cheat.
And we believed her.
We ended up with egg on our faces.
Does lindsay have a diary?
Yeah. I think i've seen her writing in it.
Harold, no!
That is her private property.
I just wanna know what's going on.
I had a diary when i was little.
If my parents had read it,
i would've been furious.
It's such a violation.
Spooning with a stranger
In the back seat oa van, that's a violation!
She hasn't done that.
There's only one way to know for sure.
Good night, dear.
Good night.
Gotall right, i want crisp.
You heard him, crisp, come on.
Join your team.
You wanna play shortstop?
No. No, i like playing back-up right.
You sure?
Yeah, i like playing back-up.
I can play shortstop.
Yeah. And, uh, i'm married to raquel welch.
In my dreams.
Phillips, your pick.
All right, i'm gonna
take, uh, not haverchuck.
Heh heh. Funny.
Hey!
Hey, kim.
So my mom, like, loved your parents.
Guess it went all right.
Yeah, i guess.
What did your parents say?
Oh, they really liked your mom.
Cool. You know, i'm glad it worked out.
And they also said...
Oh, they're such dorks.
Get this.
I'm not allowed to hang out with you.
It'll blow over.
We've just got to wait
it out a while, you know?
Oh.
Well, what did they say about me?
I don't know.
No, you can tell me.
I'm interested.
He said you're a bad banana.
Aren't they queer?
Yeah, what does that mean, you know?
I don't know. I guess like a bad influence.
Well, what else did they say about me?
Tell me!
Kim, i don't know.
You're not smart, you
do drugs, you have sex...
Stupid stuff like that.
My parents are morons, kim.
Wait. You don't actually think that i care
About what your parents think of me, do you?
No. Of course not.
No.
Lindsay!
Mueves tu cula.
Uh, just a minute.
En espanol.
Lo siento senor o'hara,
Pero esta hablando con mi amiga.
Es importante.
La clase es importante, tambien.
Yo se, pero puede esterar
un momento por favor.
Kim!
Senorita, ahora.
What?
Well, i'll talk to you later, right?
Yeah. Sure.
Lindsay?
Why do you keep calling her name?
She's in school, for god's sake.
My heart is racing, harold.
I don't think we should be doing this.
Well, look, jean, we wanna find out
What's going on in our
daughter's life, don't we?
I mean, for all we know,
she could become a junkie
Or a hooker!
Harold, she is not gonna become a hooker.
Well, everybody's got parents, jean.
Even hookers.
Remember that tv movie we saw?
Shh. Hurry up.
These stamps...
I heard the kids put
lsd on the back of them.
Are you there, god? it's me, margaret.
What?
Oh, just the name of a book.
Aha! Birth control pills.
Our little daughter with a...
Sewing kit.
Harold... What?
Here it is.
You got it?
Well, come on. break it out.
Maybe we should do this later.
Now, jean, look...
My lunch hour's almost over.
The store's not gonna run itself.
Come on, let's go. shh-shh.
"Warning to all snoops! do
not read beyond this page.
"If you read on, it's because you
have no life and nothing better to do
"Than to pry into mine.
"Anyone who keeps reading on is cursed
And will suffer until they
die a slow and painful death."
Real scared. Read on!
What's it y about kim kelly?
Oh, nothing. Just that
she thinks kim has, uh...
What? well, uh, uh...
A different word for courage.
Not...oh.
Well, does it say anything about drugs?
Pot? Acid?
I don't think so.
Well, what does it say?
Oh, here, here. "i'm-i'm sick of living
In this claustrophobic suburban world..."
Oh, get used to it.
"Where everyone is trying to fit in.
"I feel like i live in
a world of scared robots.
"Honestly, this is terrible,
But 2 of the worst ones are mom and dad."
What? What does that mean?
"They are the most boring repressed people
On the face of the entire earth."
Repressed? i'll repress her.
"They say they love each
other, but who knows?
"It's probably just part of their routine.
Anyway, can robots really be in love?"
Harold, i-i don't think
we suld be reading this.
Yeah-yeah, keep reading.
Let's see...
"Their whole life is
this monotonous routine.
"She cooks dinner, practically
the same meal every night.
"He comes home barking at
everyone like a fascist dictator
Who's scared his..."
What?
"Who's scared his penis will fall off
Walk all over her.
Not the life for me.
No, thank you."
I'll get it in the other room.
The worst would be getting
eaten alive by wolves.
From the feet up.
Uh-uh. No.
It'd be worse if you were,
like, a deep-sea diver,
And you came up too quick
and your head, like, exploded.
Oh, yeah, that's worse. lot of pressure-
You know, you guys are really morbid.
Kim, you asked the question.
Yeah, but i didn't think
we'd be talking about it
For half an hour. hey, guys.
Hey.
I gotta, uh...
Go to shop class.
I sorta told ken i'd meet him there.
Yeah...you know, come to think of it...
I should probably get going, too.
'Cause i gotta go...
You know, do drugs...
Oh, yeah, and have sex.
What?
Lindsay knows what i'm talking about.
Oh...
Is this about what my parents said?
Oh! You know what, i told you, lindsay,
I don't give what your parents say about me.
Well, why are you so mad?
Well, i do give what
my friends say about me.
I didn't say anything.
Uh, you sure know how to clear a room.
Is this the best cereal you've got?
I don't know.
I never eat breakfast.
I just have my coffee.
Before or after you shave?
Don't you have any sugar cereals?
Not in this house. rots the choppers.
Hey,ad.
Oh, hey, dr. Schweiber.
Sam, bill.
Got your shoes off?
Good.
So you guys got big plans for the afternoon?
Not really.
We're gonna make some phone calls.
Ix-nay ig-bay
outh-may.
Hey-hey-hey!
I speak pig latin, too, you know.
Who you guys gonna call?
Mean people.
Oh. Prank calls, huh?
Oh, well. Boys will be boys.
I could tell you some
great prank call stories.
Really?
All right.
Just one.
We used to pick out a number,
And we'd call it over
and over and over again.
We'd keep asking for maurice, you know?
We'd call and say, "hello, is maurice there?
"Hello, is maurice there?
Hey, is maurice at home?"
You got the idea? We'd
call for maurice a lot.
We'd call back an hour later and go,
"hello. This is maurice. Any messages?"
Anyway...
Just keep it clean, all right?
No heavy breathing.
Ok. See you later, short-stuff.
Ok.
Heavy breathing. that's a good idea.
He
Y, i thought your dad worked during the day.
Mmm. Sometimes he comes
home to change his shirt.
Root canals make him sweaty.
Listen to this. this is gonna be good.
Hello?
You're a turd. a stinky, fat turd.
Go sniff a jockstrap, you poop-head.
You love patting boys' butts.
Butt
- you butt patter.
You're a perv and a loser...
And a stinky...turd.
Who was that?
It's, uh, an old friend.
Oh-ho.
Oh, you better hope he doesn't find you out.
You know, if the cops trace that...
You're so dead.
No, if the cops trace the call, you're dead.
Who does she think she is, anyway?
I don't know.
Let's talk about it for 4
more hours and try to find out.
Oh! And you should've
heard her speaking spanish.
"Un moment-un
moment. kim-kim!"
Oh, that sounds terrible.
Yeah. She thinks she's the
queen of england or something.
Hmm.
Oh, man!
You know, will you get me a stick?
I'm gonna kill that dog!
Gross.
I mean, who are they, you know?
The great weirs to call me
a whore and a drug addict?
Well, they didn't actually call
you a whore and a drug addict.
Basically, they did.
And...i'm not just some whore, you know?
They just can't take it
that i have sex, you know?
They're afraid some bad
man's gonna come along
And soil their perfect little daughter.
Well, you do have sex.
Well, yeah. with you.
Yeah, and i'm a bad man.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
I don't know.
If i had some daughter in high school,
I wouldn't want some guy
crawlin' all over her.
What the hell are you talking about?
I'm just saying it's not
like they don't have a point.
I mean, who wants their kid
to have sex and do drugs?
Nobody.
You're a jerk.
Hey, don't get mad at me.
I'm just tryin' to be rational.
Are you calling me irrational?
Because i'll tear your head off, daniel.
I'll tear it off, and i'll
throw it over that fence.
Hey.
I'm not saying i don't love you.
I like the way you are.
You probably just scare
the hell out of them.
Oh. And how am i?
You...
Are a sex-crazed drug addict.
Screw you!
Hey, come on.
I didn't mean nothin'.
I'm just tryin' to spice
up the conversation.
Sam, you getting a kickback
from the fire department?
No. Mom was the one who put
the candles on the table.
Ok. I've got something
special for us tonight.
Ta-da!
What the hell?
Uh, harold, they're cornish
game hen with a plum wine sauce.
They're fantastic.
What'd you do, put poison in a bird feeder?
They're exotic.
Is it a pigeon?
It is not a pigeon.
It's a kind of a chicken.
Jean, you know we can afford
to buy fully grown chickens.
That-a-girl,
lindsay.
It's good to try new things.
Lindsay, watch out!
That little miniature bird
of yours is trying to escape!
But don't worry!
My little chicken will help him
'Cause i'm a brave little chicken!
I'm the hero, am i not?
Yes! Is that right?
That's right.
Follow me! We will go! let's take off! Whoa!
Whoo!
Hey, mom, dad's playing with his food.
Well, it's better than eating it.
Just try it.
They're delicious.
Help yourself to mine.
I'm gonna go make a sandwich.
Yeah, me, too.
Sit down.
Harold, if you're not gonna eat,
Help clear the table.
What?
That's not my job.
Oh, but it's mine?
Yes.
You don't run a store for 12 hours a day.
All right, settle down.
Don't bother changing yet.
Oh, great. scoliosis testing again.
Shut it.
I'veot something serious to say.
I've been getting prank
phone calls at my house.
Now, i know we got a lot of jokers here,
A lot of funny guys.
Let me tell you something.
What you're doing is not funny.
It's annoying.
More importantly, it's illegal.
So i want every one of you comedians
In my office one at a time.
Let's go.
Smooth move, alexander graham bell.
Read it.
Ahem.
"You...are a turd.
A stinky turd."
"Go sniff a jockstrap, you poop-head."
"Hey, fredricks, you
love patting boys' butts.
You love patting boys' butts."
You are a dimwit...
And an imbecile.
I blow my nose in your general direction.
That's not in there.
It isn't?
"Hey, fredricks,
"You love patting boys' butts.
Butt, butt...patter."
Start it again. make it lower.
"Hey, fredricks,
You love patting boys' butts."
Ha ha ha ha!
"You're a perv...
"And a loser...
And a turd."
"Go snik a-
Go sniff..."
Sniff?
Sniff.
"A jockstrap, you poop-head."
"Youare a turd,
"A stinky turd.
Go sniff a jockstrap, you poop-head."
Jeez, coach, this is harsh.
Ha ha ha ha!
"You're a perv and a loser
And a turd."
You know what? why don't you do spock?
All right? Go ahead. do leonard nimoy.
Ahem.
Low.
Speak low.
"You're a
- you're a perv...
"And a loser...
And a...turd."
Ok. I've heard enough.
, You think you're a comedian, hmm?
Why don't you tell me a joke?
A-a joke?
Mm-hmm.
Come on. Gimme something to make me laugh.
I don't know.
Ok. A guy goes into a bar
with a pig with a wooden leg.
See, i don't stifle.
Think we share a similar sense of humor.
I didn't do it to be funny.
Yeah?
So you did it to, uh, to what?
To be educational?
It's not fair.
Ok, you don't understand.
It's not like anyone
forgets who gets picked last.
I've always been picked last.
Everyone knows. girls know.
And the thing is, i might not be bad.
I never get better because
i'm never given the chance.
But i could be good.
You know, i mean, i know i could be good.
But it's not my fault you get picked last.
Yes, it is.
I mean, you've got all the power.
You could change everything.
And how would i do that?
Simple.
Let me pick the teams.
Hey, lindsay...
I can't take it anymore.
You gotta talk to kim.
Why? Does she wanna talk to me?
I don't know,
But you gotta do something.
She's driving me nuts.
She's bitching nonstop about her mom, you,
Your parents.
I'm dying.
Why is she going so crazy?
She says you didn't stick up for her.
I tried.
She's still mad.
I know, but mostly just
her feelings are hurt.
Oh, really?
Hmm. Thought kim was too tough
to have her feelings hurt.
Yeah, right.
Kim?
She's like the rawest nerve there is.
Yeah. She's like a body without skin.
She's like a bloody-
Ok! I get it.
Can you do it soon?
'Cause she's really being a pain in my ass.
Yeah, ok.
Great. I owe you my life.
Thanks.
All right!
Haverchuck h
Ere is one of our captains today.
Shouldn't the team captain
Tually know how to play baseball?
Don't question me, people, ok?
Who's the other captain?
Gordon crisp.
Gordon crisp it is.
Come on.
Ok. Who should i pick first?
I need a power hitter who
can hustle in the field,
With a strong arm.
Gimme weir.
Come on, weir.
Yes! Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Gimme lewis.
Um...
Now, we need a little
speed around the base pads.
Uh, schweiber. come on, schweiber.
Yes!
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah!
Oh, man, the geeks have inherited the earth.
Today we are going to continue
our discussion ofon the road.
Ms. Proetzel's comments last
time about pioneer symbolism
Were particularly interesting.
Kelly, i am sure that you
have some original insights.
Tell me, what, in your opinion,
Is the theme ofon the road?
The theme... ofon the road
Is...
The theme's about...
The theme is...
America
And...
Being...
On the road.
On the roadis about being on the road.
That's good.
You...go on.
I hated the book, all right?
I have no idea what it's about,
And the writer was clearly
on drugs when he wrote it.
I mean, it went on and on and on,
Like it was written in a total hurry.
If i handed in something like this,
There's no way i'd get a good grade on it.
I mean, it's boring, and it's unorganized,
And i only read 30 pages of it anyway.
Well, that was passionate,
Albeit entirely misinformed.
Who dares follow miss
kelly's lucid analysis, hmm?
Yes.
Well, i think kim's right.
Kerouac was high on benzedrine
During the 3 weeks he
took to writeon the road.
The structure of the story isn't strong,
And his experiments with
prose style are tedious.
In fact, truman capote
said abouton the road,
"That isn't writing. it's typing."
Pearls before swine.
What the hell does that mean?
Hey, man, sure had a lot of
fun with your wife last night.
My what?
Ball 4. Take your base.
I mean, a lot of fun!
What's the matter with you? are you hurt?
Um...time!
All right, time out!
What? I told you i couldn't pitch.
It's not about your pitching, sam.
Then what are you doing out here?
I just always wanted to
call a meeting on the mound.
This is so cool.
Hey.
Meeting on the mound?
Very cool.
Listen, bill, i've got nothing left.
Why don't you just let
one of those jocks pitch?
What are you talking about?
This isourgame.
We can do this.
I don't want them to think they were right
For putting me in deep
right field for 11 years.
Come on!
He'sthe butt patter.
Ugh!
Yeah! Ha ha ha!
Tag up!
We did it! we did it!
That's the first out, you morons!
Huh? oh.
Well...
Only 82/3 more innings to go.
Yeah!
Ha ha!
You see that? i looked like willie mays!
Hey, kim, kim.
Kim!
Yeah?
Can i talk to you for a minute?
What do you want?
What are you doing right now?
Nothing.
Do you wanna come over my house?
I thought we could hang out.
Well, what about your parents?
What about them?
Daniel, i'll see you later.
I'm gonna go over to lindsay's.
Ok. Later.
God, this is good.
With him,
And i'd puke my guts out.
Swear to god.
Jean, is the grocery
store out of normal food?
Is that the problem?
This is normal food.
No. Normal food is pot roast.
Normal food is meat loaf.
It is dead animal, and it is not on fire.
No! No! No, no!
Maybe some of us are up for something
a little different around here.
Don't you wanna live life, harold?
Or maybe you've just
turned into a mean old man.
Don't you run away from me!
What's wrong with us, harold?
What's happened to us?
We need change, don't we?
Things need to change.
I don't want us to just be robots.
We are not robots,
And things do not need to change.
I like how things are.
I like eating the same things.
And you know why?
Because those are the thgs i like.
I like chicken, and i like pot roast.
And that's how i feel about you, jean.
Oh, please.
You like me like you like a pot roast?
I love pot roast!
God, you just don't get it, do you?!
I give up! I quit!
Is that right?
Yes! You don't appreciate me.
Maybe i'll go back to school.
What about that?
You think i don't appreciate you?
Well, i do.
Everything i do, i do to serve you.
I think of you when i'm...
Stocking fishing poles, and...
I think of you when i'm answering
questions about cross-country ski wax.
My whole life is about serving you.
And i love you, jean.
Thank you.
Really?
Mom, dad, we're home.
Ooh.
Is this what's for dinner?
Ugh.
Mom?
Mom? Dad?
Jean: ha ha ha! harold: grr! Grr!
Eww!
Oh, go
D. let's get outta here.
Neal!
Those are my parents!
Ok, ok.
God, you're gross.
What?
Hey, linds...
I know what you're trying to do,
But, you know, we don't have to do this.
No.
I want to.
All right, but if they call the cops on me,
I'm outta here.
Hey Lindsay !
I was catcher in gym class today.
That's great, neal.
Where's mom and dad?
In their room.
Yeah, they've been in
there for over an hour.
Are they fighting?
No.
Oh! Hi, sweetie!
Hi, mom.
Uh, i think we're gonna
order food in tonight,
So maybe you could call a pizza place
And have them deliver.
Harold: JEAN!
Hey, dad...
Kim's here.
She gave me a ride home from school.
Hi, mr. Weir.
Nice to see you, kim.
Thanks for giving lindsay a ride home.
Jean, could i have a word with you, please?
Yeah. Your father and i
are gonna be in our room,
So let us know when the food gets here.
You kids play nice now, you hear?
Oh, my god.
Lindsay...
Your parents are swingers.