Freaks and Geeks S01E18 Discos and Dragons (VO)
Come on, you guys. this is so stupid.
No, this is not stupid.
This is a tradition.
That's right.
When the heat is on, everybody knows
They're in the mood to be a hot number...
Disco sucks!
Oh...my...god.
I don't give a damn 'bout my bad reputation
Livin' in the past, it's a new generation
Go and do what you want to do
And that's what i'm gonna do
And i don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
Not me. Me, me, me, me
Whah! No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no
Not me
Me, me, me, me
I don't give a damn 'bout my bad reputation
I've never been afraid of any deviation
And i don't really care
if you think i'm strange
I ain't gonna change
And i'm never gonna care
'bout my bad reputation
Not me!
Can't wait to get the new yearbook.
I'm only gonna let girls sign it,
'Cause that way, when i have kids,
They'll think i was a big stud.
I bet we'll find out some
girls have crushes on us.
"Dear sam, i've been in love
with you since september.
True love always..."
No, they always write the same thing.
"Neal, you're a wild and crazy guy."
Never a wild and sexy guy.
Geek clean-out !
Yeah!
Hey, thank a lot guys !
Real mature!
I hate when they do this!
I mean, why do jocks think it's so funny?
They think clean-outs are funny.
They think wedgies are funny.
They think swirlies are funny.
Where do they find time to play sports?
I'm sick of being called a geek.
I mean, what's so geeky about us, anyways?
We're just guys.
Gentlemen good news.
New dungeons and dragons handbook-
Deities & demigods.
We're gonna have fun friday night.
Captioning made possible by
dreamworks television, l.l.c.
Are you guys coming to
the disco on friday night?
Why would we do that?
Well, because nick is
entering the dance contest.
Wow, really, nick?
Yeah, i guess so.
All right, uh... we better get going,
'Cause they're gonna be
reviewing for finals and stuff.
Oh, yeah, finals.
Who cares, right?
Right. Dave fleury, i hope you've studied.
Yeah.
So, are you like p
Aying dave fleury to help
you cheat, or something?
Uh, yeah, but, um, don't tell anybody.
Oh, no!
I'd never do that.
Ok, wellwe'll see you guys later. All right.
All right, see you guys later.
What in the name of god is going on?
Oh, that is so sad.
I don't know.
Sara's cool.
I'll bet he's probably
hoping that you get jealous.
Oh, hey, you guys.
Sorry about the smoke.
These things are gonna kill me.
I know i might look cool
with a cigarette in my hand,
But, remember, it's just a crutch.
Don't forget that, got it?
How's tricks?
We got cleaned out.
Jocks?
Yeah, who else?
Let me tell you something about the jocks.
Take a seat, fellas.
Watch my hand.
This is a graph of their lives.
Ooh, i'm in pee wee football!
I'm pretty good.
What? I can be first
string on a high school team
And get to wear a jacket
with leather sleeves?
Now, r hooray!
Ight there, where they cleaned you out-
That's the pinnacle of their lives.
Hey, i want to play college ball.
What? My gpas aren't high enough
to get a sports scholarship?
Ow, i just blew my knee out during practice.
Oops, i'm out of school
and selling used cars.
What? I'm fired?
Hand me that bottle of booze, man.
Now, let's take a look
at your lives, shall we?
You get called geeks,
You get cleaned out,
Girls don't even look at you.
I thought this was supposed
to make us feel better.
Hold on, cool breeze, it gets better.
What? I'm accepted at an ivy league college?
Hey, chicks dig smart guys! who knew?
Whoa, look at me. M head
of a fortune 500 company.
An yes, mr.
Jock-who-cleaned-me-out,
Iwillhave fries with that.
But, wait!
No, but that's
Like a long time from now.
We have to put up with
this for another 3 years.
That's why you have to learn to enjoy...
The simple pleasures of life.
A 16-millimeter print ofmonty
python and the holy grail?
Yep.
Guys at a.v. at
Lincoln got it on loan
from the air force base,
So i tradethem a copy
ofhemo the magnificent.
It's ours for a week.
A.v. is paradise on earth.
I'm so happy, i think i'm gonna cry.
All right, boys and girls,
come on, settle down.
It's test time.
You know the rules.
If you pass, you fly.
If you fail, you get to look at
my pretty face again next year.
Hey.
Where's dave fleury?
He's never late.
Didn't you hear?
Broke his arm in gym this morning.
He fell off the ropes and missed the mat.
It was hilarious.
Hey!
Better be a fire, bro.
Think you're pretty cool,
don't you, mr. Desario?
No, i don't think i'm cool.
Yeah?
You don't think you're
the fonz or something?
If a jukebox was broken,
Think you could hit it
and it'd start playing?
I feel like we've been here before, daniel.
I'm a nice guy.
But you know when i stop being nice?
When people take advantageand that's
of my nicewhat you've been doing.
So guess what?
I'm not gonna be nice right now.
Do you like them apples?
Ok, cool guy.
I' got a real cool way for you to
spend the rest of the school year.
You're now in a.v.
Congratulations.
I have an announcement
That is going to make someone
in this room very, very happy.
You're quitting?
No, ms. Kelly.
Every year, the university of michigan
Picks from the top 1% of
the students in the state
To take part in an academic summit,
And it seems that our very own lindsay weir
Has been selected.
What's an academic summit?
2 glorious weeks at the u. Of m. Campus,
Reading, debating,
Matching wits with the best and brightest
Students in michigan.
You'll be ranked daily.
There'll be competitions and rivalries and-
Oh, you are one lucky girl!
Well?
What do you have to say about that?
Um...
I'm one lucky girl?
See, here's thweird thing.
Ok? Usually students are happy
About being selected to
attend the academic summit.
How can i be in the top 1%?
I don't study that much.
I mean, are the
Kids in michigan schools that stupid?
No. You're justhat smart.
Maybe you'reired and broken.
Your tongue is twisted
with words half-spoken
And thoughts unclear.
What do you want me to do?
Hrough.
Why are you talking like that?
D.
I know it always makes me feel better.
Not the who. Ha ha.
The grateful dead.
When I¨was in college,
back in the 1700s,
I put their album american beautyon
whenever i was stressing out.
You know what?
Put it on while you're studying for finals,
And soon you'll be rarin' to
go to that academic summit.
I got kinda woozy
When i had to show that
girls' time of the month film.
They didn't even let me into
the class to show that one.
They said the girls
would be too embarrassed.
I heard that's because you
could see a girl's boobs in it.
All right, fellas,
Looks like our happy little a.v. family
Is about to get a new addition.
Daniel desario is going
to be joining us here
For the rest of the year.
Why?
Well, i guess he was
having a little trouble,
And mr. Rosso thought that a stay in a.v.
Might be a good attitude adjustment for him.
Wait a minute.
He's putting him in a.v. as punishment?
Speak of the devil. here he is.
Welcome to the audio-visual
department, mr. Desario.
Thank you.
Hey, daniel, how's it going?
Fine.
Hey, daniel, do you know
how to fix a projector?
No.
We can teach ya.
Great.
This is terrible.
Daniel's gonna ruin the
only place we like in school.
Yeah, why did mr. Rosso do this to us?
I bet that daniel guy is high on drugs,
And if we make him angry, he'll
freak out and wreck the a.v. room.
Oh, no! no, he won't.
He's not a bad guy.
I mean, he's friends with my sister.
I've talked to him.
Sam, he gave you a porno.
I wouldn't exactly say you have a
meaningful relationship with him.
Um, none of us really
know him that well, neal.
All i know is, what we've gotta do
Is get him tohow movies every day.
It's the only way we'll be
able to get rid of him. Agreed?
Agreed.
Lindsay, i understand
congratulations are in order.
Welcome to the 1% club.
I was one back in 1956.
Look what it did for me!
Thank you.
Ooh!
Oh, my god! i am so sorry!
That was my fault. That
was me. I'm the clumsy clod.
Hey,american beauty. that
is a great album, man.
Oh. Yeah, that's what i've heard.
Are you a deadhead?
Um...no. I-someone just
gave it to me to listen to.
Oh, well, if you never heard it
before, you're in for a treat,
'Cause it's like the best album of all time.
Really?
Is it that great?
I wish i'd never heard it,
Just so i could hear it
again for the first time.
This is such a cool vest, kenny.
Why don' kenny?
T you come over to nick's after school?
We're gonna go over some new dance moves.
I don't think so.
Uh, ken doesn't really like to dance.
Oh, well, kenny,
That's just because you don't know how.
Now, i taught nick how to do
the hustle in less than an hour.
And you know what? You'll probably
learn even faster than that,
Because you'll have both of us
teaching you at the same time.
Um...no?
Ok. Your loss.
Um, do you guys want anything?
I'm gonna go get some more milk.
No, i'm ok.
I'll be right back, baby.
I'll be here.
All right.
I give up, nick.
When does alan funt come boogieing out?
You know, that's not cool, man.
Come on. That's my girlfriend, man.
Do i need to remind you
that you used to hate disco?
Look, what's the difference
between zeppelin and disco, really?
No, listen, they both have heavy drums
And they have bass.
Have you heard that foxy song, hot number?
It rocks, man.
No! I don't know that song, thank god.
But i can guarantee it sucks.
All right, you know what sucks, man?
You suck.
No, i've been trying really hard
To get a decent girlfriend for a long time.
And now i've got one, and
you're being a real jerk.
Nick, you are only going out with sara
To make lindsay jealous,
And it isn't working.
Admit it.
You know what? screw you, man.
Thanks for the support.
What's that all about?
Lindsay, can you please
Start going out with nick again?
I can't take much more of this.
Look out of any window
Any morning, any evening
Any day
Maybe the sun is shining
Or rain is falling from a heavy sky
What do you want me to do?
To do for you to see you through?
For this is all a dream we dreamed
One afternoon long ago
Our daughter in the top 1%.
Like my grandpa used to say,
If i was wearing my vest,
all the buttons would pop.
Here i didn't think you
were applying yourself,
And now look.
You must be absolutely thrilled.
Yeah, i don't know.
I mean, i'm not even sure if i want to go.
What's the point?
Wacky?
Can it!
You're going to that summit, lindsay.
This isn't even open for debate.
Dad, i didn't say i wasn't gonna go.
Ju sounds kinda...dumb.
Dumb?
Spend 2 weeks with the
intellectual elite of your peers?
Oh, yeah, that sounds pretty dumb.
Honey, think of all the people you'll meet.
Yeah, mom, i know.
It's just-
Haro
It's just nothing !
This is your key
To the best schools in the world...
Harvar yale, princeton.
Don't blow this, lindsay.
Dad, i didn't say i wasn't gonna go.
Can' god.
T we have a normal
discussion about something?
When it comes to something like this...no.
Well, everyone,
Last week of school can only mean one thing,
And that's that today is movie day.
But just so that we don't
completely waste time,
We'll be watching
The 1968 franco zeffirelli
version ofromeo and juliet.
If one of our astute
members of the a.v. squad
Would get his butt in here,
We'd be able to get this show on the road.
Hi, i'm here to show your movie.
I'm glad you could make it.
I was starting to think i'd
have to act out the film myself.
Oh.
Where was i?
Yes. This version of...
Geek!
Ah! Uh...
This version ofromeo and juliet
Is unique in that it is
the first time that a film
Had chosen to let teenage actors play-
Do you need a hand, sir?
No, i think i got it.
In the version before mr.
Zeffirelli's masterpiece,
The role were played by actor in their 30s,
Which caused it to have an artificial feel.
Will somebody please help mr.
demille set up the projector?
All right, i got it.
Any chance of being
ready in the near future?
Yeah, just one second, all right?
Ok.
Ready.
Ready. Saints be praised.
Instead of hitting it, could you please
Just make the film loop a little bigger?
What?
Make the film loop bigger.
Thanks.
So you guys just drive around
And follow the dead everywhere?
Yeah, it's great.
You meet a lot of really cool people.
Well, are the concerts that different?
Yeah, it's like nothing
you've ever experienced.
This one time, we were in new jersey,
And it started raining
Right in the middle of the show.
Suddenly everybody goes
running down to the pit,
And they start dancing in the mud.
And then the sun comes out,
And there's this rainbow
Right over the stage.
I started crying.
It was beautiful.
Really what it's all about
Is being together and
having a good time, as one.
Judging has nothing to do with it.
That's not what the dead are about.
It's all about being
connected and being free.
Nothing-nothing is better, i'm telling you.
Yeah, it sounds wild.
We're going down to texas when school's out.
We're gonna follow the tour up to colorado.
9 shows in a week and a half.
I can't wait.
Wow.
So, what are you gonna do this summer?
Oh, i got into this academic summit thing
It's kinda goofy.
Hey, man, you gotta do what you gotta do.
Man, i can't believe i have
to go to a.v. again today.
It's so stupid.
Well, you know, daniel,
Nobody asked you to pull the fire alarm.
Oh, what was i supposed
to do, flunk the test?
I suck at math.
I suck at everything.
Well...
What do you want me to say, daniel?
I don't know, kim.
You know, i am always listening
to your stupid problems.
You know what, daniel?
Why don't you go tell it to the fire alarm?
Thanks!
Guys, i want my new dungeons
and dragons character
To be called gorthon.
Why gorthon?
'Cause it sounds cool.
I'm gorthon the thief.
Surrender your jewels, princess!
Oh, bill, don't be a thief again!
You always fall down a
well trying to steal stuff.
Uh, sorry, kragenmore the destroyer.
So, sam, will logan the
huge be making an appearance?
I told you, i don't want to play.
What, you're too cool for us
now that you broke up with cindy?
No.
I don't know.
It's just
- it's a geeky game.
I mean, what's the point?
The
Point is, you used to like it.
I left my science book in the a.v. room.
See you guys later.
See you later.
Hey!
Hey.
What's eating you?
Huh? Nothing.
I just wish i didn't get
into that academic summit.
Just feels like i'm going
back into school again.
Life's tough.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means you've been moping around
Ever since you found out you
got into that stupid thing.
At least you get to get out of this town
For a little while.
Kim, it's summer vacation.
You can go out of town, too.
You can go anywhere you want.
No, i can't, lindsay.
I don't have any money.
And besides, daniel never
wants to go anywhere, anyway.
So?
Go without him.
You don't have to stay here.
You know that, kim.
That's easy for you to say, lindsay,
'Cause you get to leave.
I don't.
Come on, nick, you promised me.
I know. I'm just kinda freaked out about it.
I'm not that good at contests.
Nick, you are a great dancer.
Ok? You're really, really good.
And i swear, i'm not just saying that.
Thanks.
It's weird. i used to hate disco.
But i guess maybe...
I was just destined for it.
Yeah!
Totally.
Sometimes you end up being the best
At something you hate.
Mm-hmm.
She hate like lindsay.
S math, but she's the head of the mathletes.
Nick, do you still like lindsay?
No, no.
I mean, i still care about her.
Look, i really like you, sara.
I've had a crush on you
since the sixth grade.
Really?
I always sat behind you,
Even though you were so tall
i couldn't see the board.
Wow.
I just-i can't believe that you like me.
Oh...
Tonight's d&d campaign
is gonna be the best ever.
Ancient babylonia.
Have you guys seen the
drawing of the goddess ishtar?
Hubba hubba!
You should look at the goddess of vice.
I just h you can see her butt.
Ope you guys are ready
to face the dancing sword.
Bring it on !
What's a dancing sword?
Well, it like-
It's a sword that can fight
without you holding it.
What, you just send your
sword into battle for you,
And then you stay home?
That's kind of stupid.
No, no, you have to be
at least 3 inches away
From it when it's fighting.
That way you can fight 2 people at once.
That's kinda cool.
Hey, daniel.
We're playing d&d tonight. you wanna come?
Why?
I think you'd like it. We
could show you how to play.
I couldn't do that.
Yeah, you wouldn't like it,
anyway. It's really boring.
No. No, it isn't, neal.
You love it.
We sit around and crack jokes
And eat junk food all night while we're...
Fighting dragons and
saving princesses and stuff.
It's pretty fun.
You get and the best part is,
To pretend to be somebody
you can't be in real life.
Ok, i'll play.
Really?
Yeah, i'll play.
Just...don't expect me to
be good at it or anything.
You can't possibly be any worse than bill.
Hey!
So, sam, how about you? Are you in?
Yeah, i guess.
Thought you were too cool to play...
Logan the huge.
Ken, no. we shouldn't be here.
Just let nick do what he wants.
I can't do that. The poor guy's brainwashed.
I can't let him dance
in this stupid contest.
It goes against everything
that we stand for.
Well, i'm not gonna stop him.
Just talk to him!
At least tell him that he
doesn't have a chance with you
So he'll break up with sara!
No, it's not gonna work.
Look! Kenny and lindsay
came to cheer you on!
That is so cool! hey, guys!
Hey, nick. Lindsay has something
She wants to tell you.
No, i don't.
Yes, you do!
Ken, stop it!
Oh, check it out, kids.
It's our little opinionated
rock 'n' roller friend.
Who the hell's he talkin' about?
I think he's talking about you.
Uh...so what do i do?
First you have to create a character.
Roll your dice and find out
what your ability scores are.
What are those?
Oh, well, that tells you
if you're strong or smart
Or how good you are with a weapon.
What are you, some... super-smart guy?
I don't have a character.
I'm the dungeon master. i control the game
And act out all the characters
you'll meet along the way.
And, daniel, watch out for him.
He's sneaky.
Yeah, yeah, he thinks
Being a dungeon master gives him
a license to mess with our heads.
Oh, i'm sorry. Perhaps i should let you
Encounter kittens and grandmas
So as not to upset you.
Come on, daniel, roll the dice.
I wanna see what your character's gonna be.
All right.
Here goes nothin'.
Hey, man, aren't you one of those guys
Who's always yellin' in here
That disco sucks?
What's the matter?
Cat got your bong, man?
Is that how you learned to communicate,
Runnin' in here, yellin' stuff?
Is that what your precious
rock teachers you, friend?
Um...no, man.
It teaches me that...
Disco sucks!
Ken, don't, all right?
I say that rock 'n' roll sucks, ok?
Hey, have you heard the
stones' new song, miss you?
Well, guess what? it's disco, man.
Even the stones know it.
They're willing to admit it. why can't you?
This place is empty, man!
Disco is dead. give it up!
Why don't you go back
To sellin'shirts at the mall there, buddy?
All right, pal. Let's go.
Great. thanks a lot, man.
Disco is alive! it's alive, i tell you!
I know it... and you know it...
And miss gloria gaynor knows it, too!
At first i was afraid
I was petrified
Kept thinkin' i could never live without you
By my side...
Where the hell is daniel when you need him?
A dwarf? i don't wanna be a dwarf.
I wanted to be, like, a ninja or a fighter.
Well, dwarfs are fighters.
They're really good at it.
Are you a dwarf?
No. I'm kragenmore the destroyer.
You're lucky, man. i want to be
Some huge destroyer guy.
Dwarfs can do a lot of things
that huge guys can't do.
It's true. take it from me.
Yeah, dwarfs are really tough.
They're good at finding jewels.
All right, fine. i'll be a dwarf.
But my name is carlos.
Carlos the dwarf?
Yeah, you got a problem with that, gorthon?
No.
Thanks a lot, man. Thanks
for embarrassing me in there.
I gotta go dance in
front of those people now!
Best of luck, man. i mean it!
Give me a call when you get
over your saturday night fever.
And you're too tall to be a good dancer!
Hey, i agree with you, man.
That place sucks.
And you're right. They're
closin' the disco next week
And bringin' in foxy boxin'.
You should come back and check it out.
Rock 'n' roll!
What is wrong with that guy? Why does he
Have to give me such a hard time about this?
Ken's just confused. He's thinks
you're doing all this stuff
To...i don't know, to get me back.
Well, that's not true.
That's what i told him, but
he doesn't want to listen.
I mean, i'm with sara now.
You know?
I'm not some idiot. You told me to move on.
And so i did.
Yeah!
I know.
I think it's great.
Well, it is great. I mean,
sara's the best, you know?
She opened me up to all sorts of new things,
And she loves me.
I mean, that's important.
It is.
I'm really happy for you, nick.
Well, you should be, you know?
I even quit smoking pot.
Yeah. I don't even really want it anymore.
It's like i totally cleaned myself up.
Wow!
Really?
Mm-hmm.
God,
That's-i knew there
was something different.
That's so great.
You seem like you're having
Way more fun with her
than you ever did with me.
Yeah.
I mean, i am.
Tta get going.
I have a lot of studying to
do for that academic summit.
I should probably start studying for finals.
Oh, yeah. i should do that, too.
First i gotta win this dance contest.
Hey, good luck.
Thanks.
Ok, all right, everybody.
We're gonna shake our groove things
Tonight here at frontier lanes.
It's time for the big disco contest,
And let's bring up our first
contestant of the night-
That's mr. Nick andopolis!
Andopolis.
Nick.
Nicky.
Nick! Come on, baby, it's your turn.
Time to boogie oogie oogie.
Pack your grip
Takin' you on a trip
Ain't no seats
All we got's hands and feet
Leave your worries behind
Come rain or shine
Don't mind
We're ridin' on the groove line
Whoo-hoo! tonight
Hoo hoo
Get the strength
Know you'll be glad you came
Hit the track
Party hard there and back
Leave your worries behind
Come rain or shine
Don't mind
We're ridin' on the groove line
Tonight
Hoo hoo
Check out the wheels are burnin'
Ooh whee ooh
Ya know we don't stop
We got the boiler burnin'
Ooh whee ooh
We're keepin' it hot
So grab your friends
Get to say comin' through
Climb on board
Where you leave up to you
Leave your worries behi
Come rain or shine
I love you, nick!
We're ridin' on the groove line
Tonight
Hoo hoo
O-ok, all right, mr. Andopolis.
It's time to clear the floor
for the next contestant.
Yes! hoo hoo
Nick, you were so great!
Oh, my god, you are gonna win for sure.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like you to all put your hands together
For the magical disco stylings of...
Eugene.
Hoo hoo
Check out the wheels are burnin'
Ooh whee ooh
You know we won't stop
We got the boiler burnin'
Ooh whoo ooh
We're keepin' it hot
So grab your friends
What the heck? They didn't say
that you were allowed to do magic!
Where you leave's up to you
Leave your worries behind
Come rain or shine
Wow. He's really good.
We're ridin' on the groove line
Tonight
Hoo hoo
Come rain or shine
Don't mind
We're ridin' on the groove line
Tonight...
Greetings, princess.
It is i, carlos the dwarf.
The dragon has been slain,
And you're free to rule your kingdom.
Congratulations, daniel.
You just finished your first
dungeons and dragons campaign.
Whoo!
All right!
Thanks, guys.
Hey...this is really fun.
You guys wanna do this tomorrow night?
Yeah. sure.
I would,
But harris killed me again.
You had it coming, bill.
Well, kick his ass tomorrow night, bill.
Just leave it to carlos.
Yeah.
M gonna get another drink.
you guys want anything?
No.
Gordon, bill? all right.
Wow, he's cool.
Yeah.
Does...him wanting to play with us again
Mean that he's... turning into a geek...
Or we're turning into cool guys?
I don't know.
But i'm gonna go for us being cool guys.
Yeah, i'll buy that.
Yeah. Definitely cool guys.
Cool.
Oh, are you sure you don't want us
To drive you to u. Of m.?
We don't mind.
No, mom, it's ok. I'd kinda like to do this,
You know, get my head
straight before i get there.
Ok. I understand. oh!
We are so proud of you!
You're going to have yourself a great time.
Yeah, you go and make the weirs proud.
Be smarter than all ose other kids.
Dad! harold...
Have a nice time, lindsay.
I'm gonna miss you.
Thanks, sam.
Come on. I'm only going
for a couple of weeks.
You won't even know i'm gone.
Yeah, i guess so.
See you.
Bye, dad.
No, no, no! Lindsay,
lindsay, wait, wait, wait!
Hi. I got something for you.
It's chocolates for a sweet trip.
Yeah, we always give my grandma chocolates
When we put her on the bus.
That, and we pin her name
and address on her jacket
In case she gets lost.
Thanks, neal.
It's nice.
Bye, bill.
Hey, he didn't get you anything!
Oh. That's just for comin' down.
It didn't cost me a cent.
All right, i'll see you.
Ok, honey, we'll see you. Bye, lindsay.
Hey, mom.
Yes, sweetie?
I'll see you soon.
Ok, honey.
Ok. Love you.
I miss you already!
If my words did glow
With the cold warm of sunshine
And my tunes were played
On the farm on the strum
Would you hear my voice
Come through the music?
Would you hold it near
As it grew year-round?
It's a hand me down
But thoughts are broken
Perhaps
They're better
Left unsung
I don't know
Don't really care
Let there be songs
To fill the air
Ripples in
Still water
When there is no apple toss
Nor wind to blow
Reach out your hand
If your cup be empty
If your cup is full
May it be again
Let it be known
There is a fountain
That was not made
By the hands of men