04 Firefly Safe - Episode 04 2002 English
We're in trouble.
We got cut off.
- Cut off from what?
- Our platoon, Simon.
We got out playing for
the independent Squad...
and we won't make it
back to our platoon.
We need to resort to cannibalism.
That was fast.
Don't we have rations or anything?
They got lost.
We're gonna have to eat the men.
Aren't you supposed to practise
for your recital?
I learned it all.
- That's wrong.
- It's from the book, River.
No. The book is wrong.
His whole conclusion is fallacious.
So how did the Independents cut us off?
They were using dinosaurs.
Language, young man.
Sorry, Dad. The Independents
attacked us with dinosaurs.
Simon lost his head in the heat of battle.
Because there were dinosaurs involved,
I think we'll let it slide.
- Did you get my wave?
- I got it. Your text shorted.
I got it during a board meeting.
Thank you.
If I had a dedicated source box,
it wouldn't short. I lost half my essay.
Yes, and you'd have access to any tien
sha duh that filtered in from the cortex.
I absolutely forbid it.
- Dad.
I will not have it in my house.
But since your mother's
ordered you one...
I should give up the fantasy
this is my house.
Are you kidding?
You will repay me by becoming
a brilliant doctor. That's the deal.
Dedicated source box,
brilliant doctor.
- When do I...?
- Many years.
Dad, this is so...
- It's really gonna...
- I know.
You think I'd let you work
with something second-rate?
- Thank you.
- You're worth it.
Is it possible for you two geniuses
to give your tired old dad...
a couple minutes quiet?
No! No, I don't want to go in!
- It's okay.
- It's not okay.
You can't dig into me, shove 20 needles
in my eyes and ask me what I see!
I... We won't go in. Look.
- No test today.
- No rutting tests?
Stupid son of a bitch dressed me
up like a gorram doll.
No tests, no shots.
Come on. I'm just gonna give you
a smoother cuttle.
River!
Not him.
So she's added cussing and hurling
about things to her repertoire.
- She really is a prodigy.
- It's just a bad day.
No. A bad day is when someone's
yelling spooks the cattle.
Understand? Ever see cattle stampede
when they got no place to run?
It's kind of like a meat grinder.
- And it'd lose us half our herd.
- She hasn't gone near the cattle.
No. But in case you hadn't noticed,
her voice kind of carries.
We're two miles above ground and
they can probably hear her down there.
As soon as we unload,
she can holler until our ears bleed...
although I would take it
as a kindness if she didn't.
The human body can be drained
of blood in 8.6 seconds...
given adequate vacuum systems.
See, morbid and creepifying,
I got no problem with.
Long as she does it quiet-like.
This is paranoid schizophrenia, captain,
hand crafted by government scientists...
who thought my sister's brain
was a rutting playground.
I have no idea what will set her off.
- If you have some expertise...
- I'm not the doctor.
And I'm not your gorram
babysitter either.
Gag her if you have to.
Got trade to be done.
You see that?
Fancy vessels such as that don't land
here unless they got something to sell.
If it happens to be something
we need, we take it.
It's about time
you broke in them pretty shoes.
Get along!
You know, they walk
just as easy if you lead them.
I like smacking them.
Hope this corral's strong enough
to hold them.
Shepherd's a purely
figurative title, you know.
Next time we smuggle stock,
let's make it something smaller.
Yeah, we should start dealing
in those black market Beagles.
Little soul, big world.
Eat, sleep and eat.
Many souls.
Cattle on the ship three weeks,
she don't go near them.
Now we're on Jiangyin and she needs
to communicate with the beasts?
They weren't cows inside.
They were waiting to be,
but they forgot.
Now they see sky and they remember
what they are.
Is it bad that what she said
made perfect sense to me?
Come on now, let's get
you clear of the work.
What's going on?
- What are you doing?
- I'm fixing to do business.
I can't be herding steers
and your sister.
- She didn't mean any harm.
- I never figured she did.
But when a man engages
in clandestine dealings...
he has this preference
for things being smooth.
- She makes things not be smooth.
- Right.
I'm very sorry
if she tipped off anyone...
about your cunningly
concealed herd of cows.
I'm starting to think you've got
too much time on your hands.
I've got a notion regarding that.
Why don't you take your sister
for a little walk?
- A walk?
- Yeah. Some place away.
Well, probably best we stay close.
Alliance has us marked as fugitives.
Closest Alliance is the cruiser
Magellan, hours from here...
and I promise they ain't
coming to Jiangyin.
Still, I'm not sure
it's such a wise suggestion.
I wouldn't mistake it for a suggestion.
Don't worry.
We won't leave without you.
Does it seem every supply store
on every water planet...
has the same five rag dolls
and the same woodcarvings of...
What is this, a duck?
That's a swan.
- I like it.
- You do?
Looks like it was made with,
you know, longing.
Made by a person who really
longed to see a swan.
Perhaps because they'd only heard
of them by rough description.
Do you think this did make a nice gift?
A gift? For whom?
I just kinda like it.
It's rich, you know.
Oh. For Simon.
I didn't say that.
You don't do a very good job
of hiding your interest.
He's just so...
You just wanna take a bite
out of him all over, you know?
Careful.
Morning, you two.
Don't usually see you two out
and about planet-side.
Yeah, we're trying something
different today.
River...
Be careful with that. That's...
- What is that?
- That's a post-holer.
You dig holes.
For posts.
It's, it's dirty and sharp.
Let's come over here.
Jiangyin Prairie Paradise.
Good God. They're asking
money for this crap?
Hard to believe, ain't it?
Glad you're out.
Give you a chance to have a little fun.
Fun. Right.
I consider this fun.
It's fun being forced to the ass end
of the galaxy...
to get to live on a
piece of los soh ret.
And eat moulded protein.
And be bullied around by our
pien dyododo chowren of a captain.
It's fun.
Los soh?
Sorry?
Serenity ain't los soh.
- No, I didn't mean...
- Yeah, you did.
You meant everything you just said.
Well, no.
Actually I was being ironic.
So in the strictest sense...
You were being mean is what.
And if that's what you
think of this life...
then you can't think much
of them that choose it, can you?
River?
This is the last time,
last time with cows.
There's an idea with Beagles.
They have smallish droppings.
I believe so, sir.
Also, your disreputable men are here.
Better go take their money.
Morning, gentlemen.
Must be the Grange brothers.
Hope you're in the mood for beefsteak.
Attractive animals, ain't they?
They ain't well-fed. Scrawny.
Hey, wah. Milk and hay,
three times a day.
- Fed to them by beautiful women.
- That was something to see.
They's branded.
You are hitting on the selling points.
The first brand's a giveaway.
Claim them as your own.
Twenty a head.
That's an amusing figure, since
you agreed on 30 with Badger.
That's before we saw them.
They're atrophied from being
on a ship for a month.
My comprehension is less muscle,
the more tender the meat. Thirty.
- Problem?
- No.
About a minute from now,
we'll agree on 25.
Seem a mite jumpy to you?
Morning, officers.
I'm thinking maybe
we walk away entirely.
I'm thinking you do that,
and we got ourselves trouble.
Morning, ladies.
Serious trouble,
of the you-owe-us variety.
I can go to 25.
Well, we'll be taking a loss, but you
seem like clean and virtuous boys. Done.
Marcus and Nathaniel Grange,
you are wanted in connection...
to the illegal killing of Rance Durbin.
You are bound by law to stand down.
You know, I'm starting to find
this whole planet very uninviting.
Yeah.
- Careful with that!
- Seems we have ourselves a situation.
Who are you?
Just a bystander.
- This your beef?
- No, sir.
You're looking at the proper
owners right there.
I'd like to see some paper on that cattle.
Come on, hurry it up!
- Here we go.
- Never goes smooth.
How come it never goes smooth?
Hey, stay with me, Shepherd.
That's...
That's quite a lot of blood, isn't it?
It just means you ain't dead.
Afraid I might be needing a preacher.
That's good. You lie there
and be ironical. Stretcher!
- Jayne!
- They going.
Of course.
They got what they wanted.
You get the cash?
What's going on?
Oh, God! Shepherd!
Shepherd, can you hear me?
Doing good.
Wash, get down to the infirmary.
Gotta try to stop this bleeding.
Don't you worry, Shepherd.
Captain and Zoe got lots of experience
with this kind of thing.
Seen a lot worse in the war.
Shepherd?
Oh, God. He ain't breathing.
He ain't dead.
But he is bad off. We got to see
what we can do to help him.
Wash, go to town. See if you can't find
that Jin seem yong, the doctor.
Hurry.
Faster. Got to go faster.
- Won't get there before dark.
- Get where? Where are we going?
Shut up!
If it's ransom you want,
I can arrange something.
No talking!
Look, you don't understand.
My sister...
Your sister is fine, Simon.
She's not fine.
Didn't you look at the letters?
Look at the letters.
Well, I'm looking at letters.
These phrases, they don't sound
anything like her.
Some of these words,
they're misspelled.
She started correcting my spelling
when she was 3.
She's trying to tell us something.
I think there's a code.
- A code?
- Yes.
I always thought it was River
who was lost without you.
Now I'm beginning to wonder
if it isn't the other way around.
Did you have a good time at the
Darbanvilles' Ball this year?
What are you...?
River thought it was duller
than last year.
But since we don't know anybody
named Darbanville, I can't judge.
- Did you read these?
- Well, of course I did.
It's one of her silly games.
You two are always playing.
She is trying to tell us something
that somebody doesn't want her to say.
Simon, this is paranoid.
It's stress.
If they heard you talking like this
at the hospital...
it could affect your entire future.
- Who cares about my future?
- You should.
You're a surgeon in one of the best
hospitals in Capitol City.
On your way to a major position,
possibly even the Medical Elect.
You're gonna throw all that away?
Everything you've worked
for your whole life?
Being a doctor means more to you
than just a position, I know that.
A few months' time,
you'll turn around and there she'll be.
Nothing is going to keep
you two apart for long.
No! Oh, no!
- Found you.
- Get him!
River, no! River! Run! Run!
- Found you!
- Go!
Bring her.
Where is the doctor?
Why isn't he with you?
- He wasn't in town or anywhere.
- He was in town. We saw him there.
- Him and River. I can show you...
- The town's not that big, Kaylee.
Believe me, he wasn't there.
Knew it. Probably saw
them cops, turned tail.
The doctor could be called
a lot of things but not coward.
Do you think they were arrested?
Worse than that, probably.
- Looks like maybe they got snatched.
- Kidnapped?
I went by the sheriff's. If we'd checked
the posted alerts we might have known.
Settlers up in the hills
take people sometimes.
Usually tradesmen and the like.
And now they got themselves a doctor,
and we don't.
We're going.
Well, what are you doing?
What about Simon and River?
Forget them.
We already lost two people today.
If I can help it, we won't lose a third.
Wash, get us in the air.
We're lost.
- Lost in the woods.
- It's gonna be okay. They'll find us.
Once the captain realises
what happened, they'll come.
See there? No one's coming for you.
You just keep moving.
That bad?
Battle wounds are nothing
new to me, preacher.
I've seen men live with
a dozen holes in them this size.
- That right?
- Surely is.
I knew a man who had a hole clean
through his shoulder once.
Used to keep a spare hankie in there.
Where's the doctor? Not back yet?
We don't make him hurry
for the little stuff.
He'll be along.
You could hurry a little.
Well, there's Greenleaf.
They'd have med help there.
Too far. More than 10 hours.
- He's worse off than that.
- You know where to find what you need.
- Don't recall inviting you here.
- You didn't.
You know where you can
find a doctor.
He was dumb enough to get himself
grabbed in broad daylight.
Don't have time
to be looking for him now.
No assurance we'd find him
or that he wouldn't need a doctor.
I'm not talking about Simon.
I'm talking about medical facilities.
That's not an option, nor is it
a discussion I want to have right now.
It doesn't matter what you want.
He's dying.
We need a doctor now.
Look what we got!
Got ourselves a doctor!
A real doctor.
Stand up straight.
They brought home
a doctor. Thank the Lord.
Dear Diary, today I was pompous
and my sister was crazy.
Today we were kidnapped by hill folk,
never to be seen again.
It was the best day ever.
Now we're talking.
Amazing we kept them this long.
- Can I?
- Sure.
He's out, though.
He did this for me once.
How's he doing?
I cleaned it out, wrapped it up.
Best I could do.
I don't know.
Well, we're headed for help, right?
- Captain will come up with a plan.
- Well, that's good. Right?
You're not recalling
some of his previous plans.
We left them back there.
Yeah.
Don't seem right.
- You sure this is where you wanna be?
- Oh, I'm fairly certain it ain't.
Be sure to ask nicely.
Alliance cruiser Magellan
this is Firefly transport Serenity...
requesting permission for docking.
Firefly transport Serenity,
stand by for docking orders.
In here.
I don't figure it's as fancy as you're
used to, but that's what we got.
I got you a doctor.
Praise the Lord.
Doralee here will show you what's what.
- What's your name?
- Simon.
Hello there. Who are you?
This is River.
River, just sit down over there.
Has there been a...?
Is there a sickness here?
Nothing special.
Just people get sick or injured.
Though mostly people heal
on their own, but sometimes...
Sometimes you need a doctor.
Bring me light,
and any supplies you have.
You sanguine about the reception we're
apt to receive on an Alliance ship?
Absolutely.
- What's sanguine mean?
- Sanguine, hopeful.
Plus, point of interest,
it also means bloody.
That pretty much covers
all the options, don't it?
We're requesting aid.
No other purpose.
We got papers.
- What's your business?
- We're a supply ship, freelance.
Had an accident this morning,
crewman got hurt.
We need medical help.
Faster be better than slow.
Official seal's out of date,
Captain Harbatkin?
We ain't had a checkpoint in a while.
You gonna see to my man?
How did this happen?
Bystander in a gunfight.
Back on Jiangyin.
You can check. Not he nor
any of ours were the aggressors.
We aren't an emergency facility.
Our services aren't for just anyone.
Get... Med...
My ident card.
Get this man to the infirmary at once.
You keep that bandage clean now,
you understand?
She's not quite right, is she?
She's been through some trauma.
She's recovering though.
She won't get a good conversation
out of Ruby. I can tell you that much.
That little girl's mute.
Do you know the cause?
- Was she born deaf?
- No.
She was fine until two years ago
when she stopped talking.
A place like this might be good
for your sister.
Quiet, safe.
A place where folks
take care of each other.
Yes. Seems like a lovely little
community of kidnappers.
The Lord says judge not.
They took us off the street.
Sometimes life takes you places
you weren't expecting to go.
Life didn't bring us here.
Those men did.
You were on a transport ship, right?
Taking a journey?
The way of life in my findings is, journeys
end where and when they want to...
and that's where
you make your home.
This isn't our home.
If it isn't here, where is it?
This place gives me
an uncomfortableness.
So, what do you figure?
Shepherd's got some kind
of connection with the Alliance?
That's what it looks like.
It would surprise me if he did.
See? That's my whole problem
with picking up tourists.
Ain't never what they claim.
Does seem like everyone's
got a tale to tell.
River?
- What's wrong?
- River's gone. So's the girl.
Ruby. I'll check out back.
River. Don't...
What is that?
Oh.
I picked them.
Here. They'll stain your dress.
You have to eat.
Hodgeberries.
Remember when we found those giant
Hodgeberry bushes...
on the Cambersons' estate?
And we thought they'd
grown wild, but...
A long while ago.
- I took you away from there.
- No.
I know I did.
You don't think I do, but...
I get confused.
I remember everything.
I remember too much.
And some of it's made-up.
And some of it can't be quantified.
And there's secrets, and...
It's okay.
But I understand.
You gave up everything
you had to find me.
You found me broken.
It's hard for you.
You gave up everything you had.
Maybe everything I have is right here.
You need to eat.
Keep up your strength.
We won't be here long.
Daddy will come and take us home.
And I'll get better.
I'll get better.
These are better than
the Cambersons' berries.
They are. Except they're poison.
You believed her. Made a face.
You are such a brat.
You get to bed now.
We should probably think
about doing the same.
It's been a big day, what
with the abduction and all.
Well, y'all don't have to sleep here.
There's a house set aside for you.
We've been looking for a doctor
for a good while, so things are ready.
Really?
Her sister got killed.
Mother got crazy, killed the sister.
That one lived.
Ruby talked to you, honey?
It's true what she's saying.
Poor woman went out of her mind,
tried to kill her two girls.
Ruby lived.
Sweetheart, you are an angel.
No one's been able to get
Ruby to speak even a peep.
It's a miracle! That's what it is.
Ruby doesn't talk.
Her voice got scared away.
I hear crickets.
I don't understand.
If Ruby didn't talk,
how do you know...?
My sister's...
She's very good at...
What's wrong?
And they shall be among the people.
And they shall speak truths
and whisper secrets.
And you will know them by their crafts.
What are you talking about?
Thou shalt not suffer a witch to live.
Have you completely lost your mind?
- Nearly.
- We got the wave at the Friedlichs.
I had to leave your mother
at the dinner table.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I never would have tried to save
River if I had known...
there was a party at risk.
Don't you dare be flippant with me.
I just spent 2000 credits
to get you out of here.
I had to walk through that door,
which goes on my permanent profile.
- Are you trying to destroy this family?
- I didn't realise it would be so easy.
- Dad, I didn't do anything.
- You were in a blackout zone.
Talking to someone who
might be able to help River.
And I'm going right back there.
This is a slippery slope, young man.
You have no idea how far down you
can go. You're not taking us with you.
Meaning what?
I won't come for you again.
You end up here or get mixed up in
something worse, you're on your own.
I will not come for you.
Now are you coming home?
This is lunacy! You're supposed
to be the teacher here.
What exactly is it you teach?
What's going on, woman?
Why are you knocking us from our beds?
The new doctor's sister's a witch!
She read Ruby's mind.
- Saw things she couldn't.
- No, River is not a witch.
She's just a troubled girl.
I'm sure that's true.
You're not a witch, are you...?
I'm the patron here.
Do you know what that means?
Yes. You're in charge.
Ever since the old patron died.
That's right.
He was sick and he was getting better.
And you were alone
in the room with him.
- No!
- This girl reads minds...
and spins falsehoods.
She's a witch, and we must
purge the devil from her!
With fire!
You're gonna be fine,
Shepherd. Alliance patched you up.
- Alliance?
- Yeah.
They let us come, and they let us go.
What kind of ident card gets us
that kind of reception and send off?
I am a Shepherd.
- Folks like a man of God.
- No, they don't.
Men of God make everyone
feel guilty and judged.
That's not what I saw.
You like to tell me
what really happened?
I surely would.
And maybe someday I will.
It's good to be home.
Badger just hailed us.
Getting impatient for his share. Wants us
to drop it on the Common Fed Base.
That'll be a lot easier to do without
the two most wanted on board.
Life would look to be simpler
with us not carrying any fugees.
He is right, you know.
Yeah.
Simpler.
Take me instead.
Take my life for hers.
The witch must die.
God commands it.
No! Get away from her!
She has done nothing to you!
If she dies tonight, it won't be God's
will that killed her, it'll be you!
Your lunacy! Your ignorance!
That's not gonna stop us, doctor.
Post-holer.
Digging holes for posts.
Light it.
Time to go.
Well, look at this.
Appears we got here
just in the nick of time.
What does that make us?
Big damn heroes, sir.
Ain't we just.
Sorry to interrupt, folks.
Y'all got something that belongs to us,
and we'd like it back.
This is a holy cleansing.
You cannot think to thwart God's will.
Y'all see the man hanging out of the
spaceship with the really big gun?
I'm not saying you weren't easy to find,
but it was kind of out of our way...
and he didn't wanna come
in the first place.
Man's looking to kill some folk.
It's his will you should worry
about thwarting.
Gotta say, doctor, this town's real
and the folks are near miraculous.
Yes, I'm very proud.
Cut her down.
The girl is a witch.
Yeah, but she's our witch.
So cut her the hell down.
Hey, doctor.
Glad you're back now on the ship.
Thanks.
I've moved him to his room.
- How's he faring?
- He's gonna be fine. Yeah.
- They took good care of him.
- Good to know.
So finally a decent wound
on this ship and I miss out.
I'm sorry.
Well, you were busy trying to get
yourself lit on fire. It happens.
Captain...
- Why did you come back for us?
- You're on my crew.
But you don't like me.
Why did you come back?
You're on my crew.
Why are we still talking about this?
Chow's in 10! No need to dress.
So Shepherd says to him...