08 Firefly Ariel - Episode 08 2002 English
I don't want it.
River, you have to eat.
It's good. It tastes like...
- It's good.
- It smells like crotch.
- Jayne!
- Well, it does.
We don't even have
to go some place fancy.
We can just go to the park
or something. Feed the pigeons.
Sure, feed the pigeons. Probably
get the firing squad for littering.
- Come on, it's not that bad.
- It is. It's a core planet.
It's spotless. It's got sensors,
and there's Feds.
All central planets are the same.
Could you please tell my wife
the fun she's missing out on?
Ariel's quite a nice place, actually.
There's some beautiful museums...
not to mention some fine restaurants.
But not boring,
like she made it sound.
There's...
Uh... Uh...
- There's hiking.
- Yeah.
And you can go swimming
in a bio luminescent lake.
Even if it's got sunsets 24 hours a day,
I ain't going to that planet.
No one is setting foot
on that fancy rock.
I don't want anyone leaving the ship.
Come to think of it...
I don't want anyone looking out
the windows or talking aloud.
We're here to drop off Inara.
Why come to the core
if I can't even step off the boat?
You could have gotten off with
Shepherd at the Bathgate Abbey.
Could have been meditating on the
wonders of your rock garden by now.
It beats just sitting.
It is just sitting.
- How long will you be planet-side?
- No more than a day or two.
Big stop just to renew
your license to companion.
Can I use companion as a verb?
It's Guild law.
All companions are required...
to undergo a physical examination
once a year.
Could you not do that while we're...?
Ever!
So two days in a hospital.
That's awful.
- Don't you just hate doctors?
- Hey!
I mean, present company
excluded.
Let's not be excluding people.
That'd be rude.
Son of a...! God!
What the hell?
River, no.
- I got the knife.
- He's bleeding.
- That's deep.
- He okay?
River.
He looks better in red.
Gorram freak's completely
off her axle.
- I'm sorry about this. I don't know...
- Shut it. I ain't talking to you.
She gotta go. Both of them gotta go.
Ariel's as good a place as any
to leave them.
- Might even pick up a reward.
- No one's getting left.
She belongs in a bug house.
- You don't pitch her off now, I swear...
- What?
What do you swear, Jayne?
They don't get gone, you better
start locking up your room at night.
Next time she gets
in a murdering mood...
it might be you
she comes calling on.
Maybe Kaylee or Inara.
You let them stay,
we're gonna find out.
Finish your work, doctor.
This is my boat.
They're part of my crew.
No one's getting left.
Best you get used to that.
You owe me a shirt.
She's to stay confined to her room
at all times, no exceptions.
Take her to the kitchen, infirmary,
you ask me. Understand?
I do.
When I took you and your sister in,
the deal was you keep her in check.
You can't hold up your end,
we're gonna have to revisit the deal.
She's getting worse, isn't she?
Yes.
Just look at the bright side.
Maybe you'll meet a young,
handsome doctor. He'll ask you out.
What's the companion policy on dating?
It's complicated.
- Well, that figures.
- Stay out of trouble.
You too. Bye.
How we gonna find a job
if we don't leave the ship?
Alliance territory,
ain't any jobs worth having.
Where were the last three
places we've been?
My pop always said, "Anyone who can't
find work ain't looking hard enough."
We ain't even looking at all.
You can stop looking.
There's a client.
Me.
I have a job for you.
You've got a job for us?
One that'll pay for itself 10 times over.
Oh, forget it. We ain't that desperate.
Do you know what this is?
It's a common immune booster
called isoprovoline.
Street value for a dosage this size...
50 platinum, maybe 20 credits.
Propoxyn, maybe 80.
Hydrozepam, 200.
And all of these are what I had
in the med kit when I came on board.
At a hospital like the one in Ariel City,
they'll have shelves of that stuff.
Whatever the take, it's more than
enough payment for what I have in mind.
So the med vault isn't the job?
That's the payment.
I tell you how to get in,
get out and what's worth taking...
if you help me get River
to the hospital's diagnostic ward.
- What's in the ward?
- A 3-D neuro-imager.
If I get River there, I might figure out
what they did to her.
So we get you both
in there and you tell us...
how to clean out the hospital.
Yes.
Not to be negative, but don't
the hospital need that medicine?
Government-run facility. They'd be
restocked in a matter of hours.
She's right. They'll never miss it.
Plus, folks on the rim
sure could use it.
You know, it's very sweet stealing
from the rich, selling to the poor...
but you're talking about breaking into
a secure Alliance facility.
How will you get around security?
Well, it's not easy, but it can be done.
See, like all core hospitals, St. Lucy's
has its own dedicated security force.
A small battery of local Alliance
Federals sub stationed here.
Now, every floor, every doorway
is equipped with sensors...
and at all points of entry,
patient ident scans.
However, once clear of the checkpoints,
movement within the facility...
should be relatively unhindered.
The standard layout puts the med vault...
Go back to the ident scans.
You and your sister are fugitives.
How will you get in the building?
Through the front door.
Believe me, captain, getting
the two of us in is going to be easy.
The rest of you, that is going
to be the real trick.
We'll need to procure a few items
off-ship. I've made a list.
Now, given my status as a fugitive,
someone else will have to...
We have some volunteers. Good.
And before we make it to the front door,
we have to breach the perimeter.
Only official vehicles are allowed in,
so we'll need one.
Now, obviously, we can't steal
what we need.
Any illegal activity in the planning stages
could end this thing before it starts.
St. Lucy's Hospital contracts...
with a local municipal dump yard
for all its large disposals.
Figures.
First time on the core, and what
do I get to do? Dig through trash.
Why couldn't he send me shopping
at the Triplex?
Oh, synchronisers.
Big hospitals mean big waste,
so we shouldn't have trouble...
finding what we're looking for.
We'll have to look like we belong.
All we do is slip some bills
into the right hands.
That gets us uniforms,
ID badges and key cards.
A little creative forgery, and we've
got ourselves a working alias.
Now, all these items are easy to obtain.
They'll get us up to the door.
Now, in order to get us in...
Patients were cynical, not responding.
- We couldn't bring him back.
- They were cyanotic...
They were cyanotic and unresponsive...
And we're unable to...
- Resuscitate them.
- Yes.
- Resuscitate.
- Resuscitate them.
Which methods did you use?
We tried pulmonary stimulator's
and cardiac...
- Infusers.
- Pulmonary...
- Pulmonary stimulator's...
And cardiac infusers.
- What about cortical electrodes?
- Oh.
We forgot them.
- Let's try that again.
- Yeah.
The pupils were fixed and dilapidated.
- Dilated.
- Dilated. Dilated!
We got there, and the patients
were cyanotic.
Not responsive, and we tried
to resuscitate them.
And despite our best efforts,
they kicked.
In spite of our best efforts...
- Which methods did you use?
- We tried pulmonary stimulator's...
and cardiac infusers.
What about the cortical electrodes?
What's that?
We applied the cortical electrodes.
We used the electromagnetic...
Reaction from...
But unable to get a neural...
Applied cortical electrodes but did not
get a neural reaction...
Unable to get a neural...
- Response.
Hell, if I'd wanted schooling,
I'd have gone to school.
I'll get it.
That's amazing.
You two did an incredible job.
And now for the finishing touch.
If I didn't know better, I'd say
you were ready to save lives.
- Now all we need are a couple patients.
- Corpses, actually.
For this to work,
River and I will have to be dead.
I'm starting to like this plan.
We're going to be asleep.
Capt.. Reynolds will pretend we're dead
to sneak us into the hospital.
Once we're inside, we'll wake up,
everything will be fine.
You understand?
You're going to suspend cerebral,
cardiac and pulmonary activity...
in order to induce
a proto-comatose state.
That's right.
- I don't wanna do it.
- I know.
I don't wanna go to that place.
I don't wanna die.
No, no one is going to die.
The others will take care of us while
we're asleep, and when we get back...
- No, no, no.
- Shh, River? River, it's okay.
It's okay. This, this could be
what we've been hoping for.
When this is over,
I'll be able to help you.
I'll be able to make
the nightmares go away.
Okay?
Okay.
Lie back.
It's time to go to sleep.
We speak only when spoken to.
We avoid unnecessary contact and stay
together until we reach the morgue.
- Yes, sir.
- Applied cortical electrodes.
- Jayne?
- Yeah, yeah, I got it.
- Will we have a problem?
- I know what I gotta do.
That's not what I'm talking about. Will
I have a problem with you and Simon?
It's up to him.
You got stabbed the other day. It's
bound to make anyone a might onerous.
- So I figure...
- It's a good plan.
What?
Doc did good coming up with that job.
Don't mean I like him better.
Nothing buys bygones quicker than cash.
Maybe I'll give him a tattoo
while he's out.
Let him do his thing and then
get him out. No messing with him.
Don't worry about me.
As long as I get paid I'm happy.
Applied the cortical electrodes,
unable to get a neural response.
Applied the cortical electrodes.
We have a few hours
before the morning shift.
Won't be an hour.
- What do you got?
- We got a couple DOAs.
- By the time we got there...
- Take them to the morgue.
We applied the cortical electrodes
but were unable to get a neural reaction.
That should bring them out soon.
Once they're up,
get them to the imaging suite...
let Simon do his thing
and haul it back to the rendezvous.
- Fifty minutes.
- Got it.
And I'll just sit right here.
I'm in.
- Do you have the fugitives?
- You got my reward?
Yes, just like we talked about.
- Then I got your fugitives.
- Good, we'll see you shortly.
Congratulations. You're about
to become a very rich man.
Copper for a kiss.
Jesus.
What did you say?
What the hell's the matter with you?
Nothing. It's just the after effects
of the drugs.
I'll be fine. Just give me a second.
Well, your sister seems okay.
You better get dressed. We gotta move.
Two lefts, two rights, and we're there.
You see anyone, smile.
- No one smiles in hospitals.
- Yes, they do. It's the core.
Everyone's rich and happy here.
Why wouldn't they smile?
Excuse me? Excuse me?
Hi.
- Where are you taking those bodies?
- To the morgue.
Downstairs is that way.
Right. Must have gotten turned around.
Let me see your badge.
You're doing it backwards,
walking up the down slide.
Keep her quiet.
This is the recovery ward.
This is where patients
come to get better.
Going to die.
- No one is going to die.
- He is.
No, he's not. That man
standing next to him is his doctor.
- He's going to help him.
- He's not going to help him right.
River, the doctors here
are the best in the system.
This is one of the top hospitals
in the core or anywhere else.
Where you should be.
- You have to help him.
- River, we don't have time.
- He's killing him.
- Code blue.
- Stay here.
- Don't you...!
Don't move.
What do we have?
42-year-old, double-bypass post-op.
Prognosis, positive.
- BP's 60/20. Pulse is thready.
- Who are you?
- He's crashing.
- Get the cart.
- We have flat line.
- We gotta crack him.
We're not cracking a post-op.
- Should I call the code team?
- Get the infusers and.4 of atropine.
- What did you give him?
- Just 20 of apresoline push.
Clear.
- Clear.
- He's going tachy.
- But his heart's beating.
He's okay.
How do you justify administering
a vasoconstrictor to this patient?
- Apresoline is a painkiller not an vaso...
- Unless you combine it with dilaftin.
Which any first-year should know
is the standard prep medicine...
your patient took before surgery.
Your patient should be dead.
Let's go.
Walk with me a minute.
- Where are we going?
- You see this badge? It says doctor.
I say walk, you walk.
- But where are we going?
- You must be new.
Don't get comfortable.
Your type doesn't last long here.
When your supervisor hears
about the rude and disrespect... Ah!
Clear.
Ready?
1205, here it is.
Zoe.
It must have been damaged.
They opened up her skull.
That's a scalpel scar. They...
They opened up her skull,
and they cut into her brain.
Why?
The only reason to make an incision in
someone's brain is to lobotomise them.
To remove damaged tissue.
Why anyone would
cut into a healthy brain is...
They did it over and over.
They stripped her amygdala.
Her what?
You know how you get scared
or worried or nervous...
but you don't wanna be,
so you push it to the back of your mind.
You try not to think about it.
Your amygdala is what lets you do that.
It's like a filter in your brain
that keeps your feelings in check.
She feels everything. She can't not.
Well, that's fascinating.
Let's get moving.
We still have 20 minutes.
The plan changed when you were out.
We're meeting out the back way in five.
I could use a few minutes.
If we contact Capt.. Reynolds...
He gave orders.
We play it by the book.
River, it's okay. It's okay.
Get her in the chair and let's go.
No. No. No. They come out of the black.
They come when you call.
- River, it's okay. It's over. We're leaving.
- Your toes are in sand.
- And your head's up your...
- Hey, back off.
Make sure her mouth is shut.
I don't need her screeching
while we try to get away.
It's okay.
You should have let me know
the plan changed.
I told you when you needed to know.
What are you griping about?
You got what you came for.
No, no, I can't go back.
I don't wanna go back.
It's okay.
We're just going back to the ship.
We're almost home.
Federal marshals, don't move.
River and Simon Tam, by the authority
of the Union of Allied Planets...
you are hereby bound by law.
Take them to processing.
You gonna take me away for questioning
now? How you wanna play it?
You're under arrest for aiding
and abetting federal fugitives.
- Better get a lawyer.
- You're kidding, right?
- Where's my rutting money?
- You mean my money?
For apprehending three fugitives,
I expect I'll be getting it soon.
- How much did we get?
- Enough to keep us flying.
- Can we fly somewhere with a beach?
- Maybe a naked beach.
The job's not done until
we're back on Serenity.
Sorry, sir, didn't mean
to enjoy the moment.
Where are the others?
If those officers hadn't been armed,
I think you'd have had a chance.
A guy shoves me, I shove him.
Not like I was trying to mount a rescue.
Still, I appreciate you trying.
You know what I'd appreciate?
Stop flapping that mouth at me.
I'm trying to figure a way out of here.
Can't do it with you yammering.
They took Christmas away.
What the hell now?
Came downstairs
for the shiny presents.
They took the tree and the stockings.
Nothing left but coal.
Would you shut her up?
Don't look in the closet either.
It's greedy.
It's not in the spirit of the holiday.
You shut the hell up right now,
or so help me, I will shut you up.
Time?
- Ten minutes past rendezvous.
- Something's happened.
Kaylee, are you linked?
I am now. What do you need?
See if there's a security alert
in the hospital.
Hang on.
- Maybe they're late.
- Not this late.
Jayne would have sent up a flag.
Nothing from hospital security
or on the local pipeline.
Although I am getting some weird
chatter from the official 262.
It sounds like...
they're talking about ducks.
- Code.
- Feds got them.
Have her bring up a hospital schematic.
Find a way into the security substation.
Wait a minute, you don't
even know if they're in there.
- Gonna find out. Check.
- Coming in clear.
So you're just gonna walk in
through the front door?
No, you're gonna find me
a way around back.
- Get up.
- What's going to happen to us?
I said, get up.
Agent McGinnis, I'm certain
you're working under a superior...
who's keeping close tabs
on this case.
I know because important
people don't do fieldwork.
I'm also quite certain your superior
wants me and my sister alive.
Now, I'm not going to move from this
spot until one of two things happens.
You answer my very simple question,
or you shoot me.
We're transferring you to a holding
area until you can be retrieved.
Retrieved? By whom?
People who want you alive.
People. Not me.
Take them.
- Wash, we could use direction here.
- Working on it.
Kaylee, what do you got?
Tell them to go left when they
reach cryo. They'll see a door.
All right, go through that door
and down to green level.
This is exactly what I didn't want.
I wanted simple. I wanted in and out.
I wanted easy money.
Things get complicated,
don't they, sir?
Just once I'd like things
to go according to the gorram plan.
- Guys, you might wanna hurry.
- Oh, is there a problem?
I think the reinforcements just arrived.
- What are you doing?
- Going out the way we came in.
- There are four armed Feds out there.
- Six, I know.
- We run.
- You got no idea where that goes.
- We'll find our way.
- I ain't chancing that.
I can handle the Feds.
Doesn't matter.
They're here.
Gentlemen, that was prompt.
We're almost finished here.
Prisoners will be out in a minute.
Let me get the paperwork together
for you. Bobby, bring that here.
Not that it'll mean much.
The men were tight lipped. The girl was
spewing gibberish. We got it all down.
You spoke to the prisoners?
Well, yeah. Had to process them.
There was no interrogation,
if that's what you mean.
Didn't do your job for you.
- Did your men also speak with them?
- As much as they had to.
What the hell is that?
Two by two. Hands of blue.
- Where the hell's she going?
- Must be some sort of exit this way.
I don't see no exit.
- Dead.
- This one's alive.
I won't run around like a rat in a maze
till we're dead.
Now, we're going back.
Almost there.
There.
Stand back.
Come here.
Shee-niou high-tech Alliance crap!
Hey, Inara.
How was your check up?
Same as last year.
What's going on here?
Let's see, we killed Simon and River,
stole a bunch of medicine.
Now the cap and Zoe
are springing the others...
got snatched by the Feds.
Oh, there they are now.
Tell me we weren't followed.
Nothing in our rear-view
the whole way back.
All right.
- Take us out, quick as you can.
- We'll be out of atmo in five minutes.
Hey, how was your thing?
As advertised, lots of needles
and cold exam tables.
I heard you had some excitement.
Nothing much.
Lots of running around, a little gunplay.
A couple needles.
Next time we're here,
I'll stay with the preacher.
If you hadn't come, you wouldn't
be getting your payday.
So get what you needed?
I think I did. I have the information
off the imager.
I just have to go over it,
and I'm hopeful.
- What happened to your face?
- Huh?
- Ow.
- Oh, nothing.
He was amazing.
I can't even begin to tell you.
We wouldn't be standing here
if it weren't for him.
Thank you.
Well, hey, you're part of my crew.
I think I might cry.
All right. Jayne, help me with the cargo.
Everyone, make yourselves useful.
You got jobs, go do them.
This has gotta be our best take ever.
Well, doc had a good notion.
The boy's got a decent criminal mind.
So, what are you buying with your cut?
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
The job is done.
I figured it was time for a little chat.
It seems to me we had a solid plan.
Smooth, you might say.
But what I can't figure out is, what
you were doing around the back exit.
What?
I couldn't go out the front. I had
to improvise. Open the damn door!
You called the Feds.
What? I got pinched.
Which is what happens
when you call the Feds.
No. I would never do that.
My hand to God. May he strike
me down as I'm standing here.
Well, you won't be
standing there long.
Minute we break atmo, you'll be thinner
once you get sucked out that hole.
- Come on, Mal!
- Leaving atmo in 2 minutes.
- That ain't no way for a man to die.
- Secure cargo door.
You wanna kill me, shoot me.
Just let me in.
I hear tell they used to keelhaul
traitors back in the day.
I don't have a keel
to haul you on, so...
Okay. I'm sorry, all right?
Sorry for what, Jayne?
I thought you'd never do such a thing.
Money was too good.
I got stupid.
I'm sorry, okay?
Be reasonable.
What are you taking
this so personal for?
It ain't like I ratted you out
to the Feds.
But you did. You turn on
any of my crew, you turn on me.
Since that's a concept you can't
wrap your head around...
then you got no place here.
You did it to me, Jayne,
and that's a fact.
- What are you gonna tell the others?
- About what?
About why I'm dead.
I haven't thought about it.
Make something up.
Don't tell them what I did.
The next time you decide
to stab me in the back...
have the guts to do it to my face.
Can I come in?
Hi.
What are you doing?
Drawing.
That's really good.
What are you doing?
I...
I brought some medicine.
Do you remember why
we went to the hospital?
Is it time to go to sleep again?
No, Mei Mei.
It's time to wake up.