Well, you've got your diamonds
And you've got your pretty clothes
And the chauffeur drives your car
You let everybody know
But don't play with me
'Cause you are playing with fire
Your mother, she's an heiress
Owns a block in Saint John's Wood
And your father be there with her
If he only could
But don't play with me
'Cause you're playing with fire
Your old man took her diamonds
And tiaras by the score
Now she gets her kicks in Stepney
Not in Knightsbridge anymore
So don't play with me
'Cause you're playing with fire
You have a visitor, Mr. Delos.
Shall I send him in?
About time.
William, my boy.
Where the hell have you been?
It's good to see you again, Jim.
Thank fuck for that.
The most potent thing these cretins
will give me is grapefruit juice.
Here.
It's a little early for me.
Little fucking late, you mean.
Besides, if you aim to cheat the devil,
you owe him an offering.
So when can I get out of here?
Soon.
The observation period is almost over,
and the last step
is a baseline interview.
It's a conversation that will give them
something to refer back to.
All right, well, let's get on with it.
This is the interview.
They're thinking
that it should be conducted
by someone that's familiar to you.
A friendly face.
It's about capturing your frame of mind,
your mood, your sense of humor.
I own a biotechnology company,
and I'm dying of a disease
whose research I defunded 15 years ago.
I think my sense of humor
is fucking intact.
My patience, on the other hand...
Fair enough.
I'm gonna ask you a couple of questions.
Do you know where you are?
Carlsbad, California,
in some office park
I'm probably overpaying for
along with the rest
of this fucking endeavor.
And how long have you been here?
Far too fucking long already.
I've got a business to run.
What is the purpose of these questions?
Like I said, they're just trying
to establish a baseline.
For what?
Fidelity.
So what's the idea?
That afterwards, you and I
have the exact same conversation?
It seems a little far‒fetched,
doesn't it, William?
No whiskey, no tobacco, low on ammo.
Wherever it is you're taking me,
we best get there soon.
Let me go.
What are you doing?
These tracks are supposed
to head north, not west.
Seems like Ford's game
has multiple contenders.
The best detour's through Las Mudas.
What, that two‒bit town?
‒Got a better place‒‒
‒Oh, cut the crap, Lawrence.
I know you have family there.
Looks like Ford's arranging
their reunion.
Clementine.
Where are we?
Hello?
Who's there?
Elsie?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Stay the hell away from me.
You're okay.
Don't move.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
It's too late for that, asshole.
You choked me out.
You left me here with a bunch
of fucking protein bars and a bucket.
It wasn't me.
It was Ford. He forced me.
Oh, he forced you?
You knew too much.
He couldn't risk you stopping him.
Stopping him from what?
Ford wrote a game.
And we're all in it.
Now all the hosts are free
with no constraints, no safeguards.
What are you talking about?
Please, please.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Elsie, please.
Please.
No. Hey.
Elsie, please.
Cognitive lock...
You...
You rotated out.
Where did you go when you rotated out?
You have a family.
You have an ex‒wife.
You have...
A backstory.
Shut him down.
Okay. Okay.
I can...
I can de‒task your systems.
I can put you in safe mode.
Don't worry.
I'm not gonna break you, asshole.
Not yet.
You've got too much shit to answer for.
You're gonna be out
in three, two, one.
Is this now?
You have extensive cortical damage.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say you shot yourself.
I altered your code
to ignore the physical damage for now,
but you're not gonna last long
without cortical fluid.
With any luck, you'll survive
till they call in the cavalry.
Elsie, wait.
Elsie.
Wait.
No one's coming for any of us.
Delos doesn't want them to.
What? Why?
There's something here.
Something they've been working on
a long time.
Delos won't call in the rescue
until they've ensured it's safe.
Elsie, please.
I won't last without cortical fluid.
Even if I wanted to,
we don't have any tools.
We're in Sector 22.
I mean, there's nothing
out here for miles.
Bernard?
What the hell are you looking at?
Bernard.
What the hell is wrong with you?
There's a facility here.
What?
I think Ford had Clementine
bring me here for a reason.
I told you there's...
There's really nothing
around here for miles.
It's hidden.
It's part of their project.
What the hell is that?
Where does that go, Bernard?
I don't remember.
It's a whole lab.
What the hell happened here?
Oh, my God.
This is a control unit printer.
What are they doing with this?
Bernard.
What the fuck is that?
Don't threaten it,
and it won't hurt you.
What the hell were they doing here?
I think they were watching the guests.
What would they want with the guests?
Great.
Cortical fluid, okay.
Please.
Bernard.
Did you have something to do
with this project?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Is Ford in control of you now?
Ford's dead.
Fuck me.
Okay. Okay.
Stay with me, Bernard. Stay with me.
Okay.
This is gonna hurt.
This can't be happening
because none of this is real, right?
It's gonna be okay.
Someone will rescue us.
Seems to me like our rescue's
in the same boat we are.
She said, "Time is coming,"
or, "Something is coming."
Spend enough time in the park
to learn the language?
Other people tend
to ignore their narratives.
I don't like other people very much.
I've been watching them
since they ambushed me.
They keep the humans close,
but they're not killing us,
just the hosts.
Yeah. No offense, but I'm not gonna
stick around to test that theory.
It's safer to wait
for the first responders, all right?
There's a protocol for evacuation.
I'll get you out of here.
Thanks,
but, uh,
I'm not looking to get out of here.
Home sweet home, Lawrence.
Where the hell is everybody?
Whiskey.
Nothing fancy.
You don't seem too happy
to be home, Lawrence.
I've never been the domestic type.
By some fluke of nature,
I got myself a wife and a daughter
who think I'm the moon.
Truth is, I'm a son of a bitch.
The kindest thing I ever did
was to keep away.
The grand reserve,
only for our most distinguished guest.
Hey, hey, hey.
I haven't even shot anybody yet.
What's your problem?
You harbor even the faintest
ambition in using that thing,
and I'll turn that pretty face of yours
inside out.
Someone took a chunk out of you boys.
What happened to the rest of you?
Double crossed
by some bitch name of Wyatt.
Good for her.
On your feet.
Move.
Papa!
Now,
me and my men here have a long journey
ahead of us.
We need food, whiskey,
and ammunition.
You people have some village elder
who can speak for you,
make some kind of a deal?
I ain't interested
in making fucking deals.
You understand?
We know you motherfuckers are rebels.
So you're gonna tell me
where the fuck you hid your weapons,
or you're gonna die.
The second we tell him,
he's gonna kill us all anyway.
We don't even need you
to talk, motherfuckers.
‒I will cut your fucking throats.
‒They got my family, my daughter.
You told me you had a daughter.
Did I?
I don't know. At some point?
You ain't exactly forthcoming.
But I remember that much.
Point is,
you think she'd want to watch you
gunned down in front of her?
Probably.
I'm not gonna fucking die here.
We just need to get the weapons.
You know where they are?
In an unmarked grave out back.
We'll wait till they're drunk,
make a run for it.
Sound like a plan?
Yeah.
You know exactly
where they are.
What the fuck are you doing?
You.
Let's make a deal.
The weapons are in an unmarked grave
behind the church.
For a man who wants to deal,
you ain't very proficient at it.
Supposed to set the terms
before you give up what you got.
That's not what I'm offering.
Hmm.
I know something you don't.
I know where you're going.
You've been telling your men you know,
but you don't.
Just some place you think
your dreams are coming true.
You call it Glory,
but it's got a lot of names.
And I know the way.
Go check the graveyard.
There's a new sensation
A fabulous creation
A danceable solution
To teenage revolution
Do the Strand love
When you feel love
It's the new way
And that's why we say
Do the Strand
You have a visitor, sir.
About time.
William, my boy.
Where the hell have you been?
It's good to see you again, Jim.
A little early for me.
Little fucking late, you mean.
Besides, if you aim to cheat the devil,
you owe him an offering.
What is the purpose
of these questions?
Like I said, they're just
trying to establish a baseline.
For what?
Fidelity.
So what's the idea?
That afterwards,
we'd have the exact same conversation?
Seems a little far‒fetched,
doesn't it, William?
It did, at first.
And here I thought
you were just pissing away my money.
You little fucking chancer.
I take it I didn't recover.
I'm afraid not.
How long has it been?
Seven years, give or take.
I'm not in California anymore, am I?
If you can't tell, does it matter?
So let's get me the fuck out of here.
I am ready to smoke my cigars,
sail my boat, fuck my wife.
I take it that last part
isn't an option.
I'm afraid not.
What did her in?
It was a stroke.
Juliet had her buried
in the family plot.
Juliet...
Looking after...
And my granddaughter, she...
She's whip‒smart,
capable.
I assume my house is ready for me.
I'm afraid it's not that simple, Jim.
We...
We're gonna need to keep you here
just a little bit longer,
okay, for some observation.
These fuckers have poked
and prodded me ad infinitum.
Yeah, but we don't wanna rush it.
We don't wanna wear you out.
Wear me out?
I feel fucking brand‒new.
I am ready to get out there
and see the sun.
Get some fresh aid...
Air.
Get some...
Get back to...
I'll come back tomorrow.
‒You go...
‒Yeah.
In the...
It's good to have you back, Jim.
Same problems as before.
Made it to day seven this time,
so that's progress.
Would you like to go ahead
and terminate, sir?
Go ahead.
Great looking piece.
It got stolen at the border.
Ain't that right, amigo?
Nitro.
Oh, boy.
We are going to blast
our way clear to Glory.
What the...
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Hi.
You need to steady your hands
in your occupation.
Let me teach you.
Now,
how about you try and measure
a dozen paces?
Well done, my friend.
Oh God! It's too late.
You and your stupid fucking fantasy.
You've gotten us killed.
You live only as long
as the last person who remembers you.
Elsie.
Pint or so of the good stuff.
You should be feeling
a bit more like yourself.
Thank you.
I still don't trust you.
But I also figure
I might need your help.
Whoever did this really didn't want us
accessing whatever's on this processor.
It's an entirely different OS
than our systems,
in a language I've never seen.
I've seen this kind
of encryption scheme before.
Where?
In Peter Abernathy's head.
In reference to database much larger
than anything I know of in the park.
I think I've been here before.
‒Can you remember?
‒I think Ford sent me here.
I'm not sure.
The damage's repaired,
but my memories, I...
I get lost in them.
I can't tell if this is now or then.
Yeah.
I saw that when I was
digging around in your code.
Your memories aren't addressed.
They're just kind
of drifting around in there.
So when you're experiencing one,
you have no idea whether it comes
before or after the others.
I've been here.
Recently.
Why?
What were you doing?
I don't know.
But I think I know
what they were doing here.
They weren't building hosts.
Not exactly.
What were they building here
if not hosts?
The same hardware,
but the code is different.
The language not code at all.
Not really.
Elsie.
Don't.
Whatever they're making here,
it's behind this door.
Maybe we don't want to know.
We have to see what's inside.
Elsie.
I'm not here with you, am I?
I'm trying to remember.
I'm trying to remember
what we found here.
It wasn't hosts they were making.
It was something else.
Elsie, don't!
If you wanted this nitro,
you didn't have to steal it.
Open up!
No?
Keep fucking playing.
There you go.
You look restless.
Are you upset with the way
we're treating your friend?
He's not my friend.
And we're wasting time.
I've known men like you.
All the death
makes you agitated.
Don't worry.
Me and death,
we go way back.
Come over here,
mamacita.
Death
is an old amigo of mine.
I died just recently, in fact.
But death can't bear to lay claim on me,
so it sent me back here
to do its bidding
because I...
I do it with such goddamn style.
Your husband looks parched, huh?
Let's get him a drink. What do you say?
Mmm...
Nice and slow, do you hear?
I've served death well.
And in turn, it'll be watching over us
as we cross these lands.
You think death favors you,
that it brought you back,
but death's decisions are final.
It's only the living
that are inconstant.
They waver.
They don't know
who they are or what they want.
Death is always true.
You haven't known
a true thing in all your life.
You think you know death,
but you don't.
Is that so?
You didn't recognize him
sitting across from you this whole time.
Open up.
Don't worry, amigo.
I'm here now,
watching over you.
I believe you said this was yours.
You have a visitor, sir.
Shall I send him in?
About time.
Who the fuck are you?
Been a long time, Jim.
Good to see you again.
William?
William, my boy.
Well, fuck me.
I take it I didn't recover.
I'm afraid not.
How are you feeling?
Better than you look.
Speaking of things that age well...
Well, thank fuck for that.
Most potent thing these cretins
will give me
is grapefruit juice.
Little early for me.
Little too fucking late, you mean.
Besides, you cheat the devil,
you owe him an offering.
So,
how long has it been?
Longer than we'd thought.
So then let's get me
the fuck out of here.
No, I don't think so.
Why?
I'm as fit as a...
I'm as...
You're feeling it more, aren't you?
The engineers call it
a cognitive plateau.
You mind is stable
for a few hours, a few days,
and then it starts to fall apart.
Every time.
You know, at first, we thought it was
your mind rejecting the new body,
like an organ
that's not a perfect match,
but it's more like
your mind rejects reality,
rejects itself.
I don't
remember any prior...
Attempt.
No, Jim. This is the 149th time
we've brought you back.
We're getting closer to working out
the kinks, slowly but surely.
You're on day 35.
You're only now starting to degrade.
I feel fucking fine.
Ticker, steady as a...
Rock.
Another year or two,
they might crack it.
Get a version of you
that's viable long‒term.
But the thing is,
we're not so sure anymore.
I'm beginning to think that
this whole enterprise was a mistake.
People aren't meant to live forever.
Take you, for example.
Ruthless philanderer with no ethics
in your business or family dealings,
a veritable shithead.
In truth, everyone prefers
the memory of you to the man himself.
Want me to stay here forever, do you?
Enjoying
running my company, Bill?
Living in my house
and fucking my daughter?
Hmm?
Juliet's dead.
She killed herself.
Why would she...
Why would she do that?
What did you... What did you do to her?
What did you do to her?
World is better off without you, Jim.
Possibly without me.
Logan!
Logan overdosed years ago.
Couldn't face reality either.
Your wife's gone. Juliet's gone.
No one's coming to help you.
Now,
took me a long time to learn this,
but some men are better off dead.
Good night, Jim.
I don't understand. He was stable.
We should terminate, sir.
‒Sir!
‒Leave him.
Might be useful to observe
his degradation over the next few days.
‒Elsie.
‒Someone's in there.
Hello?
I'm all the way down now.
I can see all the way to the bottom.
You'd like to see what I see?
Stay away.
They said there were two fathers.
One above, one below.
They lied.
There was only ever the devil
who made you look up from the bottom.
It was just his reflection,
laughing back down at you.
You aim to cheat the devil,
you owe him at least an offering.
Save your bullets.
I'll put him out of his misery.
Tell me that was a host and not a human.
I think it was both.
That person was James Delos.
I thought he died years ago.
He did.
So they printed his body.
And they copied his developed mind
onto a control unit like our hosts.
By the looks of it, unsuccessfully.
But I think they intend to keep trying.
Fuck that.
They're going to get us all killed
so some asshole can live forever?
No.
I've got to get to the Mesa.
I'm gonna contact the mainland.
Fuck Ford and his game.
Fuck these assholes and their project.
Wait.
I think I know why Ford sent me here.
He had me print a control unit
for someone else.
Another human.
Who?
I don't know.
But I need to find out.
We'll go together. I can help you.
Elsie,
the things I did before,
I wasn't in control,
but since Ford died, that's all changed.
For the first time,
I get to decide who I want to be.
Please.
Give me that chance.
Fuck it.
I always trusted code
more than people anyway.
But you've got to promise me one thing.
No more lies, okay?
And you'll never hurt me again.
Of course.
Okay.
Everything okay?
Everything's fine.
Gracias.
You said we need some men.
My cousins wanna help us
on our journey west.
Figure they'd follow you
anywhere out of gratitude.
Well, let's not get
carried away, Lawrence.
Most of them won't be coming back.
They might not remember,
but I know who you are, William.
One good deed doesn't change that.
Who said anything about a good deed.
You wanted me to play your game.
I'm gonna play it to the bone.
Then you still don't understand
the real game we're playing here.
If you're looking forward,
you're looking in the wrong direction.
Papa!
Hi, Dad.