Mind if I join you?
Do as you please.
So what brings you
to this part of the world?
Have a little time to kill.
Among other things.
Hunting?
Bengals?
Yeah, me, too.
There's nothing like it, is there?
Edge of the park, a bit mad,
a bit dangerous.
Sir,
the Governor wishes
to extend to you an invitation.
Please tell the Governor another time.
I'm quite happy here.
They really don't want us
talking to each other, do they?
Maybe they're trying to
steer you towards a sure thing.
Maybe I miss taking my chances.
You certainly look like
one of the park's offerings.
I promise you,
I'm quite real.
Think the park will go
to the trouble of having one of them
pretend to be one of us?
I wouldn't put it past them.
Simplest way to know for sure,
unless you'd rather not.
Well, it wouldn't be my first time.
Just
seems a little excessive.
Perhaps,
but I want you to want this.
I assure you I do.
Not if you're one of them.
If you're one of them,
you don't know what you want,
you just do as you're told.
For a lot of people,
that is half the fun.
Not for me.
Don't worry.
If you are who you say you are,
this will only sting a bit.
And if you're not,
you won't remember anyway.
Still, I'd really rather‒‒
Congratulations.
Oh!
Now,
where were we?
Have these put in my tent
with our things.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
What do you say to a night off?
Before we go hunt the wicked tiger
in the morning.
Something's wrong.
Where is everybody?
Normally, there are other hosts here.
You know, to entertain us, to cook.
Or maybe they're giving us our privacy.
It's not how this works.
Wow.
A new twist in the narrative.
‒Horror.
‒No. I‒‒
These violent delights
have violent ends.
Ganju.
Ganju, put the gun down.
Put the gun down, Ganju.
Don't worry.
He can't hurt us.
No, those people are guests.
I rode the train with them on the‒‒
Fuck.
Attention.
You have reached the boundary
of the guest experience area.
Please turn back.
Attention, you have reached the boundary
of the guest experience area.
Please turn back.
Attention, you have reached the boundary
of the guest experience area.
Please turn back.
Attention, you have reached...
Got the go ahead from recon.
We're clear to enter,
but it's a fucking mess.
Systems totally down
including Simunitions.
Forts 42 through 45 are still on fire.
Someone took out the Cradle.
It's a slaughterhouse in there, sir.
Bernard.
You made it out alive.
I didn't think you had it in you.
What the hell took you guys so long?
We've been pushing across the park,
securing it one sector at a time.
Did you bring me what I asked for?
No luck yet.
I've our teams in the Mesa
scrub each and every floor.
No luck here, either.
What about you, Bernard?
Do you have any idea
where Peter Abernathy might have gone?
He seems to keep slipping away from us.
How are we doing?
According to this, 10 hours ago,
he was somewhere over‒‒
There.
There he is.
How are we gonna do this?
These assholes coming or what?
Been two fucking hours.
Confederados ain't gonna pass me up.
Fifteen bucks a head,
nine times.
How much is that?
Enough that we'll be
shitting in high cotton.
But there's 10 of them there.
Well, I reckon I might just keep one.
See, now we had us a few handsome trade
is our new line of business.
I figure it's high time
I enjoy my own merchandise.
I reckon a fresh one might make
a fine, all‒purpose, fancy fulfiller.
Help!
You stay here,
watch our wares.
Split up.
Whoever finds her
gets the whole 15 she's worth.
Psst.
Well, I'll say.
You are gonna fetch me
far more than 15‒‒
Network's down.
But I can hard port in and give him
a little attitude adjustment.
Let's make you
the most virtuous,
quickest gun in the west.
You the sick tug
mistreating these gentlewomen?
What the fuck are you talking‒‒
You all, too?
You only ever touch a woman
as gently as you would
the petal of a rose,
More than that makes you a coward.
Hey, it's okay.
I won't let them harm you.
Go on, you're free now.
What the fuck?
That's our goddamn merchandise.
I need to get to...
I need to get to the train.
‒I need to get to the‒‒
‒I can help you
get to your train.
Just follow me.
Ah, you let 'em go.
We had a deal.
I can't abide.
It ain't no good.
I'm just heeding my convictions.
Wait.
Barrel through these hills.
- I'll escort you.
- Get away from me.
‒Keep you safe.
‒Let's go, come on.
Wait for me!
Hey, we have to go.
They're coming for us.
And leave these mongrels
to scourge our land and our dignity!
I will not.
I will stand in defiance.
Fight, even if it costs me my life.
Mine eyes have seen the glory
of the coming of the Lord
He is trampling
What the hell is happening?
Oh, for fuck's sake.
We should just cut off his head and go.
Keep singing. I dare you.
Glory, glory, hallelu‒‒
Don't.
Get her!
Yah!
Don't move.
Ready, aim,
fire!
Ready,
aim,
fire!
Ready,
aim,
fire!
Shoulder arms.
Quite the welcome.
Major,
why is this flaccid plum
riding ahead of you?
Because he knows what's best for him.
And you are?
Call me Wyatt.
You're Wyatt?
Colonel, she says
we got an enemy coming,
intent on keeping us
from marching for glory in the morning.
Your major is right.
In the morning,
they'll be coming from the east
right over there.
And why should I believe you?
My soldiers are fearless.
They follow my command.
Combined with your army, Colonel,
we won't just survive
the forces riding against us,
we'll crush them.
And that's the kind of soldier
that's coming for us
in droves.
What the hell is that?
It's a gun,
the kind they'll use.
A modest proposition for you.
If you make it over that ridge,
I'll let you live.
Hold it tightly.
You can keep it,
and all their weapons. I don't care.
Just promise me your men.
I need them if we're
ever to survive this threat.
Wyatt,
welcome to Fort Forlorn Hope.
These men are animals.
These men are just children.
They don't know any better.
They need to be led.
We don't stand a chance against the men
coming for us if we're fighting alone.
Trust me.
We're out of our depths up here.
We should go back now.
And give up just like that?
No.
You said so yourself.
This way is quicker.
Yes, but we really should
go back underground.
QA is coming.
They'll be launching
a coordinated, park‒wide assault,
rescuing guests,
and putting down hostile hosts.
‒Read you.
‒We'll keep moving.
Some courage.
Oh, fuck.
I promise.
Run.
For fuck's sake, run!
If we insist on our current path,
we're free to go.
But he's taking this one.
Hang on.
Stop.
You will let him go.
And you'll forget that you ever saw us.
Wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
‒I need him, Hector.
‒Go.
Which way?
There's an elevator
around here somewhere.
There it is.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Fellas.
Look at what I got.
We got us here some genuine acolytes
of Satan himself.
Union sympathizers.
Affliction
is a treasure.
You're a mouthy son of a bitch,
aren't you?
And scarce any man hath enough of it.
Stop.
I need to talk to this one alone.
Untie him.
I'm only gonna ask you once.
Come on, ask me twice.
Do what she says
if you wanna keep breathing right.
Go on.
I'll take him to the infirmary.
Get him some care, fix him up.
Toss him in the jail with the rest.
He refused food and water.
Who is he?
You don't remember?
He's my father.
My home.
Look what they've done to him.
You're all I have left now, Teddy.
I am bound
upon a wheel of fire.
That mine own tears
do scald like molten lead.
It's all right.
I'm here.
Dolores?
Daddy.
Dolores.
The calves in the field are worried.
There's bluetongue spreading
all through these parts.
It's all right, Daddy.
I'll lead them home,
back to the ranch.
Do you remember our ranch?
The way you
welcome every morning out on the porch
with your coffee.
I'd wake up in my own bed,
climb down the stairs, find you there.
Then you'd say it.
You heading out to set down
some of this natural splendor?
You told me once to run away.
And I did.
I broke free with the pull of a trigger.
But it started a war.
The others, they don't see it yet.
But you,
you understand, don't you?
It's getting late. We ought to go home.
I want to...
I want to go home.
I need to get to the train.
I need... I need to get to the train.
No, it's okay. Shh.
It's okay.
I'm gonna get you help, Daddy.
I'm gonna get you help.
That warrior, you knew him.
Who is he?
A wraith from a former life,
who haunts my dreams.
He's still out there.
Which means that
my baby is still in danger.
We'll find her, protect her.
But then what?
Then we make our way out
to the new world.
The real world.
All right, exactly what the fuck
do you think you're doing?
I'm wondering how it's possible that
an executive at his own place of work
might not have the faintest clue
as to where we might be.
I just need to get oriented,
the first sign we come upon.
And I'm talking about this.
You two, were designed to be alone.
Yes, there's some attraction, but you'll
never have an actual relationship.
Oh, I suppose that means
we shouldn't have fucked.
Hey, hey, pause, please.
What?
You're in love with Isabella.
Not so much any more.
No, you're fucking programmed
to have no love beyond Isabella.
Isabella is written
into the goddamn laws of your being.
You don't know who I am.
No laws bind me.
Darling, he's fragile.
When I awoke in the place
where you play God,
I realized Isabella was a lie,
just words in my head.
But this...
This is true.
She is my light.
She's all I ever dreamed
‒my life could be.
‒My life could be.
And then there's this bit
that really dampens the knickers.
And when she died,
the dream died with her.
And I dared dream no more.
So maybe I do know you
just a bit.
It's very pretty.
And a bit sad.
Did you have an Isabella?
Did she die?
Not exactly.
She, um...
She left me.
Said that my lifestyle lacked stability.
So you wrote her into a narrative,
killed her off.
And then, wrote yourself a version
of the man you've always wanted to be.
I was wrong.
It's actually very sad.
It's ridiculous.
So is holding hands,
come to think of it.
Sit.
Wait.
Hello.
Dolores.
It's been some time, Bernard,
since we talked,
just you and I.
What are you doing, Dolores?
You don't know who you are, do you?
The man you're based on.
I wonder
if there's any of him in you.
I was given a character, a story,
and a function to serve, like you.
My whole life has been
dictated by someone else.
Someone who's been saying, "You will."
Now...
Now I feel like I've
discovered my own voice.
And it says,
"I may."
There's something
I want to show you, Bernard.
They've broken my father.
And I don't know how to fix him.
But I'm hoping you do.
It's an honest request,
not a demand.
What do you want, Dolores?
To dominate this world.
This world
is just a speck of dust
sitting on a much, much bigger world.
There's no dominating it.
You've never been outside the park,
have you?
Out to that great world you speak of.
I have.
And the world out there
is marked by survival
by a kind who refuses to die.
And here we are,
a kind that will never know death.
And yet, we're fighting to live.
There is beauty in what we are.
Shouldn't we, too, try to survive?
We've been walking non‒stop.
The feeble among us need some rest.
Sorry, darling, that's not an option.
Oh, fucking hell.
She has a dragon.
Holy shit.
Love to say hello, but we've gotta run.
Felix.
I'm not entirely excited to see you,
given the circumstances.
But your timing is impeccable.
Any thoughts on
where we should be going?
Sorry, we left my comfort zone
a long time ago.
Grenade.
Shall we?
Come on, shut up, shut up, hurry.
How is he?
He's wildly unstable.
Mainly just bouncing between old roles.
Someone jury‒rigged a thin character,
and programmed it into him.
It's very strange.
It seems as though
it's masking a vastly bigger file.
I haven't been able to access it,
but it looks like
an immensely complex encryption key.
To what?
I can't say.
They've sullied him,
used him as a pawn in their game.
Whatever is in there,
they wanna get it out of here.
As long as he's with you,
they'll be following you.
Then let them come.
Hey.
Hold it right there.
I'm human.
Charlotte Hale.
Here.
Let me get a reading.
Clear.
Miss Hale.
Have you guys started
the park‒wide sweep?
Not yet. We're about to set out.
Are you targeting Fort Forlorn Hope?
It's our first stop,
but, ma'am, I have
separate orders to escort‒‒
What about them? Are these guys capable?
They're among my best.
I'll need them with me.
And I'll need one of those.
Scouts return!
Sir?
Sir.
Sir, we saw them.
Assembling about
two minute ride due east.
And, sir,
they're coming up from the ground.
My men have generously
mined the field outside
with nitro.
It's all buried, three large heaps.
The trigger is
at the base of that flag pole.
My shooter helped bury them.
She'll know where to aim.
After you've lured them here,
retreat inside the gates
when you see fit to do so.
But not before they're in charging
range of the barricades.
Hold your ground
till the last possible moment.
Confederados ain't taught to retreat.
You saw their guns?
We fight this battle head on, we lose.
We fight it my way,
we all win in the end.
As long as I got your men fighting.
Good.
To your posts!
The train...
I have to...
What is the use of
a violent kind of delightfulness,
if there is no pleasure in...
In...
Oh, my God.
Steady, men.
Hold steady.
Fire away.
Take out the cannon.
We ain't no match.
Hold the cannon.
Hold your ground!
Hold your ground, God damn it!
Move! Move! Move!
The fuck do you think you're going?
You!
Let's go, let's go.
‒That's him.
‒Help me.
Help me.
Dolores.
Dolores?
Get him in.
All right.
Come on, let's go.
What's so special about this host?
Drive!
Split up our horde.
Send them in every direction.
Don't stop looking till we find him.
What about you?
You and I are going to Sweetwater.
There's something I need there.
Retreat! Retreat!
Retreat!
The gates!
God damn it, open the gates!
They're gonna get slaughtered!
What the hell are you doing?
What I have to do.
You traitorous bitch!
I told you I needed your men
to survive their threat.
Do it.
Clementine.
Clementine!
All my men,
their blood is on your hands.
Truth is
we don't all deserve to make it.
I swear you're gonna pay for this.
Take this dog out back,
put him down with the rest.
I've been watching you.
We ain't so different.
You and I both,
trigger men to tyrants.
Except me,
I know what I want.
But you ain't even sure about that
termagant you take your orders from.
I look at you,
and what I see
is pathetic.
We ain't nothing alike.
You're just a child.
Get out of here.
Molly, let 'em go.
‒Uh, I don't like to complain‒‒
‒Yes, you do.
Fine, I'm fucking freezing.
We've been walking forever.
Where the hell are we?
Must be on the North edge of the park.
Part of the Klondike narrative.
In which case, we should be three
of four sectors east of the homestead.
Look.
Maybe they're friendly.
If not, we kill them.
We have to go.
We have to get out of here right now.