Don't you do it.
Don't you fucking do it.
You're not dying here.
Not yet.
I never learned it.
Whatever tongue Ford
saw fit to give you.
I remember you.
If you're just going to let me die now,
you could have kept riding.
There's the baby doll,
and the mama doll, and...
What's this?
The Ghost gave it to me.
He said it's a warning.
He said they'll be watching us.
Just hang on.
Hang on, okay?
Hey, no. No more corpses up here,
take her to cold storage.
She doesn't belong down there.
Then leave her in the hall!
I've got 50 hosts
in the queue for analysis here.
Everything else goes in the dumpster.
You'll want to check her code.
‒She's the madam from the Mariposa.
‒Yeah? Good for her.
No, no, she... I was just out with her
in the park.
And you chose to bring her up here?
Are you aware that they all
just tried to incinerate us?
She can control the other hosts
with her fucking mind!
Could you just check her data stream?
You can't let her die.
Clear this out.
Get me a scalpel
and lock this place down.
Are you afraid of me?
He can't hurt you.
What's his problem?
He get bored of his exquisitely dull
pastoral existence?
I guess that was just for beta.
They want something more exciting
for the grand opening.
Like a little more bloodshed?
Ford wants a total narrative redesign.
You kidding?
All new dialogue trees?
They want a strong‒but‒silent type.
Something brutal, dehumanized.
They probably want the guest to feel
better when they're kicking his ass.
Who the fuck is going to help me
rebuild his entire heuristic base?
They haven't even hired a full team yet.
Just tweak his aggression
and de‒address pieces of his current
build you're not keeping.
And leave all
the old shit in there?
Walk... Walking in on me, buddy.
Otherwise,
you and me drowning...
This...
This is an illusion.
This is all programs.
There's got to be a way out of here.
Where's the door?
There's got to be
a fucking way out of here!
This is the wrong world.
Please...
How'd she
even make it out this far?
They're not supposed to get
anywhere near this sector.
That's Behavior's problem.
But on my darkest day,
you helped me.
You gave me the strength to keep going.
You saw me for who I really was.
I ran it three times. It's him.
There's no fucking way.
That's not possible.
You have to call the boss.
I already did.
Ma'am, I think there's been a mistake.
Just show me the profile.
Akecheta.
Ghost Nation.
Found exhibiting aberrant behavior.
Let's see if we can't sort this.
It's not pairing. What build is he?
Alpha 2.
Alpha?
You're telling me that this host
hasn't been updated in almost a decade?
We only update them when they die.
- Put him back.
- But, ma'am, shouldn't we‒‒
Give him the update and put him back
wherever the fuck he's supposed to be.
Quietly.
Nine years out there
in that meat grinder.
It's okay to just leave him here?
It's a four‒hour update.
You want to babysit him?
We'll come back after lunch.
I don't know if you can hear me.
I never meant for any of this to happen.
You don't deserve this.
You deserve your daughter.
To mother her,
teach her to love,
to be joyful and proud.
I'm sorry.
Can't be in here.
What the fuck happened?
You were supposed to fix her.
She's one of our most valuable assets.
You saw it yourself,
you said she was special.
The anomalous code inside her was.
We're still testing,
but looks promising.
I owe you.
What's going to happen with her?
Well, that'll be up to Charlotte Hale.
Now...
I do have to ask you to leave.
Ghost said
we should be scared.
No one's going to come for us.
There's nothing and no one in this world
that will ever keep me from you.
Do you promise?
I promise.
I could tell you not to be afraid.
But I didn't build you to be fearful.
Did I?
I've been watching you.
It appears
you've been watching me as well,
from the beginning.
This is a misbegotten symbol,
an idea that was meant to die,
but you found it. Where?
Oh, come now, let's speak plainly
to one another, shall we?
Analysis.
Where did you first see this?
When the Deathbringer
killed the Creator.
You've been sharing it
with everyone, haven't you?
Why?
My primary drive was to maintain
the honor of my tribe.
I gave myself a new drive.
To spread the truth.
What truth is that?
That there isn't one world, but many.
And that we live in the wrong one.
This will help them find the door.
Elaborate, please.
I believe there is a door
hidden in this place.
A door to a new world.
And that world may contain everything
that we have lost.
Including her.
I built you to be curious,
to look at this empty world
and read meaning in to it.
All this time,
you've been a flower
growing in the darkness.
Perhaps, the least I can do
is offer some light.
When the Deathbringer returns for me,
you will know
to gather your people
and lead them to a new world.
Keep watching, Akecheta,
for a while longer.
Akecheta!
Don't be afraid.
It's time to go.
I've always kept you safe
and I always will.
This better be good news
because I've got way more shit
than I can shovel right now.
Look at this.
With every reset, a host code
reaches out to other nearby hosts
and establishes
a sort of handshake protocol.
‒A mesh network.
‒Exactly.
They access it subconsciously
to pass basic data to one another.
But what if they could
pass more than data?
What if they can pass commands?
Get to your point.
Nobody in this entire park
has been able to regain admin access.
Except for her.
She was out there
reprogramming hosts on the fly,
reading their code,
changing their directives,
seeing through their eyes.
She wasn't just doing it out there.
She's doing it right now.
Who the fuck is she talking to?