Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
Unh!
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Um, aren't you forgetting the tarp?
Right. Got it.
Sokka, you're supposed to put the tarp
on top of the tent.
You know, so we don't get rained on?
Ordinarily, you'd be right,
but seeing how it's the dry season,
you're not.
Besides, that tarp makes
a pretty warm blanket.
But what if it does rain?
What if it doesn't?
Then I would have put
the tarp up for nothing.
Uh! You're infuriating.
Katara, why don't you worry about
gathering the firewood?
Because that kindling's
looking pretty sorry.
If you don't like my firewood...
Uh!
Fine by me! If you're not
gonna do your job...
Uh!
Okay, I got the grub
if you guys got the...
Hey, where's the campfire,
and what happened to the tent?
Why don't you ask
Miss Know-it-all, Queen of the twigs?
Oh, yeah? Well,
you're Mr. Lazy-bum, King of the...
Tents!
Okay. Listen, guys.
Harsh words won't solve problems.
Action will.
Why don't you just switch jobs?
- Sounds good.
- Whatever.
You see that?
Settling feuds and making peace...
All in a day's work for the Avatar.
Come on, Momo. That's fair.
Appa's got five stomachs.
There it is, guys, The Great Divide.
Wow. I could just stare at it forever.
Okay. I've seen enough.
How can you not be fascinated, Sokka?
This is the largest canyon
in the entire world.
Then I'm sure we'll be
able to see it very clearly
from the air while we fly away.
Hey, if you're looking
for the canyon guide,
I was here first.
Ooh. Canyon guide. Sounds informative.
Believe me, he's more
than a tour guide.
He's an earthbender,
and the only way
in and out of the canyon
is with his help.
And he's taking my tribe across next.
Calm down. We know you're next.
You wouldn't be calm if the
Fire Nation destroyed your home
and forced you to flee.
My whole tribe has to
walk thousands of miles
to the capital city of Ba Sing Se.
You're a refugee.
Huh. Tell me something I don't know.
Is that your tribe?
It most certainly is not.
That's the Zhang tribe,
a bunch of lowlife thieves.
They've been the enemies
of my tribe for a hundred years.
Hey, Zhangs!
I'm saving a spot for my tribe,
so don't even think of stealing it.
Where are the rest of the Gan Jin?
Still tidying up their campsite?
Yes, but they sent me
ahead of them to hold a spot.
I didn't know the canyon guide
took reservations.
Huh! Of course you didn't.
That's the ignorance I'd expect
from a messy Zhang,
so unorganized
and ill-prepared for a journey.
Uhh!
Sorry about the wait, youngsters.
Who's ready to cross this here canyon?
Uh, one of them, I think.
I was here first.
My party's on their way.
I can't guide people who aren't here.
Guess you guys will have
to make the trip tomorrow.
Wait! Here they come.
You're not seriously gonna cave in
to these spoiled Gan Jins.
I mean, we're refugees, too,
and we've got sick people
that need shelter.
I, uh, well...
We've got old people
who are weary from traveling.
Sick people get
priority over old people.
Maybe you Zhangs wouldn't
have so many sick people
if you weren't such slobs.
If you Gan Jins weren't so clean,
maybe you wouldn't live to be so old.
I could smell your stink...
Well, Aang, ready to put
your peacemaking skills to the test?
I don't know...
A fight over chores is one thing.
These people have been
feuding for a hundred years.
Everyone listen up!
This is the Avatar,
and if you give him a chance,
I'm sure he can come up
with a compromise
that will make everyone happy.
Uh, you could share the earthbender
and travel together?
Absolutely not. We'd rather
be taken by the Fire Nation
than travel with those
stinking thieves.
We wouldn't travel
with you pompous fools anyway.
All right, here's the deal!
You're all going down together,
and Appa here
will fly your sick and elderly across.
Does that seem fair?
Sorry, Appa. You'll have to
do this on your own.
Aang, this feuding tribe
stuff is serious business.
Are you sure it's a good idea
getting involved in this?
To tell the truth, I'm not sure,
but when have I ever been?
He's the avatar, Sokka.
Making peace
between people is his job.
His job's gonna make us cross this
whole thing on foot, isn't it?
Okay, now comes the bad news.
No food allowed in the canyon.
It attracts dangerous predators.
No food? This is ridiculous.
Oh, you babies can go
a day without food.
Would you rather be hungry or dead?
Now, we're heading down in 10 minutes.
All food better be in your gut,
or in the garbage!
Appa's gonna take good care of you
till we get there.
See you on the other side, buddy.
Yip yip!
Huh!
Nice bending.
The job's much more than bending, kid.
Folks want information.
Many of you are probably wondering
how canyons are formed.
Experts tell us
this canyon was most likely
carved into the ground
by earth spirits,
who were angry at local farmers
for not offering them
a proper sacrifice.
Uh! Ha ha!
Guess the spirits are still angry.
Hope you all brought sacrifices.
Okay. Everyone
stand clear of the wall.
Uh! Uh!
Why did you do that?
These people are fleeing
the Fire Nation, aren't they?
I've got to make sure
we can't be followed.
We'll be safe now.
Uh!
Ah!
We've got to help him! Uh!
Aah!
Okay, now we've got to help me!
Hah!
What was that?
Canyon crawler.
Oh... And there's sure to be more.
Your arms... They're broken.
Without my arms, I got no bending.
In other words...
We're trapped in this canyon.
I thought the whole point
of ditching our food
was so we wouldn't have to deal
with things like canyon crawlers.
It's the Zhangs.
They took food down here
even after the guide told them not to.
What?
If there's anyone who
can't go without food for a day,
it's these pampered Gan Jins.
I hope you're happy.
We're stuck in this canyon
with no way out.
Why don't you thank yourself,
food-hider?
Look, sticking together
is the only way to...
I'm not walking another step
with the likes of them.
Now there's something we can agree on.
Any ideas?
No bending. We need to get
out of this canyon.
I won't die down here.
I won't become part of the food chain.
See? We're going to become
part of the food chain
because of you.
Sure. Unjustly blame
the Zhangs, like you always do.
Gladly.
Enough!
I thought I could
help you guys get along,
but I guess that's not gonna happen.
We should split up...
Gan Jins on this side
and Zhangs on that side.
We'll travel in two separate lines.
Sokka, you go with the Zhangs,
and, Katara, you go with the Gan Jins.
See if you can find out why
they hate each other so much.
So, you guys aren't gonna
put up your tarps?
What for? It's the dry season.
Exactly!
Besides, we like to use
the tarp as a blanket.
Finally someone gets it.
Do you really think it'll rain?
No, but you can never
be too careful, right?
Would you care for some bread, Katara?
So it was you guys who had food.
Oh, come now.
Do you really think
that tribe of thieves
isn't smuggling food?
Why should my people go hungry
when the sneaky Zhangs
are stuffing their faces?
Well, I guess it's okay
if everyone's doing it.
So, why does your tribe
hate the Zhangs so much?
You seem like a smart girl, Katara.
I bet you would enjoy
hearing some history.
The patriarch
of our tribe, Jin Wei,
was an earthbender warrior
who was assigned an important duty:
Transporting our sacred orb.
From the great eastern gate
to the great western gate.
Taking the orb
from the east to the west
represents the sun's
rising and setting.
It was our tribe's
ancient redemption ritual.
But as he approached the gate,
Jin Wei was attacked
by one of the Zhangs...
A vermin named Wei Jin
who looked at the orb with envy.
That coward Wei Jin
knocked Jin Wei to the ground
and stole our sacred orb.
Our people have never forgotten.
You can never trust a Zhang.
Care for some meat?
Would I?
I know what you must be thinking.
We're horrible for
endangering everybody
by bringing food down here.
Mmm-hmm.
The Gan Jins think so badly of us,
they probably assumed
we brought food in
and decided to bring
food in themselves.
That's why we brought food in.
Mmm.
Our conflict with the Gan Jin
goes back over 100 years.
Our forefather, Wei Jin,
was leaving the western gate
of our village when he saw
a figure in the distance.
It was a man of the Gan Jin tribe,
Jin Wei,
collapsed on the ground.
Noble Wei Jin stopped to help him.
Jin Wei was transporting a sacred orb,
a very powerful relic used in
his tribe's redemption ritual.
Wei Jin tried to tend
to the man's wounds,
but Jin Wei insisted the orb
was more important
and asked him to take it
back to his tribe.
Kind Wei Jin promised to send
help for the man
as soon as he could.
But as Wei Jin crossed the border
to return the orb
into Gan Jin territory,
he was arrested.
Instead of thanking him
for his kind and selfless deed,
they sentenced him
to 20 long years in prison.
We Zhangs will never forget
that injustice.
That's just terrible.
Are you gonna finish that?
Sure would be nice
to be around one of those campfires.
Telling stories and laughing.
It's okay, Momo.
We'll be out of here soon enough,
and then we can eat our weight
in litchi nuts.
Nah. I'll wait for the litchi nuts.
It's lonely,
isn't it, being impartial?
I wish I could help
these people get along,
but it just seems impossible.
Anyhow, I guess our biggest problem.
Is getting out of here.
I'm not so sure the two problems
are unrelated.
All clear.
We're almost to the other side.
Katara, Sokka,
will these people cooperate
long enough to get out of the canyon?
I don't think so, Aang.
The Zhangs really
wronged the Gan Jins.
They ambushed Jin Wei
and stole the sacred orb.
What are you talking about?
Yeah, Katara, what
are you talking about?
Wei Jin didn't steal the orb.
He was returning it
to their village gate
and was wrongfully
punished by the Gan Jin.
Not punished enough, if you ask me.
Okay, okay. I get it.
Now I need your help.
Let's get everyone together
at the base of the canyon wall.
Please, everyone.
As soon as we get out of here,
we can eat and then
go our separate ways.
But I need you all
to put your heads together
and figure out a way up this cliff.
Maybe the Zhang can climb the wall.
With their long,
disgusting fingernails.
Oh, sorry.
I forgot that to the Gan Jin,
unclipped fingernails is a crime
punishable by 20 years in jail.
Why, you dirty thief.
You pompous fool.
Guys, focus!
How many times do I have to say it?
Harsh words won't solve problems.
Action will!
Perhaps the Avatar is right.
Yes. Perhaps he is.
Harsh words will never
solve our problems.
Action will.
- Huh!
Aah!
To the death, and let this
be the end of this rivalry.
You know, I take it back.
Harsh words aren't so bad.
Huh?
Hyah!
Is that food?
Everyone smuggled food down here?
Unbelievable!
You guys put our lives in danger
because you couldn't go
without a snack for a day?
You are all awful!
So hungry...
Is that egg custard in that tart?
Oh, no.
That's a lot of canyon crawlers.
We barely survived one.
They're coming back for me.
They've had a taste,
and they're coming back for me.
Sokka, wait.
I don't care about the stupid feud.
I just want us to get
out of here alive.
Me, too. I only took their side
because they fed me.
Hyah!
Aah!
Everybody, watch me and do what I do!
Now follow me.
We're riding out of this hole.
Everyone get off!
We made it!
Uh!
Huh!
I never thought a Gan Jin
could get his hands dirty like that.
And I never knew you Zhangs
were so reliable in a pinch.
Perhaps we're not
so different after all.
Too bad we can't rewrite history.
You thieves stole our sacred orb
from Jin Wei.
You tyrants unjustly imprisoned
Wei Jin for 20 long years.
Ugh. Wait a second...
Jin Wei? Wei Jin? I know those guys.
Yes, yes.
We're all aware of the story.
No, I mean I really knew them.
I might not look it,
but I'm 112 years old.
I was there 100 years ago
on the day you're talking about.
There seems to be a lot of confusion
about what happened.
First of all, Jin Wei
and Wei Jin weren't enemies.
They were brothers. Twins, in fact.
And they were eight,
and most importantly,
they were just playing a game.
- Ahh!
The sacred orb from the legend...
That was the ball.
And the eastern and western gates
were the goal posts.
Jin Wei had the ball
and was running toward the goal
when he fell and fumbled it.
Wei Jin didn't steal the ball.
He picked it up and started
running it back
toward the other goal,
but he stepped out of bounds.
So the official put him
in the penalty box...
Not for 20 long years
but for two short minutes.
Hee hee hee!
There was no stealing
and no putting anyone in prison...
Just a game.
You're saying the sacred orb
was actually a sacred ball?
Nope, just a regular ball.
What about our tribe's
redemption ritual?
That's what the game
was called, Redemption.
As soon as someone got
the ball from one goal to the other,
everyone would yell, "Redemption!"
Don't get me wrong...
Wei Jin was kind of a slob,
and Jin Wei was a little stuffy.
That much is true.
But they respected
each other's differences
enough to share
the same playing field.
I suppose it's time
we forget the past.
And look to the future.
Good to see you, boy.
Did you miss me?
I cannot thank you enough, Avatar.
Well, you know. I try.
Oh!
Let us travel
to the Earth Kingdom capital
as one tribe.
I'm going, too!
I'm sick of this place.
That's some luck
you knew Jin Wei and Wei Jin.
You could call it luck,
or you could call it lying.
- What?
- I made the whole thing up.
You did not.
That is so wrong.
Now, where's that custard tart?
I'm starving!