Water...
Earth...
Fire...
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world needed him most,
he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I
discovered the new Avatar,
an airbender named Aang,
and although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Wait till you see it, Katara.
The air temple
is one of the most beautiful places
in the world.
Aang, I know you're excited,
but it's been a hundred years
since you've been home.
That's why I'm so excited!
It's just that a lot can change
in all that time.
I know,
but I need to see it for myself.
Wake up, Sokka.
Air temple, here we come!
Sleep now. Temple later.
Sokka, wake up!
There's a prickle snake
in your sleeping bag!
Aah!
Get it off! Get it off!
Heh heh heh!
Great. You're awake.
Let's go.
Uncle, I want the repairs made
as quickly as possible.
I don't want to stay too long
and risk losing his trail.
You mean the Avatar?
Don't mention his name on these docks.
Once word gets out that he's alive,
every firebender
will be out looking for him,
and I don't want anyone
getting in the way.
Getting in the way of what,
Prince Zuko.
Captain Zhao.
It's commander now.
And General Iroh,
great hero of our nation.
Retired general.
The Fire Lord's brother and son
are welcome guests anytime.
What brings you to my harbor?
Our ship is being repaired.
That's quite a bit of damage.
Yes. You wouldn't believe
what happened.
Uncle, tell Commander Zhao
Yes, I will do that.
It was incredible.
What, did we crash or something?
Yes! Right into an Earth Kingdom ship.
Really?
You must regale me
with all the thrilling details.
Join me for a drink?
Sorry, but we have to go.
Prince Zuko,
show Commander Zhao your respect.
We would be honored to join you.
Do you have any ginseng tea?
It's my favorite.
Hey, stomach, be quiet, all right?
I'm trying to find us some food.
Hey! Who ate all
my blubbered seal jerky?
Oh. That was food?
I used it to start
the campfire last night.
Sorry.
You what?
Aww.
No wonder the flames smelled so good.
The Potola mountain range!
We're almost there!
Aang, before we get to the temple,
I want to talk to you
about the airbenders.
What about them?
Well...
I just want you to be prepared
for what you might see.
The Fire Nation is ruthless.
They killed my mother,
and they could have done the same
to your people.
Just because no one
has seen an airbender
doesn't mean the Fire Nation
killed them all.
They probably escaped.
I know it's hard to accept.
You don't understand, Katara.
The only way to get to
an airbender temple
is on a flying bison,
and I doubt the Fire Nation
has any flying bison.
Right, Appa?
Yip yip!
There it is,
the Southern Air Temple.
Aang, it's amazing!
We're home, buddy. We're home.
And by year's end,
the Earth Kingdom capital
will be under our rule.
The Fire Lord will finally claim
victory in this war.
If my father thinks
the rest of the world
will follow him willingly,
then he is a fool.
Two years at sea
have done little
to temper your tongue.
So, how's your search
for the Avatar going?
Uh... My fault entirely.
We haven't found him yet.
Did you really expect to?
The Avatar died a hundred years ago
along with the rest of the airbenders.
Unless you found some evidence
that the Avatar is alive.
No. Nothing.
Prince Zuko,
the Avatar is the only one
who can stop the Fire Nation
from winning this war.
If you have an ounce of loyalty left,
you'll tell me what you found.
I haven't found anything.
It's like you said...
The Avatar probably died
a long time ago.
Come on, uncle. We're going.
Commander Zhao,
we interrogated the crew
as you instructed.
They confirmed Prince Zuko
had the Avatar in custody
but let him escape.
Now remind me,
how exactly was your ship damaged?
So where do I get something to eat?
You're lucky enough
to be one of the first outsiders
to ever visit an airbender temple,
and all you can think about is food?
I'm just a simple guy
with simple needs.
So that's where my friends and I
would play airball,
and over there is where
the bison would sleep.
And...
What's wrong?
This place used to be full of monks
and lemurs and bison.
Now there's just a bunch of weeds.
I can't believe how much
things have changed.
So, uh,
this airball game... How do you play?
Ugh!
Ooh!
Ha ha ha!
Aang seven, Sokka zero.
Making him feel better
is putting me in a world of hurt.
Katara, check this out.
Fire Nation.
We should tell him.
Aang, there's something
you need to see.
Ok.
Oh!
What is it?
Uh... Just a new
waterbending move I learned.
Nice one. But enough practicing.
We have a whole temple to see.
You know,
you can't protect him forever.
Katara, firebenders were here.
You can't pretend they weren't.
I can for Aang's sake.
If he finds out that the Fire Nation
invaded his home,
he'll be devastated.
Hey, guys!
I want you to meet somebody.
Who's that?
Monk Gyatso,
the greatest airbender in the world.
He taught me everything I know.
But the true secret
is in the gooey center.
Hmm.
My ancient cake making technique
isn't the only thing on your mind,
is it, Aang?
This whole Avatar thing...
Maybe the monks made a mistake.
The only mistake they made
was telling you before you turned 16.
But we can't concern ourselves
with what was.
We must act on what is.
But, Gyatso,
how do I know if I'm ready for this?
Your questions will be answered
when you're old enough
to enter the air temple sanctuary.
Inside, you will meet someone
who will guide you on your journey.
Who is it?
When you are ready,
he will reveal himself to you.
Hmm.
Now...
Are you going to help me
with these cakes
or not?
All right.
One... Two...
Three.
Your aim has improved greatly,
my young pupil.
You must miss him.
Yeah.
Where are you going?
The air temple sanctuary.
There's someone I'm ready to meet.
But, Aang,
no one could have survived in there
for a hundred years.
It's not impossible.
I survived in the iceberg
for that long.
Good point.
Katara, whoever's in there
might help me figure out
this Avatar thing.
And whoever's in there
might have a medley
of delicious cured meats.
Ooh!
Unh!
Ohh.
I don't suppose you have a key.
The key, Sokka, is airbending.
Hello?
Anyone home?
So a 12-year-old boy
bested you and your firebenders.
You're more pathetic than I thought.
I underestimated him once,
but it will not happen again.
No, it will not,
because you won't
have a second chance.
Commander Zhao,
I've been hunting the Avatar
for two years, and I...
And you failed.
Capturing the Avatar is too important
to leave in a teenager's hands.
He's mine now.
Keep them here.
More tea, please.
Statues?
That's it?
Where's the meat?
Who are all these people?
I'm not sure.
But it feels like I know them somehow.
Look!
That one's an airbender!
And this one's a waterbender.
They're lined up in a pattern.
Air, water, earth, and fire.
That's the Avatar cycle.
Of course. They're Avatars.
All these people
are your past lives, Aang.
Wow! There's so many.
Past lives?
Katara, you really
believe in that stuff?
It's true.
When the Avatar dies,
he's reincarnated
into the next nation in the cycle.
Aang, snap out of it.
Huh?
Who is that?
That's Avatar Roku,
the Avatar before me.
You were a firebender?
No wonder I didn't trust you
when we first met.
There's no writing.
How do you know his name?
I'm not sure.
I just know it somehow.
You just couldn't get any weirder.
♪♪♪♪
Firebender.
Nobody make a sound.
You're making a sound.
Shh! Shh!
That firebender
won't know what hit him.
Lemur!
Dinner.
Don't listen to him.
You're gonna be my new pet.
Not if I get him first!
Wait! Come back!
I want to eat you!
Ha ha ha!
Aah! Unh!
Hey! No fair!
My search party is ready.
Once I'm out to sea,
my guards will escort you
back to your ship,
And you will be free to go.
Why? Are you worried
I'm going to try and stop you?
Ha ha ha!
You... Stop me?
Impossible.
Don't underestimate me, Zhao.
I will capture the Avatar before you.
Prince Zuko, that's enough.
You can't compete with me.
I have hundreds of warships
under my command,
And you,
you're just a banished prince.
No home, no allies.
Your own father doesn't even want you.
You're wrong.
Once I deliver
the Avatar to my father,
he will welcome me home with honor
and restore my rightful place
on the throne.
If your father really wanted you home,
he would have let you return by now,
Avatar or no Avatar.
But in his eyes, you are a failure
and a disgrace to the Fire Nation.
That's not true.
You have the scar to prove it.
Aah! Maybe you'd like one to match!
Is that a challenge?
An Agni Kai at sunset.
Very well.
It's a shame your father won't be here
to watch me humiliate you.
I guess your uncle will do.
Prince Zuko,
have you forgotten what happened
the last time you dueled a master?
I will never forget.
Hey! Come back!
Come on out, little lemur.
That hungry guy
won't bother you anymore.
Firebenders?
They were here?
Gyatso.
Hey, Aang, you find my dinner yet?
Aang, I wasn't really gonna
eat the lemur, ok?
Oh, man.
Come on, Aang.
Everything will be all right.
Let's get out of here.
Aang!
Send word
to the Fire Lord immediately.
The Avatar has returned.
Aang, come on!
Snap out of it! Aah!
Aah! Unh!
What happened?
He found out firebenders
killed Gyatso.
Oh, no. It's his Avatar spirit.
He must have triggered it.
I'm gonna try and calm him down.
Well, do it,
before he blows us off the mountain!
Remember your firebending basics,
Prince Zuko.
They are your greatest weapons.
I refuse to let him win.
This will be over quickly.
Basics, Zuko.
Break his root.
Unh!
Aah!
Do it!
That's it?
Your father raised a coward.
Next time you get in my way,
I promise,
I won't hold back.
Unh!
No, Prince Zuko.
Do not taint your victory.
So this is how
the great Commander Zhao
acts in defeat?
Disgraceful.
Even in exile,
my nephew is more honorable than you.
Thanks again for the tea.
It was delicious.
Did you really mean that, uncle?
Of course.
I told you ginseng tea is my favorite.
Aang, I know you're upset,
and I know how hard it is
to lose the people you love.
I went through the same thing
when I lost my mom.
Monk Gyatso and the other airbenders
may be gone,
but you still have a family.
Sokka and I, we're your family now.
Katara and I
aren't gonna let anything
happen to you.
Promise.
I'm sorry.
It's ok.
It wasn't your fault.
But you were right.
And if firebenders found this temple,
That means
they found the other ones, too.
I really am the last airbender.
Everything's packed.
You ready to go?
How is Roku supposed to help me
if I can't talk to him?
Maybe you'll find a way.
♪♪♪♪
Mm! Mm!
Looks like you made
a new friend, Sokka.
Can't talk. Must eat.
Hey, little guy.
You, me, and Appa...
We're all that's left of this place.
We have to stick together.
Katara, Sokka,
say hello to the newest
member of our family.
What are you gonna name him?
Momo.