Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
You have been found guilty
of breaking Aku law 1 01 and 203:
Habitation in an unauthorized facility...
...and unauthorized construction
of an escape vehicle.
Your punishment is extermination.
No! Don't!
WeII, according to my caIcuIations...
...our chances of escaping are now
6,352,27 1 -to-1 .
Oh, no! After aII these years,
to go back to work for Aku....
I can't do it!
-CaIm yourseIf, Frederick.
-Easy for you to say.
You were just a baby
when the rest of us...
...were forced to use
our scientific knowIedge...
...to buiId Aku's robot armies
and aIpha eviI technoIogy.
My age is irreIevant here.
We shouIdn't just give up.
We stiII have a chance.
ActuaIIy, there is substance to that theory.
If we Iaunch our escape rocket...
...before the faiI-safe warning head
informs Aku of our whereabouts...
...we wiII succeed.
On the other hand, Aku is quite briIIiant...
...and, knowing our position, wouId not onIy
send his ground troops to destroy us...
...but wouId aIso bIock our escape route,
forcing us to surrender.
GentIemen, the orbitaI guard has begun
to cIose in around our escape route.
You see?
There is no escaping now!
No! There has to be a way!
I humbIy apoIogize. It was not my
intention to bring these troubIes upon you.
Yes! It is aII your fauIt!
Come on! That's not fair.
We were bound to be discovered.
If anything, he saved our Iives.
Didn't you see the way
he beat those robots?
Yes. He was quite impressive.
The odds of one person with a sword
defeating three mantoids were 6923-to-1 .
HoId it, gentIemen.
I think we've found our soIution.
If we foIIow this warrior
through Aku's bIockade...
...he might create enough of a distraction
to give us a chance to sIip through.
That's impossibIe. No one can do that.
Let us surrender.
ActuaIIy, Frederick, the odds are promising.
It's onIy 5437-to-1 .
-Yes!
-This is quite a predicament.
On one hand, we have to trust a stranger
to battIe for the fate of our future.
On the other hand, the inevitabIe capture
by Aku and a Iifetime of sIavery.
-I say we give the stranger a shot.
-Yes!
This is aII pointIess.
He probabIy wouIdn't even do it.
Wait. I wiII gIadIy heIp.
But from what I understand,
your battIe is in the sky.
I am grounded. I cannot fIy.
Leave that to us.
Comrades, the odds have just improved.
Just hoId stiII, Jack.
This won't take Iong.
Okey-dokey. We're ready to go.
AII right. Everything Iooks good.
Let me expIain
your hand guidance-controI...
...system.
Send in the drones.
I am so excited.
Soon we shaII be at our new home.
We'II finaIIy be abIe
to use our science for good.
No more protection against the poIIuted air.
-No more Aku robots.
-Yeah. No more Aku.
Home.
What is wrong, friend?
Odds are 3-to-1 you shouId have fun.
I, too, desire to find my home.
You see, in days long past...
...where rockets and robots were
nowhere near creation...
...a young warrior forged
into battle with Aku.
At the point where victory was imminent...
...Aku tricked the warrior...
...and flung him from his own time
to a distant time in the future.
To reclaim his homeland
and undo the evil of Aku...
...the warrior has to find some sort
of time passage home.
Such a magic is difficult to find.
Is that warrior you?
-Yes.
-Wow!
Time traveI....
What do you say, gentIemen?
You know a way to traveI in time?
It's quite simpIe, reaIIy.
Let's say this is the rocket.
If you get into the escape pod
at the nose of the ship...
...and jettison when we hit sub-Iight speed,
that shouId put you at faster than Iight.
Which wiII easiIy send you
back to your own time.
-This wiII work?
-Oh, yes.
This theory is--
This theory is very sound.
Just make sure you're in the pod
before we hit Iight speed.
-The rest wiII take care of itseIf.
-I wiII.
WonderfuI!
So we're on for tomorrow morn--
Perhaps sooner.
Ladies and gentIemen,
we are entering Aku's bIockade.
They're going to Iaunch the first wave.
Better get Jack to the air Iock.
Don't forget, Jack, you must be in the pod
when we make the jump to warp drive.
The odds are quite staggering
against you if you are not in the pod.
-Good Iuck, Jack.
-Thank you.
Here comes the first wave.
T minus 1 2 before impact.
Five seconds untiI impact.
Jack, they're digging into the huII!
The tick droids are stiII digging through!
The fueI IeveI's dropping.
What's going on, Jack?
Jack, those are what
we Iike to caII guided missiIes!
-They appear to be withdrawing.
-We are approaching top speed.
Jack, forget them. Let's go.
Maximum veIocity wiII
be achieved in 1 .2 minutes.
StabiIizing retrorockets.
Standing by.
Jack, I'm going to Iock you in.
This is going to be quite a ride.
What is that?
Looks Iike the bugbots
are forming into a giant gun.
-Jack's unIocking!
-What?
What are you doing?
We're aImost at top speed.
The robots must not fire that gun.
The odds of them hitting us
at this speed are 325-to-1 .
I cannot take that chance.
But you'II never make it back in time!
Jack? Jack!
-Initiate the countdown!
-But what about Jack?
Darn it! There's no time!
[ENGLISH]