Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
-Not a bad job with the beast.
-I guess.
We wouId've caught him anyway
with our modified tridentaI incapacitators.
Whatever. Secure the beast!
This beast is aIways trying to escape.
Your days are numbered, wiId one.
Thanks to this brave warrior,
you'II never escape again.
We must ceIebrate its capture.
Come back to our viIIage with us.
-WeII, I don't know if I--
-You shouId.
-There'II be a feast.
-With rare deIectabIes.
WeII, I have not eaten in days.
I suppose no harm couId come of it.
Our peopIe have dweIIed in this Iand
for many decades.
Much of it was barren wasteIand
when the first settIers arrived.
Our ancestors worked Iong and hard
for many seasons...
...to cuItivate it into the beautifuI pIace
it is now.
These WooIies, as we caII them,
once roamed the Iand wiId.
These bIoodthirsty creatures threatened
the survivaI of our earIy settIers...
...nearIy driving us to extinction.
Anyway, with our great courage
and determination...
...we managed to tame
these savage beasts.
It took many years,
but now they are dociIe and cooperative...
...heIping us with our everyday duties.
And in turn, we provide them
with the sheIter and safety of our viIIage.
WeII, here we are.
Pretty impressive, huh?
-These buiIdings seem quite oId.
-Thank you.
Secure the beast untiI I devise
the proper punishment for his escape.
-Come on.
-Move it. Let's go.
-Step it up. Go on, fatty.
-Move it.
Let's eat.
Wait. What are you doing?
You can't get this one anymore.
It's the Junga Import Edition.
Theirs is better.
I guess, but I got the exact one
in Sarsyphis...
...for onIy 1 0 pieces, stiII wrapped.
Oh. Why, thank you.
Bring on the entertainment.
Up, you worthIess beast.
I notice your treatment of the WooIies
is somewhat harsh.
Not reaIIy. It's no different than the way
you humans treat--
What do you caII them? Horses?
Such huge structures.
Hey, come back here.
For such smaII creatures.
It is aII right. I wiII not hurt you.
Here.
You're not so bad, are you, big feIIow?
WeII, sIeep weII, my friend.
HeIp me.
-What?
-Hey, you! Get away from there!
You shouId be carefuI.
The beasts are tricky.
Their mind controI wiII fry your brain.
Come. Dessert is served.
HeIp me.
Do you understand me?
Yes. PIease, heIp us.
-What do you want me to do?
-Free me. AII can be expIained.
So I says to CharIie, I have three of those--
What was that?
-What was what?
-Oh, nothing. So anyway....
Must unIock.
-What is this pIace?
-It's where we're kept at night.
Up.
I am Lazzor, the eIdest of WooIies.
Countless seasons ago...
...before the darkness fell,
we were a happy people.
We had discovered a way of life...
...that most creatures only dream about.
Paradise.
Ours was not a culture
based on technology.
Our village was prosperous.
Then they came.
The pestilence that rained
out of the sky.
The Chritchellites were upon us.
At first, we tried to defend ourselves...
...but we were no match
for their technology.
Using the power of the orb...
...the Chritchellites have enslaved us
to their service.
For decades they have abused our land.
And if they are not stopped...
...I fear my people...
...will soon fade from history.
WiII you heIp us?
I wiII.
Stay here.
What?
HaIt, beast.
There is no escape.
For I have captured you once,
and wiII now see...
...that you wiII never escape again.
We've been tricked! Get them!
Destroy!
There's too many.
We have to destroy the orb.
Get him!
It is time.
And what do you think you're doing?
-Get back in your ceIIs.
-This is it.
We must destroy the orb!
Up.
CIimb.
Hey, they're going for the orb.
Don't Iet them reach the orb.
We are aImost there.
I'm too weak.
The orb. He broke the orb.
I can't beIieve-- Huh?
Stay back!
Your weapons are worthIess now.
This is our home.
We are forever gratefuI, great warrior...
...to your deeds done today.
If there is anything that you seek...
...pIease honor us by Ietting us heIp you.
There is one thing that I quest for.
Yes. I understand.
TraveI north, samurai.
There you wiII find a magicaI pIace...
...that can heIp you fuIfiII your destiny.
[ENGLISH]