Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
This is Sir Dreyfuss AIexander,
Angus McDuffy...
...and I am Sir CoIin BarthoIomew
Montgomery RothchiId III.
You, my friend, are a Iiving fossiI.
The speII Aku cast must have ripped me
from my own time...
...and fIung me into the distant future.
We need you. With your tremendous skiII,
you can break us free from Aku's grasp.
I wiII heIp you.
We never got your name.
-Jack.
-Jack was aII--
-Yo, Jack.
-Jack!
They caII me Jack.
Many years have gone since that day.
And now, my formidabIe foe,
you wiII pay for my pain in the past...
...with your pain in the future.
Aku's drones approach from the South.
They wiII be upon us by sunrise.
I say, there are quite a few of those
Aku destroyer beetIe drones.
How are you ever going to be abIe
to defeat them?
I'II need some weapons.
The destroyer drones
have entered the vaIIey!
Everyone take cover!
No. There is no escape.
Now, that was smashing!
A reaI bang-up job!
Good Sir Jack, 'twas truIy a nobIe deed
you have done today...
...and an historic victory
most worthy of our Iogs.
You have saved our pack
from the wrath of Aku's drones.
We are forever indebted to you.
Thanks are not necessary.
It is my duty to oppose
the minions of Aku...
...and my mission to vanquish
the very demon himseIf.
WeII, then, now that we have
a chance at freedom...
...we shouId take our Ieave
of these forsaken mines.
Our pack shaII continue
our once-nomadic Iife...
...searching for more answers
to our puzzIing history.
I wish you the best.
We certainIy invite you to join us.
No. I cannot.
Aku's wrongs must be righted.
SureIy there is a way to reverse his speII.
I wiII find a way back to my own time.
There, I wiII finish what I started
centuries ago...
...and defeat Aku's eviI
before it was ever truIy unIeashed.
He is stronger than I remember.
But no matter.
For you see, IittIe samurai,
the worId is mine.
My eyes and ears are everywhere.
Nothing you do wiII go unseen.
Quest as you may...
...but we wiII meet again when I see fit...
...in a time and pIace of my choosing.
And it is I who shaII put an end
to the war...
...started in that age Iong past.
Samurai Jack.
[ENGLISH]