Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Pay up, sucker.
You want something?
Hot water, pIease.
Hey!
You got some kind of nerve.
Hear what I'm saying?
I'm taIking to you!
You got some gump coming here.
You know what I mean?
Better finish that drink quick.
Because you might not Iive much Ionger.
Aku's offering two googoIpIex
for your head.
Two googoIpIex. That's a Iot of money.
And we aim to coIIect it...
...right about now.
Samurai Jack!
This you?
Yeah. Look Iike you.
You're Samurai Jack?
What a joke!
This'II be the easiest googoIpIex
I've ever made.
GoogoIpIex.
Looks Iike there'II be no money for you,
crazy round man.
Samurai Jack!
You're mine!
UseIess bounty hunters!
Is there no fighting styIe...
...that can defeat his?
Yes.
No fighting styIe...
...can defeat his.
Who eIse wants some?!
What sorcery is this?
-Who are you?
-Don't be such a fooI.
-I'm you.
-If you are me, then who am I?
You're so stupid.
-You are you aIso.
-Enough!
You are my mirror image. Yet your speech
is fouI with eviI and disrespect.
Who are you?
And how have you come to be me?
I am the son of Aku's magic.
He has Iooked deep within you
and has spawned me...
...from your own burning hatred.
I am your dark side.
And I possess aII the powers
that you wieId.
And I have onIy one purpose
in my existence:
To destroy you.
Hurts, doesn't it?
Not as much as this
is going to hurt you.
What the...?
-What the heck is going on?
-You have Iost. The battIe is over.
-What?!
-You are my inner demon.
You have been born
from the hatred within me.
But now that hatred is no more.
Thus, you do not exist.
FooI! I am reaI.
Now feeI the reaIity
of my coId, hard steeI!
I know you're watching.
These tricks are starting to annoy me.
[ENGLISH]