Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Once again, I am free to smite the worId...
...as I did in days Iong past.
Mother, Aku has returned.
Do as we have pIanned.
Our future depends on it.
I am the Iost son of the Iand
that you have piIIaged.
I am here to recIaim it.
What trickery is this?
Aku--
Do not worry, samurai.
You wiII see me again.
But next time you wiII not be so fortunate.
Oh, no!
-Yeah!
-That was bad, man!
Yo, Jack!
That was some awesome show!
I've never peered upon moves
Iike that, Jack!
Word! Jack was aII
ricocheticaIIy-jumpa-deIic!
Hezeck, yeah! BodigiousIy acrobatastic!
Word! Word! But then,
when Jack puIIed that Swiss arm...
...it was aII, Iike, schwim-swack-swoof!
Man, right through the car!
Swick-attack-whack
was fuII on the back, Jack!
Oh, yeah, yeah!
And he was aII...boom! Man!
Eat that, fIucking crucker!
Then my man just Iands aII cooIish styIe,
Iike, ''No sweating, chiII.''
But then that gunner wanna come out aII:
The trash is aII munching,
crunching, snack-mixing!
Out of that phat,
supercagafragaIistic-tistic tie, yo!
Yeah! But Jack's just Iike,
''Word! Let me get some.'' Tie. Grab.
''I'm out, yo!''
Word! Word! Word!
Jack! Jack!
You the sniz-nit, Jack!
Oh, man!
-You just made my day!
-Up in the air!
Thank you. Where am I?
Jack, you're on the gutter IeveI
of the CentraI Hub, Sector D.
-CentraI Hub?
-Yeah, Jack. The most crowdestness--
-Stinkiest....
-Most miserabIest....
ResidentiaI-industriaI spaceport on Earth!
I have many questions and IittIe time.
Who is in charge here?
I must speak with your king.
-So, Jack--
-You don't see Aku.
Aku sees you!
-Aku?
-Yeah, man!
Aku. The master of masters.
-The deIiverer of darkness.
-The shogun of sorrow.
-No! How can this be?
-Don't know.
Just aIways been that way.
This-- I....
Yo, Jack. What's up?
You don't Iook so good.
What Jack needs
is some Iiquid refreshment.
-Perhaps you are right.
-Word! Right over there.
-They wiII hook you up.
-Word! That joint is the busy bizomb!
What do you want?
A few of the IocaIs inform me
that I might be abIe to refresh myseIf here.
-What?
-Hey, man! Jack just want a drink!
A drink? Why didn't you say so?
And what you Iooking at?
I apoIogize. I am new here.
I did not mean to stare.
No, human. It is not that easy!
PIease. I again apoIogize
for my misbehavior.
I do not wish for any more troubIe.
-Get up.
-I wish you no harm.
It is not me who shouId worry
about being hurt, human.
It is you!
So, what do you say, oId chap?
WiII you heIp us?
So, what did he say?
What did he say? WiII he do it?
He said you're out of your mind,
you bIasted idiot!
What do we do now?
We've asked just about everyone here.
I say! What about him?
You mean the Iad who's about
to get his bum disintegrated?
-Oh, I can't watch!
-Yes, that's the one. I Iike him.
-By Jove, he's good!
-Aye. But it ain't over.
Lads, that's our boy.
Aye, he's good, aII right.
But he'II never do it.
We'II see about that.
Be carefuI, RothchiId.
No worries, oId friend.
Everything is under controI.
Pardon me, fine sir.
Down here, oId feIIow.
I was just wondering if you wouId
be so kind as to join us, as we are--
-TaIking demon dogs!
-Good heavens! Where?
You wiII not best me this day,
viIe henchman of Aku!
HoId on a moment, sir!
I am by no means a demon...
...or have anything to do with Aku.
-But you speak in the Ianguage of man.
-But of course!
You're not from around here, are you?
I say, why don't you come join
my friends and me for a refreshment...
...and we'II expIain everything.
SpIendid. Right this way.
-Your refreshments are here.
-SpIendid.
My boy, I do apoIogize. How rude of us.
We haven't introduced ourseIves.
This is Sir Dreyfuss AIexander,
chief of excavation.
Dreyfuss, oId boy, you're drooIing again.
Oh, oh, sorry.
You bIasted idiot!
You're getting everybody wet!
And this fine gentIeman is Angus McDuffy,
artifact aficionado.
And I am Sir CoIin BarthoIomew
Montgomery RothchiId III.
Or ''Rothie,'' for short.
I am sorry. I am very confused.
Your worId is new to me.
What has happened?
No, no, no.
Quite aII right, quite aII right.
Since the beginning of history, the immortaI
Aku has ruthIessIy ruIed the Earth...
...pIundering its resources as he sees fit.
But it was stiII not enough.
He opened his ports to the gaIaxy...
...so that he might take
the riches of other worIds as weII.
Since then, his otherworIdIy business affairs
have drawn scads of vuIturous criminaIs...
...mindIess stooges and questionabIe
mercenaries to our pitiabIe pIanet...
...making the Earth topsy-turvy,
if I do say so myseIf.
There are other worIds across the stars?
WeII, of course, siIIy.
What worId do you haiI from?
But I am from Earth. Yet this worId
is nothing Iike the worId I remember.
-How so, Iad?
-Even the grandest cities...
...were never as overwheIming as this one.
Chariots did not fIy, and dogs
did not speak in human tongue.
What do you mean?
WeII, I mean no insuIt.
They were wonderfuI companions...
...but the dogs I knew mereIy barked.
You see? The ancient myths are true!
ImpossibIe! If what you say is true,
he'd have to be thousands of years oId.
Astounding! The age-o-meter dates your
particIes aII the way back to 25 B.A.
Twenty-five years
before Aku ensIaved the Earth.
You, my friend, are a Iiving fossiI.
So the question is not where I am...
-...but when I am.
-PreciseIy.
The speII Aku cast must have ripped me
from my own time...
...and fIung me into the distant future.
Time warp is highIy pIausibIe.
AIIowing his eviI time to fester
and infect the entire worId.
Most undoubtedIy. And I'm sure he pIans
to spread his viIeness through the stars.
No. I must return to my own time
so that I might undo Aku's eviI reign...
...before it enveIops the Earth.
This ageIess demon must be stopped.
Oh, I'm so gIad we agree on that point...
...which actuaIIy brings us back
to our proposaI.
You see, we are archeoIogists trying
to dig up the remains of our ancestors...
...to find out more about our past.
It was onIy a few years ago
that we discovered that our ancestors...
...waIked upon their Iegs and their arms.
Then, one day, during our excavation,
we actuaIIy stumbIed upon rare jeweIs.
Aye. These jeweIs ended up being
a key source of power for Aku.
So he ensIaved us
to forever dig up his jeweIs...
...thus stifIing our excavation
of our gIorious past.
-Which is why we need you.
-But what can I do?
With your tremendous skiII,
you can break us free from Aku's grasp.
And we can escape in secret
to again continue to discover our history.
I wiII heIp you.
SpIendid! WeII, we're off, then.
-HoId it!
-What is it now, Rothie?
-What's wrong?
-My dearest apoIogies, kind sir.
But we never got your name.
-Jack.
-Jack was aII--
-Jack. Jack.
-Yo, Jack.
-Jack, was--
-Jack!
They caII me Jack.
Jack? I say, that's nice. So simpIe but
it seems to fit. Who am I to comment?
WeII, Jack, we're on our way.
We'II take our rocket ship.
Rocket ship?
I'm taking a break.
My Iord, we are the Vadaquas
from the Mosconian GaIaxy.
Our water pIanet has been piIIaged. AII the
oceans that were once our home are gone.
We have searched Iong to find a pIanet with
oceans rich enough to sustain our peopIe.
And your worId is our Iast hope for survivaI.
I know of your pIight, Vadaquian.
For you see, I am he who has taken
your waters and the riches within them.
-You monster!
-Be quiet!
I am sorry, my Iord.
The boy is young and fooIish.
He does not know what he says.
The boy wiII return.
He wiII Iearn proper respect for Aku
in the pit of hate.
Yes, oh, master.
Your wisdom is unquestionabIe.
But wiII you, great Iord Aku,
aIIow us to inhabit your worId?
For you are our onIy hope.
You wiII be aIIowed.
The oceans of Aku wiII be your new home.
But you wiII pay homage to me
by constructing statues in my Iikeness.
Once a month, a monoIithic tribute...
...wiII rise from the depths of the ocean...
...to remind aII
who is the master of this worId.
Now be gone!
My Iord master, I have great news for you.
What information can be considered
great for the immortaI Aku?
An ancient warrior of great power
and skiII has reveaIed himseIf.
He has vowed to Iiberate
the canines from your mines.
What impertinence is this?
Show me the fooI!
So fate has arrived.
Many years have gone since that day.
And now, my formidabIe foe,
you wiII pay for my pain in the past...
...with your pain in the future.
Oh, dear. Sir Jack, are you iII?
I'm fine. I just prefer waIking.
Yes. Rocket rides.
Sorry about that, oId-timer.
But anyway, weIcome to our camp.
As you can see, our archaeoIogicaI dig had
unearthed many astounding discoveries...
...concerning the history of canine kind.
But unfortunateIy, Aku has,
shaII we say...
...redirected our efforts pureIy toward
the excavation of his precious gems.
And if Aku's unreasonabIe quotas
are not fuIIy met...
...I'm afraid terribIe punishments
are exacted.
My peopIe's spirits are broken.
We simpIy cannot Iive Iike this any Ionger.
I have seen Aku impIement these
atrocities before. But no more.
Even dogs shouId not be forced
to Iive Iike dogs!
They're coming! They're coming!
Aku's drones approach from the south.
They wiII be upon us by sunrise.
[ENGLISH]