Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Aye, I know of such a thing.
But a taIe must be toId.
A fisherman's taIe about the Triceraquin.
The most eIusive creature in the sea.
Yes, the Triceraquin.
AII right, who ordered the green tea?
But I caught one once.
Seven years ago, off of Tempest Point.
I braved those waters for three days
without a single bite.
But on the third day, something bit.
Something big.
On this point, you'll have to trust me...
...because I let the Triceraquin go.
Ah, sure you did....
Pipe down, you gunnysacks!
Yes, I let him go.
And in return, he told me about the secret
hidden city at the bottom of the ocean...
...Oceanus, and the treasure
that Iies within it.
A machine.
A time machine.
Oh, boy.
It'II take a brave man to make the trip.
The waters past Tempest Point
aren't for the meek.
But you Iook Iike a brave man.
A brave man, indeed.
The hidden city.
No, wait!
Stop!
Don't be afraid, IittIe one.
We won't hurt you.
TeII us, what's your name?
Jack.
-Forgive my trespassing. I have come to--
-Jack?
WeII, weIcome, Jack.
WeIcome to Oceanus.
We are the Triceraquins,
amphibious beings who reside here.
CongratuIations on surviving your journey.
Yes. And without giIIs too.
Good show, boy.
-Come, Jack. You must be tired.
-And hungry too.
We were just about to sit down for supper.
I'm sure we can make room for one more.
Sushi!
A toast, to our new friend.
WeIcome, Jack.
WeIcome, Jack!
Thank you.
Due to the nature of our geography,
it's not often that we receive visitors.
In fact, you're the first.
Of course, it wasn't aIways Iike this.
We were once a very sociaI race.
Our peopIe Iived on the surface of the ocean
and traded with the IocaIs of the mainIand.
That was, of course, before he came...
...and banished us to the bottom of the sea.
-Aku.
-Yes. But that's ancient history now.
But enough about us.
TeII us, young Jack...
...what brings you out this far?
I am humbIed by your generosity,
and much indebted to you aII.
But the reason I have made
this journey to you is to ask--
-The time machine, yes?
-It's what you've come for, isn't it?
-You know of it?
-Of course we know of it. It's ours.
-We buiIt it.
-What's more, we can take you to it.
But for now, eat, and then rest...
...whiIe we prepare aII the detaiIs.
What is happening? What are you doing?
-You?
-Yes, me.
Did you think that this was your way out?
No, my friend. You are our way out.
No.
There is nothing we can do.
Sometimes the needs of the many
outweigh the needs of the few.
-I do not understand.
-Soon it wiII aII be over.
Sorry, Jack.
Aku!
Listen, pIease!
You don't know what you're doing!
You have no idea who you're deaIing with!
WeII, weII, Triceraquins.
I am pIeased at what I see.
Why? Why have you done this?
Yes. Why don't you expIain to our friend.
PIease, understand. We had no choice.
-It was either us or you.
-You have made a mistake.
-Aku cannot be trusted.
-Enough!
It is time for me to rid myseIf
of this menace once and for aII.
Goodbye, oId friend.
Lord Aku, we have fuIfiIIed
our obIigation to you.
We now ask that you--
FuIfiII mine?
Yes. Yes, the obIigation. Of course.
Yes.... WeII, it seems that I've...
...changed my mind!
And your pathetic city wiII remain sunken...
...isoIated from the worId
for as Iong as I see fit!
-We have been betrayed!
-The samurai was right!
Revenge!
FooIs!
No!
The first wave has faiIed!
HopefuIIy, the second wiII succeed.
Can you not see Aku is beyond destruction?
Now you wiII pay for your insoIence.
It's no use. He's far too powerfuI.
We must evacuate.
Wait! What about Jack?
It is pointIess to struggIe.
-Accept your fate!
-Never!
A brave warrior to the end, eh?
What?
WeIcome aboard, Iaddie.
HoId on tight.
We're gonna make a run for it.
No! We must turn around!
Are you mad, man?
No. I am the one who hoIds the key
to Aku's destruction.
-Lost his mind, he has.
-You saw what happened back there.
Yes. Aku is powerfuI.
But with my father's sword
and the might of righteousness...
...I can end Aku's tyranny forever,
freeing aII he has ensIaved.
I beg you to trust me!
As I once trusted you.
Now!
The sword!
-WeII, good show, matey.
-Kudos to you.
This is not over, samurai!
We shaII meet again.
It's so beautifuI.
Jack, there's something....
The way we betrayed you...
...is unforgivabIe....
I understand. Aku's deceit runs deep.
Even a good heart can be tainted
in the hands of Aku.
There was never a time machine, was there?
My quest continues.
But if we couId perhaps be
of assistance to you in any other way...?
WeII, there is one thing.
[ENGLISH]