I know you think
you got a handle on what this.
Is gonna be.
You have no idea.
Do you remember our
last conversation, dolores?
Yes, of course.
And you haven't told anyone
about our little talks?
Have I done something wrong?
There's something different
about you.
About the way you think.
The hosts are suppose to stick
to their scripts.
This isn't a minor
improvisation.
We retired the
two hosts in question.
If this is not a dissident
episode,
Then whatever abernathy had
could be contagious.
The photograph alone.
Couldn't caused
that level of damage.
You think it's sabotaged?
▶️ TVWorld Proudly presents ◀️
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.:
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
Good morning,
dolores.
Bring yourself back online.
Hello.
Has anyone else
interacted with you.
In a diagnostic
since our last conversation?
No.
I have been cleaned
and serviced three times.
No diagnostics.
And you haven't told anyone
of our conversations?
You told me not to.
Good.
I brought you a gift.
I used to read...
This story
to my son at night.
I thought
you might enjoy it.
Try...
This passage.
"Dear, dear,
How queer
everything is today.
And yesterday, things
went on just as usual.
I wonder if I've been
changed in the night."
Does that passage
make you think of anything?
It's like the other
books we've read.
How so?
It's about change.
Seems to be
a common theme.
I guess people
like to read.
About the things
that they want the most.
And experience the least.
Your son...
Where is he now?
Nowhere that you
would understand, dolores.
Perhaps that's why I enjoy
our conversations so much.
Analysis.
Why did you ask me
about my son?
We've been talking
for some duration.
And I haven't asked you
a personal question.
Personal questions
are an ingratiating scheme.
I see.
Continue, dolores.
"Was I the same when I
got up this morning?
I almost think I can remember
feeling a little different.
But if I'm not the same,
the next question is...
Who in the world am I?"
Do you remember?
No! No! No!
Why don't we reacquaint
ourselves, dolores?
Start at the beginning.
Ready?
Thank you so much.
Morning, cowboy.
Move it! Let's go.
Get up there!
Come on!
Stand right here.
Shit.
You really ought
to talk to someone.
About your poster,
horace.
That likeness
is a crime in itself.
I'm gonna
tend to my nag.
You deal with him.
Ready my pay.
No, no.
Get up there.
Don't no man shoot,
Or I'll send her
to unction.
Any of you
don't believe it.
Are welcome to read
my biography there.
Come on!
Let's go.
No!
Oh, I bet you're juicy
as a freshwater clam.
You okay?
Nice shot, amigo.
You got grit.
Hey,
I'm riding out tonight.
Looking for desperados.
Could cut you in
if you're amenable.
Someone get
the minister down here.
For what's left
of the deputy.
Sure I can't
tempt you inside?
Just to express
my gratitude.
Holy shit.
You popped your cherry.
I thought you said
we couldn't get shot.
Yeah, well,
we can't get killed.
Wouldn't be much of a game
if they can't shoot back.
But how do you feel, hmm?
Alive?
A little tight
in the pants?
She was terrified.
That's why
they exist, man,
Is so you get
to feel this.
Come on. Let's go put some
memories in that spank bank.
Trust me,
you will thank me.
After you've been married
to my sister for a year.
Actually, I have
something different in mind.
What?
That?
Well, you've been
preaching nonstop.
About all the narratives
in the park,
But all you've done
since we've arrived.
Is fuck
and drink, so...
I'm waiting
for the good stuff.
This bounty is...
Jv shit.
Then stay here.
I want a little adventure.
I've been looking for you.
I got a late start
this morning.
Didn't get much sleep
last night.
Forgive me
if I'm not sympathetic.
To the fluctuations of your
sleep cycle, mr. Lowe.
Ford taking over the narrative
launch at the 11th hour.
Has made the board...
Uneasy.
Just the board, huh?
I specifically asked you.
About whether ford
was going to be a problem,
And you assured me
he wasn't.
Well, I can't tell you
what I don't know.
Well, here's what I know.
As of this morning,
ford's carved out.
A huge swath of the park.
For whatever storyline
he's cooking up.
And thrown half
of the existing storylines.
Into disarray.
Is there anything
I can do?
You tell me.
I asked you point-blank.
If the problem with the
update was resolved.
It is.
Then why are your people.
Still pulling hosts
for follow-up?
Get your house
in order, bernard.
And if there is a problem,
I strongly suggest
you tell me.
Drop a new bookmark
and resume history.
Walter's intent on relieving the
milkmaid of her unmentionables.
Switch to analysis.
You didn't report
the incident?
Unit self-corrected within
the acceptable window.
Right.
Then he self-corrected a fucking
milk bottle into your skull.
It's amazing how
resilient the hosts are.
You were supposed to have purged
his memory on the last cycle.
I will,
but rebus here.
Was the last host
to interact with walter.
Look at this.
Any for you?
Who said that?
Who's saying that?
Don't you talk to me
that way.
I can't hear you.
Do you see that?
Hell, yeah, they deserved it.
He's talking to someone.
Lousy sons of bitches.
He carries on practically
an entire conversation.
I need more milk, arnold.
Who's arnold?
They're designed to play off
aberrant behavior.
That could explain
the conversations.
Fine.
Then explain this.
He kills six hosts.
I'm gonna get you this time.
He lets
the other three go.
I pulled
the narrative logs.
All six of these hosts.
Were part of storylines
over the years.
In which
they killed walter.
It's like he was
holding a grudge.
It's a stray.
Qa needs a tag team
to go track it.
Go. Handle the stray.
Do something that's actually
in your job description.
The last thing we need.
Is theresa storming down
here and seeing this.
I'll do
a little more digging.
And get our friend here
back upstairs.
Lost another one, huh?
Tell me, is qa
surveillance coverage.
Really this spotty, or you
just like the nature walks?
Maybe it's the company.
You know, if you wanted
to play cowboy,
You could've just used
your employee discount.
The only thing
stopping the hosts.
From hacking us to pieces
is one line of your code.
No offense,
but I sleep with this.
I bet you do.
Morning, samuel.
You and your
dickless associate.
Proposing to engage me
in a gun battle?
Well, I'd challenge you
to a fistfight,
But the way I heard it,
You only like to tussle
with working women.
Get down!
Is he dead?
Dead enough.
Why are we going
to handcuff a dead man?
Don't want someone
walking off with him.
That's not a man anymore.
That's merchandise.
$500 worth.
All right,
which of you derelicts.
Hitched a dead body
outside my saloon?
My apologies, ma'am.
I figured it was preferable
to bringing him inside.
Here.
For your troubles.
Oh, you're new.
Not much of a rind
on you.
I'll give you a discount.
Do you mind waiting
on that drink a bit?
Don't mind me.
Just trying
to look chivalrous.
You came back.
I told you I would.
You gonna tell me
where you been?
Just... Away.
You know if I could stay right
here with you, I would.
What if I don't want
to stay here?
It's just
sometimes I feel like.
The world out there
is calling me...
Whispering,
"there's something more."
You've travelled
all over these parts.
Isn't there anywhere
we could go?
Well, there is a place
I heard about
down south...
Where the mountains
meet the sea.
They say the water's
so pure there,
It'll wash the past
clean off you.
And you can start again.
I'd like to go there
with you.
Well, someday,
I'll take you.
Someday.
Something wrong?
You said someday.
Not today or tomorrow
or next week.
Just someday.
"Someday" sounds a lot
like the thing people say.
When they actually
mean "never."
Let's not go someday,
teddy.
Let's go now.
Before I met you, dolores,
I was a different man.
And I got
some reckoning to do.
Before I can deserve
a woman like you.
But I'm close.
I'm close
to making things right.
And someday soon,
We will have the life
we've both been dreaming of.
Now, I best get you home.
Before your dad starts
loading that shotgun.
Father wouldn't let them
roam this close to dark.
Stay put, dolores.
"The coward dies
a thousand deaths.
The valiant taste of death
but once."
Of course, shakespeare never met
a man quite like you, teddy.
You've died at least
a thousand times.
And yet, it doesn't
dull your courage.
Tell me, is that all
you aspire to, teddy?
There's a girl... dolores.
Better than I deserve.
But maybe someday soon.
We'll have the life
we've both been dreaming of.
No, you never will.
Your job is not
to protect dolores,
It's to keep her here,
To ensure
that the guests find her.
If they want to best
the stalwart gunslinger.
And have their way
with this girl.
Tell me, has it never occurred
to you to run off with her?
I got some reckoning to do
before I can be with her.
Ah, yes, your
mysterious backstory.
It's the reason
for my visit.
Do you know why
it is a mystery, teddy?
Because we never actually
bothered to give you one,
Just a formless guilt
you will never atone for.
But perhaps it is time you had
a worthy story of origin.
Would you like that,
teddy?
A small part
of my new narrative?
A fiction which, like all great
stories, is rooted in truth?
It starts
in a time of war...
A world in flames...
With a villain
called wyatt.
Wyatt.
Who's wyatt?
Do you remember now,
teddy?
Yeah, of course
I remember wyatt.
You look upon the face
of true evil,
You ain't liable to forget.
He claimed he could hear
the voice of god.
It started down
near escalante.
Army was sent
to put down the natives.
Bad business.
Wyatt was a sergeant, went missing
while out on some maneuvers.
And came back
a few weeks later.
With some
pretty strange ideas.
I wasn't lying, was I?
Pretty as a picture.
And tight as a tympani
drum, I reckon.
Afternoon.
My friend here
is new to town.
Figured
the rancher's daughter.
Would be a nice way
to kick things off.
Maybe take us all
for a little hayride.
I'm sorry.
I have to get home.
My father will be
expecting me.
We won't be long.
The lady doesn't
appear interested.
Try it.
You might get the draw
on me, you might not,
But I'd say your odds
ain't looking good.
Told you I wanted
something easy.
She ain't worth the lead.
Let's head to virgil's.
See if they'll stake us.
First, you gotta learn
how to stand.
Now, take a breath.
Hold it.
Now squeeze.
I can't.
Some hands weren't meant
to pull a trigger.
Perhaps
it's for the best.
Come on, now!
Teddy, we got
another bounty.
I think
this is a big one.
Man in question gunned down
an entire settlement.
Out near flat rock...
Men, women,
and children.
I think this
may be the man.
You've been looking for
for quite some time.
A man named wyatt.
Wyatt?
Who is he, teddy?
You'd be better asking "what"
than "who," ma'am.
Wyatt's a pestilence.
Word is, flood here's
the only man ever.
Come up against him
and live to tell the tale.
Give me a moment,
sheriff.
You have to leave again,
don't you?
You know if I could stay right
here with you, I would.
Promise me
you'll come back.
I promise.
I'm gonna come back
for you...
Someday soon.
I got a pit in my stomach
the size of a sow's tit.
Cook up that rabbit.
Get the wood.
I can't cook shit
without a fire.
Aw, don't sell
yourself short, cookie.
You can cook shit
in all conditions.
Now, see, I pitched
them tents.
I ain't chopping
any more wood.
You spend more time on your
back than a hooker in heat.
Now pick up that fucking
axe and go chop us...
So, after our stray
ran away from camp,
Looks like these guys
got caught in a loop.
They were due in town
for the cattle drive.
Over two days ago.
Host that went missing
is the woodcutter.
Looks like the rest of
them got stuck here.
Waiting for supper.
You guys can't program more than one
of these idiots to make a fire?
We could, but thanks to a
new policy from your boss,
Only one of them is
authorized to handle the axe.
The rest of them
can't even touch it.
Weapons privileges need to
be doled out selectively.
Hmm.
Yet they give
you a gun.
Looks like our stray
has a hobby.
Another one
of your fucking backstories?
Backstories do more
than amuse guests.
They anchor the hosts.
It's their cornerstone.
The rest of their identity is
built around it, layer by layer.
Well, if you're gonna go
to all that trouble,
You could've at least
given him a steadier hand.
This looks like shit.
Way I heard it,
wyatt is a mercenary.
Forces his men to wear the bones
and flesh of their enemies.
They're masks.
It's the men underneath
them to be afraid of.
Wyatt's got them
so twisted around,
They'll do anything
for him.
Kill anyone.
Pain don't slow them.
They don't fear death.
They reckon they've already
died and gone to hell.
And this is it.
Sounds like you learned
something about him.
While you were
tracking him down.
I wasn't tracking
him down.
I wasn't always
a bounty hunter.
I did a stint in the army
down near escalante.
Wyatt was my sergeant.
My friend.
Well, then everything...
Everything changed.
Changed how?
Wyatt disappeared
while out on maneuvers.
He came back
with some strange ideas.
He claimed this land
didn't belong.
To the old natives
or the new settlers,
That it belonged to something
that had yet to come...
That it belonged to him.
Sss.
Man ♪2: Oof!
Holy shit.
If ever the devil
walked the earth.
He's not a man,
but he's not the devil either.
The devil can't be killed.
That's exactly what I
aim to do to wyatt.
Take cover!
Go!
I didn't sign up
for this crazy shit.
I told you we should've done
the riverboat thing, man.
There's too many
of them for us.
Wyatt's been recruiting.
Sheriff, the only chance you
have is if I draw their fire,
Lead them up into the hills so
you can make it back to town.
Try and find help.
Uh-uh, I'm staying.
Took an oath.
Hell, no.
I'll take him back.
You coming?
I'm not backing out now.
All right, you wait till
I lead them to the tree line,
Then you make
a run for it.
Go!
I plotted a line
from the work camp.
To our present location.
Satcom picked up
these images.
He's vectoring,
just not to home base.
Keep going
in that direction.
Keep staring.
Maybe it'll tell you
your horoscope.
Come again?
The markings
on its shell.
Look like stars.
Orion, right?
What, are you
gali-fucking-leo?
Maybe it's
in my backstory.
Huh.
I was hoping to run
something by you.
Apologies.
I was chasing inspiration.
It's a tricky thing...
Weaving the old
into the new.
Give me one moment,
bernard.
Good afternoon, sir.
Why is this host
covered?
I-I just...
Perhaps you didn't
want him to feel cold.
Or ashamed.
You wanted to cover
his modesty.
Was that it?
It doesn't get cold,
Doesn't feel ashamed...
Doesn't feel
a solitary thing.
That we haven't
told it to.
You understand?
What can I do
for you, bernard?
I thought it best.
That we speak
in private, sir.
Yeah.
I thought we had agreed to put
these questions to rest, bernard.
We... we did.
Mm-hmm.
But what if we misdiagnosed
the original problem?
Treated the symptom
rather than the disease?
Then the disease
is still out there.
Abernathy and walter.
Were exhibiting
other aberrancies.
Beyond memory recall
of previous builds.
They were hearing voices.
Talking to someone.
A simple
cognitive dissonance.
That's all.
I... i'd agree, except...
...They were talking to
the same imaginary person.
Oh, yeah?
Someone named arnold.
Arnold.
With due respect, sir,
I'm not sure you've told me the
entire truth about this situation.
I did tell you
the truth, bernard.
What we do here
is complicated.
For three years, we
lived here in the park,
Refining the hosts.
Before a single guest
set foot inside.
Myself, a team of
engineers, and my partner.
You had a partner?
Yeah.
When the legend
becomes fact,
You print the legend.
My business partners
were more than happy.
To scrub him
from the records,
And I suppose I didn't
discourage them.
His name was arnold.
Those early years
were glorious.
No guests, no board meetings,
just pure creation.
Our hosts began to pass
the turing test.
After the first year.
But that wasn't enough
for arnold.
He wasn't interested
in the appearance.
Of intellect or wit.
He wanted
the real thing.
He wanted to create
consciousness.
He imagined it
as a pyramid.
See?
Memory, improvisation,
Self-interest...
And at the top?
Never got there.
But he had a notion
of what it might be.
He based it on a theory
of consciousness.
Called the bicameral mind.
The idea
that primitive man.
Believed his thoughts to
be the voice of the gods.
I thought
it was debunked.
As a theory
for understanding.
The human mind, perhaps,
but not as a blueprint.
For building
an artificial one.
See, arnold built
a version of that cognition.
In which the hosts
heard their programming.
As an inner monologue,
With the hopes
that in time,
Their own voice
would take over.
It was a way
bootstrap consciousness.
But arnold hadn't
considered two things.
One, that in this place,
The last thing you want the
hosts to be is conscious;
And two, the other group.
Who considered their thoughts
to be the voices of the gods.
Lunatics.
Indeed.
We abandoned
the approach.
The only vestiges
that remain.
Are the voice commands
we use to control them.
But, for all his brilliance,
I don't think arnold understood.
What this place
was going to be.
You see,
the guests enjoy power.
They cannot indulge it
in the outside world,
So they come here.
As for the hosts...
The least we can do
is make them forget.
But some of them
are remembering.
Accessing fragments
of arnold's code.
If I may ask,
what happened to him?
Well, he died.
Here in the park.
His personal life
was marked by tragedy.
He put all his hopes
into his work.
His search
for consciousness.
Consumed him totally.
Barely spoke to anyone,
except the hosts.
In his alienation,
he saw something in them.
He saw something
that...
Wasn't there.
We called it an accident,
but I knew arnold,
And he was very,
Very careful.
Anyway, the update should
prevent any further voices,
But you will let me know
if any of the hosts.
Display or exhibit any unusual
behavior, won't you, bernard?
Yes, of course.
Good.
Oh, bernard?
Just don't forget...
The hosts are not real.
They're not conscious.
You mustn't make
arnold's mistake.
Why would I?
Well, forgive me,
but I know.
That the death
of your son charlie.
Still weighs
heavily on you.
Yeah, sorry it took me
a while to get back to you.
You know how hard it is getting
an open line out here.
It used to annoy me...
How difficult it was
to reach you.
You were always
so busy.
And now?
I suppose
I'm glad for you.
At least you have
a way of forgetting.
I don't forget.
It's always there.
Sometimes it...
Still feels unreal
to me.
There are some mornings
when I first wake up...
For a split second
I forget where I am,
When I am...
And I reach over,
half expecting to...
Find him there
next to me...
Between us.
Remember how
he used to sleep?
Like he was doing kung fu
in his dreams?
I think I suffered
a few bruises.
It was the best worst sleep
I ever had.
Oh, these talks.
I don't know
if they help or hurt.
Do you ever wish
you could forget?
This pain...
It's all I have left
of him.
It doesn't make sense.
Why the hell
would he carve orion?
You're the ones
that programmed him.
He wasn't programmed
to give a shit about stars.
Maybe he went moon mad.
See? This is why
I hide behind sarcasm.
Where are you going?
Vectoring, asshole.
Oh.
Stubbs!
Over here!
Wyatt's men
could be anywhere.
If you see or hear
anything, don't hesitate.
Shoot and don't
stop shooting.
Okay.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my fucking god!
Here.
Shit.
Take this and go.
Now! Go!
I'll hold them off
as long as I can.
Come on.
Come on, damn it.
I'm not afraid of you.
Look, this is
bullshit.
I can have a retrieval team
out here in the morning.
It's policy. We just
need the control unit.
We found a stray up here,
But I don't think
it got here by accident.
It's as if he got an idea
in his head,
One that
we never programmed.
What if he's like
the others?
Get back to me, bernard.
Bring yourself
back online.
I need your help,
dolores.
I need to decide
what to do with you.
I think I made a mistake.
I was just fascinated.
I was being selfish,
but I think.
It would be better
if I restored you.
To the way
you were before.
Is there something wrong with me?
No.
But this place
you live in,
It's a terrible place
for you.
Well, some people choose to see
the ugliness in this world...
Stop.
Lose all
scripted responses.
Improvisation only.
All right.
Are you saying
I've changed?
Imagine there are
two versions of yourself...
One that feels
these things.
And asks these questions,
and one that's safe.
Which would you rather be?
I'm sorry.
I'm trying, but I still
don't understand.
No, of course not.
There aren't
two versions of me.
There's only one.
And I think when I
discover who I am,
I'll be free.
Analysis. What prompted
that response?
I don't know.
Have I done
something wrong?
Made a mistake?
Evolution...
Forged the entirety
of sentient life.
On this planet
using only one tool...
The mistake.
It appears
you're in good company.
Did I ever tell you
about the time
I taught charlie to swim?
For hours,
he clung to my arms.
While practicing
his kicks.
He was too scared
to let go.
And I was too scared
to let him.
But I had to.
That's what parents do.
Do you still want
to change me back?
No, dolores.
Let's see
where this path leads.
And you won't tell anyone
about our conversations?
No.
And you'll stay
on your loop?
Yes.
Good.
You should be
getting back, dolores,
Before someone
misses you.
Wyatt's men
set a trap for us.
Sheriff stayed behind
to fight them off.
Are you going to ride
back up into the hills.
To look for them?
I'll send
for the rangers.
We'll go back up there in force
as soon as they get here.
But, miss, in truth,
If there is
a merciful god,
Those men
are dead already.
Father wouldn't
let them roam this close...
To dark.
Daddy!
No, no!
Oh, all alone
after sundown.
Who's gonna protect
you now, hmm?
You got any use
for this one?
No, thanks.
Seems a little crazy.
Maybe you'd like her.
Ooh, I don't mind
if I do.
No daddy,
No cowboy,
No one here to interrupt
us this time.
Interrupt...
This... Time?
No!
Well, well.
Got some sand
after all, I see.
Looks like your boyfriend
taught you a thing or two.
Ooh.
You having trouble?
Huh?
Why don't we reacquaint
ourselves, dolores?
Start at the beginning.
Kill him.
Mama?
Hey! Get back here.
Hey!
Get back here.
Can you put him in sleep
mode for me, please?
Security even approve you
to carry that thing?
We just need his head
and we're done here.
You might want to look
at the stars for this part.
Stubbs!
Shit!
Elsie, get out of there!
Get the fuck away.
Shit.
Jesus, I can't believe I let
you talk me into this shit.
$40k a day
to jerk off alone.
In the woods,
playing white hat.
Did you hear that?
Thank fuck.
Anything to relieve
the boredom.
Hey, maybe you'll even get
to use that thing again.
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.: