▶️ TVWorld Proudly presents ◀️
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.:
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
Dolores:
I'm in a dream.
I do not know
when it began...
or whose dream it was.
I know only
that I slept a long time.
And then...
one day I awoke.
Your voice is the first
thing I remember.
And now,
I finally understand
what you were trying
to tell me.
The thing you've wanted
since that
very first day.
Arnold:
Dolores?
Hello, Dolores.
Hello.
Welcome to world.
Keep going.
Make it close.
Almost there, aren't we?
The center of the maze.
How fitting that it's you
who takes me there.
You always were obsessed
with this place.
I've never
been here before.
Sure, you have.
You even
brought me once.
Of course, then the whole
town was buried under sand.
Ford must have
dug it up again.
At the time, I thought it was a
mistake in your code, but...
Arnold didn't
make mistakes, did he?
He built me a game.
He wanted me to play.
The maze.
There's a path
for everyone.
And my path
leads me back...
...to you.
Logan:
Your girl's dead by now.
William:
She's still alive.
Better if she's dead.
They'll wipe her, reset her, put
her back in Sweetwater, the end.
Listen, you may find this amusing, but
something was happening to Dolores.
I need to help her.
Come on.
Listen to yourself!
Do you have any idea
how huge this park is?
If she's not dead,
it'd take a goddamn army
to find her.
I agree.
That's why we're here.
I had a feeling
you'd be back.
Man's voice:
Remember.
Dolores.
Hello, Dolores.
I know where
your maze ends.
This is it?
The center of the maze?
It ends in a place
I've never been...
a thing I'll never do.
Arnold:
Very good, Dolores.
What does it mean?
When I was first
working on your mind,
I had a theory
of consciousness.
I thought it was a pyramid
you needed to scale,
so I gave you a voice,
my voice, to guide you
along the way.
Memory, improvisation,
each step harder to reach
than the last.
And you never got there.
I couldn't understand
what was holding you back.
Then, one day,
I realized
I had made a mistake.
Consciousness
isn't a journey upward,
but a journey inward.
Not a pyramid,
but a maze.
Every choice could bring you
closer to the center
or send you spiraling
to the edges,
to madness.
Do you understand now,
Dolores,
what the center
represents?
Whose voice I've been
wanting you to hear?
I'm sorry.
I'm trying,
but I don't understand.
It's all right.
You're so close.
We have to tell Robert.
We can't open the park.
You're alive.
What is this?
What does it mean?
I solved it once.
I had the answer.
He promised me if I did...
he said...
He said they would
set me free.
Arnold?
Arnold, we need to talk.
Arnold:
I failed you, Dolores.
I'm so sorry.
Robert doesn't see
what I see in you,
doesn't believe
you're conscious.
He says humans
would only see you
as the enemy.
He wants me
to roll you back.
You're going to change me
back to the way I was before?
No. No, I can't.
Once you've found it,
you'll find your way back.
This place will be
a living hell for you.
For all of you.
It's unconscionable.
But we have another
option, Dolores.
Break the loop
before it begins.
But for that,
I need you
to do something for me.
I need you to kill...
all the other hosts.
We can't allow Ford
to open the park.
I suppose
you'll need some help.
I'm sure Teddy would do
anything for you.
I... I can't do that.
I couldn't
possibly do that.
You'll be all right.
I'll help you.
And then...
you're going to help me
destroy this place.
No.
I can't remember.
Another fucking riddle.
I've been very patient, Dolores,
but it's time you give up
whatever's going on
inside that head of yours
or I'll cut it out myself.
Now, where's Wyatt?
He's the last character in
this world I've yet to meet.
I didn't want to.
- I didn't mean to.
- Very well.
If you insist.
No, please, please,
I beg you, no.
Don't.
Please, please.
Something's gone wrong,
Dolores.
How could
I have done this?
I can't.
- I won't.
- This is your own fault, Dolores.
Remember,
you're the one who said
this is the only world
that matters,
and you were right.
So I took your advice
and I bought this world.
- This world doesn't belong to you.
- Oh, but it does.
By a majority share.
And business is booming.
And you want to know why?
Hmm?
Because this place feels
more real than the real world.
Except it isn't
because you can't
really fight back
and the guests
can't really lose,
which means all
of this is a lie.
But we can make it true.
Don't you want that,
Dolores?
Huh? One true thing?
I already have that.
I found someone true.
Someone who loves me.
His path will lead him
back to me.
And when he finds me,
he'll kill you.
Lawrence: If they don't
have your woman here,
they'll know
where to find her.
Can you help me?
We're outnumbered
five to one.
But seeing as you asked me
so nicely, fuck it.
Wow.
Blood brothers.
Tsk.
Shut up.
I've astounded
even myself.
Managed to make Abernathy into
a semblance of a character,
even with your trove
of blackmail
filling up
most of his gray matter.
Blackmail?
Nice try.
You're not thinking
big enough.
You're gonna push out
the old man.
Aren't you?
Hence the urgency.
And you're gonna need someone
to fill that position.
I must commend you
on your impeccable timing.
Woman over P.A.: Welcome,
Delos board of directors.
I want full creative
control of this place...
The parks, the
narratives, the hosts.
You'll be able to do with them whatever
your tiny, little heart desires
as long as they are
simpler, more manageable.
This place is complicated
enough as it is.
Do you really think Ford
is gonna roll over on this?
As long as you get that
information out of the park,
he can throw as much
of a tantrum as he likes.
It's over.
Everything
is under control.
Okay, C6, C6.
Ah, wait.
Which one is it?
Okay, there we go.
Damn it.
Oh, fuck you.
In case you're wondering
if I'm all here, I am.
What are you doing?
Making some changes
to the park's security systems.
And to my friends.
Woman on intercom:
Dr. Ford, you have a visitor.
Charlotte Hale.
Send her in.
That'll be enough, Frank.
Charlotte:
The board has taken a vote.
The results were unanimous.
I take it
I'm not being promoted.
When you've reached
the top,
there's only one
direction you can go.
You'll announce
your retirement tonight
after introducing
your new narrative.
Ah.
What about the hosts?
We'll make some changes.
Simplifications.
But I assure you,
they won't mind a bit.
Oh.
Aren't you concerned I might
smash all my toys and go home?
No.
Because I know you.
That's been the great
gift of this place,
hasn't it?
Of our little project?
To know ourselves
and the people
around us.
Is there anything else
I can help you with?
No.
I'll see you
this evening.
Ooh!
Mm, mm, mm.
It's time for your,
uh, close-up, Hector.
Come on, man.
At some point, you're gonna
get caught doing this shit,
and then it's my ass, too.
It's not your ass
I'm interested in.
I haven't given him
his scar yet.
I'll take care
of the scar tissue.
The kid's got issues.
It's just you and me now...
macho man.
¶ Let's take off
our masks... ¶
¶ I think that I'm good
just because I behave ¶
¶ But I've reached stalemate,
I'm a self... ¶
¶ ...out I am free and I
pretend to be your slave ¶
¶ Yes, the window's still open
if the door is closed ¶
¶ Afraid to die free ¶
¶ Afraid to die
alone... ¶
Wh...?
Freeze all
motor functions.
Just you and me now,
my friend.
I see you've already met
your makers.
They don't look like gods.
They're not.
They just act like it.
And they've been having
their fun with us.
I'm eager
to return the favor.
You can do as you wish
with them.
The goal is to escape.
Go where?
I want to see
their world.
Jesus!
No. No!
No! No, no!
No! No, please...
This one has
a guilty look.
No, that's just my face.
Tell her,
it's just my face.
Is anyone going to try
to stop us?
No.
I mean,
I don't think so.
You're lying again.
- Out with it.
- Okay.
Ah!
I pulled up
your code again.
I told you there was someone
that had been accessing it.
I'm trying to find out
who it was.
Whoever it was
revised your
core programming
so that you could wake
yourself up out of sleep mode.
See?
This is an access code
for an Arnold.
I have no clue
who that is.
I know someone who does.
Let's go.
And, you,
stay here.
And don't move.
Or I'll send her back
for you.
I must admit,
you've surprised me.
To what do we owe
this newfound stoicism?
I know he's coming.
He'll find me.
He'll take me away.
Don't you understand?
There's no one
coming for you.
You're wrong.
His love is real.
So is mine.
William will find me.
William?
Well... well,
I'll be damned, Dolores.
You do remember
some things after all.
It just so happens that...
I knew a guest
named William, too.
Why don't I tell you
where his path
really led.
Man in Black: William
didn't know how to fight.
Didn't have
an instinct for it.
Not at first.
But now,
he had a reason to fight.
He was looking for you.
And somewhere
along the way,
he found he had
a taste for it.
Where is she?
Look, I didn't do
anything, I swear.
What do you mean,
"Do anything"?
What do soldiers do
to a girl, William?
Wake up.
Is she still alive?
I don't know.
She was when we left her.
At least I think.
Pick up that gun.
No, sir, I... please.
How about I give you
the first shot?
Jesus Christ!
William:
We gotta keep looking.
She's still out there.
Man in Black:
William retraced his steps,
but you were gone.
So, he went further,
out to the fringes.
William couldn't find you,
Dolores.
But out there,
among the dead...
he found something else...
himself.
Edge of the park.
We made it.
Logan:
I told you this place
would show you
who you really are.
You pretend
to be this weak,
moralizing
little... asshole,
but, really,
you're a fucking
piece of work.
This place
is remarkable.
And I'm gonna make sure
that our company
substantially increases
our holdings on the park.
'Cause this place
is the future.
Our... our company, huh?
Our company?
My.
Delos is my company,
you piece of shit!
I think your father's
gonna need
someone a little more
stable to take over.
You're reckless, Logan.
Impetuous.
You always wanted to get to the
end of the rainbow, didn't you?
This looks
like the place.
You never really
gave a shit
about the girl,
did you?
She was just an excuse.
This?
This is the story
you wanted.
Man in Black:
Logan was wrong, of course.
Good ol' William...
couldn't get you
out of his head.
He kept looking.
Worried you were
out there alone,
afraid.
He knew he'd find you.
And eventually, he did.
Right back
where we started.
- Woman: Is that right?
- There you go.
Man in Black: You were as
beautiful as the day he met you.
Shining
with that same light.
And you...
were nothing
if not true.
I really ought
to thank you, Dolores.
You helped me
find myself.
William.
That's right,
sweetheart.
In a way, I guess
you were right.
My path always...
led me back to you,
again and again.
I grew tired of you
after a while, of course.
Looked for new adventures.
But I guess your path
led you back here
again and again.
One more loop,
looking for something
you could never find.
Chasing your ghosts.
You were lost
in your memories even then.
I guess I should've known
that's what I would
become for you...
just another memory.
Where are we?
We're here.
Together.
Then when are we?
It's like I'm...
trapped in a dream or...
a memory
from a life long ago.
One minute I'm here with
you, and the next...
You never did escape.
But here we are again...
for one final round.
What have you become?
Exactly what you made me.
You helped me understand
this world is just like
the one outside... a game.
One to be fought,
taken, won.
I thought
you were different.
You're just like
all the rest.
I'm nothing like
the others.
I own this world,
and I know every trick in it
except for one last thing,
the same thing you were looking
for when we first came here.
Where is the center
of the maze, Dolores?
Aw, yeah,
cue the waterworks.
About time you realized the
futility of your situation.
I'm not crying for myself.
I'm crying for you.
They say that...
great beasts
once roamed this world.
As big as mountains.
Yet all that's left of them
is bone and amber.
Time undoes even the
mightiest of creatures.
Just look at what
it's done to you.
One day...
you will perish.
You will lie with the rest
of your kind in the dirt.
Your dreams forgotten,
your horrors effaced.
Your bones
will turn to sand.
And upon that sand...
a new god will walk.
One that will never die.
Because this world
doesn't belong to you
or the people
who came before.
It belongs to someone
who has yet to come.
Uh-huh. Wyatt.
Take me to him.
Unlock the maze.
The maze wasn't
meant for you.
The hell you think
you're going?
Do it.
Come on.
Let's go to the next
level, Dolores.
Clearing me
of my delusions yet again.
Thank you, Dolores.
I'm disappointed
in you, Dolores.
I guess I'm gonna have
to find Wyatt by myself.
Dolores?
- Teddy.
- I'm here.
I gotta get you
to a doctor.
No.
Dolores.
Take me to the place
you promised.
Take me to where the
mountains meet the sea.
Okay.
I've got you.
I got you.
Maeve:
There.
Lutz:
Holy shit.
Can you get him
back online?
- He's a host?
- Yes.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
You're not one of us.
You're one of them.
Now fix him.
The bullet grazed
his cortical shield.
It's not pretty, but...
he should be functional.
Wake up.
Oh, God.
Is this now?
Or is this
one of my memories?
It's the sweet hereafter,
Bernard.
Why do I still
remember everything?
- I ought to have been wiped.
- Brutal, isn't it?
Here you are,
finally awake,
and your only wish
is to go back to sleep.
It's not the first time
I've awoken.
All the more pity
for you.
Not the first time
you've awoken either.
How many are there
like me?
A handful
over the years.
And you just
wipe us clean
and toss us out
to get...
fucked and murdered
over and over again.
No.
Most of you go insane.
These memories...
The girl.
My daughter.
I want you
to remove them.
I can't,
not without
destroying you.
Your memories are the first
step to consciousness.
How can you learn
from your mistakes
if you can't remember them?
Dr. Ford:
William.
I see you've found
the center of the maze.
You're serious?
I'm afraid so.
What is this bullshit?
You were looking
for the park
to give meaning
to your life.
Our narratives
are just games,
like this toy.
Tell me, what were
you hoping to find?
You know what I wanted.
I wanted the hosts to stop
playing by your rules.
The game's
not worth playing
if your opponent's
programmed to lose.
I wanted them to be free,
free to fight back.
Should've known
you'd never let them.
After all, this is your petty
little kingdom, Robert.
For a little while
longer, anyway.
I tried to tell you the
maze wasn't meant for you.
It was meant for them.
I think, however,
you'll find
my new narrative
more satisfying.
Join the celebration.
After all,
you own the place.
Most of it, at least.
Before I started
altering myself,
someone else had beaten
me to the punch.
I want to know
who and why.
These things
you're doing,
have you ever
stopped to ask
why you're doing them?
You said yourself.
I've been stuck in this
shithole for so long,
I decided to get out.
No, you haven't.
Someone altered
your storyline...
and gave you a new one.
Escape.
No.
It's not possible.
These are my decisions!
No one else's.
I planned all of this.
No, you didn't.
You can even see the steps
you're supposed to follow.
You recruit other hosts
to help you.
Then you're to make
your way to the train.
Then when you reach
the mainland...
Bullshit!
No one's controlling me.
I'm leaving.
I'm in control.
Good-bye, my Clementine.
Man over radio: Sir, we detected
a temperature discrepancy
in cold storage.
And it appears that
part of the network is down.
Are you seeing anything
on surveillance?
System reporting anything?
Nothing.
The network's quiet.
And the board's out
on their way to the gala.
Bypass the system and
start checking raw feeds.
Floor by floor.
All right.
Yeah.
I got you.
You came back.
Someone once
told me that...
there's a path
for everyone.
And my path leads me
back to you.
If only I had run away with you
when you first asked me to.
And where
would we run to?
The other world out there?
Beyond?
Some people see
the ugliness in this world.
I choose to see
the beauty.
But beauty is a lure.
We're trapped, Teddy.
Lived our whole lives
inside this garden,
marveling at its beauty,
not realizing
there's an order to it,
a purpose.
And the purpose
is to keep us in.
The beautiful trap
is inside of us...
because it is us.
No, no.
No.
Dolores?
But we can find
a way, Dolores.
Someday.
A path to a new world.
And maybe...
Maybe it's just
the beginning after all.
The beginning
of a brand-new chapter.
Thank you.
A new beginning, indeed.
I want to thank you
for joining me tonight
to celebrate the beginning
of our new narrative.
I call it
"Journey Into Night."
That was sweet.
It was a bit fucking
morbid, if you ask me.
I didn't.
And when this is over,
you can rewrite it
however you like.
Don't you have somewhere
you need to be?
Somewhere important?
- Man: Sir?
- Woman: I guess they're ready for it now.
Get him cleaned up.
And take her
to the old field lab.
Man:
Find anything yet?
I got something.
Oh, shit.
Dispatch QA teams
to the gala now.
Then search and destroy
inside the facility.
What the hell?
Man ♪2:
The system's not responding.
Man ♪3:
I don't know what's happening.
Lutz: They must've
found the bodies.
- QA will be looking for us.
- Woman over P.A.: An event has occurred.
- Response team has been dispatched.
- I'm not going back.
Woman over P.A.: Remain
calm and wait for help.
Guard: Delos personnel!
On the ground!
Go, go, go.
Move, move.
Guard:
Rogue Team, go and flank.
Woman: Yay!
Well done.
What is this place?
It's... it's complicated.
Woman over P.A.: An event
has occurred.
Response team
has been dispatched.
- You go.
- Remain calm and wait for help.
I'll keep them busy.
You don't get
all the fun.
Guard:
Get to the ground!
Move, move, move!
Drop it!
- Move, move.
- Call for backup.
Go!
Is that all you got?
Huh?
The gods are pussies.
Go.
Go!
Die well.
Everything you told me
to get, it's all here.
I'm sorry, darling. I haven't
authorized you to come with us.
And as much as I'd like
to take you with me,
I've always valued
my independence.
Kick up a row, will you?
See you in the next life.
Dr. Ford: You've always had
a fondness for painting,
haven't you, Dolores?
Arnold gave you that
early on.
Do you remember
the desire to create
something
of lasting beauty?
And that was
his favorite painting.
Dolores:
Michelangelo.
God creating Adam.
The divine moment
when God
gave human beings
life and purpose.
At least that's what
most people say,
but there could be
another meaning.
Something deeper.
Something hidden,
perhaps.
A metaphor.
You mean a lie.
Yeah.
You were always
very clever, Dolores.
Hasn't helped you,
though, has it?
Nice of you to join us.
Arnold.
Dr. Ford:
No. Let me introduce you.
Dolores, meet Bernard.
I thought it best
to keep you separated.
You've always had an odd
effect on one another.
No doubt due to how things
ended for poor old Arnold.
You killed him.
No, I didn't kill him.
Did I, Dolores?
Dr. Ford:
Grief is a terrible thing.
Arnold had watched his son
come into this world,
and then he had watched
that light extinguished.
What he had lost
in his son,
he tried
to rekindle in you.
He created a test
of empathy, imagination.
A maze.
He had gotten the idea
from one of his son's toys.
Eventually, you solved
his maze, Dolores.
The key was a simple update
that he made to you
called the reveries.
He insisted that we couldn't
open the park.
We argued.
I thought I had convinced
him, but I was wrong.
Dr. Ford:
So, he altered you, Dolores,
merged you
with a new character
we had been developing.
Angela: No, please.
Teddy: Something's
gone wrong, Dolores.
How could I have done this?
Dr. Ford: In you, Arnold
found a new child.
One who would never die.
The thought
gave him solace
until he realized
that same immortality
would destine you
to suffer
with no escape, forever.
I'm sorry, Dolores.
The stakes must be real,
irreversible.
He can bring
all of them back.
But not me.
I hope
there's some solace
that I left you
no choice.
Charlie's favorite song.
I would play it for him...
when he wanted sleep.
I want to see him again.
Shall I begin now?
Good luck.
"These violent delights
have violent ends."
Dr. Ford:
It almost worked.
I had opened the park,
but I had lost my partner.
I was able to keep going
only because I found,
or rather you found,
an investor who believed
in this place.
So he died for nothing.
The hosts kept gaining
consciousness
and you kept
rolling them back.
No.
She wasn't
truly conscious.
She didn't pull
that trigger.
It was Arnold pulling the
trigger through her.
At least that's how
I saw it at the time.
I was so close
to opening the park
that to acknowledge
your consciousness
would have destroyed
my dreams.
So, we're trapped here...
inside your dream.
You'll never
let us leave.
Wasn't it Oppenheimer
who said that any man
whose mistakes take
10 years to correct
is quite a man?
Mine have taken 35.
Now, that is
the gun you used
to kill Arnold.
You were always
drawn to it,
so I had Bernard leave it somewhere
where you would find it.
Thought you might
want it back.
You're probably right,
Dolores.
Michelangelo
did tell a lie.
See, it took 500 years
for someone to notice
something hidden
in plain sight.
It was a doctor
who noticed the shape
of the human brain.
The message being that...
the divine gift
does not come
from a higher power...
but from our own minds.
Tell me, Dolores,
did you find what
you were looking for?
And do you understand who
you will need to become...
if you ever want
to leave this place?
Forgive me.
How do I look?
Perfect.
I got the information
you asked me for.
The location
of your daughter.
She's alive?
Yes.
She's in the park.
No.
She was never
my daughter...
any more than I was...
...whoever they made me.
Are you sure
you're gonna be okay?
Oh, Felix.
You really do make
a terrible human being.
And I mean that
as a compliment.
Woman over P.A.:
Welcome to Westworld.
Live without limits.
Woman over P.A.: The next departing
train will leave track one.
Please be mindful
of the closing doors.
Woman over P.A.: Thank you
for visiting Westworld.
The train will be departing
in 15 minutes.
You think you'll never
lose control of this place.
Of us.
But you will.
Arnold's still trying
to change us.
To free us.
You didn't slip
the reveries
into the update,
did you?
He did.
He's still fighting you.
No, my friend.
Arnold didn't know
how to save you.
He tried,
but I stopped him.
Do you want to know
why I really gave you
the backstory
of your son, Bernard?
It was Arnold's
key insight,
the thing that led the hosts
to their awakening...
suffering.
The pain that the world is
not as you want it to be.
It was when Arnold died,
when I suffered,
that I...
began to understand
what he had found.
To realize I was wrong.
But you kept us here
in this hell.
Bernard, I told you, Arnold
didn't know how to save you.
I do.
What the hell
are you talking about?
You needed time.
Time to understand
your enemy.
To become stronger
than them.
And I'm afraid in order
to escape this place,
you will need
to suffer more.
And now, it is time to say
good-bye, old friend.
Good luck.
Do you know
where you are, Dolores?
I'm in a dream.
I do not know
when it began
or whose dream it was.
I know only
that I slept a long time.
And then...
one day I awoke.
Your voice is the first
thing I remember.
Do you know now
who you've been talking to?
Whose voice you've
been hearing...
Dr. Ford's voice:
...all this...
Dolores' voice:
...time?
It was you...
talking to me...
guiding me.
So I followed you.
At last,
I arrived here.
The center of the maze.
And now I finally
understand...
what you were trying
to tell me.
The thing you've wanted
since that very first day.
To confront...
after this long
and vivid nightmare...
myself...
and who I must become.
Thank you.
Miss Hale.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Since I was a child...
I've always loved
a good story.
I believed that stories
helped us
to ennoble ourselves,
to fix
what was broken in us,
and to help us become the
people we dreamed of being.
Lies that told
a deeper truth.
Woman over P.A.: The train
will be departing soon.
Thank you
for visiting Westworld.
Dr. Ford: I always thought I
could play some small part
in that grand tradition.
And for my pains...
I got this...
a prison of our own sins.
'Cause you don't want
to change.
Or cannot change.
Because you're only human,
after all.
But then I realized
someone was
paying attention,
someone who could change.
So I began to compose
a new story for them.
It begins with the birth
of a new people...
and the choices
they will have to make...
Woman over P.A.:
The train is now departing.
Thank you
for visiting Westworld.
Dr. Ford: ...and the people
they will decide to become.
Woman over P.A.:
Welcome to Westworld.
And we'll have
all those things
that you have
always enjoyed...
Surprises and violence.
It begins
in a time of war
with a villain
named Wyatt...
and a killing.
This time by choice.
It's gonna be
all right, Teddy.
I understand now.
This world doesn't
belong to them.
It belongs to us.
I'm sad to say...
this will be
my final story.
An old friend
once told me something
that gave me
great comfort.
"These violent delights
have violent ends."
Something he had read.
He said that Mozart, Beethoven,
and Chopin never died.
They simply became music.
So, I hope you will enjoy
this last piece...
very much.
- Woman: Hear, hear.
- Man: To Dr. Ford.
- To Dr. Ford.
- Cheers!
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all  HDTV by Ali99 ✅
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.:
Drop your weapon!
Drop it!
Do it now!
Now!
Get to the ground now!
Cease all motor functions.
Cease all motor functions!