▶️ TVWorld Proudly presents ◀️
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.:
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
Old Bill:
You got any stories, friend?
Yeah, I suppose I do.
You want to know the
saddest thing I ever saw?
When I was a boy, my brother
and I wanted a dog,
so our father took in
an old greyhound.
You've never seen a
greyhound, have you, Bill?
Seen a few showdowns
in my day.
A greyhound
is a racing dog.
Spends its life
running in circles,
chasing a bit of felt
made up like a rabbit.
One day, we took it
to the park.
Our dad had warned us
how fast that dog was,
but we couldn't resist.
So, my brother
took off the leash,
and in that instant,
the dog spotted a cat.
I imagine it must have looked
just like that piece of felt.
He ran.
Never saw a thing
as beautiful
as that old dog running.
Until, at last,
he finally caught it.
And to the horror
of everyone,
he killed that little cat.
Tore it to pieces.
Then he just sat there,
confused.
That dog had spent
its whole life
trying to catch
that... thing.
Now it had no idea
what to do.
That is one humdinger
of a story, partner.
Shall we drink to the lady
with the white shoes?
Man:
Find me.
Dolores:
Show me how.
Logan:
There she is.
Pariah...
City of outcasts,
delinquents,
thieves, whores,
and murderers.
Slim:
Once we cross the gates,
you will reap
the full benefits
of El Lazo's gratitude
for my safe return.
Are you all right?
Of course.
Did I do something wrong?
Just earlier, I thought I
heard you talking to someone.
Must have been
the wind.
Good morning.
This way.
Logan: The farther up
we get from Sweetwater,
the more grandiose,
the bigger
the narratives become.
It's beautiful
in its own way.
For once, I agree.
Some of the park feels
like it was designed
by committee
or market-tested,
but everything out here
is more raw.
But it doesn't come cheap.
Rumor is they are
hemorrhaging cash.
We're considering
buying them out.
Supposedly, this place was all
started by a partnership.
And then right before
the park opened,
one of the partners
killed himself.
Sent the park
into a freefall.
I mean, I don't know
any of the details.
I don't even know
his name.
You must have a team of lawyers
looking at this place.
Yeah, well,
they came up empty.
He's a complete mystery.
Not even a picture.
William: Well, whoever
designed this place,
you get the feeling they don't
think very much of people.
Who are they?
They call themselves
"the Army of New Virginia."
Everyone else calls them
"the Confederados."
My father told me
about them.
Ex-Confederate soldiers that refused
to surrender after the war.
Now they work as mercenaries
below the border.
- They are the key to this game.
- What game?
Well, the biggest game
there is... war.
Supposedly, it's at the
far reaches of the park.
Now, I've never made it that far,
but this could be our chance.
Lawrence:
I've known plenty
of truly fucked up
individuals in my time.
Few that would hold
a candle to you, sure.
This one?
Theodore Flood?
He was Wyatt's friend.
Those former associations
are exactly why we need him.
He's going to lead me straight
to the big, bad wolf.
I wouldn't count
on that.
Oh, shit.
Didn't take you
for the charitable type.
You should've left him
on that tree to die.
You believe in fate,
Lawrence?
If the bitch exists,
I'd like to kick her
in the teeth about now.
Don't be so glib.
You'll hurt
my feelings.
As another old friend
of mine likes to say,
"There's a path
for everyone."
Your path leads you
back to me.
You ever wonder why I've kept
you with me this whole journey?
Maybe you like the
pleasure of my company,
you sadistic fuck.
Why, maybe I do.
There's not a man
in the world
who'll take the tone
with me you do.
In a past life, perhaps.
Teddy here's not looking
long for this world.
Nearest healer
is in Pariah.
Ain't no way he's gonna
make it that far.
He's lost
too much blood.
Boy:
Are you lost?
Our friend here's
a little worse for the wear.
Any water nearby, son?
There's a creek on the
other side of the canyon.
Fetch us some, would you?
Now hurry.
Friend here needs some
if he's gonna make it.
Get!
Eh.
Too small.
What does that mean?
What are you sending him
for water for?
I'm the one you made fill up
the sow's bag this morning.
A shame, really.
I always enjoy our time
together, Lawrence.
The fuck is that
supposed to mean?
It means I was wrong.
The path that brought you
here, it wasn't for me.
It was for him.
Sorry, Lawrence.
Guess I'll see you
on the other side.
Sylvester: Uh-oh. It's not
looking good for you.
- Lutz: Closing.
- Forget it, I win.
I always win!
Hey, not fair.
All you had was a smashed
cheekbone and an ear.
You know how hard it is to get
the auricle curves symmetrical?
You had to what?
Plug and patch
of couple bullet holes?
And a knife wound.
It was
a contained incision.
Almost like they were
looking for something.
Are you fucking
kidding me?
You really think this little
fuck puppet's coming to get you?
- Huh?
- It got off the table and ran.
That's 'cause you forgot
to put her in sleep mode.
Yeah, I really think I remembered
You know, that's the thing
about forgetting.
You think you remembered,
but you didn't.
- Break time.
- Yeah!
I've got a ham sandwich
and a nubile redhead
loaded up in the VR tank,
awaiting instruction.
Yes!
Welcome back.
Looks like a couple
of gallons of Lawrence
swirling around in you
did you good.
Ready to get back
on the road?
Merciful thing would be
to put a bullet in me.
Who ever said
I was merciful?
And it's not my fault
you're suffering.
You used to be beautiful.
When this place started,
I opened
one of you up once.
A million
little perfect pieces.
And then they changed you.
Made you this
sad, real mess.
Flesh and bone,
just like us.
They said it would improve
the park experience.
But you know why
they really did it?
It was cheaper.
Your humanity
is cost-effective.
So is your suffering.
Whatever it is
you want from me, mister...
I ain't gonna be worth
a damn to you like this.
Well, that would be
a shame, Teddy.
After your misadventure,
Wyatt killed
a settler family,
made off
with their daughter.
Girl I think you know.
Name of Dolores.
They have Dolores?
There it is.
The magic word.
Hey, much obliged there,
son.
Don't worry about him.
Someone will be along
for him shortly.
Mommy!
Are you all right?
When I ran from home,
I told myself
it was the only way.
Lately, I wondered
if in every moment,
there aren't many paths.
Choices hanging
in the air like ghosts.
And if you could
just see them,
you could change
your whole life.
Is that what you want?
You want to change your life?
Doesn't everybody
want that?
Yeah, I guess they do.
Maybe that's why
they come here.
Whoever you were before
doesn't matter here.
There's no rules
or restrictions.
You can change
the story of your life.
You can become
someone else.
No one will judge you,
no one in the real world
will even know.
The only thing holding
you back is yourself.
What did you mean
by that?
You said no one in the
real world will know.
I thought you weren't supposed
to notice things like that.
Why wouldn't I?
You know, recently,
it seems like the whole
world is calling to me
in a way it hasn't before.
Logan: Billy! Where the hell you been?
Come on.
El Lazo has agreed to have an
audience with y'all tomorrow.
In the meantime, there's
a brothel I recommend.
Logan: Ooh, they have
a contortionist.
Oh, I don't think Dolores would
find that very interesting.
Who the fuck cares
what Dolores wants?
She's a goddamn doll!
Hey, can you not
say that around her?
I swear, I feel like
she understands.
Of course you do.
Woman: Our dead are never dead to
us until we have forgotten them.
Dr. Ford: May you rest in a
deep and dreamless slumber.
Dr. Ford:
Hello, Dolores.
Do you know
where you are?
- I'm in a dream.
- Yes, Dolores.
You're in my dream.
Tell me, do you know
what this dream means?
Dreams are the mind
telling stories to itself.
They don't mean anything.
No, dreams mean
everything.
They're the stories we tell
ourselves of what could be,
who we could become.
Have you been
dreaming again, Dolores?
Imagining yourself
breaking out
of your modest
little loop?
Taking on a bigger role?
Well, I suppose
I can't begrudge you that.
My father told me
to be satisfied
with my lot in life.
That the world
owed me nothing.
And so,
I made my own world.
Tell me, Dolores.
Do you remember
the man I used to be?
I'm sorry.
I'm forgetful sometimes.
Hardly your fault.
But I'm sure
you remember him.
Arnold.
The person
who created you.
I'm sorry, I don't think I
recall anyone by that name.
And yet you can.
Somewhere under all those
updates, he is still there.
Perfectly preserved.
Your mind
is a walled garden.
Even death cannot touch
the flowers blooming there.
Have you been
hearing voices?
Has Arnold been speaking
to you again?
No.
You're...
- You're hurting me.
- Analysis.
When was your last contact
with Arnold?
Last contact: 34 years,
42 days, seven hours ago.
Yes, Dolores.
The day Arnold died.
And you have no records of
any contact with him since?
No.
What was the last thing
he said to you?
He told me
I was going to help him.
Help him do what?
To destroy this place.
But you didn't, did you?
You've been content
in your little loop.
For the most part.
I wonder...
if you did take on that
bigger role for yourself,
would you have been
the hero
or the villain?
That's enough, Dolores.
I'm sorry
for bothering you,
but there's no one else
left who was there,
no one who understands
as we understand.
Are we...
very old friends?
No.
I wouldn't say friends,
Dolores.
I wouldn't say that
at all.
He doesn't know.
I didn't tell him
anything.
That's it.
Come on, little one.
Come on.
What the fuck?
Grab it!
Ah! God...
damn it.
Little shit.
Jesus, tell me... tell me
you're not this stupid.
You stole a bird
and a fucking
behavior tablet?
I wasn't stealing,
I was borrowing.
Haven't got the code right
yet, but with practice...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Is that your ace plan?
You're gonna fix up a birdie
and get yourself a promotion?
You're not
a fucking ornithologist.
And you're sure as hell
not a coder.
You are a butcher.
That is all
you will ever be.
So, unless you want
to score yourself
a one-way ticket
out of here
for misappropriating
corporate property,
you better destroy
that fucking shit.
Now, come on,
we got another body.
What?
It's her.
Again.
Jesus.
How the hell
did you get this job
if you're scared shitless
of these things.
Personality testing should've
weeded you out in the embryo.
Now, come on, let's get
this thing back in rotation.
William: Yesterday, you
seemed out of sorts.
You feeling better
this morning?
I had troubled dreams.
But I feel more myself now.
Guys, come on.
El Lazo awaits.
And I present you
El Lazo!
Logan: You're a
hard man to find.
Most wanted men are.
We saved your man Slim here
from quite a predicament.
In recompense,
I'd like an introduction
to your Confederado friends.
It's only fair.
- There's no such thing as fair here.
- - Sit down.
In Pariah, justice
ain't just blind,
she's crooked.
Bitch's scales
are always tipped.
If you don't see how,
well, that's 'cause
they're tipped against you.
Still, by way
of gratitude,
I can supply you a night
with some
very amenable women.
I've fucked enough whores.
You're gonna need
to sweeten the pot.
How about I sweeten it
by killing you quickly?
There's something
you're seeking, isn't there?
I know what that
feels like.
I'm seeking
something, too.
If you let us,
I know we can help you.
How is it the lunatics
always find their way to me?
Then again,
the Confederados
are missing a few bullets
in their barrels, too.
You folks
just might get along.
A Union convoy's
transporting a shipment
of nitroglycerin
from the front today.
The Confederados would like to
divest them of said shipment,
but we are not welcome
that side of the border.
A trio of travelers
such as yourselves, however...
You want us to help the
Confederados steal from the Union?
They're just gonna
use that nitro
to slaughter your people
below the border.
Personal grudges
hold no sway
where profit is concerned.
Logan:
Oh, we understand.
We're businessmen, too.
El Lazo:
Very well, then.
But blondie here,
she's gonna need a change of
clothes for the occasion.
Logan: Mm.
My, my.
Look who's packing.
I don't aim to use this.
Those men are Union soldiers
like my father was.
I know.
We won't hurt them.
We're gonna stick
to the plan.
We'll take
the nitro and go.
Hyah!
All right.
Showtime.
Soldier: Whoa!
Howdy.
My associates and I are here
to relieve you of your ride.
Someone's been telling
you boys tales.
Nothing in this wagon
worth taking.
The story I heard
is one bullet from us,
and that nothing blows
you all to kingdom come.
Well, then you understand
why we cannot surrender it.
We're sworn to protect
the people
of this young republic from
reckless half-wits like you.
Call me half-wit again.
Please, do as he says.
We don't want to hurt you.
I'd listen to her.
He'll shoot just to see
the fireworks.
Hand them over.
Come on.
Hey, come on down, give me
your guns, everybody lives.
Come on.
Come on,
nice and easy.
Right over here.
A little further, please.
Much obliged.
Thank you.
Here you go.
That's for lying.
Stop!
And that was
for "half-wit."
And this...
Oh!
No!
Logan:
Stop, please.
Stop.
Whoo!
That's the spirit.
I knew you would
get into this place.
Yes!
Yep.
Not bad
for a day's work.
Vamonos.
We told them
everyone would live.
Guys,
looks like Slim
didn't make it.
Whoa.
They put up a fight.
We made them pay
for it, though.
Price of doing business.
Slim knew that.
Had my doubts, El Lazo.
But you came through.
We're gonna blow
these cactus-eaters
back to the dirt holes
they crawled from.
Let's get it down
to the station.
No time to waste.
If I may, Captain,
your men are weary.
It's a long road ahead.
You have secured a great
victory for your cause today.
Perhaps an evening
of celebration's in order.
Anything you desire.
Logan:
What do you say, Captain?
There's another train
in the morning.
You will be a true asset
to our ranks.
Elsie: All right, Bart,
let's try this again.
God damn it, man.
You're still miscalibrating by
four centimeters to the right.
You keep pouring
whiskey on the guests,
I'm gonna have to reassign
you to a narrative
where your...
talents would go
tragically unappreciated.
Hey!
That's the host
that tried to kill me.
Where are you
taking that?
Livestock and then
the incinerator.
Fuck this.
Lutz:
Fuck.
Isn't she
from behavior?
You think they found
something?
All right.
Be cool, dickhead.
- Okay.
- No one's looking at us.
Hi.
You're Destin, right?
That's correct.
I almost didn't recognize
you with your pants on.
- Here.
-
What the fuck?
There's
a common misconception
that the hosts don't log
sexual encounters
when they're underground
for reprocessing,
but like I said,
misconception.
Oh, fuck.
I need something.
QA sent a body down here.
The woodcutter
from Sector 14.
I want to see it.
No, I can't.
I need this job.
Look, Destin,
in a second,
I'm gonna walk out of here
and your friends are gonna
wonder what this was all about.
Now, your answer
can either be,
"I'm helping behavior
track a problem,"
or "I'm a creepy
necro perv."
Up to you.
Five minutes,
then it's going
in the incinerator.
Huh. You took a little
more time than that
for your examination,
didn't you?
All right, big guy.
What were you doing
up there?
What the fuck?
You have been holding out
on me, Maurice.
Oh, shit.
We've got a big problem.
Turns out
our big, dumb friend
had some hidden depths.
That is a laser-based
satellite uplink.
This was in the body
of the host?
Mm-hmm, you were right.
Orion's Belt
has three stars, not four.
Our friend
wasn't drawing stars,
he was drawing a target.
Someone has been
using our hosts
to smuggle data
out of the park.
Now, this...
this I could
get used to.
You're not gonna indulge?
My flesh has tasted
a greater pleasure
than any offered in here...
War.
It's that good, huh?
Another round
on the house.
There's a place
in Glory
for a brown man
who knows his rank.
Captain: You're two able-bodied
men of strong stock.
The road to Glory
could use more warriors
in its fight
for our divine providence.
That is just
what we were thinking.
Come here, come here.
I know you wanna... you
wanna play the war game,
but I'm not going anywhere
with these psychopaths.
If you don't like them,
once we get to the fun,
you can just kill them
and join the Revolutionaries.
No, Logan,
enough's enough.
I'm not doing this.
You actually
let loose for once.
You shoot an unarmed man,
and now you feel bad
because you can't
call yourself the hero.
Don't you get it yet?
There is no such thing
as heroes or villains.
It's just a giant...
circle jerk.
I think that philosophy
says way more about you
than it does
about the world.
And you... you see
the world so clearly?
You probably think
you're on this trip
because you're
some kind of contender,
some...
Some threat to me.
I picked you
precisely because
you will never be
a threat to anyone.
My sister probably picked
you for the same reason.
I earned my place.
Nobody handed it to me.
Right, a lifetime
of working hard,
following the rules,
and you finally reach
the pinnacle of your
career trajectory...
Executive vice president,
upper middle management.
Do you remember the day that you finally
got those three fancy little letters?
EVP.
You walked into my office in
that cheap black suit of yours,
and you shook my hand
and you thanked me
for the opportunity.
That was the best day
of your life.
Right, buddy.
That's what I thought.
What does it mean?
The maze...
You must follow
the maze.
What's wrong with me?
Perhaps you are
unraveling.
Man:
Right here.
El Lazo: Easy pumping
that nitro into him.
Fill the empties with
tequila and seal them up.
Your work
for the revolution
is not quite done yet,
my friend.
Careful.
Slim always had
a bad temper.
William,
we have to go now.
Lazo's been conning us
the whole time.
He was never gonna give the
nitro to the Confederados.
We have to run.
Of course we do.
That's how
this place works, right?
They create an urgency,
a sense of danger
so they can strip us down
to something raw,
animalistic,
primal.
It's a sick game, and I don't
want to be a part of it.
This isn't a game.
They'll kill us.
But together,
I know we can find
a way out.
How can you be sure?
There's a voice
inside me
telling me
what I have to do.
And it's telling me
I need you.
Shit.
They have Logan.
Help me.
No.
No more pretending.
I thought you had no
appetite for war, boy.
This is
a declaration of war.
El Lazo set us up.
We can find him
for you.
You can find him for us
by joining him in hell.
Ah!
Dolores, run!
Dolores?
How did you do that?
You said people come here
to change the story
of their lives.
I imagined a story where I
didn't have to be the damsel.
That train
is our only chance
of making it
out of here alive.
Motherfuckers.
You pull that trigger,
we'll all go up
in a ball of hellfire.
So, why don't you
loosen your grip a mite?
It's okay.
I don't trust him.
Which is the first step
to truly knowing me.
Give me your gun,
El Lazo.
Now that we're all friends,
you can call me Lawrence.
And why don't
we settle in?
It's a long ride
to the front.
You want a sip
of this swill?
Lawrence: Don't worry,
it ain't nitro.
I'm coming.
Girls are a little worn
out, but I can rouse one.
- You boys want some company?
- No, just whiskey.
Lawrence's donation
must be running low.
But we're short on time.
You need
to buck up, Teddy.
Man in Black:
I told you no company.
Thought I might
join you anyway,
as I never like
to drink alone.
Well...
isn't this a rare honor?
Teddy...
you know who this is?
I can't say that I do.
Everything good that has
ever happened in your life
and everything rotten,
this is the man
you have to thank.
How I'm doing, Robert?
Any closer to finding
what I'm looking for?
And what is that, exactly?
Teddy: Looking for
a man named Wyatt.
Killed a rancher
back in Sweetwater.
Took his daughter.
That last part
doesn't sound familiar.
Figured your stories
could use a little
embellishment.
You know,
I always felt this place
was missing
a real villain.
Hence my humble
contribution.
I admit, I lack
the imagination
to even conceive
of someone like you.
The urgency, however, doesn't
quite fit the character.
It betrays
a certain anxiety.
Now, Wyatt,
on the other hand,
that's something new.
Is he just another stooge for the
tourists to mount on their wall at home,
or have you finally made
a worthy adversary?
Someone to stop me
from finding
the center of the maze?
And what is it you're
hoping to find there?
You know why
you exist, Teddy?
The world out there,
the one you'll never see,
was one of plenty.
A fat, soft teat people
cling to their entire life.
Every need taken
care of except one...
Purpose,
meaning.
So they come here.
They can be a little scared,
a little thrilled,
enjoy some sweetly
affirmative bullshit,
and then they take
a fucking picture
and they go back home.
But I think there's
a deeper meaning
hiding under all that.
Something the person who
created it wanted to express.
Something true.
Well, if you're looking
for the moral of the story,
you could simply ask.
I'd need a shovel.
The man I'd be asking
died 35 years ago.
Almost took this place
with him.
Almost, but not quite,
thanks to me.
Or maybe he left
something behind.
I wonder
what I would find
if I open you up.
Even at death's door,
you're still a loyal pet.
Is that why
you came here, Robert?
Try to talk me
out of it?
On the contrary.
Far be it from me
to get in the way
of a voyage
of self-discovery.
Mr. Flood,
we must look back
and smile
at perils past,
mustn't we?
We should get back
on the road.
Time's wasting.
Maeve:
Hello, Felix.
It's time
you and I had a chat.
» Extracted & Re-synced & Corrected for all HDTV by Ali99 ✅
:.:.: TvWorld.iNFO :.:.: