You are the last man
whom I could ever marry!
Do you think any consideration
would tempt me?
Your arrogance, your conceit,
and your selfish disdain
for the feelings of others!
My opinion of you was
decided when I heard
Mr Wickham's story
of your dealings with him.
Well at least in that I
may defend myself.
Could you expect me to rejoice
in the inferiority of your connections?
To congratulate myself
on the hope of relations
whose conditions in life
is so below my own?
You are mistaken, Mr Darcy.
Your declaration merely spared me the
concern I might have
felt in refusing you,
had you behaved in a more
gentleman-like manner.
Who's there, Fitzwilliam?
- Darcy! We'd quite despaired of you!
- Is that my nephew?
Where have you been?
Let him come in and explain himself!
No. You will forgive me.
You'll forgive me.
Darcy, you are unwell?
I'm very well, thank you, but I have a
pressing matter of business.
You'll forgive me.
Make my apologies to
Lady Catherine, Fitzwilliam.
To Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
Be not alarmed, madam,
on receiving this letter,
that it contains any repetition
of those sentiments
or offers which were this
evening so disgusting to you.
But I must be allowed to defend myself
against the charges laid at my door.
In particular those
relating to Mr Wickham,
which if true, would indeed be grievous,
but are wholly without foundation,
and which I can only refute
by laying before you
his connection with my family.
Mr Wickham is the son
of a very respectable man,
who had the management of our estates.
My own father was fond of him
and held him in high esteem.
We played together as boys.
After his father's early death,
my father supported him at school
and at Cambridge, and hoped
he would make the church his profession.
But by then George Wickham's
habits were as dissolute
as his manners were engaging.
My own excellent
father died five years ago.
His attachment to Mr Wickham
was to the last so steady,
that he desired that a
valuable family living
might be his as soon as it was vacant.
Mr Wickham declined any
interest in the church as a career,
but requested, and was granted,
the sum of 3,000 pounds
instead of the living.
He expressed an intention
of studying the law.
I wished, rather than
believed him to be sincere.
Thank you.
I'm most exceedingly obliged.
All connection between us
seemed now dissolved.
Georgiana.
Being now free from all restraint,
his life was one of
idleness and dissipation.
How he lived, I know not.
But last summer our paths crossed again,
under the most painful circumstances,
which I myself would wish to forget.
My sister, Georgiana,
who is more than ten years my junior,
was left to the guardianship
of Colonel Fitzwilliam and myself.
About a year ago, she was taken
from school to Ramsgate,
and placed in the care of a Mrs Younge,
in whose character we were
most unhappily deceived.
And thither also went Mr Wickham,
undoubtedly by design.
She was persuaded to believe herself in
love, and to consent to an elopement.
She was then but fifteen years old.
A day or two before the intended
elopement, I joined them unexpectedly.
Unable to support the
idea of grieving a brother
whom she looked up
to almost as a father,
she acknowledged the whole
plan to me at once.
You may imagine what I felt
and how I acted.
Mr Wickham left the place immediately.
Come.
Mr Wickham relinquished his object,
which was of course, my sister's
fortune of 30,000.
A secondary motive must have been
to revenge himself on me.
Had he succeeded, his revenge would
have been complete indeed.
This, madam, is a faithful narrative
of all my dealings with Mr Wickham.
You do look pale, Lizzy.
Why don't you have some breakfast?
I'm sure it will do you good.
I am well, Charlotte.
I've stayed indoors too long.
Fresh air and exercise is all I need.
The woods around Rosings are
so beautiful at this time of year.
Miss Bennet!
Mr Darcy.
I've been walking the grove some time
in the hope of meeting you.
Will you do me the honour
of reading this letter?
This, madam, is a faithful
narrative of my
dealings with Mr Wickham,
and for its truth I can appeal to the
testimony of Colonel Fitzwilliam,
who knows every particular
of these transactions.
I know not under what form of falsehood
Mr Wickham imposed himself on you,
but I hope you'll acquit me
of cruelty towards him.
I found that I'd better
not meet Mr Darcy.
Scenes might arise,
unpleasant to more than myself.
The other charge levelled at me,
is that regardless of the
sentiments of either party,
I detached Mr Bingley from your sister.
I have no wish to deny this,
nor can I blame myself for any
of my actions in this matter.
I had not long been in Hertfordshire
before I saw that Bingley
admired your sister,
but it was not until
the dance at Netherfield
that I suspected a serious attachment.
His partiality was clear,
but though she received
his attentions with pleasure,
I did not detect any
symptoms of peculiar regard.
The serenity of her countenance
convinced me that her heart
was not likely to be easily touched.
Insufferable presumption!
I did not wish to believe
her to be indifferent.
I believed it on impartial conviction.
Very impartial!
You've missed the two gentlemen!
They came to take their leave!
Mr Darcy came here?
He went away directly, but the Colonel
waited for you over half an hour!
Now they are gone abroad!
I dare say we shall be able
to bear the deprivation.
As to my objections to the marriage,
the situation of your family,
though objectionable,
was nothing in comparison with
the total want of propriety
so frequently betrayed by your mother,
your younger sisters,
and even occasionally your father.
That will do extremely well, child.
You have delighted us long enough.
Now there will be a great marriage!
And you know, that will throw the girls
into the paths of other rich men!
My friend left Netherfield for London
on the following day.
There I pointed out to
him the certain evils of
his choice of your sister
as a prospective bride.
It was not difficult to convince him
of your sister's indifference to him.
I cannot blame myself for
having done thus much.
For destroying all her
hope of happiness?
Yes, I'm sure you do not blame yourself.
Hateful man!
There is but one part of my conduct
in the affair on which I do not
reflect with satisfaction.
Astonish me!
That I concealed from him
your sister's being in town.
Perhaps this concealment was beneath me.
It was done, however, for the best.
On this subject I have nothing more to
say, and no other apology to offer.
Insufferable!
- Lizzy!
- Charlotte, we will be late!
Lizzy!
I have endeavoured
to count the times
Lady Catherine has invited
us since your arrival.
I believe it may be as
many as ten invitations!
- Eleven, counting this one!
- Eleven!
There! You have indeed been favoured
with peculiar condescension.
- Do you not agree, Miss Elizabeth?
- Oh... yes!
How could anybody think otherwise?
And this is your last invitation,
on this visit, at least.
It is truly a very cruel deprivation.
I hardly know how I'll bear the loss of
her ladyship's company!
You feel it keenly!
Yes, of course you do,
my poor young cousin.
They were such fine young men,
and so particularly attached to me!
They were excessively sorry to go,
but so they always are!
The dear Colonel rallied
his spirits tolerably,
but Darcy seemed to
feel it most acutely.
His attachment to
Rosings certainly increases.
You are very dull this evening,
Miss Elizabeth Bennet.
You have scarce spoke two words
together. Are you so out of spirits?
- No indeed, madam.
- Of course you are,
to be going away yourself.
Who indeed would not be sad
to be deprived of Rosings,
and indeed of the gracious...
You will write to your mother
and say you wish to stay longer.
Surely she could spare
you for another fortnight.
But my father cannot.
He wrote to hurry my return.
Your ladyship is very kind,
but I believe we must
leave as planned on Friday.
Your father may spare
you if your mother can.
Daughters are never of much
consequence to a father.
And if you will stay
another month complete,
it will be in my power to take you
as far as London myself,
in the Barouche box!
For I cannot bear the idea of two young
women travelling post by themselves.
It is highly improper!
I am excessively attentive
to all those things.
My uncle is to send a servant for us
when we change to the post.
Your uncle!
He keeps a manservant, does he?
I'm very glad you have somebody
who thinks of these things.
Where will you change horses?
- At Brom...
- Bromley, of course.
Mention my name at the Bell
and they will attend you.
Your ladyship is very kind.
Indeed, we are all infinitely
indebted to your ladyship's
kindly bestowed solicitude...
Yes, yes, but this is
all extremely vexing!
I'm quite put out.
What are you doing? I thought the trunks
went outside before breakfast.
Lady Catherine was so severe about the
only right way to place gowns,
that I couldn't sleep,
and I'm determined to start afresh!
Maria, this is your trunk
and your gowns.
You may arrange them in any way you
wish. Lady Catherine will never know!
My dear sister,
you'll have much to tell your father...
Bring that one round here.
Well, cousin...
you have seen for yourself now
the happiness of our situation.
Our intimacy at Rosings is a blessing
of which few could boast!
- Indeed they could not.
- Indeed.
Now you have seen our felicity.
Perhaps you may think your friend
has made a fortunate alliance.
Perhaps more so than...
But on this point it will
be as well to be silent.
You are very good.
Only let me assure you that I can,
from my heart,
most cordially wish you
equal felicity in marriage.
Charlotte and I have but one mind
and one way of thinking.
We seem to have been
designed for each other!
Oh, Lizzy! It seems but a day or two
since we first came!
- And yet how many things have happened!
- A great many, indeed.
We have dined
nine times at Rosings!
Oh, how much I shall have to tell!
How much I shall have to conceal.
You must allow me to tell you
how ardently I admire and love you.
Lizzy!
To see your faces when you looked up!
You didn't expect we'd come to meet you.
No, we did not.
There! Is not this nice?
Cold ham, and pork,
and salads, and every good thing!
We mean to treat you, but you must
lend us money, we spent ours. Look!
It's not pretty,
but I thought I'd buy it anyway.
It's vile, isn't it?
Very ugly.
What possessed you to buy it?
There were two or three much uglier!
I shall pull it to pieces
and see if I can make it up any better.
It doesn't signify what anyone wears,
for the regiment
will be at Brighton the whole summer!
Our hearts are broken!
And papa refuses to take us to Brighton.
- I'm glad to hear it.
- Shouldn't you like to go to Brighton?
- I should not.
- She would.
She would love it, when she hears the
news about a certain person we know!
- Shall we tell her?
- Yes, and see if she blushes!
You may go.
We'll call if you're needed again.
Very good, miss.
Wickham is not to marry
Mary King after all!
She's been taken away to Liverpool
and Wickham is safe!
Perhaps we should say Mary King is safe.
Was there a very strong attraction
between them, do you think?
Not on his side! I shouldn't think
he cared three straws about her.
Who could about such a
nasty freckled little thing?
Don't look at me like that, Lizzy.
You think just as ill of her!
Pass the celery, Kitty.
Glad we came to meet you?
It'll be merry on the journey home.
Kitty, you're
squashing my bandbox!
You should
have put it on the roof!
If you don't lollop
about there is room.
I don't lollop, you do!
Mr Darcy proposed!
I can scarce believe it!
Not that anyone admiring you
should be astonishing.
But he always seemed so severe,
so cold, apparently.
And yet he was in love with
you all the time! Poor Mr Darcy.
I cannot feel so much
compassion for him.
He has other feelings which will soon
drive away any regard he felt for me.
- You do not blame me for refusing him?
- Blame you? Oh, no.
But you do blame me for speaking
so warmly of Wickham?
No. How could you have
known about his vicious character?
If indeed he was so very bad.
But I cannot believe Mr Darcy would
fabricate such dreadful slander,
involving his own sister too.
No, it must be true.
Perhaps there has been
some terrible mistake.
No, Jane. That won't do!
You can't make them both good!
There is just enough merit between them
to make one good sort of man.
And for my part I'm inclined to
believe it's all Mr Darcy's.
Poor Mr Darcy.
Poor Mr Wickham!
There is such an expression
of goodness in his countenance.
Yes.
I'm afraid one has all the goodness,
and the other all the appearance of it!
But Lizzy, I am sure that when you
first read that letter,
you could not have made so
light of it as you do now.
Indeed I could not.
I was very uncomfortable.
Till that moment I never knew myself.
And I had no Jane to comfort me.
Oh, how I wanted you!
There is one point on
which I want your advice.
Should our general acquaintance be
informed of Wickham's true character?
Surely there can be no occasion
to expose him so cruelly.
- What is your opinion?
- That it oughtn't be attempted.
Mr Darcy has not authorised
me to make it public,
especially as regards his sister.
As for the rest, who would believe it?
The general prejudice against
Mr Darcy is so violent,
and Wickham will soon be gone.
I believe we should
say nothing at present.
Yes, I agree.
Perhaps he is sorry now
for what he has done,
and is anxious to
re-establish his character.
We must not make him desperate.
Oh, Jane! I wish I could think
so well of people as you do.
Won't you speak to papa, Lizzy,
about our going to Brighton?
You know he listens to your advice.
You flatter me, Lydia. In any case,
I shouldn't attempt to persuade him.
I think it's a very good thing that the
regiment is removed from Meryton,
and that we are removed
from the regiment.
Oh, Lizzy,
how can you say such a thing?
Very easily, ma'am.
If one company causes
such havoc in our family,
what would a whole
campful of soldiers do?
A whole campful of soldiers!
I remember when I was a girl.
I cried for two days when
Colonel Miller's regiment went away.
I thought I should have broke my heart!
I shall break mine.
And I!
There, there, my dears.
But your father is
determined to be cruel.
I confess I am.
I'm sorry to be breaking hearts,
but I have no intention of yielding.
I shall not break my heart, papa.
The pleasures of Brighton
would have no charms for me.
I should infinitely prefer a book.
Mrs Forster says she
plans to go sea-bathing.
I am sure I should love
to go sea-bathing!
A little sea-bathing
would set me up forever!
And yet, I am unmoved.
Well, well.
I'm glad you are come back, Lizzy.
I'm glad you are come back, Jane.
I want to go to Brighton!
You are not happy, Jane.
- It pains me to see it.
- It is just that I did...
I'm afraid I still do prefer Mr Bingley
to any other man I've met,
and Lizzy, I did believe he...
Well, I was mistaken, that is all.
I am resolved to think of him no more.
There. Enough.
I shall be myself again,
as if I had never set eyes on him.
Truly, Lizzy, I promise.
I shall be well.
I shall be myself again.
I shall be perfectly content.
Well, Lizzy, what do you think now
about this sad business of Jane's?
I cannot find out that she saw
anything of Bingley in London.
Well.
An undeserving young man!
And I don't suppose there's any
chance of her getting him now.
If he should come back
to Netherfield, though.
I think there's little
chance of that, mamma.
Oh, well. Just as he chooses.
No one wants him to come!
I shall always say he used
my daughter extremely ill!
If I was her,
I would not have put up with it.
My comfort is,
she will die of a broken heart,
and then he'll be sorry
for what he's done!
So, the Collinses live
quite comfortable, do they?
I only hope it will last.
And I suppose they talk about having
this house too when your father is dead?
They look on it as quite their own,
I dare say?
They could hardly discuss such
a subject in front of me.
I make no doubt they talk about it
constantly when they're alone!
If they can be easy with an estate
that is not lawfully their own,
so much the better!
I should be ashamed of having one
that was only entailed upon me!
Mamma, mamma! Lizzy!
Guess what!
You never will, so I'll tell you.
Mrs Forster has invited me,
as her particular friend,
to go with her to Brighton.
Colonel Forster is to
take a house for us!
I'm so happy!
- What an honour, to be singled out!
- Is it not unfair, Lizzy?
Mrs Forster should
have asked me as well.
I may not be her dearest friend,
but have as much right to be asked!
And more too, for I am two years older!
I'll buy her a present, I dare say.
There's no call to be in a miff because
Mrs Forster likes me best.
Before you crow too loud, remember papa
has not given you permission to go.
Nor is he like to.
Papa won't stop me.
Not when I'm invited by the Colonel to
be his wife's particular companion!
I need new clothes,
for I've nothing fit to wear, and there
will be balls and parties!
Of course you shall have new things!
We wouldn't see you disgraced
in front of all the officers!
Oo! All the officers!
I understand your concern,
my dear, but consider:
Lydia will never be easy until she has
exposed herself in some public place,
and here is an opportunity
for her to do so,
with very little expense
or inconvenience to her family.
If you were aware of the very
great disadvantage to us all,
which has already arisen from Lydia's
unguarded and imprudent manner,
you'd judge differently.
Already arisen? Has she frightened
away some of your lovers?
Don't be cast down, Lizzy.
Such squeamish youths are
not worth your regret.
- Oh come, Lizzy.
- Indeed you are mistaken.
I have no injuries to resent. I speak
of general, not particular evils.
Our...
position as a family,
our very respectability,
is called into question by
Lydia's wild behaviour.
I must speak plainly.
If you do not check her,
she will soon be beyond
the reach of amendment.
She will become the
most determined flirt
that ever made herself
and her family ridiculous!
You know that Kitty
follows wherever Lydia leads.
Don't you see that they will be censured
and despised wherever they are known?
And that they will involve their
sisters in their disgrace.
Lizzy, come here.
Don't make yourself uneasy, my love.
Wherever you and Jane are known,
you must be respected and valued.
And you will not appear to any less
advantage for having a couple or...
I may say, three very silly sisters.
We shall have no peace at Longbourn
if Lydia does not go to Brighton.
Colonel Forster is a sensible man.
And luckily she's too poor to be an
object of prey to a fortune hunter.
Leave it now, Lizzy.
I believe all will turn out well.
We are so desolated, Colonel,
that the regiment is to leave Meryton,
but words cannot express what we feel
about your kindness to our dear Lydia.
Well, ma'am, it appears that
Mrs Forster cannot do without her.
Look at the pair of them.
Thick as thieves!
Lord knows what they find to talk about.
But anything to keep the ladies happy.
What do you say, Wickham?
I say amen to that, sir.
There's one lady I shall be
very loath to part from.
We must try to bear it.
You are for Brighton,
I'll be touring the Lakes
with my aunt and uncle.
I dare say we'll find ample sources
of consolation and delight...
in our different ways.
Perhaps. How did you find Rosings?
Interesting. Colonel Fitzwilliam was
there with Mr Darcy.
Are you acquainted with the Colonel?
I...
To some respects, yes, in former years.
A very gentlemanly man.
- How did you like him?
- I liked him very much.
His manners are very
different from his cousin's.
Yes.
But I think Mr Darcy improves
on closer acquaintance.
Indeed?
In what respect?
Has he acquired a touch
of civility in his address?
For I dare not hope he
is improved in essentials.
No. In essentials,
I believe he is very much...
as he ever was.
Ah.
I don't mean to imply
that either his mind
or his manners are
changed for the better.
My knowing him better
improved my opinion of him.
I see.
Wickham. Wickham.
- Come here.
- At your service, ma'am!
Yes, go, go.
I would not wish you back again.
Goodbye, papa. Goodbye, mamma.
Lydia, my dear,
we shall miss you most cruelly!
I shall write every day of what I'm
doing and make you wild with envy.
- I can't help it!
- I shall not envy her a jot!
I must go. Goodbye, Jane.
Goodbye, Lizzy!
If I see any eligible beaux for you,
I'll send word express!
Lord, what a laugh if I should fall
and break my head!
I wish you would!
Oh, my dear girl. Take every
opportunity of enjoying yourself!
Bye! Bye!
Never mind, Kitty.
I dare say, in a year or two
you'll have got over it tolerably well.
If anyone should ask for me, I shall be
in my library, and not to be disturbed.
Hello! I can see, I can see
Alicia. Look how she has grown!
You must be so tired.
You have all grown! I think you've all
grown since we last said goodbye!
And very pretty too!
Come into the house, then.
Such a sweet, steady girl!
Well, Lizzy!
We bear you bad tidings.
Not too grievous though, I hope.
The guilt is mine.
My business won't allow me
time away to visit all the Lake country.
We shall have to content
ourselves with Derbyshire.
Oh.
But Derbyshire has many
beauties, has it not?
Indeed. To me Derbyshire
is the best of all counties.
You will judge for yourself whether
Chatsworth is not the equal of Blenheim.
And surely these southern counties
have nothing to compare to the wild
and untamed beauty of the Peaks.
Nature and culture
in harmony, you see, Lizzy.
Wildness and artifice,
and all in the one perfect county!
I was born here,
so I should never disagree with that!
Where?
At Lambton,
a town of no consequence,
but to those fortunate
enough to have lived in it.
I think it the dearest
place in the world!
Then I shall not be
happy till I have seen it.
It has one further
claim on your interest:
it is but five miles from Pemberley,
and owes much of its
prosperity to that great estate.
So near?
Not that I or anyone of my acquaintance
enjoyed the privilege
of intimacy with that family.
We moved in very different circles.
A hit! Acknowledged. Very good, sir!
- Enough, sir?
- Enough. Thank you, Baines.
- Will you come again tomorrow, sir?
- No, I have business in the North.
- I'll come tomorrow week.
- Very good, sir. Bid you good day, sir.
Thank you, Baines. Good day.
I shall conquer this. I shall!
Elizabeth, be careful!
How could I face your
father if you took a fall?
Beautiful!
- Thank you, Hannah.
- You're welcome, sir.
I should be quite happy to stay
my whole life in Derbyshire!
I'm happy to hear it. What do you say
to visiting Pemberley tomorrow?
It's not more than a mile
or two out of our way.
Do you especially wish to see it, aunt?
I thought you would,
having heard so much about it.
The associations are
not all unpleasant.
Wickham passed all
his youth there, you know.
We have no business there.
I should feel awkward to visit the place
without a proper invitation.
No more than Blenheim or Chatsworth.
There was no awkwardness there.
I shouldn't care for it myself, Lizzy,
if it were merely a fine house,
richly furnished.
But the grounds are delightful.
They have some of the
finest woods in the country.
- How far is Pemberley, my dear?
- Not more than five miles, sir.
The grounds are very fine, are they not?
As fine as you'll see anywhere, ma'am.
My oldest brother is
an under-gardener there.
- Is the family here for the summer?
- No, ma'am.
Well?
Perhaps we might visit
Pemberley after all.
I think we've seen
woods and groves enough
to satisfy even your
enthusiasm for them, Lizzy!
I confess I had no idea Pemberley
was such a great estate.
Shall we reach the house
itself before dark?
Be patient. Wait.
There!
Stop the coach!
I think one would put up with a good
deal to be mistress of Pemberley.
The mistress of Pemberley will
have to put up with a good deal,
from what I hear.
She's not likely to be anyone we know.
- How do you like the house, Lizzy?
- Very well.
I don't think I've ever seen a
place so happily situated.
I like it very well indeed.
Drive on!
A pity then, its owner should be
such a proud and disagreeable man.
Yes, a great pity.
Perhaps the beauty of the house
renders its owner a little
less repulsive, Lizzy?
Yes, perhaps.
Perhaps a very little.
Well, shall we apply to the housekeeper
to see inside the place?
That's where Mrs Darcy used to
write her letters every morning.
It was her favourite room.
This is the music room.
- Charming!
- What a lovely room!
Delightful!
And there's a fine prospect from that
window down towards the lake.
- Look at this, my dear.
- It's quite magnificent!
Of all this I might have been mistress.
This piano has just come down.
It's a present from my
master for Miss Georgiana.
Your master is from home,
we understand.
Yes, but we expect
him here tomorrow, sir.
He is coming with a large party of
friends and Miss Georgiana.
This portrait was painted earlier this
year, for her sixteenth birthday.
She is a very handsome young lady!
Oh, yes! The handsomest young
lady that ever was seen.
And so accomplished.
She plays and sings all day long!
Lizzy!
Look at this picture.
It reminds me very much
of someone we know!
This one, ma'am?
That young gentleman was the son of the
late Mr Darcy's steward, Mr Wickham.
He is gone into the army now.
But he's turned out very wild.
Very wild indeed, I'm afraid.
And that's my master.
And very like him too.
It's a handsome face,
but I've never seen the original.
Is it like him, Lizzy?
- Does this young lady know the master?
- Yes, a little.
And he is a handsome gentleman,
is he not, ma'am?
- Yes, very handsome.
- I'm sure I know none so handsome.
- Nor so kind.
- Indeed?
Aye, sir.
I've never had a cross word from him,
and I've known him since
he was four years old.
I've observed that they that are
good-natured as children,
are good-natured when they grow up.
His father was an excellent man.
He was, ma'am.
His son will be just like him.
The best landlord, and the best master.
Ask any of his tenants or his servants.
Some call him proud. I fancy that's only
because he don't rattle away,
like other young men do.
Now if you will follow me,
there's a finer, larger portrait of
him in the gallery upstairs.
This way, sir, if you please.
This fine account of
Darcy is not quite consistent
with his behaviour to poor Wickham.
Perhaps we might have
been deceived there.
That's not likely, is it?
Ah!
Magnificent!
There!
Would you not
like to ride him, sir?
No, take
him back to the stables.
Mr Darcy.
Miss Bennet. I...
I did not expect to see you, sir.
We understood the family were from home,
or we should never have...
I returned a day early.
Excuse me,
your parents are in good health?
Yes, they are very well.
I thank you, sir.
I'm glad to hear it.
How long have you been in
this part of the country?
But two days, sir.
- Where are you staying?
- Lambton Inn.
Yes, of course.
Well, I'm just arrived myself.
And your parents are in good health?
And all your sisters?
Yes, they are all in
excellent health, sir.
Excuse me.
- The man himself, I presume!
- As handsome as in his portrait.
Though perhaps a little
less formally attired.
We must leave here at once!
- Of course, if you wish.
- Oh, I wish we'd never come!
- What must he think of me?
- What did he say?
Nothing of consequence.
He enquired after my parents...
Miss Bennet.
Allow me to apologise for not receiving
you properly. Were you leaving?
We were, sir. I think we must.
I hope you are not
displeased with Pemberley?
No, not at all.
Then you approve of it?
Very much.
I think there are few who would not.
Your good opinion is rarely bestowed,
and therefore more worth the earning.
Thank you.
Would you introduce me to your friends?
Certainly.
Mr and Mrs Edward Gardiner, Mr Darcy.
Mrs Gardiner is my aunt, Mr Darcy.
My sister Jane stayed at their house in
Cheapside when she was in London.
Delighted to make your acquaintance,
madam, sir.
You're staying at Lambton, I hear.
Yes, sir. I grew up there as a girl.
Delightful village.
I ran to Lambton as a boy almost every
day in the horse-chestnut season.
- There was one very fine tree there.
- On the green, by the smithy!
- Mr Gardiner, do you care for fishing?
- Indeed I do, when I get the chance.
You must fish in my trout stream.
There are carp, tench and pike in
the lake, for coarse fishing.
I'll gladly provide you with rods and
tackle, show you the best spots.
Let's walk down now.
Follow us to the lake.
My man will show you.
There's a place down there
where we...
Is this the proud Darcy you told us of?
He is all ease and friendliness.
No false dignity at all!
I'm as astonished as you are.
I can't imagine what has
affected this transformation.
Can you not?
- Do you...
- I...
Pray continue.
I was going to say again, sir,
how very unexpected your arrival was.
If we had known you were to be here,
we should not have
dreamt of invading your privacy.
The housekeeper assured us
you would not be here until tomorrow.
Do not make yourself uneasy.
I had planned it so myself,
but I found I had
business with my steward.
I rode on ahead
of the rest of the party.
They will join me tomorrow.
And among them are those who claim
an acquaintance with you.
It's Mr Bingley and his sisters.
Oh.
There is the other
person in the party who
more particularly wishes to know you.
Will you allow me to...
Do I ask too much to introduce my sister
to you, during your stay at Lambton?
I should be very happy to
make her acquaintance.
Thank you.
I hope we shall meet again very soon.
Good day, Mr Gardiner. Mrs Gardiner.
Good day, Miss Bennet.