( Beeps )
Focus, deputy.
Remember your trainin'.
Easy, easy...
You're almost there.
Dang it! I almost
got the treasure!
The time we spend together
is treasure enough.
( Rumbling )
hey! You feel that?
Aah!
aaah!
Reckon we should
report that.
Or go for a ride
in our new convertible!
Yeee!
ha ha ha ha!
( Eerie screeching )
В™єв™є
Stan:
ladies and gentlemen,
continuing our mystery tour,
you'll see the world famous
outhouse of mystery.
I got stuck in there once!
Could I go
to the bathroom?
Save all questions
until after the tour.
( Groans )
Ohh.
And up ahead
if you look really closely--
everybody get your cameras,
you're gonna
want to see this...
Oink.
finally, waddles,
we have the whole house
to ourselves!
What do you think,
dance party?
( Snorts )
I'm not hearing a no!
В™єв™є
yes! yes! Yes!
Yes! yes! Yes...
Uh...
Uh-oh, cuddle time.
Ha ha ha!
Waddles, can i
tell you a secret?
You're my favorite pig
in the whole world.
( Snorts )
( Yawns )
( Chuckling )
Oh!
Mabel! what are you
doing on the floor?
Being cute and great.
And I thought
your brother was weird.
No, he's more like,
"oh! Let's solve a mystery!
I kiss a pillow with
Wendy's face drawn on it."
Ha ha!
That's pretty good!
Kissin' a pillow.
Go! go!
Chew that pant leg!
Uhh! nyah! Nyah!
All right, outside. Now!
No! grunkle Stan!
It's not safe for waddles
outside.
There's predators!
And barbecuers!
That's just
the natural order.
It's not my fault
your pig's potentially
delicious.
He should be inside
like a person.
People don't roll around
in their own filth.
Except for Soos.
And we're the lesser for it!
Maybe we're the ones
who should be put outside.
Huh? huh?
Think about it!
Hmph!
Today's the day, Soos.
Thanks for coming along
on this mission.
Dude, it's an honor.
Today I'm sweating
from heat and excitement.
Whew!
There's something hiding
in these woods.
Something big enough to rip
the roof off a car.
If we get a photo
of this thing,
we'll be heroes!
Yeah, we'll get
all the babes.
You'll be fending off smooches
with a stick!
Ha ha!
Shut up, man.
With a stick, dude.
Here. give me a boost.
Oof! got it.
Uhh. is sap supposed
to be this sticky?
If everything goes
according to plan,
the creature
will grab that steak,
cross through the string,
and set off
cameras a, b, and c.
And nothing can go wrong.
High five.
Uhh!
uhh!
This was poorly planned.
( Loud whoosh, roaring )
( Both gasp )
TV narrator: Hey, you!
Me?
Sick of constantly
dropping your baby?
Yes!
Hi! I'm Bobby renzobbi,
and what you need is
the huggy wuvvy tummy bundle!
I can hold ten babies at once!
Bobby:
i know what you're thinkin'--
"does it work for pigs?"
Ah ha ha!
Yeah, it does
work for pigs, stupid!
Feel your pig's heartbeat
next to yours!
It works for p-i-i-i-i-gs!
( Oinking )
(Gasps) grunkle Stan!
I'm off to get
a huggy wuvvy
tummy bundle!
Yeesh! isn't knitting
matching sweaters
for that pig enough?
Nope. anyway,
i need you to look after
this little gentleman
while I'm gone.
Not now, kid. I got
some tourists comin' through.
Grunkle Stan,
i know you're not
crazy about waddles.
He's a fat, naked jerk!
But you do care about me.
Promise me you won't
let him outside?
Fine! yeah, yeah,
i promise.
Thanks, grunkle Stan!
( Oinking )
I'm watching you, pig.
( Snorts )
ehh!
We did it!
It tripped the wire!
Somewhere in these cameras
is a photo of that creature!
I'll go develop the film.
I'll go make us
victory nachos.
Dipper and Soos for life!
( Both laughing )
Stan: and here,
ladies and gentlemen,
is our final exhibit,
the most hideous creatures
known to man!
( All laughing )
oh, it's us!
Right, right. We...
We have fun here.
But seriously, folks,
this is something.
I present to you
a unicorn
made out of corn:
The cornicorn!
I-i don't know.
I'm tired.
( All gasp )
What the--?!
What a rip-off!
Kids, we're leaving.
No! noooo!
Grrr. you!
Come on, come on...
Hmm.
That's a wing!
If camera b got the wing,
then the one that
should have got the rest is...
Camera c!
The creature!
Who wants victory nachos?
No!
Dude, don't worry.
I only ate like
a third of 'em.
Half of 'em.
(Laughing) I ate
all of 'em, dude.
Just ten minutes without
this pig in the house,
is that so much to ask?
There. if Mabel asks...
This never happened.
"Oh, but grunkle Stan!
It's not safe out there!
There's predators!"
Oh, brother.
( Loud roaring )
( Panicked squealing )
Aaah!
I can't believe you,
man!
Sorry, dude.
I was just so excited!
Nachos cause excitement.
Soos, no offense,
but you gotta be
more careful sometimes.
I'm mean, what are the odds
we'll ever get another picture
of the--
( roaring )
Wha--
wha--
dude, did you see that?
That thing was
a dinosaur, bro!
How is it possible
a dinosaur survived
65 million years?
Did you see it,
Mr. pines?
It--
it took him.
Took what?
The pig. It took waddles.
What'd you say
about waddles?
Oh, whoa.
Awkward silence.
Bleaahhhh!
What's going on?
Why are you standing around
all awkwardly?
And where's waddles?
Um, uh--
the good news is,
you're gettin' a puppy!
What happened?
Well, see,
uh, when the--
the pig got eaten
by a p-terodactyl, bro.
What?!
Waddles? waddles!
Where did he go?!
How did this happen?!
( Hyperventilating )
Grunkle Stan,
you didn't put him outside?
What?! no!
I didn't put him anywhere!
I'm not acting suspicious!
You're acting
suspicious!
What's a pig?!
Then what happened?
Uh, look, it went down
like this, see?
So there I was,
in the living room...
Tenderly nursing him with
only the richest of creams,
when all of a sudden...
( Roaring )
So I said...
Aaah! no dice, cowboy!
Aaaaah!
I start punching him
right in the face!
But he played dirty.
Huh?
Aaah! ohh!
That really happened.
Why?! why couldn't you
have taken me?!!!
( Sobbing )
Oh, grunkle Stan,
you tried to save him!
Uh, yep.
I'm a...Great man,
all right.
You punched a pterodactyl
in the face?
I thought you didn't even
believe in the supernatural.
Dinosaurs aren't magic.
They're just big lizards.
Get off my back!
Oh, waddles.
( Sniffling )
that's it.
No pterodactyl
messes with my sister.
We're gonna go out there,
catch him, and save your pig.
For Mabel, guys!
For Mabel!
But how do we even
find the little guy?
We follow that!
Oh, sweet!
Yes! Genius!
Or, ya know,
we could just
call it a day,
maybe hit the pool hall
or, uh...
Yeah! let's go...
Save waggles!
Waddles.
him too.
All right!
That p-terodactyl
won't know what hit him.
Huh.
it's "pterodactyl," man.
Actually, nobody knows
how to pronounce it
because no one was alive
back in dinosaur days,
so, uh--
whoa! almost ran over
my own head there.
Ha ha! Wow.
Mabel,
we've gotta talk.
This is a really
high-stakes mission
and I'm a little worried
about Soos coming along
on this one.
I love the guy,
but sometimes he...
Messes stuff up.
What?! since when?
Sorry, dude.
Look! a fairy!
Ha ha!
Oh, sorry, dude,
i killed that fairy.
Let him down easy.
This is so great!
You and me, bro!
Best friends,
fighting and potentially
high-fiving dinosaurs.
Soos, look, I, uh...
I gotta tell you something.
Okay, but before you do,
check out these matching shirts
i made for us.
Who's this guy
right here?
You. totally you, dude.
And these rays
indicate friendship.
So what was it
you were gonna
tell me again?
Uh...p-terodactyl,
here we come!
Yes!
( Sighs )
Soos:
bros before dinos!
Mabel:
okay, the red yarn
leads to...
В™є doodlee-doo,
deedlee-doo... в™є
old man magucket?!
Howdy, friends!
What are you
doing out here?
You'll never believe me.
So I was doing my hourly
hootenanny--
в™є deedlee-ding-dang в™є
ohh! this guy.
When this enormous
wingly critter
stole my musical spoons
and flew lickety-split
into the abandoned mines
down yonder.
Whoa!
whoa!
Looks kinda hairy
down there.
Come on, grunkle Stan,
you can handle it.
You punched a pterodactyl
in the face, remember?
Oh, yeah. Ha ha.
I did do that, didn't I?
Ha. uh ha ha.
My! what suspicious
laughter!
Guys, we're going in.
Need someone to tag along
and tell weird
personal stories?
No, thanks.
Mcgucket:
so there I am
fightin' a raccoon for
the same piece of meat,
when our mouths get close
and we kiss accidentally.
Uhh. you can't take
a hint, can you?
Nope!
( All scream )
( Thud )
( All groaning )
Whoooa.
Sweet Moses!
Razzle dazzle!
Fancy marmalade!
These plants look
all Jurassic-y.
Huh. this little fella
smells like battery acid.
Uhh!
Looks like I lost
my sense of smell.
Ha ha ha!
Oh, waddles,
we're gonna find you!
( All scream )
Whoa!
whoa!
wow!
Dipper: they're all trapped
inside tree sap!
That's how they survived
for 65 million years.
Whoa.
The summer heat must be
melting them loose!
Holy moly!
Forget the cornicorn--
this is the attraction
of a lifetime!
I could bring people down here
and turn this into
some sort of theme park.
"Jurassic sap hole."
Uh, dudes...
Maybe we should
keep moving.
This could be
a gold mine!
Velvety rope type deal there,
ticket booth here--ha!
I shoulda put
that pig outside
ages ago!
Wait. what did you
just say?
Hmm? What's that?
You said the dinosaur
flew into the house.
( Gasps )
no, wait. Uh--
if you think about it--
you put waddles outside,
then you lied to me
about it!
And now, thanks to you,
my pig could be dead!
Waddles could be dead!
Look, he's an animal.
He belongs outside.
No! that's it!
Grunkle Stan, I am never,
ever speaking to you again!
Look, you can't
be serious.
Oh, is someone
talking right now?
Because I can't hear them!
Kid!
в™є la la la la la в™є
I can't hear anyone!
No one's talking to me!
Guys, guys, don't fight.
Why can't you be
more like me and Dipper?
Look, everything's
gonna be cool.
All we gotta do
to find the pig is
follow this here yarn.
We just keep
following and following,
and when we reach the end--
uh-oh.
Wh-which cave was it again?
Ohh, Soos!
You lost the trail!
Hey, come on,
we'll find our way.
Trust me!
Sorry, dude.
Ohh!
That is it! See,
this is why I didn't want
to bring you along!
What--what do you mean?
I mean, this is really
important to Mabel,
and you keep screwing
everything up!
You ruined our photograph,
and now you've got us
hopelessly lost!
But we're p-terodactyl bros.
I made t-shirts.
It's pronounced
"pterodactyl."
And these shirts are useless!
They're gigantic!
I...have...a different.
Body type, dude!
Oh, so it's my fault?
I just thought, ya know...
( All arguing)
Mcgucket: hey!
Cheer up, fellers!
I fixed your lantern!
( All scream )
Aaaah!
Heh heh! What--
what are we doin'?
Hmm?
Nobody make any
sudden movements
or loud noises.
Yeehah! we found
a pterodactyl!
( Screeching )
( All screaming )
( Roaring )
Guys. we need a plan
to get out of here.
Okay, okay.
How's about Mabel
knits Soos a pig costume...
I like it.
And we use Soos
as a human sacrifice!
I like it.
Whaddya say, Mabel?
Humph.
Aw, come on,
you can't stop talkin'
to me forever.
Yeah, Mabel, we have
to work together here.
What? you want to
work with Mabel
but not your buddy Soos?
( All bickering )
( Waddles oinks )
Wait! did you hear that?
( Snorting )
Waddles!
Wait, kid!
Mabel!
Are you nuts?!
Oh, is someone speaking?
Because I can't hear anything!
Oh, no! She's gone
deaf with fear!
Mabel,
come back here!
Waddles!
( Oinks )
Oh! my waddles!
I'll never
lose you again!
Mmm-mm!
Uh...mabel?
Sh-sh-sh.
you're safe now.
(Whispering)
Mabel, great,
you got him.
Now we gotta
get out of here!
( Panicked squeal )
Waddles, wait!
Huh?
Ahh!
Get off me,
you dumb pig!
( Roaring )
Look out!
Aah!
Aaah!
Aaaahhh!!!!
Oh, no!
Mr. pines!
Stan!
( Stan screaming )
Uhh! ohh! Ooh!
Ohh....
( Contented oinking )
Yeah, you would enjoy this.
Aaah!
Huh?
( All gasp )
Guys, we've gotta
save them!
Mcgucket, do you have
an invention
that can distract
the pterodactyl?
Do I?!
Nope.
( Crackling )
( All gasp )
Whoa!
aaah!
( Chirps )
Aw...
Well, welcome
to the world,
little feller.
Aah!
aaah!
The dumb thing
must be hungry.
I guess it's you or me,
pig.
( Grunts )
What are you lookin' at?
Aw, come on,
don't give me that look.
What am I supposed to do,
let it eat me?
Arrghh!
Oh I get it! You're
trying to guilt me.
Well, it ain't
workin', pal.
Who cares if you're Mabel's
favorite thing in the world?
I can live without the kid
talkin' to me all the time,
tellin' me her jokes...
Makin' me laugh...
( Giggly oink )
( Chuckles )
Ah, dang it!
Well, this is just about
the dumbest thing
I've ever done.
You want this pig?
( Oinking )
Then you're gonna
have to get through me,
you flying devil!
Come and get me!!!
Uhhh!
Aaahhh!!!!
( Munching )
Aw, dude. Did he really just eat
that prospector guy?
That is messed up!
I'm okay!
Aaah!
What do we do?
We have to get
in a straight line.
What?!
A pterodactyl's eyes
are so far apart
that if you stand
right in front of it,
it can't see you.
Soos, you've been wrong
about stuff all day.
How can we--
dude, look.
I know I've messed up a lot.
I could be sorta clumsy,
and it's not always
as loveable as I think.
But please, as my friend,
just trust me on this one.
Get behind me, dudes.
Ahh! ah.
( Chirps )
It's working.
Uh-oh!
( Confused chirp )
( Relieved sighs )
Soos, you did it!
( Distant screech )
huh?
Was that...
Stan?
Ahhh....
( Screeches )
( Oinking )
Waddles!
He's punching him
in the face!
Aaah!
From heck's heart
i stab at thee!
( Screeches )
( Grunting,
panting )
Oh, yes! Ha ha!
You're all right, Stan?
Oh, Mr. pines,
you're okay!
Here's your pig, kiddo.
( Oinks )
Oooh! waddles!
Oh...
you saved him for me!
Yeah, well, sometimes
you just gotta--
look out!
( All screaming )
We're trapped!
Quick! the geyser
can shoot us back up!
Come on, go! Go!
( Roaring )
( All screaming )
Bros before dinos!
Oh. oh.
Oh. Oh.
( Panting )
Oh!
I can't believe
you did all that
for waddles!
Ah, well, I can't have
my favorite niece not
talking to me,
and if I gotta
leap onto a pterodactyl
and punch him in the face,
then that's what
i gotta do.
That's kinda sappy.
What?! that's how I feel!
No, I mean...
Oh, yeah.
Gotcha!
ahhh.
Uh-oh.
uhh! uhh!
Aaaah!
( All snoring )
Check it out,
that thing destroyed my vest.
Soos, look!
A real dinosaur tooth?
That's awesome!
Not as awesome
as you saving us
back there.
Pterodactyl bros?
Pterodactyl bros.
Boosh!
boosh!
Hey, I pronounced it
right that time.
Think we need to worry
about the rest of those
dinosaurs?
I doubt it.
( Creaking )
I ate my way through
a dinosaur!
( Cackling )
( Spoons clacking )
Hi, I'm Bobby renzobbi!
Are your arms jealous
of your legs?
Then you need arm pants--
the pants that you
wear on your arms!
Sheesh. who actually buys
this infomercial stuff?
Ha. I know, right?
Cancel the order.
Cancel the order!
( Snorting )
snorting. That's his tell.
I fold.
Tough luck, sucker.
Waddles was bluffing.
What?!
I had four aces!
That pig is a wizard!
Look at him.
He's taunting me.
I've been cheating
the last eight turns.
Ha ha!
That's my girl.