( Bleating )
( Squeaking )
Mabel, do you
believe in ghosts?
I believe you're
a big dork! Ha ha ha ha!
Aaahhh!
Soos! Wendy!
( Panting )
what's up, Mr. pines?
I'm headin' out.
You two are gonna wash
the bathrooms, right?
Absolutely not.
Ha ha!
You stay outta trouble.
Hey, guys, what's this?
A secret ladder
to the roof?
Uh, I don't think
Mr. pines would like that.
Uh?
You're freakin'
me out, dude!
Can we actually go up there?
Sure we can.
Roof time! Roof time!
Uhh...
All right, check it out.
Whoa, cool!
Did y put all this
stuff up here?
I may or may not
sneak up here during work,
all the time, every day.
Me first!.
( Car alarm chirping )
Jackpot! high five!
Don't leave me hangin'.
Both: ha!
Hey, it's my friends.
Thompson: Wendy!
Uh, you guys aren't gonna tell
Stan about this, are you?
Later, dorks.
Let's get outta here!
Whoo!
Later, Wendy!
( Laughing )
Ah, guh-oh!Mes.
Somebody's in love!
Yeah, right.
I just think
Wendy's cool, okay?
It's not like
i lay awake at night
thinking about her.
Uh-oh.
Put on some dance party
for no reason!
( Dancgo! go! Go!Ying )
Go! go! Go! Go! Go!
( Stammering )
what? Yes? Yeah?
Aren't you gonna
get in on this?
I, uh,
don't really dance.
Yeah, you do.
Mom used to dress him up
in a lamb costume
and make him do...
The lamby dance.
Now is not
the time to talk
about the lamby dance.
Lamb costume? Whoa!
Is there, like, little ears
and a tail, or...?
Well, uh... uh...
Dipper would prance around
and sing a song about grazing.
( Cuckoo clock chimes )
Hey, look at that.
Quittin' time.
The gang's waitin' for me.
Hey, wait,
uh, maybe I could--
or we could come with you.
Ooh, I don't know.
My friends are
pretty intense.
How old did
you guys say you are?
We're 13, so,
technically a teen.
All right.
I like your moxie, kid.
Let me get my stuff.
Since when are we 13?
Is this a leap year?
Come on, Mabel.
This is our chance
to hang out with,
you know, the cool kids--
and Wendy and whatever.
I knew it!
You love her!
Love, love,
love, love, love!
Oh, hey, what's that?
Huh?
Bluh bluh bluh bluh.
Hurry up.
Lee and Nate:
In the belly!
( Thompson groans )
Oh! ha ha ha!
Yeah!
All: Wendy!
Nate: Wendy! Wendy!
Hey, guys, these are
my pals from work,
Mabel and Dipper.
I chewed my gum
so it looks like a brain.
She's not much
for first impressions,
unlike this guy!
This guy...!
So are you, like,
babysitting or...?
Come on, Robbie.
Guys, this is
Lee and Nate...
Unh! ha ha ha!
Tamehh...
Thompson, who once ate a run-
over waffle for 50 cents...
Don't tell them that.
And Robbie.
You can probably
figure him out.
Yeah, I'm the guy
who spray-painted
the water tower.
Oh, you mean
the big muffin.
Um, it's
a giant explosion.
Heh heh! Kind of does
look like a muffin.
( Both laughing )
Let's hurry it up, guys.
I got big plans for
tonight, huh?
Letget in the car! Re!
( Playfully ) ow-wow!
Sorry, kid, I'll ride
shotgun, all right?
Okay, just, before we go,
my mom said you guys
aren't allowed to punch
the roof anymore, so...
Thompson! Thompson!
Thompson!
Ha ha! This is gonna
blow someone's mind.
Mabel, please.
What? am I embarrassing
you in front of your new...
Girlfriend!
( Mumbling )
Uhh! did you just
lick my hand?
( Music playing )
You're watching
the black-and-white
period piece old lady
boring movie channel.
Kids! I can't find
the remote, and i
refuse to stand up!
Stay tuned for
the Friday night movie,
the duchess approves,
starring sturly
stembleburgiss
as the duchess
and grampton
St. rumpterfrabble
as the risible coxswain
sounterbluggot
hampterfuppinshire.
Kids!
( Orchestral music rises )
No! noooo!
There it is, fellas--
the condemned dusk-to-dawn.
Whoa!
Neat! awesome!
Wh-why did they
shut it down?
It's, like, a health
code violation, or...?
Some folks died in there.
The place has been
haunted ever since.
This town has such
a colorful history!
What? are--
are you guys serious?
( Feigning terror )
yeah. We're all
gonna die!
Chill out, man.
It's not as bad
as it looks.
Come on, Dipper.
( Chuckling )
okay.
Just-- just
gotta get a foothold.
Dude,
your sister did it.
Whup whup whup
whup whup whup.
Hey, you know what?
Just... there you go.
( Thud )
( Laughing )
sorry, dude.
Robbie: good job
throwing the kid
off the fence, genius.
Lee:
your mom's a genius.
( Audibly struggling )
Ho ho ho!
This place is amazing.
I think it's--
it's stuck.
Let me take
oh, yeah.T it.
I can't get in,
but I'm sure junior here
is gonna break it down
like Hercules.
Come on, leave him alone.
He's just a little kid.
Tambri: whoa, kid!
What are you doing?
( Audibly struggling )
Go, Dipper!
Punch that metal thing!
Hey, Dipper,
take it easy.
Who wants to bet
he doesn't make it?
( Happy chatter )
Good call,
inviting this
little maniac!
Your new name
is Dr. fun times.
All right.
Cool.
yeah, man.
Nice work.
Thompson:
do you guys really
think it's haunted?
Robbie:
nah! Thompson,
are you kidding me?
Come on, shut up,
man! Ha ha ha!
Whoa! no way!
( Overlapping
awed chatter )
Oh, man.
It's even creepier
than I imagined.
Yep, it's dust.
Hey, dude, where
do you think they
keep the dead bodies?
( Laughing )
shut up, man!
Guys, check it out!
You think they still work?
( Clanking )
( Machinery whirrs to life )
( Overlapping chatter )
Jackpot!
So, what are we
gonna do now?
Anything we want.
Take that.
( Laughter and chatter )
Ha ha ha! Ohh!
Put 'em in, put 'em in!
Three at a time,
three at a time!
( Happy shouting )
( Laughter )
Oh, my gosh!
Smile dip!
I thought this stuff
was banned in America.
Maybe they had
a good reason.
Ha ha ha!
Robbie: hey, come here,
man, we got it ready!
Whatever it is,
I'll do it!
Ha ha ha! Thompson!
Dipper, this night
is, like, legendary.
Just look around.
The guys are bonding.
( Laughter )
I've never even seen
tambri look up from
her phone this long,
and your sister
seems to be going nuts
for that smile dip.
Uhh.
Maybe I've had too much.
What do you think?
( Inarticulate speech )
Would you like
to eat my candy paws?
Of course,
you little angel.
( Gnawing )
( Freezer buzzing )
You know, Dipper,
i wasn't sure
if you could hang
with our crew at first,
but you're surprisingly
mature for your age.
Yes. yes, I am.
Hey, guys,
we need more ice.
I'm on it.
( Screams )
( Panting )
What was that?
I thought I heard some
lady screaming back here.
You freakin' out, kid?
No. no, I'm cool.
Everything's cool.
Then what's all this about?
Oh, that's...
Uh... uh... uh...
Hey, look!
Dancy pants revolution,
the game that tricks
people into exercising.
All right, I'm down.
Yeah, let's all--
let's all go play that.
Hm.
Male voice:
( Dadance! Hurry up!G )
Go! go! Go! Go!
Wow! he's really
terrible at this.
( Nervous chuckle )
yeah, yeah, that's--
that's great.
( Cries out )
I'll be right back.
( Telephone rings )
Come on,
grunkle Stan,
pick up!
Uhh! what is he doing?
I don't care about
Dukes or commoners...
Or his royal highness,
Lionel of cornwall.
I'm not afraid
anymore, mother.
D ( telephone rings ) u.
I may be a duchess,
but I'm also a woman!
Yes! yes!
In your face,
Elizabeth!
( Hysterically )
it's just like my life!
( Calmly )
in a way.
( Dial tone )
Mabel,
i need your advice.
We're hanging out
in a haunted
convenience store,
I can't get ahold
of grunkle Stan,
and if I try to say
anything about it
to any of these guys,
they'll just think
I'm a scared little kid
or something.
( Groaning )
Mabel?
The future is in the past!
Onward, deoshebah!
( Car alarm blares )
Mabel! how many
of these did you eat?
Eleventeen.
Oh, man.
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
Whoa, guys,
you might wanna see this.
( Overwhat the heck?Ons )
Whoa. then the rumors
are true.
Dude, dare you
to lie down in it.
Good idea.
Go lie down in it.
I'm a dead body! Look!
Wait!
Maybe let's not do that.
This guy's scared!
All I'm saying is,
why tempt the fates?
I mean, what if
this place really is...
Haunted?
( All jeering )
Just take it down
a notch, captain buzzkill.
But I thought
i was Dr. fun times.
Well, you're acting like
captain buzzkill, right?
Yeah. little bit.
Status update:
Trapped in store
with insane 9-year-old.
I'm not a 9-year-old.
I'm 13,
technically a teen!
Whoa? what is that?
( Gasps )
Whoa!
What?
"Status update...
Aaaahhhhhhh."
Aaahhh!
Tambri! tambri!
Can you hear us?
I don't know, man!
What Ari don't know! To do?
Let's just go already!
Thwait!n!
I've almost got
the high score!
Aah! aaahhh!
Huh? what?
Male voice:
Time to shake what
your momma gave you!
Oh, no! Help!
So many arrows!
You're a dance machine!
No, you're
a dance machine!
( Crying )
Thompson!
Forget him!
Let's go!
What the--?
Guys, it's locked!
Outta my way!
Aah!
Aaahhh!
Everybody, wait.
Whatever is doing this
has to have some kind
of reason.
Maybe if we could just
figure out what it is,
then they'll
let us out of here.
"They'll let
us out of here."
Yeah, that makes
a lot of sense.
I don't know, guys.
Maybe he's got a point.
Yeah, right.
I'm sure the ghost
just wants to talk
about his feelings!
Aah! aah!
Aaahhh!
Wh-what?
I'm bonkers for
eating you alive!
No!
Lee: aaahhh!
Lee!
Okay, okay.
I'm with you, kid.
One hundred percent, man.
Evil masculine voice:
Welcome!
They got Mabel! )
Welcome to your graves,
young trespassers!
Ha ha ha!
We're super sorry
for hanging out
in your store.
Yeah, can we just
go now and leave forever?
Well... okay.
You're free to go.
But before you leave,
hot dogs are now half off.
I know it might
be crazy, but you
gotta try these dogs!
( Both screaming )
Just kidding
about the hot dog sale!
Just let us
outta here already!
I don't like your tone!
No, no! Aah!
What? no!
I'm a hot dog!
It begins!
Whoa!
Unh!
Ohh!
Aah!
Welcome to your home
for all eternity!
Dipper, duck!Do we do?
Quick, in there!
( Both panting )
What do they
want from us?
What did we do wrong?
Okay, let's
try to figure out
the pattern here.
Why was
each person taken?
Tambri was texting,
Thompson was playing
a video game,
Lee was being sarcastic--
it doesn't make any sense!
Yeah. I mean,
those are all just
normal teenage things.
Wendy, say that
last part again.
"Normal teenage things"?
Of course! Stay here
until I get back.
Dude,
what are you doing?
( Growling )
I've got something
to tell you.
I'm not a teenager!
Ho ho ho!
Well, why didn't
you say so?
Waaahh!
Ugh.
How old did you
say you were?
I'm... ( sighs )
I'm 12,
technically not a teen.
When we were alive,
teenagers were a scourge
on our store.
Always sassafrassin'
customers
with their boomie-boxes
and disrespectful
short pants,
so we decided
to up and ban them,
but they retaliated
with this newfangled
rap music!
Ma: the lyrics,
they were so... hateful!
* homework's wack,
and so are rules *
* tuckin' in
your shirt's for fools *
nooo!
Ma: it was so shocking,
we were stricken down
with double heart attacks.
( Both groaning )
( Flatline )
That's why we hate
teenagers so much,
don't we, honey?
But they're my friends.
Isn't there anything
i can do to help them?
There is one thing.
Do you know any
funny little dances?
Uh... is there
anything else I can do?
Nooooo!
Okay, okay, okay!
Um, well...
I do know...
The lamby-lamby dance,
but, uh, but I can't
really do it without
a lamb costume.
Oh. well. There it is.
Whew.
* well
* who wants
a lamby lamby lamby? *
* I do! I do!
* so go up and greet
your mammy mammy mammy *
* hi there,
hi there *
* so march, march,
march around the daisies *
yes! yes! More! More!
* don't, don't, don't
you forget about the baby *
that was some fine
girlie-dancin', boy!
Your friends are free.
Well, I don't think
you have to worry about
us comin' back, so...
All: ohh!
( Groans )
I'm never gonna eat
or d anything ever again.
Hey, there's
still some evil!
What-- what happened after
everything went crazy?
You are not
going to believe it.
The ghosts appeared,
and Dipper had to...
Uh... ahem...
And, um, Dipper
just grabbed a bat
and started
beating ghosts down,
left and right.
And then the ghosts
got all scared
and ran away like
a couple of little girls.
It no way!Ane!
Lee:
Dr. fun times!
Well, I'm probably
scarred for life.
Yeah, that was
pretty crazy.
Think I'm gonna go
stare at a wall for a while
and rethink everything.
Hey, next time we hang out,
let's stay at
the mystery shack, okay?
Ha ha! Next time?
Yeah, let's--
let's hang out
at the shack.
Ha ha! Yeah.
Next time.
Ohh!
What kind of
sick joke is this?
( Orchestral music playing )
Ah, the wedding.
I've waited
so long for this.
Oh, look at her
in that dress.
( Door bursts open;
Crowd reacts )
Count Lionel!
What's he doin' here?!
I've come to
reclaim my bride!
You had your chance
at the cotillion, you!
That's what I'm sayin'!
( Frustrated roar )
( Crash )
Uh...
Couldn't find
the remote.