Mr. Nygaard?
Oh, you betcha.
- She's a beaut.
- Yeah.
Got the low water feature
but don't skimp on torque.
Am I taking the old one?
Yeah, if that's...
They said on the phone
it'd be no problem.
Oh, sure. It's no problem.
The T-160, huh?
- Mm.
- Yeah.
Jeez.
See why you're trading her in.
She's a real lemon.
Motor mount. Chinese
used plastic screws.
Bet she bucked like a bronco.
You do not know the half of it.
Stopped making 'em pretty quick.
Recalled, I think.
Surprised to see
her, truth be told.
You'd be better off washing
your clothes between two rocks,
you know what I mean?
They got Chazz up at
Faribault till the trial.
Gordo's at Red Wing, which is...
Well, you know, at
least they're close.
His lawyer thinks we can
plea it down to probation,
time served.
For murder?
- No, Gordo...
- Oh.
- On the gun charge.
- Yeah.
Chazz? Well, good riddance.
Don't care what that man gets.
No, sir.
Not after what he did.
Killing my wife, you mean?
Oh. Well, yeah.
Yeah, of course that.
But also...
Well, I mean, look at me.
I was Miss Hubbard
County, for Pete's sake.
You don't cheat on
Miss Hubbard County.
I just don't believe
it, you know?
I mean, just three weeks ago,
we were sitting
around the table...
eating ham.
And now Gordo's having
his night terrors again.
Plus, we have to sell everything
to pay the legal bills.
Did you know...
Chazz bought a time
share in a boat?
Well, I didn't even
know that was a thing.
Yeah, it's a thing.
So if there's anything
from the house you want...
you know, like I was thinking
maybe Chazz's hunting gear...
I boxed it up for you.
Not sure it's anything you want.
Oh, sure. That'd...
that'd be fine.
Thank you.
Well...
Listen. If there's
anything I can do.
Oh, Lester, you are so sweet.
I am the one who
should be saying that
after what he did
to you, my husband.
Ooh, what'd you get?
New washer.
The old one...
Well, I had to get rid of
everything from the basement,
you know, on account
of all the...
You deserve it, Lester.
All good things, you deserve.
Sync and corrections by
n17t01 www.addic7ed.com.
Back to it, then?
Looks like.
Doc cleared me for duty, so...
Ooh.
More flowers came for
you from Duluth.
A smarter man would think
you were being wooed.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Put 'em up where we
can see 'em at least.
So you got a strategy
on this Lester thing?
Well, I'm just gonna walk
in and say, "Bill, we... ".
If you think it's best.
The direct approach.
Your point being?
Got no point.
Okay.
Bye, dad.
Chief, are you busy?
What's that?
Said, "Are you busy?"
Got a request for
your attendance.
Can it wait?
I just ate an omelet.
Waiting for it to digest.
Oh, yeah? What kind?
Well, it was mushrooms
and cheese.
- Sally make it?
- Yeah.
She wrapped it in tinfoil
to keep it warm.
Molly needs you is the thing.
Asked me to see if you'd
come down to the staff room.
She's back already?
- Yep.
- Hmm.
Thought I had another day.
All right.
Let's go see what
we're gonna do today.
There she is, the gunfighter.
Hey, Chief.
Nice collage.
You take up basket weaving
too in your downtime?
Yeah, it's just some loose
ends I wanted to...
Molly, before you...
I want you to know...
I'm not too proud to say
I was wrong on the Lester case.
I had the wrong idea.
I thought it was
a drifter thing,
which was the wrong
way to go, clearly.
But, you know, some
good police work,
and we caught the guy, so...
Well, that...
that's the problem,
actually, is that
you're still...
Still what?
Wrong.
I'm sorry... I mean,
no disrespect.
It's just...
it doesn't make any sense.
I mean... I mean, the brother?
With all the things
we know are true?
I've been lying in bed
just thinking about this.
And for example, okay,
if it was the brother,
then how do we explain
the phone call
from Lester's to the motel...
Molly, darn it now, just...
You can't keep going over...
It's time.
You got to let it go.
We did our job.
The brother Nygaard
killed the wife.
And he cornered and
shot the Chief.
And Lester was covering for him
on account of the brother thing,
which explains...
We had drinks to celebrate.
I had a Greyhound
and Knutson had... what
was it with the cherry?
A Rob Roy.
Rob Roy. Yeah.
You had a few of them,
if I'm not mistaken.
What about the Hess case?
What about it?
It's still open, yeah?
Yeah, no. See...
we're checking to see if the
hooker had a boyfriend.
Jealous type, you know?
Didn't like her
getting tooled by
every Tom, Dick, and
Jane, but otherwise...
- Who's working that now?
- Terry.
- Well, that's good.
- Yeah.
Except Terry doesn't always know
which end of a mop to
use to wash the floor.
He's not the brightest bulb.
I'll give you that.
But he's soldiering through.
Well, good for him.
Except I'm back now.
- No.
- Chief, please.
No, Molly, Deputy.
Now, I would give it to you,
I would, except we
both know in two days,
I'd be back in this room
with you pointing at names
on that whiteboard and
me chewing my tie.
Just please, Chief,
for Pete's sake,
I've got evidence that
puts Lester Nygaard
in a room with a known killer
on the day of the Hess murder,
and then the next night,
Lester called the guy.
- He called him at the motel.
- Look,
you can't... That's just
how it is sometimes.
Life.
You know, you go to
bed unsatisfied.
They're calling lottery
numbers on the TV,
and you get the first few,
and already in your mind,
you're buying a jet or
a fjord or whatever,
but it's just not meant to be.
It's just not meant to be.
Hey, look.
We're all real glad to
have you back, okay?
You're a heck of a
police officer.
Tell her about the cake.
The guys are gonna have
a cake for you later.
Try to look surprised.
It's... It's really something.
It's got an assault rifle on top
made of frosting,
which I don't know
how they do that.
But...
Heya, Lester.
I like your tie.
Thank you.
I got it online.
- Oh, yeah?
- Uh-huh.
- Oh.
- Jacket too.
I was a bit nervous
about it at first.
Had to send the jacket
back once, actually.
It was too big in the arms.
Well, I think you look terrific.
Oh.
And, um...
I was thinking of
making some chili
on Saturday night
if you maybe wanted to join me.
Where is he?
You son of a bitch.
I am gonna bust your balls.
You want me to do it, ma?
- Yeah, ma, want us to?
- Shut up!
I am gonna bust your balls.
Now, Mrs. Hess, what
can I do for you?
Don't you "Mrs. Hess" me.
I was picking your pubes out
of my teeth 12 hours ago,
and then I get this?
That is...
This is highly irregular.
I'll make some calls.
- Liar.
- Mrs. Hess.
Liar.
- You knew the whole time.
- No, no.
Missus... Gina, this is...
This...
Listen. I'm gonna
make some calls.
Like I said... I was
speaking to the guy
from mid claims just yesterday.
He didn't mention
a single thing...
I let you come inside of me.
Ma, that's really gross.
Yeah, ma, don't talk like that.
Come on, we don't need to bring
that into the conversation.
You are gonna get me my money,
you little shit.
$2 million.
You've got until the
end of the day.
Show him what we'll do.
Jesus.
All right. All right.
Sorry, loser.
Me too.
Yeah.
So are we calm?
Are we calm?
Now, here's what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna make some calls,
like I said.
Because this is the
first that I've...
But if it's true... If Sam
did miss some payments,
then, well, they're
within their rights to...
I think we might
have a problem here.
That was...
Sorry you had to
see that, Linda.
No, I'm... That was...
You're amazing.
He'll be right out.
Follow.
Sir, we...
What Agent Pepper
is trying to say,
the syndicate spree killing,
yes, technically, we were there
outside in our car
while it was...
But you have to...
You have to see
it as a positive,
uh, because it leaves us...
myself and Agent Budge...
- it leaves us...
- Poised.
That's the word we like.
Poised to catch this guy.
Because, sir, first of all,
we got this photo from an
ATM across the street.
It captures our... A
single individual
who's clearly armed
and about to...
Now, the photo's not
great, but I...
We were thinking
definitely white male.
Sir.
Listen, sir.
This is where you work now.
We are highly effective,
highly trained...
I have a commendation.
A commendation?
That's your...
Okay.
It's...
You know, we're still...
We're still good.
We're still alive.
He could have...
It could be worse, right?
Much, much worse.
Yeah.
This right here...
two weeks, tops.
He just wants to see
us sweat a little,
feel the...
No, I mean, that's...
It's only fair.
I can see that.
I mean, we did...
I mean, 22 people
did get killed,
and we were sitting in the
car like a couple of...
Yeah, we're okay.
We're all right.
Never heard of a deaf hit man.
Carolina Murphy had
his tongue cut out
by an Indian back in the '80s.
He worked a little after that
but never quite the same.
And Buzz Mead... you know Buzz?
He was born with just a socket.
Used to take his glass
eye out at parties
and drop it in his drink.
He was a shit shot, though.
Now, the other
fella, your partner,
he could hear just fine.
We had a kind of little chat
before I cut his throat.
You're unemployed
now, by the way,
in case you don't
read the papers.
I watched a bear once.
His leg was in a steel trap.
It chewed through bloody
bone to get free.
It was in Alaska.
Died about an hour later
facedown in a stream.
But it was on his own
terms, you know?
You got close.
Closer than anybody else.
I don't know if it was
you or your partner,
but look.
If you still feel raw about
things when you heal up,
come see me.
Just me and Bill, right?
Slow night.
And the call comes in.
He don't like when
I tell this story.
Heard you got some flowers.
Yeah.
Some people do love
to flap their lips.
More than once, what I heard.
Well, there's a suitor
is all I'm prepared to say.
Vern was so bad at courtship.
One time he gave me a
bouquet of poison ivy.
Picked it himself.
He's up in Duluth,
my gentleman.
Has a daughter.
What's his name?
They call him Sergio.
He's a pirate, I think.
Very funny, you.
Well...
Yours is the one
with the icing clip.
And, Ida, your frosting comes
from the barrel, I think.
Good to have everyone together
again, don't you think?
It's like one big, happy, uh...
Which is good, is all.
I wanted to thank you
for catching the guy.
Not me.
- I was in bed.
- Stop.
You were in the
hospital with a bullet.
No.
Bill may have made the arrest,
but we both know who
did the real work.
He's not convicted yet.
I mean, not all the evidence...
For me, there are still...
But yeah, no, I'm
glad it's behind us.
Deputy Solverson.
Yeah, hi. It's Gus.
Grimly.
Oh, yeah, hi.
So what's happening, then?
You know, on patrol.
Oh, sure, yeah.
I helped a fella
who got his privates
stuck to a mailbox.
Oh.
Didn't like his mail?
Something like that.
There's the hearing
tomorrow on the shooting.
Oh, yeah.
That's...
That's tomorrow.
Well, just tell the truth.
Don't you think?
It was a whiteout, and...
you saw a shadow,
and you shot at it.
But leave out the part...
Yeah, leave out the part
where the person
you shot was me.
I am really sorry about that.
Yeah, I gathered from
the volume of flowers.
Too much?
No.
No, it's nice.
So, um...
I saw in the paper this morning
the Logging Festival's coming up
over in your neck
of the, you know...
and Greta, you know, she
really likes going to that.
Yeah, me too.
Yeah? Good.
Good. Well, maybe, um...
I mean...
maybe we'll see you there.
Yeah, a certainty
if we go together.
Yeah. Yeah.
That's...
You're right about that.
And when you're
right, you're right.
On Friday there's
chain saw carving
and all you can eat.
And on Saturday they
roast a pig underground.
I've never had it, but
it's supposed to be good.
Oh.
I didn't know that
you could do that.
On Sundays they do a
pie eating contest.
Yeah, yeah. No, I...
You know, I like to
just go for the food.
Greta likes...
Dad. Come in, dad. Over.
Dad here. Come back.
What's the deal with dinner?
Over.
Yeah, just finishing up.
Thought we'd do tacos tonight.
Over.
Okay, don't forget
the red sauce.
Over and out.
- ♪- ♪ everything was ready ♪
I'm home!
You forgot the food, didn't ya?
- Mom home?
- Yeah.
That your dad?
He remember the red sauce?
Ah, shoot. I can go back.
Nah, it's okay. I think we got
some left from last time.
Go get changed up,
you, and let's eat.
- I'm starving.
- Yeah.
Why don't you just put
'em on the table?
- Okay.
- Thanks, Greta.
Okay.
Dad wants to know about
the game Sunday.
Watch his place or...
I thought we could
watch it here.
You know, I could make
that pasta thing.
- Hmm.
- The one with the peas?
Capers. You liked it last time.
Oh, don't forget,
we got that thing
at Ida's on Saturday,
the anniversary.
No, I remember.
It was a week before I met you.
Anniversary of what?
Ah, just your, uh...
Molly had a friend of hers
that got killed last year,
so we'll over there
and pay our respects.
It was, um, Vern, right?
Yeah.
He was the chief before Bill.
Hired me.
Ida, the lady with the baby...
- Yeah.
- Is his wife.
Which, speaking of, she asked
if we could bring drinks.
Yeah, I still got some of
that Halloween beer I made.
Seem to remember you
spitting that on the floor.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
I'll go to the store.
Mm-hmm.
You okay?
Oh, sure.
Just hard to sit that long.
Legs go to sleep.
FBI.
Hi.
Deputy Solverson again.
Bemidji Police.
Yes?
Well, I called a
couple times now
about the Fargo
syndicate massacre,
how I might know the
fella responsible,
meaning he's a suspect
in a case we...
Yeah, I see your name
in the computer.
Looks like those suspicions
were investigated and dismissed.
Yeah, well, they
sent a fella down,
but I'm not sure he really...
Well, do you have any
new information?
No.
No, I just...
You know, a lot of
people are dead, so...
I'll put a note in
the file you called.
Okay, but...
But I wouldn't expect
a callback, though.
We're pretty busy these days,
with the Patriot Act and all.
The file room.
A room with files.
Say you took one of them out.
Took it where?
Doesn't matter.
Say you took one
of the files out.
Is it still the file room?
Pizza today, right?
In the cafeteria?
Or is it meat loaf?
No, I'm saying that
you and I both agree
that the file room
minus one file
is still the file room.
Now, say you took
another one out
and then another.
If the file room minus one file
is still a file room,
and you keep subtracting
one at a time,
you could end up
with zero files...
I'm saying, logically...
or even negative files,
- and it would still...
- How do you have negative files?
No, I'm just...
Logically, I'm saying.
Except no one's taking files.
They just bring more.
What about a cemetery?
I mean, remove one
body from a cemetery,
it's still a cemetery.
But a cemetery with no bodies,
what's that?
Condos.
Okay, this is...
Well, these are my
officers, so...
Where is everybody?
Coffee run. Who's this then?
Oh, this is Tahir. He's...
- Hey.
- Hello. I am Tahir.
I'm Molly. Deputy Solverson.
Yeah, so remember, I told you
me and Sally were
taking in a foster.
Uh, yeah, from Africa.
Yeah, except...
I am from Sudan.
You know, Lost Boy?
I sure do.
Welcome to America.
I thought there was
a problem, though.
Oh, I'll say. Kid disappeared.
Disappeared how?
Oh, tell her the story.
Oh.
This is the craziest thing.
All right, you go on.
You tell her.
In my village, I tend goats.
You know goats?
Uh-huh.
One day, men came
and kill everyone.
Mothers, fathers,
brothers, sisters.
Jeez.
I alone am free.
Three days I walk.
Then I meet nice people...
Americans.
These nice people put me
airplane to America.
Land of free.
Home of brave.
Yeah, to us.
He's coming to live with us.
Yeah. Go on.
At the airport,
man says, "Take a bag?"
He say he's getting
a car, but...
he doesn't come back.
Guy stole his bag.
Can you believe it?
A refugee.
One day and one night
I wait at the airport,
but this man, he
does not come back.
I have no money and no paper.
Nice woman says,
"Tell policeman,"
but I am afraid.
I told her I have
a family waiting.
Nice family.
American family.
But the name is in the
bag and the number.
Nice woman give
me coat and money
to take the bus.
So not all bad.
I take the bus to the city.
But I am very hungry.
Four days I no eat.
Then I see a store.
You know...
July in... January?
Phoenix Farms.
Yes! Phoenix Farms.
Should I tell her this?
Oh.
So...
he shoplifts.
Takes some food.
In fact, he does it every day
for... how long?
- Three months.
Meanwhile, we're frantic.
You remember? All
those phone calls?
Me raising my voice?
How could you lose
a kid from Africa
in freakin' Minnesota?
Every day I steal food, but...
I am ashamed.
I don't want to steal.
I want to work, but
what work can I do?
Then a week ago,
Sally and I are heading into
the city to the ballet.
You went to the ballet?
Sally likes the ballet, yeah.
So... Go ahead. Finish.
I am looking around the store.
Skittles and peanut butter cups.
Then this man grabs me.
I think I am arrested.
It's me!
Is the point of the story.
All those weeks
looking for the kid,
writing letters,
making phone calls,
we even put up flyers.
And then I stop by a supermarket
in a city I don't live,
all so Sally can have
Chex Mix at the ballet,
and there's the kid.
Like, what are the odds?
I can't even imagine.
I'm so worried
and thinking I am arrested.
But Mr. Bill is
hugging me and crying.
Yeah, well,
you know...
And...
look where I am at,
who I'm with, my
American family.
Sally says it's a miracle.
I don't know. It might be.
But don't question the universe.
That's my motto.
Sometimes things just work out.
Yeah, I like to
think that's true.
Yeah.
We found ya, buddy. We found ya.
It causes you to
have hallucinations.
- What?
- I'll be glad to explain it to you.
It's a sort of a nightmare
where your dreams
go pell-mell helter
skelter in a month.
Oh, shut up.
Pell-mell.
Hello. Inspector
Clancy speaking.
You need something?
No, I'm good. Go back to sleep.
Stand back, everybody.
I got you covered. Stand back.
Chief! Chief!
Well, what's the
meaning of this?
Police parading all
over the hotel.
Who sent for you?
Why are you here?
Well, this is Mr.
Williams' suite.
Mr. Williams has been murdered.
Murdered?
- Quiet, everybody.
- You be quiet.
And that goes for all of you.
Yeah, the Chief is right.
Noise, bed-li-ham,
who can think?
Well, you can't, so shut up.
Where's the body?
In there.
Now, what did you do that for?
Well, isn't a girl
supposed to scream
'gonna see a dead body?
Uh, quiet now. Come on
in here, all of you.
We're doing good.
I'm up.
I'm sorry.
I was just saying
we're doing good,
you know?
Mm-hmm.
But it was here, Inspector.
Wasn't it, Johnny?
We got everything we need.
Mm-hmm.
That's preposterous.
No one would dare
commit a murder
in this hotel without
first notifying me.
Are you sure you
weren't seeing things?
No, of course he
wasn't seeing things.
Well, I'm going to sleep.
Just as I told you, Inspector.
Remember the old saying,
"Where there's gun smoke",
there's always a murder."
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, me too.
Oh, it's Jeff, the night porter.
I left him here to
watch the body.
What happened?
I was standing around,
scared stiff,
and all of a sudden,
the lights went out.
Then something hit
me on the head.
Then the lights went out again.
That's all I know,
and that's all I'm gonna
wait around to find out.
Stun Meadows, everybody.
Give it up.
Yowzer. How does he do it, huh?
Check your wallets,
ladies and gentlemen.
Make sure he didn't
make those vanish too.
Well, it's been a big year
for insurance...
a banner year.
Reserve trends are up.
And...
loss ratios are down
a whopping 17%.
And those are just numbers.
We all know that behind
every insurance policy
and the reinsurance policy
covering that policy...
There's a salesman.
A man or woman
knocking on doors, making calls,
matching people and businesses
with the right plan
for their needs.
And so without further delay,
I give you.
Insurance Salesman
of the Year 2007...
Lester Nygaard.
Boy. Come on.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much. That...
Oh, jeez. That's a real honor.
Now...
See, I knew I should
have memorized this.
Suddenly doesn't...
Speak from the heart.
- Speak from the heart.
- Okay.
Those of you that know me
know it's been a tough
year for me personally...
and that I wouldn't
have gotten through it
without the love and support
of my beautiful wife, Linda.
Let's give her a hand.
I love you, Linda.
You know, you can go
through your whole life
without a care,
and one day it all changes.
People die.
They lose their homes.
They go to prison.
It's calamity, huh?
I know it, 'cause I lived it.
And if this year has
taught me anything...
and believe me,
I've seen it all...
it's that the worst does happen.
And you need to be insured.
Thank you so much.
It's a great honor.
So proud of ya, Lester.
Oh, thanks, hon.
You tired?
Oh, aren't you?
Well...
Um...
No, actually.
I'm feeling pretty keyed up.
You know, I might grab
a nightcap at the bar.
You want me to go...
No, no, no. You go up to bed.
I'll be up shortly.
Just, you know, it's
my night, you know?
I'm sorry I'm such a downer.
You're a sunny day.
Go on. I'll be up presently.
I was yours, ♪ ♪ and
you were mine ♪
♪ I was yours, and ♪
♪ you were mine ♪
- Hi.
- Hey.
Big night, huh?
Salesman of the year.
Oh.
Drugs?
Insurance.
Ah.
They really give an award
to the guy who sells
the most drugs?
Pharmaceuticals.
Oh, that makes more sense.
Yeah.
So what are you drinking?
Something dangerous.
Let's have a look.
Uh, oh, a blood and sand.
What's that?
Scotch and blood orange.
That's the one.
All right.
I sit down and... Oh, miss,
can we have some more
sparkling water?
Thanks.
Um, anyways...
so I say, "Hi, I'm Dr.
Michaelson."
"Nice to meet you,"
and everything.
And I get ready to give
him the novocaine shot.
Stick it in my own finger.
And it hurt, but I don't
want to look stupid, so I...