Ladies and gentlemen,
it's time for magic.
Good evening, Gotham. I'm Zatanna.
Tonight, I can promise you
a few surprises.
A thrill or two along the way.
And with luck, a happy ending.
How long has it been? Ten years, 12?
All that and another lifetime.
She and her father
were very fond of you.
I was a different person then.
Yes. Intense, driven, moody.
She'd never recognize you now.
Now open your heart to magic,
and become a child again.
Remember,
concentration and control.
Focus on them,
and you can master any escape.
Go.
Congratulations. You've beaten
your old time by six seconds.
Yes!
You've got the makings
of a great magician.
I'm sorry you're going to be moving on.
Same here. It was an honor
to study with you, Zatara.
But to what end?
Three months ago you appeared
on my doorstep
with no interest in performing,
and yet dying to become
an escape artist.
And for some reason,
I wound up teaching you secrets
I'd never shown another magician.
You could've sent me away.
No. There was something
inside you I had no right to deny.
Something deep and painful.
After all, I would be foolish to assume
I was the only one with secrets.
Eh, John Smith?
Thanks for everything, sir.
I'll miss you, John.
And so, I trust, will Zatanna.
Oh! Hi, Daddy.
Good night, children.
I thought you'd be finishing
the tour with us.
I'm leaving for Japan tomorrow.
There's still a lot I have to learn.
Boy, that's you.
One big serious schoolboy.
No time in your life for fun or magic.
Here, pick a card.
I'll tell your future.
Hmm. I see emotion, intensity...
Two of hearts.
Joker.
Oh, it's a dumb trick anyway.
Look, I don't know the future,
but I know I'll see you again
someday, Zanna.
You're the only one who
ever calls me Zanna.
I really hate it.
No goodbye hug?
See? It's not so bad.
- I'll write you.
- No, you won't.
- I promise.
- You can't.
I locked your hands
to the wall.
What?
Looks like someone's missing
their plane tomorrow.
But hey,
if you were any kind of escape artist
you'd be out of those cuffs
and through the door by now.
Now you see him, now you don't.
Thank you. You know, I have this
little problem with money.
Seems like it disappears
before I even make it.
And here to help me demonstrate
are Mr. Irving Fauncewater,
director of the Gotham Mint,
and noted magic debunker
Dr. Montague Kane.
Welcome, gentlemen.
Miss Zatanna.
This is so exciting.
Oh!
Let me guess, first time on stage, Irv?
Nothing like enthusiasm, right, folks?
The way they're responding,
one would think
your ridiculous stunt was going to work.
Just to clue you in, Monty here makes
a living exposing magicians' secrets.
Simple tricks and nonsense.
Uh-huh.
And I've invited him here
to find the secret of the feat
I'm attempting tonight.
There is no secret. What you're
proposing is flat-out impossible.
Well, kids,
impossible is what I'm all about.
Mr. Fauncewater, open the doors, please.
$10 million and the means to make it.
Take a good look, folks, 'cause you
know what they say about money.
"Easy come,"
"easy go!"
Oh, my!
Bravo, my dear.
It was a pleasure to be proven wrong.
Thank you, Monty.
And now, just so Irv doesn't have a fit,
I'll bring it back good as new.
Arba decarba!
The money. Where's the money?
"Where's the money," he says.
It's right there, isn't it?
It's gone! What have you done with it?
Now, take it easy, Irv. I'm sure there's
a perfectly logical explanation.
And I'm sure the audience
would like to hear it.
- As would the police.
- Now, wait a minute.
Police, police!
The police are coming.
Look, it's a trick, an illusion.
I don't know what went wrong,
but if we can all just
calm down for a second...
"You have the right to remain silent."
"Anything you say can and will
be used against you."
This never happens to me in Vegas.
She's been set up.
Obviously, but as she's the only
suspect, the police must hold her.
Giving the real thief time to escape.
I can't let that happen.
And more important,
you can't desert an old friend.
Huh?
- Nice car.
- Thanks.
You know, I didn't love the idea of
spending the night in jail,
but this does technically
make me a fugitive.
I believe I'm looking
at some prison time now.
I heard about the mint robbery.
I can help prove you didn't do it.
Why do you care about some
leggy dame in nylons?
Or have I answered my own question?
If you want to go it alone...
No, no. I'm sorry. I'm having a bad day.
I'm sure whoever framed you
knew how your trick was done.
They may have left a clue at the mint.
- This place is surrounded by cops.
- Just relax.
That's where the money was.
Look. This line was recently
scraped into the floor.
Whatever made it
left shards of glass, too.
That would have been
one mighty big piece of glass.
Or mirror.
Like the one you used to reflect
the hologram of the vanished mint.
Oh, sure,
take all the mystery out of life.
I think the money was stolen
before you got here.
The thief reflected a hologram
of the cash while you did your trick,
then quickly hid
the mirror when it was over.
How'd he get rid of a mirror that big?
He didn't. It's still here.
Who's in here?
Hold it!
Stay where you are.
Only another magician
would have known how to rig that trick.
Or someone who knows their methods.
Like Montague Kane.
He's been ripping off
illusionists for years.
I thought I finally had a trick
even he couldn't expose. Wrong.
I'll settle with Kane.
Meantime, I'd better
drop you someplace safe.
Oh, no. Kane played me for a sap,
and I'll see him go down for it.
All right, but it could be dangerous.
You're sure there's no one
you want to call first?
Uh, friends, family, a husband, maybe?
Me? Who's got time for a relationship
when you're pulling rabbits
out of a hat 52 weeks a year?
Besides, someone's got to keep
the old act going now that Dad's gone.
- I'm sorry.
- Why?
I saw him perform when I was younger.
He was great.
Thanks. You know, I have
the weirdest feeling we've met before.
I just have that kind of face.
It would seem I have guests.
Come in, and join me by the fire.
Come, come. Don't be shy.
You've obviously unraveled
my little scheme
and I would congratulate you
face-to-face.
You're not going to have a face
when I'm done with you.
Now, you slimy...
It's a trap!
A trifle clichéd,
I know, but effective nonetheless.
And while you briefly savor
your fleeting triumph,
I am winging toward more
comfortable surroundings.
Adieu.
- I have an idea.
- Oh, I would hope so.
This way.
I always did know how to make an exit.
Unfortunately, so did Kane.
And while you
briefly savor your fleeting triumph,
I am winging toward
more comfortable surroundings.
Adieu.
Come on. The show's not over yet.
Take a last longing look,
gentlemen.
We're heading to a place
where the climate is warmer,
the people are friendlier
and the extradition laws
are nonexistent.
The only place
you're heading is to a prison cell.
Well done, Batman.
You not only eluded my trap,
but solved my clue as well.
Get rid of him.
Ta-da!
Oh, Monty. You fell for
the second-oldest trick in the book.
And here's the first.
Keep your distance, Detective.
You are most engaging, my dear.
Beautiful, impetuous.
I could be persuaded to spare you,
if properly implored.
Ow!
Bring them both!
With all reverence for the departed,
Zatara himself
couldn't escape those locks.
Still, between the two of you, you might
be able to loosen a few chains
before you hit the water.
Take my hand.
Scared? That makes two of us.
- Trust me, Zanna.
- "Zanna"?
Quick, in my glove.
Farewell, my dear Zatanna.
We could have been magic.
Incredible.
Stop firing, you fools!
Get rid of him!
Whoa!
Don't you know? A magician never
does the same trick twice.
So, you never wrote.
I meant to. Really.
Hey, it's okay.
I can see you've been busy.
- Just answer an old friend one question.
- Shoot.
What happened that made you put this on?
A painful memory.
And a promise.
I'd say you're keeping
that promise pretty well.
And for what it's worth,
Dad would've been proud of you tonight.
You, too.
Can I give you a ride?
John,
I hate goodbyes too. Love, Zanna.
P.S. Don't forget to write.