James Gordon, I have a warrant
for your arrest.
Previously on Batman...
The rally's tomorrow night.
Everything's in place.
You know what to do.
I'm going to see Jim Gordon gets
all the public support we can muster.
All the top cops will be there,
so don't worry your pretty little head.
Should be quite a show.
Yes, and I know someone who'd be
a real showstopper.
The best thing you can do for him
is to keep out of it.
Sorry, Batman. You being at the rally
could decide if Dad goes free.
So you'll be there, one way or another.
After all Commissioner Gordon
has done for Gotham City,
the least the city can do for him
is grant him bail.
Gil, you know those guys
who shot at you?
Well, I think I know who one of them...
I didn't know you had company.
My friend here was just leaving.
Yeah, gotta run. Listen, I'll see you
at the business meeting, Gil.
Miss.
Look at that.
Mr. Mason ducked before he saw the guns.
Almost as though he expected it.
What am I gonna do?
If Gil's involved in this,
there's nobody I can trust.
- Where will you start?
- With Gil Mason.
The videotape clearly shows
that he ducked
before those shots were fired.
If he knew he was gonna be shot at,
he probably knows a lot more
about what's going on.
Then he may know more
than he's letting on
about Commissioner Gordon's
unfortunate situation.
I hope so, Alfred.
'Cause if this lead fizzles,
I'm fresh out of ideas.
Stop!
You again?
Listen, under other circumstances,
this could be fun,
but I've got a job to do.
Don't flatter yourself.
Well, I don't have time
to babysit amateurs, okay?
I may not have a diploma
from crime-fighting school,
but I can do fine on my own, thanks.
- What are you doing here anyway?
- Same as you. We both suspect Mason of...
Mason here.
You wanna meet? Okay, where?
What's he saying?
Dork.
South Gotham subway,
the old river entrance. In one hour.
Right. I'm on my way.
Well, show's over.
You can run along home now.
- Okay.
- Okay?
If you won't let me help you,
what else can I do?
Good. You've got some sense after all.
Nice guy,
but a few bats short of a belfry.
Whoa!
Gotta work on that landing, girl.
I guess the party started without me.
You sure you haven't seen him
at the department?
I'd remember that face.
Who is he?
In a few minutes,
nobody's gonna care.
- Okay, you're done.
- So that's it?
You bring me all the way to South Gotham
to ID some two-bit hood?
Don't get wise with me, Mason.
Remember who got you set up
as Gordon's assistant.
Right, Harvey, right.
Don't call me that!
It's Two-Face to you, pretty boy.
Okay, okay. Two-Face, take it easy.
You're the man.
Don't you forget it.
Since our little stunt at the rally,
I got this city thinking
you're the best thing since the Batman.
Once Gordon's out of the picture...
You'll be a shoo-in to take his place.
In fact, they could be calling you
Commissioner by tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I'm stepping up the timetable.
Too many people nosing around.
This guy, that Batgirl chippy.
I'm not taking any chances.
My men will bust Gordon
out of jail tonight.
Then we'll dump him off Bayshore Wharf.
- Hey!
- What's that?
Hey, did you hear something?
We got company. Over there.
Robin, look out!
Robin?
If he's Robin, that makes you...
Let's go!
Blow it!
Just whose side are you on?
You're right. If I hadn't let him
take me by surprise...
Robin! I see you brought a date.
Me? I thought she was with you.
She's got your taste in clothes,
speaking of which...
Yes. Am I glad to see you.
Do you mind?
Sorry.
Well, this is just great. Now Batman
and Robin know what's going on.
The bat-chick too. I saw her.
The explosion probably
took care of them. But just in case...
I don't know who you are
or why you're doing this,
but let's get one thing straight.
It takes more than a costume
and an attitude to do this work.
Look, I've got a reason
for being here so...
You've already fouled up once.
Stay out of our way
so it doesn't happen again.
I should've known it would be Two-Face.
It's a perfect two-part plan.
He consolidates the gangs
while Mason takes over the police.
What he said about the Commissioner,
will he...
You saw him flip his coin.
It's judge, jury, and executioner.
And here we sit with no way to...
Huh?
Sounds like a train.
Argh!
Hold on.
Not bad. Maybe there's hope
for you after all.
Hurry, Batman!
Great. Only how do we get to it?
Always carry a spare.
You first. Press here to send
it back down to us.
Wait.
Just in case
you run into trouble up there.
Thanks.
No!
If I ever get reinstated, Bullock,
remind me to do something
about the food in here.
Relax, Commish. We got the judge
to reconsider bail, didn't we?
You gonna eat that pickle?
- What in...
- Come on, Commissioner.
Rupert Thorne doesn't
desert his friends.
Thorne...
Get some keys down here!
Never a blasted cop when you need one.
Think she made it?
I hope so.
Think we'll make it?
What do you think about the
commissioner's innocence now, Detective?
- I don't know.
- Come on, he has to be guilty.
- Have you heard from Gordon?
- Any leads about his whereabouts?
You think he's left town?
- Get out of my face, all of you.
- Detective. Detective.
I can barely hear you, miss!
The phone lines
must've been damaged by the explosion.
Speak up!
I said Commissioner Gordon's in danger.
I still can't hear you.
If you want the story
on Gordon's breakout, come down here.
Breakout?
They've got him.
I've got an idea.
It's about time.
- Where are we going?
- We'll find out when we get there.
Subways are getting
more dangerous every day.
You think they got
the Commissioner by now?
Most likely. We've got to
get to Bayshore Wharf.
Glad it's not far. I hate wet shoes.
It's business, Jim. Nothing personal.
Matter of fact, I respect you. I do.
But a fella has to take
his opportunities where he finds them.
And with you out of the way,
I'll be mayor inside of a year.
You're sick, Gil. A lot sicker than him.
At least I can see his bad half.
Sorry you feel that way.
At least you won't have to worry
about Barbara.
I'll take good care of her.
She's very fond of me, you know.
You piece of scum. I may not be around
to stop you but I know someone who will.
I wouldn't count on it, Jim.
There's been a recent decline
in the bat population.
Run, Commissioner!
Get him!
Batgirl, I presume.
Don't worry. I'll get you out of this.
Somehow.
Miss me?
I think you're safe now, sir.
Get him. Snuff the Bat!
What?
You've screwed up my plans
for the last time, Batman.
No, you don't.
Ahhh!
- That's a first. A coin flips Two-Face.
- Where's Batgirl?
Out there. On her own.
Now let's see who you really are.
- Barbara? I didn't know it was you.
- Would it have made a difference, Gil?
I ought to leave you here.
Commissioner, I understand
that Gil Mason is still in a coma.
Yes, but even so, he has been indicted.
So how does it feel to be
behind your desk again?
A heck of a lot better than it felt
being behind bars.
And what of the mysterious Batgirl?
Who is she and where has she
vanished to? Any thoughts?
As far as I'm concerned,
she's as welcome
in Gotham City as the Batman.
How do you think Batman
will feel about that?
I suppose there's always room
for one more.
And I have a feeling
we'll be seeing her again.
I wouldn't be at all surprised.