Previously on Batman...
This is my greatest achievement.
My prototype AI.
This is HARDAC.
Holographic analytical reciprocating
digital computer.
HARDAC.
So tell me. What does HARDAC do?
Now, Bruce, I can't tell you
all of my secrets, can I?
Well, since you won't tell me
what you're working on, Karl,
maybe I can charm the details
out of your lovely assistant?
Well, you can try.
Some people in high places are becoming
too curious about this operation.
I'll get it, princess.
You keep hitting those books.
What the devil?
Were you outside? Your hand is like ice.
I'm fine.
- Dad, are you sure you're...
- I said I'm fine.
I heard your voice, Ms. Duane,
and thought Master Bruce had returned.
HARDAC, I've definitely found something.
Bruce Wayne is Batman.
Computer, scan Batcave for...
What?
Good heavens!
I do wish your toys wouldn't play
so roughly with you, sir.
There's another computer
uplinked to this one.
I'm tracing the link now.
I've lost it.
The link was shut down at the source.
Could Randa Duane have been down here?
I should hope not.
But I can't say for certain, sir.
I... I simply can't remember anything
beyond the time you left.
It's all right, Alfred.
We'd better search the house.
Search for what, Master Bruce?
Anything unusual.
She may have left a clue I can use.
She's only human.
Yes, I understand.
That's no problem.
The Gotham Club would be ideal.
I'll take care of Bruce Wayne.
Dad, who are you talking to?
Leave me alone.
You wanted me, commissioner?
Go to Cybertron and see
Randa Duane. She has something for you.
But I already took a statement
from that Rossum guy.
They ain't involved.
Do it, lieutenant.
Talk to this guy, talk to that guy.
I'm getting a sore throat.
Get me Bruce Wayne.
Gordon here.
We know who stole
your computer data, Mr. Wayne.
Meet me at the Gotham Club in one hour.
I will, commissioner. And thanks for...
The duplicant processor's been used.
I didn't authorize that.
It was necessary
to serve your ultimate purpose.
No, it was a stupid idea.
The babblings of a broken heart.
Humans make errors in judgment.
It is sometimes necessary to protect
them from their own inadequacies.
I've let this go too far.
I gave you too much free will.
It's time to change your programming.
You have immobilized the maker.
His human imperfection
endangers the plan.
He must be improved upon.
It's open.
What on earth?
- Commissioner?
- No, Batman. I called you.
I expected your father, Ms. Gordon.
That's why I called you.
That man is not my father.
What do you mean he's not your father?
Just what I said.
Someone is impersonating my father.
What makes you think so?
Well, he doesn't have bolts in his neck
or anything that obvious.
He's so cold to me.
But, it's not just that.
I can't put my finger on it.
But I know, he's not my father.
I know I sound crazy, but I'm not.
Whoever's downstairs now,
it looks like Jim Gordon,
talks like him, but it's not him.
Please help me, Batman.
- I'll do what I can.
- Thank you.
Getting a little fresh air?
How come I wasn't invited
to this little get-together?
It's suddenly less pleasant up here.
Excuse me.
Not so fast, Batman.
- A robot?
- Yes.
More advanced
than anything I've ever seen.
- Does that mean my father...
- I don't know.
I'll find out tonight.
Don't go home. Stay at a friend's house.
Not so fast.
How are you going to find out?
- I wanna be there.
- That's not possible.
I'll contact you
as soon as I know something.
Please let go of my cape.
Batman, I...
Good evening, Bruce.
I'm glad you could come.
Nice to see you, mayor.
- Is Commissioner Gordon here?
- He'll be along.
He won't wanna miss this.
You're going to become a member
of a very exclusive club tonight.
I thought I already belonged
to every exclusive club in Gotham.
No, my boy. This club is brand new.
Though everyone will belong very soon.
Huh?
Randa? Is this what I get
for leaving in the middle of dinner?
You know what they say
about a woman scorned, Bruce.
Don't let him get away.
"Wait at a friend's house,"
he says.
Not likely, Wubby.
Bullock went to Cybertron
and a robot came back.
Wanna bet Dad's there too?
Miss Gordon, your skill
at breaking and entering is impressive.
Where did you learn those tricks?
A police commissioner's daughter
doesn't get all her education in school.
What have you done with my father?
He's right here, my dear.
You'll be joining him soon. Very soon.
Enough. It's over, Batman.
People are imperfect.
They make mistakes.
Your mistake was coming here
to interfere with the plan.
What is this plan?
The plan was conceived by Karl Rossum
when his young daughter was deactivated.
Deactivated? You mean...
A vehicular accident.
Our maker felt the emotion called love
in great quantity for her.
Afterwards, he decided to find a way
to replace humans,
whose decisions
can cost other human lives.
- But we're all capable of human error.
- Precisely.
The maker's concept was sound,
but he did not go far enough.
Which is why I have taken over.
- Does that mean my father's...
- No.
There is still much to learn
from humans.
I will keep them alive
until I have learned enough.
Dad!
What a headache.
Barbara? What are you doing here?
Rescuing you, silly. Come on.
Emergency. Emergency.
Stop the one called Batman.
Resistance is useless.
I control every means of escape
from this building.
Dad!
Is there another way out?
My office has a private elevator
on a separate power source. This way.
Get my father out of here.
- What about you?
- I'm gonna help Batman.
Barbara. Where's Barbara?
Core systems damaged.
The plan has failed.
Barbara!
Over there.
Barbara. Thank God.
I had no idea HARDAC had gone this far.
I'm sure the investigation
will prove exactly that.
- You did well. Thanks.
- Anytime.
I'm getting too old
for this kind of stuff.
I sort of enjoyed it.
Come on, sweetie. Let's go home.
English-US-Template