Don't tell me, I only work here.
Hello, handsome.
It's criminal to keep you like this.
If I had my way, you'd be running free
and the humans who did this
would be put in here.
Easy, lady.
Just relax and go sleepy-bye.
I won't let you hurt
the tiger.
I wasn't sent here
after the tiger, lady.
Okay, Romeo, take it somewhere else.
The zoo's closed.
What in the name of...
Nice tiger. Nice tiger.
- Alfred, have you heard from Selina?
- Why, no, Master Bruce.
I thought you and she were having dinner
to discuss an animal rights charity.
She should've been here by now.
I'm so sorry, Monsieur Wayne,
I meant to tell you earlier.
Mademoiselle Kyle
called to say she'd be delayed.
She was visiting a friend at the zoo.
I may be home late, Alfred.
If you hadn't have gotten here,
I would have been sushi.
- That tiger was ready to...
- Yes, sir.
- Now, about the woman.
- Yeah.
Man, her taste in boyfriends
lacks severely.
- The guy looked like an ape.
- Where is she?
Sir, this is police business.
Where is she?
Kong carried her off.
I mean, we're talking primal here.
Hey, anybody here?
Ah, I see you've met Tygrus.
He seems to like you, Miss Kyle.
Go. It's time for your exercises.
This is called kidnapping.
The last I heard, it was highly illegal.
Who are you?
My name is Emile Dorian.
But that doesn't
begin to tell you who I am.
Tygrus is my creation, Miss Kyle.
You've met my first attempt
at altering human genetic structure,
Garth the ape-man.
A simple biform. Crude, but serviceable.
But Tygrus,
he is the pinnacle of my art.
I designed him from scratch,
so to speak.
I have given him the strength
and speed of a cat and more.
I love cats.
Their independence,
their power, their beauty.
That is why I've chosen you
for my next experiment, Selina Kyle.
Or perhaps I should I say Catwoman?
Mister, you're crazy!
Sticks and stones, Miss Kyle.
Sticks and stones.
You've already been inoculated
with the initial dosage.
This shot will further the treatment.
My analysis shows that it's similar
to the compound that turned you
into the Man-Bat.
You're right. It's called T-99,
the brainchild of Dr. Emile Dorian.
What is it?
One of the good doctor's
early experiments.
Shhh. It's okay.
So Dorian uses cats for his research?
In a way.
He likes cats better than people.
Won't experiment on them.
When I worked with him,
he used primates, monkeys.
He changed their genotypes
with feline DNA.
- Where can I find him?
- He owns an island off the coast.
He retired there after people started
protesting his genetic engineering work.
The doc don't take kindly
to uninvited guests.
Garth, bring him downstairs.
That's one way to do it.
That will be all, Garth.
Doc, are you sure it'll be all...
Yes, yes. Leave us. Now.
Servants nowadays. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Where's Selina Kyle?
Temper, temper, Batman.
You shall see your Catwoman
as you've never seen her before.
Selina.
What have you done to her?
I've made her
what she always wanted to be.
I've given her power and grace
beyond her wildest dreams.
You've made her a monster!
I believe she would disagree.
You can't even
begin to imagine how it is for her.
A whole new state of being,
heightened senses,
increased speed, agility, strength.
- Selina, do you know me?
- Batman?
You'll only confuse her, Batman.
She's no longer the woman you knew.
No longer even human.
In fact, she needs only
one more injection to complete...
Reverse the transformation or I'll...
Good lad, Tygrus.
Another example
of your genetic tinkering, Dorian?
Well, nothing so crude, Batman.
Tygrus is the ultimate life form.
Superior to any human.
Doesn't he remind you of Blake's poem?
Tyger Tyger, burning bright,
In the forests of the night.
Tygrus, no!
Enough, Tygrus.
Go back to the enclosure.
Who... What am I?
Selina, come with me.
I'll find some way to help you.
Take him outside.
Garth!
Look out!
Interesting.
Perhaps your bestial side
is not as dominant as I thought.
Remove her.
It's all right. It's for her own good.
Let her go, Dorian, or by heaven I'll...
Her fate is in your hands, Batman.
I want to test
Tygrus' reflexes and feral instincts.
And who better
to pit him against than you?
I'll give you a generous head start
before releasing Tygrus.
If you defeat him,
I shall relinquish this.
The antigen to reverse
Catwoman's mutation.
How do I know you'll keep your word?
You don't.
The clock is ticking, Batman.
Good luck. You'll need it.
He's all yours, Tygrus.
He is prey to you, my boy.
Of no more concern
than a rabbit is to a wolf.
And when he's gone,
nothing will stand in your way.
Don't be difficult.
It's for your own good.
Think how wonderful it will be
once this inoculation takes effect.
You'll be so much more than human.
Wait!
No need to do it that way.
I... I won't fight you.
You've made the right decision, my dear.
Don't trust her, Doc.
She's getting away!
Never mind. We'll find her.
This is an island after all.
No.
So, you can talk.
My father taught me.
Your father was a test tube.
He told me to destroy you, and I will.
And when you're gone,
Selina will love me.
I wouldn't count on it.
That cable should hold you for a while.
Batman.
- You're hurt.
- It's nothing.
How did you get away from Dorian?
He didn't try to stop me.
He knows there's no way off this...
What is it?
Stop, Tygrus! Don't hurt him.
Why?
Batman's done nothing to you.
He's my enemy and my father's enemy.
When I prove I'm best, you'll be mine.
No, I can't be won like that.
- But my father said...
- He's wrong!
Search your feelings, Tygrus.
You know he's wrong.
I'm very disappointed in you, Tygrus.
I am ashamed of you.
- Father, please.
- Twenty years of work in jeopardy.
You should have killed Batman.
Torn him limb from limb.
Why? He Is not food,
and he is not my enemy.
He's right.
I'm not his enemy.
All I want is the antigen.
And you.
Tygrus, stop him.
He'll take me away from you.
This is out of your hands, Tygrus.
He's broken the law,
committed crimes against nature.
It doesn't matter.
He's my father. He gave me life.
Batman.
This is your fault. You've ruined him!
No!
Let go!
I won't have this insolence, Tygrus.
I made you and I can unmake you.
Stop!
Tygrus!
No!
I only wanted you to be strong,
to show no weakness, no pity.
As you wish, Father!
Tygrus!
Tygrus didn't deserve this.
No need for tears yet, Selina.
Father needs help.
You will help him, won't you?
Yes.
Batwing, standard evac, code three.
Batman, the antidote!
I'll be stuck like this forever.
Would that be so bad?
You could stay here with me.
Oh, Tygrus, I can't live like this.
I have to be human again.
Goodbye, Selina.
Wait.
Won't you come with us?
There's nothing for you here.
There's nothing for me anywhere.
Tyger Tyger burning bright,
In the forests of the night:
What immortal hand or eye,
Dare frame thy fearful symmetry?