Master Bruce?
Are you all right, sir?
- I'm tired, Alfred.
- I shouldn't wonder.
You've taken no meals today.
I can't recall when you last slept.
A weary body can be dealt with
but a weary spirit,
that's something else.
Sometimes, old friend, I wonder
if I'm really doing any good out there.
How can you doubt it?
The lives you've saved,
the criminals you've brought to justice.
I've put out a few fires, yes,
won a few battles.
But the war goes on, Alfred. On and on.
You have it, Alfred?
Of course, sir.
It's a done deal. You're looking
at the new vice president of...
Excuse me, folks. Spare some change?
Trying to get bus fare home.
Uh, sure.
Works every time.
I say we take them now,
before the deal happens.
We got enough on them.
What are we waiting for?
Batman. He got us the dirt
on the Jazzman.
Said he'd be here
when the hammer went down.
Batman.
You seem quieter than usual tonight.
Every year I come here, I wonder
if it should be the last time,
if I should put the past behind me,
try to lead a normal life.
Santayana says that those who forget
the past are condemned to repeat it.
He also said a fanatic is someone
who redoubles his efforts
while losing sight of his goal.
Wizard, you never call. You never write.
You never pay us our piece of kale
for letting you work that corner.
Willie. Monk. Yeah,
I was just looking for you guys.
Let's skip the pleasantries.
What do you say? 50 bucks, now.
It's that, or I cut out your liver
and fry it in a pan.
I haven't exactly got it right now.
Then what you do got
is a whole world of trouble.
Willie?
You're mine. Later.
Hey, Bats, don't worry about me.
I don't need help from some jerk
in long underwear.
Think there's room in the
Mitchell Street Mission for one more?
Of course.
Commissioner, it's gotta be now.
Hit it.
This is the police. You men
in the warehouse, you're under arrest.
Aren't you going home?
It's almost 3:00 a.m.
Promises to keep, Leslie.
I have promises to keep.
This was a setup.
The Jazzman was ready for us.
I've been waiting a long time
to play "Taps" for Gordon.
What the hell?
What's the deal? We couldn't
get close enough to use tear gas.
Looks like the fat lady
just sung, Jimmy.
Hey, where's the commish?
He should see this.
Commissioner?
Oh, my God!
BP, 90/60.
Respiration shallow.
Normal saline.
Type and cross match. Five units now.
Warm up O.R. 1.
Last night, police broke the smuggling
ring of Jimmy "The Jazzman" Peake.
But the victory in the drug war
came at a high cost.
Police Commissioner James Gordon
was badly wounded in the line of duty.
Ballistics investigation has matched
the bullet with the Jazzman's gun.
Any comments, Jazzman?
Let's just say it was time
to pay the piper.
Sources say that
the Jazzman has long nursed
a grudge against Commissioner Gordon.
The commissioner remains in
intensive care at Gotham City Hospital.
I don't know if you can hear me, Jim.
I'm sorry.
If I hadn't stopped in Crime Alley...
Batman.
- How is he?
- Not good.
It's my fault.
I should've gotten there first,
checked it out before.
Don't blame yourself.
You caught the man who shot him.
If I'd been there...
You should've been there, pointy ears.
Then maybe Peake might've shot
the right guy.
I thought you were supposed to know
what's shaking on the streets.
How come you didn't tell us
this was a setup?
- I didn't know.
- Yeah?
In my book that makes you
just as responsible
for him being here as the Jazzman.
Harvey, please. It wasn't his fault.
Hey, where you going?
This ain't over yet, outlaw!
You hear me? You're going down for this!
I ain't talking law!
I'm talking you and me!
James Peake, you are hereby remanded
to the custody
of the state pending trial.
As there is no room currently
in the Gotham City jail,
you will be taken to Stonegate
Penitentiary to await a trial date.
It ain't going to trial.
They got enough on me to play
the funeral march.
Not a problem, bro.
Talk to Southside Eddy.
He'll get you on the street
and out of Gotham
before the ink on your fingers dries.
Not out of Gotham. Not yet.
First, I'll make sure Gordon's
got a one-way ticket to harp land.
Not now, Jimmy. You gotta lay low.
Gordon busted me six years ago.
Would've been the best score of my life.
I owe him big time.
I'm so glad you could come,
Master Dick. It's been three days.
I've never seen him like this before.
Bruce?
Bruce! Stay down here much longer,
you'll be growing mushrooms
in your armpits.
- I should have been there.
- You can't be everywhere.
- I let him down.
- You're being too hard on yourself.
He's a friend. More than a friend.
Jim Gordon's the same age
my father would've been if he hadn't...
Now he's hanging by a thread.
If I'd gotten there five minutes sooner.
You're only human.
You do all one man can do.
More than any man's expected to do.
Laundry coming through, boss.
I chose this life.
I use the night. I became the night.
Sooner or later, I'll go down.
It might be the Joker or Two-Face
or just some punk who gets lucky.
My decision. No regrets.
But I can't let anyone else
pay for my mistakes.
Jim Gordon's a cop, Bruce.
He knows the risks.
How long before I let
someone else I care about down?
Leslie. Alfred. You.
Now.
When all is said and done,
how much good have I accomplished?
They sell T-shirts of me.
I've become a cliché. More good
for the tourist trade than the streets.
This city would fall apart without you.
Maybe. Maybe not.
When you look too long into the abyss,
the abyss looks back through you.
Maybe it's time for Batman to return
to the night that spawned him
before anyone else gets hurt.
Jimmy Peake's a madman, Dick.
He'll try to finish what he started.
I feel so helpless.
I can't just sit here.
I've gotta do something to...
I know how you feel.
More than you might think.
But your place is here.
There's only one person
who can find the Jazzman now.
- You're talking about Batman.
- I hope so.
You've gotta pull yourself
out of this, Bruce.
The Jazzman broke out of Stonegate.
He's gone to ground somewhere in Gotham.
You know he'll find a way
to get to Gordon.
Okay. Then I'm going after him.
You taught me everything I know
about crime-fighting, Bruce.
But the most important lesson
was to never give up.
No, Dick.
This is my hunt.
Attention, all cars.
Suspect sighted near corner
of Adams and O'Neil.
This is Bullock. I'm on him.
Roger, Detective. Use caution.
I've gotta get some coffee, Dad.
I'll be right back.
Time to face the music, Gordon.
No!
Freeze, Jimmy!
- Barbara?
- Dad! You're all right.
The bust... Went down okay?
Yes. Get some rest now.
Gotta keep fighting. Never stop.
What I try to live by.
Maybe if I'd been younger,
could've been like you.
Always wanted to be a hero.
You are a hero, Jim.
Up to your old tricks, I see.
How about returning that suitcase
to its owner.
Hey, man, I am the owner.
You know, I was kind of hoping
I'd run into you.
I'd been in those places
like where you left me before.
Heard the rap, wasn't impressed.
But this time it made sense.
Maybe I was ready to hear it.
So I'm heading back home.
I guess I kind of owe it to you, Batman.
You probably saved my life.
I bet you hear this all the time.
Look, I'm gonna miss my bus.
I'll see you around.
And thanks.