You jerks!
Ah! The wind in my hair
and the Batman at my heels.
It's the kind of night that
makes you glad to be alive.
Right, Harley girl?
Sure thing, Mr. J.
Quick! Turn here!
- But, boss, that's...
- I said, turn!
Yes, sir.
Why didn't you tell me
someone put a hill there?
- I tried, but...
- Never mind. Just hand me the gun.
Come on! Come on!
Here.
Hey, Batsy!
This is where I leave you flat.
You nincompoop!
You didn't say which gun.
Let's go. Let's go!
If he wants the car that bad,
he can have it.
Next time, clown.
No, we didn't get the diamond.
The "Dork Knight" showed up
before we even got to the museum.
I had a great shot at him, too,
except my dear little Harley Quinn
handed me the wrong gun!
But, pudding, it was kind of funny
watching you shoot at him
with the "bang" flag.
Funny?
You presume to tell me what
I should think is funny?
In fact, when have you ever
contributed a worthwhile idea
to this gang?
Well,
I did get us away from Batman.
Huzzah!
The kid gets lucky,
and she wants a medal!
Maybe I should just let
you run the gang.
Maybe you're a better crook
than the rest of us put together.
Maybe
not.
Fine! I'll show you! You'll be sorry!
I'll pull a big heist,
and I'll be laughing at you.
Ha! Ha! You hear? Laughing!
I miss him already.
Piece of cake.
Mr. J will just plotz when I give him...
No. I'm keeping it for myself.
Maybe.
The heck with it!
Nice work, butterfingers.
Why didn't you just turn on
the Bat signal while you were at it?
I wasn't trying to get caught.
Could've fooled me.
Hey! Aren't you that plant lady,
Poison Oakie?
Ivy. Poison Ivy.
Sorry.
Harley Quinn. Pleased to meet you.
This is not a good time
to get acquainted.
Freeze!
Any ideas?
What you got in the bottles?
Plant toxins
from the museum lab.
Good enough.
Heads up!
Stop in the name of the law!
Not tonight, baby.
Get in the car!
What car?
That car.
- Yes!
This could be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
I hate shots!
Now, now. You're
not immune to poison like I am
and you won't last 10 minutes
here in Toxic Acres without my antidote.
You'd think after living with
Mr. J, I'd be used to a little pain.
Why do you put up with that clown?
Don't get me wrong. My pudding's
a little rough sometimes,
but he loves me, really.
Sure he does.
You're just one big forgiving doormat,
aren't you?
I am not a doormat.
Am I?
If you had a middle name,
it would be "Welcome."
But cheer up, kid. You just need some
lessons in good old female self-esteem.
In other words, let's play with the boys
on our terms.
And now, gentlemen,
if there is no new business,
I propose we adjourn to...
A moment, please, Mr. Chairman.
- Who is that?
- A woman, here?
Outrageous!
See here, young lady,
is this some kind of joke?
The joke, my dear chairman,
is this obsolete, sexist mockery
you call a men's club.
Now, I ask you,
what kind of adventurers refuse
to admit women?
- What does she know?
- That is ridiculous.
Get her out of here.
How dare she?
Still, if it's excitement
you boys crave...
What is this?
- Let go!
- Stop!
That should keep you big strong men
busy while we weak little girls
loot your trophy room.
Gee, Red. You got style!
This is true.
What did you make? What did you make?
Steamed chard and beet juice. Hmm! Yum!
Gee, green.
My favorite color.
No offense, Red,
but I'm not very hungry.
Somehow I don't feel
like my old perky self.
Something's missing.
Will you stop? I can't believe you're
still mooning over that psychotic creep.
Well, maybe I'd feel better
if I knew he missed me, too.
Harley!
This place is going
to blinking blue blazes.
Anybody seen my socks?
Harley!
They snapped at me!
What's going on, Roc?
The place is a mess, no one's fed
the hyenas, and I can't find my socks!
Where's Harley?
You canned her,
boss, remember?
So? She's always come back before.
Gee,
I guess you ain't seen the papers then.
Papers? What are you babbling about?
I remember when I would go driving
like this with Mr. J.
"Mr. J, Mr. J."
Change the record, Harl.
You want to be some wacko's victim
the rest of your life?
Well, hello.
I think I'm in love.
Ahooga! Ahooga!
Excuse me, boys.
Didn't your mommies tell you that's not
the nice way to get a lady's attention?
Oh! And what are you gonna do? Spank us?
That's right, pigs.
And here's the paddle.
There may be hope for you yet.
Choosing a weekend date, sir?
This is one sister act
that's hard to follow, Alfred.
Only clue I have is this soil analysis
from their tire tracks.
Hmm.
Contains the same compounds
you'd find in a toxic waste dump.
Then may I suggest an accessory
this evening?
What?
Mr. J?
Harley?
Hi, pudding. You still angry with me?
Honey, baby, pumpkin pie.
You know I can't hold a grudge.
- Where are you?
- With a friend.
Look, I can't talk, but I wanted
to let you know I'm okay.
Oops. Gotta go.
I'll talk to you soon.
Sooner than you think.
- What's up?
- Wrong number.
Evening, ladies.
Playtime's over.
Land o' Goshen, Harleen.
Look who's come a-courting.
Looks like he's got us.
Looks like!
Poor Batman. All trussed up.
And no place to go.
- Yes!
Here we have
the typical male aggressor,
fittingly imprisoned within the bonds
of female domestic slavery.
And, frankly, folks,
he's never looked better.
Admit it, darling,
you didn't think two women
were capable of bringing you down.
Man or woman,
a sick mind is capable of anything.
A very enlightened statement, Batman.
We'll carve it on your headstone.
Aloha, sucker.
Hey, did you leave the lights on?
My, haven't you been
the busy little bees.
Pudding?
You were out, so we just made
ourselves at home.
Hope you don't mind.
You found me!
So much for self-esteem.
I hope you realize
we're on a toxic waste dump.
I'd say you've got 10 minutes
to clear out before the fumes do you in.
She's right, boss.
I'm feeling kind of...
Sick.
Hold it in, Rocco.
I'm only staying long enough
to collect what's mine.
Hey!
Ooh! Look at the goodies.
That's ours, you louse!
Pammy, I wouldn't
leave you empty-handed.
Since you like flowers so much...
Oh, Pudding, no!
You can have mine!
Oh!
Red!
It doesn't work on me.
Get them!
Oh, Batsy!
Stop shooting, you lunatic.
We're sitting on a powder keg.
Oops. Dopey me.
No man can take us prisoner.
All right, ladies.
Raise them.
That's it.
Next time I start a gang, no women.
Do you hear me?
No women!
I think we can still work it out.
Don't you?