Selina Kyle, you have pled guilty
to the charges brought against Catwoman.
And do you understand
you can be sentenced to
as much as 25 years in prison?
Yes, Your Honor.
Regardless of the fact
that you committed the crimes
to benefit animals and wildlife,
theft is theft.
Yes, Your Honor.
However, since you did help save
Gotham City from annihilation
and the district attorney
has recommended a plea bargain,
I have decided to sentence you
to five years probation.
Yeah.
I'm not finished!
But I'm warning you, Miss Kyle,
if you ever don your Catwoman costume
again to violate the law,
I'll not only revoke probation,
I'll throw the book at you.
I understand.
Miss Kyle, one question
from you and a picture.
I'll lose my job
if I don't get the question.
Miss Kyle, Miss Kyle.
Just one question.
Is Catwoman really finished?
And though she's been
released on probation,
the question still remains.
Can this lady leopard
really change her spots?
I do hope you'll be seeing Miss Selina
now that she's free to prowl again.
I don't think so.
But I thought
you'd grown quite fond of her.
I assumed the feeling was mutual.
Almost.
She's in love with Batman.
Oh, dear.
These modern relationships
can be so complicated.
Besides, I'm not totally convinced
she's given up her criminal life.
Oh, Maven,
I can't believe I'm really free.
Come here, Isis.
Where's my little precious?
Um, there's something
I have to tell you.
Maven, where's my cat?
I... I don't know.
A couple of days ago, I left
the window open, and she was gone.
I think she went looking for you.
I searched everywhere.
I'm so sorry, Selina.
Temperatures have reached
record lows
as another snowstorm heads our way.
We advise our listeners
to keep children and pets inside.
Isis?
Relax. I'm a friend.
Fleabags.
Dirty, lousy, stinking fleabags.
Get them, Paunch.
Come to mama, you disgusting furball.
Just what do you think you're doing?
Catching strays.
What's it to you?
You're obviously not the animal shelter.
So, what do you want with these cats?
None of your business. So kiss off.
Fine.
- But I'm taking my friends.
- Hey.
You asked for it, sister.
Now, tell me, what are you up to?
Paunch, do something!
That's one way to take out the trash.
Laugh this off, sister!
Nail her!
Paunch?
Hey, you can't do this to me!
Put a lid on it, sister.
You were supposed to
stay out of trouble.
Don't tell me you're my very own
private probation officer.
How often would you like me to check in?
I'm afraid our reunion
will have to wait.
All right, what's going on here?
She jumped us.
I wanna press charges.
They were stealing cats.
Stealing from who,
you dumb cluck?
They're strays.
We were just rounding them up
to find them good homes
when this maniac attacked us.
This is insane.
Sounds like we better settle this
downtown, Miss Kyle.
Downtown?
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
The speed at which the toxin
overtakes the animal's system
is something to behold, Mr. Daggett.
Even with a species this large.
There.
You can see the change almost instantly.
Careful, sir.
One little nip, and the toxin
will spread through you
with the same virulence.
Good, Milo.
Remember, speed is of the essence.
I expect this operation to be completed
by tomorrow night.
Sorry, kitten.
But you heard the man.
Maven, how on Earth did you
raise my bail at this hour?
I see.
Your bail money is safe.
I promise.
That's not important, Selina.
You are.
Bruce, I like you a lot.
But as a friend.
I understand.
Then, as a friend, may I point out
this arrest could revoke your probation?
I'll worry about that
after I find my cat.
What I wanna know is
what those creeps I met in the alley
are doing with a big-time attorney
from Daggett Labs.
I spend a night in jail, and he has them
back on the street in less than an hour.
Roland Daggett
is a dangerous man, Selina.
I'd be very careful.
Don't worry.
You won't see Selina Kyle
anywhere near Daggett Labs.
Our sources tell us that
Daggett's pharmaceuticals arm
is coming out with a hot new drug.
What kind?
Some sort of antitoxin.
All we really know is Daggett's
had his best people on it for months.
Why the sudden interest?
Think he's up to something?
That goes without saying, doesn't it?
Isis!
Oh, what have they done to you,
my precious?
Well, lookie what the cat dragged in.
Nasty wound you got there, pussycat.
You gonna lick it
and make it all better?
What have you done to these animals?
Nothing compared to what
we're gonna do to you, pussycat.
Let's skin that cat!
You two yobbos wouldn't have noticed,
but she's been bitten.
She can run from us, but not the toxin.
Isis.
Isis?
What's happening to me?
Isis.
Stay away from me.
No!
Catwoman, it's me.
Batman?
You're hot.
Now you notice.
I've got to get you to a doctor.
No. You can't.
Daggett will have me arrested.
I have a hideaway.
Not far. Please.
You know, you haven't told me
why you've come to my rescue, Batman.
Are you getting soft on criminals
or just on me?
I think the fever
is making you delusional.
Ever the escape artist, I see.
What's this?
Isis bit me.
It's not her fault.
They did something to her.
All the animals.
Must save Isis.
And we will.
Huh?
What's the delay, Milo?
You should have had these animals
on the street by now.
Uh, uh, right, Mr. Daggett.
We're waiting for Paunch.
I sent him to the warehouse
for a pack of the antitoxin
just in case there are any accidents
while transporting the animals.
Let's play a little game.
I'll try to guess Daggett's plan
and you'll let me know if I'm right.
Viral antitoxins for a plague
that doesn't exist yet.
But if the plague is introduced
via stray dogs and cats
it'll blanket Gotham City within weeks.
Days, actually.
You know how many strays
there are in Gotham, Batman?
Three hundred thousand.
Imagine if even a tenth of them
carried the virus.
Not only will this little bottle
make me a hero,
it'll make me a fortune as well.
Take care of him.
Get him!
Batman!
Thattaboy, Fido. Rip him to bits.
I can't imagine
he could elude that beast.
You'd better make sure of that,
my friend.
Because if he does get away,
I suggest you keep on driving
as far away from Gotham
as this truck can take you.
Ha! He's dog meat.
No!
He's not coming up.
Just let him show
those pointy little ears.
No one could withstand
this degree of hypothermia.
Guy's gotta be an ice cube by now.
Look out, you fool!
It's off to the pound for you.
Tonight on the news,
they called you a hero.
You keep this up, and they'll start
making Catwoman dolls.
Are you sure you'll be okay?
Go home, Maven.
And thanks.
She'll turn up. I know she will.
Isis.
Isis, you're all right.
But how?