I'm gonna check the parking lot, Billy.
Try to stay awake, huh?
Hey, it's not
past my bedtime, old man.
Whoa!
I didn't hear you come back.
Sorry, I forgot to check
Mr. Tarnower's office.
I better do that now.
What in the name of...
Looks like a slow night, Alfred.
When I finish patrolling this area,
I'm heading home.
Excellent timing, Master Bruce.
I've just taken dinner out of the oven.
Looks like trouble
at Tarnower Financial, Alfred.
I won't be home early after all.
Please don't take this
the wrong way, sir,
but your goose is cooked.
Step away from the safe. Now!
Do it, man. I'm cocked!
Mr. Tarnower?
What did you expect? Batman?
You should be downstairs guarding
the door. What do I pay you for?
Yes, sir. Sorry. I thought...
Hey, what happened to your accent?
And aren't you supposed to be in Hawaii?
Batman? Thank goodness you're here.
I caught a thief.
Hagen, I offered to help you
become human again.
The offer still stands.
I don't need your help, Batman.
Have it your way.
You used to be faster, Hagen.
Not to mention neater.
Matthew, get in.
Stella.
There, there.
It's gonna be all right, Matthew.
I'll fix everything. Don't you worry.
It'll be all right.
I'll take care of you.
I won't let anything happen to you.
It's okay now, Matthew.
Sleep, my darling.
Am I correct in
assuming metamorphic Mr. Hagen
is back in town, sir?
Back, but not for long, I'd guess.
It seems that Clayface
is losing his integrity.
I wasn't aware that he ever had any
to begin with.
I'm speaking in
a physiological sense, Alfred.
Based on destructive ultrasonic analysis
of the sample,
the molecular bonding
of his clay flesh is breaking down.
He's falling apart, literally.
How grotesque.
Tea?
Whatever medical process he's using
to keep himself together
must cost a fortune.
Which is why he's committing robberies.
And that woman helping him,
what's her stake in this?
Mmm. Perhaps she enjoys mud baths.
The surgery was a success, Eric...
I mean, Senator Chandler.
Oh, darling, how wonderful.
Let's get married right away.
Susan. Wait.
I love you, Susan.
You cured more than my body,
you cured my heart.
- Turn it off!
- Matthew?
That's not me anymore.
I'm sorry, Matthew.
I didn't think you'd be awake yet.
I don't know if I can stand this
much longer.
Trapped in this suit,
surviving on chemicals.
It's a nightmare!
Stella.
I'm sorry.
I know I owe everything to you.
You cured more than my body,
you cured my heart.
I have something to show you, Matthew.
Something new.
Now, watch.
- How did you do that?
- A new isotope.
MP-40. An experimental
mutagenic adaptogen.
I believe it can restore,
maybe even increase your powers,
perhaps permanently.
You can become
Matt Hagen again, forever.
Where can we get this stuff?
Well, that's a problem. The only
large source is Wayne Biomedical Labs.
It's rare and it will be well-protected.
Protected from human thieves, maybe,
but not from Clayface.
No, Matthew. It's too risky.
Without the suit, your structural
integrity could go at any time.
It's worth the risk.
I'm not spending the rest
of my life like this.
Anything interesting yet, Alfred?
It appears his past dealings with women
had nothing to do with medicine, sir.
No record so far of any female doctors.
Keep looking.
If we find her, we find him.
Let's cut to the chase.
The MP-40, where is it?
A monster. There's a monster in the lab!
Okay, okay. Just take it easy.
We'll handle it.
Look at that lady, Mommy.
She's got mud all over her.
Ew! Mommy, she's melting!
- What is it?
- Let me out of here.
- Oh, gross!
- Coming through.
- God, that smells.
- Oh, I'm gonna be sick!
Come on.
That's it, run.
Run for your measly lives.
Run from Clayface!
You're dead meat, Batman.
No room to dodge. I gotcha cold.
Other way around, Hagen.
There's nothing here about
any women doctors, Master Bruce.
The ladies Mr. Hagen knew
were generally of a less, uh,
intellectual class.
We're missing something.
I can't imagine what.
Closest thing Hagen had
to a relationship with a doctor
was in the film Dark Interlude.
In it, he plays Eric Chandler,
a senator who falls in love
with the plastic surgeon treating him.
That's it. His movies!
- Master Bruce?
- No time to explain now, Alfred.
There never is.
I... I can feel it.
Yes.
Yes! It's working.
No!
Batman. No, turn it back on.
I was so close.
So close!
I almost felt like Matt Hagen again.
How did you find us?
I realized you must've used a medical
consultant on some of your films.
I found Dr. Bates' name
in an old film log.
Dr. Bates had once owned a motel,
but sold it to get money for this,
I expect.
This was the address the bank had
in its files.
It's over, Hagen.
The lab boys can take it from here.
No!
Stella!
You've upstaged me
for the last time, Batman.
Time to bring down the curtain.
Time for your final bow, Batman.
Matthew, no! You can't.
It's the only way.
Please, stop it.
Think, Stella.
Do you want Matt Hagen or this?
No.
No, you don't!
Is... Is he...
Almost.
I can feel his heart slowing.
Slowing.
Huh?
Matthew, get back inside!
You're absorbing the rain! Matthew!
Matthew!
No.
We finish this now.
Save him, Batman. Please!
Come on, Hagen. Pull yourself together.
Too late.
Curtain's going...
- Down.
- Hagen!