An hour I've been waiting.
I don't know what Nico
wanted to meet here for anyway.
He didn't, Twitch.
I did.
You! You tricked me.
What do you want?
Information on the Society of Shadows.
Word is they've started operating here.
Tell me all about them.
There ain't that much to tell.
I mean, I only worked for them, okay?
Not with them.
It'll have to do. Now talk.
Okay, okay.
They're supposed to have their
claws in every dirty deal in Gotham.
In fact, word on the street is they got
something major going down tonight.
Gonna boost some kind of
new ultrasound gizmo, or something.
- Who runs the show?
- Strange dude.
Strangest thing about these guys,
come to think of it.
Goes by the code name "Vertigo."
They say he's...
Please, he made me talk. I didn't wanna.
No one betrays the Society.
No, no, please.
I didn't do it!
Such be the fate of all traitors.
You'll pay for that.
May the Shadows live forever.
Batman?
Over here, Jim.
I heard Twitch got away,
thanks to a couple of Shadow agents.
And when I tried to nail them,
they used some sort of gas
to erase their own minds.
Yeah, that fits with what little
we know about them.
But something Twitch said makes me think
they're going after Wayne Tech's
new sonic drill tonight
when it comes into Gotham.
Tell Bullock he should add more guards
just to be safe.
Is there anything you don't know about?
I only assigned that detail
a couple of hours ago.
One of these days,
I'm gonna nail his feet to the ground.
You don't want us to touch the drill.
Right, Mr. Fox?
Not unless you have to.
And be careful, it's the only working
prototype from our lab in Chicago.
And I don't wanna be the guy
who has to tell Mr. Wayne it broke
before we got it to headquarters
for the final shakedown.
But I thought you said
it could be dangerous.
Well, it's intended for use
in building excavations,
oil rigs and the like, but...
Relax, kid. That gizmo ain't gonna hurt
nobody as long as Harvey Bullock's...
What the...
- Who are you?
- What do you want?
The first thing I want is for you
to stop asking stupid questions.
The second is a powerful weapon,
and I think your drill will do nicely.
And I think you'll do 10 to 20
in Stonegate, minimum.
The Batman.
I suppose this had to happen
sooner or later.
You.
Come. We're due back
by the tolling of the hour.
But are you certain
the lady in black
was working with this Vertigo chap?
Had to be, Alfred. He'd never have been
able to escape if she hadn't shown up.
And she was the only one who wasn't
affected by his weapon.
- Weapon, sir?
- That eyepiece of his.
I think it gives off
some kind of radiation.
It must distort visual perception
and sense of balance somehow,
creating the illusion that
everything around you is topsy-turvy.
- My word.
- Not that it matters.
Nothing about that can give me any clues
to his whereabouts.
He mentioned returning to his base
before the "tolling of the hour,"
which suggests a clock tower,
or church bell. Then fled west.
Yet there's no such structure that could
conceal a hideout,
not within 50 miles to the west.
Might I suggest, Master Bruce,
that you take a break?
If you keep pushing yourself like this,
you soon won't know
- your right hand from your left.
- Alfred, you're brilliant!
Yes, so I've heard.
With my head turned around like that,
I couldn't tell one direction
from the other.
They didn't escape to the west,
they went east.
There, Alfred. That has to be the place.
Four against one. Nasty odds.
- I can take care of myself, thank you.
- So I see.
- Still, the gesture is appreciated.
- Don't mention it.
- Just whose side are you on?
- That would be telling.
And it would make no difference.
As of now, this battle is ended.
- Filthy creature.
- I've been called worse.
What happened to... My mask!
- What have you done with it?
- Easier to clean your wounds this way.
Then you know. You know that I'm...
Hush. Who knows what other ears
may be listening?
Just who are you?
What are you doing here?
My name is Talia.
And I, too, have business
with the Society of Shadows.
- What kind of business?
- Personal business.
Such as I imagine yours must be.
Point taken. It's a simple enough lock.
I can get it open it with... My belt!
How unfortunate.
I appreciate the sympathy, but what
we need right now is a lock pick.
I know.
We make a good team, don't you think?
Now, come. Quickly.
There's no telling what evil
Vertigo may do with your sonic device.
Sounds like you two have a history.
Yes. The man once worked for my father.
Until Father at last came to recognize
the blackness in his soul.
When he learned of Vertigo's intentions,
my father sent me as his emissary
to keep the device
out of Vertigo's hands.
How kind of him.
Why should your father even care?
Because he is concerned
for all humankind.
- This way. It leads to the lab.
- Lab? What lab?
Unlocked. How convenient.
You do, of course,
realize that this is a trap.
Naturally, but what other choice
do we have?
Welcome, friends.
You're quite right,
I have been expecting you.
Your little dizzifying trick
won't stop us, Vertigo.
Maybe, maybe not.
You see, you'll have to get
across this room alive.
And that may prove difficult,
considering this entire laboratory
has been rigged to destroy you.
Oh. And in case you think that once I go
my disorienting effect will go with me,
think again.
I've planted duplicate vertigo devices
throughout the room
to maintain the effect
once I've departed.
Goodbye and good luck. You'll need it.
- You okay?
- My contact lenses.
I lost them when we fell.
They counter the distortion effect.
Without them, I'm as helpless as you.
I don't do "helpless."
Come on, take my hand.
I can get us through this.
- How?
- I trusted you, now it's your turn.
Jump!
How did you know?
Down!
Stop!
Clear.
How did you do that?
Simple. I just kept my eyes closed.
You what?
The only way to neutralize
the vertigo effect
was to rely on my other senses
to see us through.
All right, I am impressed. Now where to?
Up.
- Going somewhere, Vertigo?
- No.
- It's impossible!
- Nothing is impossible.
Then I will finish you both myself.
I can't take much more of this.
Only one thing to do.
No!
Without Vertigo to lead them,
his agents have all fled?
Yes. The Society of Shadows
is no longer what it was.
Well, I've gotta get this back
to Gotham City.
Wait. I can't let you leave like this,
not with the drill.
I thought I finally knew
which side you were on.
I should have known better,
considering that you knew
where everything was in the monastery.
How could you have,
unless you were one of them?
I am truly sorry, Batman.
It could have been...
Sweet.
This is not over.
Vertigo has been dealt with, Father.
Small wonder you seem so pleased.
- Then your mission?
- A complete success.
I secured this just as you asked.
Then choose a target
and test it, daughter.
We must be certain it has survived
its ordeal intact.
The Batman, he sabotaged it somehow!
So, even in defeat,
the detective manages to achieve
some small measure of victory.
As you said, Detective,
this is not over.