Huh?
What the...
Excellent.
Hey, you. Stop!
What?
When you are ready.
Again.
Sorry,
some of us aren't perfect.
Master Bruce, I'm afraid
there's been another robbery
of a Wayne Enterprises company.
That's the sixth one
in less than two weeks.
Seventh.
Where, Alfred?
I didn't see him.
I was doing the closing report.
The next thing I knew,
I woke up with a headache.
Guard said he was dressed in black.
Same guy all right.
Good morning, Commissioner.
I wish.
He left something behind this time,
Mr. Wayne.
Deadly little thing.
Mean anything to you?
Don't touch it.
You'll break the evidence chain.
The match is over.
Kyodai is the victor.
Don't be depressed, Wayne-san.
You're not bad for a rich man's
pampered son.
There's always someone better,
Kyodai Ken.
Now apologize for your remark.
Mr. Wayne. Mr. Wayne!
Do you have any idea
why someone has been robbing
and sabotaging your businesses?
Two buildings burned down,
another blown up.
This one's computer system's wrecked.
Miss Gleeson, how do you know that?
A good reporter
has sources, Commissioner.
Any comment, Mr. Wayne?
If you'll excuse me.
Hmph.
You can't ignore the press, Mr. Wayne.
Hey, Bruce, wait up.
Listen, it will only take a minute
to get into my costume.
Not this time, Dick.
What's with him?
Bat got his tongue?
You know Master Bruce.
He's not one
to discuss his feelings.
Isn't that the truth.
Something's eating him, Alfred.
I don't know what.
Yet.
You practice as a man obsessed.
I'm not good enough, Yoru Sensei.
I lost!
Everyone loses now and again.
I have to be the best there is,
no matter what it takes!
Defeat can be more instructive
than victory.
So, the famous Batman.
I am honored.
However, my business is not with you.
Leave and you may live.
Stay and...
Listen, dipstick.
Batman's my pal.
He can be a major jerk,
but you gotta love him.
And nobody tries to fillet him
when I'm around.
Another time then.
How does he do that?
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
Come on.
There's nothing more to do here.
"Thanks for saving my bacon, Robin."
"Hey, no problemo, Batman."
I thought samurai live
by a code of honor.
That gas gun wasn't exactly
according to Hoyle.
He's not samurai.
He's ninja. They're spies and assassins.
Their only code is to get the job done.
I know him.
Say what?
He and Bruce Wayne were students
together in Japan,
a long time ago.
His name is Kyodai Ken.
He was good.
Yeah? How good?
Good.
I see.
I'm sure there is more to these crimes
against Bruce Wayne than meets the eye.
What do we know
about the Bruce, after all?
One of the richest men on the planet,
but he comes off
like the ultimate Boy Scout.
I think I'll just pop over
to the Wayne charities reception tonight
and see if I can't get some answers.
Be careful, Summer.
Wayne's got mondo clout in Gotham.
Hey, Harry,
I'm a big girl.
Alfred, do you know anything
about Bruce's training in Japan?
Of course, dear boy.
I was there. Lovely country.
I especially like the tea.
You ever hear of somebody
named Kyodai Ken?
Oh, indeed.
He was the only student
at the martial art school
who could consistently defeat
Master Bruce.
A bad egg, that one.
I think Bruce is worried
he can't take this ninja.
He won't admit it, of course.
He never admits fears, Master Dick.
Haven't you learned that by now?
Ah, Master Bruce.
I...
I'll be at the museum.
I should be back by midnight.
Do you think he heard us?
Who can tell?
Good thing
I decided to practice tonight.
Yoru Sensei would hate
to lose that blade.
It's 500 years old.
True, and worth a fortune.
I don't need it
to take care of you, Wayne.
Stop!
You have dishonored the dojo, Kyodai.
You no longer have any place here.
Go!
You will pay for this, rich man's son.
I'll take all that you hold dear,
and then I will destroy you!
Why have you been following me
all evening?
How did you... Look.
I know you don't like me much.
But I have a job to do.
It's late, Miss Gleeson.
I did some research, Mr. Wayne.
I know you spent some time in Japan.
Do you think
this ninja person is connected to that?
Have a nice trip, Mr. Wayne.
You really think
this is a good idea, Master Dick?
Bruce is hours overdue, Alfred.
It's not like him.
There's a tracker in his car.
I'll feel better once I check it out.
Godspeed, lad.
Huh?
Ah, the rich man awakens.
Remember me?
I remember you, Kyodai.
Well, you should recall the man
you ruined.
I was forced to become a thief
after I was cast out of the dojo.
As I remember it,
being a thief was what got you
thrown out in the first place.
Of course, you never had to worry
about money, Wayne.
A society parasite feeding off others.
Flabby, soft, weak.
It is too easy to defeat you.
Where am I?
I've stolen your bank codes
at each theft.
Soon I will have them all.
Then I'll transfer your money
to my own accounts.
I don't get it.
You mean you're nothing
but a common thief?
Not a common thief, woman.
A great thief. The best.
And now the game is about to end.
Ah, way to go, Dick.
Master crime fighter.
It appears we have an unexpected guest.
I'll be back.
Isn't it past
your bedtime, boy?
Let's just see who's going sleepy-by
in the next couple of minutes, huh?
This isn't the movies, boy.
Enough of this.
I have business I must attend to.
Ah!
Oh, really?
You have gone soft, Wayne.
Even a white belt could avoid
that throw.
Tired, Mr. Wayne?
I haven't even broken a sweat yet.
Get up!
Hang in there, Bruce.
Stop it! Can't you see
he's no match for you?
He never was.
I have had enough exercise
for one night.
Now it ends, Wayne.
Hey!
Yes!
Gotten a second wind, have you?
Good. This will make your defeat
all the more satisfying.
Shut up and fight.
You were right about one thing, Kyodai.
Now it ends.
So, what did you tell Summer?
That Batman arrived
and took care of the ninja.
That's true enough.
The police couldn't find any trace
of Kyodai Ken.
You think he escaped?
Ninjas are very resourceful.
Do you think he might return?
It doesn't matter.
I defeated him once.
If necessary, I can do it again.
He had you worried for a while though,
didn't he?
Thanks for your help.
It would have been harder to defeat him
with Summer watching.
Maybe even impossible.