I want a nice clean game,
gentlemen.
That'll be a first.
So I hear you-know-who
nailed the Mad Hatter last week.
No kidding?
He sure gets around, for one guy.
Yeah, well,
that's where you're wrong.
I don't think it is one guy.
Huh?
The way I figure it, Gordon's
got a bunch of them stashed someplace
like a SWAT team.
He wants you to think
it's one guy, but...
No, you're always seeing double.
It's obvious
our caped friend suffered
some crime-related trauma
when he was younger.
Perhaps an overanxious mugger
blew off a piece of his face.
Sure, he could be all gross
and disgusting under that mask.
No offense, Harv.
Just deal.
Well, you know what I think.
Not the robot theory again.
Well, he could be.
Hello, boys.
Get me an herbal tea and deal me in.
Scram, lady.
This is a private...
Why, you little...
Poison Ivy.
It's been a long time, Harvey.
You're still looking halfway decent.
- Half of me wants to strangle you.
- And what does the other half want?
To hit you with a truck.
We used to date.
Ah.
What brings such a dainty dove
to this dismal den?
Running from the law.
And the Batman, too, of course.
- Of course.
- Likewise.
- You got it.
- Same here.
You'd think one of us
would've got him by now.
I've come the closest.
Are you kidding?
I was the one who nearly...
Nobody's come closer to
snuffing the Batman than me.
- In your dreams.
- Says you.
Get out of my face.
The fact of the matter is,
we each have
an "almost got him" Batman story.
I know mine's the best,
but let's hear yours anyway.
I'd say, "Ladies first,"
but since we don't have any...
We'll start with you, Pam.
All right. This happened last Halloween.
I had rigged hundreds of pumpkins
to blow out poison-ivy gas
when they were lit.
I knew Batman would show
as soon as Gotham started scratching.
In fact, I was counting on it.
Trick or treat.
It's midnight, darling. Time to unmask.
Poison gas...
It's just the darnedest thing.
I have this natural immunity
against poisons, toxins,
the pain and suffering of others.
Go figure. Bye.
And that's how I almost got him.
With exploding pumpkins.
I'd like to hear you do better.
Oh, you will,
but I'm saving the best for last.
Can't be better than mine.
There was this time I had
just robbed the Gotham Mint
of $2 million in $2 bills.
Lucky for me,
I brought along the Two-Ton Gang.
The coin says you lose, Batman.
Tie him up.
And just so you don't get any ideas...
We'll see how tough you are
without your toys.
So, what happened next?
I thought as long as I had
Batman at my mercy,
he deserved a 50-50 chance.
Here's the deal. The coin lands
face down, you'll be squashed flat.
It lands face up, it'll just break
every bone in your body.
Hey, where's my coin?
Anybody see where I... Oh, no.
Now. Launch it now!
Here. I owe you a dollar.
And if it
weren't for this blasted coin,
I would've got him.
Gee, that's too bad, Harv.
But I guess
you'll always come in second.
Anyone else want a go?
Me!
There I was, holed up in this quarry
when Batman came nosing around.
He was getting closer, closer...
- And?
- I threw a rock at him.
So, Harvey,
what became of the giant penny?
It was a big rock.
They actually let him keep it.
- Whose deal is it?
- Mine.
I find your middling
machinations mildly diverting.
But for sheer criminal genius,
none surpasses my most recent
ornithologically-inspired entoilment.
Smaller words, please.
You're losing Croc.
For weeks, I let rumors circulate
through the underworld
of my plan to steal a pair of priceless
breeding condors from the Gotham Zoo.
Sure enough, on the appointed night,
guess who showed up.
Curses, I would grab the wrong umbrella.
Welcome,
my ebon-winged adversary.
You have taken the bait
as I knew you would.
Now, prepare to meet your end
within my aviary of doom.
Aviary of what?
Yeesh, Pengers, how corny can you get?
Just because you mundane miscreants
have no drama in your souls...
Anyway, there he was in my...
Big birdhouse.
Beautiful, aren't they?
Like glittering fragments
of the rainbow.
By the way, that mist I sprayed on you
is derived from the nectar
these birds drink.
It's quite harmless.
But their poison-tipped beaks,
however, are not.
A scratch or two
will merely slow you down.
Three or four,
and you'll start to get drowsy.
And after that, well, I wish I could say
it's been nice knowing you.
Oh, well played.
Now to take a poison antidote
from your miraculous belt.
And I suggest you do it quickly,
before my cassowary's
razor-sharp talons rend you asunder.
Naturally, I had flown the coop
by the time he escaped.
Still, I almost got him.
Not even close.
You see, the thing you're forgetting
is that there are
all sorts of ways to get someone.
Take my latest run-in with Batsy.
It was just last night,
as the entire country
was tuning into its favorite talk show.
It's Late Night Gotham Live!
And here's the man who puts a smile on
your face, whether you want it or not,
the Joker.
Good evening, folks. I'm the Joker.
Living proof that you don't have to be
crazy to host this show,
but it helps.
We've got a real treat for you, kids.
I ran into my first guest last night
while making a withdrawal from the bank.
You know him as "The Dark Knight,"
but we prefer to think of him
as history.
Here he is,
the one and only...
Batman.
We're back with my extra-special guest.
So how's Robin?
Oh. Moving right along.
You know, kids, we've got an item here
no home should be without.
The laughter-activated
electric chair.
Yes, sir, the merest titter or guffaw
starts the chair's generator revving up
towards maximum zappage.
Harley?
Ha, ha, ha.
But for a real demonstration,
we're pumping our studio audience
full of my patented laughing gas.
These yahoos will laugh at anything now,
even the phone book.
Marvin Abbott, 555-8976.
Gerald Adams, 555-9011.
M.J. Addison, 555...
Hey!
Show's over, Joker.
Catwoman, ladies and gentlemen.
Let's hear it for her.
Almost got him.
Yes, if not for that infatuated feline.
Oh, but that's the best part.
Once the chair went up,
I was out of there tout de suite.
Miss Kitty still wanted
to play cat-and-mouse,
never dreaming I still had
an ace up my sleeve.
And by golly,
speaking of aces, looky here.
- I can't believe his luck.
- Oh, darn.
Let me see those cards.
Now, now, no sore losers.
Hey, I don't get it.
You just knocked out Catwoman
and left her?
Oh, come on, Crockers,
didn't I say there's more
than one way to "get someone"?
Even as I speak,
Catwoman is being trussed up
at the Pussykins Pet Food factory.
First thing tomorrow, I'm sending
a lovely case of cat food to Batman.
I don't think so.
Was it something I said?
Well, well.
An impostor in our midst.
Risking everything
for your kitty, Batman?
You're not getting out of this one.
Maybe.
But I'm not bad with traps myself.
I had a kitty once. You know,
they don't always land on their feet.
Look on the bright side.
Tomorrow, you'll be feeding
hundreds of hungry cats.
The fun starts
as soon as Mr. J comes back.
Don't wait up.
Back off, Bats, or say "ciao"
to your girlfriend. Cat chow, that is.
That's a good little rodent.
And just to make sure
you don't follow me...
Gee, Batman, what you gonna do,
kick me around or save your kitten?
You've only got time for one.
Good call. Help.
Thanks for coming after me.
I owed you.
Well, I'd like to think our relationship
isn't just restricted to saving
each other from freaks and weirdos.
And that maybe we'd have a place
for each other without Gotham,
without the freaks.
Maybe without masks.
Maybe.
Hmm. Almost got him.