Emergency vehicle.
Pull over and let him by.
What's going on?
Get the box.
That's it.
We're out of here.
Hey, man, did I call it or what?
Only two guards. No cops for miles.
It was, like, no sweat, right?
Huh?
Whoa!
The Batman!
Huh?
Hey! Hey, I can't see!
Chubb, you okay?
No, please! Let me go!
He's history. Gotta be.
Nobody could take that fall and live.
No more fingerprints, Doc, ever? Wow!
You think you iced the Batman?
Not on your best day, Jake.
I'd cover my back if I were you.
You mean there's actually somebody
you don't think you can push around?
To what do I owe
this unexpected pleasure, Rupert?
I brought you some more equipment,
the latest in medical technology.
After all, nothing's too good
for my brother, the crime doctor.
Oh, great. A laser,
for all that critical brain surgery
I'll be doing
on my distinguished patients.
Still, after all these years,
still such contempt.
Now why would I have contempt for
the man who made me what I am today?
How would I know?
I'm the fool who keeps giving you
everything you want,
even though you act
like an ungrateful punk!
What I want is to be a real doctor,
Rupert, with a respectable practice!
Is it my fault you lost your license?
I would've reported
that bullet to the police,
as I was supposed to.
But, no, you insisted.
You knew what I'd turned into before
you took that slug out of me, Matthew.
So for that, I get to spend
the rest of my life like this?
I had much bigger plans,
and you know it, you vulgar...
Don't you ever talk to me like that!
Me, who gave up everything
so you could...
So you could...
On the table with him. Stat!
It's just the flu, that's all.
Keep him in bed a few days,
and he'll be fine.
Excuse me.
I have another patient waiting.
Well, Bruce, what is it this time?
Bruce!
Just a minor concussion.
Probably from the fall.
Here. Take one of these
every four hours.
Though why I ever bother is beyond me.
You never follow my instructions.
Your father, God rest him,
he called you stubborn
from the day you were born.
Always used to say
you had a very hard head.
He didn't know the half of it.
Come back tomorrow night.
I'll take another look.
And stay in bed the whole day.
- Understand?
- Right.
The tumor's pressing against the aorta,
restricting the flow of blood
into your heart.
Normally, these things are benign
and easily removed.
But we can't do it here.
I said, no hospital!
I got enemies who'd pay a fortune
to make sure I don't come out.
Without the operation,
you're a goner anyway.
I told you, if you don't do it here,
it won't get done!
Forget it, Rupert. I'm in over my head.
There must be somebody
you could get to help you.
No. No, they'd
never work with me, not voluntarily.
Who is he, Matthew?
I'll get him for you.
I'll send the boys.
Matt, please!
Remember what I promised you.
About your license.
Okay.
But I'll go, too.
I have to face her myself.
Her name is Thompkins.
Leslie Thompkins.
I'm sorry, the clinic is closed.
- Leslie?
- Unless this is an emergency?
Oh, but it is.
Someone's in trouble.
An old friend of yours.
Get out, or so help me,
I'll knock your brains
across the street.
Sure you will.
Now that takes me back.
Remember when I took this?
Big AMA mixer. Graduation week
at the Waldorf. Remember?
And they booked Benny Goodman.
Matt?
Matt Thorne?
I'd heard things about you, Matt.
The word was you were still practicing,
without a license.
I heard other things, too.
Looks like most of them are true.
Now, about this friend in trouble.
It's me.
Because of what a certain patient
of mine will do to me
if I don't operate on him.
But I can't do it alone, and he won't
let me check him into County.
So you want me to assist?
Forget it.
Look, there will be
a lot of money in it for you.
I know what kind of money that is.
Get out!
I'm sorry you feel that way.
No!
Leave me alone.
You can't do this.
No!
- I thought he looked familiar.
- Who, sir?
The guy who pushed me off the bridge.
He's one of Rupert Thorne's men.
Take a look. It's from the surgical mask
he was wearing.
"Rose Commercial Laundry."
One of Thorne's legitimate businesses.
Rose, Thorne. Of course.
How clever, in a prosaic sort of way.
But what would Thorne want
with a surgical laser?
It's a chance at a decent life
again, Leslie. That's why.
And you believe him?
Of course. He's got
a lot of important friends.
Judges, politicians,
the medical society.
If Rupert says he can get me
my license back...
I meant, do you believe he will?
Of course. He's my brother.
Shall we call the police, sir?
Not just yet.
"My two best friends. Love, Matt."
My word, sir.
That's your father and Dr. Thompkins.
Mmm-hmm.
Forty years ago.
But I never saw this before.
Any idea who Matt is?
Yes, I believe
your father mentioned him.
One of their colleagues
in medical school.
Very close friends
they all were.
Called themselves
"The Three Musketeers," in fact.
"Matthew Thorne?" As in Rupert Thorne?
Two medical connections
to a Thorne in 24 hours.
I doubt that's a coincidence.
It went better than I could've hoped.
I owe everything to you, Leslie.
I don't know how I can repay you.
Leslie?
Leslie!
Good work, Doc.
Me and the boys will take it from here.
With the old lady, I mean.
Thank you, Tony, but I'd rather see
Dr. Thompkins home myself.
Sorry, Doc. You don't understand.
We can't let her talk
about this place, see?
Before he went under,
Mr. Thorne said to us,
"When it's over,
make sure you shut her up."
She's gotta go, Doc.
And Mr. Thorne said
not to let you interfere.
If you do, the deal's off.
Okay, okay. But we'll do it my way.
Quickly and without pain.
I'll give her an injection.
That's not what the boss ordered.
It'll be cleaner this way.
It'll look like she had a heart attack.
Of course. That's for me, isn't it?
My payment for services rendered?
You're no better than your brother.
I'm sorry, Leslie.
I don't have any choice.
No!
Oh, no!
Don't worry. It's just a sedative.
We've got to get you out of here.
Come on. This way.
What about your brother? Your license?
Forget it.
It's not worth someone's life.
Now you're talking like a doctor.
Chubb!
Jake!
This way.
You're not going anywhere!
They're headed for the roof!
Matt!
Come on.
I can't make it.
Hurry!
Don't! Please!
I can't hold on!
I thought I told you
to take the day off.
Visitor, Thorne.
Bruce Wayne, Dr. Thorne.
Thomas Wayne's son.
- Did you get my letter?
- Yes.
Thomas Wayne.
I told you I can help you
with your legal costs,
maybe even put in
a good word with the judge.
Yes, but what do you get out of it?
Well, there is something
you can do for me.
I knew it. I knew there'd be a catch.
Sorry, Mr. Wayne.
Matthew Thorne is no longer for sale.
- I'm not looking for any illegal favors.
- What, then?
Something you know.
Something only you can give me.
Tell me about my father.