No!
You can't do this.
I've seen what you've done
to the others.
Please let me go. I'll pay anything.
You've done enough damage
with your money.
You wicked, evil...
Evil, Mrs. Thomas?
I don't control a company
that leveled a 1,000-year-old forest
for a strip mine.
That's evil.
You and your kind owe Mother Nature
a big debt,
and I'm going to see that you pay it.
I don't care
how much money we'll lose.
I won't have Wayne Enterprises involved
in an operation
that destroys a rainforest.
Shut it down or you're gone!
One of my greedy directors made a deal
with a slash-and-burn outfit
in the Amazon.
Hmm, it's fortunate
you caught it in time.
I hate it when things slip by me.
And with me helping you
to answer your mail,
nothing will.
Ah, it says here
you just won $10 million.
That's nice.
Hmm, you also received a tape from
some enterprise called Eternal Youth.
Shall I have a look?
Be my guest.
Hello, Mr. Wayne, I'm Violet.
And I'm Lily.
And we'd like to invite you...
To a free weekend at...
- The Eternal Youth Spa.
Oh, my. They even speak in unison.
Maggie.
Hello, love.
Care to join me for a morning jog?
As much as I'd love to,
Master Bruce insists I review this tape.
"Eternal Youth."
Sounds intriguing.
- Hello, Bruce.
- Good morning, Maggie.
Our founder, Dr. Daphne Demeter,
has created a medical program
- that actually reverses
- My, my, my.
The aging process.
My gracious.
Everyone's got a gimmick.
You'll enjoy a weekend
of sumptuous mineral baths,
specially prepared meals,
and invigorating nature hikes.
In two days, you'll look...
And feel...
- Years younger!
It's the perfect weekend
for the harried, stressed-out executive.
You might wanna try this, Bruce,
with your late nights and all.
My weekends are shot, Maggie.
But if you and Alfred would like
to go in my place...
Uh...
Thank you, sir,
but we couldn't possibly accept.
It's much too generous.
I thought they said it was free.
They did. Oh, Alfie,
don't be an old fogy.
A little fresh air would do us both
some good.
And you have been promising
to take me somewhere.
I'm afraid
it's quite out of the question.
I've been shanghaied.
Oh, hush.
Maggie!
May I help you?
Hello. I'm Ms. Page.
And this is Mr. Pennyworth.
We'll be filling in for Mr. Wayne.
Our target is a no-show.
What should we do?
Let them in.
Somebody's got to pay
for the sins of Wayne Enterprises.
Good morning.
I am your director, Dr. Demeter,
and I welcome you
to our wonderful program
of organic rejuvenation.
Would you put that thing down and relax?
After years of research in my lab,
I have developed this enzyme. Demetrite.
The secret of eternal youth.
Doesn't she look wonderful?
Not a day over 90.
Here you'll find demetrite in the food,
the water,
even the air you breathe at night.
What a relaxing thought.
I assure you,
the enzyme is thoroughly non-toxic
and completely biodegradable.
And once you see
those wrinkles melt away,
you'll want to saturate
every cell with it.
To eternal youth.
- To eternal youth.
Mmm. Quite refreshing, actually.
You should taste these.
Delicious.
Now, this is the kind of
wilderness experience I could enjoy.
It's a real brain-buster,
my friend.
No ransom note, no goodbye note,
no nothing.
And she's not the only
vanishing industrialist.
Three more were reported this week.
I'll search her penthouse.
Good luck.
We put that place under a microscope.
And all we got was eye strain.
Maybe your Bat radar can...
Oh, never mind.
Hello, Mrs. Thomas,
I'm Violet.
And I'm Lily.
And we'd like to invite you...
To a free weekend at...
The Eternal Youth Spa.
Yes, Master Bruce,
I did ask about that lady
as you requested.
But it seems she left by herself
two weekends ago.
Why anyone would want
to leave this place is beyond me.
Alfred, are you okay?
Never better, sir.
Everywhere I turn,
I see another sign of nature's...
Beauty.
I assure you that when I return,
I'll be feeling like a new man.
You know, Maggie, I never realized
how dreary this place actually looks.
Especially after where we've been.
Ah, well,
thanks for a splendid weekend.
Oh.
You are feeling younger,
aren't you?
What the...
Good to see you, sir.
You too, Alfred.
What's with the jungle?
Oh, I thought this drab old cave
could use a little color.
How does it look?
Green.
Yes, so lovely.
I fear all this decorating has given me
a dreadful thirst.
What's that?
Special spa water, sir,
with a drop or two
of Dr. Demeter's formula.
Wonderful stuff, this demetrite.
Ah. Excuse me, sir.
I couldn't help myself...
Alfred!
Really, sir.
It was merely a case of overexertion.
My weekend must have been
more tiring than I realized.
Well, you get some rest.
I need to check on something.
Alfie!
Maggie.
How strange to see you.
I've just been thinking about...
Going back to the spa?
How did you know?
That's all I've been thinking about
since I got home.
Computer log continuing.
The active ingredient
in the demetrite formula
is a chlorophyll-based enzyme.
Analysis indicates that it does affect
human cellular membranes.
I am now combining equal amounts
of the enzyme
to human plasma.
What the...
Alfred!
I don't know why, Doctor,
but we felt absolutely compelled
to come back.
We couldn't keep ourselves away.
Hmm.
Already your bodies have been primed
for the true value of my treatment.
The ultimate rejuvenation,
the promise of life everlasting.
I say, what is this?
Run, Maggie!
You go after the wrong people, Batman.
Poison Ivy.
Only you would identify yourself
with Demeter,
the Greek goddess of plants.
Hey, a high school graduate.
Don't even think about it.
Unusual trees.
Subtropica brasilias.
As rare as winter roses, Batman.
I tap their sap for my growth enzyme,
which you see here
in its purified, most concentrated form.
The secret of eternal youth.
But you haven't seen
my most intriguing trees.
Actually, Batman,
you and I are surprisingly alike.
We both strive
to see evil-doers punished.
But while you have your gallery
of rogues,
I have my grove.
This can't be.
This dog of a dogwood
leveled enough trees
to shade a small state.
And weep not for this willow.
She slaughtered an ancient forest
to produce cardboard.
Cardboard!
Of course, I still owe Bruce Wayne
for his involvement
with that slash-and-burn outfit.
But for now,
I'm content to settle for his friends.
Right now,
the bark is merely exoskeletal.
It will take months
of additional spraying
before the transformations
become irreversible.
But, of course,
I have the patience of a redwood.
And the convictions of a fanatic.
Well, if you're not going
to be part of the solution,
you're obviously part of the problem.
Ladies.
This spray is triple-strength, Batman.
It will start the transformation
without any preliminaries.
He should be sprouting leaves by now.
You made your secret
too accessible, Ivy.
I coated my outfit
with an herbicidal antidote.
Keep spraying!
Huh?
And I thought
you believed in justice.
Justice, yes.
But not the vengeance
of an eco-terrorist.
You're as destructive
as those you punish.
Look what you've made me do
to my poor, defenseless tree.
The enzyme!
No!
Alfie,
do you realize
that this is the second place
we've been together in as many weeks?
This relationship is branching out.
Please, Maggie.
After our encounter with Joan of Bark,
the last thing I want
to be reminded of is trees.
Hey, good news.
I just heard all of Poison Ivy's victims
are expected to recover.
Bruce, please.
The plant. Must you?
Oh.
Maybe I'd better leave this outside.
Nice man, but sometimes not too bright.