# Love #
# Connection #
# Experience #
Yeah, Morty.
# Come together #
# With love, connection,
and experience #
- It's my favorite song.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah, distress beacon!
Yeah, baby!
You're excited about that?
The first rule
of space travel, kids,
is always check out
distress beacons.
9 out of 10 times,
it's a ship full of dead aliens
and a bunch of free shit!
- Whoa!
- 1 out of 10 times, it's a deadly trap,
but I'm ready
to roll those dice.
Seems like something
terrible happened here.
Yep. Cha-ching.
Oh, yeah, if you find
a room full of eggs,
don't shy away from it.
Give one of them a shake.
Those facehuggers
are worth more than this ship.
Uh, what's that?
This'll make the cops
write it up
as a looting by the Korblocks.
That's horrible.
I hear you, man.
Cops are racist.
Oh, hey. You're alive.
Thank god.
Can you help us?
Our planet was taken over
by some kind of... entity.
It absorbed
the minds of our people.
We didn't notice
until it was too late.
The people it takes over,
they... they look
like your friends,
your family, your leaders,
but they're not
themselves anymore.
They're part of... it.
Then how do you know it didn't
get on the ship with you?
Those two dingdongs seem pretty
calm about the whole thing.
Hey, no! No, wait! Stop!
Called it.
Hello, Rick.
Long time no see.
Unity?
- Rick?
- Grandpa?
Oh, boy. Uh...
these are my grandkids,
Summer and Morty.
Summer, Morty,
this is, uh, Unity.
We sort of used to, uh... date.
Quite an operation
you got going here, Une.
You're a whole planet now, huh?
After we broke up,
I spent some time
wandering through space.
- Then I found this world...
- where I was better able
to focus on my passion
for unification.
You mean
stealing people's bodies?
Summer, rude.
Why don't you two kids
go run off and play with Unity
while Unity and I
do some catching up.
Ugh. No, wait, Rick,
aren't these people gonna barf
into our mouths and absorb us?
You're guests here on my planet.
You're free to be yourselves.
I've never been any good
at disappointing Rick.
Well, now I'm going to barf.
Come on, Morty.
Jerry, what are you...
What are you doing in here?
I'm trying to find
our weed whacker,
'cause our weeds are wack, yo.
But you can't go in the garage
when Rick's not here.
I "can't"?
- Well, he doesn't like it.
- What's he gonna do?
Crash rent-free
at his other family's house?
What is that supposed to mean?
Your dad gets to walk
all over us
because of
your abandonment issues.
He's playing you, shorty.
Oh, stop affecting
that stupid hip-hop dialect.
Stop shifting the cross hairs
to my ironic urban patois
just because your relationship
with your father
is to' up from the flo' up.
What the hell was that?
I don't know. Let's just leave.
That is a hatch.
Your father put a hatch
in my garage.
You don't know it was him.
Anyway, we're not
supposed to be in here.
Obviously, neither is whatever's
gurgling down there.
"World peace achieved." Nice.
Little weird to publish
a paper about it
for yourself, but hey.
So, what's next?
After I become
a type-one civilization,
this world will be invited
into the Galactic Federation.
Oh, goody.
From there, I'll have access to
countless planets and species.
One by one, I will unify them,
I will become the universe,
and I will be what
the single-minded
once called a god.
I like that.
Oh, that's pretty sexy.
Hey, listen, where can we get
a drink around here?
Recreational substances
were phased out here.
There's no need
for escape from the self
when your world is one.
Unity, Unity,
who am I talking to?
I watched you assimilate
a whole police station
just to get your hands on
the evidence locker.
Rick, when we met,
I was a young hive mind
with the population
of a small town.
People change...
Especially when I change them.
I'm sorry to disappoint you,
but I've grown.
Hey, listen, I've grown, too.
I have!
See, I've... I've reconnected
with my family, right?
Hm. Why's that, I wonder?
Maybe it's part of getting old.
Maybe I just missed
being with a collective.
Yes, Rick. Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yes. Yes.
Wait, wait. Stop. Hold it.
Not like this.
We need a hang glider
and a crotchless
Uncle Sam costume,
and I want the entire field
of your largest stadium
covered end to end
with naked redheads,
and I want the stands packed
with every man that remotely
resembles my father.
Man, look at them go.
So coordinated.
What's your problem?
They're making you into
a Mount Rushmore.
They made burgers!
Morty, open your eyes.
There is no "They."
These poor people's bodies
are being used.
They're a planet of puppets.
- I can hear you.
- Ugh.
Well, it seems like
everybody here's cool with it.
Except for all those redheads.
They seem like
they're in a hurry
to be somewhere else.
Balloon, Summer? Balloon, Morty?
No, we don't want
your dumb balloons, okay?
We're bored.
Take us back to Rick.
Now's not a good time.
Oh, yeah!
I want yooooooou!
Go, son, go!
Go, son, go! Go, son, go!
Oh, real nice. Real nice.
How does a man do this
without me noticing?
Oh, you know my dad
once he puts his mind
to something.
You're spinning this
to his credit?
I'm going down there.
- Jerry...
- Beth, this is my house,
which makes this my garage,
my secret hatch,
my hidden subterranean lair,
and my faceless gargler.
Now, are you gonna keep
hating this playa
or are you gonna jack my steez?
Okay, you're just
making stuff up now.
Ugh. Oh, my god.
Oh, my god.
Ugh!
Oh, Rick. That was so bad.
What's this "was" stuff?
I just need to hydrate,
Then we're doing that again.
- Oh, damn.
- Listen, if this is an invasion,
I got to sit this one out,
but I'll be back to have sex
with the survivors.
It's a neighboring
hive-mind species,
Beta Seven.
Our planets maintain
a practical alliance
for exchange of vital resources,
so be nice.
Unity,
is it a bad time?
Are all present life forms
assimilated?
Beta Seven,
this is my single-minded friend
from Earth, Rick.
Rick Sanchez.
Unity has spoken of you.
All bad, I hope. Ha ha!
Bleeeeeeeeeh!
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Beta Seven, if my allies
are a problem for you,
perhaps our alliance is,
as well.
Our alliance is beneficial.
When Beta Seven
expresses concern,
it... it's only be-because...
Oh, snap! Powdered neutronium?
Amphetetron?
You know I can make
with this stuff?
Oh, Rick, I... I shouldn't.
Come on. It's not every day
that I'm town.
It's...
It's for old time's sake.
Uh... okay, what the hell.
We can purify the resin
and make fractal dust.
Oh, I was thinking
velocitinis, but...
Aw, old man Rick can't party
with a whole planet?
I can do whatever
you do and more, baby.
You know, I think
Beta Seven over there
is hoping your alliance
can be more than practical.
Stop.
Well, this explains
the $6,000 electric bill.
Whoa!
Well, nice. Real nice.
Alien prisoners under the house.
Real nice.
Nice. Reeeeeeeeeeeeeal...
God damn it, stop.
Wake up, people!
You have to fight it!
You're under the spell
of an evil monster!
- I can hear you.
- Yeah, so you keep saying.
- Summer!
- Wake up!
You have to have some
individuality left in there!
Why do you hate me, Summer?
I'm not talking to you.
I'm talking to...
Steven Phillips.
Steven, set yourself free.
Summer, before I took
over this planet,
this man was
a registered sex offender.
Yeah? Well, so what?
At least he was himself.
This woman was a drug addict
on the verge of suicide.
Now she's a marine biologist.
Listen, Unity, I don't think
my sister's trying to say
that life would be perfect
without you.
I think she's just saying
that life would be,
you know, life.
I have transformed life
here into a paradise.
Prostitutes are now scientists.
The homeless
are now "Phisosophers."
Oh. Oh. "Ph-phisosophers"? Nice.
- Philopol... Phiphophopher...
- Oh, my god.
Where did you learn to talk,
you grandpa-stealing slut?
I'm feeling...
Ugh.
Oh, man, let me help
all of you guys up.
I'm fine.
Do you know
what I love about you, Rick?
You're the only single mind
I've met
that really sees
the big picture.
You got that right.
But, baby, listen...
Y-you're talking about taking
over planets and galaxies.
You got to...
Got to just remember
to let go sometimes, you know?
I can let go. Hey, look.
You see that town
across the river?
Watch this.
- Whoa!
- Ha ha! Whoo!
Whoa! That's not what I meant!
It's okay. It's okay.
I evacuated.
I evacuated the town. Look.
Hey! We're right here. We're fine.
Oh, that was awesome.
My... my grandkids
weren't in that town, right?
A-are my grandkids alive?
M-my drink is empty.
- Unity, what's happening?
- Who's Unity?
You kids have nice feet.
Mind if I take a picture?
Gross. No.
I think you're getting
what you wanted, Summer.
Something's happening to Unity.
Do all of you remember
who you are?
Yeah, uh, my name is Ron Benson.
I'm an electrical engineer,
father of two,
and, as you can see from my
flat, concentric nipple rings,
I'm a member of
this planet's top race!
Okay, that's good.
Uh, don't focus too much
on the last part, but...
I'm Daryl Jefferson.
I'm a landscaper.
And I'll be damned if
that ripple-nipple bitch's
race is superior!
The cone-nipple people
will rule this world!
You shut your mouth,
you dirty knife-nipple bastards.
What'd you say to me,
you target-chest piece of shit.
Race war!
Ugh!
Why are you fighting?!
Can't you see
you're all the same?
Oh, Summer.
First race war, huh?
Way to go, Summer.
You started a race war.
I didn't start it!
They're the racists.
I... I merely empowered them
to follow their apparently
misguided dreams.
Okay, thanks for clarifying.
I'll have a super-accurate
headstone now.
Hey, wait...
What race are you guys?
We're neither. S-see?
Yeah, take my word for it.
We just have regular nipples.
Hey, these two freaks
have no race!
Oh, there's no place like home.
There's no place like home.
Remember, Summer?
From Dorothy
and the tiny people movie?
Yes, yes.
- All the tiny people.
- Dorothy, take us away.
Hello, Summer. Hello, Morty.
- It's okay. You're safe now.
- Unity?
- Yes.
- Oh, Unity, I am so sorry.
I didn't know freedom meant
people doing stuff that sucks.
I was thinking more of
a choose your own
cellphone-carrier thing.
Oh, Summer,
you did nothing wrong.
I'm having fun
with your grandpa.
Lost a little control.
Probably shouldn't be
piloting a hovercopter,
nor should I be running
200,000 pediatric hospitals
and 12 million deep fryers,
but hey,
it's not like this planet
can take its business elsewhere.
Um, should we maybe
stop somewhere
and get you a coffee?
Maybe splash a little water
on your face, or...
No, no, if I wanted to be sober,
I wouldn't have gotten drunk.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh, man. I cannot wait...
I cannot wait to hear Rick
explain his way around this.
He is gone.
Jerry, stop, please, okay?
We weren't even
supposed to be down here.
If we confront him about this...
Oh, my god! I love this.
I love that this is
how far you will go for him.
You want to go upstairs
and cut carrots
and watch a Lifetime original
above a fucking alien dungeon!
Your relationship with
your father is psychotic.
Oh, listen to you
relish the idea
that my genius father
is a bad person.
Step out of your ego
for a second
and look at this thing...
It's a monster.
He might have it chained up
so that it doesn't
eat the planet!
Right, because your father's
such an altruist?
I once saw him briefly
forget the word for "Humans."
He's probably harvesting
this creature's organs.
He's probably racing
to cure its space AIDS.
- He's going to eat it!
- He's protecting it!
Shut up!
Whoa!
Unity, this place is a mess.
Oh, it's cool.
The part of me
that's the cleaning lady
is coming on Friday.
Oh, my god. I have a meeting
at the Galactic Federation
in an hour.
Oh, I'll never make it.
Ah, I'll push it to next week.
Unity, could you get Rick
out here, please?
He's unavailable. He's...
having sex with you.
We get it. Gross.
Get him out here now.
I don't think he wants to be...
- Grandpa Rick!
- Rick! Rick!
I'm gonna tell mom and dad
about the gagoo
you have locked up
under the garage!
What the hell is your problem?
Grandpa,
we need to go home, now.
Fine. Sheesh.
See you.
Uh, Rick,
I think we should all go.
Tend to your garden, kids.
I'm kind of doing a thing here.
Whoo!
Grandpa Rick,
we're not leaving without you.
Oh, my god, you guys. I get it.
You're afraid
the big, bad hive mind
is gonna steal
your grandpa away.
Actually, no.
I think Unity's great
and you're
a horrible influence on it.
- What?
- This isn't healthy, Rick.
You know, you're...
You're really up to no good
around here a-at
this place, you know?
You and Unity are like...
Like leggings
and mid-calf boots.
You think you're great together,
but you're just bringing out
the worst in each other.
Oh, gee. Boy, Summer. Well put.
Uh, why don't we see
what Unity thinks?
Unity?
I'm just taking
a little break from stuff.
You know? I need to relax.
Oh, hey, w-what's this
on the news, guys?
L-l-let me turn it up.
In the news today,
this looks
a lot worse than it is.
We're really just
having a good time.
Karen? Thanks, Todd.
Up next, are you
a concerned grandchild
or just a buzzkill?
We'll tell you
how you can know for sure.
I think you two
are a little outnumbered.
Okay, well, what if
you did it for me?
What if you came with us
as a favor to us
because you love us?
What? Dumb. Bye.
But Rick, Summer's just...
Summer's just a hyper-emotional,
needy little...
What's the word
I'm looking for here?
Uh... human.
It runs in the family.
I can tolerate it,
but I can't
give a crap about it.
Take a hike.
Take care of yourself, Unity.
I'm not looking for judgment,
just a yes or no...
Can you assimilate a giraffe?
You're the worst!
No, you're the worst!
You don't support this family!
All you care about is yourself!
You think supporting the family
is about supporting you emotionally...
you've got two children
being dragged across the cosmos
because it's never
enough, Jerry!
By your dangerously ill father!
And you force me to
watch it happen...
because you'd rather
lose them and lose me...
it's like to be afraid
of losing anything...
- than lose him!
- Because you cling...
And why? Because
you're the child, Beth!
You, not me! You!
- Aah!
- Oh, my god.
Um, first of all, hello.
Uh, my name is
Blim Blam the Korblok.
Second of all,
cards on the table,
I'm a murderer that eats babies,
and I came to this planet
to eat babies.
However, I am also carrying
a highly infectious disease
that I suppose you could call
"Space AIDS" as you put it.
And Rick did chain me up
so that he could
attempt to cure it.
At the same time,
Rick's motivation
to cure my disease
was not to save my life
or anyone else's,
but to patent and sell the cure
for billions of blemflarcks.
But you know the reason why
I ripped my chains
out of the wall?
And do you know why I'm never
coming back to this planet?
Because the two of you
are the fucking worst!
You both hate yourselves
and each other.
And the idea that it has
anything to do with Rick
is laughable.
I'd laugh,
but I'm biologically incapable.
That's how alien I am.
And even I'm sitting here
listening to the two of you
and being like, "What the fuck"!
So good luck
with your shitty marriage,
and tell Rick I'm sorry he has
to deal with either of you.
Blim Blam out.
You know what? I'm taking this.
How do you... what is this?
Uh, is there a slow setting?
Best door ever.
Okay, okay. Now make them cry,
but happy crying.
Now make them all
make fun of the blonde one.
do it on the table.
I can't believe you created
a whole show for me.
Now cancel it.
Okay, now put it back on.
All right, I'm bored.
Rick, is there a way for you
to call Summer and Morty?
- I feel bad that they...
- Pbht. Screw those guys.
Ugh. I'll be right back.
Don't waste your brain
on those weirdos, Unity.
They're no different
from any of the aimless
chumps that you occupy.
They just put you at
the center of their lives
because you're powerful.
And then because
they put you there,
they want you
to be less powerful.
Never gonna happen
though, right?
Never.
Never. Back in a flash.
Best weekend ever, Rick.
I agree, Rick.
Let's see how long we can go.
Hey, Une. You got any more...
Rick, forgive me for doing this in notes.
I'm not strong enough
to do it in persons.
I realize now that I'm attracted to you
for the same reason
I can't be with you.
You can't change.
And I have no problem with that,
but it clearly means
I have a problem with myself.
I'm sure there's no
perfect version of me.
I'm sure I'll just unify
species after species
and never really be complete.
But I know how it goes with us.
I lose who I am
and become part of you.
Because in a strange way,
you're better at what I do
without even trying.
Yours, and nobody else's, Unity.
P.S., I don't know where
those coal miners were
before they were assimilated.
You might want to get checked.
Man:
Hey.
Dad.
I, um... Jerry and I
were looking for
our weed whacker
and found your subterranean lair
and your alien prisoner,
and he got away.
And I know I sound like mom,
but I can't sacrifice
this whole family's safety
just because I'm afraid
you'll leave again,
so no more alien prisoners
and no more
subterranean excavation
without consulting us.
- Okay.
- Okay?
"Okay"... like you're gonna
quietly teleport somewhere
and never come back?
No. It's your house.
Grandpa Rick,
what happened with Unity?
Who? Oh, Unity. Yeah, well...
I mean, honestly,
we're talking about an entity
that thrives on
enslavement, you know?
It's not cool. Fun's fun,
but who needs it?
I'll be in the garage.
# Lay it, lay it down #
# Let me see your hand #
# Show me what you got #
# You're always talking #
# But you're not playing #
# It doesn't match your face #
# Get them away,
away from this place #
# Can you take me now? #
# I, I want it #
# I want it real #
# Are you afraid of me now? #
# Do you feel it? #
# Do you feel
that I can see your soul? #
# Do you feel it? #
# Do you feel the pain
in your heart? #
# I, I want it #
# I want it real #
# Run away with me now #
# I, I want it #
# I want it real #
# Run away with me now #
# Ah, ah #
# Don't leave me #
# Never leave me out #
Unity! Unity!
Unity!
How can I assist you?
I want to talk to
Unity, Beta Seven.
I know it's in there.
You're classified
as a hostile entity,
and Unity
doesn't want to talk to you.
I know your game, Beta Seven.
I've met a billion of you,
you little on-deck,
in-the-wings shoulder to cry on!
You are classified
as a hostile entity.
Oh, you're just loving this, mother...
This isn't gonna
shake out like you think, pal.
Unity's not into other
hive minds.
It's gonna suck you in
and use you up,
and a month from now,
I'm gonna be making out
with all of you
in a bunch of red wigs!
Unity! Unity!
Unity, I know you can hear me.
Get out here.
Weapons systems engaged.
Oh, in your dreams
you have weapon systems.
Ugh, Rick, you said
we were going to a movie.
We are, Morty.
All right, Beta shit Seven,
you just got
saved by the bell, bitch!
Did you get any of that?
It's-a good show-a.