First time I saw this film,
was in the middle of the war.
I remember half-way through it there was
an air raid and we all had to run for the shelter.
I bet you all hated the Kaiser
that night eh?
What's the matter with you you
moaning little git??
What's the matter with...
I'll tell ya!
Grandad, it is Christmas night
and I am stuck in here with...
I am stuck in - here, watching
a film that the Germans tried to bomb!
I know what you mean Rodney, I
feel exactly the same.
I thought you liked this film.
I do! I mean it's it's Christmas night
and I'm stuck in with you!
Thank you very much.
Well stop yer whining! I
don't know why you didn't go out with Del.
He's seeing Lassie again ain't he?
You don't wanna let Del hear
you refer to her as a dog!
Well he must know!
When she come back from Tenerife it
took him two weeks to get her out of quarantine!
Was that the bell Rodney?
It sounded very much like it
Grandfather!
There it goes again! Whatever
could it mean?
It means there's someone at
the door you lazy little toe-rag!
Go on Rodney, it might
be Del popped back for something.
I suppose you've run out of
Bob Martins again!
- Yeah?
- Oh, good evening sir.
I'm sorry to bother you but I
wonder if you could help me?
Yeah, hang on.
No, I don't mean like that!
I'm looking for a family called the Trotters.
The Trotters?? What makes you
think the Trotters live here?
It's written on your bell.
Who is it? Ro...Reggie??
Hello old 'un, how you diddling?
- It's really you!
- It's me alright! Long time, eh?
Too long Reg, too long!
Oh it's good to see you, it
really is!
You two have met before have you?
I'm sorry, let me introduce
you. Reg, this is Rodney.
Rodney, I'd like you to meet
your Dad.
Right - where is he?
Will you just calm down a bit!
Before you go in there shouting and bawling,
just you remember, he's still our father.
Well you and me could be spending the night in the
orphanage by the time I've finished!
He's not the man you
remember, I promise.
I know you've told me how he used to be a right
Jack the lad, all flashy shirts and gold cuff-links,
a bit like...a bit like some of
the lads down the pub! But he's old now Del.
He's disheveled, he's pathetic, he
seems sort of, frightened!
Just bear it in mind will
you, please!
Alright, Rodney, alright.
Del Boy! Good to see you son.
Pour yourself a drink.
I used to have a shirt like that.
Yer Dad had a bath and a shave
Del, then he found he was low on clothes!
He's gonna get bit low on teeth before
he's much older!
Get yer things,
sling yer hook!
Alright, if you wanna talk it
over I'm listening!
He only wants to stay for one
night Del!
When he closed that front door
in 1965 he closed it for good!
Have I got any say in this?
Let's hear what Rodney's got
to say.
What's to be said Rodders? You
know what he's like!
No I don't!
Of course you do, I've told
you often enough!
Yeah and that's all I know! I wouldn't mind
the opportunity of judging him for myself.
I never raised a hand to your
Mother Rodney except in self-defense!
What do you mean 'judging
him'?
He deserted you when you
were five years old!
And not only that. He walked out on his
own Father!
But he's back now!
After eighteen years! Did his watch stop?
Stone me Rodders, we see more of
Hayley's Comet that we do with him!
Just go will yer?
Look, whatever you may think of
him Del, he's still my son.
He only wants a bed for the
night!
I don't believe it! Can't
you see what he's doing?
He's playing on your sympathy,
he's playing on your loyalty!
That man is evil! That is the devil
standing there!
Don't be so stupid Del!
That's your own Father!
Yeah, but he sold his soul for
an ounce of Old Holborn years ago!
Give me one good reason, just
one,
why I shouldn't chuck
you out by the scruff of the neck?
I can't think of one Del. I'm
not proud of what I did.
I'm ashamed - ashamed and
sorry!
Just recently I've been
laying in that hospital bed,
night after night, re-living
the moment I walked out of here!
It hurts Del Boy, it
hurts!
Hospital bed? What's wrong
with you Reggie?
Something serious I hope!
Just wrap up for five
minutes, would ya!
Don't be fooled by him Rodney.
He's had everything from
Galloping Lurgy to Saturday Night Fever!
Once when I was a kid I was doing my homework
and I asked him what a cubic foot was.
He said he didn't know but he tried to
have a week off work with it!
What's wrong with you Reggie?
Come on, you and tell me and Rodney.
Well, a few months back they took me
into hospital, just for a few routine checks.
Jackanory Jackanory.
I'm telling you the truth this
time Del, look!
Newcastle Infirmary?
I've been living up there for
the last year or so.
What's the matter with you then?
They discovered I had
this em, hereditary blood disease.
It's called...well
it's a medical word!
A long one Reggie?
Ooh yeah Dad!
Can they cure it?
They're not sure! I just live
in hope. Hope's about the only thing I've got!
Oh come on... Dad! These
doctors can perform miracles nowadays.
You just gotta be brave?
Just be...Hereditary??
You said it was hereditary! That
means I could have it.
And me!!
Yes. Well this is half the
reason I dashed down here!
The doctor said I had to warn my
children immediately!
What have they got to do? Go
for blood tests?
As soon as possible! I've done
me best by you this time ain't I Del Boy?
Yeah. Thanks!
I'm feeling a bit weak. I
think I'll climb in. 'Night boys.
- 'Night!
- And Merry Christmas.
Will I have to have
blood tests as well?
No, it's hereditary, it means
it's passed on not back!
You're most probably the
carrier!
What a right blinding
Christmas this has turned out to be!
Some people get wise men bearing gifts –
we get a wally with a disease!
You two better get down to that hospital
straight away after the holidays.
Yeah, but with these National
Health cuts we could wait for ever!
I'll give Dr
Becker a ring first thing in the morning.
He's not gonna see us on
Boxing Day!
Oh yes he will! He owes me a
favour.
His ten-year-old son thinks the bike that
he got for Christmas came off the back of a sleigh.
Mister Becker and I know better! Just a minute,
where's he sleeping?
I offered him my bed.
You're a great big softy
ain't yer!
Well, he's not very well and
all.
You'd have done exactly
the same thing wouldn't you?
Yeah, of course I would!
Good, 'cos he turned my bed
down and chose yours! Nite!
Where's the ghost of Christmas
past?
He ain't here Del.
You mean he's gone?
Only down the pub for the New
Year's Eve do.
Oh, I thought it was too good
to be true.
You talk about your father
as if he is an alien.
You seem to think of him as ET.
No I don't Grandad, ET went
home!
A couple of letters arrived
for you two.
I think it's the results of your
tests!
Oi, these have been opened!
Your Dad must have done that.
Well the saucy git...
You can't blame him Del! I
suppose he was too worried to wait for you!
Yeah, well alright then! Well
go on then Rodney, see what yours says.
All clear! All clear! I got an
all clear my son!
Well don't
look too cheerful about it Del!
I haven't seen mine yet have I?
Oh no, sorry!
What - what's it say Del?
The results of my tests
...are negative!
Negative?
Well that means all clear  as well you
plonker!
Does it??
I thought it was a medical
term for curtains!
Why don't they bloody
say all clear then?
Oh who cares? We'll
have a drink to celebrate?
Yeah I need something Rodders!
Right, I'll go'n get changed.
That's funny!
Your blood group's AB -
Rodney's is just A.
We both have the same blood,
don't we?
That's what I thought!
Giss 'em here!
My blood group is AB...
and Rodney's blood group is A!
Well, how's did that wally
manage to get himself a different blood group?
We're brothers aren't we?
We both have the same blood!
We both had the same mother,
and we both got the same fath...er!!
Are you suggesting Rodney's
got a different dad?
I'm saying nothing! But I
always remember Maisie Turner!
Maisie Turner! Who the hell's
Maisie Turner?
She married Bernie. Remember
Bernie?
Used to pull the stall
out down the market.
Yes I remember! What about 'em?
Well she had two boys.
One by Bernie, the other by some
bloke she met on a charabanc trip to the lights!
Bernie
found out and divorced her.
How did he find out? Blood
tests?
No, the youngest boy was half-
caste!
Now I ain't saying anything against yer Mum,
Gawd rest her soul.
But if you put
two and two together...
You come up with Rodney!
You remember just before your
Mum announced Rodney was on his way,
she and yer Dad were
having lots of rows.
She started going out with...new
friends.
You mean that trumpet player
from the Locarno?
I thought he played the saxophone!
No that was the other one!
I can see it all now, it's beginning to
make sense!
Don't you remember when Rodney joined the Boys'
Brigade? He was a natural with that bugle?
And when toy look at him Del.
I mean, he's sort of...
...different!
Why did this have
to happen eh? This of all things!
Alright?
- Yes, wonderful Rodney!
- Couldn't be better Rodney!
What's wrong?
No, no! Everything's
brill!
Good! I wonder where Dad is?
That's exactly what me and your
Grandfather were wondering...
I mean there's no telling which pub
he'll be in now, is it?
What?
Just admiring the suit. Great,
I love it, it is a new one is it?
No, I bought it five years
ago, it weren't new then!
Come on, something's up, innit?
Are you gonna tell me?
Oh I suppose you've got a
right to know Rodney!
I want you to know that
it won't make a blind bit of difference!
Everything will still stay exactly the same!
See the thing is, Rodney,
that man you call Dad - ain't!
- Ain't what?
- He ain't yer Dad!
- What is it, a joke?
- No, I wish it was Rodney!
I don't get you. Of course
he's my Dad!
But he must be, Grandad introduced us!
Say no more about it,
leave it at that!
No I will not leave it at
that!
You are trying to say
that that man is not our father?
No he just isn't yours! You've
got a different blood group Rodney, look!
So I've got a different blood
group, what does that prove?
It proves you're a whodunnit.
That's not the only thing.
You see, just before Mum fell for you,
she'd met this, like new 'friend'!
He was a trumpet player from the
Locarno!
And a saxophone player!
Yes, alright Grandad, alright.
What are you trying to tell
me. My Dad was a band?
No Rodney, no! Just the brass
section!
No I don't believe ya!
The way you've always
described Mum she'd never do anything like that!
She wouldn't normally! This
must have been just a one off.
Great! I can't wait to fill in
my next passport application form.
Mother's name: Joan
Mavis Trotter.
Father's name:
Herb Alpert and the Tijuana Brass!
Been for a drink Reggie?
Yeah I've bin for a drink Dad.
I've got damn good reason to ain I?
What are you moaning about
now?
I can read Del Boy!
Earlier this morning I happen to
notice them medical reports!
I thought that's funny, different blood groups!
So just to be on the safe side I checked
my group with me donor's card,
then I checked yer Grandad's
group with his old army records.
And what do I discover? We've got a Lone
Ranger in the family!
I'd just like to know ho the
hell Tonto was!
If your Mother
was alive now I'd kill her!
You what??...
Try'n see it from my point of
view Del!
How would you like
to have a son who you love and care for,
who you fetch up as yer own,
only to find years later that he's a mystery?
Waht do you mean you loved and cared for him?
You walked out on Rodney
when he was five years old!
You didn't care if he had
shoes on his feet or food in his belly!
What do you keep bringing
Rodney into this for? You're the mystery!
AB. Why?
You alright Del?
Eh? Yeah, I'm alright darling.
I thought you'd have been in
last night or the New Year's Eve do!
The rest of the family
was here.
Were they? No, I er, I got a
bit involved elsewhere.
Your Dad's a giggle ain't he?
Yes Karen, that man is one
long grin!
He got up on the stage and
started singing Adam Faith songs.
You're kidding?
After all these years he's still doing
the Adam Faith impression?
He was good!
He sang 'What do you want if you don't want
money?' and, what was the other one?
'Someone
Else's Baby'.
Do you want another one?
Grand Marnier and grapefruit juice please.
- Oh leave it out Dad!
- It's true I'm telling you!
He still didn't know it
was you?
He didn't have a clue. I saw
him years later and he still had the scar!
- Alright Del?
- Yeah triffic Rodders.
Why didn't you come down last
night for the New Year's Eve party?
I had a bit of business to
attend to, you know what I mean...
Can I get you a drink?
That's nice of you, but I'm
with my family.
Perhaps I can get yer family a
drink as well!
Karen, give those people  a large
brandy each, will yer.
Anyway let me finish the story.
Well I'm gonna have a chat
with Del.
Oh! Alright Rodney - don't be
long, eh!
You didn't come home last
night?
No, er, I stayed the night at
Trigger's place.
I'm fed up
with kipping on that settee.
Is that the only reason?
Yeah of course it is the only
reason!
You seem to be seing a lot
of the ond man lately.
Yeah. I think he's trying to
make up for all the lost years.
You been out this morning?
Yeah. He took me to the zoo.
Oh yeah...alright was it?
Yeah, you know, animals and...
things!
Good! Listen, I don't want to
spoil the surprise,
but I saw him up Selfridges on Friday
looking at the Action Men!
Why don't you just
come back home, eh Del?
I'm not with him now. He won't let me
forget that I'm a - a Lone Ranger!
Del he hasn't mentioned it,
honest!
Maybe not to you,
but every time I see him on the
landing he always shouts hi ho silver!
D'you know, at school once,
during the biology lesson
the subject of genetics came up,
and the teacher said that children
with same parents can have different blood groups!
That's alright Rodney - you're trying
to cheer me up. You're a diamond, you really are!
No, I mean it.
Why don't you get some advice on the
subject. Go and see Dr Becker.
- I couldn't Rodney!
- Why not?
Because then he'd know everything, wouldn't he?
He's the family doctor.
He treated Mum when she
was ill.
I don't want him thinking 'that' of her!
No, I mean it's clear cut, Rodney,
I am as the French say
oeuf sur le plat.
The family is A, and I'm AB!
So what does that matter? That's nothing, is it?
You're only one letter out.
Look, the only
difference between us is a B.
And we all know what B stands
for, don't we?
Rodney! You gonna play cards
with us?
Yeah, in a minute! You wanna
game?
No not me Rodney. He'll always find a way
winding me up!
No he won't Del!
Look, if you just sit over here on your own
he's gonna think he's beaten you!
C'mon. He who dares wins!
Yeah, OK, come on.
Take a seat Rodney...oh, does
your friend want to play as well?
Now just lay off him
Reg!
Don't you say nothing to annoy me!
Oh as if I would! He's touchy
ain't he?
Don't know who he gets it from. Right, what
shall we play?
Before you say it, no, we don't
wanna play Happy Families!
Alright. We'll play Pontoon...
Dad, Rodney,
Kimasabi.
You got any money Rodney?
I gave you my last fiver this
morning.
Dad?
You know I'm skint!
Well why didn't you nip Del
for a few quid?
I can't ask Del for money
after what's happened!
No I don't suppose you can!
Rodney could!
Alright Grandad, Rodders.
Evening Reginald! Grandad do me a favour.
Stick me a pizza under the grill.
You in for the night Del?
Yes I'm in for the night!
Good!
We can all have a family sing-
song together this evening.
You can join in if you like!
What's up with you?
Well, earlier on I showed him
my GCE certificates.
He said he was proud of me!
Then he went and wrote a bet on the
back of one of 'em!
He wrote a bet on the back of one of your GCE's?
That man is the devil Rodney!
I'm beginning to think you're
right!
I know one thing, you were
Was I?
Oh yes. I took your advice.
Good! What advice was that then?
I'll tell you in a minute!
Well there were four in there
earlier!
Yeah, and you drunk 'em all!
You don't fancy popping down the off-licence
and get a few drinks in do you Del?
No!
No I'm off the drink for the
moment. I went and saw Dr Becker this evening.
Yeah? Why what's wrong with
you Del?
Well, for the last week or so
I've been suffering from this pain in the arse!
So I asked doctor Becker if he'd give me another
blood test, you know
just in sort of, double check it.
But he said there was no need to, because,
you were absolutely right Rodney,
a person's blood group doesn't
make a blind bit difference.
A mother and father could have three
children,
and each one of those kids
could have a completely different blood group!
That's rubbish! I mean what
does he know anyway?
Oh he knows quite a lot! Like he
knows that my blood group is group A!
Well why's he written AB on
the results?
He didn't Grandad! Somebody added
the B!
Now I wonder who could have
done that??
Well it must have been someone
at the clinic having a joke!
I mean the letters arrived by
post. The envelopes were sealed!
Until you opened 'em!
I was only trying to make sure
that you two didn't have the same...
...illness as me!
Oh yeah, Dr Becker was very
interested in your 'blood disorder'.
So he phoned up Newcastle Infirmary to
find out exactly what was wrong with it.
- And what do you reckon?
- They'd never heard of him!
- Now how'd you know that Rodney?
- I must be clairvoyant Del!
You see, they ran your name through
their computer
They found they didn't
have a patient called Trotter.
But, they did have a porter called
Trotter!
But he left two weeks ago with 57 blankets,
133 pair of rubber gloves
and the chief gynaecologist's Lambretta!
I don't feel all that well!
I mentioned that to Dr Becker, and you know
what he suggested: Plenty of fresh air
new surroundings and lots of
exercise - like take a long...brisk...walk!
Did he? Yeah maybe he's right.
Is that the time? I really
must be on my way!
So soon?
Don't wanna outstay me welcome
Del! I'll...I'll get my things together.
The dirty, conniving little...!
Alright Grandad, alright. Listen, I'll tell you what.
I hid a bottle of scotch underneath the sink.
Good boy Del.
I'm glad he's gone! Made it
a right miserable Christmas for all of us.
It'a alright Rodney. All over now.
Don't worry. We'll all soone be back
to just the way we were.
Del Boy, I've burnt yer pizza!
See what I mean!
Subtitles by NVL