Yeah, well, you try and have a nice kip, eh?
His legs are still playing him up.
Well, I told him not to run
in the London Marathon?
Anyway, he's not coming to the
tenants' meeting with us.
You're still coming ain't yer?
Eh? No way bruv, I'm going out with that
little waitress that I blagged from the Pizza Palace.
Eh? How did you manage to pull her?
Well, I read somewhere that woman were turned
on by men in situations of power.
So I told her I was a Euro Minister.
And she believed you?
Oh yeah.
She must be thicker than them
pizzas she dishes out.
Oi, don't get sardonic.
Here what's all this about anyway?
I'm writing out a list of
questions I want to ask at the meeting.
Oh yeah, like why the lifts
are still out of action in our block?
- No, more important things than that, Del.
- Oh yeah.
I mean, in the last year or so we've had
a crime explosion on this estate, yeah,
and yet the police don't come near or by.
And I want to know the reason.
Well, they can't get on the estate, can they?
The natives won't let 'em.
Come on, that is rubbish.
No, no, it ain't.
Look, last month a copper came round just to return
a lost dog and we had three nights of rioting.
Look, I don't care what their excuses are,
I'm gonna demand more police patrols on this estate.
Not too many Rodney.
Come here, I'm writing out this catalogue of crime,
see what the Chairman's got to say about that.
Catalogue, let's see. Some catalogue innit - look.
'May the sixth. Grandad's shopping trolley
stolen from the pram sheds.'
Yeah, well that's the only one
I can think of.
Gordon Bennett. There are 2,000 stories in the Naked City
and this plonker is looking for a basket on wheels.
Look, I've heard of other crimes, but I don't know
the times and the dates and what 'ave yer.
I've got to provide
details, not rumours.
Well, why don't you tell them
what happened to poor Rita Alldridge then?
Yes, good idea.
What happened to Rita Alldridge then?
Last Friday night she was indecently assaulted
over by the adventure playground.
No, did she report it?
Yeah, I saw her this morning,
she'd just been down the police station.
Right, there you are you see,
that's exactly the sort of thing...
Hang on a minute - if this happened on Friday night,
how come it's taken her till Wednesday to report it?
Because she didn't know she'd been indecently assaulted
until this morning when the bloke's cheque bounced.
- How you going Dave?
- Oh. Alright Trigger.
- No Del Boy?
- No, he's out.
How's your grandad, I heard
his legs were playing him up!
Yeah, well, it's most probably
a touch of fibrositis, you know.
Yeah, more than like...that's how my nan
started off. Did you ever meet my nan?
Well, only at her funeral!
That's right, you were at her
funeral weren't you Dave?
Trigger - why d'you call me Dave?
My name's not Dave - my name's Rodney.
- I thought it was Dave!
- No, it's Rodney.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm positive. I've looked it up on me
birth certificate and passport and everything!
It is definitely Rodney!
Oh well, you live 'n' learn -
so what's Dave, a nickname like?
No. You're the only one who calls me Dave.
Everybody else calls me Rodney,
and the reason they call me Rodney
is because Rodney is my name.
Oh well, I shall have to get
used to calling you Rodney!
Thank you.
Here Basil. You gonna get this meeting started??
Me and Dave ain't got all night!
- Rodney.
- Oh yeah.
I can't start the meeting until the Vice Chairman's
in attendance. It's in our constitution!
Well how long's he gonna be?
Could be a hell of a long time
son - he died a fortnight ago!
Died? Well, what was the point
in calling the meeting?
I was hoping - if we'd had a bigger turn-out –
to elect a new Vice Chairman from the floor.
You need a new Vice Chairman?
Well, if it'll help you out any Baz, I nominate Rodney!
- What?
- Right, seconded!
- Now hang on a minute!
- All those in favour?
Against?
Nomination accepted. Welcome aboard, son!
But I didn't wanna be Vice Chairman!
I thought you was interested in
all that political malarky?
Well, yeah, I am, but I don't
want this job!
Oh well, I suppose Del Boy was
right all along.
What d'you mean?
Well, he always said you were
too immature to accept responsibility.
Oh did he? Well, we'll have to see about that then,
won't we? Where do I sit Baz?
Eh - oh, next to me, son -
right then, I declare this meeting open.
Now, the first item
on the agenda is my resignation!
You're the new Chairman, congratulations son.
You going down there, Trigger?
Yeah, I'll have a quick one with you Baz.
Oi, what about the meeting?
Well, you'll have to close it won't you?
You ain't got a Vice Chairman!
Oh yeah - well, um, meeting closed!
He done that well didn't he?
Oranges, they're lovely, three for 25p. See?
Suck one of these a day, you'll never catch scurvy.
There you go, three darlin.
God bless you, luv. Look after yourself.
Come on girls - the finest Spanish oranges,
just in from Seville!
They're fresh then?
Fresh? Fresh? They were playing
castanets this morning my love.
- There you go...take that one for luck..
- Thank you very much.
God bless you my luv. Don't
swallow the pips will you?!
Where the ruddy hell have you
been, eh?
You know where I've been.
I told you I had to go down to the Town Hall.
You said you'd only be 20 minutes,
that was 4 hours ago,
Sorry, I got a bit involved with Council bussiness,
Well, of course, I got a bit involved
myself here you know,
with silly little things like
trying to organise us some profit!
Oi, you little git!
You wanna get your priorities sorted out, my son.
You want to make your mind up
whether you want to be Chairman of the Tenant's Association
or you wanna work this pitch, right?
No, no, 'cos I had to go down
and introduce myself to Miss Mackenzie.
Who's Miss Mackenzie?
She's in charge of the housing and welfare down
the Town Hall, she's a very important lady.
And she was very
impressed with me.
Oh well, she would be, wouldn't she?
I mean, it's the suit innit, eh?
Well, yeah.
What d'you want, three? God
bless darling.
She's very intelligent actually.
We got really well.
Yeah well, they do say opposites
attract don't they, eh?
Come on you, get these crates sorted out,
will you?
What? Oh come on, Del.
I mean, don't you think it's gonna be a little bit
demanding for the Chairman of the Tenant's Association
to be been 'umping dirty
old crates around a market?
D'you want any wages tomorrow
Where shall I put 'em?
Don't tempt me Rodney, don't
temp me!
Alright, Del Boy?
Hello Grandad, what you doing
here, eh?
I've just been gettin something in for dinner.
- What have I got, Grandad?
- Er - d'you like haddock pie, Del?
No I don't!
You've got haddock pie, Rodney!
- Triffic...How's yer legs?
- Still hurting.
I've told you, told you what
they are, they're growing pains.
Look, if you wanna hang on
I'll give you a lift back in the van.
No, that's alright Rodney,
I'll try 'n' walk it off. See you later.
Yeah, see you!
Has he got pineapples?
No, it's just rheumatism. Oh.
No, no, sorry, no!
No, we ain't got any pineapples luv, you see.
No, it's this weather we've been having, you know,
you can'tget the people to go out and pick 'em!
Never mind, look, I've got some nice
pineapple-tasting oranges here.
No, I got them in special today, I knew you was coming in.
They come from Seville. There's three for 25p...
For you 6 for 90.
And then after that, right,
me and Miss Mackenzie were thinking of forming
a Police and Local Community Action
Committee.
You wanna get them pigging
lifts fixed first!
No, that's alright, that's all
in hand.
Oh look at this! He ain't even
put the shopping aw...
The lazy git, I'm gonna sack
him one of these days I will! Hang about.
Oh my Gawd. Grandad, Grandad!
What's the matter with him?
How the hell do I know?
- Del, the brandy!
- Yeah, yeah.
No, he ain't been at this!
I meant pour him some...Shall
I give him the kiss of life?
I ain't that bad, Rodney!!
Thank God for that, you're
live! I mean awake.
I just got up to switch over
to 'Crossroads.'
And what happened?
I don't know Del Boy, I didn’t
see the end of it!
No, he actually meant what
happened to you?
I just came over bad, Rodney - me legs give way.
Them stairs'll be the death of me.
Yeah, come on, come on, get him into bed.
Come on Grandad.
Come on, that's it, get up.
Look, I'll put him to bed, you
phone for the doctor, Rodney.
Right.
No need to call the doctor Del
Boy, I' be alright.
Now just shut up, it's nothing
to do with you.
Oh good evening.
Could you put me through to Dr Becker please...
Yes it is an emergency.
Hello, Dr Becker, look, sorry to bother you
but it's my grandad, he's not very well.
Yeah, yeah, my name is Trotter,
we live on...Oh you remember...
Has what cleared up? No, I've
never had anything like that.
No, no, you must be getting me
mixed up with somebody else.
Well, is he coming round?
Could you come round straight
away please? You're going out to dinner?
Tell him he can have inner
here!
Yeah, you could have dinner here...
He can have my haddock pie!
Your haddock pie? Give us that will you.
Hello Doctor, my name is Del Trotter,
now you don't know me but we've got a mutual friend.
Her name is Rita Alldridge!
That's right!
And I happen to talk to your good lay wife
every day in the market! Right!
He's on his way round.
I want you to make sure that
he gets plenty of sleep and lots of fresh air.
Yeah, we could put his bed on the balcony!
Fresh air? Fresh air. Haven't you noticed all the
juggernauts and buses smoking their way past this place?
The only fresh air my grandad gets is
when he's listening to 'The Archers.'
Well, there isn't very much I
can do about the pollution problem.
No, no, I'm sorry, I'm sorry
doctor. What about his legs?
Oh, don't worry, he's got legs
like Nijinsky.
Nijinsky's a racehorse!
No, Del, he means Nijinsky, the
Russian ballet dancer.
No I don't.
Oh, um, well, what's - what's
the matter with him, Doctor?
Exhaustion. 12 flights of stairs is difficult enough for
a young man, let alone someone of your grandad's age.
Now what he needs is ground-floor
accommodation.
Have you seen any of those new council
bungalows in Herrington Road?
Oh yeah, them. They're lovely ain't they.
They've got three bedrooms, little garden,
right opposite the park.
Still what chance do we stand?
I mean, you need to have nine kids
and speak with a foreign accent to
get one of them.
If you think it would do any good I could write
a letter to the council recommending you be moved.
You did that for my Mum back
in 1962 and they moved us here.
I'll put the shopping away.
The only thing that could hold a lot of sway
with the council’s housing department
would be support from the
Chairman of the Tenant's Association.
Now who is the Chairman of the Association
these days?
It's me.
Alright, alright, good boy.
- What?
- Nothing, good boy.
I didn't know you were in
here. You keeping a vigil?
No, I'm just sitting here with
Grandad.
- What you got there?
- Oh, it's just some fruit.
What you get?
Got him some grapes have you?
No, they're oranges.
Oranges - oranges?
Well, I couldn't think of what else to get him...
Look, Del, you know I'd like to help.
I've got nothing further to
say on the subject.
Here you are Grandad,
have a suck of that - go on.
How you could do this to your own flesh
and blood, I've got no idea.
Look, what's Miss Mackenzie
gonna think?
I mean, I've only been Chairman of the Association
for two days and already I'm into her for a new bungalow.
I'm not concerned with what -
I'm not concerned with what Miss Mackenzie thinks.
I'm only concerned with Grandad.
I mean, look at him.
His brain went years ago. Now his legs have gone.
There's only the middle bit of him left.
We could take him to Lourdes?
Lord's. Lord's. But he don't
even like cricket.
I meant the Lourdes in France.
Lourdes in France, no, no,
that's no good.
I mean, what you gain on the miracle cures
you'd lose on the sea-sickness on the way home.
Still here, Del Boy?
Yes, I'm here Grandad, it's alright, don't worry.
Look Rodney's brought you some oranges.
I'll put 'em over
there shall I, with the other 3,000?
You're a good boy, Rodney.
You've always looked after your old Grandad...
Rodney, put your hand under my pillow.
Yeah, okay.
Why, what's under there?
It's just something what was
left to me by my grandad.
What is it?
It's my grandad's old cigarette case. He carried
that with him right throughout the Boer War.
That's a bit of history you're holding, not like them
Nelson's eyepatches Del Boy flogs to the tourists.
What's this big dent?
There's a story behind that Rodney.
See, one night my grandad was on sentry duty,
standing out there alone in the middle of Africa.
And suddenly a sniper fired at him.
The bullet was aiming straight for my grandad's heart,
but he had that cigarette case in his breast pocket
and the bullet hit that instead.
Jeez. It saved his life?
Well, not really.
See, the bullet ricocheted up his nose
and blew his brains out!
I want you to have it, Rodney.
What?
My gran always said it were
lucky.
Grandad, it made the bullet
ricochet up his nose and blow his brains out.
Yeah, well, it could have ricocheted
downwards and ruined his entire life!
And do you know where he died, Rodney?
Fighting the Zulus at the Battle of Rorks's Drift.
No. Was he actually there? Oh
Cosmic!
I always thought it was the Welsh.
No, no, it was definitely the
Zulus, I saw the film.
You keep that with you always,
Rodney. It'll be something to remember me by.
Now you don't talk like that,
Grandad.
It's alright Grandad, it's alright. He'll remember what
he done to you. I'll see to that, don't you worry!
Oh don't keep on at him, Del.
He's doing what he thinks is best.
Besides, I might not have liked living on the
ground. I've always been up in the air somewhere...
I think I would have liked the garden
though. I could have gown some flowers.
I've never ever had a garden. Still what you've
never had you never miss, eh Del Boy?
That's right Grandad. That's
right. Rodney, where you going?
I'm gonna phone Miss Mackenzie
about that bungalow.
That's a good boy Rodney, good boy.
You know it makes sense...
Welcome back, you're one of
the family again!
Del Boy. I'd like to be cremated.
Well, you'll have to wait till
morning 'cos they'll be closed now.
Oi, cor, Rodney. Come on, look, clear this place up,
that old biddy from the council'll be here any minute.
Del, I'd like you to meet Miss Mackenzie.
Good evening.
Entende, I'm sure.
Please do sit down Miss Mackenzie.
Can I get you
a drink? Tea, coffee, Pina Colada?
No thank you, that's very kind
of you, Mr Trotter.
Mais oui, mais oui, Derek please.
Derek - I've just been in to
see your grandfather.
He's a very interesting man, he was telling me
how his own grandfather had died
at the Battle of Rorke's Drift.
Well, no, he wasn't actually
at Rourke's Drift.
What he was doing, see, he camped
in a little field behind it,
and one night he went over to the
Zulus to complain about the noise.
Well - has it always been your ambition
to work for the council, Miss Mackenzie?
Please call me Margaret.
Margaret, Margaret, do you
know, that is my most favourite name.
Thank you. Actually, when I left school
I wanted to be a choreographer.
Really? What a coincidence 'cos I always wanted
to into the medical profession meself.
A choreographer, Del, it means
she wanted to teach dance.
Oh yeah, course, that sort of choreographer, yeah.
Are you interested in dancing then,
Margaret?
Well, I was a student of dance
for two years.
Was you really, amazing, so
was I.
Really? I was at the London
School of Dance, Knightsbridge.
Del was at the Arthur Murray
School, Lewisham.
Thank you Rodney.
Rodney, why don't you go into the kitchen
and put your head in the food blender.
Well, do you like ballet, Margaret?
Oh yes, very much.
So do I. Triffic innit? What
about that Nijinsky then, eh?
Nijinsky?
Fabulous dancer, eh? Well, for a Soviet.
Yes. I suppose so.
- I'm a great fan.
- Of Nijinsky's?
Yeah, actually I was thinking of getting a couple of
tickets, you know, for one of the shows.
Derek - Nijinsky died in 1950.
Did she?
She? Nijinsky was a man.
Oh yes, yeah, of course he was. Sorry, sorry,
I always get him mixed up with...er...
- Arkle.
- Yeah, Arkle.
Well, that seems to be about it.
I think I have all the information I need.
How long will we have to wait until we know if our
application's been accepted?
You can know right now, Rodney.
I've just signed it.
You mean we've got the
bungalow?
Of course. Here's your new rent book
and all the necessary paperwork.
I don't believe it. Are you sure you don't
want to double-check nothing?
That won't be necessary Rodney.
Margaret knows what she's doing.
I don't know what to say.
Well, just say thank you to
the nice lady.
Really there's no need,
I'm only too pleased to help.
Many people get themselves voted on
to Tenants Committee's purely for their own ends.
But Rodney's different. He cares.
Oh he does, he cares. He's a
diamond, he really is.
Well, I hope you'll be very
happy in your new home.
I'll see you at our next
committee meeting then?
Yes, yes of course. And thanks again –
I can't wait to tell Grandad.
Well, I suppose we better...
No, I'll see Margaret out, Rodney. Excuse me.
There you go. Don't drink it.
Well,I suppose you must have
pulled a few strings?
Well, let's just say I applied some rather
liberal interpretations to our rules.
Yeah, well, if only there was some way
that I could show my appreciation.
But mon dieu - mon dieu - why don't I take
you out for a celebratory drink?
Oh that's very nice of you,
but I've got a lot of paperwork to finish.
Okay, well some other time
then maybe?
Yes. Well, goodbye.
No, not goodbye, Margaret,
just bonjour.
Well, we've done it. Now that
is the power of being a Chairman, Del.
Leave it out. It was my chat
what did it.
Oh yeah, your chat, yeah. 'A
choreographer.
Of course, I've always wanted to be in the
medical profession meself.'
Oi, cut that out will you?
Have we got it, Del?
Yeah, of course, we've got it,
Grandad. Look, we move in next week.
'My old man said follow the van,
and don't dilly-dally on the way.'
Hang on, I'll get
you a beer, Grandad.
We feeling a little better are
we, Grandad?
I'm feeling on top of the
world Rodney.
You know, I thought as much.
Because five minutes ago you couldn't wiggle your toes and
now you're doing an audition for the Hot Shoe Show.
You two have really stitched me
up ain't yer?
And not just me - Dr Becker and Miss
Mackenzie as well.
Oh shut up you tart.
We couldn't let you in on our
little plan could we, 'cos, well,
to put it politely, you're full of principle,
aren't you? Here you are Grandad.
How else could we have done
it, Rodney?
We've got ourselves a beautiful new home,
a bit of garden, a garage and no stairs.
Grandad the point is that is...
I suppose them stairs were a bit much for you.
And I can hardly blame Del for the
lifts breaking down.
You mean you even went to the
- right, come here you.
Oh hello, Margaret. Did you
forget something?
Only my manners I'm sorry to say.
I've just realised that you, quite naturally,
would like to celebrate your new home.
But as Rodney would have to stay in with
Grandad you have no one to go with.
So if you're invitation is still open?
Oh well, of course it is.
If you'd just like to hang on uno momento.
I mustn't have too much to drink though –
it goes straight to my head.
Does it really? We'll have to
keep a close eye on you then won't we?
Oi, listen, I'm off out. I don't know what time I'm going
to be back so don't put the Chubb on, right.
Listen what I thought we might do is slip down
the Nag's Head for a couple of swift halves
and then we could go to this - well - go on to this spick
drinking club I know over at New Cross.
I don't want to be out too late.
Don't worry we'll get you back
in your flat before three.
Here are Del, don't forget
your scarf, it's freez...Ooh my good Gawd.
Well, hello again.
He seems to be over the worst.
Yeah, well, you know, it comes - and goes.
So it would appear.
- Collapse.
- What?
Collapse!
I shouldn't bother, you might
do yourself an injury.
Oi, you're gonna need the keys.
I am disgusted with the lot of you.
But especially with Rodney. I believed you.
I believed me.
I assume you'll be resigning,
Mr Chairman?
First thing in the morning,
yeah.
And I'll tell you what I'm going to do in the morning.
I'm going to do you all yet another favour.
I'm going to save you the inconvenience
of moving. Goodnight to you all.
- Margaret.
- What?
We still on for that drink?
Subtitles by NVL