What d' you reckon then?
They're alright ain't they!
Don't 'alf look alike.
They're identical twins!
Yeah, which one d' you fancy?
I'm easy!
Are you sure that's not one
bird sitting next to a mirror?
No they're sisters or something,
they've been here before! G'on then!
What?
- Say something!
- What?
- I don't know! Anything!
- Like what?
Just say the first thing that
comes into your head. It's easy!
Alright then, if it's so easy,
you say something.
- What?
- Anything. It's easy!
Alright then I will.
- Well go'n then!
- I will...
There you are.
- Was that it?
- Yeah!
You're a right little John Travolta
when you get going ain't yer Mickey!
They looked didn't they?
Of course they looked, someone
just shouted 'Oi' at them!
Hold up, they're looking over here.
Hello, I think we've cracked
it Mickey my son!
Watcha Rodders, alright Mickey
my son? Who you two after?
- Not the gruesome twosome are you?
- They're alright!
Alright? Look, they're so ugly
they even look alike!
Del! They happen to be two sisters!
Sisters!
Oi girls, seen much of
Cinderella since the wedding?
Cinderella! Ugly sisters.
That's a good 'un innit Rodders, eh?
Anyway, look, I won't hang about 'cos I
don't wanna spoil your chances!
Hello darling! You alright?
Are you still working at Sainsbury's?
See you. Just a minute.
- I'll see you Tuesday then?
- See you Tuesday!
'You made me love you. I
didn't want to do it...'
- You okay love?
- Who is it?
Shall I phone you a cab?
No - there'll be a bus along
in a minute my lovely!
No, no, ain't got no buses
going along here.
No, they cut the route in about 1973!
I'll get you a nice taxi, eh?
No, no, I shall be alright!
Careful!
- What you doing?
- I'm just steadying you that's all!
You touched me!
I've read about your sort!
Hey, hold on, I was just
trying to stop you from falling flat on your face!
I'll have the police on you!
You touched me.
No, I didn't, honest!
- Help!
- What you doing? Don't shout!
- You touched me!
- No, no, it's alright 'cos I'm a doctor!
- You're not a doctor!
- I am, I am really! Alright, say 'ah!'
No, not that loud! Bloody hell!
Look, I tell you what I'm just going back to the van
right, to get a thermometer! Alright listen!
Help, help! Rape! Rape! Help! Help!
Del Boy, your breakfast's ready!
Yeah, hang on a minute!
Come on Rodney shake a leg,
six o' clock!
It's on the table.
Nothing like a traditional
British breakfast is there?
That's right.
Gordon Bennett. Why don't you
try cooking one every now and then?
Blimey, it looks like a
bad day at the Blue Cross.
- Were you two alright last night?
- Yeah, of course, why?
Well, when Rodney came in he
was behaving very strangely.
He was all trembling and
sweating.
No, he's probably alright, don't worry,
it's just the start of the mating season.
No Del - something's up. Ain’t
you eating that?
No, Grandad, see I'm on a diet.
Rodney, your breakfast's ready.
- Alright Rodders?
- What d'you mean 'alright?'
- Nothing - nothing, just alright Rodders?
- Yeah, fine why shouldn't I be alright?
No reason. I just said like,
alright Rodders.
Like I say, you know,
alright every morning don’t I?
Yeah, sorry!
That's alright, what did you
do when you left the pub last night?
- What makes you think I did something?
- Gordon Bennett!
No, I mean, I just asked you like if you
went on anywhere? If, you met anyone or anything?
No! No, I didn't. I come
straight home.
Didn't meet anyone, didn't talk to anyone,
a very uneventful journey!
That's alright, as long as you
enjoyed yourself!
Go on, get that down, come on, we've got
to get away early.
Got to pick up the van from the Nag's Head.
Why?
Ah, well, when we fell out the pub last night
the whole area was teeming with the Old Bill!
I mean, they were all there.
There was the Flying Squad,
alsatians and the SGB!
Anyway, I thought to myself, I thought,
there's no way I'm driving home through that lot.
Not with me like being as soppy as a
sack, so I, you know, I got a cab!
- Did they have a clear description of him?
- Who?
- The man they were after?
- Who said they were after a man?
Oh, I just assumed they were
looking for someone that's all.
See what I mean?
Alright Rodney, come on sit down.
Something bothering you ain't there?
No!
Has somebody threatened you?
If they have, you tell me their name and I'll go and
sort them out before we go to the market!
It's nothing like that!
You might as well tell us sooner rather than later
Rodney. It'll  save a lot of time!
Oh it's probably nothing!
My journey home last night was
not as uneventful as I made out!
There was this woman!
Well, she weren't feeling very
well, see!
I don't know what was wrong with her but she
stunk of booze!
So I stopped, right, to ask if she wanted
any assistance, and
- and she started acting all sort of odd!
- Odd?
- Yeah...Um, screaming shouting things!
- What kind of things?
Oh, things like 'Rape!' you know,
that sort of thing!
So to try and reassure her and calm her down –
I told her I was a doctor!
You told her you were a...
You, you didn't give her a
prescription or nothing did you?
Oh no, nothing like that!
Why was she accusing you of
these things?
Well, I think 'cos at one
point right she - she stumbled forward.
So I put my hands out
to stop...you know.
I didn't touch her!
Well no, obviously I did touch her, but I didn't,
you know, honestly!
Alright. Alright, okay, take
it nice and easy right.
This is gonna take
a bit of working out!
What did this woman look like?
Well she was blonde, 45 and
her hair had black roots and,
purple fingernails and she
was really heavily made-up.
- Did she call you 'My lovely?
- Yes! D'you know her?
No, no, no, you didn't catch her –
you didn't catch her name or nothing did you?
Oh she was wearing an identity
necklace that said something like - Blossom...
Del, honestly, I did not touch
her I swear to God.
- You expect me to believe that?
- Yes!
Alright, let's go through the
facts shall we!
After a night's drinking, on your way
home you meet a sick woman!
And, instead of phoning for an ambulance
like any rightminded citizen, you touch her!
What do you think you've got,
healing hands?
I don't believe you're saying
this to me!!
No, no, no, this is not me
Rodney!
That is what the council for the prosecution
will say during his cross-examination!
You don't think it will go to
court?
Oh it's a pound to a penny
Rodney.
I mean, the police
don't let matters like this drop lightly!
No, Old Bailey would be my
bet! The case of the Peckham Pouncer!
Who called me the Peckham
Pouncer?
Look, the police did last night! You see at the time,
well, I didn't think nothing of it!
Why don't you give yourself up
Rodney?
I'm not giving myself up!
You ever seen some of them detectives
give someone the third degree on the telly?
Well, one of them pretends he really wants to bet you up
bad, right, and the other pretends to be Mr Nice!
So it's...you know.
Yeah p'rhaps you're right.
After all, you've got form ain't yer! I mean, you still
ain't finished that two year suspended yet!
No! I'd forgotten about that!
- It's the others what worry me!
- What others?
Well, last night there were mobs of vigilantes
roaming the street
and they were shouting things like
'Lynch him! Lynch him!’
At the time, I didn't
think nothing of it you know!
Well maybe it would be better if I did give myself up then
'cos all they've got is circumstantial evidence.
Circumstantial? A sick woman is attacked
at night by a known criminal posing as a doctor!
D'you know what they'd call me
if I went in the nick? I'd be a beast!
A beast?
Well, that's what the other
prisoners call people like me!
Everywhere I went the walls
would be whispering 'Beast, Beast.'
There'd be posses of them waiting for me in the
shower room, there'd be razors in me soap,
there'd be broken
glass in me porridge.
Oh you'll soon learn to adapt
Rodney!
No, it's not fair Del! I swear to God I didn't touch her.
I was only trying to help!
Alright Rodney, alright. Now
come on. Take it easy - relax - alright.
Now listen, I'll tell you what I'm going to do.
I want to go out, put me ear
to the ground, see what I can find out!
In the meantime I want you to go and get some
kip and, above all, stop worrying!
Yeah. I'm innocent Del. Honest!
- I believe you!
- So do I Rodney!
.
D'you reckon he done it Del?
Leave it out Grandad! All he's
done, he's bumped into Blossom that's all!
I don't understand you?
Well she's well-known for this
sort of thing! She's as nutty as a fruit cake.
She spends most of her time
in the Happy Home,
they only let her out at
weekends to get a bit of practice!
You mean she's always accusing
blokes of doing this sort of thing?
Yeah, it's her hobby! She's
well known to the police.
But why didn't you tell young
Rodney?
What, and spoil all the fun? No way.
I'm gonna wind him right
up with this!
By this time tomorrow evening I'll have him
believing that all these flats are under siege!
You wanna be a bit careful Del Boy!
A joke's a joke but you
never know when to stop!
What about that April Fool's day!
You told me the pools had rung
to say I'd won 'alf a million!
Yeah that was a belter weren't it!
Oh wonderful! But you could have least
stopped me going up West with me pension money!
Oh it wasn't funny Del.
I mean there was I, in a Soho night-club
drinking champagne, with a bird called Camilla
and I suddenly realised I didn't
even do the bloody pools!
Stop it!
You should have seen his
little face! It was a picture.
I wish I'd had a camera!
How could he swallow that, eh?
Well, you know Rodney don't
you.
He said he was thinking
of forming an appeal committee!
I said you've no need to worry about that. You
ought to form an escape committee I said.
I thought that everyone round
here knew what Old Blossom was like...
- She accused my cousin once!
- Who's that, young Sidney?
No, Marilyn! There again,
Marilyn's always been a bit of a Tom Boy!
Oh yeah, it was a crew cut,
braces and a pipe last time I saw her!
She still up at Greenham Common?
Here, you playing Trigger or what?
No, I'll be away in a minute!
Of course, this Blosom person
is completely loopy you know!
Oh yes, I don't think they
should be allowed out!
Oh yeah, why's that?
Well they might be a danger to
the public!
Still selling them second-hand
cars Boycie?
Oh yeah, I knocked out a
couple tod...
of course, I 'ave heard she receives
electroyde treatment, you know.
Oh yes, every three months or so they
take her away and plug her head into the National Grid!
The lights have been known to
dim as far away as Watford!
Yeah but they reckon she's as
sane as anyone when they're finished!
Yeah, until she gets her
electric bill!
Del - there's a call for you.
Oh excuse me chaps won't be a
moment.
Oh Karen, can we have three large scotches -
Boycie's paying.
Oh cheers, Boycie.
Hello? Oh hello Grandad! You
what...
What about Rodney? What d'you mean
he's gone on the run? Why?
Oh leave it off,
Grandad it was just a joke!
Yeah alright, alright now don't - don't panic, he'll be
home when he's hungry and he wants something to eat...
Oh has he!
Alright, alright Grandad, I'll tell you what
I'll do, I'll go and have a look round for him
and I'll be home in about an hour!
Yeah, alright, bye.
What's up Del?
It's that dipstick Rodney.
He's only gone on the run ain't he.
Reckons he's found a secret hiding place!
Where?
Well how do I know?
If I knew where it was it wouldn't be a
secret would it, eh?
No, I meant there must be a
clue!
Yeah, well, he left a note
saying it's no good trying to find him
'cos he'd be in the last place
anyone would think of looking for him!
Have you tried under his bed?
He'll be home as soon as he
gets hungry!
No he won't, Grandad reckons he's taken
all the tinned food from the cupboard!
So, what are you gonna do then
Del?
I don't know Trigger, I just
don't know!
Ain't you got nothing in the
freezer then?
- Any luck Del?
- Na, no sign of him Grandad!
Where did you look?
I've been everywhere!
I've been traipsing round Charing
Cross, Soho, Leicester Square!
Oh, you want to see what it's
like up there in the early hours Grandad!
It's like the end of the world! It's full
of drug addicts, glue-sniffers, winos!
D'you know what, if a nightingale sang
now in Berkeley Square someone would eat it!
Bad night, eh Del?
Yeah, very bad.
You know I've been offered everything from 50
quid for me passport to a plate of Magic Mushrooms!
- You cooking something?
- No!
What's that horrible smell
then? Sweet and sickly!
Oh, perhaps it's this aftershave I've got on!
Gordon Bennett! Where d'you
get that from?
Out of your room!
Well, that can't be it then
can it!
Oh, I know the smell you're
talking about.
It was here last night, everyone in the
flats was moaning about it!
Here, why don't you get some
sleep Del Boy!
No, I'll be alright Grandad.
I'll have a cup of tea and have another
punt round for him! Where can he be?
I had a note from him here somewhere,
he said he's in the last place you'll ever think of looking!
Yeah I know I remember! You
have looked under his bed haven't yer?
First place I checked!
Well he's hardly likely
to be in that bloody drawer is he?
I'm looking for the note!
Now don't you get funny with me
Del, this is your fault, you and your silly jokes!
I know, I was gonna tell him
this morning!
Well you could have told him
yesterday.
Instead of that you sat there playing your Johnny
Cash Live at San Quentin LP!
Alright, don't go on at me -
don't go on. I feel bad enough as it is!
What is that smell?
I've smelt it before somewhere!
- I know, so did I.
- When?
- I told you! Last night!
- No, no, no, before that.
It seems to be coming from the
ventilating system!
Grandad, go and get them
chicken legs at the fridge!
I think I know where Rodney's hiding.
Rodney! Rodney, it's Del Boy!
Rodney I know you're in here!
Rodney don't be a plonker all
your life!
Listen I can explain everything there's
nothing to be frightened of!
I've got - got some scotch
here, something to eat!
Or if you prefer I could get a saucer of milk?
Come on, least
we can talk about it cant we?
- Oi! That is you innit Rodney?
- No, it's that cat again!
You had me going there for a
minute, know what I mean?
How did you know I was here?
I know a lot of things Rodney!
Like I know you've bin smoking your funny fags again!
No I ain't Del, honest I ain't
touch...Well, a couple!
I tell you that was the give away you see.
The smell from your exotic tobacco has been
wafting down the air ducts!
There's not a man, woman or
child that isn't high as a kite!
You're kidding?
No I'm not.
If you stand outside this tower block all you
can hear is giggling!
Grandad's calling everybody 'Man'.
Thinking of growing his hair in dreadlocks!
Is Grandad okay?
Yeah he's alright. Worried about you though.
What are you doing up here?
Nothing much! There's not a
lot to do in a tank room Del.
I mean you can look at the view but that gets a bit
boring after eight hours or so.
In wasn't - wasn't asking
about your activities.
I was speaking meteorically.
What you playing at?
Playing at! Well, Del this is
a little game called 'Not Going to Prison'!
The rules are ever so easy you know.
All you gotta do is find yourself
a place to hide and stay there till you die!
Don't reckon it will catch on
Rodney!
You could be right there Del,
but I'll tell you something, if necessary
I will shoot my
way out of this room.
Oh so while you've been up
here, you've been making a gun have you?
Well, I'll throw tins at 'em
then!
Yeah, well, you could get an
empty can couldn't you...
...you know and you could
like, splash 'em to death!
I ain't had nothing to eat
since I've been up here!
Why's that, you been too
frightened?
No, I forgot the tin-opener!
Well why didn't you pop down
for it!
Del, desperate men on the run
don't pop home to borrow a tin-opener!
Anyway, going without food ain't so bad!
People like us are used to it!
Oh come on. Don't give me all
that James Cagney stuff!
'Look at me Ma! I'm on top of the
World Ma! Look I'm in the tank room Ma!'
Why don't you shut up!
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
Here you are. Get that down
your neck.
Oh cheers, Del, great.
Oi, have the police been round to
question you and Grandad yet?
Er, no!
Good! Good! That means they
ain't on me trail yet, gives me a bit of time!
Yeah, Rodney, I've got to explain something like –
well, this is sort of like, confession time!
You know that woman you met, Blossom.
- Well she's mad, Rodney!
- I'm not with you.
She's mad you know. She's well-known to the Old Bill.
They don't take no notice of her.
No - you're lying to me.
No, no, I'm not. No I'm not,
look - look, cross my heart, swear to die.
You remember old man Corby, well a couple weeks
ago she accused him of assaulting her!
Well, I mean, he was so surprised he nearly
fell off his wheelchair!
Alright then. Alright then.
You explain this to me then, what were all them police
doing outside the pub that night?
That was the - that was the mod and the skinheads,
they were at it in the kebab house!
Terrible scenes, for all I
could hear.
I mean there was chairs going through the
windows, there was chilli sauce up the wall,
then somebody knocked over a frying
pan and the staff rest room went up in flames!
No, I don't believe you Del,
you're just trying to get me to come quietly!
No I'm not.
Look go on then, go on - look out - look out there look,
go on. Now, you see the kebab house?
No!
Exactly, it ain't there no
more! What further proof do you need?
No Del, I don't understand
this!
You mean there's been no photofit pictures,
no house-to-house searches, no public outcry?
No, none at all! Here, look,
d'you want some water with yer scotch?
No!
Then why did you tell me I'd
go away for ten years as a special category prisoner,
that they'd nicknamed me the
Peckham Pouncer?
That there were gangs of men roaming the
street looking to hang me from the nearest lamp post!
For a laugh!
A laugh?
Yeah, it was just a bit of a
wind up that's all?
Del, I haven't slept, I'm starving hungry
and I've been freezing my - boots off
in this tank room because of your wind up!
You take things too seriously,
that's your trouble Rodney!
- I'm gonna kill you!
- No, no, no, don't be silly!
No, really, I mean it. I'm
gonna kill you right now!
Now just a minute! Just a
minute.
Alright now, I realise
that I took the joke too far!
And I should have told you
earlier, and I'm - I'm sorry Rodney, I really am!
I'm still gonna kill you!
I've been all over London
looking for you!
I've been in more doss-houses
than a tramp's vest!
So that's where you were going
so late that night, eh? I saw you drive off!
You saw me. Why didn't you say
something?
Del, I'm a desperate man on the run!
I can hardly lean out and go 'Ooh oooh, Del!'
No, I s'pose you can't.
Listen Rodney, I feel - you know, I feel really sorry
for all the aggro that I've caused you.
I'd like to try and make it up to you,
let's say I take you out
and I buy you a big slap upmeal, eh?
Yeah, with the wine, all the
works!
I mean look at these clothes!
That's alright. Come on I'll
buy you a new suit.
Yeah, but then I'd look silly, you know
brand- new suit and these dirty old plimsoles!
Don't you bloody come it
Rodney!
Come on, come here. Come on I'll buy
a new pair of rhythm an' blues as well! How's that?
Yeah, alright!
That's a good boy - good boy,
you know it makes sense, don't you!
- All in the past, eh?
- All in the past cheers!
Look at the state of me!
Don't worry. You'll have a nice hot shower
when you get down the flat!
Oh, I don't fancy standing
under that water Del.
Not after what I've been doing in it!
Subtitles by NVL