Captions made possible by
HOME BOX OFFICE
A Division of TIME WARNER
ENTERTAINMENT COMPANY, L.P.
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D GET THROUGH D-DAY.
LET ALONE THE NEXT PHASE
OR THE NEXT PHASE.
I THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO
GET KILLED INSTANTLY.
I THOUGHT ONE
OF TWO THINGS:
A QUICK DEATH,
ER, OR...
I'D COME THROUGH PROBABLY
WITHOUT A SCRATCH.
I THINK EVERYBODY
HAD FEAR.
I THINK THERE'S PEOPLE
THAT CAN HANDLE FEAR.
I THINK...
I THINK I WAS
PROBABLY ONE OF THEM.
JUST AS...
SCARED AS ANYBODY ELSE
EXCEPT I COULD THINK.
IT'S A FEELING YOU WOULD
NOT LET YOURSELF DOWN,
AND YOU WOULD NOT LET YOUR
CAMRADES OR YOUR UNIT DOWN.
WE ALL HAD FEAR...
BUT WE ALL HAD
TRAINING TO KNOW THAT...
YOU TRY TO HANDLE
YOUR FEAR
AND WORK TO ACCOMPLISH
WHAT YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE DOING.
HEY, IT LOOKS LIKE
WHAT'S-HIS-NAME.
YOU KNOW,
FROM 1st PLATOON?
OUR 1st PLATOON?
IT SURE DOES.
BLITHE.
HEY, BLITHE.
BLITHE!
( gunfire )
THOUGHT THAT
WAS YOU.
YOU ALONE?
YOU'RE THE FIRST
FAMILIAR FACES I'VE SEEN.
I AIN'T SURPRISED.
THEY DROPPED US
ALL OVER THE PENINSULA.
WE'VE BEEN FIGHTING
WITH THE 502nd
SINCE WE HIT THE GROUND.
YOU?
OH, I'VE BEEN...
TRYING TO FIND EASY.
JOIN THE CLUB.
( gunfire )
HEY, FELLAS.
WELL, LOOK WHO DECIDED
TO SHOW UP, FLOYD.
Hl THERE, LADZ.
WE THOUGHT WE'D
NEVER FIND YOU GUYS.
HEY, TAB,
GET A LOAD OF THIS.
YOU LIKE THAT?
YEAH, IT'S
THE REAL STUFF, MAN.
YEAH, OF COURSE.
YOU LIKE THIS?
OH, NICE.
THAT'S A BEAUTY,
SARGE.
MY LUGER'S GONNA PUT YOU
ALL TO SHAME WHEN I GET IT.
HOW WAS YOUR JUMP?
AH, MISSED THE DZ.
YEAH, THAT GOES
WITHOUT SAYING.
I GUESS SO.
GOT ANY SOUVENIRS
TO TRADE?
HUH?
THEY'RE ALL TICKIN'.
UNLIKE THEIR
PREVIOUS OWNERS.
GOT ANYTHING GOOD?
NOT YET.
HEY.
SO, HAVE
WE LOST ANYBODY?
TOMMY BURGESS
TOOK ONE IN THE FACE.
POPEYE WYNN GOT
PINCHED IN THE BEHIND.
BUT THEY'RE
GONNA BE OKAY.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU RUN INTO LIEUTENANT MEEHAN
IN YOUR TRAVELS?
NO, WHY?
COMPANY HQ'S
STILL MISSING.
THEY THINK THE PLANE
WENT DOWN.
THEY SAY
HE'S GONNA TURN UP.
YEAH, I AIN'T
HOLDING MY BREATH.
WHO'S IN COMMAND,
THEN?
WINTERS FOR NOW.
LIEUTENANT WELSH
IS 1st PLATOON.
( male )
LET'S GO,
1st PLATOON!
EASY'S MOVING OUT!
ON YOUR FEET.
STAND UP, LET'S GO.
LlSTEN UP!
IT'LL BE DARK SOON.
I WANT LIGHT AND NOISE
DISCIPLINE FROM HERE ON.
NO TALKING,
NO SMOKING.
AND NO PLAYING GRAB-FANNY WITH
THE MAN IN FRONT OF YOU, LADS.
SO, WHERE WE HEADED TO,
LIEUTENANT, HUH?
WE'RE TAKING
CARENTAN.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE FUN.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
WHERE ARMOR FROM OMAHA
AND UTAH BEACH
CAN LINK UP
AND HEAD INLAND.
UNTIL WE TAKE CARENTAN,
THEY'RE STUCK IN THE SAND.
GENERAL TAYLOR'S SENDING
THE WHOLE DIVISION.
REMEMBER, BOYS...
GIVE ME THREE DAYS AND
THREE NIGHTS OF HARD FIGHTING
AND YOU WILL
BE RELIEVED.
LIEUTENANT.
LIEUTENANT,
I'LL TAKE POINT.
CORPORAL HOOBLER
WILL BE LEAD SCOUT.
BLITHE, GLAD YOU
COULD JOIN US.
THANK YOU, SIR.
1st PLATOON, FALL IN
BEHIND FOX COMPANY.
YOU PEOPLE FROM 2nd
AND 3rd PLATOON, FOLLOW US.
LET'S SHAKE A LEG.
ANOTHER THING
TO REMEMBER, BOYS...
FLIES SPREAD DISEASE.
SO, KEEP YOURS CLOSED.
( laughing )
DON'T WAKE JERRY.
DAMN!
WHAT?
WE LOST
"F" COMPANY, SIR.
AGAIN?
WE LOST
"F" COMPANY.
AGAIN?
HEY, BLITHE,
SKINNY, GUESS WHAT?
PERCONTE, GO BACK AND PASS
THE WORD TO HOLD UP.
YES, SIR.
HOOBLER, TAKE BLITHE,
GO FIND "F" COMPANY.
YES, SIR.
BLITHE.
SHIT.
DID YOU SEND
SOMEBIDY?
YEAH, I GOT HOOBLER
AND BLITHE OUT THERE NOW.
WHY HAVE
WE STOPPED?
THIS IS ABOUT OFFICERS
CRAPPING OUT IN
THEIR TRAINING, NIX.
COME ON, LET'S GET
THIS SHOW ON THE ROAD.
DANG MISQUITOES.
WHAT IS IT?
SHH.
FLASH.
THUNDER.
I CAN HEAR Y'ALL ALL THE WAY
ACROSS THE FIELD.
YOU "F" COMPANY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHERE Y'ALL BEEN?
BLITHE, GO BACK
TO THE LIEUTENANT.
TELL HIM WE'VE
FOUND "F" COMPANY.
I'LL FIGURE OUT WHERE
THESE YOKELS ARE AT.
HEY, WHO Y'ALL
CALLING A YOKEL?
HE'S DEAD,
PRIVATE.
DID YOU FIND
FOX COMPANY?
YES, SIR.
I THOUGHT HE...
I THOUGHT
HE HAD ME.
FALLSCHIRMJAGER.
PARATROOPER?
DIVISION THINKS
THERE'S A REGIMENT OF 'EM
HOLDING CARENTAN.
WELL, THERE'S ONE LESS
TO WORRY ABOUT.
YEAH.
THAT'S EDELWEISS.
THAT ONLY GROWS IN THE ALPS
ABOVE THE TREE LINE,
WHICH MEANS HE CLIMBED
UP THERE TO GET IT.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE THE MARK
OF A TRUE SOLDIER.
I WANT YOU TAKE THE 1st
STRAIGHT UP THE MIDDLE,
HARD AND FAST.
WE HAVE TO
MOVE QUICKLY.
I'LL BE RIGHT BEHIND YOU
WITH 2nd AND 3rd.
GO!
LET'S GO, 1st,
LET'S GO.
GO, GO, GO!
IN THE DITCH!
INCOMING!
GODDAMN IT!
WHERE THE FUCK
IS EVERYBODY?!
WHERE DID
EVERYBODY GO?!
I HAVE NO IDEA!
LET'S GO, EASY!
GET THESE MGs MOVING,
WILL YA!
LET'S GET THEM
OUT OF THERE.
THEY'RE IN THE OPEN,
FOR PETE'S SAKE!
GO, GO!
GET GOING, BUCK.
FOLLOW ME, EASY!
MOVE OUT!
MOVE OUT, MEN!
GO!
MOVE OUT,
MOVE OUT!
GET YOURSELVES
OUT OF THAT DITCH!
WE HAVE MEN GETTING KILLED
OUT THERE, BLITHE!
MOVE!
UPSTAIRS WINDOW, LEFT.
GET YOURSELVES
OUT OF THESE TRENCHES!
INCOMING!
THAT'S AN MG42.
THERE'S ONE IN
THE RIGHT UPPER WIN--
MEDIC!
UPPER FLANK!
OH, SHIT!
SNIPER...
TAKE HIS
LOWER LEFT.
AH, SHIT!
WE NEED SOME COVERING FIRE,
READY, LADS?
OKAY, I'M OUT.
SHIT!
GUARNERE, CLEAR THAT
SECTOR ON THE RIGHT!
WITH ME!
YOU OKAY,
SHIFTY?
WE GOTTA TAKE
THAT WAREHOUSE!
SHIFTY!
HAMMER THESE WINDOWS.
TIPPER, TAKE LIEBGOTT, START
CLEARING THESE BUILDINGS.
RIGHT.
SECOND TWO,
GO, GO!
HOUSES ON
THE RIGHT!
SMASH.
GRENADE.
LADS, COME ON, LADS.
COME ON.
CLOSE BEHIND.
SHIT!
THEY GOT US ZEROED!
SPREAD IT OUT,
SPREAD IT OUT!
GO!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF THERE.
THEY GOT US ZEROED!
GET OUT
OF THERE!
GO, GO!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF THE STREET!
MOVE, NOW.
GO, GO, GO!
( moaning )
COME ON, LET'S GET YOU
OUT OF HERE.
COME ON,
COME ON.
MOVE, MOVE, MOVE!
GET OFF
THE STREET!
GO, GO!
MOVE, NOW!
HEY, BUDDY
YOU'RE OKAY, LIP.
EVERYTHING'S RIGHT
WHERE IT SHOULD BE.
COME ON,
UPSY-DAISY.
GET TIPPER UP HERE
WITH THE BAZOOKA.
HELLO?
ANYBODY THERE?
TIPPER!
TIP!
ANSWER ME, TIP!
JOE?
LOOKING GOOD, TIP.
IS THAT YOU?
LOOKING REAL GOOD.
COME HERE, BUDDY,
YOU GOTTA SIT DOWN.
COME HERE,
COME ON.
EASY, EASY.
THERE YOU GO,
THERE YOU GO.
AH, JESUS.
YOU HANG IN THERE,
BUDDY.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
GET YOU FIXED UP.
ALRIGHT, OKAY.
GUYS, YOU WANNA
GIVE ME A HAND HERE?
COME ON.
TAKE THE LEFT FLANK!
TAKE THE
LEFT FLANK!
IN THE NAME OF THE FATHER
AND OF THE SON...
HEY, MALARK.
YOU SEE WHAT
I'M SEEING?
IS NOW AND EVER SHALL BE,
WORLD WITHOUT END.
AMEN.
CRAZY FOOLS,
THE IRISH.
YOU SHOULD KNOW.
SMIKEY, THE WINDOW,
LET'S GO!
HO.
MORNING, SIR.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
TROOPER?
SERGEANT FARMSWORTH
FROM ABLE COMPANY 501st.
I'M HERE AND I'M SUPPOSED
TO TELL YOU
THAT WE GOT IT CLEAR FROM
HERE ALL THE WAY TO THE NORTH
OF THEM KRAUTS, SIR.
WELL, TELL YOUR CO
506 ARRIVED IN FORCE
AND SECURED ALL POSITIONS
SOUTH OF YOU.
YES, SIR,
I'LL TELL HIM.
COME ON, BAD BOY,
LET'S GO!
LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
YES, SIR?
IS IT SAFE
TO CROSS NOW?
WHAT'S THAT, SIR?
IS IT SAFE
TO CROSS?
WE WANNA MOVE
THE WOUNDED.
AH, YES, SIR.
OKAY.
COME ON, LET'S GET 'EM
OUT OF HERE.
THERE SHE IS.
YOU'RE LUCKY
IT WAS A RICOCHET.
YOU JUST CAUGHT
A PIECE OF IT.
STUPID.
WHAT?
NOTHING.
( male )
WALKING WOUNDED
TO THE REAR.
NOW, YOU GONNA BE
ABLE TO STAY OFF IT?
DOESN'T LOOK
THAT WAY.
WELL, YOU GOTTA
TRY, HUH?
WHAT HAVE WE GOT
PLANNED, CHIEF?
WELL, WE EXPECT
A COUNTERATTACK.
CARENTAN'S AS IMPIRTANT
TO THEM AS IT IS TO US.
ANY IDEA WHEN?
WE'RE NOT WAITING
AROUND TO FIND OUT.
BATTALION WANTS US
TO HEAD EAST TOWARD
HIGH GROUND,
SET UP A DEFENSIVE
POSITION.
WITH ALL
THE FLOODED FIELDS,
IT'S THE ONLY
DIRECTION THEY
COULD APPROACH FROM.
YEAH.
YOU GONNA
BE ALRIGHT?
YEAH.
GOOD.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH BLITHE?
WELL, NOTHING,
EXCEPT HE CAN'T SEE.
HE CAN'T SEE?
SO HE SAYS.
BLITHE?
IT'S LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
THINGS,
THEY JUST KINDA
WENT BLACK ON ME.
YOU CAN'T SEE?
NOT A THING, SIR.
I CAN'T SEE
A THING.
WELL, YOU JUST
TAKE IT EASY, BLITHE.
WE'RE GONNA GET YOU
OUT OF HERE.
GET YOU BACK
TO ENGLAND.
IT'S GONNA
BE OKAY.
SIR.
I DIDN'T WANNA
LET ANYONE DOWN.
JUST TAKE IT EASY.
IT'S OKAY, SON.
SIR.
YEAH, WHAT IS IT?
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M OKAY.
YEAH, I'M OKAY.
I THINK I'M OKAY.
YOU CAN SEE?
GOD, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED.
I THINK, I THINK
I'M OKAY.
ALRIGHT.
WELL, STAY HERE
A LITTLE WHILE LONGER...
AND MAKE SURE.
AND, THEN YOU CAN
REPORT BACK TO YOUR PLATOON.
YES, SIR.
NOW, CAN WE GET
THAT BANDAGE ON?
YEAH.
BERLIN BY CHRISTMAS.
THAT'S HOW I SEE IT.
YEAH, YOU'RE
FULL OF IT.
OH, GOD.
THIS KRAUT CHEESE
TASTES LIKE...
IT STINKS.
BREAD'S STALE, TOO.
GIVE ME THAT.
YES, SIR, THE WAY WE CAME
IN TOWN TODAY AND TOOK OVER,
YOU KNOW, IT DON'T
SEEM LIKE JERRY'S
GOT TOO MUCH FIGHT
LEFT IN HIM.
HEY, MOORE, DON'T GET
HIT IN THE FACE
WHEN JERRY THROWS IN
THE SPONGE, ALRIGHT?
YOU MARK MY WORDS, MAL,
BERLIN BY CHRISTMAS.
ENJOY IT WHILE
IT LASTS.
WE'LL BE
MOVING OUT, SOON.
OUT OF TOWN,
LIEUTENANT?
ALREADY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
DON'T THEY KNOW
WE'RE JUST GETTING
SETTLED HERE?
NlCE, GROUCHO.
WHAT?
REAL SMART.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE TAKING
YOUR LIFE IN YOUR OWN HANDS.
AIN'T THAT RIGHT?
I TOLD YOU, I DIDN'T
ACTUALLY SEE IT.
WHAT, SPEIRS SHOOTING
THE PRISONERS
OR THE SERGEANT
IN HIS OWN PLATOON?
SERGEANT?
I DIDN'T
HEAR THAT ONE.
HE SHOT ONE OF
HIS OWN GUYS?
WELL, SUPPOSEDLY
THE GUY WAS DRUNK
AND REFUSED TO
GO ON A PATROL.
WHO KNOWS IF
IT'S TRUE?
WELL, I KNOW A GUY
WHO SAID AN EYEWITNESS
TOLD HIM THAT SPEIRS
HOSED THESE PRISONERS.
WHY?
WHAT FOR?
ON D-DAY.
SPEIRS COMES ACROSS THIS
GROUP OF KRAUT PRISONERS
DIGGING A HOLE
O SOME SUCH.
UNDER GUARD
AND ALL.
HE BREAKS OUT
A PACK OF SMOKES,
PASSES THEM OUT.
HE EVEN GIVES
'EM A LIGHT.
THEN, ALL OF
A SUDDEN,
HE SWINGS UP
HlS THOMPSON...
AND HE HOSES 'EM.
I MEAN, GODDAMN,
GIVES 'EM SMOKES FIRST?
MMM, YOU SEE THAT'S
WHY I DON'T BELIEVE
HE REALLY DID IT.
OH, YOU DON'T
BELIEVE IT?
I HEARD HE
DIDN'T DO IT.
OH, NO, NO,
IT WAS HIM ALRIGHT.
BUT IT WAS MORE
THAN EIGHT GUYS.
IT WAS MORE
LIKE 20.
HELL OF A SHOT.
ALL EXCEPT ONE GUY...
WHO HE LEFT ALONE.
WELL, ALL I KNOW,
FROM WHAT I HEARD,
HE TOOK THAT LAST 105 IN D-DAY
PRACTICALLY BY HIMSELF.
RUNNING THROUGH
MG FIRE LIKE A MANIAC.
YEAH, THAT
I DID SEE.
ON HIS OWN?
YEAH.
I DON'T CARE IF ANY OF
THE OTHER STUFF'S TRUE.
HEY, ALBERT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO TAKE
EVERYBODY'S WORD FOR IT.
I DIDN'T SEE
ANY OF IT.
LET'S GO, 1st PLATOON,
WEAPONS ON ME.
WE'RE MOVING OUT.
HEY, TAKE ALL
YOUR SMOKES.
ON YOUR FEET,
TACTICAL COLUMN.
FLANKERS, UP.
THAT MEANS YOU,
PRIVATE BLITHE.
COME ON, BLITHE,
GET UP.
HEY, LADS?
WHAT?
HOW FAR WE GOING?
OH, JESUS CHRIST,
FRANK, I DON'T KNOW.
UNTIL THEY
TELL US TO STOP.
HIGH GROUND.
THERE'S HIGH
GROUND UP AHEAD.
OKAY, GENIUS,
ANSWER ME THIS THEN:
WHY IS EASY COMPANY THE ONLY
COMPANY WHO'S EITHER AT
THE FRONT OF AN ADVANCE
OR, LIKE NOW,
EXPOSED AT THE FAR
EDGE OF THE LINE?
TO KEEP YOU
ON YOUR TOES.
NO, THAT'S NOT
WHAT I'M SAYING.
I'M SAYING THAT WE'RE
NEVER IN THE MIDDLE.
AND WE'RE THE FIFTH OF NINE
COMPANIES OF THIS REGIMENT.
"ABLE" THROUGH "ITEM".
THINK OF IT.
SEE THERE,
YOU SEE THAT?
( gunfire )
INCOMING!
CONTACT RIGHT!
GET IN
THE HEDGEROW!
SEE WHAT I MEAN?
LEFT, BRING IT
AROUND!
STAY LOW!
LADS, GET DOWN HERE
WITH THE RADIO NOW!
( singing )
( thundering )
AH!
WHAT HAVE THEY GOT
TO SING ABOUT?
FLASH!
THUNDER.
CATCHY TUNE...
AIN'T IT?
HEY, LIEUTENANT,
WHAT'S THE NEWS?
OH, SAME AS IT WAS
THIS AFTERNOON.
THEY'RE IN THEIR HEDGEROW,
WE'RE IN OURS.
SPELL ME
A MINUTE, SIR?
ARE YOU GONNA LET BLITHE
GET SOME SACK TIME?
MY BACK TEETH
ARE FLOATING.
GET BACK HERE
ASAP, MARTIN.
COUNT ON ME, SIR.
OH.
HOW YOU DOING,
BLITHE?
I'M OKAY, SIR.
WHAT HAPPENED AT
THE AID STATION TODAY?
DOC ROE,
HE CALLED IT
HYSTERICAL BLINDNESS.
NO, THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THEY SAID ON BASIC:
DEHYDRATION'S
A SOLDIER'S WORST ENEMY.
YEAH.
IT'S A GAME,
BLITHE.
THAT'S ALL.
HELL, WE'RE JUST
MOVING THE BALL FORWARD
ONE YARD AT A TIME.
NOTHING BUT A GAME.
WHAT IS, SIR?
THIS.
THE WHOLE THING.
NO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
JUST A GAME.
HARRY?
S2 SAID THE GERMANS
ONLY LEFT A COMPANY
TO DEFEND CARENTAN.
YEAH.
THE REST PULLED OUT
SOMETIME LAST NIGHT.
I KNEW THAT TOWN
WAS TOO EASY.
YEAH.
THEY REGROUPED
SOUTH OF TOWN.
MAY HAVE BEEN ON THEIR WAY
TO A COUNTERATTACK
WHEN WE RAN
INTO 'EM HERE.
STRENGTH UNKNOWN.
( gunfire )
THEY WANT
THE TOWN BACK.
AND WE'RE
IN THEIR WAY.
OF THEY DON'T
COME BEFORE THEN,
WE'RE ATTACKlNG AT
FIRST LIGHT 0530.
I'LL TELL THE MEN
TO FIX BAYONETS.
NOT MUCH OF
A LIMP.
I'LL SURVIVE.
HOW IS IT?
HURTS.
WAR IS HELL.
( snoring )
( whispering )
SMITH, WAKE UP.
COME ON, SMITH.
GET UP,
IT'S YOUR WATCH.
SMITH.
EASY, SMITH,
IT'S ME, TALBERT.
SMITH, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
THAT'S TALBERT.
GODDAMN.
OH, GOSH.
MEDIC!
I'M SIRRY,
I DIDN'T MEAN TO.
HE LOOKED
LIKE A KRAUT.
I DIDN'T KNOW
IT WAS HIM.
YEAH, I CAN
BREATHE.
LOOK AT ME,
LOOK AT ME.
CAN YOU BREATHE?
YEAH, I CAN
BREATHE!
I'M JUST GONNA PUT SOME
SULPHUR ON THE WIUND, FLOYD.
WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT?
SOUNDS LIKE IT'S COMING
FROM 3rd PLATOON.
YOU WANNA GET
SOME SLEEP?
I DON'T THINK,
I DON'T THINK I CAN.
THEN GO
TAKE A LOOK.
SARGE.
( groaning )
FLASH.
THUNDER, THUNDER!
LIEUTENANT SPEIRS, SIR.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING,
PRIVATE?
CHECK OUT
THE NOISE, SIR.
I JUST CAME
FROM THERE.
EVERYTHING'S
UNDER CONTROL.
YES, SIR.
GOT SOME NERVOUS PRIVATES
IN YOUR COMPANY.
WE DO, SIR.
YEAH, WE DO,
I CAN VOUCH FOR THAT.
THEY JUST DON'T SEE
HOW SIMPLE IT IS.
HOW SIMPLE
WHAT IS, SIR?
JUST DO WHAT
YOU HAVE TO DO.
LIKE YOU DID
IN D-DAY, SIR?
LIEUTENANT.
SIR, WHEN I LANDED
IN D-DAY,
I FOUND MYSELF lN A DITCH
ALL BY MYSELF.
I FELL ASLEEP.
I THINK IT WAS THESE
AIR-SICKNESS PILLS
THEY GAVE US.
WHEN I WOKE UP, I DIDN'T
REALLY TRY TO FIND MY UNIT...
TO FIGHT.
I JUST...
I JUST KINDA STAYED PUT.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
TROOPER?
BLITHE, SIR.
ALBERT BLITHE.
YOU KNOW WHY YOU HID
IN THAT DITCH, BLITHE?
I WAS SCARED.
WE'RE ALL SCARED.
YOU HID IN THAT DITCH BECAUSE
YOU THINK THERE'S STILL HOPE.
BUT, BLITHE, THE ONLY HOPE
YOU HAVE IS TO ACCEPT THE FACT
THAT YOU'RE
ALREADY DEAD,
AND THE SOONER
YOU ACCEPT THAT,
THE SOONER YOU'LL
BE ABLE TO FUNCTION
AS A SOLDIER'S
SUPPOSED TO FUNCTION.
WITHOUT MERCY,
WITHOUT CIMPASSION,
WITHOUT REMORSE.
ALL WAR DEPENDS
UPON IT.
GUYS, GOT
ANY SMOKES?
YOU WANT SOME OF
THIS CANDY SHOT?
NO, I'M ALRIGHT.
THE OUTPOST
GOT AMMO.
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
NO, WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEY'VE GOT.
WE MAY BE ATTACKlNG
A WEAKER FORCE,
POSSIBLY MORE
PARATROOPERS.
AND YOU KNOW
HOW THEY CAN BE
FIRE AND MANEUVER.
THAT'S THE NAME OF THE GAME,
DOG AND FOX COMPANIES
WILL BE ON OUR LEFT FLANK,
MOVING WITH US.
ANY QUESTIONS?
LET'S MAKE
'EM HOLLER.
IT'S 9:30 IN
THE EVENING BACK HOME.
MUST BE.
MORTAR!
INCOMING!
DOWN, DOWN, DOWN,
DOWN, DOWN!
GET THAT O.P. HERE!
TELL 'EM TO HOLD,
I'M CHECKING THE LINES.
ALL EASY STATIONS,
EASY SIX.
HOLD IN POSITION,
OVER.
GO, LOCK AND LOAD!
EASY SIX,
EASY RED SIX.
I'VE GOT MORTARS
ACROSS MY LINE.
NO SIGN OF
INFANTRY YET.
I'M PULLING
THE O.P. IN, OVER.
RIGHT PLUS 15,
CHARGE THREE.
RANGE, 600.
( gunfire )
COME ON, MOVE IT,
MOVE IT, HURRY!
WATCH FOR SlLHOUETTES
ON THE HORIZON!
KEEP LOW,
GO, GO, GO!
PERCINTE!
GET YOUR MEN
IN ORDER!
STAY LOW!
POUR IT AT 'EM,
PERCINTE.
TO YOUR LEFT.
KEEP GOING,
KEEP GOING.
KEEP IT UP!
I WANT FIRE
SUPERIORITY!
GUARNERE, KEEP 'EM
PINNED DOWN.
KEEP FIRING!
SIR, JUST REVERSE!
COVER THE CREST
OF THAT HlLL!
( screaming )
WHERE IN THE HELL
DID THEY COME FROM?
HOLY SHIT, THERE GOES
OUR LEFT FLANK.
SIR, DOG AND FOX
ARE PULLlNG BACK.
WHAT?
WHO GAVE THAT ORDER,
GODDAMNIT.
KEEP FIRING,
STAY LOW!
STAY LOW, KEEP FIRING,
PERCINTE.
COME ON, BLITHE!
STAND UP!
GET UP ON YOUR FEET,
SOLDIER.
GET UP, BLITHE.
THAT'S RIGHT,
BLITHE.
YOU CAN DO IT!
FIRE YOUR WEAPON,
BLITHE.
HIT THESE GODDAMN GERMANS,
BLITHE!
KEEP FIRING!
LET 'EM HAVE IT.
DON'T SLACK IT OFF.
LET 'EM HAVE IT,
BLITHE!
POUR IT ON 'EM,
GET SOME UP THERE!
MOVE IT!
LET'S GO, MCGRATH,
ON ME.
SHIFT YOUR
FIRE RIGHT.
DOWN, DOWN!
COME ON!
YOU'RE GONNA GET
ME KILLED, LIEUTENANT.
I KNEW YOU'D
GET ME KILLED.
DON'T FIRE TILL
I TELL YOU, MCGRATH.
I KNEW YOU WERE
GONNA GET ME KILLED.
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
NO, THAT'S TOO CLOSE!
BITCH, SONOFABITCH!
MEDIC!
GO NOW.
NOW, FIRE, MCGRATH!
FIRE!
COVERING FIRE!
KEEP FIRING SOUTH.
YOU HIT
A HOME RUN, HUH?
SMITH,
I'VE BEEN HIT.
JUST GET ME
OUT OF HERE!
MEDIC!
YOU OKAY?
MOVE IT, MOVE IT!
ROUNDS COMPLETE!
SKIP, MORE AMMO!
GO, GO!
ON MY WAY.
MEDIC!
JESUS,
WHAT WAS THAT?
SHERMANS.
WELL, HELLO
2nd ARMORED.
( laughing )
THAT'S RIGHT,
YOU SORRY ASSES.
RUN!
OH, YOU BEAUTIFUL
BABIES, YOU!
LET'S GO!
POUR IT ON 'EM!
LET 'EM HAVE IT,
COME ON!
CHECK IT OUT,
SHERMANS.
ABOUT DAMN TIME.
COME ON!
COME ON.
HEY, BUDDY?
HEY, BUDDY,
YOU OKAY?
LOOKS LIKE YOU FELLAS
HAD A HECK OF A FIGHT.
( soldier )
MOVE FORWARD ON
THE RIGHT FLANK.
WE NEED TO KNOW
WHAT'S IN THERE.
I DON'T KNOW WHO
THE HELL TO SEND.
ASK FOR VOLUNTEERS.
I HATE ASKING
FOR VOLUNTEERS.
THEN PICK THEM.
NEED TO TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT FARMHOUSE.
WHO WANTS TO GO?
I'LL GO.
ANYBODY ELSE?
MARTIN, DUKEMAN,
YOU JUST VOLUNTEERED.
HUBBA-HUBBA.
I'LL BE LEAD.
BLITHE'S LEAD SCOUT,
MOVE OUT.
HARRY...
WHAT EXACTLY ARE YOU DOING
WITH YOUR RESERVE CHUTE?
YOU BEEN HAULING
THAT THING AROUND
EVER SINCE WE JUMPED?
GONNA SEND IT
TO KITTY WHEN WE
GET BACK TO ENGLAND.
SILK.
FIGURE IT'LL MAKE A GOOD
WEDDING DRESS, YOU KNOW?
WHAT WITH
RATIONING AND ALL.
JEEZ, HARRY, I NEVER
WOULD HAVE GUESSED.
WHAT?
THAT I'M SO
SENTIMENTAL?
NO, THAT YOU THINK WE'RE GONNA
MAKE IT BACK TO ENGLAND.
OKAY.
( gunshot )
HERE WE GO AGAIN.
COVERING FIRE,
COVERING FIRE!
GO, GO!
HANG IN THERE,
BLITHE.
COME ON.
KEEP MOVING DOWN!
MEDIC!
TOP WINDOW RIGHT!
HANG IN THERE.
MEDIC!
WE NEED A MEDIC
DOWN HERE!
CEASE FIRE,
CEASE FIRE!
TAKE IT EASY,
BLITHE.
TAKE IT EASY.
COME ON, DUKE,
COME ON.
MOVE, MOVE.
COMING THROUGH,
GIVE ME ROOM.
OUTTA MY WAY.
I GOT IT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
SNIPER.
ALRIGHT, BLITHE,
I GOT YOU.
NlCE AND EASY,
NlCE AND EASY.
THEY'RE PULLING US
OFF THE FRONT LINE.
NOW?
TO A FIELD CAMP
NORTH OF UTAH BEACH.
HOT FOOD.
AND SHOWERS.
THEN BACK
TO ENGLAND.
HARRY.
HOW'S THE LEG?
STIFF.
SORE.
THEY WANT ME
TO TAKE IT EASY
FOR A FEW DAYS.
YEAH, YOU SHOULD.
TALKED TO
COLONEL SINK.
SAID HE
APPRECIATED EASY
HOLDING THE LINE.
HMM.
SAID GENERAL TAYLOR
WAS PLEASED.
WELL, THAT'S WHY
I CAME TO FRANCE
TO PLEASE
GENERAL TAYLOR.
HMM, YEAH.
( male )
IN GRATEFUL ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
OF THE BLOOD SHED
IN THE SERVICE OF
YOUR COUNTRY,
IT IS MY HONOR
TO PRESENT YOU
WITH THE ORDER OF
THE PURPLE HEART.
THANK YOU, SIR.
HOW MANY'S
THAT MAKE?
TWO?
THREE?
YOU HAVE NO SHAME.
HEY, I GOT ONE HOLE
IN MY SHOULDER,
A SECOND
IN MY CALF.
THEN THERE'S THE BOIL IN
MY SHIN THAT HAD TO BE LANCED.
AND HE ONLY
GETS ONE.
( male )
THIS lS GREAT
( laughing )
SHE FANCIED ME,
AOTON.
JESUS CHRIST!
IT'S GOOD TO
BE ALIVE!
JESUS CHRIST,
THAT SURE WAS CLOSE.
NAH, MISSED HIM
BY A MILE.
HEY, HOOBLER.
BE QUIET
FOR THE MAN.
WHAT?
"THE NIGHT OF
THE BAYONET".
THE NIGHT WAS FILLED
WITH DARK AND COLD,
WHEN SERGEANT TALBERT--
THE STORY'S TOLD,
PULLED ON HIS PONCHO
AND HEADED OUT,
TO CHECK THE LINES
DRESSED LIKE A KRAUT.
WHY IS EVERYINE IN SUCH
A HURRY TO GET BACK, HUH?
HOSPITAL FOOD
DON'T SUIT YOU?
WE DON'T NEED
YOU ANYMORE,
UPON A TROOPER
OUR HERO CAME,
FAST ASLEEP,
HE CALLED HIS NAME.
OH, SMITH!
GET UP, IT'S TIME,
TO TAKE YOUR TURN
OUT ON THE LINE.
DO YOU GUYS HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT HE'S TALKING ABOUT?
"THE NIGHT OF
THE BAYONET".
WHATEVER THAT IS.
... SO VERY WEARY,
CRACKED AN EYE,
ALL RED AND BLEARY,
GRABBED HIS RIFLE,
HE DID NOT TARRY.
HEARING FLOYD
BUT SEEING JERRY.
WAY TO GO, SMITHY.
"IT'S ME", CRIED TAB,
"DON'T DO IT",
AND YET SMITH CHARGED,
TOUT DE SUITE,
WITH BAYONET
HE LUNGED, HE THRUST,
BOTH HIGH AND LOW,
AND SKEWERED
THE BOY FROM KOKOMO.
I'M HEADlNG
BACK TO BARRACKS.
YOU HEFFRON?
YEAH.
WHERE YOU FROM?
WHO'S ASKING?
YOU FROM
PHILADELPHIA?
SOUTH PHILLY, YEAH.
AH.
I COULD TELL.
17th STREET.
FRONT STREET.
HEY.
COME HERE,
SIT DOWN.
HEY, YOU KNOW A GUY NAMED
JOHNNY WAYLIN?
YEAH, I KNOW
JOHNNY.
YEAH, TAR-HEAD, YEAH.
SINCE YOU WEREN'T
WOUNDED BY THE ENEMY,
AND THUS DIDN'T QUALIFY
FOR A PURPLE HEART,
WE'VE TAKEN MATTERS
INTO OUR OWN HANDS.
TAB, THIS IS
FOR YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I COULD HAVE SHOT
THE KID A DOZEN TIMES.
YEAH, RIGHT.
I JUST DIDN'T THINK
WE COULD SPARE A MAN.
COUPLE OF
ANNOUNCEMENTS, MEN.
FIRST, LISTEN UP.
THE TRAINING EXERCISE
SCHEDULED FOR 2200
HAS BEEN CANCELLED.
OH, YEAH.
SECONDLY...
ALL PASSES ARE
HEREBY REVOKED.
WE'RE HEADING
BACK TO FRANCE.
SO, PACK UP
ALL YOUR GEAR.
WE WILL NOT BE RETURNING
TO ENGLAND, BOYS.
ANYONE WHO HAS NOT
MADE OUT A WILL,
GO TO THE SUPPLY OFFICE.
THE TRUCKS DEPART
FOR MEMBURY AT 0700.
AS YOU WERE.
HELLO?
OH.
GOOD MORNING,
MISS LAMB.
UM, SORRY TO
BOTHER YOU SO EARLY.
THAT'S ALRIGHT.
PRIVATE...
MALARKEY.
COME IN.
ACTUALLY, IT'S
SERGEANT MALARKEY NOW, MA'AM.
I JUST GOT PRIMOTED.
OH, LOVELY.
I EXPECT YOU'LL BE
WANTING YOUR LAUNDRY.
I HEARD THE TRUCKS
RUMBLING BY ALL NIGHT.
I GUESS THE YANKS MUST BE
ON THEIR WAY OFF AGAIN.
YES, MA'AM.
LOOKS LIKE FOR
GOOD THIS TIME.
I'M SORRY TO
HEAR THAT.
ER, TWO SHIRTS,
TWO PAIRS OF TROUSERS,
LIGHT STARCH.
TWO BOB
AND TUPPENCE, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
WOULD YOU, ER,
LIKE A CUP OF TEA?
I'VE GOT
THE WATER BOILING.
NO, NO, THANK YOU.
I'M IN A HELL OF A...
BIT OF A HURRY BUT,
ER, THANK YOU ANYWAY.
IH, UM, PRIVATE?
YES, MA'AM.
LIEUTENANT MEEHAN'S
ONE OF YOURS, ISN'T HE?
I HOPE HE HASN'T
FORGOTTEN HIS LAUNDRY.
I'LL TAKE IT.
THANK YOU.
YOU, UM, YOU COULDN'T
BE A DEAR
AND HELP ME WITH
A FEW OTHERS, COULD YOU?
ER, LET'S SEE.
SERGEANT EVANS.
PRIVATE MOYA.
BLOWZER.
GRAY.
MILLER.
OWEN.
COLLINS,
ELLIOT,
BLITHE.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOX OFFICE
A Division of TIME WARNER
COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBI COMMUNICATIONS CENTER