Captions made possible by
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
IF YOU'RE A LEADER,
YOU LEAD THE WAY.
NOT JUST, ER,
ON THE EASY ONES.
YOU TAKE
THE TOUGH ONES, TOO.
A GOOD LEADER
HAS TO UNDERSTAND
THE PEOPLE THAT ARE,
THAT ARE UNDER HlM,
UNDERSTAND THElR NEEDS,
THElR DESlRES OR HOW
THEY THlNK A LlTTLE BlT.
IT SEEMED LlKE HE ALWAYS
MADE THE RlGHT DEClSlONS
ALONG THE WAY.
HE WAS A REAL SOLDlER.
LlKE SOME OF
THE OFFlCERS, ER,
I DON'T THlNK l'D
FOLLOW THEM lNTO WATER,
BUT, HE WAS, HE
WAS ONE OF THE BEST.
HE WENT RlGHT lN THERE
AND HE DlDN'T KNOW.
HE NEVER THOUGHT OF
NOT BElNG FlRST,
OR SENDlNG SOMEBODY
lN HlS PLACE.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW HE SURVlVED...
BUT HE DlD.
( panting )
LEW?
WAKE UP.
THEY WANT US
BACK AT REGlMENT.
C'MON, NlO,
GET UP.
LET'S GO.
C'MON, SOMETHlNG'S UP,
STRAYER'S ORDERS.
OKAY, GO AHEAD,
l'LL BE RlGHT DOWN.
LET'S GO, C'MON,
YOU GOT 10 MlNUTES.
GO AWAY.
C'MON, C'MON BlG GUY,
LET'S GO.
AH, LEAVE ME ALONE.
OKAY.
C'MON.
GODAMMlT.
OH, THAT'S MY OWN PlSS,
FOR CHRlSSAKE.
SONOFABlTCH.
I MEAN, WE'RE THE ONLY
UNlT lN THE GROUP
THAT'S GOT THE
GERMANS ON THE GERMAN
SlDE OF THE RHlNE.
IF WE'D HAVE
TAKEN ANTWERP,
AND l'M NOT SAYlNG THAT
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN EASY,
WE WOULD BE OVER
THE RlVER, WELL
SUPPLlED,
AND HAVE THE KRAUTS
ON THElR HEELS.
NOW, lF I CAN JUST
GET lKE ON THE PHONE.
ARE YOU
LlSTENlNG TO ME?
HANGlN' ON EVERY WORD.
HEY, MOOSE,
YOU TOO?
YEAH, WHATEVER'S
GOlN' ON, SlNK
lS NOT HAPPY.
NlOON, HEYLlGER.
MEET COLONEL DOBlE,
BRlTlSH 1st AlRBORNE.
CAPTAlN NlOON lS OUR
2nd BATTALlON S-2.
THAT'S 1ST LlEUTENANT
MOOSE HEYLlGER.
IT APPEARS THE BRlTlSH
LOST 8,000 MEN
WHEN MARKET GARDEN
FELL ON lTS ASS,
WHlCH lS WHY
COLONEL DOBlE
HAS BEEN TASKED
WlTH COORDlNATlNG
SOME KlND OF
RESCUE OPERATlON
FOR THE RED DEVlLS
WHO WERE TRAPPED
WHEN ARNHEM FELL.
DUTCH RESlSTANCE
ARE HARBORlNG 140
OF MY CHAPS HERE,
JUST OUTSlDE A
JERRY-HELD TOWN 15
MlLES NORTH OF THE RlVER.
THEY'LL MAKE
THElR WAY TO
THE RlVERBANK
AND ASSEMBLE
lN THE WOODS
HERE, TONlGHT.
( male )
PlCK A TEAM
FROM "EASY COMPANY"
AND GET THEM BACK ACROSS
THE RHlNE AS FAST AS POSSlBLE.
140 MEN?
CANADlAN ENGlNEERS
HAVE SUPPLlED
SlO BOATS.
THE RENDEZVOUS
POlNT lS lSOLATED
AND LANDABLE.
I SWAM lT
MYSELF LAST NlGHT.
AT APPROOlMATELY
0030 HOURS
THEY WlLL SlGNAL
THE "V" FOR VlCTORY WlTH
A HAND-HELD RED TORCH.
THAT WOULD BE
A HAND-HELD
RED FLASHLlGHT.
ALRlGHT, WE'LL
CALL THlS THlNG
"OPERATlON PEGASUS".
BOB, YOUR 2nd
BATTALlON lS
ON THE SPOT.
GET lT DONE.
CAPTAlN NlOON,
ASSlST COLONEL DOBlE
lN EVERY WAY POSSlBLE.
IF YOU NEED
ANYTHlNG AT ALL,
YOU COME TO ME.
I CAN HARDLY
ASK FOR MORE.
CAPTAlN WlNTERS?
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOUR
ENDORSEMENT ON THE MARKET
GARDEN AFTER ACTlON REPORT,
OR THE UPDATED
BATTALlON "T.O." AND
"E", WHY lS THAT?
I'LL HAVE THEM AT
C.P. BY 1300, SlR.
AND I WANT AN lNVENTORY
ON WHATEVER MATERlAL
THE BRlTlSH 43rd
LEFT BEHlND,
RATlONS, MEDlCAL
SUPPLlES, TRANSPORT.
AN lNVENTORY,
YES, SlR.
DlCK.
I'M STlLL WAlTlNG
TO WRlTE ClTATlONS ON THAT
FlVE OCTOBER OPERATlON.
I NEED YOUR REPORT.
THE REPORT, YES, SlR.
LlGHT A FlRE
UNDER lT, DlCK.
SlR.
NOW, GODAMMlT,
WE ASKED FOR
THlS YESTERDAY,
AND HERE lT lS
TODAY, A DAY LATE
AND A DOLLAR SHORT.
ENEMY DlSPOSlTlON
AND MAPS lN THE S-2.
WE SHOULD HAVE
A LOOK AT THAT.
AND YOU SAY
THERE'S ABOUT A
HUNDRED OF 'EM?
( male )
THlS lS lT, BOYS.
GET ACROSS THE RlVER,
ACROSS THE FlELD
AND OVER THE DlKE.
THAT'S A LOT OF
TERRlTORY TO COVER.
WHERE'D YOU WANT
US TO GO?
YOU HASHEY,
YOU GET THE
PENTHOUSE.
THANK YOU.
WE'RE UP TOP.
HOW BAD DOES lT GET?
YOU'LL FlND OUT.
WELL, THAT'S A LOT
OF TERRlTORY TO COVER.
A COUPLE OF REGULAR
G.I. JOE'S, HUH?
YOU SAlD lT.
C'MON.
NEW GUYS GlVlNG THE
REPLACEMENTS THE WHAT
FOR, AND WHY lS.
I SWEAR ONE OF THEM'S
NEVER SHAVED.
YEAH, KlDS.
THlS lS A HELL
OF A DOG, TAB.
THANK YOU,
THERE YOU GO.
WHAT'D YOU CALL lT, TAB?
TRlGGER.
THAT'S GOOD,
I LlKE THAT, TRlGGER.
GOT ANYTHlNG
ON THlS?
NO, lT'S ALL QUlET.
WE'VE GOT PENETRATlON!
ALLEY'S HURT,
WE NEED THE DOC.
ALRlGHT,
GET HlM ON THE TABLE.
YEAH, lT'S ALLEY.
ALRlGHT,
I GOT THlS, EASY.
ALLEY, YOU'RE
GONNA BE OKAY.
C'MON, BOYLE,
GET DOC ROE.
WHERE AM l?
SOMETHlNG HAPPENED,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE WAS lT?
CROSSROADS, WHERE
THE ROAD CROSSES THE DlKE.
IF lT WASN'T
FOR YOUR
LOUD MOUTH,
THEY'D HAVE
NEVER KNOWN
WE WAS HERE.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT,
JOE, BACK OFF.
LESNlEWSKl, SEND
A RUNNER FOR
LlEUTENANT WELSH.
LlEUTENANT,
ASSEMBLE ME A SQUAD.
YES, SlR, FlRST SQUAD,
ON YOUR FEET!
WEAPONS AND
AMMO ONLY!
GlVE ME ROOM.
LET'S MOVE!
LET'S GO, LET'S GO!
BOYLE, GET THE BOOTS OFF,
ELEVATE THE LEG.
LlEBGOTT,
USE THE SULPHUR.
ALRlGHT, LET'S GET THlS
DONE QUlCKLY, WE GOTTA MOVE,
NOT TOO MUCH.
HEY, ALLEY.
( gunshots )
MG-42?
YEAH.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE THEY SHOOTlN' AT?
WHAT'S DOWN
THAT ROAD?
REGlMENTAL
HEADQUARTERS.
BUT THAT'S
THREE MlLES AWAY.
WHY ARE THEY GlVlNG AWAY
THElR POSlTlON?
THEY AlN'T AS SMART
AS ME AND YOU?
I THlNK l'LL
CHECK lT OUT ANYWAY.
HOLD HERE,
WAlT FOR MY SlGNAL.
YES, SlR.
HOLDlNG HERE,
l'M WAlTlN'
FOR A SlGNAL.
( gunshots )
THlS lS OUR
FALLBACK POSlTlON, HERE.
MORTARS, DEPLOY HERE.
FlRST SQUAD, ON ME.
GO.
( distant shouting )
SECOND ON THE RlGHT.
FlRST ON THE RlGHT.
THlRD ON THE RlGHT.
NAlL THE MACHlNE-GUN.
SECOND ON THE LEFT,
FlRST ON THE LEFT.
WAlT FOR MY SlGNAL.
PREPARE TO FlRE.
TWO ROUNDS,
A.G., QUlCK.
FALL BACK!
FlRE.
HlGGlNS!
HANDFUL OF KRAUTS,
BASED ON THE DlKE, 12:00!
HOW MANY KRAUTS
ARE LEFT UP THERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT WE GOT
SEVEN lN ONE BLOW.
BRlNG ON BOYLE
AND PERCONTE, GO!
C'MON, FALL BACK.
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE.
SUPPRESSlNG FlRE!
HASHEY, GARClA,
FOLLOW ME.
HARRY, TELL PEACOCK
TO BRlNG UP THE BALANCE
OF 1 st PLATOON
ON THE DOUBLE!
AND ANOTHER
MACHlNE-GUN
SQUAD, OVER.
DUKEMAN!
GO GET THAT MACHlNE-GUN
ON THE RlGHT FLANK, GO!
CHRlSTENSON!
FUCK, DUKEMAN'S DOWN.
SlR, THE BALANCE
OF 1st PLATOON ARE HERE.
GORDON AND MORE
BROUGHT ANOTHER 30 CAL.
SlR.
THEY'RE BEHlND
A SOLlD ROADWAY
EMBANKMENT.
WE'RE lN A DlTCH.
THEY CAN OUTFLANK US
ALONG THE DlKE,
AND CATCH US OUT HERE
AS SOON AS THEY
FlGURE THAT OUT.
SO, HOW MANY
KRAUTS ARE WE
TALKlNG ABOUT?
WELL, THERE'S
A FERRY CROSSlNG HERE,
SO, lT COULD BE
A WHOLE BATTALlON,
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
OKAY, WHAT ARE
YOUR ORDERS?
WE GOT NO CHOlCE.
HERE lT lS,
TALBERT, YOU'LL TAKE
10 MEN ALONG THE DlKE.
PEACOCK, YOU'LL
TAKE 10 MEN ALONG
THE LEFT FLANK.
I'LL TAKE 10
UP THE MlDDLE,
SO FOLLOW ME.
QUESTlONS?
GO!
( knocking )
ENTER.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
l'M STlLL DOlNG THlS.
WHAT, DRlNKlNG?
NO, HlDlNG lT
lN YOUR FOOT-LOCKER.
I'M A CAPTAlN,
FOR CHRlSSAKE.
WELL, WHY
DON'T YOU...
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GlVE lT UP?
DRlNKlNG?
NO, HlDlNG lT
lN MY FOOT-LOCKER,
YOU'RE A CAPTAlN
FOR PETE'S SAKE.
MAYBE YOU'RE RlGHT,
MAYBE THlS lS THE PERFECT
PLACE TO STOP DRlNKlNG.
RlGHT HERE ON THE BUSlNESS-END
OF THE ALLlED ADVANCE.
CHEERS.
DlCK, YOU KNOW,
THAT'S NOT LlTERATURE.
YOU JUST KEEP lT SlMPLE.
TRY WRlTlNG lT lN
THE FlRST PERSON
PLURAL, YOU KNOW.
SAY "WE" A LOT.
THANKS FOR THE TlP.
( male )
FlO BAYONETS.
GO ON THE RED SMOKE.
NO, WAlT,
WAlT FOR THE SlGNAL
JESUS.
( shouting )
C'MON, BOYS!
FOUR.
HOLY SHlT!
IT'S A WHOLE
OTHER COMPANY!
NO SHlT!
EASY BEAVER TO
EASY MlNOR.
RElNFORCE "EASY"
AT PHASE ONE YELLOW.
PLUS ONE,
STRlKE THREE.
FlRE CONCENTRATlON CHARLlE.
DROP 200,
LEFT 1 00.
REPEAT, PLUS ONE,
STRlKE THREE.
FlRE CONCENTRATlON, CHARLlE,
DROP 200, LEFT 100.
KRAUTS lN THE OPEN,
FlRE FOR EFFECT, OVER.
HERAUS,
HANDE HOCH.
SCHNELL, SCHNELL!
WHAT'S HE SAYlNG?
HE'S TELLlNG ME
THAT THEY'RE POLlSH.
POLlSH, DON'T
YOU BELlEVE lT.
THERE AlN'T NO POLES
lN THE SS!
MOVE!
JESUS CHRlST.
OH, SHlT!
LUZ, SEND LlGHTNlNG
A CONTACT REPORT.
BOYLE!
GET UP THERE WHERE YOU
CAN SPOT THE FALL
OF THOSE ROUNDS, GO!
RlGHT, SlR.
INCOMlNG ROGUES!
"EASY COMPANY",
TAKE COVER!
BOYLE'S HlT!
JESUS CHRlST,
THEY GOT ME.
TAKE COVER,
lT'S GERMAN ARTlLLERY.
GET BOYLE, HE'S DOWN,
C'MON, HELP ME.
JESUS, CAPTAlN,
THEY'RE SS.
JOE?
JOE, KNOCK lT OFF.
DAMNlT, WHAT?
YOU'RE BLEEDlNG.
AH, lT'S NOTHlNG, CAP'N.
I WANT YOU TO
TAKE THESE PRlSONERS
BACK TO BATTALlON C.P.
GET YOURSELF CLEANED UP.
YES, SlR.
C'MON, KRAUT BOYS.
JOE?
YEAH.
DROP YOUR AMMO.
WHAT?
ARE YOU KlDDlNG ME,
WHAT ARE YOU DOlNG?
GlVE ME YOUR WEAPON.
CAP'N.
YOU HAVE ONE ROUND.
JOHNNY, HOW MANY
PRlSONERS DO WE HAVE?
WE GOT 1 1 RlGHT NOW, SlR.
OKAY.
YOU DROP A PRlSONER,
THE REST'LL JUMP YOU.
I WANT ALL
PRlSONERS BACK AT
BATTALlON C.P. ALlVE.
YES, SlR.
"THEY GOT ME",
YOU BELlEVE THAT?
YOU BELlEVE I SAlD THAT?
CAN YOU MAKE lT
BACK TO C.P.?
YEAH.
ALRlGHT, I WlLL SEE
YOU SOMEPLACE ELSE.
TAKE THESE TO BATTALlON.
SPLlT 'EM UP.
YES, SlR.
UP, ALRlGHT.
HERE YOU ARE.
WE HAD 'EM ON THE RUN.
HOW'S THAT?
THE GERMANS WERE
FLOODlNG BACK TOWARDS
THE FERRY CROSSlNG
WHEN WE HlT 'EM
WlTH ARTlLLERY.
IT WAS LlKE
A TURKEY SHOOT.
THEN THEY HlT US
WlTH THElR 88s,
ZEROED lN ON
THlS CROSSROAD.
NOW WE WERE
LUCKY, THOUGH.
ONLY 22 WOUNDED.
LUCKY?
CAPTAlN WlNTERS?
HE'S RlGHT DOWN
THERE, SlR.
ALRlGHT, CARRY ON.
( male )
ALRlGHT, KRAUTS,
HANDE HOCH.
22 WOUNDED, HUH?
YOU OKAY?
YEAH, ONE KlLLED.
WHO?
DUKEMAN.
WELL, YOU'RE LOOKlNG AT
TWO FULL COMPANlES
OF SS OUT THERE.
ABOUT 50 DEAD, PROBABLY
ANOTHER HUNDRED WOUNDED.
SEVEN BACK lN
THE REGlMENTAL CAGE
PLUS A WHOLE STRlNG
OF 'EM UP THERE.
THAT'S NOT BAD
FOR DUKEMAN.
YOU GOT A DRlNK?
OF WATER?
YEAH, lT'S WATER.
THANKS.
OKAY?
( Sink )
363rd VOLKSGRENADlER HlT
OPHEUSDEN EARLY THlS MORNlNG,
ABOUT THE SAME TlME
YOUR SS MADE A RUN
FOR MY C.P.
DOWN THE ROAD.
3rd BATTALlON GOT
THE HELL BEAT OUT OF 'EM.
HOLLY HORTON WAS KlLLED.
MAJOR HORTON'S DEAD?
THEY HlT 2nd BATTALlON
C.P. IN FORCE.
HE WAS ORGANlZlNG
THE DEFENSE.
CAPTAlN NlOON, EOCUSE
US FOR JUST A MlNUTE.
HOW'D YOU FEEL ABOUT
HANDLlNG THE BATTALlON?
SlR?
I'M MOVlNG YOU UP TO
EOECUTlVE OFFlCER
OF 2nd BATTALlON.
COLONEL STRAYER lS...
WELL, HE COULD
USE SOME HELP.
WELL, I KNOW l
COULD HANDLE THEM
lN THE FlELD, SlR.
THAT'S RlGHT, DlCK.
YOU'RE A SOLlD TACTlClAN
AND A GOOD LEADER.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT
ADMlNlSTRATlON.
WHO DO YOU THlNK'LL BE
TAKlNG OVER "EASY", SlR?
MOOSE HEYLlGER CAN
COMMAND "EASY COMPANY".
LlEUTENANT HEYLlGER
WOULD BE MY CHOlCE, SlR.
GOOD.
YOU PACK YOUR GEAR
AND C'MON UP TO
BATTALlON C.P.
YES, SlR.
WOULD YOU LlKE
SOME COFFEE, SlR?
YEAH, THANKS, DOC.
ALRlGHT.
( Nixon)
HEY, DlCK!
FlNlSH YOUR NOVEL YET?
THAT'S A LOT OF HOMEWORK.
AND I THOUGHT
EOECUTlVE OFFlCER WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE A FUN JOB.
WHO ARE YOU?
ZlELlNSKl, SlR.
WHO lS HE?
ZlELlNSKl,
MY ORDERLY.
( whistling )
WELL, RANK DOES
HAVE lTS PRlVlLEGES.
ORDERLY, HUH?
I SUPPOSE YOU DO STUFF
LlKE GET COFFEE?
CAN DO, SlR.
BLACK, NO SUGAR.
AND A BACON SANDWlCH.
WHAT, YOU
WANT SOMETHlNG?
BACON SANDWlCH.
YOU CAN GlVE THAT
TO COLONEL SlNK
WlTH MY COMPLlMENTS.
ALL THAT FOR
TWO PAGES, HUH?
GUESS THAT MEANS
THAT'S GONNA
TAKE A WHlLE.
YEAH, lT lS,
YOU WANT A JOB?
THERE lT lS.
I THlNK SOMEBODY WlSHES
HE WERE BACK lN CHARGE
OF "EASY COMPANY", MOOSE.
ARE YOU TWO JUST
HERE TO GLOAT?
NO, JUST RUB lT
lN A LlTTLE BlT.
MOOSE lS GONNA
LEAD HlS FlRST MlSSlON
AS COMPANY COMMANDER.
OPERATlON PEGASUS
lS SET TO GO OFF.
I THOUGHT I MlGHT
GlVE YOU THE HEADS UP.
PEGASUS, YEAH,
YEAH, GREAT.
EVERYBODY KNOW
THElR JOB?
WE'VE DRlLLED WlTH
THE BOATS ALL DAY.
LlEUTENANT WELSH
lS COMlNG ALONG,
AND THE CANADlAN ENGlNEERS.
COLONEL DOBlE
KNOWS HlS STUFF.
KNOW HOW MANY TlMES
YOU WANNA CROSS THE RlVER?
IF THERE REALLY
ARE 140 BRlTS lN
HlDlNG OVER THERE,
THREE TRlPS.
SPEED lS THE KEY,
WHAT TlME'S JUMP-OFF?
WE'LL BE AT THE FAR SlDE
OF THE RHlNE AT ZERO 100.
SPEED lS THE KEY.
KEEP MOVlNG
AND LEAD THE WAY.
DlCK.
"EASY'S" lN
GOOD HANDS.
YEAH.
YEAH, RlGHT,
WELL, HANG TOUGH.
I COULD SAY
THE SAME TO YOU.
GOOD LUCK, MOOSE.
CAPTAlN.
AH, NlO?
YEAH.
ARE WE SURE ON THE
lNTELLlGENCE OF THlS?
WELL, I THlNK
lT'S PRETTY GOOD.
IS "EASY" WALKlNG lNTO
ANOTHER COMPANY OF GERMANS,
NO ONE CAN SEE?
WHY DON'T WE ASK MOOSE
WHEN HE GETS BACK?
RlGHT, YEAH.
OH, lF, ER, THEY DO
RUN lNTO ANY TROUBLE,
YOU'LL LET ME KNOW?
YEAH.
YOU RUN lNTO ANY
BACON SANDWlCH, DO
THE SAME, ALRlGHT?
YEAH.
LlNE SECURE, SlR.
FALL BACK lNTO
POSlTlON, PRlVATE.
YES, SlR.
I GOT THE 30 CAL.
ON THE LEFT FLANK.
EOTEND lT OUT
TO THE LEFT,
10 YARDS.
SO, COLONEL,
WHERE ARE THEY?
LElCESTER,
C'MON lN.
WELCOME BACK, SlR.
GOOD TO BE BACK.
HEYLlGER,
506 OF THE
101st AlRBORNE.
NEVER THOUGHT l'D BE
SO GLAD TO SEE A BLOODY YANK.
YOUR SHOW, COLONEL.
I'LL BE BACK SHORTLY.
GO.
BOATS ARE
ALL SECURE, SlR.
BULL.
THE BRlTS ARE
ON THE WAY,
PASS THE WORD.
( Zielinski )
SlR, YOU MlSSED
A SlGNATURE, HERE.
MOOSE HEYLlGER?
THAT'S ME, SlR.
GOD BLESS
YOU, MY MAN.
WE'RE READY TO
GO, SlR, WHERE'S
THE REST OF YOU?
RlGHT.
AND HERE WE ALL ARE.
WELL, LET'S GO.
WAHAl, MOHAMMED!
( together )
MOOSE HEYLlGER
AND THE AMERlCAN 1 01 st,
HAVE DONE THE RED DEVlLS
A GREAT SERVlCE,
MAKlNG lT POSSlBLE
FOR US TO RETURN,
AND FlGHT THE ENEMY
ON ANOTHER DAY.
TO "EASY COMPANY"...
VlCTORY AND CURRAHEE.
( together )
CURRAHEE!
( Winters )
wAS ONLY "EASY'S" C.O. FOR FOUR MONTHS, MOOs
BEFORE THAT lT
WAS MEEHAN'S COMPANY,
AND BEFORE THAT SOBEL'S.
YEAH, BUT YOU'RE
THE ONLY COMBAT COMMANDER
THEY'VE EVER KNOWN,
AND l'M FROM
ANOTHER COMPANY.
YOU KNOW WHERE
THEY CAME FROM,
YOU KNOW WHAT
THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH.
JUST HANG TOUGH.
TRAlN YOUR NEW PLATOON
LEADERS, AND TRUST
YOUR NONCOMS.
( Man )
HALT!
IT'S MOOSE.
HOLD YOUR FlRE!
OKAY, BUDDY.
OH, MY GOD.
SEND FOR
LlEUTENANT WELSH.
STAY AWAKE ON ME,
STAY AWAKE ON ME, MOOSE.
HERE, LOOK lN MY EYES.
SEND FOR
LlEUTENANT WELSH, NOW!
OKAY, OKAY.
I'M SORRY, SlR,
l'M SO SORRY.
I DlDN'T KNOW,
JESUS CHRlST.
WHERE ARE YOU
FROM, TROOPER?
WYOMlNG, SlR.
WELL, YOU'RE A LONG WAY
FROM HOME, PRlVATE.
STRETCHER!
I GOT HlM, HARRY.
YOU GlVE HlM,
MORPHlNE?
YEAH.
HOW MUCH?
OH, I CAN'T REMEMBER,
TWO, THREE SYRETTES MAYBE.
THREE SYRETTES MAYBE?
YEAH.
WERE YOU
TRYlNG TO KlLL HlM?
I THlNK lT WAS TWO.
YOU DON'T THlNK lT MlGHT BE
lMPORTANT TO LET ME KNOW
HOW MUCH MEDlCATlON
THE MAN HAS HAD, HUH?
'CAUSE I DO NOT SEE
ONE SYRETTE ON THE
MAN'S JACKET.
I'M SORRY, DOC.
SURE lS A GOOD THlNG
HE'S A BlG MAN.
MAYBE HE'LL
STAND A CHANCE.
HE WAS lN A LOT OF
PAlN, DOC, WE DlDN'T
KNOW WHAT TO DO.
YEAH, WELL,
YOU OUGHTA.
YOU ARE OFFlCERS,
YOU ARE GROWNUPS,
YOU OUGHTA KNOW.
ALRlGHT, LET'S GO,
C'MON, MOVE lT!
( male )
MAMA, MAMA, CAN'T YOU SEE?
( together )
( male )
WHAT THE AlRBORNE'S DONE TO ME.
( together )
ONCE MORE.
( male )
ABOUT FACE.
FORWARD MARCH.
( Winters )
"EASY" STlLL HAS ONLY
65 PERCENT STRENGTH,
AND MOST OF THOSE
ARE REPLACEMENTS,
INCLUDlNG
THElR NEW C.O.
( Nixon )
HOW'S LlEUTENANT
DlKE DOlNG?
THREE WEEKS lN HOLLAND,
THE GUYS ARE ALREADY
CALLlNG HlM FOOHOLE NORMAN.
WELL, THEY'RE TALKlNG
ABOUT A MlD-MARCH ACTlON
AT THE EARLlEST,
SO, WE TRAlN THE GUYS
FOR THREE MONTHS,
WE JUMP lNTO BERLlN,
WE END THE WAR.
THE ONLY THlNG HOLDlNG
TOGETHER "EASY COMPANY"
lS THE NCOs,
TOCCOA MEN.
SlR, THERE'S A SERGEANT
GUARNERE HERE TO SEE YOU.
LOOK WHAT
THE TRAlN
BROUGHT lN.
HEY, THE DAREDEVlL.
HlYA, CAPTAlN.
WELCOME BACK, BlLL.
JESUS, lT'S TRUE.
I NEVER THOUGHT l'D SEE
YOU BEHlND A DESK, SlR.
YEAH, AND SOMEDAY
HE'LL SlT BEHlND lT.
WELL, I JUST WENT AWOL
FROM THE HOSPlTAL TO
GET BACK HERE, SlR.
I HOPE THAT'S NOT GONNA
CAUSE YOU A PROBLEM.
WOULD YOU CARE
lF lT DlD?
NOT A BlT, SlR.
GOT A LETTER FOR YOU
HERE FROM MOOSE.
LlEUTENANT HEYLlGER, SlR.
HE'S RECOVERlNG
BUT lT'S GONNA
BE A LONG HAUL.
THANKS, BlLL.
SO, I HEAR THERE'S
GONNA BE A FOOTBALL GAME,
THOSE CHUMPS FROM
THE 5-0 DEUCE,
lS THAT RlGHT?
OH, YEAH,
CHRlSTMAS DAY.
GREAT, SKY
TRAlN BOYS.
CAN'T WAlT.
GREAT.
WELL, ER...
I'LL JUST GO
FlND SOME TROUBLE.
YOU DO THAT.
HEY, BlLL.
YES SlR?
NO MORE JOYRlDlNG,
RlGHT?
OH, ER, ANYBODY
EVER HEARD
OF A LlTTLE JOlNT
CALLED, "LULU'S"?
YOU GOT ME.
I'LL JUST ASK AROUND.
WELL, I GUESS NOW'S
AS GOOD A TlME AS ANY.
WHAT'S THAT,
A PlECE OF PAPER?
I DON'T WANNA SEE
ANOTHER PlECE OF PAPER.
GENERAL TAYLOR HAS FLOWN
BACK TO WASHlNGTON.
HE'S LEFT GENERAL MCAULlFFE
lN CHARGE OF THE DlVlSlON.
COLONEL SlNK lS lN RHElMS
TO SEE MARLENE DlETRlCH.
MARLENE DlETRlCH
lS lN RHElMS?
AT THE U.S.O.
I'M OUTTA HERE,
l'M GOlNG TO RHElMS.
STRAYER WlLL BE lN LONDON
FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER WEEK
FOR LT. COLONEL
DOBlE'S WEDDlNG.
I PERSONALLY AM HEADlNG BACK
TO ALDBOURNE TO LOOK UP
A CERTAlN YOUNG LADY.
WHAT ARE YOU
TELLlNG ME?
YOU, MY FRlEND,
ARE HEADED TO PARlS.
ClTY OF LlGHT.
THAT'S A
48-HOUR PASS.
IT'S BEEN DEClDED THAT
YOU NEED A LlTTLE DOSE
OF ClVlLlZATlON.
BON VOYAGE.
I SECOND THAT
( male )
THE AlRBOURNE lS
AS TOUGH AS THEY COME.
BASlC TRAlNlNG.
THAT'S BASlC,
YOU KNOW WHAT I DlD
lN BASlC TRAlNlNG?
I HAD TO EAT RATS.
IN BASlC TRAlNlNG.
WELL, THAT'S
THE FlRST TlME...
MONSlEUR?
MONSlEUR,
C'EST LA TERMlNUS...
EVery time I look at you,
I see eight or nine of you.
I'll be alright
when I can only see one.
LOOK AT ME,
l'M JOHN WAYNE.
THE COSTUME DEPARTMENT
SET ME UP
WlTH THESE GREAT
NAVY WHlTES.
LUZ, SHUT UP.
WHAT DO YOU THlNK?
I'M TRYlNG TO
WATCH THlS.
I'VE SEEN THlS MOVlE
13 TlMES, OKAY?
WELL, I HAVEN'T,
SO, SHUT UP.
WATCH THE MOVlE,
lT'S FlNE.
HEY, SKlP.
SHH, C'MON.
WHERE'VE YOU BEEN?
I'VE BEEN LOOKlN'
ALL OVER FOR YOU.
WELL, DON, l
WAS AT HOME
lN TANNAWANDA.
BUT THEN HlTLER
STARTED THlS
WHOLE THlNG,
SO, NOW l'M HERE.
HOW'D YOU MAKE
OUT lN CRAPS?
NOT SO BAD.
HERE'S THE 60
BUCKS I BORROWED.
YOU'RE PAYlNG
ME BACK?
AND, TO SAY
THANK YOU...
SURPRlSlNG.
A TlP.
JESUS!
SHUT UP!
I WAS UP SlO
GRAND, BUT I ONLY
HAVE 3,600 LEFT.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WlTH ALL THAT DOUGH?
BLOW MOST OF lT
lN PARlS AS SOON
AS POSSlBLE.
GlMME A TlP.
I don't think that climate
in there agrees with you.
As a matter of fact,
I'Ve been worried about
your health altogether.
HEY, BUCK.
You don't look well.
HOW ARE YOU FEELlNG?
YOUR WOUNDS HEAL,
ALL FOUR OF THEM?
YOU SEEN THlS BEFORE?
BUCK.
Hl.
IS lT ANY GOOD?
ER, YEAH.
IT'S A REAL CORKER.
I warned you about
this girl, a month ago.
Oh, won't anybody
giVe you a light?
LlP, FAVORlTE PART.
Well, you took the words
right out of my mouth.
GOT A PENNY?
Got a penny?
WHAT?
Sure, it's an
English penny...
LlGHTS!
C'MON.
QUlET!
YOU CAN'T
DO THAT TO THE DUKE.
I SAlD, QUlET!
ELEMENTS OF THE 1st AND
THE 6th SS PANZER DlVlSlON
HAVE BROKEN THROUGH lN
THE ARDENNES FOREST.
NOW, THEY'VE OVERRUN
THE 28th lNFANTRY
AND ELEMENTS
OF THE 4th.
ALL OFFlCERS
REPORT TO
RESPECTlVE HQs.
ALL PASSES
ARE CANCELLED.
ENLlSTED MEN REPORT
TO BARRACKS AND
YOUR PLATOON LEADERS.
DAMN, WHAT A DAY.
GOT A LlGHT?
SlR?
LlEUTENANT PEACOCK?
SlR, HAVE YOU SEEN
COLONEL STRAYER?
WHERE'S THE
COMPANY COMMANDER?
OH, LlEUTENANT DlKE,
l'VE BEEN LOOKlNG
FOR HlM ALL DAY.
I MEAN, HOW lS lT THAT
THE 4th ARMY'S PROBLEM
GETS DUMPED
ON THE AlRBORNE?
LlEUTENANT PEACOCK,
LlEUTENANT COMPTON.
CAP'N WlNTERS.
OH, LlEUTENANT DlKE,
l'VE BEEN LOOKlNG FOR YOU.
SlR, WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
COLONEL STRAYER
HAS NOT YET RETURNED
FROM SOME
WEDDlNG THAT HE'S
ATTENDlNG lN LONDON.
CAN YOU BELlEVE THAT?
WE'RE GOlNG
TO THE FRONT,
WE'RE GOlNG TO
THE FRONT HERE,
AND OUR C.O.
ISN'T EVEN lN THE
SAME DAMN COUNTRY.
YOU HAVE A
BlGGER PROBLEM,
LlEUTENANT DlKE.
YOU HAVE MEN
RETURNlNG TO ACTlON
WlTHOUT PROPER
COLD WEATHER CLOTHlNG
AND NOT ENOUGH AMMO.
SlR?
I SUGGEST YOU TAK
E A CANVASS OF THE
ENTlRE BASE.
GET WHAT MATERlALS
YOU HAVE BEFORE
YOU ROLL OUT.
OR HAVE YOU DONE
THAT ALREADY?
NO, SlR.
"K" RATlONS, AS MANY
AS YOU CAN SCROUNGE.
WE DON'T KNOW
lF WE'LL BE
RESUPPLlED OR NOT.
YES, SlR.
WHAT ABOUT AMMO?
THERE lS NO
MORE AMMO.
DlSTRlBUTE lT AMONGST
THE MEN AS BEST YOU CAN
SO, AT LEAST
EVERYBODY HAS
SOMETHlNG.
YES, SlR.
LlEUTENANT COMPTON,
LlEUTENANT PEACOCK,
INFORM LlEUTENANT
SHAMES OF
THE SlTUATlON.
GET ALL YOUR
PLATOONS AS BEST
EQUlPPED AS YOU CAN,
AND THEN REPORT BACK
HERE TO ME, UNDERSTOOD?
YES, SlR.
CAP'N.
I GUESS THE BLACKOUT'S
NOT lN EFFECT.
LUFTWAFFE
MUST BE ASLEEP.
WHAT A DlFFERENCE A DAY
MAKES, HUH, LlEUTENANT?
CHRlST, l
MlSS THOSE C-47s.
WE'VE GOT A
TAlLGATE JUMP HERE.
I JUST WANNA KNOW
WHERE THEY'RE SENDlNG US,
WHAT THE HELL WE'RE
SUPPOSED TO DO WlTH NO AMMO.
HEY, KlD, WHAT'S
YOUR NAME AGAlN?
SUERTH.
SUERTH JUNlOR.
YOU GOT ANY AMMO,
JUNlOR?
ER, JUST WHAT
l'M CARRYlNG.
WHAT ABOUT SOCKS, JUNlOR,
YOU GOT EOTRA SOCKS?
A PAlR.
YOU NEED FOUR,
MlNlMUM.
FEET, HANDS,
NECK, BALLS.
( together )
EOTRA SOCKS WARMS
THEM ALL.
OKAY, WE ALL
REMEMBER THAT ONE.
BUT DlD WE REMEMBER
THE SOCKS?
( Guarnere )
YEAH, l'D GlVE MY GODDAMN
BOOTS FOR A ClGARETTE.
WE'RE ALL OUT OF
AMMO AND SOCKS.
ANYBODY
GOT A ClGARETTE?
I BET JUNlOR'S GOT
PLENTY OF BOTH.
I DON'T.
HOW ABOUT A HAT,
YOU GOT A HAT?
HEY, YOU GOT
EOTRA AMMO?
WHAT ABOUT A COAT,
YOU GOT A COAT?
I NEED TO PEE.
HOW ABOUT
SOME SMOKES THEN?
YEAH, I GOT SOME SMOKES.
OH, NOW YOU'RE TALKlNG.
HEY, HEY,
HEY, HEY.
HEY, OVER HERE.
PASS THEM DOWN.
SOMEBODY,
GlVE ME A LlGHT.
KEEP MOVlNG, C'MON.
KEEP lT COMlNG.
OVER TO THE LEFT.
KEEP lT MOVlNG.
ALL THE WAY DOWN,
KEEP MOVlNG.
CLEAR THE WAY.
ALRlGHT GUYS,
15 MlNUTES.
SMOKE 'EM
lF YOU GOT 'EM.
KEEP WARM, GUYS.
WHERE THE HELL
ARE WE?
SURE WE AlN'T lN HELL,
lT'S TOO DAMN COLD.
HEY, STAND BACK, GUYS.
I'VE BEEN HOLDlNG THlS
FOR THE LAST HOUR.
ANYBODY GOT
ANY MATCHES?
OH, THAT'S BETTER.
WAlT RlGHT HERE,
DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
WELCOME TO BELGlUM.
THlS AREA'S
KNOWN AS BASTOGNE.
STRATEGlC CROSSROADS TOWN.
SEVEN ROADS LEADlNG lN,
SEVEN ROADS LEADlNG OUT,
WHlCH MAKES lT lDEAL
FOR KRAUT ARMOR.
NOW, lKE WANTS TO
MAKE SURE THAT THE KRAUTS
CAN'T USE THOSE ROADS,
SO, WE'RE GONNA PUT
A PERlMETER AROUND BASTOGNE,
DlG lN TlGHT
AS A TlCK.
2nd BATTALlON WlLL BE DEPLOYED
OVER HERE TO THE EAST
IN THlS WOODED AREA.
THANK GOD,
BARELY MADE lT.
BETTER GET YOURSELF
SOME O.D.s, BOB.
OKAY.
1st BATTALlON'S TO
THE NORTH ON YOUR
LEFT FLANK.
3rd BATTALlON'S
lN RESERVE.
ANDY, LET'S ROLL.
SlR, WE'RE A LlTTLE
SHORT ON AMMUNlTlON.
HOW SHORT?
THERE WAS A LlMlTED
SUPPLY lN CAMP, SlR.
CAP'N, YOU BEG, BORROW,
OR STEAL AMMO,
BUT YOU DEFEND
THlS AREA.
YES, SlR.
JESUS CHRlST.
HEY, BlLL, DON,
COME HERE, LOOK AT THlS.
COME HERE,
LOOK AT THlS.
HOLD ON.
JESUS, l'M DONE.
WHAT THE...
WHAT THE HELL
lS GOlNG ON?
HEY, YOU'RE GOlNG
THE WRONG WAY.
HEY, PAL.
HEY, PAL,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE THE HELL
ARE YOU GOlNG?
THEY CAME OUT OF
NOWHERE, THEY
SLAUGHTERED US.
YOU GOTTA
GET OUTTA HERE.
WE JUST GOT HERE.
GlMME YOUR AMMO.
C'MON.
TAKE lT,
YOU'LL NEED lT.
GO ON, GET
OUT OF HERE.
HOLY CHRlST.
HEY, WHO'S GOT AMMO?
YOU GOT AMMO?
GlMME YOUR AMMO.
WHO'S GOT AMMO?
YOU GOT ANY GRENADES?
C'MON,
HAND 'EM OVER.
GlMME lT.
YOU GOT GRENADES?
GOT ANY GRENADES, LlEB?
WHO'S GOT GRENADES?
PRlVATE, PRlVATE,
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
MAKE A HOLE!
HEY, MAKE A HOLE.
I GOT AMMO,
GRAB WHAT YOU CAN.
LlEUTENANT,
YOU'RE A GODSEND.
WHAT'S THE SlTUATlON?
WELL, I HEARD YOU GUYS
WERE COMlNG lN.
THERE WAS
AN AMMO DUMP, SO...
HERE.
IS lT JUST YOU GUYS
lN THE 101st?
LOOKS LlKE.
WHAT HlT YOU FELLOWS?
EVERYTHlNG.
THE KRAUTS HAD TlGERS,
PANTHERS, S.P.s, STUKERS...
AND lNFANTRY THAT
JUST KEPT ON COMlNG.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
LlEUTENANT?
GEORGE RlCE,
10th ARMOUR.
GOOD WORK, SON.
YOU GOT ANYMORE
MORTAR ROUNDS, SlR?
WE'RE REAL SHORT.
WELL, l'LL TRY TO MAKE
ANOTHER AMMO RUN lF I CAN
BUT, ER, DON'T
COUNT ON ANYTHlNG.
THANK YOU, SlR,
l'LL TAKE THlS, CAP'N.
A PANZER DlVlSlON'S
ABOUT TO CUT THE ROAD SOUTH.
LOOKS LlKE YOU GUYS
ARE GONNA BE SURROUNDED.
WE'RE PARATROOPERS,
LlEUTENANT.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO
BE SURROUNDED.
GOOD LUCK.
THANKS.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOO OFFlCE
A DiVision of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNlCATlONS CENTER