[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW.
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
IT LIES BETWEEN THE PIT
OF MAN'S FEARS,
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
THE TIME IS THE DAY
AFTER TOMORROW,
THE PLACE, A FAR
CORNER OF THE UNIVERSE.
THE CAST OF CHARACTERS, THREE
MEN LOST AMONGST THE STARS,
THREE MEN SHARING THE COMMON
URGENCY OF ALL MEN LOST.
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR HOME.
AND IN A MOMENT
THEY'LL FIND HOME.
NOT A HOME THAT IS
A PLACE TO BE SEEN
BUT A STRANGE, UNEXPLAINABLE
EXPERIENCE TO BE FELT.
[rocket sound]
I HEAR
THE ATMOSPHERE.
KEEP YOUR FING ERS
CROSSED, PETE.
THIS MAY BE IT.
IT BETTER BE ;
WE'RE ABOUT
OUT OF FU EL.
[vehicle decelerating]
20.95 PARTS OXYG EN
78.09 N ITROG EN.
I DON'T GET IT,
THAT'S AIR.
G RAVITY, U N IT ON E.
THAT'S I NCREDI BLE.
CON DITIONSIDENTICAL
TO EARTH
AND YET WE'RE
655 M I LLION M I LES
AWAY FROM EARTH.
WAIT A MINUTE, PETE.
THESE I NSTRU MENTS
COULD BE WRONG.
WHAT'S
THE DIFFERENCE?
WE'RE NOT GOING
ANYWHERE NOW.
YEAH, I GU ESS
YOU'RE RIGHT.
HOW FAR DID YOU SAY
WE WERE FROM EARTH?
655 M I LLION M I LES.
WE'RE BACK
ON EARTH.
NO.
NO? WHAT DO
YOU CALL THAT,
A MARTIAN?
HERE, BOY,
COME ON.
[suspense music]
WELL, ANYWAY, LOOK
AT THOSE TREES.
IT'S GOT
TO BE EARTH.
WELL, WHAT DO
YOU CALL THAT?
IT'S CALLED
A TRACTOR.
THEY WERE IN
USE ON EARTH
DU RING THE 20th CENTURY
BEFORE THE TOTAL WAR.
YOU MEAN,
WE'RE ON EARTH
200 YEARS AGO.
IT'S AN
I NTERESTING
TH EORY, PETE
AND AS POSS I BLE
AS ANY OTH ER
EXCEPT THAT
TO MY KNOWLEDG E
EARTH HAS NEVER HAD
MORE THAN ONE SU N.
(Pete)
ALL RIGHT.
YOU EXPLAIN IT.
THE ONLY THING
I'M CERTAIN OF
IS THAT WE'RE
NOT ON EARTH.
WE'RE
NOT ALON E.
EXCUSE ME,
S I R.
MY NAME
IS WEBBER,
WE HATE TO
BOTHER YOU--
(Pete)
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH HIM?
SEEMS TO BE
IN SOME SORT
OF A TRANCE OR--
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
HEY, LOOK,
THERE'S SOMEBODY!
HEY, MISTER!
MISTER!
[panting]
HOW ARE THEY B ITING?
MISTER?
HEY, WAKE UP.
[suspense music]
[band playing]
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
THE MUSIC, A BAN D,
DO YOU HEAR IT?
THERE'S SOMEBODY HERE.
IT SEEMS
TO BE COMING
FROM OVER THERE.
[band music]
THE MUSIC'S COMING
FROM THAT LOU DSPEAKER.
IT'S BEING P I PED
IN FROM SOMEWHERE.
LOOK!
[music stops]
CONCERT'S
OVER.
WELL, ANY IDEAS,
PROFESSOR?
WELL, I SU PPOSE
IT COULD BE SOME
SORT OF I LLUS ION.
YES, MAYBE
WE'RE BEING MADE
TO SEE AND HEAR
WHAT WE HOPE
TO F IN D
THE SIGHTS AND
SOU N DS OF HOM E.
NO, NO, THAT'S
ALL WRONG.
THIS IS MORE
THAN 200 YEARS
AHEAD OF OUR TIME.
OR IT COULD BE
THAT TIME ITSELF
IS SUSPEN DED HERE.
OR TIME MAY HAVE,
IN A SENSE
HAVE SPEEDED UP
FOR US
OR SLOWED DOWN
FOR THEM.
YOU MEAN, THEY MIGHT
ACTUALLY BE MOVING?
IT'S POSS I BLE.
THEN WHY CAN'T
WE SEE IT?
WELL, YOU DON'T
SEE THE MOVEM ENTS
OF A CLOCK'S HAN DS
N EVERTH ELESS
THEY DO MOVE.
WELL, THIS CLOCK
HAS NO HAN DS.
[suspense music]
CARL, DO YOU
REALLY BELIEVE
WHAT YOU'RE
SAYING?
NO, OF
COURSE NOT.
BUT THEY'RE NOT
JUST STATU ES.
THEY'RE FLESH
AND BLOOD
OR SOMETHING THAT FEELS
LIKE FLESH AND BLOOD.
IT'S
SOMETHING REAL.
IT'S GOT
TO BE HERE.
NOW, I SAY
SEPARATE
AND MEET BACK
HERE IN ONE HOUR.
WELL,
IT'S BETTER
THAN H U DDLING
TOG ETHER LIKE
FRIGHTEN ED CH I LDREN.
(Webber)
REMEMBER, WE
MEET BACK HERE
IN ONE HOUR.
[knocks]
HELLO.
ANYBODY THERE?
[romantic violin music]
OH, I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
[vioIin music continues]
[distorted strings]
[pIeasant music]
YOUR MAJ ESTY.
I DON'T BLAM E
THE J U DG ES.
YOU'RE THE PRETTI EST
OF THEM ALL.
BUT TELL
ME SOMETHING,
YOUR MAJ ESTY,
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH YOU?
[distorted strings]
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH EVERYBODY
IN THIS CRAZY PLACE?!
ANSWER ME!
CAN'T YOU TALK?
CAN'T YOU MOVE?
ANSWER ME!
[suspense music]
[mischievous music]
THIS IS THE WAY
IT WAS ON EARTH
NOT SO LONG AGO.
MY GREAT
G RAN DFATHER SHOWED
ME PICTURES OF IT.
QU I ET AND PEACEFU L.
YOU MEAN
YOU LIKE
IT HERE?
I WOULD IF IT
WERE REAL,
IF I COULD BE SURE IT
WASN'T GOING TO VAN ISH
IN A PU FF OF P IN K SMOKE.
[ring]
WELL, AS FOR ME, IT'S
A NICE PLACE TO VIS IT
BUT I WOULDN'T WANT
TO LIVE HERE.
LIKE IT OR NOT,
THIS IS HOM E
FROM NOW ON.
CHARMING.
LOVELY, ISN'T IT?
IF YOU WANT IT,
IT'S YOURS.
YES, THAT'S TRU E
ISN'T IT?
YOU DON'T MIND
IF WE HAVE
A LOOK AROUND
DO YOU, S I R?
NOT AT ALL.
YOU'RE MOST WELCOM E.
MY NAME'S WICKWI RE,
J EREMY WICKWI RE.
G ENTLEM EN, THERE'S
NOTHING TO BE
AFRAI D OF.
TRU LY, THERE ISN'T.
BUT, Y-Y-YOU'RE REAL.
BUT, OF COURSE, I AM.
ISN'T EVERYBODY?
I USED TO
THINK SO.
OH, YOU MEAN,
[chuckIes]
DO COME I NSIDE.
COME ON,
WON'T YOU?
COME I NSIDE.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAI D OF
I ASSURE YOU.
EH, DO YOU
LIKE IT?
WE BU I LT IT
FOR A M R., UH,
MR. J EN KI NSON.
BUT AT THE LAST
MOM ENT HE DECI DED
THAT THE ONE THING HE WANTED
TO BE WAS A KNIGHT IN ARMOR
SO HE'S OUT THERE
IN THE MEDI EVAL SECTION
SLAYING A DRAGON.
YOU MEAN THERE
ARE OTHER SECTIONS?
HM?
(Wickwire)
OH, YES,
OF COURSE,
WE HAVE
MANY SECTIONS.
THERE'S
THE ROMAN,
THE EGYPTIAN,
THE WILD
WESTERN
BUT THIS IS
THE MOST POPU LAR
BECAUSE IT
REPRESENTS
A PERIOD
IN AM ERICAN CU LTU RE
WHEN CREATU RE
COM FORTS WERE
MOST ABU N DANT
AND BEFORE PEACE ON EARTH
BECAME IMPOSS I BLE.
NOW, LOOK,
M R., UH,
WICKWI RE.
WICKWI RE, WE
ARE FROM EARTH.
OH?
(Webber)
WE WERE ON A ROUTINE
GEOLOGICAL MISSION.
WE RAN INTO
A METEORITE STORM.
SOME OF OUR EQU I PM ENT
WAS KNOCKED OUT.
WE GOT LOST.
NOW, THAT WAS
SIX MONTHS AGO.
WE SAW
THIS ASTERO I D
AND WE LAN DED.
OUR FU EL
IS GON E.
WE'VE GOT
TO STAY HERE.
I SEE.
I SEE, THEN YOU'RE
NOT FROM THE GLADES.
THE WHAT?
BUT YOU ARE FROM THE EARTH.
TELL ME, DID THEY EVER
HAVE THAT ATOM IC WAR?
YES, IN 1 985.
MOST OF THE EARTH'S
SU RFACE WAS DESTROYED
AND IT'S TAKEN
US 200 YEARS
TO PICK UP
THE P I ECES.
OH, HOW SAD.
MR. WICKWI RE
NOW, YOU'VE
GOT TO EXPLAIN
SOME THINGS
BEFORE WE
GO OUT OF
OUR MINDS.
YES, BUT YOU LOOK H U NG RY.
LET ME F IX YOU LU NCH,
THEN WE'LL TALK.
(Pete)
WAIT A SECOND.
NOW, YOU TELL US
ONE THING RIGHT NOW.
WHERE ARE WE?
WHY, YOU'RE IN A CEM ETERY.
DIDN'T YOU KNOW?
[suspense music]
PLEASE, MAKE
YOURSELVES COM FORTABLE.
I'LL BE BACK
IN A FEW MOM ENTS.
CEM ETERY?
COFFEE WI LL
BE SERVED
IN A FEW MINUTES,
G ENTLEM EN.
MAY I PROPOSE
A TOAST?
TO PEACE,
MY FRIENDS
TO EVERLASTING
ETERNAL PEACE.
[suspense music]
EXCELLENT!
LI EBFRAU M I LCH,
ISN'T IT?
YES.
MISTER--
WICKWI RE.
WE'RE VERY
CON FUSED.
WE NEED H ELP.
WELL, S IT DOWN,
MY BOYS, S IT DOWN.
COME ON,
S IT DOWN.
WHAT IS IT?
NOW, YOU SAID
THAT WE WERE
IN A CEM ETERY.
WHAT DID
YOU MEAN?
J UST
EXACTLY THAT.
BUT BEFORE
I EXPLAIN
YOU MUST GIVE ME
SOME IN FORMATION.
IF YOU WERE GRANTED
YOUR DEAREST WISH
WHAT WOULD
YOUR WISH BE?
I'M NOT SURE I KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
I MEAN, WHERE
WOULD YOURATHER BE
RIGHT NOW?
I'D LIKE TO BE ON THE SH I P
H EADED FOR HOM E.
AND YOU, CAPTAI N.
I'LL GO ALONG
WITH THAT.
SPLEN DID, AND J UST
ONE THING MORE.
WHEN YOU LEFT EARTH,
WHAT WAS THE DATE?
SEPTEM BER.
NO, NO, THE YEAR.
2 1 85.
2 1 85?
[chuckIes]
NOW I UNDERSTAND.
WELL, THAT'S N ICE.
WE DON'T!
WHEN YOU ARRIVED
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
FROM HAPPY GLADES.
BUT BY YOUR BEHAVIOR
OF COURSE, I SEE
YOU COULDN'T BE.
WE'RE STILL
NOT FOLLOWING YOU.
WHAT'S HAPPY GLADES?
THE WORLD'S
G REATEST MORTUARY.
AT LEAST, THAT'S
WHAT IT USED TO BE.
YOU SEE,
THE MANAG EM ENT
H IT UPON THIS SCH EM E
AS A SERVICE
TO THOSE WHO
COULD AFFORD IT.
"THIS SCH EM E"
BEING?
THIS LITTLE
ASTERO I D
WHERE WE WOULD RECREATE
THE EXACT CON DITIONS
U N DER WHICH
THE DEAR DEPARTED
COULD BE MOST HAPPY.
FOR AN EXAM PLE,
IF THE DECEASED ALWAYS
WANTED TO BE ELECTED MAYOR
HE WOULD ACH I EVE
HIS AM B ITION HERE
FOR ALL ETERNITY.
YOU MEAN THOSE PEOPLE
ARE ALL DEAD?
NO, NO, NOT ALL OF THEM.
JUST A SELECT FEW.
THE OTH ERS ARE IMITATIONS.
(Professor)
IN OTHER WORDS,
THIS IS THE PLACE
WHERE YOUR
DREAMS COME TRU E AFTER
YOU'VE STOPPED DREAMING.
YES, THAT MIGHT
BE ONE WAY OF
PUTTING IT.
YES, THAT'S
VERY GOOD.
YOU EXPECT
US TO BELIEVE
THAT EXPLANATION?
I HADN'T THOUGHT OF THAT.
DON'T YOU?
IT'S TRU E, YOU KNOW.
WELL, I'LL ADM IT
WE HAVEN'T COME UP
WITH ANYTHING BETTER.
BUT A CEM ETERY
OUT IN SPACE.
M I LLIONS OF M I LES
FROM EARTH.
WHY?
YES, WHY?
NOW, YOUR BOSS
COULD HAVE BOUGHT
A P I ECE OF DESERT.
OH, NO, NO
YOU DON'T
U N DERSTAND AT ALL.
HAPPY GLADES PROMISES
ETERNAL PEACE
EVERLASTING PEACE.
YOU COULDN'T
HAVE THAT ON EARTH
NOW, COULD YOU?
HE HAS A PO I NT.
U H, WHAT
ABOUT YOU?
ME?
YES, YOU, HOW
DO YOU F IG U RE
IN ALL THIS?
WHY, I'M
THE CARETAKER.
IT'S MY JOB
TO MAKE SURE
THAT OUR GU ESTS
ARE NOT,
DISTU RBED.
WELL, WHEN DID
THIS MORTUARY-- OR
WHATEVER IT IS-- BEG I N?
1 973, I BELIEVE.
YES, YES.
THAT'D MAKE
YOU A B IT
ON THE
ELDERLY SIDE
WOULDN'T IT,
MR. WI REWICK?
WICKWI RE.
[chuckIes]
NOW, I'M AFRAI D
YOU'RE FORCING ME
INTO A RATH ER
EM BARRASSING ADMISS ION.
YOU SEE, I'M NOT
ACTUALLY HUMAN,
OH, I AM NOW
BUT WHEN YOU'VE GON E
I SHALL GO BACK
TO SLEEP AGAIN
U NTI L I'M NEEDED.
YOU SEE, I'M-- I'M MERELY
A SCI ENTIF IC DEVICE.
I GO ON AND OFF AGAIN
LIKE A MACHINE.
YOU UNDERSTAND.
YES, IT'S NOT
VERY COM PLICATED
IS IT, REALLY?
HE GOES
ON AND OFF.
YES, I THINK IMUST HAVE BEEN
OFF FOR ABOUT 200 YEARS.
LOOK, MISTER,
YOU THINK--
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT, PETE.
MR. WICKWI RE
WE'RE
STAYING HERE.
YES, I KNOW.
YES, BUT YOU
SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT OU R
BEING GON E.
OH, THAT'S A F IG U RE
OF SPEECH, CAPTAI N.
I MEANT "DEPARTED."
"GONE ON" AS IT WERE.
WELL, YOU KNOW
WHAT HE'S SAYING
DON'T YOU?
I TOLD YOU NOT
TO TRUST HIM.
I TOLD YOU!
WE MEANT YOU
NO HARM.
I REALIZE THAT AND I'M SORRY.
TRU LY I AM.
(Webber)
THE ANTIDOTE--
GIVE US THE ANTI DOTE.
(Wickwire)
THERE IS NO
ANTIDOTE, CAPTAIN.
EVEN NOW THE
ETERNIFYING FLU ID
IS COURSING
THROUGH YOUR VEINS
BUT IT-- IT WON'T
BE PAIN FU L, I ASSURE YOU.
BUT WHY?
WHY US?
BECAUSE YOU ARE HERE
AND YOU ARE MEN
AND WHILE THERE ARE MEN
THERE CAN BE NO PEACE.
[mischievous music]
[humming]
(male narrator)
KIRBY, WEBBER AND MEYERS,
THREE MEN LOST.
THEY SHARED A COMMON WISH,
A SIMPLE ONE REALLY,
THEY WANTED TO BE ABOARD
THEIR SHIP HEADED FOR HOME.
AND FATE, A LAUGHING FATE,
A PRACTICAL JOKESTER
WITH A SMILE THAT STRETCHED
ACROSS THE STARS
SAW TO IT THAT
THEY GOT THEIR WISH
WITH JUST ONE RESERVATION,
THE WISH CAME TRUE
BUT ONLY
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, I TRY
TO SETTLE AN ARG U MENT
TO THE EFFECT THAT I'M NOT
AT MY BEST WHEN WRITING
SCRI PTS FOR WOM EN
MISS VERA M I LES
TAKES MY SIDE
IN A MOST U N USUAL AND U N IQU E
STORY WE CALLED
M IRROR IMAGE.
I HOPE TO SEE YOU NEXT WEEK,
YOU IN YOUR LIVING ROOM
AND MISS VERA M I LES
AND THE REST OF US
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
CAN WE HAVE DYNAM IC
GROWTH, LOW UNEMPLOYMENT,
AND REASONABLY STABLE PRICES?
WRITE FOR THIS FREE BOOKLET
TO AMERICAN ASSEMBLY,
COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY
NEW YORK CITY.