[eerie music]
(male narrator)
YOU ARE ABOUT TO ENTER
ANOTHER DIMENSION
A DIMENSION NOT ONLY OF SIGHT
AND SOUND, BUT OF M IND
A JOURNEY INTO A WONDROUS
LAND OF IMAGINATION.
NEXT STOP,
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING AT
IS A GHOST
ONCE ALIVE, BUT NOW DECEASED.
ONCE UPON A TIME,
IT WAS A BASEBALL STADIUM
THAT HOUSED
A MAJOR LEAGUE BALL CLUB
KNOWN AS THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS.
NOW IT HOUSES NOTHING
BUT MEMORIES
AND A WIND THAT STIRS
IN THE HIGH GRASS
OF WHAT WAS
ONCE AN OUTFIELD.
A WIND THAT SOMETIMES BEARS
A FAINT GHOSTLY RESEMBLANCE
TO THE ROAR OF A CROWD
THAT ONCE SAT HERE.
WE'RE BACK IN TIME NOW
WHEN THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS
WERE STILL A PART
OF THE NATIONAL LEAGUE
AND THIS
MAUSOLEUM OF MEMORIES
WAS AN HONEST-TO-PETE STADIUM.
BUT SINCE THIS IS STRICTLY
A STORY OF MAKE-BELIEVE
IT HAS TO START THIS WAY.
ONCE UPON A TIME
IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
IT WAS TRYOUT DAY.
AND THOUGH HE'S NOT YET
ON THE FIELD
YOU'RE ABOUT TO MEET
A MOST UNUSUAL FELLOW.
A LEFT-HANDED PITCHER
NAMED CASEY.
G RAN D-LOOKING BU NCH
OF BOYS, HUH?
WERE YOU EXPECTING
THE ALL-STARS?
YOU HAVE TRYOUTS
FOR A LAST-DIVIS ION CLU B
3 1 GAM ES OUT OF FIRST
THIS IS THE MATERIAL
YOUROU N D UP.
YOU USUALLY ROU N D UP.
YOU'RE GEN ERAL MANAG ER.
WHY DON'T YOU GET
ME BALLPLAYERS?
YOU'D KNOW
WHAT TO DO
WITH THEM?
20 GAM ES
OUT OF FOU RTH PLACE
AND THE ONLY BIG
AVERAG E WE GOT
IS A MANAG ER WITH THE WI DEST
MOUTH INEITHER LEAG U E.
MAYBE YOU BETTER
GET REMINDED
WHEN THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS
WIN ONE GAM E
WE GOT TO CALL IT
A STREAK.
OH, BUDDY BOY, WH EN
CONTRACT TIME COMES AROUND
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
HOW'S FLETCHER DOING?
ARE YOU KI DDING?
HE P ITCH ED
ONE IN NING
LAST WEEK
AND ONLY ALLOWED
SIX RUNS.
HE'S THE MOST VALUABLE
PLAYER OF THE MONTH.
[phone ringing]
DUGOUT.
YEAH.
WHO?
WANT TO LOOK
AT A P ITCH ER?
AT THIS PO I NT,
I'LL EVEN LOOK
AT YOU.
SEND HIM OVER.
HE'S A LEFTY.
LEFTY, SCH MEFTY.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
IF HE'S GOT MORE
THAN ONE ARM
AND LESS THAN FOU R,
HE'S FOR US.
HEY, MON K!
YEAH?
FLETCHER CAN QU IT.
I GOT A NEW BOY
COMING DOWN.
CATCH HIM
FOR A WHILE.
CHECK.
YOU GOT THE LIN EU P
FOR TONIGHT?
I'M WORKING ON IT.
WHO'S P ITCHING?
I JUST FEEL THEM
ON E-BY-ON E.
WHOEVER'S WARM
GOES TO THE MOU N D.
ALL RIGHT, CHAVEZ.
STOP ALREADY WITH
THE CALISTHEN ICS.
THAT GUY ON THE EN D'S
TURNING BLU E.
(man)
MR. MCGARRY?
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT'S THE GAG?
DID THIS M UTTON H EAD
PUT YOU UP TO IT?
YOU'RE THE
P ITCH ER, HUH?
B IG JOKE.
YU K-YU K-YU K!
B IG JOKE!
OH, NO, I'M NOT
THE P ITCH ER.
I'M DR. STILLMAN.
I HAVE
THROWN BASEBALLS
IN MY TIME.
THAT WAS
BEFORE THE WAR.
YEAH? WHICH WAR?
[chuckling]
(Stillman)
AH, HERE
COMES CASEY NOW.
HE'S THE PITCHER.
CASEY, THIS IS M R.
MCGARRY, THE MANAG ER
OF THE ZEPHYRS.
NO, NO, YOUR RIGHT HAN D,
CASEY, YOUR RIGHT HAN D.
[groaning]
OH H.
OH!
[groaning]
YOU CAN LET GO
NOW, CASEY.
SEE THAT
FELLOW OUT THERE
WITH THE BIG M ITT?
HE'S WHAT IS KNOWN
AS A CATCH ER.
HIS NAME IS MON K.
GO ON OUT AND
THROW HIM
A FEW.
THANKS VERY MUCH,
MR. MCGARRY.
PUT YOUR CAP
ON, CASEY.
GOOD LAD.
ALL RIGHT,
I SEE YOU,
I SEE YOU.
YOU HIS FATH ER?
HIS FATH ER? CASEY'S?
OH, NO, NO.
HE HAS NO FATH ER.
I AM WHAT
YOU MIGHT
CALL, H IS--
WELL, KIND OF,
U H, CREATOR.
HOW OLD IS H E?
THAT'S A LITTLE
DI FF ICU LT TO SAY.
WELL, GU ESS.
WHAT I MEAN IS
IT'S HARD TO
BE CH RONOLOG ICAL
WHEN DISCUSSING
CASEY'S AG E
BECAUSE HE'S ONLY BEEN
IN EXISTENCE THREE WEEKS.
WHAT I MEAN IS THAT
HE HAS THE PHYS IQU E
AND THE MIND
OF A BOY OF 22.
BUT IN TERMS
OF HOW LONG
HE'S BEEN HERE
THE ANSWER TO THAT
WOULD BE, UH,
THREE WEEKS.
YOU WANT TO
GO OVER THAT AGAIN?
IT'S NOT TOO
DI FF ICU LT, REALLY.
YOU SEE,
I MADE CASEY.
I BU I LT HIM.
HE'S A ROBOT.
THESE ARE
THE BLU EPRI NTS
I WORKED FROM.
WHY DO YOU HAVE
TO PICK ON ME
ALL THE TIME, HUH?
[loud thud]
[whoosh]
THAT'S H IS
FAST BALL.
[loopy]
THAT'S HIS CU RVE.
[long slow whistle]
THAT'S H IS
SLOW BALL.
HE'S A BIT LATE.
[soft thud]
WELL, LOOK, I'LL, UH--
YOU, UH--U H--
[cIears throat]
WHY DON'T YOU WAIT
RIGHT HERE, HUH?
U H-HUH.
ALL RIGHT,
LET ME SEE
THAT FAST BALL.
[whoosh]
ALL RIGHT,
THE SLOW BALL.
[slow loop]
DID YOU SEE
THAT KI D?
THE BEST P ITCH ER
I EVER CAUG HT.
YEAH, MON K,
I SAW IT.
H E... H E...
I SAW IT, I SAW IT!
TAKE A SHOWER.
HE'S GOT
A FAST BALL...
GO TAKE A SHOWER.
TAKE A SHOWER!
HE P ITCH ES
LIKE NOTHING HUMAN.
WELL, H E'S...
HE'S ROUG H, DOC,
HE'S PLENTY ROUG H
BUT I THINK WE CAN
GIVE HIM A TRY.
HE'S A ROBOT,
YOU KNOW.
DON'T EVER SAY THAT.
THAT'S ONE WE'LL JUST KEEP
IN THE FAM I LY HERE.
DON'T EVER SAY THE
WORD R-O-B-B-O-T-T.
U H, CASEY.
BABY...
WANT TO COME HERE?
WELL, IT LOOKS
LIKE YOU GOT
A LITTLE POTENTIAL
THERE, CASEY.
I WAS TELLING THE DOC
YOU'RE A LITTLE ROUG H
BUT WE'LL
WORK THAT OUT.
I THINK WE'LL
GIVE YOU A CHANCE.
I LIKE TO H ELP
YOU NG BALL PLAYERS.
[hoIIow pIunk]
WHY DON'T YOU
GO DOWN NOW
AND CHANG E YOUR
CLOTH ES, HUH?
HE DOES
WEAR CLOTH ES,
DOESN'T H E?
OH, YES, YES.
GO DOWN
AND TAKE
A SHOWER
AND THEN
THE THREE OF US
WILL DISCUSS
A CONTRACT, HUH?
GO WITH HIM AND
CHECK HIS BLU EPRI NTS.
I THINK THAT
LAST SLOW BALL
SHOOK HIM UP.
VERY WELL.
COME ON, CASEY.
G EN ERAL
MANAG ER'S OFF ICE.
BEASLEY? DRAW
THE CONTRACT.
THE ONLY THING
BETWEEN US AND
THE PEN NANT
IS IF THIS GUY'S
BATTERY GOES DEAD
OR HE RUSTS IN THE RAI N.
N EVER MIND WHAT I MEAN.
YOU DRAW THE CONTRACT.
THEN, UH,
COME ON DOWN HERE.
I WANT YOU TO SHAKE
HAN DS WITH YOUR N EW
ACE P ITCH ER.
[crowd cheering]
YOU, UH, YOU GOT
THE SIGNALS DOWN
ALL RIGHT, KI D?
YES.
KI D, DON'T
BE N ERVOUS.
N ERVOUS?
I LL AT EASE,
CASEY, AS I F
YOUR ELECTRODES
WERE MALFU NCTIONING.
YOU KNOW, N ERVOUS.
LIKE THERE'S
TWO OUT IN
THE N I NTH.
YOU'RE ONE UP,
AND JOE DI MAGG IO
COMES TO THE PLATE
LOOKING I NTENT.
WELL, THAT WOULDN'T
MAKE ME N ERVOUS.
I DON'T KNOW ANYONE
NAM ED JOE DI MAGG IO.
OH, YEAH.
I FORGOT
ABOUT THAT.
WELL, YOU
JUST GET
IN THERE.
GO AHEAD.
MR. MCGARRY,
WHAT TEAM IS CASEY
P ITCHING AGAINST?
THE NEW YORK GIANTS.
OH, I'D LOVE
TO BEAT THOSE GIANTS.
BUT FOR THAT MATTER,
I'D LOVE TO BEAT CI NCIN NATI
OR PH I LADELPH IA,
OR THE BRAVES.
OR EVEN THE
H ICKSVI LLE BU LLETS.
THEY BEAT US 1 1 -0
IN SPRING TRAINING.
OH, I THINK CASEY
WILL COME TH ROUG H
FOR YOU, MR. MCGARRY.
YEAH? WHAT'S IN THIS
FOR YOU, DOC?
OH, YOU MEAN
WITH CASEY?
OH, JUST SCI ENTIF IC,
THAT'S ALL.
PU RELY EXPERI MENTAL.
YOU KNOW, I THINK CASEY'S
SOME SORT OF A SU PERMAN.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE
THAT PROVEN.
ONCE, I BU I LT
A HOME ECONOM IST
AND MARVELOUS COOK.
I GAIN ED 46 POU N DS
BEFORE I HAD
TO DISMANTLE H ER.
NOW WITH
CASEY'S SKI LLS
I CONSIDER THAT
WITH HIS STRENGTH
AND ACCU RACY
H E'D BE A
BASEBALL P ITCH ER.
NOW IN ORDER
TO HAVE THAT PROVED
I HAD TO HAVE HIM
P ITCH IN COM PETITION
AND AS AN ACI D TEST,
TO P ITCH
ON ABSOLUTELY
THE WORST BALL TEAM
I COULD F IN D.
THANKS A LOT, DOC.
YOU GOT A LOT OF CLASS.
PLAY BALL!
[whoosh]
STEE-RI KE!
[crack of bat]
[hollow plunk]
[crowd gasping]
NO FRACTU RE,
NO CONCUSS ION,
REFLEXES SEEM NORMAL.
I THINK YOU'RE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT,
MR. CASEY.
OH, BOY. I CAN
BREATHE AGAIN.
ALL I KEPT
THINKING ABOUT
WAS, "THERE
GOES CASEY.
"THERE GOES
THE PEN NANT.
THERE GOES
THE SERI ES."
YOUR CAREER.
(doctor)
YES, SIR,
MR. CASEY.
I THINK YOU'RE IN
GOOD SHAPE HERE.
ALTHOUGH WH EN
I HEARD
HOW HARD THAT
BALL H IT YOU,
I WON DERED TO
MYSELF HOW A--
HOW A--
COUG H, MR. CASEY.
[mechanical click]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WELL, THERE'S
NOTHING WRONG.
THEN WHAT ARE
YOU PRYING FOR?
WELL, THERE'S NOT
A THING WRONG.
EVERYTHING IS
JUST F IN E.
IT'S JUST THAT--
JUST THAT WHAT?
WELL, THIS, UH--
THIS MAN
DOESN'T HAVE
ANY PU LSE.
NO HEARTBEAT.
TH IS, UH...
THIS MAN
ISN'T ALIVE.
IT WILL HAVE TO
COME OUT NOW.
WHAT'S THIS
ALL ABOUT, MOUTH?
WHAT ARE
YOU TRYING
TO PULL OFF?
YOU'RE NOT GON NA
LIKE THIS BUT--
U H, DOCTOR, I THINK
YOU SHOU LD KNOW THIS
BEFORE YOU GO
ANY FU RTH ER.
THIS MAN HASN'T A
PU LSE OR A HEARTBEAT
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T
HAVE A HEART.
HE'S A ROBOT.
(doctor)
A WHAT?
(Stillman)
A ROBOT.
YOU'RE SURE?
BY ALL MEANS.
I BU I LT HIM.
AND HE'S BEEN P ITCHING
FOR THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS.
U N DER THE CI RCU MSTANCES,
AS TEAM PHYS ICIAN
I'M AFRAI D IMUST NOTI FY
THE BASEBALL COM MISS ION ER.
CASEY, MOVE OVER.
ARTICLE SIX,
SECTION TWO,
THE BASEBALL CODE.
I QUOTE--
"A TEAM
SHALL CONSIST
OF NINE MEN."
END OF QUOTE.
"MEN," UNDERSTAND?
NOT ROBOTS.
HE'S SUSPENDED.
THAT'S MY
FINAL DECISION.
COM MISS ION ER, TO ALL
I NTENTS AND PU RPOSES
HE IS HUMAN!
CASEY...
TALK TO HIM.
TELL HIM
ABOUT YOURSELF.
WHAT SHOU LD I SAY?
SEE? HE TALKS
BETTER THAN ME
AND HE'S A
LOT SMARTER
THAN MOST OF
THOSE M UTTON H EADS.
HE IS NOT HUMAN!
HOW HUMAN DO
YOU WANT HIM?
HE'S GOT ARMS AND LEGS
AND A FACE AND HE TALKS.
AND NO HEART.
HE DOESN'T EVEN
OWN A HEART.
HOW COULD
HE BE HUMAN
WITHOUT A HEART?
BEASLEY HASN'T GOT
A HEART EITHER.
HE OWNS 40%
OF THE CLU B.
THAT'S IT.
HE DOESN'T
HAVE A HEART
THAT MEANS
HE ISN'T HUMAN.
THAT'S A
CLEAR VIOLATION
OF THE
BASEBALL CODE.
HE DOESN'T PLAY.
MR. COM MISS ION ER
SU PPOSE WE GAVE
HIM A HEART.
IF THAT'S WHAT
MAKES HIM DIFFERENT
I THINK I COULD
OPERATE AND SU PPLY
HIM WITH A HEART.
YOU CAN DO THAT ?
NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
DO YOU WANNA PLAY?
OF COURSE H E
WANTS TO PLAY.
[Iaughs]
YOU'RE SURE?
I GUARANTEE IT.
IF HE WERE TO
BE GIVEN A HEART
WOULD YOU CLASS I FY
HIM AS A...
WELL, WHAT I MEAN IS,
WOULD YOU CALL HIM A...
HE HAD ME FOOLED
EVEN WITHOUT ON E.
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
WITH A HEART,
I'LL GIVE HIM
A TEM PORARY OKAY
U NTI L THE LEAG U E
M EETING IN OCTOBER.
THEN WE'LL HAVE
TO TAKE IT UP.
THE OTHER CLU BS
ARE GONNA SCREAM
BLOODY M U RDER.
I CAN JUST HEAR
DU ROCHER NOW.
[chuckling]
WELL, THEN IT'S
ALL SETTLED.
CASEY GETS A HEART
AND ACCREDITATION
AS BEING A HUMAN
AND THE
HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS...
TAKE IT, MOUTHY.
THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS
WIN THE PEN NANT
FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN 23 YEARS.
[jiggling]
(Beasley)
OPERATOR.
[jiggling]
OPERATOR!
OPERATOR, YOU SURE
YOU'RE RINGING THE
RIGHT NUMBER?
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
ANY N EWS?
THE OPERATOR
CAN'T GET AN ANSWER.
THE DOCTOR'S STILL
NOT AT HIS HOUSE.
MAYBE HE'S STILL
IN THE M I DDLE OF
THE OPERATION.
WHATSAMATTER? HE CAN'T
USE ONE HAND TO P ICK
U P A PHON E?
I CAN'T WAIT
ANY LONG ER.
I GOTTA GIVE
TH EM THE
LIN EU P.
CARTER, YOU START.
FOLLOWED BY
O'HARA, SM ITH
AND JONES.
NOW LISTEN,
YOU GUYS.
THAT'S THE
EN EMY OUT THERE.
THAT'S THE N EW
YORK GIANTS.
WHILE YOU'RE OUT THERE,
REMEMBER THERE'S
A BIG FELLOW
NAM ED CASEY
LYING ON A TABLE
STRUGG LING FOR
HIS LIFE.
AND I KNOW
THAT THE LAST
THING HE SAID
BEFORE THAT NIGHT
WHEN HE HAD
HIS CH EST,
[sniff]
HE SAID, "GO OUT
THERE, ZEPHYRS,
AND WIN THIS ONE
FOR THE BIG GUY."
PULL YOURSELF
TOGETHER, MON K.
AND I'LL TELL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE,
YOU GUYS,
FROM NOW ON, THERE'S
GONNA BE A GHOST IN
THE DUGOUT,
NUMBER 7.
OLD NUMBER 7.
SO JUST BEFORE
YOU GO TO BATTLE,
I WANT YOU TO LOOK OVER
TO WHERE HE USED TO S IT,
'CAUSE HE'S
GONNA BE THERE.
HE'S GONNA BE
THERE IN SP I RIT.
AND HE'S GON NA
BE YELLING FOR US,
AND ROOTI N' FOR US!
AND SCREAM I N'...
"GO, ZEPHYRS!
GO, GO, GO!"
HI, CASEY.
AND I'LL TELL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE
ABOUT THE BIG GUY.
HE HAS GOT A HEART.
CASEY!
[all shouting]
HOW ARE YOU,
OLD BOY?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
QU I ET DOWN. QU I ET DOWN.
WELL?
(Stillman)
TELL HIM, CASEY.
LISTEN, MR. MCGARRY.
[ticking]
YOU GOT A HEART.
LOOK AT
HIS SMILE.
THE ONE THING
I COULDN'T GET
HIM TO DO.
YEAH. IT'S WON DERFU L.
JUST WON DERFU L.
I FEEL
LIKE TOGETHERN ESS.
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GET
OUT THERE!
[shouting]
HERE YOU ARE, SEVEN.
GO SU IT UP.
TOGETHERN ESS.
PLAY BALL!
[crowd cheering]
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL LISTEN.
I'M A REASONABLE MAN,
I'LL LISTEN TO ANYTHING.
AS YOU WELL KNOW, DOCTOR,
BUT MAYBE YOU CAN TELL ME
HOW ONE MINUTE
HE CAN LOOK LIKE
THREE BOB FELLERS
AND THE NEXT LIKE
A TAN KER WITH NOTHING.
OR MAYBE YOU CAN
EXPLAIN, CASEY,
HOW YOU CAN P ITCH
N IN E BALLS AND ALLOW
FOUR SING LES
TWO DOUBLES,
TWO TRIPLES
AND A HOME RUN.
SHALL I TELL
HIM, CASEY?
WELL, SOMEBODY
TELL ME.
CASEY'S GOT
A HEART.
ALL RIGHT,
SO CASEY'S
GOT A HEART.
THE THING IS,
MR. MCGARRY,
I JUST COULDN'T
STRI KE THOSE
POOR FELLOWS OUT.
I DIDN'T HAVE
IT IN ME TO
DO THAT,
TO H U RT
THEIR FEELINGS.
I FELT COM PASS ION.
THAT'S IT. HE'S
GOT COMPASSION.
SEE HOW HE SMILES?
GIVE A MAN A HEART,
MR. MCGARRY,
PARTICU LARLY SOMEON E
LIKE CASEY
WHO HASN'T
BEEN AROUND
LONG ENOUGH
TO U N DERSTAND
COM PETITIVEN ESS OR
DRIVE OR EGO.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS.
I'M SORRY,
MR. MCGARRY.
I JUST CAN'T H U RT
FELLOWS' CAREERS.
DR. STILLMAN THINKS
I SHOU LD GO
INTO SOCIAL WORK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I WANT TO
H ELP PEOPLE.
BYE.
WELL, I KNOW SOMEBODY
HE CAN H ELP FOR A START.
M E.
PERHAPS YOU'D
LIKE TO KEEP
CASEY'S BLU EPRI NTS.
A LITTLE MEM ENTO
MIGHT CH EER YOU UP.
GOODBYE.
WAIT, WAIT.
HEY, DOC,
WAIT A MINUTE!
DOC!
HEY, DOC!
WAIT A MINUTE!
DOC!
HEY, DOC!
WAIT A MINUTE!
(male narrator)
ONCE UPON A TIME THERE WAS
A MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL TEAM
CALLED THE HOBOKEN ZEPHYRS
WHO DURING THE LAST YEAR
OF THEIR EXISTENCE
WOUND UP IN LAST PLACE
AND SHORTLY THEREAFTER
WOUND UP IN OBLIVION.
THERE'S A RUMOR,
UNSUBSTANTIATED, OF COURSE,
THAT A MANAGER NAMED MCGARRY
TOOK THEM TO THE WEST COAST
AND WOUND UP
WITH SEVERAL PENNANTS
AND A COUPLE
OF WORLD'S CHAMPIONSHIPS.
THIS TEAM HAD A PITCHING
STAFF THAT MADE HISTORY.
OF COURSE, NONE OF
THEM SMILED VERY MUCH
BUT IT HAPPENS TO BE A FACT
THEY PITCHED
LIKE NOTHING HUMAN
AND IF YOU'RE INTERESTED
AS TO WHERE THESE
GENTLEMEN CAME FROM
YOU M IGHT CHECK UNDER "B"
FOR "BASEBALL"
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male announcer)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK,
WE TAKE YOU BACK
INTO THE DARK AND H I DDEN,
U N EXPLORED RECESSES OF
A WRITER'S MIND,
AND DO SOME PROBING
AS TO JUST HOW THIS
TYPE OF B I RD OPERATES.
IT'S A FASCI NATING
EXCU RS ION INTO
THE ODDBALL.
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE NEXT
WEEK, KEENAN WYN N AND
PHYLLIS KI RK
STAR IN RICHARD MATH ESON'S
A WORLD OF HIS OWN,
AND IN THIS PARTICU LAR ON E,
EVEN THIS KOOKY WRITER GETS
INTO THE ACT.
GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
(male announcer)
KIMBERLEY CLARK
INVITES YOU
TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE
SAME STATIONS.