[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[thunder]
EXCUSE ME.
HM?
U H, THE BUS
TO CORTLAN D.
WHAT ABOUT H ER?
WELL, IT WAS DU E
A HALF AN HOUR AGO.
YU P, HALF HOUR AGO.
[sighs]
WHEN WILL IT BE I N?
HARD TO SAY.
BEEN RAINING HARD.
ROAD'S SLICK.
MAYBE A BRI DG E
OR TWO OUT.
THAT'LL PLAY HARD
WITH THE SCH EDU LE.
WELL, WHEN DO YOU
THINK IT WILL BE I N?
SHE'LL BE IN
WHEN SHE'LL BE IN.
THAT'S ALL.
I TOLD YOU THAT
THE LAST TIME YOU ASKED.
THE LAST TIME I ASKED?
THE LAST TIME I ASKED
WAS RIGHT NOW.
LOOK, ALL I WANT FROM YOU
IS A CIVI L ANSWER.
YOU'RE GETTING
A CIVI L ANSWER.
THE TROU BLE IS EVERY
TEN MINUTES YOU'RE
U P HERE REQU I RING ON E.
SITUATIONS JUST DON'T
CHANGE THAT RAPIDLY
AND YOU WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT THE CORTLAND BUS.
IT WAS LATE WHEN YOU ASKED
A HALF HOUR AGO
LATE WHEN YOU COME BACK
1 5 M INUTES LATER
AND IT'S LATE NOW.
AND ALL THE ASKING
IN THE WORLD
AIN'T GOING TO PUSH IT NON E.
BUT THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I'VE BEEN UP HERE--
THE VERY FIRST TIME.
E ITHER YOU NEED YOUR EYES,
NOW WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NOTHING.
NOTHING'S THE MATTER.
(male narrator)
M ILLICENT BARNES, AGE 25,
YOUNG WOMAN WAITING FOR A BUS
ON A RAINY NOVEMBER NIGHT.
NOT A VERY IMAGINATIVE TYPE
IS MISS BARNES.
NOT GIVEN TO UNDUE
ANXIETY OF FEARS
OR FOR THAT MATTER
EVEN THE MOST
TEMPORAL FLIGHTS OF FANCY.
LIKE MOST YOUNG CAREER WOMEN,
SHE HAS A GENERIC
CLASSIFICATION
AS A "GIRL WITH A HEAD
ON HER SHOULDERS."
ALL OF WHICHIS MENTIONED NOW
BECAUSE IN JUST A MOMENT
THE HEAD ON
MISS BARNES'S SHOULDERS
WILL BE PUT TO A TEST.
CIRCUMSTANCES WILL ASSAULT
HER SENSE OF REALITY
AND A CHAIN OF NIGHTMARES
WILL PUT HER SANITY
ON A BLOCK.
M ILLICENT BARNES,
WHO IN ONE M INUTE WILL WONDER
IF SHE'S GOING MAD.
[suspense music]
WELL, SHALL WE
RU N TH ROUG H IT
AGAIN, MISS?
OH, NO THANK YOU.
I WAS JUST NOTICING
IT ISN'T
VERY MUCH BUT,
BUT THAT BAG--
WHAT ABOUT IT?
WELL, IT'S J UST
LIKE M IN E.
IT'SIDENTICAL,
EVEN TO THE BROKEN HAN DLE.
WHAT IS THIS,
SOME KIND OF A GAME?
WHAT?
THAT IS YOUR BAG--
YOU CHECKED IT.
OH, NO, THAT ISN'T MY BAG.
IT LOOKS J UST
LIKE MY BAG, BUT MY--
[suspense music]
WELL, HOW--?
WILL YOU GO OVER
THERE AND S IT DOWN?
YOU'RE E ITHER WALKING
IN YOUR SLEEP
OR H U NG OVER
OR SOMETHING.
GO BACK OVER THERE
AND S IT DOWN
AND BREATH E
TH ROUG H YOUR NOSE
AND LET ME READ
MY MAGAZIN E.
WHEN THE CORTLAND BUS COMES
THERE'LL BE A LOU D SOU N D
OF AN ENG IN E, A DOOR OPENING,
PEOPLE WILL COME IN HERE.
THEN YOU'LL KNOW
THE BUS IS HERE.
BUT I DIDN'T CHECK MY BAG.
AND ANYWAY, WHEN I
SAW THAT, MY BAG--
ALL YOU
ALL RIGHT, MISS?
YES, OF COURSE
I'M ALL RIGHT.
I'M PERFECTLY ALL RIGHT.
WHY? DON'T I LOOK
ALL RIGHT?
YOU LOOK F IN E.
YOU LOOK JUST F IN E.
IT'S JUST THAT
WHEN YOU WERE
IN HERE BEFORE--
BEFORE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BEFORE?
I'VE NEVER BEEN
IN HERE BEFORE.
HONEY, YOU WERE
JUST IN HERE
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
ME?
I'VE NEVER BEEN
IN HERE BEFORE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THIS PLACE ANYWAY?
SOMEBODY KEEPS
TAKING MY BAG
SOMEBODY SAYS I KEEP
ASKING ABOUT THE BUS
AND YOU SAY I'VE
BEEN IN HERE BEFORE.
JUST TAKE IT EASY.
EVERYTHING'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
OF COURSE
EVERYTHING'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT!
NOTHING WRONG
TO BEG IN WITH.
THE ONLY THING WRONG
WITH YOU PEOPLE
IS YOU NEED SOME SLEEP
OR SOMETHING.
[gasps]
[suspense music]
LET ME GET YOU A
COLD CLOTH, HONEY.
I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE WELL.
NO, I DON'T
NEED THAT.
NO, I'LL
BE ALL RIGHT.
I M UST
BE OVERTIRED
BUT I'LL
BE ALL RIGHT.
[thunder]
EXCUSE ME.
YES?
I WON DER I F
YOU SAW SOMEON E
S ITTING IN MY SEAT.
I DON'T THINKS SO, MISS.
I WASN'T LOOKING
VERY CLOSE.
[mumbIing]
WHAT'S THE TROU BLE?
NO, NO TROU BLE.
I JUST THOUGHT
I SAW SOMEBODY
I KNEW.
IN HERE?
THANK YOU.
I'M SORRY TO HAVE
DISTU RBED YOU.
(Millicent)
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH ME?
WHAT ON EARTH IS
THE MATTER WITH ME?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
DELUSIONS,
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE.
THEY'RE DELUSIONS.
I MUST BE SICK.
I MUST BE RUNNING A FEVER.
I'M NOT EVEN WARM.
I DON'T HAVE ANY FEVER.
NO FEVER AT ALL.
(man)
EXCUSE ME, MISS.
YES.
OH.
YES, WHAT IS IT?
YOUR BAG, I THINK
YOU DROPPED IT.
OH, THANK YOU.
THE BUS IS LATE,
ISN'T IT?
IT SEEMS SO.
OVER A HALF
AN HOUR LATE.
YOU DO MEAN
THE BUS TO CORTLAN D,
DON'T YOU?
THAT'S THE ON E.
I WAS SU PPOSED
TO BE IN SYRACUSE
TONIGHT BY 1 0 :00.
THE PLAN ES WERE
ALL GROU N DED
SO I TOOK A CAB
FROM BING HAMTON.
IT SKI DDED
INTO A TREE
A FEW M I LES
OUTSIDE OF HERE.
I HAD TO WALK INTO
TOWN TO GET HERE.
FORGIVE ME, MISS,
YOU'RE NOT I LL,
ARE YOU?
OH, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME.
I-- I REALLY DON'T.
WELL, IS THERE
SOMETHING I CAN DO?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST THAT ALL SORTS
OF QU EER THINGS
HAVE BEEN HAPPENING TO ME.
I'VE BEEN SEEING THINGS.
SEEING THINGS?
WHAT SORT OF THINGS?
I'M NOT SURE
I SHOU LD TELL YOU.
YOU'D PROBABLY WANT TO MOVE
TO ANOTHER PART OF THE ROOM
OR CALL THE POLICE
OR AN AM BU LANCE
OR SOMETHING.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME.
MAYBE I CAN H ELP.
I NCI DENTALLY, MY NAME IS
G RI NSTEAD, PAU L GRI NSTEAD.
I'M FROM BING HAMTON.
HOW DO YOU DO?
I'M M I LLICENT BARN ES.
AT LEAST I WAS
M I LLICENT BARN ES.
I'M A PRIVATE
SECRETARY.
I QU IT MY JOB HERE
ON TH U RSDAY
AND I'VE GOT ANOTH ER
JOB IN BU FFALO.
THAT'S WHERE
I'M GOING TONIGHT,
TO BU FFALO.
EVERYBODY KEEPS TELLING ME
THAT I'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE.
THAT MAN WHO TAKES
THE TICKETS--
HE SAYS I KEEP ASKING
ABOUT THE BUS.
AND THE WOMAN IN
THE POWDER ROOM
SAYS I'VE BEEN IN THERE
BEFORE, AND I HAVEN'T.
AND MY BAG HERE,
[gasps]
MY BAG!
THERE IT IS.
OH.
OH, THANK GOD.
FOR A MINUTE I THOUGHT
EVERYTHING WAS STARTING
ALL OVER AGAIN.
THAT MAN SAID I
CHECKED IT AND I HADN'T.
BUT THERE WAS A BAG,
ALMOST I DENTICAL TO M IN E
IN THE BAGGAG E ROOM.
AND THEN WHEN I CAM E
OUT OF THE POWDER ROOM
IT WASN'T THERE.
GO ON.
WELL, IT SOU N DS
VERY STRANG E BUT,
WHEN I CAME OUT
OF THE POWDER ROOM
I LOOKED
IN THE M I RROR
AND I COULD
SEE THE WHOLE
WAITING ROOM
IN THE M I RROR,
AND I--
WELL, WHAT DID YOU SEE,
MISS BARN ES?
I SAW MYSELF S ITTING
RIGHT HERE ON THIS BENCH.
IT'S DELUS IONS.
YES.
YES, THAT'S WHAT
IT MUST BE.
DELUS IONS, SOME SORT
OF DELUS IONS.
BUT I'M NOT S ICK.
I DON'T HAVE A TEM PERATU RE.
I'M NOT RU N NING A FEVER.
BUT IT'S NOT
JUST SEEING THINGS
THAT DON'T EXIST.
WHY DID THAT MAN
AND THAT WOMAN SAY
THAT THEY HAD SEEN ME BEFORE?
I DON'T KNOW.
THIS ON E'S TOUG H
TO F IG U RE OUT.
WELL, WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
WHAT-- WHAT'S WRONG?
I'M NOT SOME SORT OF KOOK,
I'VE NEVER HAD ANY
TROU BLE LIKE THIS BEFORE,
I MEAN, TROU BLE
WITH MY MIND.
OF COURSE YOU HAVEN'T.
THERE'S AN EXPLANATION
SOM EPLACE.
THERE'S A REASON.
MAYBE--
MAYBE WHAT?
MAYBE THERE'S SOMEONE HERE
WHO RESEM BLES YOU.
THAT COULD BE IT.
OR MAYBE SOMEONE IS PLAYING
SOME KIND OF A JOKE
OR SOMETHING.
OH, IS THAT POSS I BLE?
OH, THAT'S TOO FANTASTIC
AND THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
ABOUT THE BAG.
AND ANYWAY, IF THERE IS
SUCH A PERSON, WHERE IS SH E?
WHERE IS THIS PERSON?
[bus engine]
(man)
BUS TO CORTLAND.
SYRACUSE, BU FFALO,
NOW ARRIVING.
LET ME TAKE THAT
FOR YOU.
LOOKS H EAVY.
OH, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
YOU'RE EASY
TO BE KIND TO.
NO, I MEAN, MORE
THAN JUST KIND.
WE BETTER GET
ON THE BUS.
I'LL TAKE YOUR BAG.
ALL RIGHT.
[gasps]
MISS BARN ES!
M I LLICENT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WAIT A MINUTE.
ON OUR WAY.
YOU AND THE LADY
COMING OR AREN'T?
NO, WE'LL WAIT
FOR THE NEXT ON E.
NEXT ONE AIN'T DU E
TILL 7 :00 IN THE MORNING.
YOU'VE GOT
A LONG WAIT.
THAT'S
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY.
I'M SHUTTING OFF
SOME OF THESE LIGHTS.
"WHEN NOT IN USE,
TURN OFF THE J U ICE."
THAT'S WHAT
I ALWAYS SAY.
I BEST BE
GETTING HOM E.
OH, I SURE HOPE
SHE FEELS BETTER.
THANK YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN
VERY N ICE.
OH, IT'S ALL RIGHT
BUT OFFHAN D, MISTER
I'D SAY SHE NEEDED
SOME LOOKING AFTER.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
YOU FEELING BETTER?
THE BUS.
IT HAD TO LEAVE.
THERE'LL BE ANOTH ER
BEFORE TOO LONG.
YOU DIDN'T GET ON.
I'M THIS
LATE ALREADY.
A FEW MORE
HOURS WON'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT SOMETHING.
IT'S VERY ODD, BUT,
I'VE BEEN REMEMBERING.
REMEMBERING WHAT?
ABOUT SOMETHING
I READ OR HEARD
ABOUT A LONG TIME AGO.
ABOUT DIFFERENT
PLAN ES OF EXISTENCE.
ABOUT TWO
PARALLEL WORLDS
THAT EXIST
SIDE BY SIDE
AND EACH OF US
HAS A COU NTERPART
IN THIS WORLD
AN D, AND SOMETIMES
TH ROUG H SOME FREAK
TH ROUG H SOMETHING
U N EXPLAINABLE
THIS COU NTERPART--
AFTER THE TWO
WORLDS CONVERG E--
COMES INTO OUR WORLD
AND IN ORDER
TO SU RVIVE
IT HAS TO TAKE OVER.
TAKE OVER?
REPLACE US.
MOVE US OUT
SO THAT IT CAN LIVE.
THAT'S A LITTLE
M ETAPHYS ICAL FOR ME.
I REMEMBER
READING IT SOMEWHERE.
EACH OF US HAS A TWI N
IN THIS OTHER WORLD,
AN I DENTICAL TWI N.
MAYBE THAT WOMAN I SAW--
M I LLICENT, THERE'S
ANOTHER EXPLANATION.
THERE HAS TO BE.
ONE THAT COMES
WITH MORE REASON.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT
BUT I KNOW
THAT'S WHAT'S HAPPENED.
THIS OTHER WOMAN,
MY COU NTERPART--
FORGET ABOUT IT, PLEASE.
DON'T THINK ABOUT IT.
I JUST THOUGHT OF SOMETHING.
I'VE GOT A GOOD FRI EN D
WHO LIVES IN TU LLY.
I'LL CALL HIM.
MAYBE HE'LL BRING H IS
CAR DOWN HERE FOR US.
HE MIGHT EVEN
DRIVE US INTO SYRACUSE.
I'LL CALL HIM.
ALL RIGHT, M I LLICENT?
SHALL I CALL MY FRI EN D?
U NASKED, I'LL TELL
YOU WHAT I THINK.
I'D SAY SHE'S GOT
A LEAK IN HER ATTIC.
PARALLEL PLAN ES.
COUNTERPARTS
FROM ANOTHER LIFE.
[guffaws]
YOU GOT A THING
ABOUT S ICK PEOPLE?
IS THAT IT?
POOR, POOR KI D.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
GO CALL YOUR FRI EN D.
HM?
YOUR FRI END IN TU LLY
WITH THE CAR.
I DON'T HAVE
ANY FRI END IN TU LLY.
SHE NEEDS H ELP, MEDICAL H ELP.
IF IG U RED IT WOULD
BE EASIER THIS WAY.
IF IG U RED SH E'D COME ALONG.
POOR KI D.
CAN I USE IT?
GO AHEAD.
WHO'RE YOU GOING
TO CALL?
THE POLICE, I GU ESS.
I THINK THEY'RE
THE ONES THAT
COULD H ELP US.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH, SH E
KIND OF GIVES ME THE WI LLI ES.
I'D AS LEAVE
SHE LEFT HERE SOMEHOW.
[suspense music]
WHERE ARE YOU?
WHERE DID YOU GO?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
(Millicent)
WHERE ARE YOU?
M I LLICENT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
HOW ABOUT GETTING
SOME FRESH AIR?
ALL RIGHT.
[screams]
(man)
DID YOU GET
HER OFF ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. THEY'RE GONNA TAKE
HER TO THE HOSP ITAL
FOR OBSERVATION.
WHAT WAS SH E
TALKING ABOUT?
SOMETHING ABOUT ANOTHER LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW. THAT'S
PART OF HER I LLN ESS, I GU ESS.
[sighs]
YOU SAID THE NEXT
BUS IS AT 7 :00?
YOU GOT ABOUT FOU R
AND A HALF HOURS, PAL.
YOU CAN TAKE A SNOOZE
ON THAT BENCH.
YOU'LL BE ALL ALONE,
NO NOISE WHATSOEVER.
THIS PLACE
IS LIKE A TOM B
BETWEEN NIGHT AND MORNING.
MAYBE I WILL GET SOME SLEEP.
[suspense music]
HEY.
HEY!
WHERE ARE YOU?
(male narrator)
OBSCURE AND METAPHYSICAL
EXPLANATION
TO COVER A PHENOMENA.
REASONS DREDGED
OUT OF THE SHADOWS
TO EXPLAIN AWAY THAT
WHICH CAN NOT BE EXPLAIN ED.
CALL IT PARALLEL PLANES
OR JUST INSANITY.
WHATEVER IT IS, YOU FIND IT
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, ON TWILIGHT ZONE,
WE PUT YOU ON A FRONT PORCH.
SUMMER EVENING,
TREE LIN ED STREET,
TYP ICAL SMALL TOWN.
AND THEN WE PULL THE RUG
FROM U N DER YOUR FEET AND WE
THROW A NIGHTMARE AT YOU.
CLAU DE AKI NS, JACK WESTON
AND BARRY ATWATER ARE
YOUR N EIGH BORS
JUST AT THAT MOM ENT WH EN
THE MONSTERS ARE DUE
ON MAPLE STREET.
DON'T CH ICKEN OUT.
SEE YOU NEXT WEEK.
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER MOST
THESE SAME STATIONS.