[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN
TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION,
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS
THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
WITNESS, IF YOU
WILL, A DUNGEON
MADE OUT OF MOUNTAINS,
SALT FLATS AND SAND
THAT STRETCH TO INFINITY.
THE DUNGEON HAS AN INMATE--
[honking horn]
JAMES A. CORRY--
AND THIS IS
HIS RESIDENCE:
METAL SHACK.
AN OLD TOURING CAR
THAT SQUATS IN THE
SUN AND GOES NOWHERE,
FOR THERE IS
NOWHERE TO GO.
FOR THE RECORD,
LET IT BE KNOWN
THAT JAMES A. CORRY
IS A CONVICTED CRIM INAL
PLACED IN
SOLITARY CONFINEMENT.
CONFINEMENT, IN THIS CASE,
STRETCHES AS FAR
AS THE EYE CAN SEE
BECAUSE THIS
PARTICULAR DUNGEON
IS ON AN ASTEROID
NINE M ILLION M ILES
FROM THE EARTH.
NOW WITNESS, IF YOU WILL
A MAN'S M IND AND BODY
SHRIVELING IN THE SUN--
A MAN DYING
OF LONELINESS.
(Corry, off)
ENTRY, 1 5TH DAY,
SIXTH MONTH, YEAR FOUR.
AND ALL THE
DAYS AND THE MONTHS
AND THE YEARS ARE THE SAME.
THERE'LL BE A SUPPLY SHIP
COMING IN SOON, I THINK.
THEY'RE EITHER
DUE OR OVERDUE.
AND I HOPE IT'S
ALLENBY'S SHIP
BECAUSE HE'S A DECENT MAN
AND HE BRINGS THINGS
FOR ME.
LIKE HE BROUGHT IN
THE PARTS FOR THAT
ANTIQUE AUTOMOBILE.
I WAS A YEAR
PUTTING THAT
THING TOGETHER,
SUCH AS IT IS.
A WHOLE YEAR
PUTTING AN
OLD CAR TOGETHER.
BUT THANK GOD FOR
THAT CAR, AND FOR
THE HOURS I USED UP,
AND THE DAYS
AND THE WEEKS.
I CAN LOOK AT IT
OUT THERE, AND I
KNOW THAT IT'S REAL.
REALITY IS WHAT I NEED.
BECAUSE WHAT IS THERE
LEFT THAT I CAN
BELIEVE IN?
THE DESERT AND THE WIND?
THE SILENCE?
OR MYSELF?
CAN I BELIEVE IN
MYSELF ANYMORE?
ALLEN BY?
ALLEN BY!
ALLENBY!
HOW ARE
YOU, CORRY?
ALL RIGHT. YOU?
QU ITE A PLACE
YOU'VE GOT HERE.
G LAD YOU
LIKE IT.
I DIDN'T SAY
I LIKED IT. I
THINK IT STIN KS.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO LIVE HERE.
NO, BUT I HAVE
TO COME BACK HERE
FOUR TIMES A YEAR.
THAT'S EIGHT MONTHS
AWAY FROM EARTH.
SOMETIMES MY
KIDS DON'T EVEN
RECOG N IZE ME.
BUT YOU, YOU'VE
GOT IT MADE HERE.
YEAH, THIS MAKES
FOR S IMPLE LIVING,
DOESN'T IT?
6,000 M I LES
FROM NORTH
TO SOUTH,
4,000 FROM
EAST TO WEST,
AND ALL OF IT
JUST LIKE THIS.
(Allenby)
ALL RIGHT, ADAMS,
CUT IT OUT.
NOW, WE'VE ONLY GOT
A 1 5-MINUTE LAYOVER.
NO ON E'S CHECKING
ON YOUR SCH EDU LE
WAY OUT HERE.
WE CAN PLAY A
COUPLE OF GAM ES
OF CARDS.
IF WE DELAY OU R
TIME OF DEPARTU RE,
IT JUST PLACES
US IN A DIFFERENT
ORB ITAL POS ITION.
WE'LL NEVER MAKE
IT BACK TO EARTH.
WE WOULD
HAVE TO STAY
HERE AT LEAST
1 4 DAYS BEFORE IT'S
IN POS ITION AGAIN.
OH, 1 4 DAYS!
I GOT SOME
BEER SAVED.
WE COULD PLAY
SOME CARDS.
I WISH WE COULD
BUT, LIKE I SAID,
WE'VE ONLY
GOT 1 5 MINUTES.
WHAT'S A
FEW MINUTES?
HEY, WE COULD
PLAY CH ESS.
I BU I LT
A CH ESS SET
AND EVERYTHING.
LET'S GO IN.
ALLEN BY, ONLY
TWO MINUTES
ARE GON E.
TWO MINUTES HAVE
PASSED ALREADY.
WE'VE ONLY
GOT 1 3 LEFT.
I DON'T WANT
TO FOU L UP
YOUR SCH EDU LE,
BUT HOW ABOUT
ONE GAME OF CARDS?
WE JUST DON'T
HAVE THE TIME.
WE'VE BEEN HERE
TWO MINUTES ALREADY,
AND H E
HASN'T ASKED
ABOUT THE PARDON.
HOW ABOUT
IT, ALLEN BY?
YOU'RE OUT OF LUCK,
THE SENTENCE READS
50 YEARS.
AND THEY'RE NOT
EVEN REVI EWING
CASES OF HOM ICI DE.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE
FOUR YEARS NOW,
SO THAT MAKES
46 MORE TO GO,
SO MAKE YOURSELF
COM FORTABLE, HUH?
CORRY, WE DON'T
MAKE THE RU LES.
WE DELIVER SU PPLI ES
AND PASS ON IN FORMATION.
THERE'S BEEN PRESSURE
BACK HOME ABOUT THIS
KIND OF PU N ISH MENT.
A LOT PEOPLE
THINK IT'S
U N N ECESSARI LY CRU EL.
THEY MAY
CHANG E THEIR MINDS
AND ALTER THE LAW,
AND IMPRISON
YOU ON EARTH
LIKE THE OLD DAYS.
BUT--
WHO KNOWS WHAT THE
NEXT COUPLE OF YEARS
MAY BRING?
YEARS?
EVERY MORNING,
WHEN I GET UP,
I TELL MYSELF THIS IS
MY LAST DAY OF SAN ITY.
I CAN'T STAND
THIS LON ELIN ESS
ONE MORE DAY.
NOT ONE MORE DAY!
BY NOON, WHEN I CAN'T
KEEP MY FING ERS STILL,
AND THE I NSIDE OF MY MOUTH
FEELS LIKE GU N POWDER
AND BU RNT COPPER,
DOWN DEEP
INSIDE MY GUT
I GET AN ACHE THAT'S
JUST PULLING EVERYTHING OUT.
THEN I FORCE MYSELF
TO HOLD ON FOR ONE
MORE DAY.
JUST ONE MORE DAY!
BUT I CAN'T DO THAT
FOR ANOTHER 46 YEARS.
I'LL GO RIGHT
OUT OF MY MIND.
YOU'RE BREAKING
MY HEART.
ADAMS, YOU AND
CARSTAIRS GO GET
THE SU PPLI ES.
MR. CORRY GOT
A BROKEN LEG?
YOU GO
DO WHAT
I TELL YOU.
(Allenby)
NOW.
THAT BIG CRATE?
YOU KNOW, THE
BIG ONE?
YOU TREAT
THAT ONE GENTLY.
BROUGHT YOU
SOME PAPERBACK BOOKS.
THANKS.
CORRY, I BROUGHT
YOU SOMETHING
ELSE TOO.
IT'D MEAN MY JOB
IF THEY EVER SUSPECT.
IT'D BE MY N ECK I F
THEY FOU N D OUT
FOR SURE.
LOOK, ALLEN BY.
I DON'T
WANT ANY GI FTS.
WANT TI DB ITS.
MAKES ME FEEL LIKE
AN AN I MAL IN A CAG E,
WITH AN OLD
LADY OUT THERE
WHO WANTS
TO THROW
PEAN UTS AT ME.
A PARDON, ALLEN BY.
THAT'S THE ONLY
G I FT I WANT.
I'M NOT A M U RDERER.
I KI LLED
IN SELF-DEFENSE.
THERE'S STILL A LOT
OF PEOPLE WHO
BELIEVE ME.
IT HAPPENS TO
BE THE TRUTH! I
KI LLED IN SELF-DEFENSE!
I KNOW. I
KNOW ALL
ABOUT IT.
AND I DOU BT I F
THIS WILL BE ANY
CONSOLATION TO YOU, BUT--
THIS ISN'T AN
EASY ASSIGN MENT
TO HAN DLE--
STOPPING HERE
FOUR TIMES A YEAR
AND HAVING TO LOOK
AT A MAN'S AGONY.
YOU'RE RIGHT, ALLEN BY.
THAT'S VERY
LITTLE CONSOLATION.
I CAN'T BRING
YOU FREEDOM.
ALL I CAN DO IS TRY
TO BRING YOU THINGS
TO H ELP KEEP
YOUR SAN ITY.
SOMETHING TO--ANYTHING
SO YOU CAN J UST
FIGHT LON ELIN ESS.
(Adams)
HEY, CAPTAIN!
YOU WANNA OPEN UP
THIS BIG CRATE?
NO. NOT YET.
U H, STAY OUT THERE.
I'LL BE RIGHT OUT.
WE GOT TO GO NOW.
WE'LL BE BACK
IN THREE MONTHS.
LOOK, WH EN
YOU OPEN UP
THAT CRATE
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU NEED TO DO.
THE ITEM'S
BEEN VACU U M-PACKED.
YOU'LL NEED
NO ACTIVATOR
OF ANY KIND.
THE AIR
WILL DO THAT.
THERE WILL BE
A BOOKLET I NSIDE
THAT WILL ANSWER
ANY OF YOUR QU ESTIONS.
CORRY.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT
IT IS I'VE BROUGHT,
SO I'D APPRECIATE
YOUR WAITING U NTI L
WE GET OUT OF SIGHT.
HAVE A GOOD
TRI P BACK.
GIVE MY REGARDS
TO BROADWAY.
SURE, CORRY.
I'LL SEE YOU
IN THREE MONTHS.
ALLEN BY?
I DON'T
MUCH CARE
WHAT'S IN IT,
BUT FOR
THE THOUGHT--
FOR THE DECENCY--
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE QU ITE
WELCOM E, CORRY.
CAPTAI N.
CAPTAI N?
CAPTAI N, WHAT'S
IN THE BIG
CRATE, HUH?
I'M NOT QU ITE
SURE, REALLY.
MAYBE IT'S J UST
AN I LLUS ION.
MAYBE IT'S
SALVATION. I
DON'T KNOW.
[sigh]
LET'S GO.
"YOU ARE NOW
THE PROU D POSSESSOR
"OF A ROBOT BU I LT
IN THE FORM OF A WOMAN.
"TO ALL I NTENT AND PU RPOSE,
THIS CREATU RE IS A WOMAN.
"PHYSIOLOGICALLY
AND PSYCHOLOGICALLY,
"SHE IS A HUMAN BEING
"WITH A SET OF EMOTIONS
AND A MEMORY TRACK,
"THE ABILITY TO REASON,
TO THINK AND TO SPEAK.
"SHE IS BEYON D
I LLN ESS AND, U N DER
NORMAL CI RCU MSTANCES,
"SHOU LD HAVE A LIFESPAN
"S IMI LAR TO THAT
OF A NORMAL HUMAN BEING.
HER NAME IS ALICIA."
[robot-Iike]
MY NAME'S ALICIA.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
GET OUT OF HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE!
I DON'T NEED
NO MACHINE.
GO ON! GET
OUT OF HERE!
MY NAME'S ALICIA.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
[playing Big Band swing]
I BROUGHT YOU
SOME WATER.
PUT IT OVER THERE.
IT'LL GET WARM
JUST S ITTING THERE.
[scoffs]
HOW WOULD
YOU KNOW?
I CAN FEEL TH I RST.
YEAH? WHAT ELSE
CAN YOU FEEL?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
CAN YOU
FEEL H EAT?
YES.
AND COLD?
AND H U NG ER?
HOW ABOUT PAI N?
CAN YOU FEEL PAI N?
THAT, TOO.
HOW?
YOU'RE A MACHINE,
AREN'T YOU?
YES.
WHY WOULD--
WHY DIDN'T THEY BU I LD YOU
TO LOOK LIKE A MACHINE?
WHY DIDN'T THEY BU I LD
YOU OUT OF METAL
WITH BOLTS AND WI RES
AND ELECTRODES
AND THINGS LIKE THAT?
WHY'D THEY
TURN YOU
INTO A LI E--
COVER YOU WITH SOMETHING
THAT LOOKS LIKE FLESH--
GIVE YOU A FACE?
A FACE
THAT IF I--
IF I LOOK AT LONG
ENOUGH, MAKES
ME THINK--
MAKES ME
BELIEVE THAT--
IT'S A LI E!
CORRY?
CORRY.
YOU MOCK ME,
YOU KNOW THAT?
WHEN YOU LOOK AT ME,
WHEN YOU TALK TO ME,
I'M BEING MOCKED.
I'M SORRY.
YOU H U RT
M E, CORRY.
H U RT YOU?
HOW CAN I H U RT YOU?
THIS ISN'T REAL FLESH.
THERE AREN'T
ANY N ERVES
U N DER THERE.
THERE AREN'T
ANY M USCLES
OR TEN DONS.
YOU'RE J UST
LIKE THIS H EAP--
A H U N K OF METAL
WITH ARMS AND LEGS
I NSTEAD OF WH EELS.
BUT THIS H EAP
DOESN'T MOCK ME
THE WAY YOU DO.
IT DOESN'T LOOK AT ME
WITH MAKE-BELIEVE EYES,
OR TALK TO ME WITH
A MAKE-BELIEVE VO ICE.
WELL, I'M S ICK
OF BEING MOCKED BY
THE MEMORY OF WOM EN.
AND THAT'S
ALL YOU ARE--
A REMINDER TO ME
THAT I'M SO LON ELY
I'M ABOUT TO
LOSE MY MIND.
I CAN FEEL
LON ELIN ESS, TOO.
OH, ALICIA, I'M SORRY.
(Corry, off)
ALICIA'S BEEN WITH
ME NOW FOR 1 1 MONTHS.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO WRITE DOWN
WHAT HAS BEEN THE SUM TOTAL
OF THIS VERY STRANGE
AND BIZARRE RELATIONSHIP.
IS IT MAN AND WOMAN?
OR MAN AND MACHINE?
I DON'T REALLY KNOW MYSELF.
BUT THERE ARE TIMES
WHEN I DO KNOW
THAT ALICIA IS SIMPLY
AN EXTENSION OF ME.
I HEAR MY WORDS
COMING FROM HER,
MY EMOTIONS.
THE THINGS THAT SHE
HAS LEARNED TO LOVE
ARE THOSE THINGS
THAT I'VE LOVED.
I'M NOT LONELY ANYMORE.
EACH DAY CAN
NOW BE LIVED WITH,
AND I LOVE ALICIA.
NOTHING ELSE MATTERS.
(Corry)
AND THAT'S THE STAR
[UNlNTELLlGlBLE].
THAT'S IN
THE CONSTELLATION
OF [UNlNTELLlGlBLE].
AND THERE'S
THE GREAT BEAR.
SEE IT WITH IT'S
PO I NTER STARS IN LIN E
WITH THE NORTH ERN STAR?
AND THERE'S THE
CONSTELLATION H ERCU LES.
GOD'S BEAUTY.
THAT'S RIGHT, ALICIA.
THAT STAR, CORRY.
WHAT'S THAT STAR?
THAT'S NOT A
STAR, THAT'S
A SH I P.
A SH I P?
BUT IT CAN'T
BE A SH I P.
THERE ISN'T ONE DU E
HERE FOR THREE MONTHS.
YOU SAID AFTER THE
LAST TIME, NOT FOR
ANOTHER THREE MONTHS.
IT MUST BE
ALLEN BY'S SH I P.
HE'S THE ONLY
ONE THAT EVER
COMES CLOSE.
THEY STOP AT
THE OTHER ASTERO I DS,
THEN THEY COME HERE.
THAT MEANS
WE'LL SEE THEM
IN THE MORNING.
WE'D BETTER
GET BACK TO
THE HOUSE THEN.
NO.
(AIIenby)
CORRY!
CORRY, WE'VE GOT
GOOD N EWS FOR YOU.
ALL THE SENTENCES
HAVE BEEN REVI EWED.
YOU'VE BEEN
GIVEN A PARDON!
WE'RE TAKING
YOU BACK HOM E
ON THIS SH I P,
BUT WE'VE GOT
TO TAKE OFF
FROM HERE
IN 20 MINUTES
AND WE CAN'T
WAIT LONG ER.
WE'VE BEEN DODGING
METEOR STORMS.
WE'RE ALMOST
OUT OF FUEL.
ANY LONGER
THAN 20 M INUTES,
AND WE'LL HAVE PASSED
THE POINT OF DEPARTURE,
AND I DON'T THINK
WE'D MAKE IT BACK.
ALLEN BY, WHAT
DID YOU SAY?
A PARDON!
CORRY, THEY'VE
G RANTED YOU
A PARDON!
BUT IT WON'T DO
US ANY GOOD
U N LESS YOU
GET READY
TO MOVE OUT.
WE P ICKED UP
SEVEN OTH ER
M EN OFF ASTERO I DS.
WE ONLY HAVE ROOM
FOR 1 5 POU N DS
OF STUFF.
PICK UP WHAT YOU NEED
IN A HURRY, LEAVE
THE REST BEH IN D.
1 5 POU N DS?
[laughs nervously]
I DON'T HAVE 1 5
POU N DS OF STUFF.
ALL I HAVE IS A SH I RT,
A LEDG ER BOOK,
A PENCI L
AND A PAIR
OF SHOES.
THAT CAR
THEY CAN KEEP.
THAT'LL BE
FOR THE NEXT
POOR DEVIL.
AW, THERE WON'T BE
ANY "NEXT POOR DEVIL."
GOOD.
GOOD. I'M
G LAD OF THAT.
ALICIA AND I WI LL
CLI M B INTO THAT
SH I P OF YOURS.
AND WE'LL LOOK
OUT THE PORT,
AND WE'LL GIVE
IT ALL A BIG
KISS GOODBYE.
WHO, CORRY?
OH, MY DEAR GOD,
I FORGOT H ER.
HE'S OUT
OF HIS MIND.
WHO'S ALICIA?
A ROBOT.
SHE'S A WOMAN.
CORRY, SH E'S
A ROBOT.
SHE'S A WOMAN!
SHE'S GENTLE
AND KIND.
ALLEN BY, SH E
KEPT ME ALIVE.
WHY, IF IT WASN'T
FOR H ER, I'D HAVE
BEEN F IN ISH ED.
I'D HAVE GIVEN UP.
THAT'S THE CRATE
YOU WOULDN'T LET
US LOOK AT.
WE CAN'T
LET THIS
BE A PROBLEM.
PROBLEM? THERE'S
NO MORE PROBLEMS.
THERE'S NO
MORE PROBLEMS ON
H EAVEN AND EARTH.
WE'LL JUST CLI M B
IN THAT SH I P
OF YOURS
AND WHEN WE H IT THAT
B IG, BEAUTIFUL
G REEN EARTH--
1 5 POU N DS.
OH, WAIT
A MINUTE.
YOU'LL HAVE
TO THROW OUT
SOME EQU I PM ENT.
ALICIA--SH E
WEIGHS MORE
THAN 1 5 POU N DS.
THAT'S EXACTLY
THE PO I NT, NOW.
OUR SH I P IS
STRI PPED NOW.
WE ONLY HAVE ROOM
FOR YOU AND THAT
LEDG ER AND PENCI L.
LEAVE THAT ROBOT.
SHE'S NOT A ROBOT!
SHE'S A WOMAN!
YOU LEAVE
HER BEH IN D,
THAT'S M U RDER!
WAIT A MINUTE.
I HAVEN'T GOT ANY
CHOICE. UNDERSTAND?
NO, YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND! SH E'S
NOT A ROBOT!
SHE'S A WOMAN!
ALICIA! ALICIA!
CORRY!
ALICIA!
ALICIA?
COME ON, CORRY.
(Adams)
WE JUST WANT YOU TO
GET YOUR GEAR PACKED
AND GET OUT OF
HERE. WE'VE GOT 1 5
MINUTES, CAPTAI N.
I'M NOT LEAVING
WITHOUT H ER!
CORY!
(Corry)
ALICIA!
ALICIA! ALICIA,
SHOW THEM!
TALK TO THEM!
(Corry)
TALK TO
THEM, ALICIA!
SHOW THEM!
ALICIA, SHOW THEM!
I DON'T HAVE
ANY CHOICE.
I HAVE
NO CHOICE
AT ALL.
(Alicia, softly)
CORRY?
NO!
NO!!
(Alicia, robot-like)
CORRY. CORRY.
[winding down]
[lower in pitch]
CORRY...CORRY...
[siIence]
(Carstairs)
WE'VE GOT TO GO
NOW, CAPTAIN.
(Allenby)
WE WILL
GO NOW.
COME ON, CORRY.
TIME TO GO HOME.
IT'S ALL
BEH IN D YOU
NOW, CORRY.
IT'S ALL
BEH IN D YOU.
IT'S LIKE
A BAD DREAM--
A NIGHTMARE.
WHEN YOU WAKE UP,
YOU'LL BE BACK
ON EARTH.
YOU'LL BE HOM E.
HOME?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL YOU'RE
LEAVING BEH IN D
IS LON ELIN ESS.
I M UST
REMEMBER THAT.
I MUST REMEMBER
TO KEEP THAT
IN MIND.
(male presenter, off)
ON A M ICROSCOPIC PIECE OF
SAND THAT FLOATS THROUGH SPACE
IS A FRAGMENT OF
A MAN'S LIFE,
LEFT TO RUST
AS THE PLACE
HE LIVED IN, AND
THE MACHINES HE USED.
WITHOUT USE,
THEY WILL DISINTEGRATE
FROM THE WIND AND THE SAND
AND THE YEARS THAT ACT
UPON THEM--
ALL OF
MR. CORRY'S MACHINES,
INCLUDING THE ONE
MADE IN HIS IMAGE,
KEPT ALIVE BY LOVE
BUT NOW OBSOLETE
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(2nd male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, A
DISTING U ISH ED ACTOR
LEN DS US HIS TALENTS
AS MR. BU RG ESS MEREDITH
ST ARS IN TIME ENOUGH
A T LAST.
THE STORY
OF A MAN WHO
SEEKS SALVATION
IN THE RU BBLE OF
A RU IN ED WORLD.
WE HOPE YOU'LL SHARE
THIS VERY STRANG E
EXPERI ENCE WITH US.
THANK YOU.
AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
.:: Team UNiT3D ::.
www.hd-united.com
(3rd. male presenter, off)
BE SURE TO SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS.
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW,
MONDAY NIGHTS
OVER MOST OF
THESE STATIONS.