[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION,
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION,
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS
THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
OH, MY DARLING.
TONY, NOW
YOU ARE GOING,
BUT I SHALL HAVE
A MEMORY OF YOU
FOR MY EYES,
THOUGHTS OF YOU
FOR MY MIND
AND A TOUCH OF YOU
FOR ALL OF ME.
I'LL NEVER FORGET YOU.
(male presenter, off)
PICTURE OF A WOMAN
LOOKING AT A PICTURE.
MOVIE GREAT
OF ANOTHER TIME.
ONCE-BRILLIANT STAR
IN A FIRMAMENT NO
LONGER A PART
OF THE SKY,
ECLIPSED BY
THE MOVEMENT
OF EARTH AND TIME.
BARBARA JEAN TRENTON,
WHOSE WORLD IS A
PROJECTION ROOM,
WHOSE DREAMS ARE MADE
OUT OF CELLULOID.
BARBARA JEAN TRENTON,
STRUCK DOWN BY
HIT-AND-RUN YEARS
AND LYING ON THE
UNHAPPY PAVEMENT,
TRYING DESPERATELY
TO GET
THE LICENSE NUMBER
OF FLEETING FAME.
MISS TRENTON?
[projector whirring]
MISS TRENTON!
WHAT IS
IT, SALLY?
[shouts startIed
and gasps]
I--I
BROUGHT YOU--
I BROUGHT
YOU A SNACK,
MISS TRENTON.
THANK YOU.
JUST PUT IT
DOWN THERE.
YES, MA'AM.
[doorbell rings]
HELLO, SALLY.
HELLO.
IS MISS TRENTON I N?
YES, S I R.
IN THERE FOR A CHANG E?
MR. WE ISS, I'M VERY
WORRI ED ABOUT H ER.
I'M WORRI ED ABOUT--
I'LL TALK TO H ER.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND,
MR. WE ISS.
IT'S GETTING
MUCH WORSE.
WELL, SHE'S BEEN
IN THERE TOO MUCH.
I THINK IT'S
BEG IN NING TO
DISTU RB YOU, TOO.
I'LL SEE
WHAT I CAN DO.
ALL RIGHT.
[movie soundtrack playing]
[orchestral flourish]
DAN I EL, F IX
YOURSELF A DRINK.
IT'S 1 1 :00
IN THE MORNING.
SO, IT'S 1 1 :00
(Daniel)
IN THE MORNING
AND THE
SUN IS OUT.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN BEVERLY HILLS.
THERE'S NO SMOG,
IT'S 84 DEG REES
[birds chirp]
AND IT IS LOVELY.
WHAT EVER WOULD I DO
WITHOUT YOUR DAI LY
WEATHER REPORTS?
QU ESTION IS
WHAT DO YOU
DO WITH THEM?
S IT HERE IN THIS
AIR-CON DITION ED CAVE
SHOWING ONE PICTURE
AFTER ANOTH ER.
LET'S SKI P IT.
BARB I E, IT'S
NO GOOD, HONEY.
NONE OF THIS
IS ANY GOOD.
IF YOU WON'T F IX
YOURSELF A DRINK,
S IT DOWN AND BE QU I ET.
YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE A
HAB IT OF LOOKING PO ISED,
READY TO SPRING.
WHAT WAS
THE PICTURE?
TWO OF THEM.
A FAREWELL
WITHOUT TEARS,
COSTARRING J ERRY HEARN DAN.
NOT COSTARRING,
DARLING, HE WAS
MY LEADING MAN.
1 933.
AND A NIGHT
IN PARIS.
1 934.
I KNOW IT
WAS 1 934.
WHAT ARE
YOU NOW?
FATHER TIME?
BARB I E--
LOOK, I FAI LED TO
M ENTION THIS BEFORE :
I HATE
CLIN ICAL TI PTOEING.
YOU DON'T LIKE
WHAT I DO, DON'T
KNOCK WHAT I DO.
BARB I E, I HAVE TO
KNOCK WHAT YOU DO,
AND I HAVE TO
GET CLIN ICAL
WHEN I SEE YOU BOTTLE
YOURSELF IN THIS ROOM
AND STOP THE CLOCK.
YOU PUT IT BACK
1 5, 20, 25 YEARS.
YOU DO THIS EVERY
DAY. NOW, HONEY,
THAT'S S ICK.
THAT IS
REALLY SICK.
IS THAT ALL?
NO, IT ISN'T.
I'VE SET UP
AN APPO I NTM ENT
FOR YOU TODAY
OVER AT I NTERNATIONAL.
AT I NTERNATIONAL?
YES.
A PART, DAN NY?
SOU N DS LIKE
A GOOD ON E, TOO.
WELL--OH, DARLING.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
IN EVER
DID GET ALONG
WITH MARTY SALL
WHEN I WAS U N DER
CONTRACT THERE.
HE'S MUCH
OLDER NOW.
I THINK YOU'LL F IN D
THAT HE'S MELLOWED.
OH, YOU KNOW,
HE SAID I WAS
THE MOST DI FF ICU LT
STAR H E'D EVER
WORKED WITH.
DAN NY, YOU'RE
A NICE GUY AND
A LOYAL FRI EN D.
AND IN
MY SELF ISH,
DEVIOUS WAY,
I'M VERY
MUCH IN
LOVE WITH YOU.
OH, DAN NY.
I HOPE IT'S
A MUSICAL.
OH, I'D LOVE
TO DANCE AGAIN.
[laughing]
OR A LOVE
STORY. OH, I'D
GIVE ANYTHING
TO PLAY LOVE
SCENES LIKE I
SAW THIS MORNING.
SCENES WITH
J ERRY HEARN DAN.
YOU KNOW,
WE DID THREE
PICTURES TOGETHER.
"I HAVE A MEMORY
OF YOU FOR
MY EYES.
"THOUGHTS OF YOU
FOR MY M IND
AND THE
TOUCH OF YOU
FOR ALL OF ME"
OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
AND THEN WE
DID A NIGHT IN
PARIS TOGETHER.
BARBARA, YOU WERE
MUCH YOU NG ER THEN.
GO TO THE DEVIL.
NOW, BARBARA,
HONEY, THIS
IS 1 959.
IT'S 25 YEARS
FFOM NIGHT IN PARIS
AND 26 YEARS
S I NCE YOU MADE
FAREWELL WITHOUT TEARS.
THAT ROOM ACROSS
THE HALL
IS DARK,
IT'S DAM P,
IT'S FU LL
OF COBWEBS.
SNAP OUT OF IT.
SNAP OUT OF
THIS KICK.
GET YOUR
WAR PAI NT ON
AND I'LL MEET YOU
OVER AT
SALL'S OFF ICE
AT 3 :00, OKAY?
OKAY, DAN NY.
SEND THEM IN.
NICE TO SEE YOU
AGAIN, BARBARA.
HELLO, MARTY.
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME.
YES.
S IT DOWN.
YOU KNOW DAN NY,
OF COURSE.
YES. H E'S
TOLD YOU
ABOUT THE PART?
WELL, UH,
NOT EXACTLY.
I THINK IT F ITS YOU.
IT'S NOT A BIG PART,
BUT I THINK IT'LL BE
A NICE SHOWCASE
FOR YOU.
NOT BIG, BUT A
NICE SHOWCASE?
OH, COME ON,
BE MORE SPECIF IC.
YOU, OF ALL
PEOPLE, MARTY,
SHOU LD KNOW WHAT
I DEMAND IN A PART.
WHY IS IT WE
ALWAYS SEEM TO
FIGHT, BARBARA?
DOESN'T THAT ALWAYS
SEEM TO BE THE CASE?
WE BEG IN BY FIGHTING.
I'M STILL
WAITING TO HEAR
ABOUT THE PART.
RAISE THE VE I L.
YOU PLAY A MOTH ER.
HOW OLD
A MOTH ER?
H M M, FORTYISH,
BUT VERY VI BRANT,
VERY MUCH ALIVE.
AS OPPOSED
TO WHAT?
A CORPSE?!
I DON'T
PLAY MOTH ERS,
MR. SALL.
I NEVER HAVE,
AND I WON'T
START NOW.
I ALSO DON'T TAKE
B IT ROLES, AND YOU
SHOU LD KNOW THAT!
COME ON, DAN NY.
LET'S GO.
(Sall)
I'M SORRY, BARBARA.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE STILL
SO PARTICULAR.
WELL, NOW YOU DO.
AT LEAST I WOULD
THINK YOU'D LOOK
AT THE PART.
IT'D BE A SH EER
WASTE OF MY TIME.
MAYBE WE SHOU LD
GET THE SCRI PT,
LOOK AT IT,
SEE WHAT IT'S
ALL ABOUT.
YOU LOOK AT IT AND SEE
WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT
AND YOU PLAY THE PART.
I NEVER DID LIKE
THIS TASTELESS,
CRU DE MAN
WHEN I WAS U N DER
CONTRACT HERE
AND I DON'T LIKE
HIM ANYMORE NOW
WHEN HE OFFERS ME
FAST BIT PARTS.
ALL RIGHT, MISS--
MISS PRI MA DON NA.
YOU, I GOT
N EWS FOR.
YOU MAY THINK
YOU ARE STILL
THE NUMBER-ONE LADY
ON THE TOP OF THE
H EAP, BUT YOU'VE
GOT IT WRONG.
YOU'RE J UST
AN AGING BROAD
WITH A SCRAPBOOK.
LOOK, MARTY--
ANY PART
YOU GET AT
THIS STU DIO
WON'T HAVE TO GO
TH ROUG H AN AG ENT.
WE CAN SET
IT UP TH ROUG H
THE COM M U N ITY CH EST
BECAUSE IT'LL
BE CHARITY!
SALL?
REMIND ME SOMEDAY
WHEN YOU'VE GON E
OVER THE H I LL
AND YOU'RE DOWN ON
YOUR HAN DS AND KN EES,
REMIND ME TO GIVE YOU
A SWI FT KICK IN
THE TEETH
SO THAT YOU KNOW
EXA CTL Y HOW IT FEELS!
BARB I E?
WHAT?
YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT HIM.
HE'S A PETTY
LITTLE MAN.
A MEAN TEM PER
AND A DIRTY MOUTH.
YOU SHOU LDN'T PAY
ANY ATTENTION
TO HIM.
YOU TALKING
ABOUT MARTY SALL?
YES.
HE DOESN'T EXIST.
THAT STU DIO
DOESN'T EXIST.
NOT ANYMORE,
NOT THE WAY
IT IS NOW.
THIS IS
THE WORLD, DAN,
RIGHT IN HERE.
FROM NOW ON,
I KEEP
THE DRAPES DRAWN
AND DOORS LOCKED.
I DON'T WANT ANY OF
THE OUTSIDE WORLD
COMING IN.
NOT THE MARTY SALLS
OR THE MOVIES
WITHOUT SENTIMENT,
ACTORS IN U N DERSH I RTS,
ROCK AND
ROLL, JUKEBOXES,
NOT ANY OF IT.
WH ETHER YOU
LIKE IT OR NOT,
THAT'S THE WAY
THINGS ARE,
THAT'S THE
WAY IT IS.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
SHUT YOUR EYES,
SAY IT DOESN'T EXIST
BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T SEE IT?
IT DOESN'T
HAVE TO EXIST
IF I SHUT MY EYES.
IF I SHUT MY EYES,
IT ALL DISAPPEARS.
IF I WISH HARD ENOUGH,
I CAN WISH IT
ALL AWAY.
AS OF THIS MOM ENT--
RIGHT NOW, DAN NY--
THESE ARE
THE 1 930s AGAIN
WITH ALL
THE CHARM
AND ROMANCE
ALL THE GAI ETY.
THAT WAS
A CAREFREE
WORLD, DAN NY,
AND I'M GON NA
MAKE IT THAT
WAY AGAIN.
YOU CAN'T!
IT'S NOSTALG IC,
IT'S N ICE, BUT
IT'S NOT TRU E.
IT'S PHONY.
IT DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE PHONY.
IF I WISH HARD ENOUGH,
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO
BE PHONY.
DARLING, WE'LL
GIVE A PARTY.
WE'LL I NVITE
ALL MY FRIENDS.
YOU TELL THEM
I'M STILL HERE
AND WHAT IT'S
LIKE HERE.
TELL J ERRY HEARN DAN
STEVE BLACK,
PAU L NADER--
TELL THEM, DAN NY.
BARBARA, THIS
IS RI DICU LOUS.
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN?
PAU L NADER'S
BEEN DEAD FOR
FIVE YEARS.
J ERRY HEARN DAN
LIVES IN CH ICAGO.
STEVE BLACK HASN'T
BEEN AROUND FOR
1 5 YEARS.
AND IF I COULD GET
TH EM, WHAT KIND
OF A PARTY
DO YOU THINK I CAN
I NVITE THEM HERE?
DON'T YOU U N DERSTAND
WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
YOU'VE BU I LT YOURSELF
A GRAVEYARD HERE.
YOU KEEP WISHING FOR
THINGS THAT ARE DEAD!
[romantic music pIaying]
(JERRY)
ALL FOR YOU.
WITH LOVE,
FROM ME.
SALLY, IS
SHE ALL RIGHT?
I WISH I COULD
TELL YOU,
MR. WE ISS,
BUT I
DON'T SEE
HER ANYMORE.
SOMETIMES HER BED'S
NOT EVEN SLEPT IN.
SHE JUST STAYS
IN THAT ROOM
ALL THE TIME,
DAY AND NIGHT.
A COUPLE OF TIMES
WHEN I'VE GON E
IN THERE--
I TELL YOU,
I DON'T WANT
YOU TO THINK
I'VE GON E
OUT OF MY MIND
OR SOMETHING--
BUT I SWEAR TO YOU,
I SEE HER UP ON
THAT SCREEN.
NOW, SALLY,
DON'T, PLEASE.
DON'T UPSET YOURSELF.
THERE'LL BE
A GENTLEMAN BY
IN A LITTLE WHILE--
A MR. HEARN DAN.
J ERRY HEARN DAN?
WHO PLAYED
OPPOS ITE MISS TRENTON?
HE'S IN TOWN ON
A BUS IN ESS TRI P,
AND I THOUGHT
IT MIGHT BE GOOD
FOR HER TO SEE HIM.
TAKE HIM INTO
THE STU DY WH EN
HE COMES.
[knock at door]
(Daniel)
BARBARA, IT'S
ME, DANNY.
CAN I COME
IN, PLEASE?
DAN NY, PLEASE
GO AWAY!
OH, BARBARA, PLEASE.
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
IMPORTANT TO TELL YOU.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DON'T LIKE
THE MERCHAN DISE?
THE MERCHAN DISE
IS BEAUTIFUL
BUT IT LOOKS
A LITTLE TIRED,
LIKE IT HASN'T SLEPT
IN A COUPLE OF WEEKS
AND COULD USE SOME
FRESH AIR AND SU N.
IT'S QU ITE HAPPY.
THANK YOU FOR THE
WEATHER REPORT
AND THE DOOR'S
THE SAME ONE
YOU CAME IN.
A FRI EN D'S COMING
TO SEE YOU TODAY.
FRI EN D?
OH, I THOUGHT
ALL MY FRIENDS
WERE DEAD,
RETIRED OR FORGOTTEN.
YOU TOLD ME
THAT YOURSELF.
AH, BUT
THIS ON E'S
AN OLD FRI EN D.
HE'S IN TOWN AND
H E'D LOVE TO
SEE YOU.
TELL HIM I'M NOT
RECE IVING THIS YEAR.
IT'S JERRY
HEARNDAN, BARBARA.
J ERRY?
J ERRY!
WHERE IS H E?
HE'S IN TOWN
ON BUS IN ESS.
I HAPPENED
TO MEET HIM
AT THE HOTEL.
HE ASKED ABOUT YOU,
ASKED IF HE COULD
COME TO SEE YOU
AND I TOOK
THE LI BERTY.
OH, IMUST
LOOK AWFU L.
OH, DARLING,
WHEN HE GETS HERE,
TAKE HIM INTO
THE STU DY.
I'VE GOT TO DO
MY FACE, CHANG E.
H E'D LOVE YOU IF YOU
CAME DOWN IN SACKCLOTH,
BUT GO AHEAD.
I'LL HURRY.
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME,
BARBARA J EAN.
A LOT OF WATER
OVER THE DAM.
YES.
ISN'T IT ODD
WE ALWAYS
PICTURE PEOPLE
THE WAY THEY WERE,
N EVER AS THEY
REALLY ARE?
FU N NY. I THOUGHT
YOU'D BE IN HERE
IN AN
OFFICER'S U N I FORM,
OR WH ITE TI E, TAI LS,
WITH A
CHAM PAG N E GLASS.
THAT'S HOW I
THOUGHT YOU'D BE.
THAT WAS 20
YEARS AGO.
I EVEN HAD
SOME CRAZY IDEA
THAT WE'D DO
ANOTHER PICTURE
TOG ETHER AGAIN.
NO, BARB I E,
I GAVE THAT
U P LONG AGO.
THAT WENT
DOWN THE DRAI N
WITH MY YOUTH.
YOU DON'T
ACT ANYMORE?
WHAT DO
YOU DO?
[chuckIes]
I RU N A STRING
OF SU PERMARKETS
OUTSIDE OF CH ICAGO.
A STRING
OF SU PERMARKETS?
M M-H M M.
OUTSIDE OF CH ICAGO?
THAT'S N ICE.
HE'S THE ONE
I EXPECTED.
HE'S THE ONE I
WANTED TO HAVE
COME AND SEE ME.
BUT H E'S
DEAD NOW.
DEAD LIKE ALL
THE OTH ERS.
BARB I E. BARB I E, PLEASE.
GO A WA Y,
BOTH OF YOU!
PLEASE GO AWAY!
[crying]
GO AWAY!
GOODBYE,
BARBARA J EAN.
GOODBYE, MY DEAR.
[movie soundtrack pIaying]
THERE YOU
ARE, J ERRY.
THERE YOU ARE.
YOU LOOK SO YOU NG.
SO WON DERFU LLY YOU NG.
WHO'S THE STRANG E
OLD MAN HERE
A WHILE AGO
WHO SAID
HE WAS YOU?
J ERRY--
I WISH
I COULD BE
THERE WITH YOU.
I WISH I COULD
BE UP THERE
WITH YOU.
I WISH.
OH, HOW I WISH.
MISS TRENTON?
I'VE BROUGHT
YOU A LITTLE
SNACK, DEAR.
WOULDN'T YOU
LIKE SOME COFFEE?
[projector whirring]
WHO SHUT IT OFF?
I--I DID.
AN HOUR AGO.
AND THEN
I CALLED YOU.
HAVE YOU LOOKED
IN HER ROOM?
THAT'S THE FIRST
PLACE I CHECKED.
THEN I WENT
TO EVERY ROOM
IN THE HOUSE.
SHE'S NOT HERE.
AT LEAST
NOT IN THE
WAY THAT--
SHE'S NOT HERE
THE WAY YOU
AND I ARE.
YOU'RE GON NA
RU N IT,
MR. WE ISS?
YES, SALLY.
I'M GONNA RU N IT.
[suspenseful soundtrack]
[laughter and chatter]
DARLINGS, IT'S
SO GOOD TO
SEE YOU.
WE'RE ALL HAVING
DINNER BY THE POOL.
PLEASE, EVERYONE OUTSIDE.
OH, STEVE.
PAUL.
JERRY.
BARB I E!
PLEASE! COME
BACK, BARBARA!
BARB I E, IT'S
M E, DAN NY.
BARBIE, COME BACK!
PLEASE, BARBIE!
BARB I E!
COME BACK, BARB I E!
TO WISH ES, BARB I E,
TO THE
ON ES THAT
COME TRU E.
(male presenter, off)
TO THE WISHES
THAT COME TRUE--
TO THE STRANGE,
MYSTIC STRENGTH
OF THE HUMAN ANIMAL
WHO CAN TAKE
A WISHFUL DREAM
AND GIVE IT
A DIMENSION
OF ITS OWN.
TO BARBARA JEAN TRENTON,
MOVIE QUEEN OF
ANOTHER ERA,
WHO HAS CHANGED THE
BLANK TOMB OF AN EMPTY
PROJECTION SCREEN
INTO A PRIVATE WORLD.
IT CAN HAPPEN--IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, WE I NVITE YOU
TO TAKE A STRANG E JOU RN EY
BACK IN TIME
WITH MR. GIG YOU NG,
WHO TRI ES TO MAKE
THE EXODUS OF ALL MEN
IN THEIR DESPERATE
ATTEM PT TO RELIVE
THE PAST.
WE OFFER A
MOST B IZARRE STORY
CALLED WALKING DISTANCE.
WE HOPE YOU'LL BE
AROUND TO SHARE
IT WITH US.
THANK YOU.
AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES
YOU TO WATCH
STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD
OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER
MOST OF THESE
SAME STATIONS.