[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
TWO, THREE, FOUR.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
MRS. CHESTER,
HAVE YOU EVER READ
DAVID COPPERFIELD?
HOW'S THAT?
IT'S A WONDERFUL BOOK.
THERE'S THIS
POOR LITTLE FELLA
AND HIS FATHER
HAS PASSED AWAY
AND HIS MOTHER
HAS MARRIED
THIS MISERABLE MAN
CALLED MURDSTONE.
ISN'T THAT
A VILLAINOUS
NAME? MURDSTONE.
WELL, THIS MURDSTONE
HAS A SISTER
CALLED JANE--
MR. BEM IS,
YOU SHORTCHANGED ME AGAIN.
YOU OWE ME
ONE MORE DOLLAR.
SEE?
THERE'S ONLY 24 HERE
AND THERE
SHOULD BE 25.
OH, I'M TERRIBLY SORRY,
MRS. MURD-- ER, UH--
MRS., UH, CHESTER.
I THOUGHT THERE WAS FIVE ONES
AND THERE'S ONLY FOUR.
I THOUGHT
I'D GIVEN YOU FIVE.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
THEN THERE'S ANOTHER
FUNNY CHARACTER,
CALLED M ICAWBER,
MR. M ICAWBER.
AND HE'S
ALWAYS BEING SENT
TO DEBTOR'S PRISON.
HM!
THEN THERE'S
ANOTHER CHARACTER
CALLED PEGGOTY.
THAT IS DAVID'S--
NURSE.
[sighs]
OH, WELL.
[mumbIes]
YES, SIR?
I WONDER IF IMIGHT
SEE YOU IN MY OFFICE,
MR. BEM IS?
WHY, CERTAINLY,
MR. CARSVILLE.
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'VE READ
DAVID COPPERFIELD?
NO, MR. BEM IS,
I HAVE NOT.
NOW IF YOU'D KINDLY
ACCOMPANY ME.
(male presenter, off)
WITNESS MR. HENRY BEMIS,
A CHARTER MEMBER
IN THE FRATERNITY
OF DREAMERS.
A BOOKISH LITTLE MAN
WHOSE PASSION
IS THE PRINTED PAGE
BUT WHO IS CONSPIRED
AGAINST BY A BANK
PRESIDENT AND A WIFE
AND A WORLD FULL
OF TONGUE-CLUCKERS
AND THE UNRELENTING
HANDS OF A CLOCK.
BUT IN JUST A MOMENT
MR. BEMIS WILL ENTER A WORLD
WITHOUT BANK PRESIDENTS,
OR WIVES, OR CLOCKS,
OR ANYTHING ELSE.
HE'LL HAVE A WORLD
ALL TO HIMSELF,
WITHOUT ANYONE.
(President)
NOW, MR. BEMIS
I SHALL COME
TO THE POINT.
I SHALL ARRIVE VIA
THE FOLLOWING ROUTE
WHICHIS NAMELY,
"WHAT CONSTITUTES
AN EFFICIENT MEMBER
OF THIS ORGANIZATION?"
VIZ, A BANK TELLER
WHO KNOWS HIS JOB
AND PERFORMS IT.
I.E.,
AN ORGANIZATION MAN
WHO FUNCTIONS
WITHIN AN ORGANIZATION.
YOU, MR. BEM IS,
DO NOT FUNCTION
WITHIN THE ORGANIZATION.
YOU ARE NEITHER
AN EFFICIENT BANK TELLER
NOR A PROFICIENT EMPLOYEE.
YOU, MR. BEM IS, ARE A READER.
A "READER"?
A READER!
A READER OF BOOKS,
MAGAZINES
PERIODICALS, NEWSPAPERS.
I SEE YOU CONSTANTLY
GOING DOWNSTAIRS
INTO THE VAULT
DURING YOUR LUNCH HOUR.
ULTIMATUM, MR. BEM IS!
YOU'LL HENCEFORTH
DEVOTE YOUR TIME
TO YOUR JOB
AND FORGET
READING, OR YOU'LL
FIND YOURSELF OUTDOORS
ON A PARK BENCH READING
FROM MORNING TILL NIGHT
FOR WANT OF HAVING A JOB.
DO I MAKE MYSELF
PERFECTLY CLEAR?
THAT'S PERFECTLY
CLEAR, SIR. IT'S
JUST THAT,
JUST THAT WHAT, BEM IS?
MAKE IT QUICK
AND GET BACK TO YOUR CAGE.
IT'S JUST THAT MY WIFE
WON'T LET ME READ AT HOME.
SEE, WHEN I GET
HOME AT NIGHT AND TRY
TO PICK UP A NEWSPAPER
SHE YANKS IT OUT OF MY HAND
AND AFTER DINNER
IF I TRY TO FIND
A MAGAZINE, SHE HIDES THEM.
WELL, I GOT SO DESPERATE
THAT I FOUND MYSELF
TRYING TO READ THE LABELS
ON THE CONDIMENT BOTTLES
ON THE TABLE.
NOW, SHE WON'T
EVEN LET ME USE
THE CATSUP.
UNASKED, I GIVE
MY REACTION TO THIS.
YOUR WIFE
IS AN AMAZINGLY
BRIGHT WOMAN.
I REMEMBER LAST NOVEMBER
YOU SPENT THE DAYS
READING CAMPAIGN BUTTONS
ON CUSTOMERS' LAPELS.
YOU WILL RECALL
THE LADY WHO TOOK
EXCEPTION TO THIS
AND TRIED TO HIT YOU
WITH HER UMBRELLA.
YES, I REMEMBER THAT.
I NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO TELL HER
THAT I WAS ONLY
LOOKING TO SEE
WHO SHE VOTED FOR.
GOOD DAY, BEM IS.
[cIears throat]
[startIed gasp]
(wife, shrill call)
HENRY!
YES, DEAR?
I'M IN THE LIVING ROOM!
YOU WANT MORE
COFFEE OR DON'T YOU?
NO, THANK YOU, DEAR.
BUT THEN WHY DON'T
YOU TELL ME THAT,
AND DON'T SNEAK OFF
INTO THE LOVING ROOM
TO BURY YOURSELF IN NEWSPRINT?
I THINK WE'VE
BEEN OVER THIS
QUITE ENOUGH, HENRY.
I WON'T TOLERATE A HUSBAND
OF MINE SACRIFICING THE ART
OF CONVERSATION.
[chuckIes]
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
NO, NO, DEAR, IT'S
JUST THAT YOU SAID
"A HUSBAND OF M INE."
HOW MANY HUSBANDS
HAVE YOU GOT? YOU'VE
ONLY GOT ME!
I WOULD APPRECIATE THAT
NOT BEING RUBBED IN!
[beats newspaper]
WE'RE PLAYING CARDS
TONIGHT. I WANT YOU
TO CHANGE YOUR SHIRT.
WE'RE GOING OVER
TO THE PHILLIPS' HOUSE.
OH, DEAR.
ALL RIGHT, HENRY.
ANYTHING TO SAY?
NO, DEAR, NOTHING TO SAY.
WHAT TIME
DO WE DO THAT?
IN ABOUT 1 5 M INUTES.
I'LL BE READY ON TIME.
SEE THAT YOU ARE!
[startIed]
OH!
HENRY?
YES, MY DEAR?
WHAT HAVE
YOU GOT, HENRY?
GOT?
GOT!
NOTHING, MY DEAR.
WHAT'S THIS?
WHAT, THAT?
THIS!
ISN'T THAT ODD?
HOW DID THAT
GET HERE?
I CAN ONLY HAZARD
A GUESS.
"A BOOK
OF MODERN POETRY."
YOURS, HENRY?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO READ ME SOME?
READ YOU SOME?
DO YOU MEAN
READ YOU OUT LOUD
OUT OF THE BOOK?
DO YOU WANT TO?
OH, I WOULD LOVE TO.
YOU KNOW,
THERE ARE SOME
LOVELY THINGS IN HERE.
THERE ARE
ONE OR TWO THINGS
FROM T.S. ELIOT
AND EDNA ST. VINCENT M ILLAY,
ROBERT FROST, CARL SANDBURG.
HELEN.
WHO DID THIS, HELEN?
WHO DO YOU THINK
DID IT, HENRY?
YOU SHOULD
THANK ME, REALLY.
A GROWN MAN WHO READS SILLY
RIDICULOUS,
NONSENSICAL DOGGEREL.
THIS ISN'T DOGGEREL!
THERE'S SOME BEAUTIFUL
THINGS HERE.
I SAY IT'S DOGGEREL.
AND I ALSO SAY
IT'S A WASTE OF TIME.
HELEN, HELEN,
DON'T DO THAT!
HELEN, PLEASE
WHY, HELEN?
WHY DO YOU DO
THESE THINGS?
BECAUSE I'M
MARRIED TO A FOOL.
[crash]
[expIosion]
(Carsville)
I CAN ONLY TELL YOU
THAT IN ADHERENCE TO DUTY,
A CONSTANT REMEMBRANCE
THAT A BANK,
LIKE A POLITICAL OFFICE
IS A PUBLIC TRUST.
THESE THINGS
ARE OF THE ESSENCE.
THOSE THINGS ARE BASIC
ABOVE ALL THINGS.
JUST THE QUALITIES
I'VE MENTIONED.
MISS JACKSON, THAT'S MY SPEECH
FOR THURSDAY NIGHT BANQUET.
WOULD YOU TYPE THAT--
[expIosion]
(presenter, off)
SECONDS, MINUTES, HOURS,
THEY CRAWL BY
ON HANDS AND KNEES
FOR MR. HENRY BEMIS
WHO LOOKS FOR A SPARK
IN THE ASHES OF A DEAD WORLD.
A TELEPHONE CONNECTED
TO NOTHINGNESS.
A NEIGHBORHOOD BAR, A MOVIE
A BASEBALL DIAMOND,
A HARDWARE STORE
THE MAILBOX OF WHAT
WAS ONCE HIS HOUSE
AND IS NOW A RUBBLE.
THEY LIE AT HIS FEET
AS BATTERED MONUMENTS
TO WHAT WAS, BUT IS NO MORE.
HELEN!
WHERE ARE YOU?!
(male presenter, off)
MR. HENRY BEMIS,
ON AN EIGHT-HOUR TOUR
OF A GRAVEYARD.
THEY'RE ALL DEAD.
THEY MUST BE.
EVERYBODY'S DEAD EXCEPT
ME.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHY AM I ALL RIGHT?
I WAS RIGHT THERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF--
THE VAULT!
I WAS DOWN IN THE VAULT.
THAT'S WHY I'M ALIVE.
I WENT DOWN IN THE--
THE THING OF IT IS, THOUGH,
THE THING OF IT IS
I'M NOT AT ALL SURE
THAT I WANT TO BE ALIVE.
WELL, I'M NOT
GOING TO STARVE
TO DEATH ANYWAY.
LOTS OF FOOD.
FOOD ENOUGH TO LAST
FOR YEARS AND YEARS
AND YEARS
AND YEARS.
ALL THE FOOD I CAN EAT.
ALL THE FOOD
AND MORE TOO.
[humming]
LET'S SEE, THE WORST PART,
THE VERY WORST PART
IS BEING ALONE.
IS THIS HOW IT'S GOING TO BE
SITTING AROUND DAY AFTER DAY
EATING?
SMOKING A CIGARETTE.
READING THE SAME HALF
OF A NEWSPAPER
OVER AND OVER,
AND OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
[horn honking]
[engine sputtering]
IS SOMEONE THERE?
PLEASE, SOMEONE!
SOMEONE!
NO. NO. NO.
NO. NO, THAT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
NO, IT DOESN'T. IT DOESN'T
MAKE A BIT OF DIFFERENCE.
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS SOLITUDE.
I'VE NEVER HAD MUCH SOLITUDE.
I HAVE ENOUGH
TO OCCUPY MY M IND
AND MY TIME.
I HAVE ENOUGH FOOD
AND I'M REALLY
VERY FORTUNATE.
YES, I'M REALLY
EXTREMELY FORTUNATE.
HELP. HELP. HELP.
SOMEONE, PLEASE! SOMEONE!
PLEASE. PLEASE, SOMEONE!
SOMEONE! PLEASE!
SOMEONE, PLEASE!
SOMEONE.
[suspense music]
IF IT JUST WEREN'T
FORTHE LONELINESS.
IF IT JUST
WEREN'T FOR THE SAMENESS.
IF THERE WERE
JUST SOMETHING
TO DO, DO, DO.
OH, WELL,
I'M SURE I'LL BE FORGIVEN
FOR THIS--
THE WAY THINGS ARE.
I KNOW I'LL BE FORGIVEN.
COLLECTED WORKS OF DICKENS!
COLLECTED WORKS
OF GEORGE BERNARD SHAW!
POEMS BY BROWNING!
SHELLEY, KEATS.
GREAT DRAMAS OF THE WORLD!
BOOKS. BOOKS.
ALL THE BOOKS I'LL NEED.
ALL THE BOOKS
I'LL EVER WANT.
SHELLEY, SHAKESPEARE,
SHAW, OH.
ALL THE BOOKS I WANT.
ALL THE BOOKS.
AH.
[sighs]
JANUARY,
FEBRUARY, MARCH,
APRIL,
MAY,
THIS YEAR,
THE NEXT YEAR,
AND THE YEAR AFTER,
AND THE YEAR
AFTER THAT,
AFTER THAT.
AH.
[chuckIes]
OH.
AND THE BEST THING,
THE VERY BEST THING OF ALL.
IS THERE'S TIME NOW.
THERE'S ALL THE TIME I NEED
AND ALL THE TIME I WANT.
TIME, TIME, TIME.
AH, THERE'S TIME ENOUGH
AT LAST.
[crash]
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
THAT'S NOT FAIR AT ALL.
THERE WAS TIME NOW.
THERE WAS,
WAS ALL THE TIME I NEEDED.
[sobbing]
IT'S NOT FAIR.
(male presenter, off)
THE BEST LAID PLANS
OF MICE AND MEN
AND HENRY BEMIS
THE SMALL MAN IN THE GLASSES
WHO WANTED NOTHING BUT TIME.
HENRY BEMIS, NOW JUST A PART
OF A SMASHED LANDSCAPE
JUST A PIECE OF THE RUBBLE
JUST A FRAGMENT OF WHAT MAN
HAS DEEDED TO HIMSELF.
MR. HENRY BEMIS,
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU
ABOUT NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
(male presenter, off)
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK WE ENLIST
THE CONSIDERABLE
LITERARY TALENTS
OF CHARLES BEAUMONT
AND INVITE YOU TO JOIN US
IN A STRANGE
AND SHOCKING DREAM.
OUR STORY IS CALLED
PERCHANCE TO DREAM
AND STARS RICHARD CONTE.
I HOPE YOU WILL BE ABLE
TO JOIN NEXT WEEK'S EXCURSION
INTO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES
YOU TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
INWANTED DEAD OR ALIVE
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER MOST
OF THESE SAME STATIONS.
(male presenter, off)
TWILIGHT ZONE
IS BEING BROUGHT
TO YOU TONIGHT
BY KIMBERLY CLARK
WHOSE HANDY KLEENEX
PAPER PRODUCTS
HELP YOU EVERY DAY
IN SO MANY WAYS.
WHY A NEW KIND
OF PAPER TOWEL?
LET ME SHOW YOU.
WE'LL COVER YOUR SCREEN
WITH THIS FILM
NOW LET'S SEE HOW
AN ORDINARY TOWEL WORKS.
SEE? IT LEAVES
STREAKS BECAUSE IT
DOESN'T SHAPE TO THE SURFACE.
LOOK AT THE DIFFERENCE
WITH A NEW KLEENEX TOWEL.
KLEENEX TOWELS
ARE BUILT LIKE A SPONGE.
AND LIKE A SPONGE,
THEY HAVE A SOFTNESS
THAT SHAPES TO THE JOB.
SO THE WHOLE TOWEL
SURFACE IS ABSORBING.
KLEENEX TOWELS
HELP YOU IN SO MANY WAYS
BECAUSE THEY'RE SO SOFT
AND SO STRONG
WET OR DRY
TO HELP YOU SCOUR
THE MOST STUBBORN STAINS
AND ALUMINUM SCUFF MARKS
FROM YOUR SINK.
AND LOOK, EVEN
WITH A HARSH CLEANSER
THERE'S NO SHREDDING,
NO BREAK THROUGH
IN A KLEENEX TOWEL.
WHEN YOUR SHOPPING
SQUEEZE THE KLEENEX
TOWEL PACKAGE
YES, SQUEEZE IT,
AND FEEL THE DIFFERENCE IN,
(jingle)
? THE BIG SOFT TOWEL
THAT'S BUILT LIKE A SPONGE
HELPFUL KLEENEX TOWELS ?
(female presenter, off)
ANOTHER GOOD VALUE
FROM KLEENEX.
(jingle)
? SOFT, STRONG,
POPS UP, TOO
? KLEENEX TISSUES
ARE BEST FOR YOU
? HELPING ME
TO WIPE UP QUICK
? HANDY KLEENEX
DOES THE TRICK
? SOFT, STRONG,
POPS UP, TOO
KLEENEX TISSUES
ARE BEST FOR YOU ?
YOU KNOW, I FIND KLEENEX
TISSUES SO USEFUL
I KEEP A BOX IN EVERY
ROOM OF MY HOUSE.
IT'S A MUST IN OUR
LIVING ROOM, OF COURSE.
YOU KNOW HOW
YOUNGSTERS WILL
SPILL THINGS.
AND WHAT CLEANS UP
QUICKER THAN KLEENEX?
WE FIND IT BEST
FOR COLDS, TOO.
IT'S SO WONDERFULLY
STRONG AND ABSORBENT.
NATURALLY, WE KEEP
SOME HERE.
THOSE PRETTY KLEENEX COLORS
JUST MATCH OUR DECOR.
AND OF COURSE,
THE BEDROOM, TOO.
THESE GENTLE TISSUES
SUIT MY SKIN JUST PERFECTLY.
THEY'RE SO SOFT AND SOOTHING.
KLEENEX TISSUES
IN THE POP UP BOX,
THERE'S A COLOR
FOR EVERY ROOM
IN YOUR HOUSE.