[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS
THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA WHICH WE
CALL THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
THE PLACE IS HERE,
THE TIME IS NOW,
AND THE JOURNEY
INTO THE SHADOWS
THAT WE'RE
ABOUT TO WATCH
COULD BE OUR JOURNEY.
[jazz music drifting out]
[ jazz playing loudly ]
SAY, I NOTICED THERE'S
A TOWN UP THE ROAD.
WHAT'S THE NAME OF IT?
CUSTOM ER.
HEY, YOU
GOT A CUSTOM ER
OUT IN FRONT!
CUSTOMER!
[percolating]
HAM AND EGGS!
[thud]
[music stops]
EGGS OVER EASY!
HASH BROWNS!
HEY, YOU GOT
A CUSTOM ER
OUT HERE!
HAM AND EGGS,
EGGS OVER EASY,
HASH BROWNS!
H U NG RY CASH CUSTOM ER!
I GOT $2.85,
AM ERICAN MONEY.
SURE. AM ERICAN MONEY.
WELL, WE'VE GOT
THAT MUCH SETTLED.
I'M AN AM ERICAN.
YOU SEE, THERE'S
SOME QU ESTION
ABOUT MY I DENTITY.
LET ME PUT IT
TO YOU THIS WAY:
I'M NOT SURE WHO I AM.
BUT I GOT $2.85,
AND I'M H U NG RY--
THAT MUCH
IS ESTABLISH ED.
$2.85, AND I'M H U NG RY!
I'M GON NA
WAKE UP IN
A MINUTE.
I KNOW IT.
I'M GON NA
WAKE UP.
[bell clanging]
ANYBODY HERE?
HEY! HEY!
HEY, MISS?
MISS, OVER HERE!
LOOK, I WON DER IF YOU
COULD DO ME A FAVOR.
IT'S THE
CRAZI EST THING,
BUT I'VE LOOKED
AND I HAVEN'T
SEEN ANYBODY AROUND.
MAYBE THEY'RE
ALL ASLEEP OR
SOMETHING, BUT--
WELL, LITERALLY,
THERE HASN'T
BEEN A SOU L.
LOOK, I DON'T WANT YOU
TO THINK I'M N UTS
OR ANYTHING.
IT'S NOTHING LIKE THAT.
IT'S JUST THAT, WELL--
IT'S J UST
THAT I DON'T SEEM
TO REMEMBER WHO I AM.
WELL, IT'S A REAL
ODDBALL THING,
BUT, WHEN I WOKE UP
THIS MORNING, I--
WELL, I DIDN'T
EXACTLY WAKE UP.
I J UST--I J UST
FOU N D MYSELF OUT ON
THAT ROAD, WALKING.
AM N ES IA. ISN'T THAT
WHAT THEY CALL IT?
THAT MUST BE WHAT I GOT
'CAUSE I JUST DON'T
REMEMBER A THING,
AND I CAN'T
SEEM TO F IN D
ANYBODY TO ASK.
YOU'RE THE
FIRST PERSON
I'VE SEEN.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE FRIGHTEN ED
OR ANYTHING,
BUT I WAS WON DERING
IF THERE'S A DOCTOR--
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY, MADAM.
I CAN ASSURE YOU THAT
AT NO TIME DID I MEAN
TO BE SO UPSETTING.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I'VE ALWAYS HAD
KIND OF A SECRET YEN
FOR THE QU I ET TYPE.
GET WHAT I MEAN, BABE?
HEY! ANYBODY HERE?
YOU HAVEN'T GOT
THE IG N ITION KEY,
HAVE YOU, DOLL?
[telephone ringing]
[ringing]
HELLO.
OPERATOR.
HELLO, OPERATOR.
HELLO. OPERATOR?
OPERATOR?!
(female recorded voice)
THIS IS THE
SPECIAL OPERATOR.
OPERATOR, LOOK--
THE NUMBER YOU
HAVE REACHED IS NOT
A WORKING NUMBER.
I JUST WON DERED
IF ANYBODY THERE
COULD TELL ME--
PLEASE MAKE SURE YOU
HAVE THE RIGHT NUMBER.
OPERATOR, WI LL
YOU LISTEN TO
M E, PLEASE?
THIS IS THE
SPECIAL OPERATOR.
THE NUMBER YOU HAVE
REACHED IS NOT A
WORKING NUMBER.
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR H EADS
DOWN THERE?
I DIDN'T DIAL A NUMBER!
I DIALED THE OPERATOR!
THIS IS A RECORDING.
A RECORD--? OPERATOR.
THIS IS THE--
OPERATOR, LOOK,
ALL I WANT TO
KNOW IS WHERE I AM.
NOT A WORKING NUMBER.
LOOK, PLEASE,
CAN YOU--
MAKE SURE
THAT YOU HAVE--
ABEL, ADAMS, ALLEN, ATMAN.
BOYS, WHERE ARE YOU?
WHERE DO YOU BOYS LIVE?
JUST IN THIS BOOK?
BAKER, BARG MAN,
BLOD, BELMONT.
WELL, GANG, WHO'S
WATCHING THE STORE?
WHO'S WATCHING
ANY OF THE STORES?
ALRIGHT, WHO'S
THE WISE GUY WHO
LOCKED THE DOOR?
IT'S A GREAT GAG.
HOW ABOUT A HAN D, SOMEBODY?
A LITTLE ASS ISTANCE,
HOW ABOUT IT?
THIS IS AN ABSOLUTELY
HYSTERICAL TURN-ON.
I'M GROWING
VERY FON D OF IT.
THIS ISN'T FU N NY ANYMORE.
I DON'T LIKE
THIS [inaudibIe].
I WISH I COULD SHAKE
THAT CRAZY FEELING
OF BEING WATCH ED.
LISTEN ED TO.
CALLING ALL CARS,
CALLING ALL CARS.
U N KNOWN MAN
WALKING AROUND
POLICE STATION.
SUSP ICIOUS-LOOKING
CHARACTER, PROBABLY
WANTED BY THE F--
[door creaking]
[water pouring]
[creaking]
TIME TO
WAKE UP NOW.
TIME TO WAKE
U P NOW!
[creaking ]
HEY!
WHERE IS EVERYBODY?!
[loud clanging of bell]
ANYBODY WANT A SU N DAE?
I'M SORRY, OLD BUDDY,
I DON'T RECOLLECT
THE NAME.
THE FACE IS
VAG U ELY FAMILIAR, BUT
THE NAME ESCAPES ME.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT MY PROBLEM IS.
I'M IN THE M I DDLE
OF A NIGHTMARE I
CAN'T WAKE UP FROM,
AND YOU'RE PART OF IT--
YOU AND THE ICE CREAM
AND THE POLICE STATION
AND THE PHONE BOOTH,
THAT LITTLE MAN N EQU I N--
THIS WHOLE BLOODY TOWN,
WHEREVER IT IS.
WHATEVER IT IS.
I J UST
REMEMBERED SOMETHING.
SCROOG E SAID IT.
YOUREMEMBER
SCROOG E, OLD BUDDY?
EBEN EZER SCROOG E?
IT'S WHAT HE SAID
TO THAT GHOST,
JACOB MARLEY.
HE SAID, "YOU MAY BE
AN U N DIG ESTED B IT
OF BEEF,
"A CRU M B OF CH EESE,
A BLOT OF M USTARD,
"A FRAG MENT OF
AN U N DONE POTATO.
BUT THERE'S MORE OF GRAVY
THAN OF GRAVE ABOUT YOU."
YOU SEE, THAT'S
WHAT YOU ARE.
YOU'RE WHAT I
HAD FOR DIN N ER
LAST NIGHT.
YOU MUST BE.
BUT NOW I'VE HAD IT.
I'D LIKE TO WAKE UP.
I'D LIKE TO
WAKE UP NOW.
IF I CAN'T WAKE UP,
AT LEAST
I'D LIKE TO F IN D
SOMEBODY TO TALK TO.
I MUST BE A VERY
I MAG I NATIVE GUY.
NOBODY IN THE
WHOLE BLOODY WORLD
COULD HAVE A DREAM
AS COM PLETE AS M IN E,
RIGHT DOWN TO
THE LAST DETAI L.
AIR FORCE.
AIR FORCE. I'M AIR FORCE!
AIR FORCE!
I'M IN THE
I'M IN THE AIR FORCE!
HEY, I'M IN
THE AIR FORCE!
I'M IN THE AIR FORCE!
HEY, EVERYBODY,
AIR FORCE.
WHAT DOES
THAT MEAN?
WAS THERE A BO--?
THAT MUST HAVE
BEEN IT-- A BOM B.
BUT IF THERE WAS
A BOM B, EVERYTHING
WOULD BE DESTROYED,
AND NOTHING
IS DESTROYED.
[plane engine roaring]
[suspenseful music playing]
HEY!
WHO'S UP THERE?!
WHO'S RU N NING
THE PICTURES?!
WHO'S UP THERE?!
WHO'S RUNNING
THE PICTURES?!
HEY!
WHO'S UP THERE?!
CAN'T YOU SEE ME?!
WHO'S IN HERE?!
[groans]
[panting]
[whimpering]
[shouts in fear]
PLEASE, SOMEBODY,
HELP ME.
H ELP ME. H ELP ME.
PLEASE, H ELP ME.
PLEASE, SOMEBODY, H ELP ME.
H ELP ME, PLEASE.
SOMEBODY, H ELP ME.
PLEASE, SOMEBODY,
HELP ME.
(lonely man)
PLEASE, SOMEBODY,
HELP ME!
SOMEBODY'S LOOKING
AT ME!
SOMEBODY'S WATCHING ME!
HELP ME! PLEASE, HELP ME!
HELP ME! HELP ME!
HELP ME! HELP ME, PLEASE!
HELP ME!!
SOMEBODY'S LOOKING AT ME!
PLEASE, HELP ME!
HELP ME! HELP ME!
CLOCK HIM.
HELP ME!
SOMEBODY'S LOOKING AT ME.
SOMEBODY'S WATCHING ME.
HELP ME!
GET HIM OUT
OF THERE, QU ICK.
RELEASE THE SU BJ ECT
ON THE DOU BLE.
BE CAREFU L, COLON EL.
DON'T CUT HIS HAN D.
THE GLASS ON THE
CLOCK IS BROKEN.
I CAN SEE
THAT, SERG EANT.
SERGEANT--
ALL RIGHT, COLON EL, GO.
HE'S ALL
RIGHT, S I R.
DELUS IONS, I THINK.
HE'S COMING
OUT OF IT NOW.
F IN E. DID YOU GET
ALL THE DATA RECORDED?
YES, S I R,
EVERY B IT
OF IT.
GET A TI MING
ON HIM?
484 HOURS,
36 MINUTES.
GOOD. I WANT
TO HAVE A LOOK
AT ALL THE DATA
AS SOON AS
IT'S COM P I LED
AND I WANT TO SEE
THE REACTION SHOT
ON HIM, TOO.
YES, S I R. OH,
THE PRESS, S I R.
YES, ON THE RU N,
G ENTLEM EN, IF YOU
DON'T MIND.
I WANT TO SEE
SERG EANT FERRIS.
DO YOU
CONSIDER THIS
A SUCCESS, S I R?
VERY MUCH SO.
THE MAN
WAS CON F IN ED
ALONE IN A BOX
FOR SOMETHING IN
THE N EIGH BORHOOD
OF 484 HOURS.
THAT'S ROUG H LY
EQU IVALENT TO A
TRI P TO THE MOON,
SEVERAL ORB ITS
AND RETURN.
THEN THIS WAS
A S IMU LATED TRI P
TO THE MOON?
FOR ALL I NTENT
AND PU RPOSE, YES.
WHAT ABOUT
THESE WIRES
ATTACHED TO HIM?
ELECTRODES.
ALL OF HIS REACTIONS
WERE CHARTED AND GRAPH ED.
RESP I RATION, HEART
ACTION, BLOOD PRESSURE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM
TOWARD THE END, GENERAL,
BEFORE HE PUSH ED THAT
BUTTON, WHATEVER IT WAS?
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM
IS THAT HE CRACKED.
DELUS IONS OF SOME
KIND, WE ASSU ME.
BUT LET ME TELL YOU
ALL SOMETHING, GENTLEM EN.
IF ANY ONE OF YOU
WERE CON F IN ED
IN A BOX
FIVE FEET SQUARE
FOR TWO AND A
HALF WEEKS
ALL BY YOUR LON ESOM E
WITHOUT HEARING
A HUMAN VO ICE
OTHER THAN YOUR OWN,
I'LL GIVE YOU
ESPECIALLY GOOD ODDS
THAT YOUR I MAG I NATION
WOULD RU N AWAY
WITH YOU, TOO,
SUCH AS H IS
OBVIOUSLY DID.
EXCUSE ME.
(coIoneI)
DETAI L.
HOW DO YOU FEEL,
SERG EANT?
(Ferris)
I FEEL MUCH
BETTER, SIR.
I'M SORRY ABOUT
TOWARD THE EN D.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WHAT WAS IT
LIKE, FERRIS?
WHERE DID YOU
THINK YOU WERE?
A PLACE I DON'T WANT
TO GO AGAIN, S I R.
A TOWN.
A TOWN WITHOUT PEOPLE,
WITHOUT ANYBODY.
WHAT WAS THE MATTER
WITH ME, DOC?
JUST OFF MY
ROCKER, HUH?
JUST A KIND
OF A NIGHTMARE
THAT YOUR MIND
MAN U FACTU RED FOR YOU.
YOU SEE, WE CAN
FEED THE STOMACH
WITH CONCENTRATES.
WE CAN SU PPLY M ICROF I LM
FOR READING, RECREATION,
EVEN MOVIES
OF A SORT.
WE CAN PU M P OXYG EN IN
AND WASTE MATERIAL OUT.
BUT THERE'S ONE THING
WE CAN'T SIMULATE
THAT'S A VERY
BASIC NEED--
MAN'S H U NG ER
FOR COM PAN IONSH I P.
THE BARRIER
OF LONELINESS--
THAT'S ONE THING
WE HAVEN'T
LICKED YET.
NEXT TIME, IT WON'T
BE JUST A BOX IN A
HANGAR, WILL IT?
NO, M I KE.
NEXT TIME, YOU'LL
REALLY BE ALON E.
HEY. DON'T GO
AWAY UP THERE.
NEXT TIME, IT
WON'T BE A DREAM
OR A NIGHTMARE.
NEXT TIME,
IT'LL BE FOR REAL.
SO DON'T GO AWAY.
WE'LL BE UP THERE
IN A LITTLE WHILE.
(male presenter, off)
UP THERE,
UP THERE IN THE
VASTNESS OF SPACE
IN THE VOID
THAT IS SKY--
UP THERE IS AN ENEMY
KNOWN AS ISOLATION.
IT SITS THERE IN
THE STARS, WAITING--
WAITING WITH THE
PATIENCE OF EONS.
FOREVER WAITING,
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
IN A MOMENT,
ROD SERLING WILL
TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY,
AFTER THIS WORD FROM OUR
ALTERNATE SPONSOR,
KIMBERLY CLARK.
NEXT WEEK, I'LL HAVE A REU N ION
WITH A U N IQU E TALENT AND
A VALU ED FRI EN D.
OUR FIRST
SINCE REQUIEM
FOR A HEAVYWEIGHT.
NEXT WEEK, ON
THE TWILIGHT ZONE,
MR. ED WYN N STARS IN
ONE FOR THE ANGELS,
PLAYING AN OLD
P ITCH MAN WHO SELLS
M ECHAN ICAL TOYS LIKE THIS.
BUT WHOSE COM PETITION
IS MR. DEATH.
WE HOPE YOU'LL JOIN US THEN.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
(male voice, off)
FOR THE YOUNG AND THE OLD,
THE SICK AND THE TROUBLED,
GIVE THE UNITED WAY.