[eerie music]
(male narrator)
YOU'RE ABOUT TO ENTER
ANOTHER DIMENSION
A DIMENSION NOT ONLY
OF SIGHT AND SOUND,
BUT OF M IND
A JOURNEY INTO
A WONDROUS LAND
OF IMAGINATION.
NEXT STOP,
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male narrator)
THE HOME OF
MR. GREGORY WEST--
ONE OF AMERICA'S
MOST NOTED PLAYWRIGHTS.
THE OFFICE
OF MR. GREGORY WEST.
MR. GREGORY WEST--
SHY, QUIET, AND
AT THE MOMENT, VERY HAPPY.
MARY-- WARM, AFFECTIONATE.
YOUREALLY SHOU LD
BE WORKING, YOU KNOW.
YOU'RE NAGGING ME.
I'M ONLY THINKING
OF POSTERITY.
THINK OF ME I NSTEAD.
DON'T I ALWAYS?
YES, YOU DO.
DRY ENOUGH?
WE'LL LET
THE MASTER DECI DE.
PERFECT, AS ALWAYS.
ARE YOU DESCRI BING
YOURSELF, MR. WEST?
LET THE
M ISTRESS DECI DE.
SHE'S DECI DED.
AND THE FINAL INGREDIENT:
MRS. GREGORY WEST.
[front door opening]
[door closing]
(Mrs. West)
GREGORY?
[glass breaks]
[knocking]
G REG, NOT AGAIN.
I HAVE TO.
GREGORY, I'M
HOME, DARLING.
NO, GREG.
WHAT ELSE
CAN I DO?
ARE YOU WORKING?
ARE YOU
SO AFRAI D?
[knocking]
I HOPE I'M NOT
INTERRUPTING YOU.
DARLING, I'LL
ONLY BE A MOM ENT.
I JUST WANT TO
COME IN AND--
KISS YOU.
WELL, I DIDN'T
EXPECT YOU--
[cIears throat]
WHAT'S THE
MATTER, DEAR?
SOMETHING WRONG?
HOW COME YOU'RE HOM E
SO EARLY, DEAR?
DIDN'T YOU LIKE
THE MOVIE?
NO. NOT VERY MUCH.
I JUST DECI DED
I'D COME HOME EARLY.
HAVE YOU, UH,
BEEN BUSY?
OH, YES, YES, I GOT
QU ITE A BIT DONE.
DID YOU?
OH, I SEE YOU
DROPPED A GLASS.
OH, YES.
YOU LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING, DEAR?
OH, NO. I
JUST THOUGHT
I'D SEE
IF YOUR ROOM NEEDED
TO BE CLEAN ED.
I DON'T THINK SO.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING, DEAR?
HONEY, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
H M M?
OH, I, UH...
CHECKING THE WALL.
OH.
WHAT'S THAT?
OH!
MY SCISSORS.
G REGORY?
M M-H M M?
YOU WOULDN'T
BY ANY CHANCE
HAVE A SECRET DOOR
IN HERE, WOULD YOU?
A SECRET DOOR?
THAT'S WHAT I SAID,
DARLING, SECRET DOOR.
NOW, WHAT ON EARTH
WOULD I WANT
WITH A SECRET DOOR
IN HERE?
YES. WHATEVER
ON EARTH FOR?
[sighs]
ARE YOU ALL
RIGHT, VICTORIA?
H M M? OH, WELL,
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M NOT TOO SURE.
REALLY?
I THINK I
MAY BE SU FFERING
FROM HALLUCI NATIONS.
OH, YOU POOR DEAR.
IT'S THE STRANG EST THING
BUT I WAS JUST STANDING
OUTSIDE THIS WIN DOW
ONLY A MOM ENT AGO
RIGHT HERE.
YOU WERE?
YES, I WAS.
AND YOU'LL NEVER GU ESS
WHAT I SAW TH ROUG H
THAT WIN DOW--
OR AT LEAST YOU'LL
N EVER GU ESS WHAT I
THOUGHT I SAW.
I COULDN'T
POSS I BLY GU ESS.
I THOUGHT I
SAW A WOMAN
IN YOUR ARMS.
DID YOU?
YES. ISN'T THAT J UST
TOO RI DICU LOUS?
YES, YES, IT IS.
OH, WELL, LISTEN--
WOULDN'T YOU LIKE TO HAVE
ME DESCRIBE HER TO YOU?
WELL...
OH, LET ME, LET ME.
SHE HAD MASSES
OF BLON DE HAIR
AND SHE WORE ONE OF THOSE
FRU M PY LITTLE BLOUSES
WITH A TACKY LITTLE
BROOCH AT THE BOSOM
AND ONE
OF THOSE DREADFUL
PEASANT SKI RTS.
BUT THE FU N NY THING WAS
THAT SHE HAN DED
YOU A DRINK.
[both Iaughing]
OH, SUCH DETAI L. IT'S
QU ITE REMARKABLE.
YES. ISN'T IT?
OF COURSE,
IF I'D THOUGHT ABOUT IT
I WOULD HAVE REALIZED
HOW RI DICU LOUS IT WAS.
IF I HAD THOUGHT
ABOUT IT FOR A MINUTE
THAT A MAN OF YOUR
EXTRAORDINARY TASTE
COULDN'T POSSIBL Y
BE INTERESTED
IN SUCH A DRAB
UG LY LITTLE CREATU RE.
OH, SHE'S NOT
SO DRAB.
AHA.
DI DN'T THINK I'D BE HOM E
SO EARLY, DID YOU?
THE WHOLE AFTERNOON, DID YOU?
THOUGHT YOU HAD ME
FOOLED, DIDN'T YOU?
LET ME TELL
YOU SOMETHING,
I'VE HAD MY EYE ON YOU
FOR SOME TIME NOW.
DI DN'T THINK I SUSPECTED
THE REAL REASON
FOR WHY YOU WERE ALWAYS
SEN DING ME OUT OF
THE HOUSE,
DID YOU?
"I MUST BE ALON E
TO WORK,"
YOU SAID,
THE GREAT AND
FAMOUS PLAYWRIGHT,
FAMOUS PH I LAN DERER!
NOW, VICTORIA,
IT'S SO S IMPLE.
WHERE IS SH E?
I CAN EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING.
DO YOUREMEMBER MY PLAY,
FURY IN THE NIGHT?
[groaning]
OH, YES.
DEAR, DO YOU
REMEMBER IT?
YOUREMEMBER
THE CHARACTER
PH I LI P WAI NWRIGHT?
G REGORY, J UST
TELL ME ONE THING.
WHAT'S HER NAME?
WHAT?
MARY! BUT
THAT DOESN'T--
"MARY!" HOW COMMON.
PLEASE, VICTORIA--
JUST S IT DOWN HERE
AND LET ME EXPLAIN.
I'M LISTENING.
YOU KNOW HOW SOMETIMES
I'VE TOLD YOU
THAT F ICTIONAL CHARACTERS
COME ALIVE SO VIVI DLY
THEY MAKE DECISIONS
OF THEIR OWN?
A PLAYWRIGHT MAY
HAVE WORKED OUT
SOME KIND
OF MOVE FOR THEM
BUT THEY
REFUSE TO DO IT.
THEY WI LL
NOT ACCEPT ANYBODY'S--
THEY BECOME SO STRONG
THAT SOMETIMES THEY TAKE
OVER THE WHOLE STORY!
I HARDLY
SEE THAT THIS
HAS ANYTHING...
PLEASE BEAR
WITH ME, VICTORIA.
I'VE BORNE WITH
YOU FOR YEARS.
PH I LI P WAI NWRIGHT
WAS THE FIRST ONE OF
MY PLAY CHARACTERS
TO EVER BEHAVE LIKE THAT.
NO MATTER WHAT I HAD
PLAN N ED FOR HIM,
HE BALKED, HE REFUSED.
HE WOULDN'T ACCEPT
ANY OF MY DECIS IONS.
HE BECAME ALIVE--
WITH A WILL OF HIS OWN!
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I UNDERSTAND THAT
YOU ARE TRYING TO
CHANG E THE SU BJ ECT.
I'M NOT!
THIS IS THE SUBJECT.
PHILIP WAINWRIGHT
BECAME ALIVE!
ONE NIGHT,
WHILE I WAS
WORKING HERE--
RIGHT UP HERE
IN MY OFF ICE--
PH I LI P WAI NWRIGHT
WALKED IN TH ROUG H
THAT DOOR.
OH, GREG,
NOW, REALLY.
VICTORIA, YOU'VE
GOT TO BELIEVE ME!
HE WALKED IN RIGHT
TH ROUG H THAT DOOR.
HE CAME IN HERE,
AND HE SAT DOWN
IN THAT CHAIR...
ALIVE...
A REAL FLESH
AND BLOOD MAN!
AND I CREATED HIM.
OH, MY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I AM AFRAI D
THAT PSYCH IATRY IS
NEXT ON THE AG EN DA.
YOU'VE GOT TO BELIEVE
M E, VICTORIA.
CHARACTERS IN MY PLAYS
DO COME ALIVE.
I'VE SEEN THEM,
TALKED TO THEM.
I'VE EVEN
SHAKEN HAN DS
WITH THEM.
YOU EVEN MADE LOVE
TO THEM, REMEMBER?
YES... I MEAN NO!
LOOK, YOU KNOW HOW I WORK.
I DICTATE DIALOG
AND STAG E BUS IN ESS
INTO THE TAPE RECORDER.
I DESCRI BE
ANY CHARACTER I WANT
AND IF I DO IT WELL ENOUGH,
THEY COME TO LIFE--
TO LIFE, VICTORIA.
AND I DON'T EVEN
HAVE TO DESCRI BE
THE CHARACTERS
IN MY PLAYS ANYMORE.
I CAN DESCRI BE
ANY CHARACTER I WANT!
YOU SHOU LD BE
PUT AWAY.
NOW, YOU SAID THAT YOU
SAW MARY HERE, RIGHT?
OH, I SAW
HER HERE,
ALL RIGHT.
THEN HOW DID
SHE GET OUT?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TRYING
TO F IN D OUT.
SHE COULD
NOT HAVE GONE OUT
TH ROUG H THE WIN DOW.
YOU KNOW THERE ARE NO
SECRET DOORS IN HERE.
BUT I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU
HOW SHE GOT OUT OF HERE
BECAUSE I WANT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND.
I TAKE MY SCISSORS,
I SN I P
OFF THE PART
OF THE TAPE
ON WHICH
SHE IS DESCRI BED,
I ROLL THE TAPE
INTO A LITTLE BALL,
I THROW IT
INTO THE F I REPLACE,
SHE'S GONE!
U NCREATED.
I'M GOING TO
HAVE YOU COM M ITTED.
YOU'VE GOT
TO BELIEVE ME.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
NOW, JUST A MINUTE.
I'M TRYING TO SAVE
OUR MARRIAG E.
DON'T WASTE YOUR TIME.
I COULD DESCRI BE A
DOG OR A CAT OR ANY
CHARACTER YOU WANT
BUT I'M SURE YOU WOULD
PREFER TO SEE MARY
AND I'VE CREATED MARY
SO MANY TIMES,
THAT SHE'LL BE
MUCH MORE AVAI LABLE.
I'LL JUST BET SHE IS.
GIVE ME THE KEY, GREGORY.
HER NAME--IS MARY.
SHE'S 30 YEARS OLD...
FIVE FEET
SIX I NCH ES TALL,
N ICELY BU I LT,
BLON D HAIR,
FAIR COM PLEXION,
A S IMPLE,
U NASSU MING FEMALE,
BUT WITH THAT QUALITY
OF IN N ER LOVELIN ESS
THAT BRINGS REAL
BEAUTY TO A WOMAN.
A TEN DER,
G ENTLE WOMAN...
AN UNDERSTANDING WOMAN.
SHE'S DRESSED
IN A SOFT BLOUSE...
OLD-FASH ION ED BROOCH...
FU LL SKI RT.
HER HAIR...
IS ATTRACTIVELY ARRANG ED.
SHE'S COMING UP
THE FRONT WALK.
SHE'S CROSSING
THE PORCH.
SHE'S OPENING
THE FRONT DOOR.
[front door opening]
SHE'S CLOSING IT.
[door closing]
SHE'S WALKING
ACROSS THE HALL...
[footsteps approaching]
GOOD AFTERNOON,
M RS. WEST.
THERE'S NOTHING TO BE
AFRAI D OF, MRS. WEST.
DO YOU BELIEVE ME
NOW, VICTORIA?
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I BELIEVE.
I BELIEVE THIS IS SOME
SORT OF F I EN DISH PLOT.
YOU LET HER OUT OF HERE
TH ROUG H A SECRET DOOR,
THEN YOU TELL ME
THIS RI DICU LOUS STORY
ABOUT BRINGING
CHARACTERS TO LIFE.
THEN YOU LOCK THE DOOR
AND PRETEN D
TO BRING H ER
BACK TO LIFE.
THEN SHE COMES
IN THE FRONT DOOR
AND TRI ES TO MAKE
ME BELIEVE THAT--
YOU'RE TRYING
TO DRIVE ME I NSAN E.
YOU WANT TO HAVE
ME COM M ITTED.
YOU WERE GOING TO
HAVE ME COM M ITTED.
YOU WANT
TO HAVE ME COM M ITTED
SO THAT YOU CAN GET
ALL OF OUR PROPERTY
SO THAT YOU CAN SHARE
OUR PROPERTY WITH...
I JUST WANTED
TO SHOW YOU.
IS THAT WHY
YOU BROUGHT ME--
JUST TO SHOW H ER?
NOW, PLEASE TRY TO
UNDERSTAND, MARY.
AFTER ALL,
VICTORIA IS
MY WIFE.
NOT ANY LONG ER,
I'M NOT.
NOT AFTER THIS
DIABOLIC CONSP I RACY.
CAN'T I DO
ANYTHING RIGHT?
NO.
YOU HAVEN'T
ANSWERED ME, GREG.
YOU DON'T REALLY
BELIEVE THAT I
WANT TO HAVE--
YES.
HERE WE GO AGAIN.
YOU LET ME OUT OF HERE,
YOU MONSTER.
G REGORY WEST,
YOU LET ME
OUT OF HERE
OR I'M GOING
TO SCREAM.
I PROMISE YOU,
I'M GOING TO SCREAM.
WHAT FOR?
AGAIN?
WHY DO
YOU DO THIS
TO ME, GREG?
OH, I'M SORRY,
MARY, BUT...
WHAT ELSE
CAN I DO?
I JUST GOT
HERE, GREG.
WHAT ELSE
CAN I DO?
THAT'S ALL YOU EVER SAY.
YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE ME, HUH?
YOU JUST GOT
TO MAKE ME
SHOW YOU, HUH?
YOU'VE GOT TO MAKE
ME FORCE POOR MARY
TO LEAVE AGAIN.
VICTORIA...
SOMETIMES I WON DER.
DON'T BRING ME
BACK AGAIN.
NOW, MARY...
J UST... DON'T.
I CAN'T BEAR
IT ANY LONG ER.
OH...
FORGIVE ME, MARY
BUT SHE IS MY WIFE.
WHERE IS SH E?
I TOLD YOU.
WH-WHERE IS SH E?
YOU STILL DON'T
BELIEVE ME, HUH?
G REGORY, WHERE DID SHE GO?
I TOLD YOU!
I...
U NCREATED H ER.
OH, DEAR.
NOW, DON'T
YOU WORRY.
WE WON'T LET IT
HAPPEN ANYMORE.
I PROMISE YOU,
I WON'T DO IT AGAIN.
THE ONLY REASON I
DID IT THE FIRST TIME
WAS THAT, WELL,
I WAS LON ELY.
DON'T YOU SEE,
VICTORIA?
YOU'RE SO PERFECT
YOU'RE SO IMPECCABLE,
YOU'RE SO FLAWLESS, AND...
WELL, I JUST
FELT INFERIOR.
I WOULDN'T HAVE
CREATED MARY.
I DIDN'T CREATE H ER
TO I NSU LT YOU.
I WAS LON ELY,
THAT WAS ALL.
I WANTED SOMEBODY
TO TALK TO.
OH...
SOM EONE THAT I'D
FEEL COM FORTABLE WITH.
NOT LIKE A WORM.
WELL, YOU UNDERSTAND,
DON'T YOU?
OH, YES, I UNDERSTAND.
OH, F IN E.
WE'LL WORK IT OUT.
WE'LL WORK IT
OUT SOMEHOW.
IT'S JUST THAT I,
I FEEL SO I NADEQUATE
COM PARED WITH YOU.
OF COURSE,
THAT'S REALLY MY FAU LT.
I GU ESS I SHOU LD HAVE...
NOW, DON'T TRY
TO STOP ME, GREGORY.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I'M GOING
TO THE NEAREST LAWYER
AND I'M GOING
TO HAVE YOU PUT AWAY
FOR THE REST
OF YOUR U N NATU RAL LIFE--
AWAY FROM TAPE RECORDERS
AND FROM ME.
I'M GOING TO
LIVE ALL BY MYSELF
IN PERFECT PEACE AND HARMONY
IN THIS HOUSE
FREE OF YOUR
DISEASED M IND.
NO, VICTORIA!
YES, VICTORIA.
(Greg)
A GIANT RED-EYED ELEPHANT
IS STANDING IN MY HALLWAY,
AND WILL NOT
LET HER PASS.
OH, DON'T
BE RI DICU LOUS.
[screams]
G REGORY, WOULD
YOU PLEASE
GET THAT ELEPHANT
OUT OF MY HALL.
WILL YOU STAY?
YES.
[elephant crying out]
YOU ARE STARK STARING
RAVING MAD.
YOU SHOU LDN'T SAY
THOSE KIND OF THINGS.
THEN YOU'LL STAY, HM?
YOU DON'T SERIOUSLY THINK
YOU'RE GOING
TO KEEP ME
IN THIS HOUSE
NOW, DO YOU?
YOU WANT ME
TO DO IT AGAIN?
NO!
NO, NO, I--I, UH,
I'LL STAY HERE
FOR THE MOM ENT.
BUT BELIEVE ME, THE
FIRST OPPORTU N ITY
I GET,
I'M GOING TO
HAVE YOU PUT AWAY.
BELIEVE ME.
I BELIEVE YOU.
WELL, I GU ESS
THERE'S NOTHING
ELSE TO DO.
HOW LONG HAS
THAT BEEN THERE?
OH, EVER S I NCE
YOU AND I WERE,
U H... MARRI ED.
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT IS THIS
SU PPOSED TO MEAN?
NOW, VICTORIA, SHALL
I PUT THIS BACK
IN THE SAFE
OR SHALL I THROW
IT IN THE F I RE?
G REGORY, YOU'RE NOT
SERIOUSLY TRYING TO
MAKE ME BELIEVE--
I AM TELLING
YOU, VICTORIA.
LOOK AT YOURSELF.
REGAL, BEAUTIFUL.
YOU COULD HAVE ANY
MAN IN THE WORLD
THAT YOU WANTED.
HAVEN'T YOU
EVER WON DERED
HOW YOU HAPPENED
TO GET STUCK WITH ME?
WELL, I'M
TELLING YOU.
YOU'RE AN
I M PECCABLE, FLAWLESS--
YOU'RE JUST
THE SORT OF
WIFE THAT--
I ALWAYS USED TO
THINK I WANTED
MORE THAN
ANYTHING ELSE
IN THE WORLD.
IS THIS ANOTHER ONE
OF YOUR TAWDRY
LITTLE TRICKS?
NOW, WHY DO YOU THINK
I GOT SO UPSET
WHEN YOU
CAME BACK HERE
A WHILE AGO?
NOT BECAUSE OF MARY,
BUT BECAUSE YOU
CAME BACK
AGAINST MY WI LL
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE FRIGHTENING ME?
NO, I GU ESS NOT.
YOU'RE BEYON D THAT.
I MADE YOU
TOO STRONG.
I FORGOT TO
ADD A LITTLE--
HUMAN FRAI LTY.
WELL, I ASKED FOR IT.
I'LL PUT THIS
BACK IN THE SAFE.
I'VE GOT...
G REGORY.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT I THINK OF YOUR
CH I LDISH NONSENSE, HM M?
TH IS.
VICTORIA!
OH, GREG...
G REG, I FEEL
SO STRANG E. I--
YOU, YOU DON'T MEAN THAT
YOU WERE TELLING ME
THE TRUTH?
YOU WERE RIGHT.
VICTORIA!
NOW, I TOLD H ER,
I TOLD H ER.
SHE J UST
WOULDN'T LISTEN TO ME.
HER NAME...
HER NAME IS
M RS. VICTORIA WEST.
SH E...
WHY NOT LEAVE
WELL ENOUGH ALON E?
HER NAME...
IS MARY.
M RS. MARY WEST.
SHE'S 30...
FIVE FEET, SIX I NCH ES TALL...
BLON DE HAIR...
N ICELY BU I LT...
CLEAR COM PLEXION.
SH E'S... A PLAIN,
U NASSU MING FEMALE
WITH THAT IN N ER QUALITY
OF LOVELIN ESS
THAT MAKES A WOMAN
TRU LY BEAUTIFUL.
SHE IS DRESSED
IN A SOFT, P IN K BLOUSE
OLD-FASH ION ED BROOCH,
FLOWING SKI RT.
HER HAIR
IS ATTRACTIVELY ARRANG ED.
SHE IS IN H ER
H USBAN D'S STU DY
PREPARING HIM A DRINK.
(male narrator)
WE HOPE YOU ENJOYED
TONIGHT'S ROMANTIC STORY
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
AT THE SAME TIME,
WE WANT YOU TO REALIZE
THAT IT WAS, OF COURSE,
PU RELY F ICTIONAL.
IN REAL LIFE, SUCH
RIDICULOUS NONSENSE
COULD NEVER--
(Greg)
ROD!
[clucking tongue]
YOU SHOU LDN'T.
I MEAN, YOU SHOULDN'T
SAY SUCH THINGS AS
"NONSENSE" AND "RI DICU LOUS."
WELL, THAT'S THE
WAY IT GOES.
(male narrator)
LEAVING MR.GREGORY WEST--
STILL SHY, QUIET, VERY HAPPY
AND, APPARENTLY,
IN COMPLETE CONTROL
OF THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[eerie music]
KI M BERLEY CLARK
I NVITES YOU
TO WATCH
STEVE MCQU EEN
IN WANTED DEAD
OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS
OVER MOST OF THESE
SAME STATIONS.