[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN THE PIT
OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[expIosion]
[gunfire and bombs]
[machine gun firing]
KEEP THOSE TRUCKS COMING!
CLOSE IT UP!
I SAID CLOSE IT UP!
(male narrator)
INFANTRY PLATOON, U.S. ARMY,
PHILIPPINE ISLANDS, 1 945.
THESE ARE THE FACES
OF THE YOUNG MEN WHO FIGHT.
AS IF SOME OMNISCIENT PAINTER
HAD M IXED A TUBE OF OILS
THAT WERE AT ONE TIME
EARTH-BROWN, DUST-GREY
BLOOD-RED, BEARD-BLACK,
AND FEAR, YELLOW-WHITE.
AND THESE MEN WERE THE MODELS.
FOR THIS IS THE PROVINCE
OF COMBAT
AND THESE
ARE THE FACES OF WAR.
EVENING, CAPTAI N.
AIN'T IT A CRUMMY NIGHT?
ROUG H?
WE'VE GOT THE BRI DG E,
WHATEVER THEY WANT IT FOR.
HERE YOU GO.
JAPS HAVE GOT NAVAL GU NS
STUCK IN THE GROU N D.
THEY'RE ZEROED IN.
THAT BRI DG E GETS IT
EVERY THREE MINUTES.
[explosion]
IF THE GEN ERAL WANTS TO KNOW
WHERE THE JAP FLEET IS
IT'S DUG IN
ON THE ROAD TO MAN I LA.
SERG EANT,
WHO'D WE LOSE?
LOTS OF WOU N DED.
MAYBE TEN, TWELVE.
FOUR DEAD.
[suspense music]
H I BBARD, HORTON,
MORGAN AND LEVY.
ALL RIGHT, SERG EANT,
BED THEM DOWN.
CHECK WITH THE MESS.
MAKE SURE THEY GOT
HOT COFFEE AND A MEAL.
IF THEY'RE NOT H U NG RY,
EAT ANYWAY.
YES, S I R.
"A" COM PANY,
FIRST PLATOON, CHOW DOWN!
F ITZ,
S I R?
LOOK, I HAVE GOT ME A BOTTLE
OF PH I LI PP IN E TU PA IN MY TENT.
NOW IT'S NOT EXACTLY
BOTTLED IN BON D
BUT YOU'D BE SURPRISED WHAT
IT DOES TO A MAN'S OUTLOOK.
COME ON.
CH EERS.
[artillery
whistling overhead]
[explosion]
BAD DAY, HUH, F ITZ?
A LOT OF WOU N DED,
FOUR DEAD.
ALL IN TWO
AND A HALF HOURS.
1 2 WOU N DED, FOUR DEAD.
ANYTHING SPECIAL
ABOUT THE FOU R?
ANYTHING SPECIAL?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, F ITZ,
WE'VE LOST FOUR MEN BEFORE.
WE'VE LOST EIGHT AND TEN.
YOU SEEM TO BE TAKING THIS
A LITTLE HARDER THAN USUAL.
I JUST WON DERED
IF THERE WAS SOMETHING
SPECIAL.
THESE FOUR MEN
WERE ALL U N DER 2 1.
DOES IT HAVE TO BE
MORE SPECIAL THAN THAT?
NO, BUT THIS HAS
GOTTEN TO YOU, FITZ.
MORE THAN I'VE EVER SEEN.
I'D JUST LIKE TO KNOW WHY.
YOU'RE A PERCEPTIVE MAN, PH I L.
IT'S THE MARK OF A GOOD
OFFICER, ISN'T IT?
TO WARD OFF TROU BLE
BY ANTICI PATING.
ARE YOU GONNA GIVE ME
A HARD TIME?
I DON'T THINK SO, F ITZ.
YOU'RE A GOOD OFFICER.
YOU GOT GUTS AND BRAI NS.
BUT SOMETHING
HAS GOTTEN TO YOU.
I TOLD YOU,
I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHAT IT IS.
WOULD YOU?
H I BBARD, HORTON, MORGAN, LEVY.
KI LLED IN ACTION,
LUZON, P. I., 1 3 JAN UARY 1 945.
SO?
SO YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT'S GOTTEN INTO ME, PHIL,
I WROTE THOSE NAMES
DOWN YESTERDAY.
I WROTE THEM DOWN
BEFORE WE WENT UP.
WHY DID YOU WRITE DOWN
THE NAMES, F ITZ?
WELL, WE HAD A WEAPONS CHECK
AND I LOOKED INTO THEIR FACES
AND THOSE FOUR MEN
[artillery
whistling overhead]
[explosion]
FEEL BETTER?
I LOOKED INTO FORTY FOU R
FACES YESTERDAY MORNING
AND WHEN I GOT TO THOSE FOU R,
THERE WAS SOMETHING SPECIAL
A LIGHT OR SOMETHING.
I CAN'T DESCRIBE IT TO YOU.
THERE ISN'T ANY DESCRIPTION.
I LOOKED INTO THEIR
FACES AND I KNEW.
I KNEW THIS
WAS THEIR LAST DAY.
I KNEW THEY WERE
GOING TO GET IT.
I KNEW, AND THERE
THERE WASN'T
ANY DOU BT ABOUT IT.
WELL, THAT'S, UH,
THAT'S FU N NY.
THAT'S REAL FU N NY.
I HAVEN'T SLEPT MUCH.
I KEEP WON DERING
IS THIS THE WAY
IT'S GOING TO BE?
IF EVERY TIME I STAND
IN FRONT OF A PLATOON
AM I GOING TO BE ABLE
TO LOOK DOWN THE LIN E
AND KNOW WHICH ONES
AREN'T COMING BACK?
F ITZ, WHEN DID YOU WRITE
THESE NAMES DOWN?
YOU'RE SURE IT WAS YESTERDAY?
YOU'RE SURE IT WASN'T TODAY
ON THE WAY BACK IN THE TRUCK?
YESTERDAY.
YESTERDAY MORNING,
I SWEAR TO YOU.
I WROTE THOSE
NAM ES DOWN YESTERDAY.
WELL?
(man)
I CAN'T TELL, CAPTAIN.
THE STUFF YOU'VE GIVEN ME
IS INCONCLUSIVE.
I LOOKED UP HIS RECORDS.
HE'S NEVER BEEN WOU N DED.
LOOKS LIKE A PRETTY
STEADY CUSTOM ER,
NO EVI DENCE OF BATTLE
FATIG U E OR ANYTHING.
WHY HE SHOU LD SU DDEN LY GET
THIS WE I RD IDEA IS HARD TO SAY
BUT WE BETTER RU N SOME CHECKS.
HE BELIEVES IT.
YOU HEAR HIM TELL IT
YOU ALMOST BELIEVE IT YOURSELF.
I'D APPRECIATE YOU
TAKING A LOOK AT HIM.
HE'S A GOOD MAN.
HE'S ONE OF THE BEST
OFFICERS WE'VE GOT.
I'LL DO WHAT I CAN, CAPTAI N.
HE'S HERE NOW, YOU KNOW.
NO, I DIDN'T KNOW.
HE'S IN THE WARD VIS ITING
ONE OF THE BOYS
FROM HIS PLATOON.
I'M F IN E, LI EUTENANT.
HOW'S THE REST OF THE BOYS?
OH, THEY'RE ALL FINE.
PORKY GOT A P I ECE
OF SH RAPN EL ON HIS FING ER
YOU KNOW PORKY, THAT'S ABOUT
AS BAD AS HE EVER GOT.
[coughs]
HE'S A LUCKY KID.
THAT HE IS.
AND YOU'RE NOT
DOING TOO BAD.
YOU GET THAT ALL PATCH ED UP
AND YOU'LL BE GOING HOM E.
THAT'S NOT SO HARD
TO TAKE, IS IT?
NO, S I R.
IT SURE ISN'T.
NO, NO.
THANK YOU, S I R.
COULD YOU LAY IT
DOWN OVER THERE, LEASE?
I WON'T BE NEEDING
IT FOR A WHILE.
U H, LISTEN, SM ITTY, I GOT
SOME STUFF TO DO SO I'LL
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
YOU TAKE IT EASY,
YOU HEAR?
YES, S I R.
U H, ANYTHING YOU NEED--
YOU GOT STUFF TO READ?
ALL I NEED.
OKAY, YOU TAKE
CARE, SM ITTY.
THANKS FOR COMING, LI EUTENANT.
GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE, SM ITTY.
[suspense music]
YOU OKAY, LI EUTENANT?
YEAH. I--
YEAH, I'M OKAY.
HE'S DEAD.
JUST LIKE THAT.
THEY GO AWFU L
QU ICK SOMETIMES.
AWFU L QU ICK.
F ITZ?
I WAS UP SEEING SM ITTY.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I READ HIS TAG.
DOC SAID H E'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
NO, HE ISN'T.
I TOOK A LOOK AT HIS FACE.
I TOOK A LOOK AT HIS FACE,
AND I KNEW.
AND A MINUTE LATER,
HE'S GON E.
SAME THING?
SAME THING.
THE LOOK.
THE FU N NY--
THE FU N NY LIGHT
OR WHATEVER IT IS.
AND I KNEW,
AND I KNEW.
F ITZ, I CAN'T
EXPLAIN THIS, BUT--
I DON'T WANT
YOU TO EXPLAIN IT.
HOW CAN YOU EXPLAIN IT?
HOW CAN ANYBODY
EXPLAIN IT?
I JUST WANT YOU
TO BELIEVE IT, CAPTAI N.
THAT'S ALL I WANT FROM YOU.
I WANT YOU TO BELIEVE IT.
(Paramedic)
BED FIVE, SIR.
SM ITH. HE JUST DIED.
I'LL HAVE
A LOOK AT HIM.
FOR WHAT?
(Fitz)
THERE'S NOTHING
TO LOOK AT BUT A BODY.
HE'S DEAD.
AND I KNEW
HE WAS GOING TO DIE
'CAUSE I READ IT
ON HIS FACE.
GO ON BACK,
CORPORAL. I'LL
BE RIGHT IN.
SO YOU KNEW,
LI EUTENANT?
YOU BET I DID.
I TABBED FOUR MEN
THE OTHER DAY.
THAT'S ODD,
DON'T YOU THINK?
(Fitz)
ODD? THAT'S
NOT ODD, CAPTAIN.
ODD WHEN IS YOU GO
30 DAYS ON THE LINE
AND YOU DON'T
LOSE A MAN.
THAT'S ODD!
ODD IS WHEN YOU WALK
25 MILES AND YOU DON'T
GET A BLISTER.
NOW YOU'RE TALKING ODD!
THIS ISN'T ODD, CAPTAI N.
THIS IS NIGHTMARE.
THIS IS A LOUSY,
DOG-FACED, LYING OFFICER
WHO CAN SEE DEATH
ON PEOPLE'S FACES.
(Doctor)
YOU'RE A DOG-FACED,
LYING OFFICER
WHO'S CRACKING U N DER
THE STRAIN FROM HAVING
DONE TOO MUCH
AND FELT TOO MUCH.
F I NALLY HAVING TO
SUCCU M B TO IT!
I'M FIVE
FOR FIVE, CAPTAI N.
HOW MANY CO I NCI DENCES
ADD UP TO A FACT?
HOW MANY MEN
DO I HAVE TO TAB
AS THE LEAST LIKELY
TO SUCCEED?
HOW MANY MORE FACES
DO I HAVE TO LOOK INTO?!
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW
IS WHAT DOES IT TAKE
TO MAKE YOU GUYS REALIZE
THAT SOMEWHERE
ALONG THE LIN E
I P ICKED UP A TALENT
THEY DON'T TEACH AT O.C.S.
ONE THING YOU MIGHT DO
WHILE YOU'RE WAITING
AND SCRATCHING
YOU MIGHT PUT
TAPE OVER MY EYES
OR POKE THEM OUT
OR DO SOMETHING
WHERE I WON'T
BE ABLE TO SEE
SO I WON'T
HAVE TO LOOK
AT ANY MORE FACES!
NOW WE SPEARH EAD
THE ATTACK MOVING
ACROSS AT THE PO I NT
FOLLOWED BY BAKER
AND CHARLIE AND COM PANY.
NOW, AT THIS PO I NT
TO THE EAST,
SOME F I LI P I NO
G U ERRI LLAS WILL BE
CROSSING THE RIVER BY BOAT.
NOW THEIR JOB
WILL BE TO KNOCK OUT
ANY AND ALL JAP GUNS
IN THAT SIDE OF THE RIVER.
SO THAT WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO MOVE ACROSS THE BRIDGE
AGAINST ONLY
SMALL ARMS FIRE.
WE'VE GOT ABOUT
22 MINUTES BEFORE
WE LOAD UP THE TRUCKS.
GIVE YOUR PLATOONS
A GOOD BRI EFING.
MAKE SURE THAT EACH MAN
HAS A BELT, FIVE GRENADES,
SIX AM MO CLI PS,
AND NO BACKPACKS.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S IT.
GOOD LUCK.
CAPTAI N,
YOU STILL WANT MY PLATOON
TO TAKE THE PO I NT?
I DON'T KNOW YET, F ITZ.
I THINK THAT PROBABLY--
[suspense music]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, F ITZ?
ARE YOU WELL ENOUGH
TO TAKE THE PLATOON?
NOW, GU NTHER THINKS
YOU'D BE BETTER OFF
WITH THREE WEEKS
BACK AT DIVIS ION.
I AG REE WITH HIM.
THIS THING WILL TAKE
A FEW HOURS BUT IT
WILL BE MESSY.
CAPTAI N, YOU BETTER NOT GO.
WHY, F ITZ?
[suspense music]
YEAH.
IT'S ON YOUR FACE TOO.
IF YOU GO,
YOU WON'T BE COMING BACK.
F ITZ, GET
YOUR PLATOONS SET.
YOU'VE ONLY GOT
ABOUT 1 5 MINUTES LEFT.
PLEASE--
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT WE'LL DO!
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT
WHEN WE GET BACK. WE'LL
HAVE A DRINK TO IT.
WE'LL DRINK
TO AN I LLUS ION,
TO A COUPLE OF CO I NCI DENCES.
NOW THAT'S IT, F ITZ!
I'LL SEE YOU AT THE TRUCKS!
CAPTAI N, YOU WON'T BE
DRINKING TO ANYTHING.
'CAUSE YOU'RE
NOT COMING BACK!
[suspense music]
[waIIa]
[far away explosions]
LI EUTENANT?
WHAT ABOUT IT?
EVERYBODY SAYS
YOU CAN TELL.
EVERYBODY SAYS YOU KNOW
WHO'S GOING TO GET IT
AND WHO ISN'T.
WELL, HOW ABOUT IT,
LI EUTENANT? GIVE US
A BREAK, HUH?
COME ON, LI EUTENANT.
IT AIN'T FAIR--
YOU KNOWING!
KNOCK IT OFF, FREEMAN.
(Captain)
ALL RIGHT, SERGEANT.
NOW LOOK, SOMEBODY
STARTED THIS WILD GAG
AND SOMEBODY
WILL GET BU RN ED FOR IT.
THERE'S NOBODY
IN THIS COM PANY
WHO'S A MIND-READER.
I NCLU DING LI EUTENANT
F ITZG ERALD.
(Captain)
ALL RIGHT, LIEUTENANT?
YEAH. THAT'S RIGHT, S I R.
ALL RIGHT,
SERG EANT, LET'S GO.
YES, S I R.
LET'S GO!
(Sergeant)
OKAY, LOAD 'EM UP.
LET'S GO!
IN THE TRUCKS!
IN THE TRUCKS, EVERYBODY!
[expIosions]
CLOSE IT UP!
ALL RIGHT, CLOSE IT UP!
OKAY, FIRST PLATOON,
FALL IN.
FORGET ABOUT EXTRA DETAI LS.
LET'S DO IT THE SAM E.
YES, S I R.
COME ON,
HURRY IT UP.
FALL IN.
ROLL CALL.
VERALL.
(Verall)
HERE.
ASHBAR.
(Ashbar)
HERE.
[roll call continues]
(Commander)
FITZ.
JUST THOUGHT
I'D DROP AROUND
AND CONG RATU LATE YOU BOYS
ON THE GOOD JOB YOU DID.
THANK YOU, S I R.
THE ODDS FELL
ON OUR SIDE.
M UST BE ALL THOSE
RIGHT-HAN DY JOB ON THOSE GU NS
AND YOU FELLOWS
WALKED RIGHT ACROSS.
RIGHT ACROSS.
THAT'S FORTU NATE.
THE AIR FORCE
M UST HAVE P ICKED OFF
AT LEAST SIX OR SEVEN
OF THOSE 25s.
OF COURSE THOSE GU NS
WERE OPERATING.
THAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
THE LONG EST BRI DG E
YOU'VE EVER BEEN ON,
OR THE SHORTEST.
SN I PER F I RE,
THAT'S ALL YOU HAD?
YES, S I R,
SN I PER F I RE.
M M-H M M.
WE LOST ONE MAN.
OH, THAT'S A P ITY.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
YOU WERE GOOD FRIENDS,
WEREN'T YOU, F ITZG ERALD?
SO MUCH FOR MRS. RI KER'S
LOVELY WEDDING.
SEVEN HAPPY YEARS.
TWO F IN E SONS.
MAN, WAR STIN KS.
(Sergeant)
LIEUTENANT?
CAPTAIN GU NTH ER
WANTS TO SEE YOU.
LI EUTENANT, YOU ARE
TO REPORT BACK TO DIVIS ION.
BACK TO DIVIS ION?
YEAH. THEY WANT
TO LOOK YOU OVER.
IT'LL BE A NICE COUPLE
WEEKS REST FOR YOU.
TAKE YOUR GEAR WITH YOU.
OKAY.
THANK YOU, CAPTAI N.
[suspense music]
(soldier)
LIEUTENANT FITZGERALD?
THE JEEP'S READY
TO TAKE YOU BACK
TO DIVISION, SIR
ANY TIME
YOU'RE READY.
LI EUTENANT
F ITZG ERALD?
WHAT?
THIS YOUR BAG, S I R?
YES, THAT'S MY BAG.
MAY I PUT IT
IN THE J EEP
FOR YOU, S I R?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL, S I R,
WE'RE READY
ANY TIME YOU ARE.
[suspense music]
WELL, IT'S
A LITTLE BOU NCY, S I R
BUT IT SURE
BEATS WALKING.
YOU'RE
GOING BACK
TO DIVIS ION?
YEAH.
FU RTHER BACK I GET,
THE BETTER I LIKE IT.
YOU'RE TAKING
THE CONVEN I ENT ROAD?
YEAH. THERE'S A BRI DG E
U P THERE ON THE HIGHWAY.
THE ENG IN EERS
THINK THEY'VE SPOTTED
SOME M IN ES UP THE ROAD
THEY HAVEN'T
DUG THEM UP YET
SO STAY CLOSE
TO THE SHOU LDERS.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE GOOD CARE
OF THE
LI EUTENANT HERE.
SERGEANT, I'M THE
MOST CAREFUL DRIVER
IN THE UNITED
STATES ARMY.
IF I CAN LI FT THIS
HERE J EEP AND WALK
TI PPYTOE CARRYING IT
BELIEVE ME, BROTH ER,
I'D DO IT.
LIEUTENANT,
YOU MAY AS WELL
GET COMFORTABLE.
I GUESS WE GOT ABOUT
A FOUR-HOUR RIDE
AHEAD OF US.
DO WE?
I DOU BT IT.
[suspense music]
[soft harmonica playing]
YOU PLAY THAT
PRETTY GOOD.
ONE HAN D.
[loud explosion in distance]
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
TH U N DER?
I DON'T THINK SO.
IT SOUNDED MORE LIKE
AN EXPLOS ION.
[suspense music]
MAYBE IT WAS TH U N DER. YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT IT WAS--
PROBABLY TH U N DER.
[pIays harmonica]
(male narrator)
FROM WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE,
RICHARD THE THIRD,
A SMALL EXCERPT,
THE LINE READS,
"HE HAS COME TO OPEN
THE PURPLE TESTAMENT
OF BLEEDING WAR."
AND FOR LIEUTENANT
WILLIAM FITZGERALD--
"A" COMPANY, FIRST PLATOON,
THE TESTAMENT IS CLOSED.
LIEUTENANT FITZGERALD
HAS FOUND THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU
ABOUT NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR
AND NOW, R. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK,
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE
WE OFFER YOU THE U N BELI EVABLE
ALONG WITH AN EXPLANATION.
THREE MEN VIS IT
A STRANG E NEW WORLD
WITH PEOPLE, CARS,
HOUSES, THE WORKS.
BUT SOMETHING'S
WRONG IN THE SCENE.
SOMETHING VERY ABNORMAL
AM I DST THE NORMAL.
YOU'LL SEE WHAT I MEAN
WHEN NEXT WEEK WE BRING YOU
"ELEGY" BY CHARLES BEAU MONT.
IT STARS CECI L KELLAWAY.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES
YOU TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER MOST
OF THESE SAME STATIONS.