[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A
FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[airplane engine revving]
WITNESS FLIGHT LIEUTENANT
WILLIAM TERRANCE DECKER,
ROYAL FLYING CORPS,
RETURNING FROM A PATROL
SOMEWHERE OVER FRANCE.
THE YEAR IS 191 7.
THE PROBLEM
IS THE LIEUTENANT
IS HOPELESSLY LOST.
[engine roaring]
LIEUTENANT DECKER WILL
SOON DISCOVER
THAT A MAN CAN BE LOST
NOT ONLY IN TERMS
OF MAPS AND M ILES
BUT ALSO IN TIME.
AND TIME, IN THIS CASE,
CAN BE MEASURED
IN ETERNITIES.
[sirens blaring]
ALL RIGHT, MISTER.
GET OUT OF THERE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
WHO IN THE NAME OF--?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
RU N NING THIS ANTIQU E
IN FRONT OF AN
APPROACHING AIRCRAFT?
DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYING?
ARE YOU FRENCH?
I'M BRIT'SH.
ARE YOU AM ERICAN?
CAN'T YOU SEE THIS
IS AN AM ERICAN BASE?
WHAT, ALL THIS?
WE HAD NO IDEA
YOU WERE SO ADVANCED.
WHAT?
YOU BETTER COME
WITH ME.
(male voice)
MAJOR WILSON
TO SEE YOU, GENERAL.
S IT DOWN, MAJOR.
I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN A MINUTE.
WELL, WHAT IS THIS?
THIS MAN, S I R.
HE'S APPARENTLY BRIT'SH.
HE LAN DED HIS SH I P
ON OUR FIELD.
HIS SH I P,
I MIGHT ADD--
WHO ARE YOU?
SECON D LI EUTENANT
WI LLIAM DECKER, S I R.
ROYAL FLYING CORPS.
YOU MEAN ROYAL AIR FORCE.
NO, S I R.
ROYAL FLYING CORPS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHY ARE YOU DRESSED
LIKE THAT?
I BEG YOUR PARDON, S I R?
THERE SOME KIND
OF AN AIR SHOW NEARBY?
AIR SHOW, S I R?
ARE YOU MAKING A F I LM?
I'M AFRAI D I DON'T
QU ITE U N DERSTAND
YOU, S I R.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND?
WHAT ARE YOU--?
WHY ARE YOU WEARING
THIS COSTU ME?
THIS IS MY
U N I FORM, S I R.
YOUR--!
AT EASE.
THANK YOU, S I R.
EXCUSE ME, S I R.
WHERE EXACTLY AM I?
NOW, WHERE
EXACTLY DID YOU
THINK YOU WERE?
WELL, I THOUGHT
I WAS LAN DING
AT 56th SQUADRON,
R. F.C.
56th SQUADRON
R. F.C.?
WASN'T THAT A--?
WHAT'S TODAY'S DATE?
MARCH 5.
WHAT YEAR?
WHY, 191 7.
191 7?
YES, THAT'S CORRECT.
WELL, ISN'T IT?
IT'S MARCH 5, 1 959,
LI EUTENANT.
[no audio]
U H... LOOK HERE.
YOU'RE NOT JOKING
WITH ME, ARE YOU?
GOOD LORD.
YOU DON'T SERIOUSLY
EXPECT US TO
BELIEVE THAT--
BUT IT'S TRU E.
IT'S TRU E.
WHEN I TOOK OFF
THIS MORNING,
IT WAS 191 7.
[airplane taxiing outside]
(Decker)
THAT CLOUD--
WHILE I WAS PASSING
TH ROUG H IT,
I COULDN'T
HEAR MY ENG IN E.
IT WAS LIKE
BEING SWALLOWED
IN A VACU U M.
THE SAME SORT OF THING
HAPPENED TO GU I MERD.
THE FRENCH
FIGHTER PILOT?
HE DISAPPEARED
ONE DAY WHILE FLYING.
AT THE MEMORIAL SERVICE,
THE CARDI NAL SAID
"HE BELONG ED TO THE SKY
AND THE SKY
HAS TAKEN HIM."
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE FOOLING,
DECKER?
OR WHATEVER
YOUR NAME IS.
S I R, I SWEAR TO YOU
WHEN I TOOK
OFF THIS MORNING
IT WAS MARCH 5, 191 7!
MACK AND I WERE--
WHO?
CAPTAIN MACKAYE.
MACKAYE?
YES, WE'RE I N--
ALEXAN DER MACKAYE?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
WHAT HAVE YOU
GOT TO DO WITH--
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
I SU PPOSE YOU'RE
GOING TO TELL US
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT
ALEXAN DER MACKAYE,
AIR VICE-MARSHAL
IS AT THIS MOM ENT
EN ROUTE TO
THIS BASE
FOR A TOU R
OF I NSPECTION!
BUT THAT'S IMPOSS I BLE.
WHY IS IT IMPOSS I BLE,
LI EUTENANT DECKER?
BECAUSE HE'S DEAD.
(Harper)
IT'S INGENIOUS, I'LL
GIVE YOU THAT MUCH.
THIS COULD BE
CHECKED ON, S I R.
IF WE WANTED
TO WASTE OU R
TIME, YES.
WELL, I F
IT'S A HOAX,
IT'S CERTAINLY
AN ELABORATE ONE.
IF IT'S A
HOAX, MAJOR.
I MEAN, S I R,
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
THAT ANYONE WOULD GO
TO SUCH I NCREDI BLE
LENGTHS JUST TO
PLAY A JOKE.
WHO SAID IT
WAS A JOKE?
ALRIGHT, S I R,
WHAT IS IT?
WE'LL F IN D OUT
WHEN MACKAYE ARRIVES.
WE COULD ASK THE
M IN ISTRY OF WAR
IN LON DON.
THERE MIGHT
BE RECORDS ON
THIS DECKER.
I THINK YOU
BELIEVE HIM.
NO, S I R.
IT'S JUST THAT I
CAN'T H ELP FEELING
THERE'S MORE TO THIS
THAN JUST A HOAX.
EXACTLY.
YOU DON'T THINK
HE MEANT TO USE
THAT ON MACKAYE?
WE'LL KNOW
SOON ENOUGH.
BUT, S I R, I'D
SWEAR THE MAN WAS
G EN U IN ELY SHOCKED
WHEN HE HEARD
MACKAYE WAS
COMING HERE.
IF H E'D MEANT
TO DO THE MAN
ANY HARM
HE WOULD'VE WORN HIS GU N,
HE WOULDN'T HAVE LEFT IT
IN HIS PLAN E.
MAJOR, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I HAVE A LOT OF WORK
TO DO.
BUT, GEN ERAL,
THIS WHOLE IDEA
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE!
MAJOR! I F
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
YES, S I R.
[deafening roar]
[clicking]
LI EUTENANT.
WHY AM I A
PRISON ER HERE?
NOT QU ITE AS BAD
AS ALL THAT.
I'M BEING KEPT HERE,
AM I NOT?
I'M ONLY FOLLOWING
ORDERS, DECKER.
WHAT EARTH LY GOOD
IS IT GOING TO DO
FOR ME TO
SEE MACKAYE?
WHY ARE YOU SO AFRAI D
OF SEEING MACKAYE?
I'M NOT AFRAI D.
I'M NOT AFRAI D
OF ANYTHING.
WELL, THEN?
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
I'LL SEE HIM.
GOOD.
ABOUT THAT WH ITE
CLOU D YOU SPOKE OF.
I'VE TOLD YOU EVERYTHING.
NOW, LOOK HERE, DECKER.
DO YOUREALIZE YOU'RE
ASKING US TO BELIEVE
SOMETHING RATHER I NCREDI BLE?
A CLOU D OF S I LENCE?
A WORLD WAR I PILOT
LAN DING AT AN AM ERICAN
BASE IN FRANCE IN 1 959?
SUCH A THING J UST
DOESN'T HAPPEN
EVERY DAY!
WELL, IT HAPPENED TODAY!
NOW, LOOK HERE, I'VE TOLD
YOU I'LL SEE MACKAYE.
NOW, WHY DON'T YOU
LEAVE ME ALON E?
YOUREALLY FEEL YOU
KNOW HIM, DON'T YOU?
KNOW HIM?
"OLD LEADBOTTOM?"
LEADBOTTOM?
YEAH, WELL,
WHEN EVER WE FLY--
WHEN EVER WE FLEW
OVER THE GERMAN LIN ES
THE SOLDI ERS F I RED AT US.
WELL, ONE DAY MACK GOT H IT
IN A MOST EM BARRASSING SPOT.
I ALWAYS CALLED HIM
OLD LEADBOTTOM AFTER THAT.
IT'S A PRIVATE JOKE,
OF COURSE.
MACK'S A PROU D FELLOW,
YOU KNOW.
HE WOULDN'T LIKE IT
IF I BRU ITED IT ABOUT.
BUT WHY DO YOU KEEP
I NS ISTING THAT
HE'S DEAD?
BECAUSE THE LAST
I SAW OF HIM
HE WAS CAUG HT IN A CI RCLE
OF SEVEN GERMAN PLAN ES.
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD
DO ABOUT IT, OF COURSE.
I WAS I NVOLVED
WITH THREE OTH ERS.
OBVIOUSLY, H E
GOT AWAY.
I DON'T SEE
HOW HE COULD HAVE.
NOT ONLY COULD
HAVE, HE DID.
HE WAS ONE OF
BRITAI N'S GREAT
H EROES DU RING THE BLITZ.
THAT WAS
THE SECON D WAR
WE TOLD YOU ABOUT.
WON THE D.F.C. FOR
KNOCKING DOWN THREE
GERMAN BOMBERS
ONE NIGHT OVER LONDON.
HE UNDOUBTEDLY SAVED
HUNDREDS OF LIVES.
MAYBE EVEN THOUSANDS.
DECKER!
YOU MANAG E, S I R?
YES, YOU CAN
WAIT OUTSIDE.
WHAT'S WRONG, DECKER?
I'VE GOT TO LEAVE!
THAT'S IMPOSS I BLE.
MACKAYE WILL BE HERE
IN A WHILE. WE'LL GET
TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS.
I CAN'T SEE HIM.
WHY NOT?
HE'LL KNOW
ME FOR WHAT
I AM.
WHAT ARE YOU?
I'M A COWARD!
I'M A COWARD.
I'VE ALWAYS
BEEN A COWARD.
ALL MY LIFE I'VE
BEEN RU N NING AWAY
PRETEN DING TO BE SOMETHING
I NEVER WAS, NEVER COULD BE.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE--
BECAUSE I WAS TRYING
TO RU N AWAY.
BECAUSE I WANTED
SO DESPERATELY TO ESCAPE
THAT I DID ESCAPE.
OH, I GOT BY WITH MY
PRETENDING WELL ENOUGH.
MY KIND OF
STRAIN ED I DIOCY
IS EXACTLY
THE BRAND WE
ALL PUT ON.
WE'RE PLAYING A PART,
YOU KNOW?
BOYS ON A
LARK--LAUGHING,
JOKING, DRINKING--
OH, IT'S TOO MUCH,
ALL OF IT.
AND TURNING INTO DEADLY,
ICE-COLD KI LLERS
IN THE SKY
ALTHOUGH NOT ME,
OF COURSE.
NO, NOT ME.
U P THERE, I'M
JUST AS AFRAI D
AS I AM ON THE GROU N D.
AND MACK AND I ARE SU PPOSED
TO GO ON PATROLS TOGETHER
BUT, UH... I CAN USUALLY
MANAG E TO PERSUADE HIM
INTO SPLITTING UP.
YOU KNOW, I THINK
HE ACTUALLY HOPES
HE'LL RU N
INTO SOME TROU BLE.
M E, WELL, I J UST...
LING ER IN THE CLOU DS
FLYING BACK AND FORTH,
DREADING THE POSS I B I LITY
THAT I MIGHT SEE
AN EN EMY PLAN E, AND...
JUST HOPING
FOR ENOUGH TIME TO PASS
SO THAT I CAN GO BACK.
YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES I THINK...
I'LL LAND BEH IN D
THE GERMAN LIN ES
AND I'LL LET
MYSELF BE CAPTU RED.
THE PILOTS
ALWAYS GET THE BEST
OF TREATM ENT, YOU KNOW.
BUT I'M AFRAI D
OF DOING THAT EVEN.
I'M AFRAI D THAT I'D
BE DISCOVERED, AND--
DISCREDITED.
I COULDN'T BEAR THAT.
I HAVE TO CARRY ON
THE SELF-DELUSION,
YOU KNOW.
YOU KNOW--
I'VE ACTUALLY
F I RED BU LLETS
TH ROUG H THE
COCKP IT WALLS
SO THAT THE CHAPS
WILL SEE THEM
AND BE IMPRESSED.
GOD H ELP ME.
[sigh]
IT ISN'T A CRI ME
TO BE AFRAI D, DECKER.
EVERYBODY'S AFRAI D
AT ONE TIME OR ANOTH ER.
I'M SURE MACKAYE
WOULD U N DERSTAND THAT.
NO.
WELL, WHAT MAKES YOU
THINK HE KNOWS ANYWAY?
BECAUSE IT WAS
ME THAT LET THE
G ERMANS TRAP HIM.
BUT I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU WERE FIGHTING THREE
G ERMAN PLAN ES YOURSELF.
I WASN'T FIGHTING ANYONE!
I WAS RU N NING!
WHEN THE GERMANS CAME AT US,
I LEFT HIM UP THERE TO DIE.
BUT HE DIDN'T DIE!
WELL, I CAN'T
U N DERSTAND THAT!
WELL, MAYBE H E
GOT H ELPED SOMEHOW.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT YOU SAID.
WHAT?
THAT HE GOT H ELP.
IT'S CERTAIN LY IN THE
REALM OF POSS I B I LITI ES.
DON'T YOU SEE?
MAYBE IT WAS ME
THAT H ELPED HIM.
I SAID WH EN
HE GOT H ELP
I MEANT THAT
SOMEBODY ELSE--
THERE WASN'T ANYONE
WITH IN 50 M I LES
WHO COULD
HAVE H ELPED HIM.
MAYBE IT
WASN'T AN ACCIDENT
THAT I LAN DED HERE.
MAYBE I WAS BROUGHT HERE
FOR A PU RPOSE--
TO F IN D OUT THAT
MACK HAD SU RVIVED.
TO F IN D OUT THAT TIME
WAS GIVING ME A
SECON D CHANCE.
YOU'VE GOT TO LET ME GO.
BUT I CAN'T.
YOU'VE GOT TO,
DON'T YOU SEE?
IT'S THE ONLY CHANCE
I HAVE.
HE HAS.
BUT HE'S ALIVE.
HE'S COMING
HERE TODAY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT IF I DON'T GET BACK
HE WON'T BE HERE?
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT HE WON'T
HAVE BEEN KI LLED
42 YEARS AGO
U N LESS I H ELP HIM NOW?
THAT'S I NSAN ITY, DECKER.
(technician)
HEY, WHERE DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE GOING?
(Wilson)
TURN IT OFF!
NO.
CAN'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT'S NOT JUST HIM.
IT'S ALL THOSE
OTHER LIVES
HE SAVED.
ARE THEY TO BE LOST AS WELL?
TURN IT OFF, DECKER,
OR I'LL F I RE.
WELL, F I RE.
I'D RATHER DIE.
YOU'RE IN TROU BLE, MAJOR.
I HOPE YOU KNOW THAT.
I KNOW IT, S I R.
YOU KNOW, YOUR THOUGHT
PROCESSES ELUDE ME.
THEY POS ITIVELY ELU DE ME.
LETTING THAT MAN IAC LOOSE.
HOW COULD YOU POSS I BLY--?
[knocking]
YES?
AIR VICE-MARSHAL
MACKAYE, S I R.
F IN E, F IN E.
WE WERE SU PPOSED
TO MEET HIM WH EN
HE LAN DED.
ALL RIGHT.
AT EASE.
MARSHALL MACKAYE.
HOW DO YOU
DO, GEN ERAL?
I'M VERY PLEASED
TO MEET YOU, S I R.
I TRUST YOU HAD
A COM FORTABLE FLIGHT.
OH, YES, SPLEN DID.
GOOD. THIS IS
MAJOR WI LSON.
HOW DO YOU DO, S I R?
HONORED, MAJOR.
WON'T YOU S IT
DOWN, S I R?
THANK YOU.
MAY I?
OH, THANKS.
S I R, DID YOU EVER
KNOW A MAN
BY THE NAME OF
WI LLIAM TERRANCE DECKER?
TERRY DECKER?
WELL, I CERTAIN LY
SHOU LD KNOW HIM.
SAVED MY LIFE.
WHAT?
HOW DID H E
SAVE YOUR
LIFE, S I R?
WELL, YOU SEE, WE WERE
OUT ON PATROL TOGETHER.
NOW, AS A RU LE,
WE'D HAVE SPLIT UP
BUT ON THAT DAY, WE
WERE FLYING TOGETHER
WHEN A FLIGHT
OF GERMANS
DROPPED DOWN ON US.
YOU FOUGHT
TH EM TOGETHER?
WELL, NOT
AT FIRST.
WHAT DO YOU
M EAN, S I R?
WELL, I HAD
A FEELING
THAT OLD TERRY
WAS LIGHTING
OUT ON ME.
HE FLEW AWAY?
YES. CLIMBED HIGH.
DISAPPEARED IN
A CLOUD.
A WH ITE CLOU D, S I R?
I DON'T KNOW.
I SU PPOSE SO.
AND THEN?
WELL, THEN, OUT OF
NOWHERE, IT SEEM ED,
TERRY CAME DIVING
DOWN, HIS GU N
CHATTERING AWAY.
HE GOT THREE
OF THE BLIGHTERS
BEFORE THEY GOT HIM.
SAVED MY LIFE.
THEN HE DID
GET BACK.
WHAT?
DI DN'T THE GERMANS
USUALLY BRING BACK
THE PERSONAL EFFECTS
OF PILOTS
WHO HAD BEEN
SHOT DOWN?
USUALLY.
I SAY, WHAT IS
THIS ALL ABOUT?
THEY BROUGHT
BACK H IS?
NO.
NO?
WHERE IN
H EAVEN'S NAME
DID YOU GET THESE?
THEY'RE H IS?
YES. NOW, WHAT
THE DEVIL IS
THIS ALL ABOUT?
MAYBE YOU'D
BETTER S IT DOWN,
OLD LEADBOTTOM.
OLD--
WHAT DID
YOU CALL ME?
(male narrator)
DIALOG FROM A PLAY--
HAMLET TO HORATIO:
"THERE ARE MORE THINGS
IN HEAVEN AND EARTH
THAN ARE DREAMT OF
IN YOUR PHILOSOPHY."
DIALOG FROM A PLAY
WRITTEN LONG BEFORE
MEN TOOK TO THE SKY.
THERE ARE MORE THINGS
IN HEAVEN AND EARTH
AND IN THE SKY
THAT PERHAPS CAN
BE DREAMT OF.
AND SOMEWHERE IN BETWEEN
HEAVEN, THE SKY, THE EARTH
LIES THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[curtain music]
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING, THE
CREATOR OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT
NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD FROM
OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW,
MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, WE SHOW
YOU THE FACE OF WAR.
BUT THE KIND OF PORTRAIT WE
VETN U RE TO SAY YOU'VE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
DICK YORK AND
WI LLIAM REYNOLDS STAR
IN THE PURPLE TESTAMENT.
THE STORY OF A MAN WHO
CAN FORECAST DEATH.
THAT'S NEXT WEEK
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE
THE PURPLE TESTAMENT.
WE HOPE YOU'LL JOIN US.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
[curtain music]
(male presenter, off)
BE SURE TO SEE THE
FUN-FILLED FAMILY LIFE
OF ONE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST ENTERTAINERS,
THE DAN NY THOMAS SHOW.
MONDAY NIGHTS, OVER
MOST OF THESE STATIONS.