[eerie music]
(male presenter, off)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT
WHICHIS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS AS INFINITY.
6S
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[music intensifies
dramatically]
[cheerful music]
RIGHT HERE,
LADI ES AND GENTLEM EN,
SPECIAL J U LY CLEAN UP SALE!
LOVELY THINGS,
CALAM IN E LOTION,
GOOD FOR SU N BU RNS!
HOW ABOUT B I NOCU LARS?
(male presenter, off)
STREET SCENE
SUMMER, THE PRESENT.
MAN ON THE SIDEWALK
NAMED LOU BOOKMAN.
AGE, SIXTYISH.
OCCUPATION, PITCHMAN.
LOU BOOKMAN,
A FIXTURE OF THE SUMMER.
A RATHER M INOR COMPONENT
TO A HOT JULY.
A NONDESCRIPT
COMMONPLACE LITTLE MAN,
WHOSE LIFE IS A TREADM ILL
BU ILT OUT OF SIDEWALKS.
IN JUST A MOMENT,
LOU BOOKMAN
WILL HAVE TO CONCERN
HIMSELF WITH SURVIVAL.
BECAUSE AS OF 3 O'CLOCK
THIS HOT JULY AFTERNOON
HE'LL BE STALKED
BY MR. DEATH.
[ominous music]
[cheerful music]
[Lou Iaughs]
(chiIdren)
HI, LOU!
(Lou)
HELLO, DARLING!
OH, HERE, HERE.
OH, MY GOODN ESS,
IT IS HOT TODAY!
YEAH.
LET'S S IT DOWN.
WHAT ARE YOU
SELLING TODAY, LOU?
TOYS, LOU?
ARE YOU SELLING TOYS?
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHAT I WAS SELLING.
[chuckIes]
THERE'S ONE FOR YOU.
THANKS, LOU!
THAT'S ALRIGHT, MAGG I E.
HERE, RICKY.
THANKS, LOU!
NOW THE LOU BOOKMAN
SOCIAL AND ICE CREAM HOUR
TAKES PLACE
RIGHT AFTER SU PPER.
THE REG U LAR
TURN NOW!
DON'T FORG ET!
GOOD BYE.
(chiIdren)
BYE, LOU.
(Lou)
DON'T FORG ET
THE ICE CREAM, HUH?
[humming]
[intense ominous music]
YOU'RE, YOU'RE
THE MAN I SAW
ON THE SIDEWALK TODAY.
YOU WERE WRITING
IN A BOOK.
YOU ARE LOU BOOKMAN,
AREN'T YOU?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOUIS J. BOOKMAN,
IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN SHOW YOU?
MAYBE SOMETHING
IN COLLAR STAYS?
I'LL GET THAT.
NO, MR. BOOKMAN.
I'M NOT HERE
TO BUY ANYTHING.
NOW LET'S GET
TO BUS IN ESS, SHALL WE?
LOU IS J. BOOKMAN,
AG ED 69, RIGHT?
I'LL BE 70
IN SEPTEM BER.
H M. OCCU PATION,
P ITCH MAN, RIGHT?
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
[chuckIes]
ARE YOU
A CENSUS TAKER?
BORN IN NEW YORK
CITY IN 1 890.
THAT'S RIGHT, 1 890.
FATHER JACOB BOOKMAN,
MOTHER FLORA BOOKMAN.
FATH ER'S PLACE OF B I RTH,
DETRO IT, M ICH IGAN,
MOTH ER'S PLACE OF B I RTH
SYRACUSE, NEW YORK, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
MY GOODN ESS,
[chuckIes]
YOU GOT IT ALL DOWN
IN THAT BOOK THERE.
YES, WE HAVE TO KEEP
THESE THINGS EFF ICI ENT.
NOW TODAY
IS THE 1 9TH OF J U LY.
AND YOUR DEPARTU RE'S
AT M I DNIGHT TONIGHT.
MY DEPARTU RE?
[knocking at door]
OH, EXCUSE ME.
HI, MAGG I E!
THE KEY'S BAD, LOU.
CAN YOU F IX IT?
OH, SURE,
COME ON RIGHT IN!
COME ON IN.
(chuckIes)
LET ME SEE IT.
WELL, THERE'S YOUR
TROU BLE RIGHT THERE.
SEE THAT LITTLE COGWH EEL?
WELL, YOU'VE BEEN PUSHING
IN THAT KEY WHEN YOU WERE
WIN DING IT. YOU SEE?
SEE? NOW
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
SEE?
I'D I NTRODUCE
YOU TWO, ONLY I
DON'T KNOW YOUR NAME.
NO NEED.
I THINK I GOT IT
NOW, LOU.
THIS GENTLEMAN
CAME HERE TO ASK ME
A LOT OF QU ESTIONS.
WHAT GENTLEMAN?
[ominous music]
THAT GENTLEMAN!
WHAT GENTLEMAN?
(Mr. Death)
MR. BOOKMAN, SHE CAN'T
SEE ME OR HEAR ME.
WHY NOT?
WHY NOT WHAT, LOU?
WHY CAN'T YOU
SEE HIM OR HEAR HIM?
SEE WHO, LOU?
IT WORKS GREAT NOW, LOU.
THANKS AN AWFU L LOT.
SEE YOU AFTER SU PPER, HUH?
NOW WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU HAVEN'T FORGOT
YOUR MAN N ERS.
AREN'T YOU GON NA
SAY GOODBYE?
OH, YEAH.
GOOD BYE, LOU.
THANKS A LOT!
NO, NO, I MEAN
TO THE GENTLEMAN THERE.
OH, IT'S A GAM E.
THE I NVIS I BLE MAN.
GOODBYE, I NVIS I BLE MAN.
SEE YOU
AFTER SU PPER, LOU.
[suspense music]
I CAN SEE YOU,
YET SHE CAN'T.
(Mr. Death)
ONLY THOSE WHO ARE
TO ACCOMPANY ME
CAN SEE ME.
UNDERSTAND, MR. BOOKMAN?
UH, MR. BOOKMAN,
ONLY THOSE THAT ARE
TO ACCOM PANY ME CAN SEE ME.
NOW DON'T YOU THINK
YOU OUGHT TO START MAKING
YOUR ARRANG EM ENTS?
ARRANG EM ENTS?
FOR WHAT?
FOR YOUR DEPARTU RE.
MY DEPARTU RE WHERE?
[sighs]
YOU JUST DON'T GET IT.
I JUST WILL NEVER
U N DERSTAND YOU PEOPLE.
YOU GET THE I DIOTIC NOTION
THAT LIFE GOES ON FOREVER.
OF COURSE, IT DOESN'T.
EVERYONE HAS
TO GO SOMETIME.
GO? YOU MEAN--
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND WHAT I FU RTH ER
DON'T U N DERSTAND
HOW LITTLE YOU APPRECIATE
THE NATU RE OF YOUR DEPARTU RE.
THINK OF ALL
THE POOR SOU LS WHO
GO IN VIOLENT ACCIDENTS.
THE NON PRECOG N ITION VICTI MS.
WE'RE NOT PERM ITTED
TO FOREWARN THEM.
YOU, MR. BOOKMAN,
FALL INTO THE CATEGORY
OF "NATU RAL CAUSES."
"NATU RAL CAUSES?"
NUMBER ON E, IF IN D YOU
A VERY DEVIOUS SORT,
NUMBER TWO,
I THINK THAT
YOU'RE DISHON EST.
NUMBER THREE,
WHY DON'T YOU SAY
WHAT YOU MEAN!
MR. BOOKMAN, I'VE DONE
EVERYTHING BUT PHON E
YOUR OWN U N DERTAKER.
HOW MUCH CLEARER
DO YOU WANT IT?
IF YOU STILL
DON'T KNOW WHO I AM
THEN YOU'RE THE DU M BEST
MAN I'VE COME UP AGAINST.
[intense ominous music]
YOU ARE--
YOU'RE DEATH?
EXACTLY, MR. BOOKMAN.
NOW, SHALL WE GET
DOWN TO BUSINESS?
TIME OF DEPARTU RE
IS M I DNIGHT TONIGHT.
I TRUST THAT
WILL SU IT YOU.
PREORDI NATION IS
FOR DEATH DU RING SLEEP.
I ASSU ME THIS TOO
WILL MEET WITH
YOUR APPROVAL.
YOU'LL F IN D
THIS A RELATIVELY
S IMPLE AND PAIN LESS--
NO, JUST A MINUTE.
I DON'T WANNA GO!
NO, THEY NEVER DO.
BUT THERE'S
NO REASON TO GO.
I'M A VERY H EALTHY MAN!
OUTSIDE OF A SLIGHT COLD
I HAD LAST WI NTER,
AND A SLIVER THAT FESTERED
IN THAT FING ER THERE,
I DON'T THINK I'VE HAD
A S ICK DAY IN 20 YEARS!
THAT MAY BE,
BUT DEPARTU RE TIME
IS SET FOR M I DNIGHT.
AND DEPARTU RE
WILL BE M I DNIGHT.
DON'T I HAVE ANYTHING
TO SAY ABOUT THAT?
WE DO LISTEN TO APPEALS
BUT FRANKLY, MR. BOOKMAN,
THERE'S VERY LITTLE HERE
IN THE WAY OF AN
EXTEN UATING CI RCU MSTANCE.
THERE ARE THREE MAJOR
CATEGORI ES OF APPEALS.
ON E, IS HARDSH I P CASES.
NOW DO YOU
HAVE A WIFE OR FAM I LY
WHO MIGHT SU FFER BEYON D
A REASONABLE PO I NT
YOUR DEM ISE?
[softIy]
NO, NO FAM I LY. NO.
THE SECON D CATEGORY
IS PRIORITY CASES
STATESM EN, SCI ENTISTS,
M EN ON THE VERG E
OF DISCOVERI ES.
I TAKE IT YOU'RE NOT WORKING
ON ANY MAJOR SCI ENTIF IC
PU RSU IT AT THE MOM ENT.
[softIy]
NO [chuckIes] NO.
[firmIy]
WHAT'S THE THIRD CATEGORY?
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE
QUALIF I ED HERE EITHER.
U N F IN ISH ED BUS IN ESS
OF A MAJOR NATU RE.
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY U N F IN ISH ED
BUS IN ESS, DO YOU?
AH, BUT I DO!
IN DEED I DO!
THAT'S IT,
YOU SEE. I-- YEAH.
I HAVE SOME
U N F IN ISH ED BUS IN ESS.
U N F IN ISH ED BUS IN ESS, YES.
I'VE NEVER FLOWN
IN A H ELICOPTER. THAT'S IT.
I'VE NEVER FLOWN--
(Death)
INSUFFICIENT, MR. BOOKMAN.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NOW YOU LOOK HERE.
I'VE LIVED IN THIS
ROOM FOR 2 1 YEARS.
AND YOU KEEP POPPING UP
IN CORN ERS OF THE ROOM
I'VE NEVER EVEN SEEN BEFORE.
WILL YOU PLEASE
STAY IN ONE PLACE?
IS THERE ANYTHING
ELSE, MR. BOOKMAN?
YES, YES.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN
A ZU LU WAR DANCE.
NOW THAT'S
THE ANSWER RIGHT THERE.
SO YOU'LL HAVE TO GIVE
ME A COUPLE OF MONTHS TO GO
OVER TO THAT ZU LU COU NTRY
NO?
NO. U N F IN ISH ED BUS IN ESS
OF A MAJOR NATU RE
IS SOMETHING A MAN
HAD YEARNED FOR
AND SOMETHING
HE M IGHT ACCOMPLISH
GIVEN AN EXTENSION.
WELL, THERE IS ONE THING.
WHAT IS IT, MR. BOOKMAN?
WELL, BETWEEN YOU AND ME,
I NEVER MADE
A TRU LY BIG P ITCH.
I MEAN, I MEAN
A BIG P ITCH.
A P ITCH BIG ENOUGH
FOR THE SKI ES TO OPEN UP.
YOU KNOW,
A PITCH FOR THE ANGELS.
OF COURSE,
IT WOULDN'T MEAN
VERY MUCH TO YOU,
BUT IT WOULD MEAN
A GREAT DEAL TO ME.
IT WOULD MEAN
THAT FOR ONE MOMENT
IN MY WHOLE LIFE
I WOULD HAVE DONE
SOMETHING SUCCESSFUL.
IT WOULD MEAN
THAT MAYBE THE CH I LDREN
WOULD BE VERY PROU D OF ME.
THE CH I LDREN?
YES, YES, I'VE ALWAYS
HAD QU ITE A FON DN ESS
FOR CH I LDREN, YOU KNOW.
YES, THAT'S ALL
HERE IN THE RECORD.
THE PROBLEM HERE,
MR. BOOKMAN, IS THAT
YOU'D REQU I RE DELAY U NTI L--
U NTI L I MAKE A P ITCH!
THE KIND OF P ITCH
I WAS TALKING TO YOU ABOUT.
THE ONE FOR THE ANGELS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ONE FOR THE ANGELS.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY,
MR. BOOKMAN,
BUT, NO.
YOU SEE, THESE CATEGORIES
ARE VERY SPECIFIC
AND WHEN REFERENCE IS MADE
TO U N F IN ISH ED BUS IN ESS
OF A MAJOR NATU RE,
THE ONLY I NTERPRETATION
TO BE MADE HERE
IS S IMPLY THAT--
WHAT-- WHAT I MEAN
IS THAT, UH,
U N FORTU NATELY, MR. BOOKMAN,
AN AB I LITY TO, TO SUCCEED
IN A GIVEN
PROFESS IONAL VENTU RE
IS REALLY HARDLY
OF A MAJOR--
M EAN A GREAT
DEAL TO YOU, DOES IT?
A GREAT DEAL.
ALL RIGHT,
MR. BOOKMAN.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES
I BELIEVE I CAN GRANT
YOU A DELAY.
U NTI L--
WHAT DO YOU MEAN 'U NTI L?'
U NTI L YOU'VE MADE THIS P ITCH.
I CAN LIVE TI L THEN?
THAT'S THE AG REEM ENT.
OH, WELL I THINK
THAT'S A F IN E BARGAI N.
I DIDN'T GET YOUR NAME.
NOW, ABOUT
THIS P ITCH, MR. BOOKMAN,
WHEN MIGHT
WE EXPECT IT?
WH EN?
OH, SOON.
YOU KNOW.
MAYBE NOT THIS YEAR, MAYBE
NOT FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS,
[chuckIes] BUT SOON.
I HAVE THE VERY ODD FEELING
THAT YOU'RE TAKING
ADVANTAG E OF ME.
OH, YOU HAVE?
WELL, THAT'S A P ITY,
BECAUSE I AM!
YOU'LL NEVER CATCH ME
MAKING A P ITCH ANYMORE.
YOU THINK YOU CAN
FOOL ME, EH?
[chuckIes]
I'LL HARDLY OPEN
MY MOUTH FROM NOW ON.
[mischievous music]
REALLY, MR. BOOKMAN?
THIS IS MUCH MORE
SERIOUS THAN YOU I MAG IN E.
IT'S MUCH MORE COM PLEX
THAN YOUREALIZE, WHAT
YOU'VE JUST DONE.
HERE I'VE GON E
OUT OF MY WAY TO H ELP YOU
AND THIS IS THE WAY
YOUREPAY ME?
MR. BOOKMAN.
IT WON'T JUST END HERE,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
THERE WILL BE
CONSEQU ENCES, YOU SEE?
FYI, THAT MEANS
FOR YOU IN FORMATION
YOU MADE YOUR BED
AND YOU SHALL HAVE
TO SLEEP IN IT.
WE MADE A BARGAI N
THAT I DON'T HAVE TO GO
U NTI L I MAKE A P ITCH.
AND YOU'LL HAVE TO WAIT
U NTI L I MAKE THAT P ITCH.
I CAN SAY THIS
WITHOUT THE LEAST
FEAR OF CONTRADICTION.
HAVE YOU GOT
A LONG WAIT!
[chuckIes]
THAT MAY WELL BE,
MR. BOOKMAN,
BUT S I NCE YOU WON'T
COME WITH ME,
I'VE BEEN FORCED
TO SELECT AN ALTERNATIVE.
[brakes screeching
and woman yelling]
[people shouting]
MAGG I E!
I SWEAR
I DIDN'T SEE H ER.
SHE J U M PED RIGHT
OFF THE CURB AND I
HAD NO CHANCE TO STOP.
I SWEAR TO YOU
I NEVER HAD NO
CHANCE TO STOP AT ALL.
WELL, THEN SOMEON E
SEND FOR A DOCTOR!
GET AN AM BU LANCE.
I'LL CALL ON E.
(Lou)
YOU'RE GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT, DARLING.
YOU'RE GON NA
BE JUST F IN E.
HI, LOU.
HELLO, SWEETHEART.
[intense ominous music]
LOU?
YES?
WHO'S THAT MAN?
[ominous music]
DO YOU SEE HIM?
YES, LOU.
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU CAN'T TAKE H ER.
NO, S I REE,
NOW LISTEN, I'LL GO.
N EVER MIND THE P ITCH.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO WAIT,
I'LL GO RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN'T TAKE H ER.
I'LL GO WITH YOU, I'LL--
[ominous music]
(man)
HOW'S MAGG I E, DOCTOR?
(Doctor)
I CAN'T TELL.
DOCTOR?
IT'S HARD TO TELL.
SHE'S A VERY S ICK
LITTLE GIRL,
BUT WE'LL KNOW
SOON, SHE SHOU LD HAVE
A CRIS IS BY M I DNIGHT.
BY M I DNIGHT?
I THINK BY THEN.
HE WON'T COME HERE.
I WON'T LET HIM COME HERE.
[suspense music]
[intense ominous music]
GOOD EVENING,
MR. BOOKMAN.
YOU'VE GOT
BUS IN ESS IN THERE?
I MOST CERTAIN LY DO.
IT'S QUARTER TO 1 2 :00.
IN 1 5 MINUTES, M I DNIGHT.
THAT'S MY APPO I NTM ENT.
MR. DEATH, THAT LITTLE
G I RL'S ONLY 8 YEARS OLD.
I'M READY NOW.
I'M SORRY, MR. BOOKMAN,
BUT I HAD TO MAKE
OTHER ARRANG EM ENTS.
IT'S IMPOSS I BLE
TO CHANG E THEM NOW.
SHE'S TO COME
WITH ME AT M I DNIGHT,
SO IMUST BE
IN THERE AT M I DNIGHT.
AND IF YOU'RE
NOT IN THERE?
IT WOULD BE PRETTY
MUCH U N HEARD OF.
YOU SEE,
IF I DIDN'T GET IN THERE
AT PRECISELY M I DNIGHT,
THEN THE WHOLE
TIMETABLE WOULD
BE UPSET.
IT'S U N HEARD OF.
IT'S U N HEARD OF?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING, MR. BOOKMAN?
I'M JUST SETTING UP
A P ITCH, THAT'S ALL.
AT THIS TIME
OF NIGHT?
OH, I VERY OFTEN
HAVE A LATE SALE.
VERY OFTEN!
NOT MANY CUSTOM ERS.
OH, THEY'LL BE HERE.
THEY'LL COME ROU N D--
YOU'RE HERE, ANYWAY.
OH, YES, I'M HERE.
BUT I'M AFRAI D
I'M NOT MUCH OF A CUSTOM ER.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
HAVE YOU SEEN MY STOCK?
TAKE THIS LOVELY TI E
HERE, FOR I NSTANCE.
OH, OH, EXCUSE ME.
WHAT DOES THAT
LOOK LIKE TO YOU?
IT LOOKS LIKE A TI E.
FEEL IT.
SO--
LADI ES AND GENTLEM EN,
IF YOU WI LL
FEAST YOUR EYES
ON PROBABLY THE MOST
EXCITING INVENTION
S I NCE ATOM IC EN ERGY.
A S IMU LATED S I LK
SO FABU LOUSLY CONCE IVED
AS TO MYSTI FY
EVEN THE ANCI ENT
CH IN ESE S I LK MAN U FACTU RERS.
AN ALMOST U N BELI EVABLE
ATTENTION TO DETAI L!
IT HAS A WON DERFU L
WORK OF WEAVING.
[suspense music]
(Lou)
WITNESS, IF YOU
WILL, A DEMONSTRATION
OF TENSILE STRENGTH.
FEEL THAT IF YOU WI LL, S I R.
UNBELIEVABLE, ISN'T IT?
AS STRONG AS STEEL.
YET AS FRAG I LE
AND DELICATE
AS SHANTU NG S I LK.
(Lou)
PICTURE IF YOU WILL
300 YEARS
OF BACKBREAKING
RESEARCH AND LABOR,
TO DEVELOP THIS.
THE ABSOLUTE
ULTIMATE IN STRENGTH.
AND WHAT WOULD
YOU EXPECT TO PAY
FOR THIS FABU LOUS,
I SAY FABU LOUS, I NCREDI BLE,
AMAZING DEVELOPM ENT
OF THE TAI LOR'S ART?
WOULD YOU PAY
30 DOLLARS A SPOOL?
25? 20? 1 0?
WELL, VERY WELL
YOU MIGHT, S I R,
IF YOU WERE TRYING
TO PU RCHASE THIS
AT STORES.
BUT THIS FANTASTIC THREAD
IS NOT AVAILABLE IN STORES.
IT IS SM UGG LED IN
BY ORI ENTAL B I RDS
ESPECIALLY TRAIN ED
FOR OCEAN TRAVEL.
EACH CARRYING A B IT
QUANTITY IN A SMALL SATCH EL
U N DERN EATH THEIR
RU BY TH ROATS.
IT TAKES 832 CROSSINGS
TO SUPPLY ENOUGH THREAD
TO GO AROUND ONE SPOOL.
AND TONIGHT,
AT MY SPECIAL
GET ACQUAI NTED, I NTRODUCTORY,
M I D J U LY HOT
SUMMER SALE
I OFFER YOU THIS
FABU LOUS TH READ
NOT AT 20
DOLLARS A SPOOL,
NOT AT 1 0, NOT AT 5,
BUT AT THE RIDICULOUSLY
LOW PRICE OF 25
CENTS A SPOOL.
I'LL TAKE ALL YOU HAVE.
(Lou)
SEWING NEEDLES, YARN,
MARVELOUS PLASTIC SHOELACES,
GENU INE STATIC ERADICATOR
WILL F IT
ANY STAN DARD RADIO,
SUNTAN OIL,
ECZEMA POWDER,
RAZORS, ATHLETE'S
FEET DESTROYER,
HOW ABOUT SOME N ICE
S IMU LATED KASH M I R SOCKS--
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
I'LL TAKE IT ALL.
ALL OF IT.
RIGHT THERE.
(Lou)
AND NOW FOR
THE P I ECE DE RES ISTANCE.
AN ITEM NEVER BEFORE
OFFERED IN THIS OR ANY
OTHER COU NTRY.
ONE GUARANTEED
LIVE HUMAN MAN SAVER.
HOW'S THAT?
FOR WHAT I ASK
YOU S I R, RECE IVE
A WI LLING, CAPABLE,
WORLDLY, HIGHLY SOPH ISTICATED,
WON DERFU LLY LOYAL
RIGHT HAND MAN
TO USE IN ANY
CAPACITY YOU SEE F IT.
HOW'S THAT?
ME!
LOU IS J. BOOKMAN,
THE FIRST MODEL
OF HIS KIND,
HE COMES TO YOU
WITH AN ABSOLUTE GUARANTEE
ALL PARTS I NTERCHANG EABLE.
WITH A CERTIF ICATE OF 4 YEARS
SERVICE AB I LITY
HE EATS LITTLE,
HE SLEEPS LITTLE,
HE RESTS ONLY OCCAS IONALLY,
AND THERE HE IS
AT YOUR ELBOW
AT YOU BECK AND CALL
WHENEVER YOU NEED HIM.
MR. BOOKMAN, YOU ARE
A PERSUAS IVE MAN.
I CHALLENG E
ANY OTHER STORE
WHOLESALE HOUSE
OR IN DUSTRY
TO EVEN COME
CLOSE TO MATCHING
WHAT I OFFER YOU HERE.
BECAUSE MY DEAR MAN,
I OFFER YOU, I OFFER YOU--
[beIIs toII]
IT'S M I DNIGHT!
IT'S M I DNIGHT AND I'VE
MISSED MY APPO I NTM ENT!
GIVE HER THE SEDATIVES
EVERY THREE HOURS,
M RS. POLANSKY.
SHE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
SHE JUST NEEDS A LOT
OF REST NOW.
[bells continue to toll]
SHE'S ALL RIGHT.
ONE MINUTE PAST
1 2 :00, MR. BOOKMAN.
AND YOU MADE ME
MISS MY APPO I NTM ENT.
THANK GOD.
A MOST PERSUAS IVE
P ITCH, MR. BOOKMAN.
AN EXCELLENT P ITCH.
YES, IT'S QU ITE A P ITCH,
VERY EFFECTIVE.
IT'S THE BEST
I'VE EVER DONE.
IT'S THE KIND OF A P ITCH
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO MAKE.
A BIG ON E.
A P ITCH SO BIG,
SO BIG THAT THE SKY
WOULD OPEN UP.
A P ITCH FOR THE ANGELS.
THAT'S RIGHT,
[soft melancholy music]
WELL, I GU ESS IT'S
TIME FOR ME NOW.
AS PER OUR AG REEM ENT.
WELL, I'M READY.
AFTER YOU, MR. BOOKMAN.
OH, EXCUSE ME,
I FORGOT SOMETHING
I'LL BE BACK IN A MINUTE.
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHO MIGHT NEED
SOMETHING UP THERE.
U P THERE?
U P THERE, MR. BOOKMAN.
YOU MADE IT.
(male presenter, off)
LOUIS J. BOOKMAN,
AGE, SIXTYISH,
OCCUPATION, PITCHMAN.
FORMALLY, A FIXTURE
OF THE SUMMER,
FORMALLY, A RATHER M INOR
COMPONENT TO A HOT JULY.
BUT THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE
A MAN BELOVED BY THE CHILDREN
AND THEREFORE,
A MOST IMPORTANT MAN.
IT COULDN'T HAPPEN, YOU SAY?
PROBABLY NOT
IN MOST PLACES,
BUT IT DID HAPPEN
IN THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter, off)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE,
WILL TELL YOU
ABOUT NEXT WEEK'S STORY
AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, WE I NVITE
YOU TO TAKE A WALK
DOWN A WESTERN
FRONTI ER STREET
AT THE ELBOW
OF A DOOM ED GU N MAN.
WHOSE SALVATIONS LI ES
IN NOTHING LESS THAN
A MAGIC POTION,
AND A COLT 45.
MR. DAN DU RYEA STARS
ON MR. DENTON ON DOOMSDAY.
NEXT WEEK
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
WE HOPE YOU'LL
BE ABLE TO BE WITH US.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
(male presenter, off)
KIMBERLY CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OR ALIVE,
SATURDAY NIGHT OVER
MOST OF THESE SAME STATIONS.
(male presenter, off)
THE TWILIGHT ZONE
BROUGHT TO YOU BY
OASIS FILTER CIGARETTES
THE TOBACCO IS SOOTHED
FOR THE SOFTEST TASTE OF ALL.
AND MENTHOL
M ISTING MAKES IT SO.
[relaxing music]
(male presenter, off)
THIS IS AN OASIS.
COOL. REFRESHING.
THIS IS AN OASIS, TOO.
JUST AS THE M IST OF MOUNTAIN
DEW REFRESHES A FLOWER,
KEEPS IT FRESH ALL DAY,
SO THE TOBACCO
IN OASIS IS M ISTED,
GENTLY M ISTED
ALL OVER WITH MENTHOL.
THE TOBACCO IS SOOTHED
FOR THE SOFTEST TASTE OF ALL.
AND MENTHOL M ISTING
MAKES IT SO.
THAT'S OASIS,
THE ONLY FILTER CIGARETTE
THAT'S OASIS COOL,
OASIS M ILD,
OASIS FRESH.
? BUY OASIS,
TRY OASIS,
MOST REFRESHING CIGARETTE?
OASIS, THE TOBACCO
IS SOOTHED WITH THE SOFTEST
TASTE OF ALL.
MENTHOL M ISTING MAKES IT SO.
(male presenter, off)
TWILIGHT ZONE WAS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY,
KIMBERLY CLARK, WHOSE
HELPFUL KLEENEX PRODUCTS
INCLUDE KLEENEX TISSUES,
KLEENEX TABLE NAPKINS,
NEW KLEENEX TOWELS,
AND DELSEY BATHROOM TISSUE.