[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT
A TABLEAU OF REALITY.
THINGS OF SUBSTANCE,
OF PHYSICAL MATERIAL.
A DESK, A WINDOW, A LIGHT.
THESE THINGS EXIST
AND HAVE DIMENSION.
NOW, THIS IS ARTHUR CURTIS,
AGE 36, WHO ALSO IS REAL.
HE HAS FLESH AND BLOOD,
MUSCLE AND M IND.
BUT IN JUST A MOMENT, WE WILL
SEE HOW THIN A LINE SEPARATES
THAT WHICH WE ASSUME TO BE REAL
WITH THAT MANUFACTURED
INSIDE OF A M IND.
GOOD MORNING,
MR. CU RTIS.
AH, GOOD MORNING, SALLY.
I THOUGHT I'D BETTER
GET ANEARLY START.
I GOTTA LEAVE ABOUT 3 :00.
MY WIFE AND I HAVEN'T
GOTTEN A THING FOR TI NA'S
B I RTH DAY PARTY YET.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S SATU RDAY
AFTERNOON, ISN'T IT?
YEAH, IF MY DEAR DAUG HTER
CAN HOLD OUT THAT LONG.
IS SHE EXCITED?
THAT'S ALL SH E
CAN TALK ABOUT.
THAT'S ABOUT NORMAL.
ARE THE MATSON
CONTRACTS READY, YET?
SURE. IF IN ISH ED THEM
LAST NIGHT BEFORE I LEFT.
HERE THEY ARE.
THANKS. WELL,
TO THE GRIN DSTON E.
OH, UH, I ALMOST FORGOT.
COULD YOU CALL AND SEE I F
YOU CAN CHANG E THE PLAN E
RESERVATIONS TO SATU RDAY NIGHT?
OF COURSE.
STRAINING AT
THE B IT, HUH?
IT'S THE FIRST REAL
VACATION MARIAN AND
I HAVE HAD IN YEARS,
SO WE F IG U RED WHY
LOSE THE WHOLE WEEKEN D
BEFORE STARTING OUT.
I DON'T BLAME YOU,
MR. CU RTIS.
SO, UH, SATU RDAY NIGHT,
IT'S SAN FRANCISCO,
HERE WE COME.
[whistling Coming
Through the Rye]
OH, FOR H EAVEN'S SAKE.
(Man)
CUT!
COME ON, J ERRY.
IS IT SO HARD
TO MAKE A PHONE CALL?
HEY.
HEY!
REMEMBER ME, JERRY?
MARTY F ISH ER.
YOUR FRI EN DLY
N EIGH BORHOOD
MOVIE DI RECTOR.
SALLY, WHAT--
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
MR. RAIGAN?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I'M WARNING YOU, JERRY.
THEY WON'T TAKE
IT ANYMORE.
WISE UP, BOY.
YOU'RE ON THE EDG E.
JERRY?
IT'S OKAY, MARTY.
JUST A LITTLE GAG.
WE'LL TRY IT AGAIN,
SHALL WE, J ERRY?
WE'LL PICK IT UP
FROM THE PHONE CALL.
YOU'RE PHONING YOUR WIFE
TO TELL HER TO MEET YOU
DOWNTOWN AT 3 : 1 5, RIGHT?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WHERE AM I?
WHAT IS THIS,
SOME KIND OF A
JOKE OR SOMETHING?
I DON'T KNOW YOU.
I DON'T KNOW ANY OF YOU.
DON'T LET HIM GET AWAY.
MARTY, I SWEAR
THE AG ENCY HAD NO
IDEA THAT RAIGAN WAS--
JUST KEEP HIM
HERE, SAM.
SURE, SURE. I'LL PHON E--
I'LL PHONE BRIN KLEY.
IS THERE A
TELEPHONE IN HERE?
WHY DON'T YOU S IT DOWN?
I ASKED YOU
IF THERE WAS
A PHON E--
IF I HAVE TO CALL
BRIN KLEY ON THIS,
YOU'RE DEAD.
J ERRY, WHY DON'T YOU
LISTEN TO ME FOR ONE
MINUTE, WILL YOU?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU.
CALL AN AM BU LANCE.
MAKE IT FAST.
SHALL I USE
THE STAG E PHON E?
NO. IF HE F IN DS OUT,
THERE'S NO TELLING
WHAT H E'D DO. GO ON.
J ERRY, LET'S GO
TO YOUR DRESSING ROOM.
WHERE'S THE
N EAREST PHON E?
J ERRY.
MY NAME IS
ARTH U R CU RTIS.
ARTH U R CU RTIS?
LU NCH, ONE HOUR.
MAY I HAVE
IN FORMATION, PLEASE?
WOULD YOU GET ME
THE TELEPHONE NUMBER
OF ARTH U R CU RTIS?
22437 VENTN ER ROAD
IN WOODLAND
H I LLS, PLEASE?
VENTN ER. V-E-N-T-N-E-R.
WHAT? OH, NO, NO.
YOU'RE M ISTAKEN.
OF COURSE THERE'S
A PHONE THERE.
NO, LISTEN,
IT'S MY OWN HOM E.
I'M ARTH U R CU RTIS. I--
WELL, I-I CAN'T SEEM
TO REMEMBER IT AT THE
MOM ENT. WILL YOU--
NO, NO, IT'S NOT AN
U N LISTED NUMBER. I--
I DON'T THINK.
WILL YOU PLEASE
TRY AGAIN, OPERATOR?
I KNOW THERE'S
A PHONE THERE.
(Fisher)
JERRY?
YOU'RE WRONG, OPERATOR.
PLEASE, CON N ECT ME
WITH YOUR SU PERVISOR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
J ERRY, I WANNA TALK TO YOU
IN YOUR DRESSING ROOM.
YOU'RE NOT WELL.
I'M GETTING OUT OF
HERE. I'M GOING HOM E.
J ERRY!
[tires screeching]
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR MIND?
J ERRY, IF YOU'RE
DRU N K AGAIN, SO--
TAKE YOUR
HAN DS OFF ME.
LOOK, I DON'T CARE
IF THEY BOU NCE YOU.
I DON'T CARE IF YOU NEVER
WORK AGAIN THE REST OF
YOUR MISERABLE LIFE.
BUT YOU'RE GON NA
PAY ME WHAT THE J U DG E
TELLS YOU TO PAY ME,
OR, SO H ELP ME, I'LL PUT YOU
SO FAR BEH IN D BARS THEY'LL
N EVER F IN D YOU AGAIN.
M RS. RAIGAN?
I'M NOT MRS.
RAIGAN ANYMORE.
I'M SORRY.
CAN I TALK TO
YOU IN PRIVATE?
I HAVEN'T THE TIME.
HE'S COMING WITH ME.
HE'LL BE BACK FOR
THE AFTERNOON SHOOTING.
THAT'S NOT EXACTLY
WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
I'VE CALLED AN AM BU LANCE.
JERRY'S HAVING
A NERVOUS BREAKDOWN.
AM BU LANCE?
I'M NOT JOKING,
M RS. RAIGAN.
[engine starting]
[tires screeching]
OKAY, MARTY, I
CALLED THE HOSP ITAL.
I'LL DRIVE.
I'LL DRIVE, J ERRY.
I SAID I'LL DRIVE.
YOU'D THINK YOU'RE
GONNA KI LL US.
J ERRY, I'M GON NA
BLEED YOU. I'M GON NA
BLEED YOU DRY.
NOW LISTEN TO ME,
WHOEVER YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU
THINK I AM, BUT YOU'RE
WRONG! YOU'RE WRONG!
MY NAME IS CU RTIS,
ARTH U R CU RTIS.
AND I HAVEN'T THE
SLIGHTEST IDEA WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I'M GONNA DRIVE TO MY
HOME IN WOODLAND H I LLS.
WHEN WE GET THERE,
YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
CAR BACK.
YOU THINK YOU CAN CH ISEL
YOUR WAY OUT OF PAYING ME
WITH A CH EAP TRICK--
MY NAME IS ARTH U R CU RTIS.
MY WIFE'S NAME IS MARIAN.
I HAVE A DAUG HTER NAMED TI NA.
WE LIVE AT 22437
VENTN ER ROAD IN
WOODLAND H I LLS.
I'M WARNING YOU, J ERRY.
MY NAME IS
ARTH U R CU RTIS!
[tires screeching]
NO, HE ISN'T DRUNK,
MR. BRIN KLEY.
I-I-I COULD TELL
YOU HE'S CRACKED.
HIS MIND IS GON E.
HE SWEARS H E'S
ARTH U R CU RTIS.
SWEARS IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ARTH U R CU RTIS,
THE CHARACTER
HE'S PLAYING
IN THE PICTURE.
YOU'LL LET ME KNOW
WHEN THE GRAND TOU R
IS OVER, WON'T YOU?
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND. I--
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE I AM AND
YET IMUST--
I LIVE HERE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, JERRY?
AN ACADEMY AWARD?
I TOLD YOU,
MY NAME IS--
CUT IT OUT.
YOU NEVER HAD A LESS
RECEPTIVE AUDIENCE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU GO AHEAD.
PLAY IT OUT.
DO WHAT YOU PLEASE.
I COULDN'T CARE LESS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU ASK WHERE
VENTN ER ROAD IS.
TI NA.
TINA.
MOM MY!
GET IN. WOULD YOU
RATHER GO TO JAIL
FOR ATTEMPTED ASSAULT?
GET IN.
THAT'S THE ON E, MOM MY.
HE'S THE ONE
THAT GRABBED ME.
HE SCARED ME.
I WON DER WHAT
BRIN KLEY WANTS.
YOUR BLOOD PROBABLY.
WELL, HE'LL HAVE
TO WAIT HIS TURN.
WELL? COME ON. I SAID
I'D HAVE YOU BACK FOR
THIS AFTERNOON'S SHOOTING.
GET OUT, J ERRY.
WHERE ARE WE?
COME ON.
I GOTTA GET HOM E.
YOU ARE HOME.
NOW, LET'S GO.
[door closing]
J ERRY, WHERE
HAVE YOU BEEN?
SAM PHON ED ME OVER
AN HOUR AGO. SAID
YOU LEFT THE STU DIO.
COME ON.
CAN'T THIS WAIT, NORA?
NO. IT CAN'T.
IT'S WAITED
LONG ENOUGH.
I WANT MY MONEY
BEFORE HE GOES OFF
ON HIS NEXT BING E.
AND I'M GOING
TO GET IT. NOW.
NOW, LOOK, I TRI ED
TO EXPLAIN TO THAT,
THAT WOMAN
THAT I'M NOT WHO YOU ALL
SEEM TO THINK I AM. MY NAME
IS CU RTIS. I LIVE I N--
J ERRY, STOP IT.
YOU DON'T SEEM TO REALIZE
THE POS ITION YOU'RE IN.
WHERE DO YOU H I DE
THE CHECKBOOK?
I'LL F IN D IT IF I HAVE
TO TEAR THIS HOUSE APART.
J ERRY, I'LL HAVE
TO LAY IT RIGHT
ON THE LIN E.
IF YOU LOSE THIS
ASSIGN MENT, WE'LL
HAVE TO DROP YOU.
WE CAN'T COVER UP
FOR YOU ANYMORE. IT'S
BEYON D THAT, WAY BEYON D.
I'M SORRY, BUT
YOU'RE M ISTAKEN--
NOW, LOOK!
ALL RIGHT.
THEY CAN SHOOT
AROUND YOU TODAY.
I'LL TELL THEM
YOU'RE...S ICK.
THEY WON'T BUY IT,
BUT I'LL MAKE IT
STICK SOMEHOW.
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO BE THERE
TOMORROW, BRIGHT AND EARLY.
YOU'VE GOT TO CONVI NCE THEM--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON. I DON'T
NOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
(Nora)
ALL RIGHT,
GET OVER HERE.
NORA, DON'T.
LOOK, YOU STAY
OUT OF THIS.
CAN'T YOU SEE
THAT HE'S UPSET?
YOU'RE GONNA TO SIGN THIS
CHECK. YOU'RE GON NA
SIGN IT RIGHT NOW.
G ERALD RAIGAN.
G-E-R-A-L-D
R-A-I-G-A-N!
THAT'S NOT MY NAME!
NOW, LISTEN, THIS
HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH!
I'M NOT GERALD RAIGAN.
I DON'T KNOW ANY OF YOU.
MY NAME IS
ARTH U R CU RTIS.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
ARTH U R CU RTIS,
AND I WORK FOR--
I'D LIKE TO HAVE
A TELEPHONE NUMBER
OF THE DAVIS
MORTON COM PANY.
ONE-EIGHT-NINE
BRAND STREET,
LOS ANGELES.
OF COURSE THERE IS!
I WORK THERE!
I'VE WORKED THERE FOR
THE LAST SEVEN YEARS!
HELLO? HELLO!
FEELING BETTER?
YOU DON'T
BELIEVE ME,
DO YOU?
I BELIEVE YOU'VE
BEEN OVERWORKED,
U N DER A TERRI BLE STRAI N.
YOU NEED H ELP, J ERRY.
H ELP?
IT'S NOT IN MY
PROVI NCE, BUT I'VE
KNOWN YOU A LONG TIME.
CAN'T YOU SEE
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
"CAST OF CHARACTERS.
ARTH U R CU RTIS, 36.
"A YOUNG BUSINESS
EXECUTIVE, HAPPILY MARRIED.
"CURTIS LIVES IN
WOODLAND HILLS WITH
HIS WIFE AND CHILD. HE--
"MARIAN CU RTIS, 33.
A CHARMING YOU NG WOMAN.
"TYPICAL OF THAT
EFFICIENT BREED
WHICH CAN MANAGE
A HOUSE AND FAMILY
AND STILL HAVE AMPLE--"
STOP IT!
THE ONLY IN FORMATION
YOU HAVE ABOUT
ARTH U R CU RTIS
IS WRITTEN
IN THIS SCRI PT.
NO.
J ERRY, SOMETIMES I'D
LIKE TO ESCAPE MYSELF
AWAY FROM THIS TU RMO I L
TO SOME S IMPLER EXISTENCE.
YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT
THIS IS A DELUS ION.
THAT I'M REALLY
G ERALD RAIGAN,
A DRUNKEN--
GERALD RAIGAN,
A SWEET, UNHAPPY MAN,
BU RDEN ED WITH
THAT HARPY.
JERRY RAIGAN,
TRYING TO FIND A LITTLE
HAPPINESS, THAT'S ALL.
NO. IT'S REAL.
IT'S REAL.
I WISH IT WERE.
FOR YOUR SAKE,
I'VE GOT TO GO, J ERRY.
TRY AND GET SOME REST.
FORGET ABOUT THE
PICTURE. YOU DON'T
HAVE TO F IN ISH IT.
I JUST SPOKE
TO THE STU DIO
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
THEY'RE CANCELING
PRODUCTION.
ARTH U R CU RTIS IS DEAD.
I'VE GOTTA GET BACK.
IT'S TOO LATE, J ERRY.
IT'S F IN ISH ED.
I'VE GOTTA GET
BACK TO MY OFF ICE.
YOUR OFF ICE?
IF YOU MEAN THE SET,
THEY'RE PROBABLY
TEARING IT DOWN RIGHT NOW.
THEY CAN'T.
THEY CAN'T!
JERRY!
[tires screech]
[muffled voices]
WAIT!
MR. RAIGAN!
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
WE'RE JUST FOLLOWING
ORDERS, MR. RAIGAN.
DON'T LEAVE ME HERE.
HONEY?
MARIAN.
[sighs]
OH, MARIAN.
WELL, MY GOODN ESS.
I'VE BEEN PHONING
YOU ALL DAY LONG.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
BEEN?
SALLY KEPT SAYING YOU
WERE OUT. SHE DIDN'T
SEE YOU GO OUT--
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
ARTY! ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
WELL, SURE.
WHERE WERE YOU?
MR. CURTIS?
ARE YOU LEAVING NOW?
YES.
I HAVE YOUR TICKETS
FOR SATU RDAY NIGHT.
HERE YOU ARE.
F IN E. THANKS.
(man)
ALL RIGHT. LET'S GET THOSE
LAMPS AND TABLES OUT OF HERE.
HONEY, WHAT'S THE MATTER?
PLEASE.
HONEY, LET'S NOT WAIT.
LET'S GO ON OUR VACATION
RIGHT AWAY.
HEY. WHAT'S WRONG?
NOTHING, DARLING.
I JUST DON'T WANT
TO LOSE YOU.
HAS RAIGAN BEEN HERE?
YEAH, HE WAS HERE
A M INUTE AGO.
YOU DIDN'T
SEE HIM LEAVE?
NO, I DIDN'T. HEY,
ANY OF YOU GUYS SEE
RAIGAN LEAVE?
(man)
NO, WE DIDN'T.
WOULD YOU TAKE A LOOK
IN HIS DRESSING ROOM?
YEAH. SURE.
HE'S NOT IN
HIS DRESSING ROOM.
WON DER WHERE HE IS.
(narrator)
THE MODUS OPERANDI FOR
THE DEPARTURE FROM LIFE
IS USUALLY A PINE BOX OF
SUCH AND SUCH DIMENSIONS,
AND THIS IS
THE ULTIMATE
IN REALITY.
BUT THERE ARE
OTHER WAYS FOR A MAN
TO EXIT FROM LIFE.
TAKE THE CASE OF
ARTHUR CURTIS, AGE 36.
HIS DEPARTURE
WAS ALONG A HIGHWAY
WITH AN EXIT SIGN THAT
READS "THIS WAY
TO ESCAPE."
ARTHUR CURTIS, EN ROUTE
TO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR OF
TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
NEXT WEEK, THE CU LPRIT
IS CHARLES BEAU MONT,
THE GENTLEMAN RESPONS I BLE
FOR A STORY U N LIKE ANY
YOU'VE EVER SEEN.
YOU TALK OF IMMORTALITY,
THE BUS IN ESS OF BEING ABLE
TO LIVE FOR AS LONG AS
ONE WANTS.
WELL, NEXT WEEK YOU'LL SEE
KEVIN MCCARTHY AT THE
TAI L-END OF A LIFE
THAT'S GONE ON FOR
TWO THOUSAND YEARS.
THE PLAY IS CALLED
LONG LIVE WALTER JAMESON
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
[eerie music]
EVERY YEAR
THE RED CROSS
NEEDS MONEY.
THIS YEAR AIN'T
NO DIFFERENT.