[eerie music]
(male narrator)
THERE IS A FIFTH DIMENSION
BEYOND THAT WHICH
IS KNOWN TO MAN.
IT IS A DIMENSION
AS VAST AS SPACE
AND AS TIMELESS
AS INFINITY.
IT IS THE MIDDLE GROUND
BETWEEN LIGHT AND SHADOW,
BETWEEN SCIENCE
AND SUPERSTITION.
AND IT LIES BETWEEN
THE PIT OF MAN'S FEARS
AND THE SUMMIT
OF HIS KNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE DIMENSION
OF IMAGINATION.
IT IS AN AREA
WHICH WE CALL
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
WELL, MR. AND MRS. GIBBS.
OH, HELLO,
MR. HENSON.
IS YOUR ROOM COM FORTABLE?
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
OH, IT'S LOVELY.
IT'S JUST LOVELY.
YOU KNOW, YOU
MAKE US FEEL, YOU
MAKE US FEEL IMPORTANT.
YOU ARE IMPORTANT,
MRS. GIBBS.
AFTER ALL, IT ISN'T
EVERY DAY THAT WE ENTERTAIN
CELEBRATED CONTEST WINNERS.
NO, NOT EVERY DAY.
MAYBE EVERY OTHER DAY.
I BROUGHT ALONG OUR HOTEL
PHOTOGRAPHER TO TAKE A PICTURE
OF YOU AND MR. GIBBS
FOR YOUR HOMETOWN PAPER.
NOW, IF YOU COULD JUST GET
A LITTLE BIT CLOSER TOGETHER.
AND SMILE. SMILE.
OKAY, JOE. READY?
UH-HUH. HOLD IT.
OH, THIS IS
SO EXCITING.
THAT'S THE ELGIN
BUGLE, MR. HENSON.
HOW'S THAT?
THE ELGIN BUGLE. THAT'S
OUR HOMETOWN PAPER.
OH, YES, OF COURSE.
WELL, WE'LL SEND THEM
OUT A COPY RIGHT AWAY.
NOW, ENJOY YOURSELVES, FOLKS,
AND REMEMBER, YOU HAVE
UNLIMITED CREDIT.
(narrator)
MR. AND MRS. FRANKLIN GIBBS.
THREE DAYS AND TWO NIGHTS,
ALL EXPENSES PAID AT
A LAS VEGAS HOTEL.
WON BY VIRTUE
OF MRS. GIBBS'
KNACK WITH A PHRASE,
BUT UNBEKNOWNST TO EITHER
MR. OR MRS. GIBBS
IS THE FACT THAT THERE'S
A PRIZE IN THEIR PACKAGE
NEITHER EXPECTED
NOR BARGAINED FOR.
IN JUST A MOMENT, ONE
OF THEM WILL SUCCUMB
TO AN ILLNESS
WORSE THAN ANY
VIRUS CAN PRODUCE.
A MOST INOPERATIVE, DEADLY,
LIFE-SHATTERING AFFLICTION
KNOWN AS "THE FEVER."
[cheering]
NUMBER TEN.
FRANKLIN, THERE IS SUCH
A FLAVOR TO THIS PLACE.
FLAVOR. THIS IS
THE KIND OF FLAVOR
I CAN DO WITHOUT, FLORA.
YOU KNOW PERFECTLY WELL
HOW I FEEL ABOUT GAMBLING.
OH, THIS IS
DIFFERENT, THOUGH.
IT IS NEITHER
DIFFERENT NOR MORAL.
GAMBLING IS GAMBLING.
HOWEVER, THIS IS YOUR
VACATION, FLORA.
YOU WON IT.
BUT IN ALL GOOD CONSCIENCE,
I MUST REPEAT TO YOU WHAT
I'VE BEEN SAYING ALL ALONG,
IT'S A MISERABLE,
TERRI BLE, WASTE OF TIME.
BUT, OF COURSE,
IT'S WHAT YOU WANTED.
OH, FRANKLIN, TRY
TO ENJOY IT, WON'T YOU?
[bells ringing]
I WON! I WON
THE JACKPOT!
I WON!
I WON. LOOK, I WON.
I WON, I WON, I WON.
LOOK, I WON. I WON.
ISN'T THAT MARVELOUS?
JUST WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
WELL, IT'S-IT'S ONLY
A NICKEL MACHINE.
ONLY A NICKLE MACHINE?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST TAKE
HANDFULS OF NICKLES
AND THROW THEM OUT
INTO THE STREET?
ALL RIGHT. WE GO
TO LAS VEGAS.
WE WASTE THREE DAYS
AND TWO NIGHTS.
WE DO IT BECAUSE THAT
IS YOUR SILLY IDEA OF
ENJOYING YOURSELF,
AND BECAUSE IT'S NOT
COSTING US ANYTHING.
BUT NOW YOU'RE SPENDING
MONEY. AND NOT EVEN
SPENDING IT, FLORA.
YOU'RE-YOU'RE J UST
THROWING IT AWAY!
WELL, THIS IS WHERE
I PUT MY FOOT DOWN.
IT'S QU ITE OBVIOUS TO ME
THAT YOU ARE NOT
MATURE ENOUGH--
PLEASE. FRANKLIN, PLEASE,
DON'T MAKE A SCENE.
I WON'T PLAY.
I PROMISE YOU.
FRANKLIN?
THE NICKEL'S
ALREADY IN.
ALL RIGHT.
THROW IT AWAY.
[coins clattering]
I'M NOT VERY
LUCKY, AM I?
I'M GOING BACK
TO THE ROOM, FLORA.
HERE YOU ARE, OLD BOY.
HERE, WAIT A MINUTE.
PLEASE!
WAIT, YOU TRY IT.
I'M ONE HOUR AND
30 MINUTES
ON THIS MISERABLE,
CRUMMY, MONEY-G RABBING--
PLEASE.
HOLD IT. HERE.
YOU PLAY. IT'S YOURS.
GO AHEAD, PLAY IT.
NO, REALLY,
I'M NOT INTERESTED.
I'M IN A HURRY.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
PUT IT IN THERE, SEE?
AND PULL THE THING.
ALL RIGHT, SWEETI E,
I'M COMING. THAT'S THE
LITTLE WOMAN, YOU NOW.
LOTS, LOTS OF LUCK,
AND I'LL SEE YOU
LATER, HUH?
I'M COMING, HONEY.
(MAN)
PAY THE LADY
RIGHT HERE.
PAY THE LADY RIGHT HERE.
[coins clattering]
OH, FRANKLIN,
YOU ARE LUCKY!
IT WASN'T EVEN
MY DOLLAR. THAT--
THAT MAN GAVE IT TO ME.
HE MADE ME PUT IT
IN THE MACHINE.
WELL, NOW YOU'LL
SEE THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A NORMAL,
MATURE THOUGHTFUL MAN
AND THESE-THESE WILD
I DIOTS AROUND HERE.
WE'LL-WE'LL PUT THIS IN OU R
ROOM AND WE'LL TAKE IT
HOME WITH US.
OF COURSE, DEAR.
YES, BUT NOT THESE
BABOONS AROUND HERE.
THEY'D THROW IT AWAY.
THEY'D COMPULSIVELY
PUT IT BACK IN
THE MACHINE.
BUT NOT THE GIBBS.
THE GIBBS KNOW THE
VALU E OF MONEY.
WELL, COME, MY DEAR.
I-I WANT TO SHAVE
BEFORE DIN N ER.
[metallic voice]
FRANKLIN.
DID YOU SAY SOMETHING?
WHAT?
DID YOU CALL MY NAME?
WHY, NO, DEAR.
I THOUGHT I HEARD--
[metallic voice]
FRANKLIN.
FRANKLIN, IS
SOMETHING THE MATTER?
NO, NO.
NOTHING IS THE MATTER.
NOTHING, EXCEPT
THAT-THAT--
THIS IS NOT
THE KIND OF MONEY
I LIKE TO KEEP, FLORA.
THIS IS-IS TAINTED.
THIS IS HIGHLY IMMORAL.
NO GOOD CAN COME
FROM MONEY WON LIKE THIS.
I'M-I'M GOING
BACK IN THERE
AND FEED IT BACK INTO
THE MACHINE, FLORA,
AND GET RID OF IT.
OH, FRANKLIN,
DO YOUREALLY
THINK THAT--
OF COURSE.
IF THERE'S ONE THING I
KNOW, FLORA, IT'S MORALITY.
AND I WILL NOT HAVE
THIS TAINTED MONEY
SMELLING UP OUR POCKETS.
I'M GOING BACK IN THERE
AND I'M-I'M JUST GOING
TO GET RID OF IT.
SO, YOU GO BACK
TO SLEEP, FLORA.
FRANKLIN, IT'S
TERRIBLY LATE.
I KNOW IT'S
LATE, FLORA!
LOOK, YOU STAY
RIGHT HERE, FLORA.
AND DON'T LET ANYONE
ELSE USE THIS MACHINE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
FRANKLIN, THAT'S THE
THIRD TIME YOU'VE
CASHED A CHECK.
I KNOW THAT.
WELL, YOU'VE SPENT
A GREAT DEAL OF MONEY.
I KNOW THAT, TOO.
DON'T YOU THINK YOU
OUGHT TO STOP NOW?
HOW CAN I STOP?
I'VE LOST A GREAT
DEAL OF MONEY.
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF.
I'VE GOT TO WIN IT BACK.
BUT WHAT IF YOU DON'T
WIN IT BACK, FRANKLIN?
YOU'VE BEEN STANDING
HERE NEARLY THREE HOURS.
YES, I KNOW THAT, TOO.
FRANKLIN? DEAR.
YOU KNOW HOW AWFU L YOU FEEL
IN THE MORNING AFTER YOU'VE
BEEN UP TOO LATE AT NIGHT.
FLORA, WILL YOU KINDLY
SHUT YOUR MOUTH?
I HATE A SHREW, FLORA!
I HATE A WOMAN WHO STANDS
IN BACK OF YOU
AND SEES TO IT THAT
YOU HAVE MISERABLE LUCK!
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE DOING
TO ME NOW. YOU'RE GIVING
ME MISERABLE LUCK!
NOW PLEASE GO AWAY
AND LEAVE ME ALONE!
PLEASE, PLEASE,
PEOPLE ARE LISTENING.
THE DEVIL WITH PEOPLE!
I'M NOT CONCERN ED
WITH PEOPLE.
I'M--I'M CONCERN ED
WITH THIS-THIS MACHINE.
IT'S IN HUMAN THE WAY
IT LETS YOU WIN A LITTLE
AND THEN, AND THEN
TAKES IT ALL BACK.
IT TEASES YOU.
IT-IT HOLDS OUT PROMISES
AN D-AND WHEEDLES YOU.
IT SUCKS YOU
IN AND THEN--
FRANKLIN.
FLORA, GO AWAY!
FIVE HOURS.
THAT'S HOW LONG
HE'S BEEN THERE.
WHEN THEY GET HOOKED,
THEY REALLY GET HOOKED,
DON'T THEY?
YEAH.
SOMEBODY
GET ME
A DRINK OF WATER, PLEASE.
FRANKLIN.
HM?
OH. OH, FLORA,
WOULD YOU,
WOULD YOU GET ME
A DRINK OF WATER?
I--I'VE ALMOST
GOT HER LICKED NOW.
YOU SEE,
"SPECIAL JACKPOT,
$10,000."
YOU SEE? $10,000.
SHE'S BOUND TO-TO
TURN UP IN A LITTLE WHILE.
YOU-YOU JUST HAVE TO STICK
WITH HER LONG ENOUGH.
THAT'S ALL.
FRANKLIN.
HUH?
WHAT, UH,
WHAT TIME IS IT, FLORA?
IT'S 8 :00 IN THE
MORNING, FRANKLIN.
I-I SWEAR TO YOU, FLORA,
THIS MACHINE MOCKS ME.
IT TEASES,
BECKONS, MOCKS ME.
PUT IN FIVE,
GET BACK FOU R.
PUT IN SIX,
GET BACK FIVE.
BUT IT'S GOT TO PAY
OFF, SOONER OR LATER.
IT'S JUST GOT TO,
I TELL YOU.
GIVE ME BACK
MY DOLLAR.
THAT'S MY LAST DOLLAR!
YOU MISERABLE, DIRTY--
GIVE ME BACK
MY DOLLAR!
FRANKLIN!
GIVE ME BACK MY DOLLAR!
WE NEED A DOCTOR.
IT TOOK MY DOLLAR!
IT OWES ME A DOLLAR!
THAT, THAT MONSTER!
I WANT MY DOLLAR!
(Flora)
DARLING?
CAN'T YOU SLEEP?
THAT MACHINE.
FRANKLIN.
THAT MACHINE, FLORA.
IT WAS READY
TO PAY OFF.
AND IT DELIBERATELY
BROKE DOWN SO IT
WOULDN'T HAVE TO.
IT--IT'S NOT EVEN
A MACHINE, FLORA.
IT'S AN ENTITY.
IT'S A THING WITH A MIND
AND A WILL OF ITS OWN.
IT DELIBERATELY
BROKE DOWN.
BROKE DOWN!
THAT--THAT THING!
THAT MONSTER!
THAT THIEF!
IT--
IT TOOK MY LAST
SILVER DOLLAR, FLORA.
IT STOLE MY LAST
SILVER DOLLAR
AND BROKE DOWN!
[metallic voice]
FRANKLIN!
WHAT'S THE MATTER, DEAR?
FRANKLIN.
COME BACK TO BED, FRANK--
FRANKLIN!
FRANKLIN, WHAT
IS THE MATTER?
FRANKLIN.
FRANKLIN, WHAT IS IT?
IT'S-IT'S CHASING ME.
IT'S FOLLOWING ME.
IT'S TRYING
TO GET ME, FLORA!
WHAT IS? WHAT?
THERE'S NOTHING THERE!
FRANKLIN!
FRANKLIN, THERE'S
NOTHING HERE, DEAR.
BELIEVE ME, THERE'S
NOTHING HERE.
FRANKLIN.
FRANKLIN, FRANKLIN,
FRANKLIN. FRANKLIN!
FRANKLIN! FRANKLIN!
FRANKLIN!
[machine continues
calling Franklin's name]
[screaming]
[shouts]
NO!
[sobbing]
HIS WIFE SAID
HE HADN'T SLEPT
FOR 24 HOURS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE SEEN A LOT OF THEM
GET HOOKED BEFORE, BUT
N EVER LIKE HIM.
THERE'S A STRETCH ER
COMING. IT'LL BE HERE
IN A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY,
LET'S GET BACK TO BED.
THE SHOW'S OVER.
LET'S GO.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
[bell rings]
[coin clacking]
(narrator)
MR. FRANKLIN GIBBS,
VISITOR TO LAS VEGAS,
WHO LOST HIS
MONEY, HIS REASON,
AND FINALLY, HIS LIFE
TO AN INANIMATE
METAL MACHINE
VARIOUSLY DESCRIBED
AS A ONE-ARMED BANDIT,
A SLOT MACHINE.
OR IN MR. FRANKLIN
GIBBS' WORDS
"A MONSTER WITH
A WILL ALL ITS OWN."
FOR OUR PURPOSES
WE'LL STICK WITH
THE LATTER DEFINITION
BECAUSE WE'RE IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
(male presenter)
ROD SERLING,
THE CREATOR
OF TWILIGHT ZONE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT NEXT
WEEK'S STORY AFTER THIS WORD
FROM OUR ALTERNATE SPONSOR.
AND NOW, MR. SERLING.
THIS IS THE MODEL
OF A NIEU PORT,
FIGHTER AIRCRAFT
VINTAGE WORLD WAR I.
NEXT WEEK IT'S FLOWN
ON A PATROL OVER
FRANCE IN 1917.
AND ITS PILOT DISCOVERS
THAT TIME HAS PASSED
HIM BY.
KENNETH HAIGH STARS NEXT
WEEK IN RICHARD MATHESON'S
EXCITING STORY
OF THE LAST FLIGHT
ON THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
WE HOPE YOU'LL JOIN US.
THANK YOU AND GOOD NIGHT.
[eerie music]
KIMBERLY-CLARK INVITES YOU
TO WATCH STEVE MCQUEEN
IN WANTED DEAD OF ALIVE.
SATURDAY NIGHTS OVER MOST
OF THE SAME STATIONS.