Yeah, so we out on Carlton.
This old white motherfucker
and his wife roll up.
He's like, "Young man, you know
where the Poe House is?"
I'm like, "Unc, you kidding?
Look around, take your pick."
So, the old man, he's like...
"The Poe House.
The Edward Allan Poe House."
Shit, you back already?
First of the month, yo.
I'm like,
"I don't know no Edward Allan Poe."
The man look at me all sad and shit,
like I let him down.
- I know you know you ain't coming in here.
- What?
Shorty, I don't know you.
You know Miss Elaine
in the back room, right?
This her brother, Earl, from the V.A.
Hospital. He's supposed to stay with her.
Can you help me inside? I'm Chantal.
So, what's good?
Thank you, young man.
Oh, shit.
Now, now, now.
Hey, yo, Omar.
Yo, all due respect, but this right here...
it's a Barksdale joint, man.
Do tell.
You think this boy woke up
yesterday morning...
sat on the edge of his bed and said,
"Today's my day to die"?
You don't think this can happen to you?
Doc, hold that up.
Look at what that bullet did to his heart.
That's his heart.
- What was that, Scared Straight?
- More like bored stiff.
What's the deal with this?
I go down to MCI Jessup, hoping
to pull up a fellow with some years on him.
See if he's ready to share his feelings.
Turns out "Barksdale, D'Angelo"
got himself rung up as a suicide.
- D.O.D. Of 7l21l03.
- Who worked it?
State Police.
You want me to pull the postmortem
on this?
Yeah, he's kind of a made guy down there.
I just want to make sure
nobody did the suicide to him.
It ain't nothing but dust and bricks
over there now.
Shit, all the battling we did
to take them Towers, man.
You're trying to tell me
we back on the street with the rest of them?
Any way beatin'.
Now that the Towers is gone,
everybody know how it got to go down.
I say we send our people over there early.
Corner chiefs, like, "Yo, we here now...
"you know what I mean,
but we bringing something to the table."
Lay it out like it's their lucky day.
No flexing, no threats.
Just be like, "This a good thing."
Yeah, but you know,
we gonna need good corners...
that's what we're gonna need.
Close to downtown.
Get the workaday trade.
- Talking about, like, Fremont.
- Fayette.
Yeah, make us like $40,000,
$50,000 a day, easy.
Yeah, I'm on it.
And, you know,
everybody watching us on this, man.
They wanna see if we're gonna fuck this up
now that the Towers are down.
You know what I'm saying?
They measuring us up.
They wanna see
if we're gonna be weak or real.
If a fool step to us, man,
we gonna do what we got to do.
But it's them bodies that got you in here.
If we can do this without the bodies,
we should.
You know what I mean?
Especially now we light on muscle.
Speaking of muscle, man,
you hear from that man I sent you?
Yeah, Cutty from the cut.
Yeah, he rang, we took care of him.
Good, good.
- How you fixed for the hearing?
- It's all good, man.
Shit.
Levy got everything straightened up
tight for me, man.
I'll be home before it get cold.
Terrace came down.
So?
So, we're coming in.
To my corners? I don't think so.
Hey, hold on now.
This is gonna be good for you, too.
Yeah? Now, how you figure that?
Yo, what you paying now, $37,000, $38,000?
Yo, we can go $31,000, $32,000 shots, man.
The shit's so John Blaze,
you can step on it seven, eight times...
and still take the cake.
Spider bags. Got those spider bags.
Damn.
Yo, you all seen Marlo?
Y'all ain't seen him?
You all know him?
Marlo?
Yeah, yeah, he was here.
Now he ain't.
Get those spider bags!
Spider bags!
Jesus, Tommy. I'd like to shit.
When I looked up,
saw you on the news, giving it to Erv.
- You fucker, you're up to something.
- I'm up to nothing, I'm telling you.
I can help him, he can help me.
A little itch here, a little scratch there.
This is a win-win for you, ain't it?
He won't play? You beat the shit out of him
because crime is up.
Press loves it and you score.
Flip side is that if he caves...
you get yourself a snitch
in the Mayor's inner circle.
So, what's my role in your little drama?
I thought you might broker a meeting.
You know...
help your fearless leader see the light
about his new friend on the Council.
And I should tell him, what?
Make nice
or invest heavily in petroleum jelly?
Hey, his ass, his choice.
- You didn't talk to him?
- I couldn't find the motherfucker.
Man, we just walk up, we gonna bump.
There. Middle of the block, right there.
Yo, where that whistle at?
Hold on.
Wait for Marlo.
Yo, Cheese. Where you been at, man?
Nigger, that ain't nothing but bait.
Soap your bitch.
Who's my dawg? You my dawg?
Who's my dawg? Who's my baby?
- You make Daddy some money, all right?
- Yeah.
25 large on Dawg!
Cheese!
Yeah.
Anybody I want?
Anybody.
I want more than one.
I want the Olsen twins.
You got them.
Slaves.
All they live for is to get you off.
But, so now, who you gonna do for them?
One guy, one act, one time.
Right. And the minute I name a guy,
you're gonna be like...
"I knew you were a cocksucker
from the first time I laid eyes on you.
"Steve McQueen, huh? That's your fantasy?
"You fucking closet-case motherfucker."
- Steve McQueen?
- Fuck you. It's a set-up.
Both Olsen twins.
Ashley.
- Kate.
- Mary-Kate.
And, yeah, I admire their body of work.
They're yours.
All you got to do is name a guy.
- I'm not catching, I'm pitching.
- No problem.
Corner men out of the pit.
Release your dogs.
Yeah! I got that!
Break your dogs!
Bait.
Oh, shit, there it is.
Can't it just be like
this unbearable-looking woman?
You know, like that old tune from
The Golden Girls?
The short one with the Coke-bottle glasses.
A guy.
- Hey, yo.
- Huh?
Let me ask you a question.
Where do you guys get those hats
with the bills over the ears like that?
I go into all the city stores
and the only ones I can find...
are the ones with the bills in the front.
No, it's the same.
Just turn it sideways on your head.
Thanks. Thank you.
That's a knucklehead from the low-rises,
right there.
The Terrace is spreading out.
Got to go somewheres, I guess.
Don't think you all needed to do that.
He turned cur on me, man.
No.
I think you got played.
So, I'm guessing from the Terrace...
them being all cute about the property line.
I just wanted to wait and see
what you wanted us to do about it.
So, what you want us to do?
Get back to work.
All right.
Your boy really jammed me, that little prick.
It was all over the news.
You did not look
particularly commissioner-like.
The Mayor told me the same thing.
You can't have that shit every week.
Not if you want His Honor to give you
the job permanent.
Tommy's a good kid, usually.
An ass pain when he wants something.
- But mostly good people.
- I don't give a shit what he is.
Well, you can't have him
pounding on you, Erv.
Throw him a bone.
He'll take care of you.
All right.
But I draw the line
at going behind the Mayor for this guy.
You can't sit where I'm sitting
and backdoor the fucking Mayor.
Sorry I'm late, guys.
The kid had a Little League game.
It started late.
Well, I'll leave you boys to it.
And what I have brought together,
let no man tear asunder.
- He win?
- Who?
Your kid, his team.
Shit, who keeps score?
I mean, yes. It's a little hectic, but
everybody stepping off at the right time.
These corner boys we dealing with...
I don't think they even listen
to their own people.
Yeah, I'm gonna talk to peoples.
- Where you at?
- Marlo?
I can't find him.
And you told us not to start nothing.
So I set up in the middle of the block.
You know, even that got hard stares.
I don't...
It ain't gonna hold, I don't think.
Now, this Marlo...
how hard you looking for him?
Like, why ain't you out there
looking for this motherfucker right now?
'Cause you called this meeting here.
Shut the door.
- What's your good news, man?
- Omar right inside the stash.
Couple ounces of raw, already vialed, 600.
Cocksuckers even took my watch.
Second stash this month they done got to.
I mean, he called you by name, String.
I mean, all due respect...
but dude, like, unless you step to him,
it's gonna be like this.
All right, man.
Double the muscle on every stash we got.
And if the man coming,
make ready for the man.
It's not personal.
I swear to God,
it is never personal with me.
Truth is, I've been a councilman
for almost three years now.
And that's a long fucking time
to be ignored.
And this being Baltimore...
a white boy doesn't stand much chance
running citywide.
Maybe the legislature,
if the right seat opens up.
But until then,
I'm stuck in a job with no power...
except getting potholes filled.
All due respect, Councilman...
you're fucking with me because,
what, you're bored?
A little, yeah.
And what the fuck?
I mean, when it comes to the crime thing...
this city can use
all the fucking help it can get.
- Lf you're looking for dirt, there isn't any.
- There's always fucking dirt.
But right now, I'm just looking to know
how we can do better.
And you give me that much...
and I can try and get you
what you need privately.
No hearings, no press, no grandstanding.
And if I don't play ball...
you're gonna have my ass every time
I'm in front of your committee, right?
- One thing comes to mind.
- Shoot.
I can't get my marked units back
from Dickman Street to save my life.
Cars that are shopped for service
don't come back for weeks.
You tell the Mayor?
- Not that you heard it from me.
- Of course not.
- How much these?
- $10,000 a set.
A nigga show that on a ride,
he hanging a sign on himself.
"Lock my ass up."
No shit.
So how you gonna play it?
If they from the Terrace, that's Avon.
- I know.
- And Avon, he coming home, too.
Well, if you inclined to work something out,
that's one thing.
If not, Avon can seriously handle up.
I know.
So if you want to hold on to what's yours,
you best be ready.
You remember that Barksdale kid?
The one who took all the weight?
Tied his neck to a doorknob
in the prison library and sat his ass down.
I don't know.
Men of color usually don't do themselves.
I mean, take me, for instance.
Yeah, I mean,
you got all the reason in the world.
And yet here I am, still standing.
Give or take.
- You looked at the scene photos?
- No, there ain't none.
State Police dogged it.
My turn, Bunk.
Come on. Go with number three.
You gonna play my song, darling?
- You play the right song...
- Hey, Bunk.
...I can make you hit the high notes, baby.
- Hey, look, I saw her first, Jimmy.
- Come on, man.
Come on, baby.
I got a place right here in Camden.
Come on, be a gentleman, come on.
- I'm being a gentleman, man.
- I'm really not interested, okay?
- Come on, let's go.
- It's all pink, baby.
I'm really sorry, he's had
a bit too much to drink, you know?
It's okay. Thank you. Thanks.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- You get yourself home?
Knock it out.
- No, the baddest nigga of all time?
- Who?
This nigga from New York,
from the olden days, Bumpy something.
- Bumpy?
- Yo.
He'd do shit like run up
to a police station by hisself.
- No.
- You know what I'm saying, shit like that.
Cops be like hiding, like,
"Yo, Bumpy, we sorry, man, we sorry."
"Please go away. Please, please."
Woof.
And obtain gainful employment and refrain
from associating with known criminals...
and keep this office informed
of your residence...
and any change in that residence.
So I gather you're not working
at this particular time.
They still doing morning shape-ups
down at the market?
I don't know and I don't care.
Just get a job, any job.
- "Woof"?
- "Woof," like a dog.
- Oh shit, it was like...
- It was Cheese's boy, Tri.
So you gonna hit back or what?
- You got a better shot of the ligature?
- Yeah. Inside.
What'd he do, hang himself twice?
He could have been leaning
straight forward until he blacked out...
then slid down,
which would give you the vertical.
Or how about I come up at him
from behind and...
And then set him down,
make it look like, "Goodbye cruel world."
- What do the scene shots show?
- There were none taken.
The troopers really fucked the pooch
on this one.
All I have is some half-assed report.
Reads like the investigator
went off his Ritalin.
- What's a "large ecchy"...
- Large ecchymotic area, mid-back.
Bruising.
What, mid-back as in...
Or he banged himself a few days earlier
in the shower. But yeah, maybe.
Nothing like a definite maybe.
Tri finally got that M. Done it on foot, too.
Caroline?
Nigger lying in chalk, but my boy, Tri,
got that dapple all up his sleeve.
Looks like polka dots. But that's just
something you gotta know from experience.
You know what I'm saying?
I even had to school him on the whistle,
still walking around with it.
"Yo, Tri, stash that shit at Neesey's.
What's wrong with you?"
You know them niggers
is gonna get mad busy over this.
- So we getting busy, too.
- So what time you coming over?
Damn, bitch, ain't you even listening?
You still there?
Shakedown!
Time-out.
- Do that again.
- Do what again?
Do that thing with your hand.
Do it in my face.
What the fuck you talking...
Whoa, man.
Got a lot of room in here!
The law think they can do
what the fuck they want.
Yo, I ain't do nothing.
Fuck the police!
- No, man, we was just hanging.
- Just slinging.
How'd you work it out
with the corner crews...
all you guys from the Terrace
coming in like this?
- I don't know what you talking about.
- Well, you best watch your ass.
'Cause the slingers out here,
they're like the crack babies' babies.
Man, every year everybody's like...
"Yeah, these kids out here,
they're a new breed.
"I ain't never seen nothing like this before.
This the end of the world now."
Look around you, fuckhead. This seem like
the dawn of a new day to you?
Can I go now?
Or you want to slap me up some more first?
Get the fuck out of here.
How about a hand job?
My man, you don't even get
Weezy Jefferson for a hand job.
Come on.
- Dozerman.
- Wanna call it a day?
They came back on us this time.
Daz and them. They got Peanut.
- Oh, shit, is Peanut dead?
- No, he's okay.
His brains are all over the sidewalk.
But he's okay.
What the hell do you think?
Shit, I got to call Tony. I'll get back at you.
All right.
- Well, that's two we heard about.
- What the hell's going on?
Drug war maybe?
- What's up?
- Nothing good, man.
I ain't sleep since I capped his ass.
Close my eyes, see him laying there
all bloody and shit.
Cheese, man, you did what you had to do.
What I thought I had to do.
That's Cheese?
He was my dawg, yo.
Had much love for me, even then.
I ain't never gonna find another dog
like that.
- Well, they paying for it now.
- Mos def.
For months, these assholes
show perfect phone discipline.
Now, they're talking up murders?
Cheese is only a level below
Proposition Joe.
All of a sudden, this case has legs.
- Homicide.
- This is Freamon, Major Case.
- Who's the O.I.C. Tonight?
- Hold on for Norris.
Yo, T. T man.
I'm shot! I'm shot!
Oh, shit. Shit!
They coming back!
Motherfucker!
Who this?
Damn.
Detective Norris.
Ed, this is Lester.
I hear you're catching bodies
on the east side.
You hear it?
Like what, "probable cause" hear it?
Like, "I got something concrete" hear it?
Or just, "gas up my head" hear it?
Like, "I got all the fucking time in the world
to jaw with you" hear it?
- How many bodies you got, Eddie?
- "How many you got, Eddie?"
Asshole.
- You want me to go up to Homicide?
- No, I got it, I got it.
You're early man on tomorrow.
So go home. See your kid.
I'm telling you,
this kid Berman's a fucking wizard.
I mean, check it out, right?
Six reported auto thefts,
two of which state:
"Not impossible car was borrowed."
Making four auto thefts,
with two unfounded.
And the prizewinner?
Four armed robberies...
two of which complainants state,
"Too dark to I.D. Weapon.
"Not impossible knife wasn't a comb."
- He might have groomed them to death.
- Yeah.
Wine into water.
There he is.
- Abbadabba Berman.
- The Dr. Atkins of crime.
Just doing what I'm told.
- God, what a beautiful film.
- I couldn't understand a word.
Honey, you gotta read the subtitles.
Oh, shit.
Does y'all go to the movies?
And you must be the lovely Mrs. Herc.
How'd you like your movie?
Okay.
Herc and Carver here,
they try to snatch us up every day...
like, "Where the shit? Who got the shit?"
But they never get nothing.
So y'all go to the movies.
Damn.
All right, then. See you tomorrow.
Everything okay?
On two.
Pick up, pick up.
- Ed, you got to help me.
- I can't, not now.
And a bucket full of worms.
Oh, my God!
So.
Everything good?
How's that fontanette?
Fontanelle.
Is he closing up?
He won't close for a while.
Good.
- Good?
- I can't stand it anymore!
Come on, sweetheart,
just a few more seconds.
Well, I'm just saying.
I ain't sleep since I capped his ass.
Close my eyes, see him laying there
all bloody and shit.
- Cheese.
- Cheese on a platter.
He never talks like that.
Now, why would...
Because all good things come
to those who wait.
- Does McNulty know?
- I'll raise his ass.
We'll keep our ears to the wire,
keep gathering string, no problem.
But if bodies keep falling
in the Eastern District...
we might have to give up this wiretap.
Now you coming around?
Been more than a damn year.
Looks just like his dad, huh?
Let me ask you.
When you heard D was a suicide,
what'd you think?
Hey, little fella. Come here.
Yeah.
Here's the thing, we got a tip.
And the autopsy report, it backs us up.
Can you put him down, please?
Sure.
You know, I'm sorry about your loss.
He seemed like a pretty decent guy,
all things considered.
So when I found out about this,
I felt like I owed him.
The last thing I wanted to do was upset you
if there was no point to it.
So...
If there's anything I can help with
or any questions you need answered...
or whatever.
Major, how many people
are under your command?
278, sir.
278.
And how many felony arrests
did they make last month?
Don't bother.
You made sixteen.
Sixteen in a month.
Same time period.
How many handguns you pick up?
All shifts, all sectors.
Once again, don't bother.
The answer is "none."
None.
You had four bodies last night
in how many hours?
- Shut the fucking book, how many hours?
- Seven.
Try five.
Tell me about this kid.
- I believe his name is James...
- James Toney.
When's the last time he was arrested?
With who?
Where's he sling?
How about this guy?
Or him? Or him?
You know what? You got four bodies,
all within two blocks of each other...
and you can't even start to connect
the fucking dots.
You got eight hours to get a grip
on this mess or you're done. You hear me?
Done.
Marlo?
You know I'm with Avon, right?
Stringer Bell?
Can we talk?
I need you to walk back up there
and pack up your people.
I'm being a gentleman about it
for the moment.
You offer up what you have on this,
you start the clock running on yourselves.
The wiretap has to surface in court.
- No way around it.
- She's right.
We finally got something
worth listening to...
and you're talking about
giving up the wire?
Makes no sense.
There's a war going on.
We might have four more bodies tonight.
This is Baltimore, we might have six.
I watched Marvin Taylor from the Eastern
get his asshole ripped today...
because he has no fucking clue.
I don't believe this.
We got top lieutenants
talking about murders...
and we can't figure out
just to shut up and take notes?
We got bodies on the ground, Jimmy.
That's got to matter for something.
No, if we're at Cheese
then we're close to Prop Joe...
and if we're close to Joe,
then we're close to Stringer.
That has to matter.
Look, I was right there with you
when we left Stringer on the street.
And it grinds me, too.
But the fact is we didn't create this unit
just to lock up dope dealers.
There's a narcotics unit downtown for that.
We're about the violence.
Have been from the jump.
Barksdale was violent.
But right now, Stringer's quiet
and over on the East side, we got bodies.
We got enough from the tap...
to take a real good shot at Cheese.
Put a murder case or two together...
you may be able to roll someone up
at Proposition Joe or Stringer.
As far as bodies go, four's a big number.
Okay, then. As of now,
we use the phones to work these murders.
- Yo, we bracing up, son.
- Huh?
Gather yourself, nigga.
We got a bead on Daz.
Be at Neesey's crib in a hour.
Daz be with Neesey?
I thought that was your girl.
Neesey, huh? Got it.
We just hooking up there,
and going to the battle.
Bring your whistle, in a hour. One.
Mount up.
Caroline, call Q.R.T. With that 20
and stay on the wire.
- We're on channel two.
- All right.
Yo, Tri, what size fries you want?
What?
Go!
- Police! Search Warrant!
- Freeze!
Hands up!
Put your hands up!
Get down on the ground!
- Freeze!
- Go! Come on, let's go!
Put your hands up! Put your hands up!
Hands on your head!
Okay, Mary Tyler Moore, buck-naked.
Open the door, here I come...
drop my attaché case down,
bend her over...
give it to her on the ottoman,
and she's like:
"Oh, Rob. Oh, Rob."
- Who's Rob?
- It's from the show.
Done.
Mary Kate and Ashley. I don't want to say.
Just accept whatever pictures
are on my mind right now.
Anybody else?
Yeah, Dozerman's girl, what's her name?
She's baking a cake, naked.
White flour splotches
all over her fine brown skin.
I come in, in a chef's hat, nothing else on...
Johnson out to here and say:
"That's no way to stir a batter.
Here, let me try to get..."
- Bobby! Hey!
- Hey, Doze.
- What's up?
- Done, now the guy.
This is a hard one
for anybody to understand.
I mean, it's got nothing to do with sex.
It's about sympathy.
- It's about giving a guy a break.
- Yeah, okay, okay.
Gus Triandos.
Who's Gus Triandos?
A catcher with the Orioles back in the day.
Me and my brother had his card.
Sorry-looking motherfucker, man.
I mean, he looked like this little kid
who got left at a bus station by his parents.
You know why?
Because he had to catch
Hoyt Wilhelm's knuckleball.
Five fucking years.
The worst gig in baseball.
It was like trying to catch
a greased pig with wings.
I mean, he even told a reporter once,
"Wilhelm nearly ruined me."
Gus Triandos. Big slow guy.
- Good choice.
- Go ahead, say it.
- I know you want to say it.
- Say what? There's nothing to say.
- Nothing?
- You put a lot of thought into it.
- It's cool.
- Okay.
Okay. Tonight, three things.
Number one.
Keep your incident numbers sequential
or it's gonna be a stone mess tomorrow.
Number two.
We'll be photographing
evidence at the scene.
That means don't bag anything
until you get the shot off.
And number three,
don't embarrass yourselves.
Make sure your camera's loaded with film.
Okay, mount up.
So Cheese, who's your dawg?
You my dawg.
I just want to know who's your dawg.
Dawg.
What's this, some psychology?
Yeah, okay. Yo, please stop, stop.
I'll tell you everything I know.
Come on, Cheese.
Who's your dawg?
Hell, no.
Hell, you ain't laying no bodies
on me, man.
Lawyer time.
"He was my dawg, man."
"I ain't sleep since I capped his ass.
"Looking up at me all bloody and shit.
"He had much love for me...
"even then.
I ain't never gonna find another."
Man, you all some
cold-ass motherfuckers, man.
We got you on tape.
So what happened, Cheese?
I thought he punked me, all right?
So I did what I had to do.
Which was?
Lit him up.
Well, he's talking anyway.
Well, what's done is done.
But, maybe we can help you on this.
How? You gonna bring him back?
No, on the consequences.
Help us help you.
- What?
- Maybe we can trade up.
Trade up for what, man? For this?
- What the fuck...
- Proposition Joe.
You give us Prop Joe and maybe we look
at this whole thing with Dawg differently.
Now, why would I be talking
about Prop Joe behind...
You know what, man?
I don't even know no Prop Joe.
Okay. Dawg?
Which one of these is he?
Where's that body?
Where I left it, most likely.
- Warehouse on the East Side.
- And he still there?
Far as I know.
Unless the SPCA come around.
What?
Looks like they broke him.
I got to say,
you really showed me something on this.
What can I possibly add to that?
Except, I owe you one, Cedric.
You ever have one of those
"have your cake and eat it, too" days?
I believe this could be my first.
Tell me something good.
We're charging him.
Improper disposal of an animal.
Discharging a firearm in city limits.
Animal cruelty,
if you want to run wild with it.
Go ahead, call me a cocksucker.
- You know you wanna.
- Excuse me?
You know, I actually looked up
the stats on Gus Triandos.
Power hitter, right?
Fuck the both of you.
Later, dawg.
Kiss my ass.
- Goodnight, Bunk.
- Goodnight.
Funny day.
I'm the new departmental pet
for shutting down a drug war.
But I blew my wire for a dead terrier.
You remember how you said...
you hoped today would be your first
"have your cake and eat it, too" day?
What about it?
Okay, gents.
You see the brake lights pump twice,
you know we got a clean hand-to-hand.
So I get in this morning
and I'm looking at three phone messages...
from Buddy Ferraro over at DPW.
All assuring me that I'll have 20 radio cars
back in service...
at the end of the week.
Buddy and my old man go way back.
Made their First Communion together
at St. Leo's.
So, what else do you need?
And you didn't go to the Mayor with it?
Did you get your cars?
Did anyone get fucked over it?
Or did your job just get a little easier?
I got 70 cops retiring at the end of the year
that I know of...
and no money for academy class.
Well, the Mayor fucked you, 'cause I know
that money was in the budget.
The Mayor delayed it till next summer.
I mean less troops, less salary,
less bennies.
I mean, even a six-month delay
saves the city $2, $3 million.
Let me talk to some people.
Yeah?
- Major Colvin?
- Yeah.
This is the Com Center.
I'm sorry to inform you of this, sir, but
we have an officer down in your district.
Which hospital?
I just got the lease, so...
Fucking solo cars.
I should have teamed him. I fucked up.
Dead-ass motherfucker's dead.
If we catch up to him,
he don't come in alive.
Right?
Nicked jugular, shattered jaw.
He'll live.
Give me one of those.
I just got back from Shock Trauma.
You guys saved his ass
getting him down as fast as you did.
So who do we got for a suspect?
Number one male, white T-shirt,
baggy jeans, tennis shoes.
In the wind,
but we're locking it down out there.
So what's this I hear about the gun?
Doze tried to return fire,
he dropped his piece.
Some fuck picks it up and books.
I mean, I can't believe this shit.
- I'll take it.
- No.
No, no, no.
It'll be nicer when I fix the place up.
Cedric, I don't care.
No, tell him I'm cooked.
I just got done at the hospital, I'm all in.
Well, he was asking if you could
maybe talk to the reporters.
He doesn't want me
talking to reporters right now.
- All right.
- That would truly be unwise.
- All right, all right, I'll tell him.
- All right.
Bunny, you look hellacious.
You got any coffee going in there?
You know what I was thinking?
That tonight's a good night.
Why?
Because my shot cop didn't die.
And it hit me.
This is what makes
a good night on my watch.
Absence of a negative.
It was a good night.
Here's the thing.
Six months from now, I'm gone.
I put in my 30 and the only thing
that'll be left of me on that job...
is an 8"-by-11" framed picture
in the Western hallway.
But you know what?
The shit out there.
The city is worse than when I first came on.
So what does that say about me?
About my life?
Come on, man. You're talking about drugs.
That's a force of nature.
That's sweeping leaves on a windy day,
whoever the hell you are.
You fought the good fight.
Not a call since we gave it up to Cheese.
What did you expect?
Attention.
Be seated.
Regarding Officer Dozerman...
his condition has been upgraded
to "guarded."
I'm told he can receive visits,
and he's been moved to Recovery Unit.
As of this tour...
all hand-to-hand undercover buys of CDS...
are suspended in the Western District.
You're kidding me.
Somewheres...
back in the dawn of time...
this district had itself a civic dilemma
of epic proportion.
The city council had just passed a law
that forbid alcoholic consumption...
in public places, on the streets...
and on the corners.
But the corner is, and it was,
and it always will be...
the poor man's lounge.
It's where a man wants to be
on a hot summer's night.
It's cheaper than a bar, catch a nice breeze,
you watch the girls go by.
But the law is the law.
And the Western cops rolling by,
what were they gonna do?
If they arrested every dude out there
for tipping back a High Life...
there'd be no other time
for any other kind of police work.
And if they looked the other way?
They'd open themselves
to all kinds of flaunting.
All kinds of disrespect.
Now, this is before my time
when it happened, but...
somewhere back in the '50s or '60s...
there was a small moment
of goddamn genius...
by some nameless smokehound
who comes out the Cut Rate one day...
and on his way to the corner...
he slips that just-bought
pint of elderberry...
into a paper bag.
A great moment of civic compromise.
That small wrinkled-ass paper bag...
allowed the corner boys
to have their drink in peace...
and it gave us permission...
to go and do police work.
The kind of police work
that's actually worth the effort.
That's worth actually taking a bullet for.
Dozerman...
he got shot last night trying to buy...
three vials.
Three!
There's never been a paper bag...
for drugs.
Until now.
If we ain't doing hand-to-hands,
then what the fuck?
And the shit with the bag?
What the fuck is that?