[lighter clicks]
[door opens, closes]
[exhales]
[girl] Hey!
- Good day, Calonice.
- Claire, what are you doing?
Thinking.
You're supposed to be on-stage right now.
"Calonice, it's more than I can bear.
I am hot all over
with blushes for our sex.
- Men say we're slippery rogues..."
- "And aren't they right?"
Come on, let's go.
[Claire inhales and exhales]
Come on.
We're all gonna die one day.
What?
I'm gonna be dead,
you're gonna be dead.
They're all gonna be dead.
Everybody.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Are those my earrings?
I... didn't think you'd care.
You do it.
You be Lysistrata.
You know all my lines, right?
You can't just...
[blubbers]
What about the show? Claire!
We are almost good.
We just have to adjust the lights.
That's fine.
I did want to thank you personally
for doing this.
I really appreciate it.
Wait till we're finished
before you do that.
[laughs]
Well, I won't deviate from the questions.
You can ask me anything,
as long as it's about the...
the president.
Can you get away from me with that? -[man] My apologies.
- [Bill] I'm fine.
Sorry, Mr. Shepherd. It's just
that the lights are pretty harsh.
It's fine. Let's go.
This Russia debacle,
it's essentially a 20% tax
on American companies that are just
over there trying to help out the region.
It's the latest in a series of...
disastrous steps taken
by this White House.
And you wonder...
You wonder why Congress
was looking at legislation
to take the nuclear button away from her.
[scoffs] As a patriot,
as an American who loves his country
and, yes, his company,
we can do better.
We can do so much better.
Even Bill Shepherd, who the last time
he was interviewed on air was never...
Even he felt compelled to speak out.
She's the head of my party,
and I have to say, I'm at a loss.
- Her entire schedule is empty.
- Presidents have gone missing before...
But there's a difference between
clearing your head at Camp David
and going full-blown Howard Hughes.
She hasn't been seen publicly
in three weeks or heard from.
Except for a late night pardon
for her husband's chief of staff.
- Which many consider a strategic mistake.
- Well, Doug Stamper has issues.
Everyone in her administration has issues.
Sean Jeffries, the press secretary,
has resigned.
And there are probably
more departures to come.
Her cabinet has had enough.
And if she thinks a pardon
is gonna keep the US Attorney away,
- she's...
- She's...
- Depressed.
- I don't know about depressed.
You know, she looks either very disturbed,
or depressed.
But, I mean, "disturbed"?
Can you really say that?
Yeah. Look, hold on.
I'm asking a very real question
about her ability to lead here.
Have you seen this photo? Because we have.
Now we're not here to diagnose,
but you look at this, and you need to ask.
[Cruz] On behalf of our country,
that woman undid 30 years
of foreign policy
by acting like,
pardon my French, a... [bleep]
But now,
now we're into a new phase.
When the White House lights are on,
but nobody's home.
I mean, she's home, but she won't leave.
Been hunkered down in there
for 23 days and counting.
Apparently, she's stopped doing anything.
She's paralyzed.
A paralyzed... [bleep]
And there's nothing more dangerous
than a paralyzed... [bleep]
Seriously,
I think she might be the worst thing
that has ever happened to this country.
SOS.
Save our souls, save our ships,
Take your pick.
This [bleep] is real.
I'm Melody Cruz, and that's what I got.
Hi.
That's quite a snapshot, right?
Unique. Carefully calibrated.
Pain, hysteria
and just a small dose of crazy.
Claire Underwood,
like they've never seen before.
It's actually not as easy as it looks.
See, in order for me to make that face,
I have to imagine...
the perfect combination of things.
Here's the recipe.
First, I have to think about all the ways
in which men have tried
to manage me my whole life.
Then, I think of...
America's worst fear...
when it comes to a female
in the Oval Office.
[door opens]
- [Kelsey] Her schedule has been cleared.
- And finally...
[Mark and Kelsey chattering]
...my biggest regret...
Francis J. Underwood.
- [knock on door]
- [sighing]
Madam President.
Are you ill?
If you're ill,
I'll call the White House physician.
Claire.
Just get out, Mark.
- Claire, this has to stop.
- Please, just leave me alone.
You are alarming the nation.
You need to get up.
Listen.
I've prepared a short statement
explaining your absence
and announcing your return.
You can deliver it
in the Rose Garden this afternoon.
I promise you
this is for both of our sakes.
[sniffles] You don't understand...
[Mark] If you would, please.
Claire...
look at me.
- Look at me.
- Get out.
Please get out. Just leave me alone.
You are not only digging your own grave,
you are burying the presidency. Stop it.
You can try.
- Can you try?
- [gasping] I can't, Mark.
I just can't.
[sighs]
I can't. [shudders, sighs]
[panting]
Don't worry.
I have a plan.
[electronic whirring]
[man] Excuse me.
[man] Sir.
We're good here?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Was it paranoia or is it due diligence?
You tell me, Mark.
We both just lived through
what that bitch is capable of.
Something is definitely wrong.
She...
Coffee?
I mean, she can't even
put two sentences together.
[Annette] Are you sure?
I've never seen her like this.
She's a mess.
Well...
Either way,
that doesn't change where we are.
And, Mark...
when Conway imploded,
we recognized
that you were a little squea...
squeamish about stepping in.
And we appreciate that.
But it's time.
You'll make a great president.
- We'll see to that.
- Now, wait, wait. Let's be clear, okay?
I know we've been hitting her pretty hard,
but I can't condone another attempt.
- I can't.
- Calm down.
My God, Mark. I mean, really.
There are other ways.
Okay, so we're talking about impeachment
or a congressional government?
25th Amendment, Section 4.
- Which has never been used.
- [Annette] It's built for speed,
intended to smother a crisis
of confidence.
Reassure the public.
Reassure the world
that continuity remains
at the American government,
even if a president becomes...
- Unable to fulfill his duties.
- Her duties.
- It requires her to be unfit.
- And she is.
I mean...
our lawyers have already looked into this.
She only needs to be deficient.
The language is vague and accommodating.
Mark, if you have any doubt about this
- at all...
- I'm just listening.
The Cabinet is yours.
You have relationships inside the Senate,
the House, on both sides of the aisle.
It's a natural fit.
But the thing has to cascade with...
Precision.
A chain reaction beginning
with a letter to Congress,
signed by the vice president
and a majority of his Cabinet,
recommending my removal from office.
And how do I know
that's what they'll try to do?
Because the 25th gets personal.
Bill likes me being the damsel
in distress.
He wishes I were.
[gulps]
Where you headed?
I have family up north.
Where?
North.
Cathy's sister still on the Cape?
Hyannis, right?
It's good.
Family's important.
- Especially during trying times...
- I'd invite you in, but I really...
There's still something
that I can't get straight.
If we could go through it
one more time. So...
she was picked up by car
to be taken to the doctor.
- She wasn't feeling well. - You were with her the whole
time -leading up to the embolism? - Mr. Stamper, enough!
I'm just trying
to understand what happened.
I don't need you
coming around here anymore.
You know exactly what happened.
You have the coroner's conclusions.
And that's that.
I'm in mourning for my wife,
and I'm not reliving the final moments
of her life anymore. Not with you.
I think your wife was murdered.
I'm closing the door now.
[car alarm chirps]
[phone ringing]
- Hello.
- Doug. Fred Amburg here.
- Whose phone is this?
- This one's mine.
I just got out.
I had no idea.
I talked to Cole this morning.
Heard an interesting thing
about our esteemed shrink.
You know, that sabbatical, leave,
walkabout, whatever you want to call it.
You are looking for him, aren't you?
Yes.
He's in a cabin down in Virginia.
Here you go.
Would you mind if I...?
Thanks.
[phone line trilling]
[phone ringing]
[beeps]
Oh, hello?
[Fred] Don't say another word.
Don't speak. Just wait.
Ah...
[grunts]
My apologies, I took a wrong turn
and wound up in some stairwell.
We don't have much time
until we have to get back upstairs.
When Marcy first came to me
with this proposition,
I was stunned, to say the least.
Until recently I...
I don't know. I didn't realize
how truly bad things were.
But unseat the president?
Jesus Christ.
President's my friend.
And while I worry about her mental state,
I worry about the state
of this nation more.
Mr. Vice President, I admire you greatly.
But I'm not used to this kind of thing.
Back rooms, after hours.
We need to take every precaution.
And yet we're still at risk
just by being here.
I'm sorry,
but I believe in the sanctity
of the office of the presidency.
[Siegerson]
And that's exactly why we're here.
You're asking us to betray an oath.
I'm asking you to speak your mind.
A concentrated effort,
all of us in this room.
We may not be able to save the president,
but we may just be able
to save our administration.
[man] The 25th is not just about timing.
It's about secrecy.
- And the Senate hasn't kept a secret...
- [Mark] Earl, I appreciate that.
I have the House,
and I'll take care of the Senate.
[Siegerson] I'll prepare a letter
detailing the president's dereliction
of duty,
laying out a case for Congress
and for posterity.
And when the time comes,
you'll all be notified.
[Mark] Look, we're all patriots here.
[sighs] Our first concern,
our only concern, has got to be...
the survival of our nation.
[crickets chirping]
[sighs]
[exhales]
[Rosen] Fuck! Ah!
[panting] [laughs]
[both sigh]
- Sit and take a deep breath.
- [exhales]
Sit down.
Dr. Rosen, sit down.
[panting]
How did you get in here?
I'm assuming you're here
because you're suffering.
And if it's not over Zoe Barnes,
it's over some other soul
that you've torn apart.
No.
You're assuming I'm here because
I figured out what you took from me.
- Took?
- Kept.
All personal property
should have been returned upon release.
You're right. It should have.
There's no accounting for the behavior
of supposed professionals.
[clears throat]
I once met this psychologist, socially,
who told me about a party that
she hosted once for a group of her peers.
It was just a roomful of shrinks.
At the end of the night,
she was cleaning up,
she went into the bathroom
and she saw that one of her colleagues
had smeared shit
all over the bathroom wall.
Now, what kind of fucked up person
would do something like that?
Well, I guess it's true what they say.
That shrinks
are the most fucked up of all.
[Rosen sighs]
Such a violence to that act.
But violence is a funny thing.
You know, it's not so much
the physical pain
that can victims can remember.
It's the feelings around it.
- The fear.
- [shouts]
Where is it? The will you intercepted?
Where is it?
I don't have it anymore. [whimpering]
[glass shatters]
I don't have it!
What was in it?
[gasping]
He left you everything.
[coughs]
[sobbing]
God...
[Doug] Take it.
[Rosen] Thank you.
I thought it was a strange question.
What?
When you asked me what Francis Underwood
had given me.
That's how the will ends.
"Remember the last thing I gave you."
Don't call her or I'll be back.
Hope you figure out your problems, Doctor.
[crying]
[Claire] Take it.
If you want it, it's yours.
Do you ever wonder if you're living
somebody else's life?
Whose life are you living, Jane?
Not me. You.
You seem to be struggling
with your identity.
If that's not too impertinent
to say to a...
sitting president.
Come keep me company
while I put my jammies on.
Please.
Your little show of compliance
at the funeral
as you made your side deal with Victor.
Makes me wonder.
And now what?
What do you call this show?
How to turn 323 million people against you
in three short weeks?
Congratulations, Claire.
You've become a problem for everybody.
And...
Just so you know,
Syria may be too far gone.
Tell me what to do, Jane.
I was at an event tonight.
An event the president usually attends.
And how was that evening?
The storm that's gathering is a rough one.
When you think they'll strike?
I have no idea.
It's late.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
I think I should move out.
I understand.
Stick to this course, Madam President,
and...
[Kelsey] Full house.
You must be looking for different answers
to the same questions
we've been going over for the last...
Now, 24 days.
And the president still hasn't left the residence.
- And this is where I say... - [woman] Kelsey, come on.
For now, the ground-breaking accord
with Russia,
which aims for a just and lasting peace
in Syria, speaks for itself.
So,
unless there are any more questions,
or shall I say new questions? Yes.
Isn't the vice president
really the one running the show,
essentially acting as president?
There are members of the cabinet
who are saying as much.
Well, firstly, I would refrain
from using the word "show,"
- when it comes to the White House.
- [woman scoffs]
And... yeah. That's all for today.
- [shouting]
- Thank you.
Are you sure you're not hungry?
The soup is quite nice.
I don't know how you can...
Eat?
[sighs] No, I'm...
glad to see you're eating.
Madam President, it's beyond repair.
You understand that, at this point?
You've lost the Hill.
You've lost your cabinet.
You've lost the country.
You've lost.
Your own party can't even
find a reason to support you.
I entreat you...
You entreat me?
Resign.
And are you speaking to me as vice
president? I'm speaking to you as a person.
Blame it on...
the strain after Francis' death,
the strain of the office itself.
Language can be found,
but the best you can hope for now...
is a dignified exit.
What's so moving about him
is he can't help himself.
He can't help being decent. Human.
His glorious flaw.
What this means is
they're gonna go through with it.
No, Mark.
I'm staying right where I am.
[police radio chatter]
[man] You got two minutes.
That's not Rachel Posner.
Is it?
You knew Rachel Posner.
Uh, I mean...
yeah, I guess.
Enough to use her name
for someone else's ID?
That's what you do, isn't it?
Kind of pay the names forward?
No.
What name did you give Rachel?
I don't remember.
I don't.
When did you last see her?
Come on. Um...
Couple of years ago or something.
It was where she worked.
Is she dead?
- I got nothing to do with that.
- Did you help kill her?
[man] Oh.
I'm talking to you.
Hey, hey, hey, man. I want my lawyer.
Do you know...
Doug Stamper?
No.
What name did you give her?
What was her name?
Lisa.
- Lisa?
- Yeah. Lisa Cassie.
- Lisa Cassie?
- Cassie, Lisa.
- [man] Yeah.
- [Hammerschmidt] Lisa and Cassie?
Back at the White House.
You took his room.
It's bigger.
Can you tell me why it was so important
that we meet here and now?
Honestly, I was hoping we could meet
in the West Wing.
I haven't left the residence in...
Well, I'm sure you still read the news.
And your pardon...
hasn't helped me or Francis.
I don't feel comfortable here.
[sighs]
Whatever bad memories
you may have, Doug...
sometimes it takes a long time
to understand
who's the real source of our harm.
And I have failed to make you trust me,
and that's a shame.
I trust what I know.
You have enemies,
and they underestimate you.
And how do you think they'll come at me?
Has Congressman Cole said anything to you?
I think she's alive.
Cathy Durant.
I don't know where she is
or what she's up to, but...
I knew you'd want to know.
I want you to know something.
Francis died in this room.
I told everyone it was in my bed.
But it was right there on the floor.
Whoever killed him.
Am I missing something?
Whoever killed him
will get what she or he deserves.
Timing decided the shape of the universe.
[man] Who said that?
Me.
Hell is truth seen too late.
Did you say that?
Thomas Hobbes.
Usher...
your bet.
- Hmm. I'll check, please.
- Don't be polite.
I played with you before.
I know you're holding.
Bill, you sure?
I can deal you in on the next hand.
- I don't play.
- Is it true she's a basket case?
Or just a plain old Democrat.
- [laughing]
- So, I'll have the letter.
That's a hundred to see mine.
And when it comes time, Hank,
I don't want to end up on the Senate floor
with a piece of paper in one hand...
And your balls in the other?
We've all been there.
Just keep my balls out of it.
Usher, you want me to whip,
but you don't want me
to tell my senators
what they're voting on.
And pass without debate.
I'm out.
At least tell me what they're getting.
A new resident in the White House.
[Hank] Well, Mr. President.
Are you in or are you out?
I call.
And...
Um... bump you 500.
[Duncan]
I would never call this enemy territory.
It might sound quaint,
but I believe in the Republic.
[Claire] Oh. Well, thank you for coming.
[sighs] It's not sustainable.
This media onslaught.
I wonder if you'd consider
calling off the dogs.
All I'm asking for is a pause.
Couple of days or so.
You flatter me, Madam President.
But my reach only goes so far.
It seems they want you to resign.
Who's they?
Who isn't?
Pardon my bluntness.
Oh, no, I enjoy bluntness. Saves time.
But should I resign
for the high crime of being a female?
Oh, I think the reasoning
goes deeper than that.
I think...
and this is just my perspective,
- if you want to hear it.
- Oh, please.
Dueling agendas between my family,
and, well, you,
have taken on their own life.
And in some sense,
your husband just won't leave you alone,
will he?
I can't change history.
I'll bet sometimes you'd like to.
Wouldn't you like to erase him?
Madam President...
your dead husband told my mother things.
Things you don't want the world to know.
A dead man's words are worthless
as far as I'm concerned.
Not when his claims can be verified.
It's possible to make the memory
of a person disappear.
Digitally.
Move them far
into the background, anyways.
There are ways.
Algorithms.
You're a very confident young man.
Even your deeds can go away.
Now, I can make it easier
for all of us to work together.
Does your mother know you're here?
No.
Just out of curiosity,
what's your first memory?
Your first memory of her?
That's a strange question.
I was just curious.
I have a photograph of her catching me.
My mother had thrown me up into the air,
and my uncle snapped a picture
on his new Nikon camera.
She's beaming.
Gleeful.
I treasure that photo.
It's how I like to think of her.
[inhales sharply] Do me a favor.
Ask Annette...
Ask your mother where you came from.
It's still light out?
[sighs]
You're very dehydrating.
I know, I know.
You want to talk about the deal.
[clicks tongue] You excluded me, Jane.
When the dust settles,
I'll give you what you want.
Never doubted your value.
Have you seen my phone?
It's in the restroom.
[sighs]
Shit.
Did you do something to my...
I went to the EPA.
There is nothing.
Jesus Christ.
There are people walking around this town,
dressed down, acting like they belong.
But I know they don't.
- Have you been threatened?
- Come on, they're too smart for that.
Well, so they're following you.
- But if there's nothing, then there's...
- I have screenshots...
of the e-mail chain.
'Cause it's wrong what they did.
'Cause I'm so stupid.
So stupid to believe
in doing the right thing
in this totally fucked up world.
[sighs]
There's an e-mail from Bill Shepherd's office
in the chain. [scoffs] I told you. They knew.
They knew somebody was gonna die.
I gotta go.
Hey! Hey, wait.
What?
Your phone.
- What about it?
- I don't trust it.
I got rid of mine. I swear, it felt like
they were following my phone and not me.
- How?
- Look, I gotta go. I'll reach out to you.
- Okay?
- No. What...
[panting] She's somewhere in Saudi Arabia.
Ma'am, she poses a significant risk
in enemy hands. You know that.
The United States does not negotiate
with terrorists.
No negotiations.
Options are being drawn up at SOCOM.
But nothing can happen
without an executive order.
Well, then.
That's gonna have to happen
when you're president.
No one's secrets are safe
with Jane in captivity.
That may be more concerning for you
than it is for me.
Kicking the hornet's nest.
Time to move this thing along.
- You arrogant little prick.
- Please, just calm down.
Did you think I wouldn't find out?
I'm not staying if there's name-calling.
Oh. There's not enough names
to call him, Annie.
- Such stunning stupidity.
- Nice alliteration, Uncle Bill.
This towel is smarter than you.
This window is smarter than you.
This rug is smarter than you.
- Hello, Seth.
- Hello, sir.
Seth is smarter than you!
The sweat on my brow
is smarter than you, Duncan.
- Jesus H. Christ, spare us.
- Because sweat on my brow,
would have at least known
not to pay an unsanctioned visit
- to the President of the United States.
- Get your hands off him.
I know you're not feeling well, but...
Well, what the hell
is that supposed to mean, anyway?
You can't act like this.
You know, I was trying to help.
She invited me and...
And you went, like a fucking idiot...
I wanted to be a bridge.
[Annette]
Shut up, both of you, just shut up.
God, is there anything
we haven't done for you?
Well, you know,
that's what people do for family.
- Anything.
- Listen, you shouldn't have gone.
She can't be trusted,
as I've told you a million times.
He jeopardized our timing.
He jeopardized our timing with her!
I can't stand the sound
of male arguing anymore.
You know, she told me
to ask you something.
She told me to ask you where I came from.
[Annette] Seth. Seth!
Sixteen weeks.
The one from the pregnancy
with her husband.
Annie, I do think it'd be a mistake.
Seth, confirm it.
- That's right. Sixteen weeks.
- Her husband told me.
But you don't know
how it's gonna play. Okay?
It could backfire. Get her sympathy.
- [Annette] Who waits 16 weeks? - The narrative can't be controlled...
What kind of person, that's what people will be talking about.
Let's get Mark on the phone.
We start this now.
Only "Lisa" is what we called her.
The lady at Central Market,
where she worked,
said you stopped by
a few times asking for her.
She owed us some money, but...
She dead?
Hmm. I don't know.
There's not much in there.
Some letters.
Scraps and lists and...
Picture.
Nothing, really.
Our country has a problem right now.
The president,
she has ignored the advice
of her senior advisers,
people who have studied
and fought battles.
Her state of mind has left us
in a weakened...
[sighs] We need to hold the line
till our country gets back on course.
That is a truly stunning video.
What is your reaction
to the secretary of defense's critique
of this president?
Secretary Defense Hanna
is a four-star Marine General
with over 40 years of service
to this country.
I understand his frustration.
Is there any truth to the idea
that Mark Usher
is the Dick Cheney of this White House?
No, there is only one Dick Cheney.
- Okay, fair enough.
- Mark Usher is
the Mark Usher of this White House.
So, how would you characterize
- the vice president's role?
- The vice president
has the full support
of the entire cabinet.
And the president?
Well, the president speaks for herself.
Are you suggesting that
the secretary of defense
is not the only one
who's frustrated with this president?
You know, Lawrence, this town
feeds off of rumor and gossip
- and it's counter-productive.
- Raha? [Siegerson] It's a distraction. I don't work that way.
[O'Donnell] You don't work that way.
How do you work?
- How do you work with this president?
- You have a call.
It's your president.
Is this a dysfunctional administration?
[Siegerson] My relationship with this...
[Jane] Claire.
Jane, I just need to know exactly
when they're going to pull the trigger.
Don't you want to come home?
You look like you're having fun.
I see real affection there.
And, listen, there were rumors
about Tom and me, of course,
but nothing to them.
He was like a brother to me.
So comforting.
Which is what makes this
all the more difficult.
The truth is, Kelsey...
the Russians killed Tom...
and Mark Usher covered it up.
Now, I'm doing my best
to hold him accountable,
but I need your help.
I need you to tell the FBI
about your relationship with Tom.
- Madam President, I...
- I know. It's fine.
You just say you were dating.
You were in love.
And in a private moment,
he told you about
his suspicions regarding
Mark Usher and his collusion with Russia.
And the last time you saw him,
he was on his way
to the vice president's home
to confront him.
I'm not going to let the vice president
get away with this.
You and I, as women,
we have to fight back.
I need you by my side.
And before we transmit the letter,
I'd like to suggest we all take a moment
to bow our heads
and pray for this great nation.
Could you pass me that letter?
[Siegerson sighs]
And gather all of your things.
Every single cabinet member in this room
is dismissed.
You're all fired.
[murmuring]
[Claire] Escort them out.
[chattering]
You know,
I never took you for someone
who wanted to get himself into the Oval.
All it is, is a four year job,
eight if you're lucky.
- [cell phone rings]
- [beep]
Hey, where are you?
What?
All right. I'm on my way back.
Listen, if she prevented the signing,
that's obstruction.
And likely, it's impeachable.
You hear me?
[Wolf Blitzer]
Details are still coming in.
But we're being told there are reports
that the FBI...
- Mark.
- ...has today been provided evidence...
- Get to a television.
- ...that Mark Usher had quote...
- Or a computer.
- ..."significant and ongoing...
Or a goddamn radio.
...contact outside the logs
with Russian officials."
This leading up to
and during the president's
recent polarizing Syrian peace deal.
The FBI's expected
to look into the matter,
but has yet to announce
whether or not they are opening
an official investigation.
If so, this could be
a catastrophic setback
for an already-beleaguered administration.
Before we begin, I'd like
to offer youthe chance to resign.
I'll leave you to it then.
I never had any contact
with any Russians outside the logs. None.
[woman] You vacationed at Deputy Foreign
Minister Zorkin's family dacha
- on the Black Sea in summer 1991.
- [Mark] That was 20 years ago.
[man] Let's work backwards,
start with questions that have arisen
after Ms. Kelsey Stewart's deposition.
Who?
We located her phone
in a liquor store in Bellport.
She knows about the app.
We should assume so.
Have you told my uncle yet?
- I can't reach him.
- [knock on door]
I can't reach your mother, either.
We have some men tracking the journalist.
But we don't even know
if she has her hands on anything yet.
- Package for Mr. Shepherd.
- Oh, thank you.
This is addressed to you.
Leave me alone, please.
My name is Catherine Durant.
Today is Tuesday, July 18, 2017.
And the time... [inhales]
is 8:37 p.m.
Now, before I begin, let me just say...
that every punishment
that history will surely visit
upon Claire Underwood
will be exactly what she deserves.
I rue the day that I accepted
her husband's offer
of secretary of state.
Now, then...
I hereby swear that everything
I'm about to say
is the truth.
Her husband has disappeared,
as of six hours ago.
- Do you want to hear any more?
- No.
I know the rest.
Do you think the Russians got them out?
Uh, no, I'm sure of it.
Do you think she sent it to anyone else?
We would know about it by now.
[Claire]
I've asked Nathan to be available to you.
I know how well you two work
with one another.
We'll find her.
And, Doug, I haven't forgotten about
the promise we made to each other.
I hope you haven't.
[sighs]
[line trilling, phone ringing]
[beep]
I just got back from New Mexico.
What did you do with Rachel?
Or is it Cassie?
I'm five minutes away.
Hang up the phone.
- Doug...
- Hang it up
or you'll never hear from me again.
I'll come to you.
[beep]
Nathan,
are you still listening?
You're a fool to think she'll protect you.
[beeps]
Seems fitting, somehow,
that you're the first person I meet with
after I've returned to work.
There's something
very full circle about it.
So, you've talked to your son.
Or rather, not your son.
Do you know how developed
a fetus is by then?
Sixteen weeks is... beyond the beyond.
That is what 16 weeks looks like.
That is what I can't get out of my head.
I'm quoting Melody Cruz here, by the way.
She just taped her segment,
due to run tomorrow.
Visual aids and everything.
For the first time ever,
Americans will hear the story
of a childless president...
who had an abortion,
while married,
at 16 weeks.
I wanted to see your face.
I wanted to see Frank's betrayal register.
[sighs] Nobody can keep
their mouths shut these days.
Not even to-the-death secrets are safe.
It's shameful.
But honestly, what's worse?
That he betrayed your secret
or that you waited until 16 weeks?
You and your party.
Your moral rectitude, how convenient.
You don't even believe half
of what you say, Annette.
Run it.
Cruz's piece.
And then go home
and talk to Duncan
about the beginning of life.
But actually before you go,
I want to show you something.
Come with me.
Meet my new cabinet.
I just wanted to see your face.
Thank you all for assembling
at such short notice.
And I want to thank you
for your willingness to serve.
I am looking forward
to building a new America together
and our work begins today.
Now, if you could all
place your left hand on the Constitution
in front of you.
And repeat after me:
I do solemnly swear