Precedently on Fargo...
Who?
Fargo.
Freeze! Police officer!
Halt!
That cop, the female,
says you're a suspect.
Suspect of what?
For Pearl, the Chief,
even Sam Hess.
If you want this to go away,
you gotta give 'em someone.
It's good waffles, hon.
It's a mix.
Who's ready for seconds?
- Gordo?
- Yeah?
- What you doing there?
- Reading a comic.
It's breakfast time, though.
Supposed to be family time.
Yeah, put the comic away, huh?
One more page.
That's not...
It's breakfast, mister.
Family time. You heard your mother.
700 to 1,000
people are without power...
Your mom needs help after school.
Got hockey.
After hockey then.
Supposed to play with Kevin.
Well, you can play with Kevin tomorrow.
It's time you learned some responsibility.
Ooh, hon, listen to this.
Meteorologists are saying the incident
was probably caused by a tornado
which sucked up water and fish from a lake
and dropped them miles away.
And we'll have more on
this developing news story
a little later tonight
- along with our meteorologist's take on...
- The darndest thing.
Come on, bud, get your boots on.
You don't wanna be late for the bus.
Kiss, kiss. Kiss, kiss, kiss.
Mwah. Love ya.
And me?
Dad.
On what reporters are calling
the storm of the century.
Plow drivers have been
working for 24 hours straight
without rest, and though exhausted,
we spoke to one earlier today...
No funny stuff today.
So then Neo's like, "I'm the one."
And agent
what's-his-name is like...
"The sound of inevitability."
Yeah, and he's got him,
right? Around the neck.
- Oh, it hurt me a little.
- Don't be such a baby.
Guys. So they're on the tracks, right?
And the train's coming. Stop...
And Neo says, "No way, huh?"
And he...
Uh...
So we're in the room
with the stripper, yeah?
And Blackman wants to know
how much for a blumkin.
Which I'm like, "What the heck is that?"
- Blackman.
- Yeah, so he says,
"You know, why not stick
around and find out?"
And I'm like...
Mr. Nygaard,
your wife is on one.
Yeah, I'll call her back.
Oh, no, she said it's urgent.
Yeah, hon?
Chazz, the cops are here.
Gordo's been arrested,
and the cops are here.
Whoa, whoa, slow down.
What do you mean the cops are there?
In the house.
They say that Gordo
brought a gun to school,
and they're tearing up the house.
They say they got a search warrant.
Don't... don't let them.
I'll be right there.
Just... I'll be right there.
- I'm coming!
- Chazz, what have you done?
- I'm on my way!
- Chazz?
No.
Wait, hold on!
What?
You son of a bitch! He's my baby!
Now, I got...
- I got permits for those.
- You son of a bitch!
Now, Bill Oswalt, hold on...
Son of a bitch!
I can explain that.
I...
What have you done?
Oh, hey.
Bill.
Busy morning, huh?
Is there a... some kinda
development with the case?
Is that why I'm...
Where's the female deputy? Is she...
She got shot, Lester.
- She got...
- In Duluth.
I should be up there right now,
but then there's this mess.
I don't even know where to start.
It's like when you see on the news
a boat sinks in India
and 300 people drown,
and you ask yourself,
"Do I know 300 people?"
Or one of those African massacres
with 12-year-olds
with machetes,
and they kill... You can't even...
You can't even count that high.
We lost 16 people in 1920
to the flu.
I looked it up.
In '78, six people died
in a pharmacy fire,
but nothing like this ever.
Three people murdered in two days,
including the Chief of Police,
Lenny Potts missing, and a cop shot.
And now a kid brings a gun to school.
A kid?
It was Gordo, Lester.
Gordo? My Gordo?
He had a handgun in his backpack,
unloaded, thank gosh.
But still, you can't... Not
with the current climate...
Is he in trouble?
Is he...
He brought a gun to school!
And still... Gordo's the least of this.
We searched the house.
And, Lester, I gotta tell you,
I don't know whether to...
After all these years,
I like to think that
you could've come to me,
you could've trusted
me as a friend with...
We know you were in the room
when Vern was shot.
You had a shotgun pellet in your hand,
same as killed Vern.
Was your wife having an affair?
With Chazz?
Mm-hmm.
We found a photo.
Photos. At his place.
Suggestive.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Boudoir photos.
- And a pair of...
- Bill!
Yeah, and I know...
I know how much you loved her.
I remember
ninth grade science class, Mrs. Nagutuck.
Pearl walks in the first day of class
and sits down, and you look at me...
"I'm gonna marry that girl one day."
But she was always...
I know this is outta line, but...
we all heard the stories.
But to sleep with your own brother?
I know.
God... Your own brother!
And what then?
She tells him it's over and he...
We all know your brother had a temper.
He broke a guy's nose once
just for crackin' wise at the state fair.
Ha! I remember!
Had to do community service.
So what, she cuts it off, the affair,
and then he...
All I know is that I came home from work,
and they were arguing in the basement.
I heard the voices. I
thought, is that Chazz?
And so I went over to
the top of the stairs
to hear, you know?
And she says, uh,
"Love? Is that what you think this is?"
Or something like that.
She laughs.
And then she says,
"You know, you're not half
the man your brother is."
Then I hear this sound.
This...
I'll never forget it.
So, um...
I run downstairs, and, uh, there's Chazz.
And he's got the hammer.
And he looks up at me and says,
"Oh, jeez, Lester.
What did I..."
I'm upset.
I...
I try to get to Pearl, you
know, to check if she's...
And Chazz says to me,
"Lester, this was an accident."
And I... "An accident?"
You hit her with a hammer.
And, uh, he raises up the hammer again.
He's still looking at me.
Uh, I don't know if he's gonna... or what.
So... so I say, um, something like,
"Chazz, what the heck..."
And the doorbell rings.
- Vern?
- Mm-hmm.
I wanted to say something, Bill.
I swear.
But Chazz, you know, he's...
You were afraid.
Oh, I was afraid, yeah.
And Chazz is my only brother.
So then what happens?
So then... Uh, we go upstairs.
And, uh, Chazz says, "Take care of it."
And he goes in the back.
Where you kept the shotgun.
Where I kept the shotgun. I
should have thought of that.
The shotgun... I know... I know, but I...
I was in shock.
So I let Vern in, and right away
I think to... to tell him,
to say what's happened,
because Pearl could
still be alive downstairs.
There might still be time to...
And then Chazz comes in with the shotgun.
And I should've stopped him.
I should've said right away,
"Chazz is in the house, and he's, um..."
but I was afraid, like you said.
And now... And now it's...
Bill, if you think that
makes me guilty of something,
then I want you to throw the book at me.
Put me in jail.
'Cause I loved her.
You know, Pearl, despite all...
she was...
She was my wife.
Lester!
Lester, what did you do?
Freeze! Police officer!
Halt!
She's awake.
What happened?
Um, you got shot.
Go outside, now, okay?
Why?
Just do it.
Did we get him? Who?
Malvo.
I had him and...
Until this other fella popped up.
Uh...
Look now, I-I-I gotta
tell you something...
Do you know what happened
to the fella I shot?
Is he...
He's, uh...
They got him upstairs in Intensive.
I shot him twice.
Just like they teach you.
Center mass.
And him with a bazooka.
How the heck did I do that?
'cause you're you.
Look, here's the, um...
Um...
I shot you.
Well, that don't make sense.
You ran off, you know,
and... and I couldn't
see anything, you know?
I mean, not that that's any...
I mean, there's...
There's no excuse for it,
for what I did.
You were out there alone,
needing backup, and I...
What'd I lose?
A spleen.
Oh.
I'll get you a new one, I swear.
Yeah, you better.
There's gonna be an inquiry.
I was too shook up at the scene to,
but I'll... I'll confess.
They'll probably take my badge,
but with all that's happened
that's likely best, so...
Come on now.
You said yourself,
it's a blizzard and whiteout conditions.
And I... I could've shot you just as easy.
No, I've just been
messing things up from the go.
Hey now. That's enough of that.
You want some pop or something?
No, I want a new spleen.
That's what I want.
So, you know, better get crackin', mister.
Dad.
Who's watching the restaurant?
Screw the damn restaurant.
Guess we both got bullet holes now, huh?
You got, uh, premium channels?
I'm not sure. I just woke up.
Work that
is extremely difficult.
Rock formations...
The bark beetle
carries the wood to its nest...
on the way to Kessel.
He shoots, he scores!
Gophers are playing.
If that's what you wanna watch.
Forcing a turnover and
the assist to Kessel.
Ben Schmidt says you put down
a guy with an assault rifle.
Well, he was pointing it at me.
Yeah.
Proud of you.
C... C...
Hmm.
All right.
Cleaners.
Hi, yeah, I got...
How you doing there then?
Oh, I'm real good now. How are you?
Oh, you know, can't complain.
Wife's got a bit of a cold,
but that's life, right?
Sure.
Well, my house needs, uh...
It's... well, I'm not
gonna lie, it's a real mess.
Heck, that's our bread and butter.
Well, do you fellas do crime scenes?
Had a break-in, huh?
Yeah, it's a little worse than a break-in.
A lot of broken glass or...
Well, I'd rather not get...
Sometimes they defecate in your...
Let's just say there's a lot of blood.
Hello?
Good!
And twist.
And front.
And side.
And two.
And three.
And good!
Left arm.
And bend.
Bend.
Good!
So I notice you got a pin on your map
in every state but Georgia.
What the hell do you got against Georgia?
My first wife.
She was Korean.
She used to spit at me when we had sex.
Can I sit?
Or did you want to kill me standing?
Two hombres took a run at me in Duluth.
Mexicans?
That's the wrong part
of the sentence to be focusing on.
The point is they said Fargo sent them.
So I have two questions.
First.
Did you tell these boys where to find me?
Second.
Who do I see about this in Fargo?
Look, you know I can't...
Did you put 'em on me?
No. Course not.
But you gotta understand,
this is a business of relationships.
I can't just...
Relationships.
Right.
And, well...
It's not my position professionally
to get involved in squabbles.
Especially not of a private nature.
How do you know it's private?
If people are unhappy with our services,
they call.
A guy screws up, arrangements are made.
A cash settlement.
If that's not enough,
break a leg or an arm.
No calls.
Not about you.
So whatever it is,
it's gotta be personal.
Doesn't matter. It's the principle.
This one calls an ambulance,
that one calls a hearse.
I'm gonna ask you again,
and depending on the answer
I pick up this or that.
Who do I talk to in Fargo?
You remember me?
Uh...
_
Dead.
Can...
Can you talk? Speak, I mean?
_
Right, but you... you... you read lips?
Okay.
You know I'm the one shot you, yeah?
Do you remember me from before?
In Bemidji?
The insurance office?
You were talking to Lester Nygaard.
Just hit me lying in bed
thinking about that...
What happened, you know.
Hold the phone, I know that fella.
Did you come here looking for Malvo?
For... look...
Lorne...
Malvo.
Lorne Malvo?
Did Lester tell you where to find him?
It hurts?
Yeah.
Mine too.
I mean, it's crazy.
I never shot anyone before.
I'm gathering this wasn't
your first time though.
Look at us.
And you got a dad somewhere I bet.
Just like me.
And, I mean, what's the point, you know?
'Cause here you are,
and your friend is dead,
and you're gonna spend the
rest of your life in jail.
And for what?
Okay.
Okay, Mr. Nygaard, I
gotta ask you to stand
and put your back to the bars.
Listen, officer, this is a huge mistake.
I... This is a setup.
- Sir.
- Do you understand?
Evidence has been planted,
it's been falsified.
Sir, turn your back towards me...
If I could just talk to my brother...
or I'm gonna have to tase you.
This is a nightmare.
You... you gotta believe
me. I didn't do these things.
Not for me to say, sir.
Where are you...
Transfer to County.
You'll be there until the trial.
Or until you make bail.
Jeez, Lester.
Oh, hey.
Heard you got arrested.
Ah, well, you know how it is.
Had a few too many. Slept
it off at the station.
And who can blame you, really?
After what you been through.
Yeah. Yeah.
They were real sweet to me.
I'm the victim here, you know?
Course.
So what's on the agenda for today?
I'm ready to go.
You know, start fresh.
I can work late even.
There's nothing at home
but an empty house, so...
Right.
Well, uh, I was just about
to call the widow Hess.
Yeah, her claim's been denied.
You don't say.
Yeah, seems Sam stopped
paying the premium.
Shame really.
Good for us. That was a big policy.
Well, she's not gonna be happy about that.
No, she's not.
Why don't... why don't I
take that off your plate?
Really?
I mean, I don't know. You
sure you're ready for...
Look, she can't shout at me, right?
Not after... I mean,
we're in the same boat.
So I figure I tell her,
she has a good cry,
and that's that.
Otherwise she's gonna be all claws-out.
That makes sense.
Yeah, it's settled. I'll head over.
You don't wanna just call?
Mm, no, in person's better, I think.
Give her a shoulder, you know?
Come in!
I, uh, brought you some flowers.
Oh, thanks.
Just put 'em...
What are you...
Oh.
It's making my head hurt,
this whole case,
all the moving pieces.
Thought I'd put it up,
you know, graphically.
See if things made much more sense.
I called back to Bemidji
to talk to Bill, but he's...
I don't know, some kid
brought a gun to school
or something.
So everyone's kinda running around.
And to be honest, everything they said
didn't make much sense anyway.
Who's the deaf fella then?
Fella upstairs, tried to
murder me with a bazooka.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Turns out he can't hear.
And the other fella with his throat cut,
I'm guessing he translated.
And they're who now?
Well, that's the thing.
All I can think is...
and, you know, maybe this is a stretch,
but heck if I know any
other way to think about it.
Sam Hess, right?
So he owns a trucking company.
And we always thought
he had maybe alleged ties
to organized crime,
this operation out of Fargo.
So when Hess gets killed,
I'm thinking maybe Fargo
sends these two boys to
figure out what happened.
And how do they end up here?
Well, follow me.
If we think, which we do,
that Lester, on the day of the murder,
got bullied by Hess
and then met Malvo at the hospital.
Right.
And hired Malvo to kill Hess.
Which he did.
And then these two boys
come in from out of town asking questions.
Get to finding Lester.
And he sends 'em here.
So Lester knew that Malvo was here
in Duluth.
It would appear that way, yeah.
But that's...
That's ammunition, right?
I mean, to go back to Lester.
Oh, yeah. You betcha.
Took forever, but I got 'em to sign off
on taking you home.
Oh, so you're, uh...
Oh, yeah.
Sure that... Recover at home, you know?
That makes sense, sure.
Thanks, dad.
Uh, well, okay.
Uh, guess I'll see you later.
Oh, dad, my flowers.
Oh, yeah.
Thanks for these.
He bought me flowers.
You don't say.
Glad you like 'em.
I'm gonna put 'em in water
as soon as I get home.
You keep your chin up, Gus Grimly.
We're winning this thing.
Don't you forget.
Say bye to Greta for me.
_
So he's got the stick in his mouth, right?
Biting down.
And I grab the arrow.
Then Craig is in the car having a giggle.
Thinks the whole thing's hi-larious.
Which that's my cousin out there, right?
So I slip the knife outta me boot
and give him the old what-for.
Held the knife to his bloody face.
And lunch is over.
I don't know how they
eat that crap every day.
Speaking of...
What?
It's fresh.
Do you know the conditions of
a modern fast food restaurant?
I'm not just talking about hygiene.
Get bent.
They did an experiment once.
Scientist took two glasses of water.
Then he starts cursing at one,
calling it all kinds of names.
You're making this up.
I swear to God.
He yells at one glass.
And then whispers sweet
nothings to the other glass...
Can I help you, sir?
Gun!
Was that shots?
Oh, my God, my God!
Drop it!
Call 911!
Where's the top dog?
The what?
The boss man.
Unh! Third floor! Private elevator.
Oh, no!
Freeze, shitbird!
Shit... unh!
What's the code?
For the elevator?
933.
Son of a...
Drop dead... ah!
Shoot him!
Get out, boss!
Come on, get him, quick!
Agh!
Boss, get back!
Shoot him!
Jesus.
What... what... Was that...
Call it in.
Oh... okay.
Call it in, man.
Your pop is in the way.
Where are you... Hold on.
Got me all...
Maybe we should get in the car
and then back up a few feet
and then pull back in
like we just arrived.
Can we just focus on the...
You need to have fewer ideas.
Shit balls.
We're in so much...
Okay, let me do the talking.
Why? I can do...
Because, when you talk...
- Back! Get back.
- ...bad shit happens.
FBI.
We're FBI.
Back! Get back!
Back, please. Police on the scene.
- What do you guys got?
- Really?
It's a body.
- Well, he doesn't know.
- Lock it down.
Multiple gun shots.
Shooter's still inside the building.
- And you're gonna need more
patrolmen than this. - Okay. Okay.
Okay. We're good.
We're going in, back us up.
James.
You follow us. Come on.
It's about time.
I've been calling.
Sorry about the delay.
- You know the red tape on these things.
- Mm-hmm.
♪ There's trouble, trouble, trouble ♪
Come on in.
Thanks.
You look real nice today.
You're sweet.
Boys home?
No, thank God.
They have a game.
Good. Good.
You don't go then, no?
Are you kidding?
I just stay here trying to drink enough,
so I'm numb by the time they get home.
Got one of those for me?
Why, Lester.
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ oh, then this man of mine ♪
Hmm?
Sure.
Ha ha!
Cheers.
To fresh beginnings.
Yeah.
So it's all set, right?
Getting paid.
Uh, ahem, well, they should.
What do you mean, "Should"?
When do I get the money?
It's like I said, there's a few
more hoops on these homicide cases.
We're not just talking about
filing a death certificate.
I don't think I'm telling
you anything you don't know
when I say these insurance companies,
they don't like writing checks.
But I'm gonna get it, right?
Well, that is where
a skilled middleman
such as myself comes in.
You see, it's all about
knowing who to call.
All about knowing which palms to grease,
if you get my meaning.
I know a little something
about greasy palms.
Well, why don't you and
me have another drink?
You can show me that.
Oh, Lester.
Slow down, tiger. You're hurting me.
I'm sorry.
Ah, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, God.
I should take you home and put you to bed.
Just be a second, I promise.
Hey.
Oh, my gosh, are you...
They said you were still...
Oh, the bullet went clean through.
Doc says take a few days, rest up.
Otherwise fine.
Where is everyone?
Celebrating.
We got him...
who killed the Chief.
Lester?
You arrested Lester?
No, didn't you hear? It was his brother,
Chazz, the whole time.
He was having an affair with the wife.
She broke it off.
What?
Yeah, beat her with a hammer,
then shot the Chief.
Lester covered for him.
Bill thinks 'cause of Chazz's temper.
You know, the fear factor.
Where...
That's not...
I gotta talk to Bill. Where's Bill?
Yeah, with the rest over at Bernard's.
I'm supposed to go over after my shift.
Okay, I gotta...
Shouldn't you go home?
You okay, hon?
Now I get it.