Precedently on Fargo...
Lester,
is this what you want?
Yes.
See you later, Lester.
Okay. Hon, get dressed.
Lester, are you okay?
Vegas PD's gonna send over some pictures
from the hotel security camera,
so don't leave town for a while.
I may have some more questions.
Ready to go?
What? I thought we weren't gonna go.
Acapulco, here we come.
Do you think you could run in?
The passports are in the safe.
There's some cash in there too.
It's cold out there.
You're sweet.
Is this what you want?
Anywhere you like.
Thanks.
Just you?
Uh, no, there's... it'll be two of us.
Linda's just grabbing
something over by the shop.
She dropped me off, said,
"Order the grilled cheese."
So I guess two of those.
And to drink?
Beer would change things for the better.
Eh, family place, I'm afraid.
Oh, okay.
Two ginger ales, then.
And I'll... I'm gonna use the bathroom.
- Free with the meal. - Right.
Oh, hey, that's the, uh...
Hey, how you doing?
Oh, hi. How are you?
Boy, he sure looks different.
Yeah, really successful guy.
Good for him.
Bemidji police.
Yeah, I'd like to report shots fired.
Sir, this is a nonemergency number.
You should've dialed 911.
Over on Elk and 3rd.
Gunshots, real loud,
like, about ten seconds ago.
Sounded like they come from
inside one of the shops.
Okay, sir...
Grilled cheese, coming right up.
That's great. Thanks.
Linda's just...
Well, she dropped me off,
grabbed something over at the shop,
and said she had to pick something up.
Yeah, you said that.
Want me to keep hers
warm till she gets here?
Oh, yeah, that's...
Although, like I said, she
should be any second now.
You know, there was a fella in here earlier
asking about you.
About me?
Yeah, silver hair. Little goatee.
Said he went by your old house,
but you moved.
Yeah. Well, we got the house up...
What... what did you tell him?
Said if he wanted to leave a number,
I'd give it to you.
He couldn't see his way clear to it,
so we left it at that.
Can't say I much liked his demeanor.
Well, sorry for the bother.
No bother. Thought you ought to know.
We're going to Acapulco.
Oh, my God.
- Nothing good's gonna come out of that.
- Right.
- $1,000 in your case. - I don't.
- You want a million dollars in your case.
- I want a million.
- It's all right. All right.
- One more case.
- Three. - Three.
Take the money, right?
Forget that. I say go for it.
- I'll get it. - No, I got it.
Solverson.
Wait, what?
The other one now?
Jeez.
Well, where's Lester?
Okay, put out an APB. I'm getting my coat.
What's that now?
Someone killed the second Mrs. Nygaard.
Hey, you didn't have to come.
Now, we both know that's not true.
Okay.
Poor thing.
A head shot, I think.
I didn't look too close.
Yeah.
She's wearing his coat.
Meaning?
Meaning maybe it's not Linda
supposed to be lying here.
- Sir, you're not allowed in there.
- Let me through.
- Oh, Lester. - Mr. Nygaard.
Oh, jeez.
- Yeah, yeah. Go over here.
- Let's get him to sit down.
- Come on. - Oh, jeez. What?
That's right. Go sit down.
- Sit down. - Here we go. Sit.
This is not happening.
This is not possible.
Mr. Nygaard, I have to ask you
where you're coming from.
I just... I was over waiting
at the restaurant,
drinking ginger ale.
Your dad was keeping her
grilled cheese warm,
and I'm... I'm just waiting there.
I can't understand.
She said she had to pick some papers up.
This is not possible.
This is impossible.
Lester, is there any way that...
Do you think that this is
connected to Las Vegas,
the murders we talked about earlier?
What are you saying?
A repercussion for what you saw maybe?
She's wearing your coat, the wife.
Molly saw that, so she's...
What do you mean she's wearing my coat?
What does that mean?
Well, she...
Her coat got a rip, and so I...
Oh, wait.
You think...
You're...
I'm gonna be sick. I'm gonna be sick.
No, Lester, if you throw
up, then I'm gonna.
We got to get him out of here.
Okay, Mr. Nygaard, we're gonna
take you down to the station now.
Oh, god.
They'll ask you a lot of questions...
Time line, et cetera, okay?
Yeah, whatever you think's best.
Uh, wait, do you... do you think...
Can I just say good-bye?
Well, this is an active crime scene...
Of course you can, Lester.
Go ahead, and take your time.
Mr. Nygaard.
Can't have you touching the body, sir.
I know.
Of course not. I'm sorry.
I-I'm just so...
I understand.
Come on. Come away now. Okay?
That's right. Okay.
612 to base.
Chief says send the bus.
Roger that, 612. I'll let 'em know.
Base to emergency one.
Chief says send the bus to 1381 Elk.
613 to base. I'm inbound with the husband.
We'll need interview one.
Roger that, 613.
613 to base.
Yeah. Go ahead, Molly.
Also, someone should wake those FBI boys.
They're over at Leroy's.
Tell 'em we got developments.
They should meet me at the station.
Roger that, 613. We'll scoop 'em up.
We're awake, right?
Who?
Us.
You're asking if we're awake?
Me and you?
Yeah, I was just...
You know sometimes you're
in the middle of a dream...
Do you say everything
that comes to your head?
Got him in Interview One.
Also, they just called from the scene.
Looks like the wife had plane
tickets in her pocket.
Mexico.
Uh-oh. This could be a dream.
What's he saying?
Coroner's saying a single
shot from close-up.
Said they found feathers
in her head from her hood.
They were stuck in...
So execution-style.
Should've said something earlier.
You heard what happened?
More than heard. Saw the
prowlers scream by.
Lester's sitting not 10 feet
away eating a grilled cheese.
Any chance you can put an
exact time on his arrival?
Not down to the minute,
but that's not why I'm...
You remember you came by with
those FBI fellas earlier,
and I was looking out the glass.
With a peculiar look on your face?
Yeah, well, there was a fella in
just before you got there,
and he was asking about Lester.
- What? - Yeah.
I'm a fool for not saying.
He was maybe mid-50s, upscale-looking.
Silver hair brushed back with a goatee.
Drove a red BMW.
This fella?
Not unless he changed his whole...
Although maybe.
Drove a red BMW you said?
Yeah.
Oh, Molly, we're going in.
Dad, I got to go.
Well, there's two ways of looking at it.
The first is, you got to.
The second is, you don't.
Will you call home for me?
Let Gus know that...
Tell him it's gonna be all night.
Screw that.
Getting my gun is what I'm doing.
Go sit on the front porch.
Make sure my granddaughter's safe.
You're a good man.
Lester, is this what you want?
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
Is she... Bill, tell me she's
not still lying there
and everyone's just stepping over her.
Mr. Nygaard, these fellas are from the FBI.
The wh... is this ab...
Come on, I told you, I didn't see nothing.
All I did was get on an elevator.
We're not here about Las Vegas, sir.
Well, we... we are, and we aren't.
Okay.
We're here about him.
Based on the hustle of the deputy,
we have a name for him:
Lorne Malvo.
Uh, Bill?
Answer the question.
Um, yeah, I'm now asking for a lawyer,
just for the record.
He's changed his look, hasn't he?
I'm done answering your...
You've obviously made up your mind
that some kind of... and I'm... I'm...
I'm not... my wife is dead!
And there are arrangements to see to,
so you can either lock me up or let me go.
He's not gonna stop.
You know that, right?
A man like that...
Maybe not even a man.
Hey, there.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, it's 7:00 in the morning,
and you're sitting on my front porch
with a shotgun.
There is some consensus this
Malvo fella may be back.
Where's Molly?
Left her at the precinct last night.
Had Lester Nygaard in custody,
about to talk to him.
I'm going after her. Keep an eye on Greta.
Believe me, I mean to.
Okay, so the plan is, we fan out.
Prowlers on all the main
roads looking for Malvo.
Encircle the town, in other words.
There's pic... yeah.
Well, there are three main roads,
So actually more of a triangle.
There's photos of the
suspect in your packets.
We hear he might have
changed his look, though,
so silver hair now, brushed back,
possibly a goatee.
Drives a red BMW, possibly stolen.
The FBI's sending a team,
and in the meantime, the
two original agents
are staking out Lester's house.
Molly, Gus on one.
Yeah.
I'll be out there with you
coordinating maneuvers, so...
pass those out for me. Thanks.
- Yeah, hon? - Hey, I've been calling.
Yeah, I know. Sorry, it's been...
Is it true? Is he back?
Yeah, I just... I just finished
briefing the guys, so...
We tried to crack Lester,
but he wouldn't flinch,
so the plan is, now we're
gonna use him as bait.
Molly...
Yeah, so things are... they're
real busy here, hon.
Look, hon.
Don't, okay?
I got to ask you not to...
don't go out there.
You, personally, don't go looking for...
It's my job.
Yeah, I know, and you're
amazing and the best,
and I have no doubt that if you wanted,
you could handcuff Al Capone.
But some days, sometimes you get forces
you can't control.
Bad luck, you know?
Bad luck.
Yeah, and this is all...
If it really is him, Malvo,
I just...
with everything we've been
working for, you know,
our family, and...
Gus.
And I know it's not fair.
It's not.
It's your job, and I am just a mailman,
but you've got a precinct full of cops,
and the FBI is there, so I just...
Bottom line, I can't make
her go to another funeral,
you know?
Yeah.
Okay, don't worry. I'll just...
yeah, I'll run things from here.
Okay, good. Good.
I'm in the car, coming over.
No, don't. That's not...
No, just go home.
Be with our girl.
Hey, is my dad there?
Yeah, yeah, he's on the
porch with a shotgun.
Got to love a man who
keeps his word, right?
So you promise?
Yeah, I won't leave the building
until they call and tell
me he's surrounded.
No, until he's dead.
I'll call you in a little bit, okay?
So it's decided.
FBI fella's gonna call for backup.
We're gonna take Lester
home, sit on the house,
see if we can't draw this Malvo fella out.
You okay, Chief?
Hanging it up after this.
What's that?
I quit, is what I'm saying.
Don't got the stomach for it,
not like some.
Wearing the badge, seeing the
lengths people are capable of,
the inhumanity.
What ever happened to saying
good morning to your neighbors
and shoveling their walk
and bringing in each other's toters?
Well, still goes on.
Yeah, but not the same.
I used to have positive
opinions about the world,
you know, about people.
Used to think the best.
Now I'm looking over my shoulder.
An unquiet mind,
that's what the wife calls it.
The job has got me staring
into the fireplace,
drinking.
I never wanted to be the type
to think big thoughts about
the nature of things and...
All I ever wanted was
a stack of pancakes and a V8.
So I'm recommending that
you take over as chief.
Oh, I-I appreciate that, but I...
No, no, you're the real deal.
You got the instincts and the disposition.
I didn't see it before, but now...
and Vern saw it. I know that.
And so I'm hoping that
after you have the baby,
you come back here and take things over.
I-I will think about that.
I will.
Got to talk to Gus, so...
So you're okay with the plan then,
call in the cavalry and set a trap?
Yeah, we're a small-time force.
We're not equipped for, you know,
urban warfare.
Most of these guys can't
shoot a can off a fence.
Okay.
Chin up, chief.
Police.
Yes, this is FBI main. I'm
looking for my agents.
Yeah, they're with a suspect.
I could interrupt.
You want Pepper or Budge?
Uh, negatory. Don't interrupt.
Just tell 'em to call
home when they're done.
FBI.
Operations.
Pass code.
61αθ9
6-1, alpha, theta, 9.
Transferring.
Operations.
Uh, yes, this is Agent Budge.
We've hit a dead end out here,
so we're gonna be heading back.
Say again.
Dead end. Heading back.
Hold on, didn't you just
call looking for backup?
Uh, yeah, my partner...
He kind of jumped the gun on that one,
but looks like local pd
has it under control,
so we're gonna just pack and blow.
Whatever. Get your shit straight.
Cancelling backup.
Help you, sir?
I hope so. I got my eye on this one.
She's a beaut. That's for sure.
V8 engine, only 22,000 miles on her.
I like it 'cause it looks
like an undercover vehicle,
like an FBI car.
Well, sir, I guess she does.
Never thought about it.
You even got the long antenna on the back.
Mind if we take a test-drive?
We... well, we're not officially open yet.
But I don't see why not. Hold on.
I'll grab the keys.
Shotgun.
Okay.
So we're letting you go.
About time.
Yeah, and so the FBI fellas
are gonna drive you home.
Not necessary. I can call a cab.
Yeah, well, like I said,
we're letting you go, but at the same time,
a wanted fugitive has been spotted in town,
and we think he's got
intentions towards you,
so ride home's not really optional.
Well, they're not coming in the house.
Sure, okay, we can play it that way,
but they're still gonna
stick around for a while,
keep an eye on things.
You know, I'm not sure what it is
that you've had against me since day one,
but I am not the person you think I am,
this... this kind of monster.
There was a fella once running for a train,
and he's carrying a pair
of gloves, this man.
He drops a glove on the platform,
but he doesn't notice.
And then later on, inside the train,
he's sitting by the window, and he realizes
that he's just got this one glove left.
But the train's already started
pulling out of the station, right?
So what does he do?
He opens the window,
and he drops the other
glove onto the platform.
That way, whoever finds the first glove
can just have the pair.
So what are you telling me?
Good-bye, Mr. Nygaard.
Good-bye, deputy.
I didn't do this, you know.
Any of it.
That deputy... boy.
She's got a thing for me.
- So, Lester, say you had a boat. - No.
Say you've got a boat,
and you've got a fox,
a rabbit, and a cabbage.
Now, you can only row
one of them across the river at a time.
Now, you can take the cabbage,
but then the fox would eat the rabbit.
Or you can take the fox,
but the rabbit would eat the cabbage.
- What are you asking...
- Same thing on the other side.
You could leave the rabbit there alone,
but what happens when
you bring the fox over
and go back for the cabbage?
Forget it.
My partner doesn't know
what he's talking about.
I already told you, just
eat all three of them.
Can I only row them
across in one direction?
No, no, either way.
Well, then you row the rabbit across,
and the fox won't eat the cabbage.
Then you go back for the fox,
and when you drop him off,
put the rabbit back in the
boat and go get the cabbage.
Only this time, you leave
the rabbit behind,
and then you row the cabbage back across.
Again, the fox will not eat the cabbage,
and then you go back for the rabbit.
That's it.
See, that wasn't so hard.
We feel we need to say again
that your life may be in danger.
Like, a lot of danger,
So we're gonna sit right here for a bit,
keep an eye on things.
Free country, isn't it?
Thanks.
You were police once, Molly says.
State cop, 18 years.
Took a bullet in the hip on a traffic stop.
Retired, full pension.
You ever do this before,
stand guard?
One other time, winter of 1979.
-4 degrees.
Sat on a dark porch from dusk till dawn.
Your stepmom was inside sleeping.
Four years old.
Who did you think was coming?
It wasn't a question of who,
more like what.
Did it come?
Not that night,
but soon after.
What are you planning to do with that?
If he comes, I'll put his eye out.
You can finish him off.
That's my girl.
Yeah, so car 18, checking in.
Over on Bear Patch.
Pretty quiet, huh?
Okay, team, keep your eyes peeled. Over.
Hey, car 6, anything?
Oh, hey. This is car 6 out on 71.
I had a pickup with an unsecured load.
All quiet otherwise.
Yeah, roger that, 6.
Keep me posted, okay?
I'm gonna run over to Lester's,
but give a shout when
the other FBI rolls up.
You think it's safe?
For me, I'm saying.
Here.
With that fella out there.
I mean, everyone else is gone.
Yeah, maybe lock the door.
You still think this is a dream?
What?
This. Today.
No.
What if my whole life has been a dream?
Yeah, but whose dream is it?
Heads up.
What do you think?
Could be our backup.
FBI. Step out of the car!
Out of the car, now!
Let me see your hands!
His hands are taped.
I'm sorry.
This is a dream.
Please.
I got a little girl.
Gosh.
Police.
Yeah, I need the police, please.
Yes, it's an emergency.
Uh, this is Lester Nygaard.
You got to... I think the f...
You need to send somebody.
I need help now. I need you to come.
Please.
My... Les... Lester Nygaard.
Please just hurry up.
I'm upstairs in the bathroom.
There's no lock on the door.
Oh, god. You've gotta hurry.
Oh, shit.
God damn it.
I figured it out.
Good for you.
Your riddle... shades of green.
I figured it out.
And?
Open it.
Yeah?
Yeah, yeah, it's me. It's Lester.
Uh, she's... my wife, she's... oh, hell.
I think I...
She's in the basement dead and...
Look, I'm freaking out here.
I don't know what to do.
Lester, have you been a bad boy?
Jeez.
The hammer and... look, can you come over?
I'm on... I'm on Willow
Creek Drive, number 613.
Sure, Lester. I'll be right there.
I think that's him.
Oh, no.
Get after him! - Come on!
Stop!
It's not safe!
Hey, come back!
It's too dangerous!
Stop!
Solverson.
Are you sure?
Okay, well, let me know
what the divers turn up.
Take the money, right?
No, I say go for it.
What'd I miss?
The lady brought a list,
and dad's being a wuss again.
Oh, stop it.
Scooch over, you.
Hey, so I got a call today.
They're gonna give me a
citation for bravery.
You?
Come on, you're afraid of spiders.
Buzz Aldrin was afraid of spiders,
and he went into space.
Proud of you, hon.
They really should be giving it to you.
No.
No, this is your deal.
I get to be chief.