1
00:00:01,370 --> 00:00:02,859
Precedently on Fargo...

2
00:00:02,860 --> 00:00:03,860
Lester,

3
00:00:04,680 --> 00:00:06,710
is this what you want?

4
00:00:07,930 --> 00:00:08,720
Yes.

5
00:00:12,500 --> 00:00:14,040
See you later, Lester.

6
00:00:14,320 --> 00:00:16,019
Okay. Hon, get dressed.

7
00:00:16,020 --> 00:00:17,870
Lester, are you okay?

8
00:00:19,570 --> 00:00:21,869
Vegas PD's gonna send over some pictures

9
00:00:21,870 --> 00:00:23,569
from the hotel security camera,

10
00:00:23,570 --> 00:00:25,839
so don't leave town for a while.

11
00:00:25,840 --> 00:00:27,639
I may have some more questions.

12
00:00:27,640 --> 00:00:28,650
Ready to go?

13
00:00:28,680 --> 00:00:30,239
What? I thought we weren't gonna go.

14
00:00:30,240 --> 00:00:32,059
Acapulco, here we come.

15
00:00:32,060 --> 00:00:33,319
Do you think you could run in?

16
00:00:33,320 --> 00:00:34,619
The passports are in the safe.

17
00:00:34,620 --> 00:00:36,030
There's some cash in there too.

18
00:00:36,040 --> 00:00:37,710
It's cold out there.

19
00:00:38,350 --> 00:00:40,360
You're sweet.

20
00:03:43,870 --> 00:03:45,290
Is this what you want?

21
00:04:33,020 --> 00:04:34,040
Anywhere you like.

22
00:04:35,280 --> 00:04:36,060
Thanks.

23
00:04:36,910 --> 00:04:37,750
Just you?

24
00:04:37,810 --> 00:04:41,060
Uh, no, there's... it'll be two of us.

25
00:04:41,350 --> 00:04:45,170
Linda's just grabbing
something over by the shop.

26
00:04:45,270 --> 00:04:48,260
She dropped me off, said,
"Order the grilled cheese."

27
00:04:48,270 --> 00:04:50,340
So I guess two of those.

28
00:04:50,800 --> 00:04:51,880
And to drink?

29
00:04:52,620 --> 00:04:54,500
Beer would change things for the better.

30
00:04:54,880 --> 00:04:57,170
Eh, family place, I'm afraid.

31
00:04:57,360 --> 00:04:58,490
Oh, okay.

32
00:04:58,850 --> 00:05:00,529
Two ginger ales, then.

33
00:05:00,530 --> 00:05:02,860
And I'll... I'm gonna use the bathroom.

34
00:05:03,220 --> 00:05:04,980
- Free with the meal. - Right.

35
00:05:05,180 --> 00:05:07,050
Oh, hey, that's the, uh...

36
00:05:07,060 --> 00:05:08,310
Hey, how you doing?

37
00:05:08,320 --> 00:05:10,120
Oh, hi. How are you?

38
00:05:11,470 --> 00:05:13,139
Boy, he sure looks different.

39
00:05:13,140 --> 00:05:16,060
Yeah, really successful guy.

40
00:05:16,420 --> 00:05:17,630
Good for him.

41
00:05:36,290 --> 00:05:37,550
Bemidji police.

42
00:05:38,920 --> 00:05:41,539
Yeah, I'd like to report shots fired.

43
00:05:41,540 --> 00:05:43,700
Sir, this is a nonemergency number.

44
00:05:43,710 --> 00:05:44,959
You should've dialed 911.

45
00:05:44,960 --> 00:05:46,710
Over on Elk and 3rd.

46
00:05:47,110 --> 00:05:49,180
Gunshots, real loud,

47
00:05:49,190 --> 00:05:52,360
like, about ten seconds ago.

48
00:05:52,620 --> 00:05:54,939
Sounded like they come from
inside one of the shops.

49
00:05:54,940 --> 00:05:56,350
Okay, sir...

50
00:06:13,980 --> 00:06:15,169
Grilled cheese, coming right up.

51
00:06:15,170 --> 00:06:16,409
That's great. Thanks.

52
00:06:16,410 --> 00:06:17,770
Linda's just...

53
00:06:18,140 --> 00:06:19,179
Well, she dropped me off,

54
00:06:19,180 --> 00:06:20,690
grabbed something over at the shop,

55
00:06:20,700 --> 00:06:22,489
and said she had to pick something up.

56
00:06:22,490 --> 00:06:23,670
Yeah, you said that.

57
00:06:24,740 --> 00:06:26,219
Want me to keep hers
warm till she gets here?

58
00:06:26,220 --> 00:06:27,899
Oh, yeah, that's...

59
00:06:27,900 --> 00:06:31,660
Although, like I said, she
should be any second now.

60
00:06:33,190 --> 00:06:35,539
You know, there was a fella in here earlier

61
00:06:35,540 --> 00:06:36,720
asking about you.

62
00:06:37,710 --> 00:06:38,230
About me?

63
00:06:38,240 --> 00:06:41,550
Yeah, silver hair. Little goatee.

64
00:06:42,360 --> 00:06:43,329
Said he went by your old house,

65
00:06:43,330 --> 00:06:44,840
but you moved.

66
00:06:45,790 --> 00:06:48,099
Yeah. Well, we got the house up...

67
00:06:48,100 --> 00:06:49,829
What... what did you tell him?

68
00:06:49,830 --> 00:06:50,800
Said if he wanted to leave a number,

69
00:06:50,810 --> 00:06:52,059
I'd give it to you.

70
00:06:52,060 --> 00:06:53,759
He couldn't see his way clear to it,

71
00:06:53,760 --> 00:06:55,690
so we left it at that.

72
00:06:57,230 --> 00:06:59,230
Can't say I much liked his demeanor.

73
00:06:59,380 --> 00:07:02,260
Well, sorry for the bother.

74
00:07:02,280 --> 00:07:04,570
No bother. Thought you ought to know.

75
00:07:18,620 --> 00:07:20,630
We're going to Acapulco.

76
00:07:24,570 --> 00:07:25,960
Oh, my God.

77
00:07:34,040 --> 00:07:36,280
- Nothing good's gonna come out of that.
- Right.

78
00:07:43,290 --> 00:07:44,679
- $1,000 in your case. - I don't.

79
00:07:44,680 --> 00:07:45,679
- You want a million dollars in your case.
- I want a million.

80
00:07:45,680 --> 00:07:47,470
- It's all right. All right.
- One more case.

81
00:07:47,750 --> 00:07:49,370
- Three. - Three.

82
00:07:49,730 --> 00:07:51,090
Take the money, right?

83
00:07:51,430 --> 00:07:53,450
Forget that. I say go for it.

84
00:07:54,610 --> 00:07:56,470
- I'll get it. - No, I got it.

85
00:08:05,080 --> 00:08:06,130
Solverson.

86
00:08:08,750 --> 00:08:09,580
Wait, what?

87
00:08:13,240 --> 00:08:14,440
The other one now?

88
00:08:16,690 --> 00:08:17,670
Jeez.

89
00:08:18,260 --> 00:08:19,480
Well, where's Lester?

90
00:08:22,160 --> 00:08:24,280
Okay, put out an APB. I'm getting my coat.

91
00:08:26,910 --> 00:08:27,890
What's that now?

92
00:08:28,140 --> 00:08:30,410
Someone killed the second Mrs. Nygaard.

93
00:08:58,240 --> 00:08:59,810
Hey, you didn't have to come.

94
00:09:00,520 --> 00:09:02,400
Now, we both know that's not true.

95
00:09:03,650 --> 00:09:04,530
Okay.

96
00:09:13,610 --> 00:09:14,610
Poor thing.

97
00:09:15,740 --> 00:09:17,559
A head shot, I think.

98
00:09:17,560 --> 00:09:19,150
I didn't look too close.

99
00:09:19,160 --> 00:09:19,990
Yeah.

100
00:09:24,360 --> 00:09:25,800
She's wearing his coat.

101
00:09:26,690 --> 00:09:27,550
Meaning?

102
00:09:29,440 --> 00:09:31,909
Meaning maybe it's not Linda
supposed to be lying here.

103
00:09:31,910 --> 00:09:33,990
- Sir, you're not allowed in there.
- Let me through.

104
00:09:34,680 --> 00:09:36,230
- Oh, Lester. - Mr. Nygaard.

105
00:09:36,350 --> 00:09:37,139
Oh, jeez.

106
00:09:37,140 --> 00:09:39,290
- Yeah, yeah. Go over here.
- Let's get him to sit down.

107
00:09:39,300 --> 00:09:41,640
- Come on. - Oh, jeez. What?

108
00:09:42,950 --> 00:09:44,790
That's right. Go sit down.

109
00:09:45,230 --> 00:09:47,040
- Sit down. - Here we go. Sit.

110
00:09:47,130 --> 00:09:49,770
This is not happening.
This is not possible.

111
00:09:50,120 --> 00:09:52,740
Mr. Nygaard, I have to ask you
where you're coming from.

112
00:09:53,110 --> 00:09:55,990
I just... I was over waiting
at the restaurant,

113
00:09:56,000 --> 00:09:56,969
drinking ginger ale.

114
00:09:56,970 --> 00:09:59,570
Your dad was keeping her
grilled cheese warm,

115
00:09:59,660 --> 00:10:00,909
and I'm... I'm just waiting there.

116
00:10:00,910 --> 00:10:01,589
I can't understand.

117
00:10:01,590 --> 00:10:03,690
She said she had to pick some papers up.

118
00:10:03,980 --> 00:10:06,819
This is not possible.

119
00:10:06,820 --> 00:10:08,099
This is impossible.

120
00:10:08,100 --> 00:10:10,430
Lester, is there any way that...

121
00:10:11,630 --> 00:10:14,080
Do you think that this is
connected to Las Vegas,

122
00:10:14,210 --> 00:10:16,030
the murders we talked about earlier?

123
00:10:16,800 --> 00:10:18,000
What are you saying?

124
00:10:19,490 --> 00:10:21,630
A repercussion for what you saw maybe?

125
00:10:24,080 --> 00:10:26,209
She's wearing your coat, the wife.

126
00:10:26,210 --> 00:10:27,829
Molly saw that, so she's...

127
00:10:27,830 --> 00:10:30,190
What do you mean she's wearing my coat?
What does that mean?

128
00:10:30,520 --> 00:10:31,420
Well, she...

129
00:10:31,790 --> 00:10:33,740
Her coat got a rip, and so I...

130
00:10:34,780 --> 00:10:35,980
Oh, wait.

131
00:10:37,060 --> 00:10:37,980
You think...

132
00:10:42,690 --> 00:10:43,520
You're...

133
00:10:46,910 --> 00:10:49,289
I'm gonna be sick. I'm gonna be sick.

134
00:10:49,290 --> 00:10:51,499
No, Lester, if you throw
up, then I'm gonna.

135
00:10:51,500 --> 00:10:52,809
We got to get him out of here.

136
00:10:52,810 --> 00:10:54,889
Okay, Mr. Nygaard, we're gonna
take you down to the station now.

137
00:10:54,890 --> 00:10:55,979
Oh, god.

138
00:10:55,980 --> 00:10:57,780
They'll ask you a lot of questions...

139
00:10:58,730 --> 00:11:00,329
Time line, et cetera, okay?

140
00:11:00,330 --> 00:11:02,790
Yeah, whatever you think's best.

141
00:11:05,310 --> 00:11:07,959
Uh, wait, do you... do you think...

142
00:11:07,960 --> 00:11:11,120
Can I just say good-bye?

143
00:11:12,510 --> 00:11:13,899
Well, this is an active crime scene...

144
00:11:13,900 --> 00:11:15,189
Of course you can, Lester.

145
00:11:15,190 --> 00:11:17,200
Go ahead, and take your time.

146
00:11:54,120 --> 00:11:55,260
Mr. Nygaard.

147
00:11:56,520 --> 00:11:58,440
Can't have you touching the body, sir.

148
00:11:59,030 --> 00:11:59,800
I know.

149
00:12:01,160 --> 00:12:03,209
Of course not. I'm sorry.

150
00:12:03,210 --> 00:12:04,680
I-I'm just so...

151
00:12:04,780 --> 00:12:05,720
I understand.

152
00:12:07,920 --> 00:12:09,860
Come on. Come away now. Okay?

153
00:12:11,000 --> 00:12:12,700
That's right. Okay.

154
00:12:26,370 --> 00:12:27,720
612 to base.

155
00:12:28,290 --> 00:12:29,960
Chief says send the bus.

156
00:12:31,250 --> 00:12:33,460
Roger that, 612. I'll let 'em know.

157
00:12:36,500 --> 00:12:38,109
Base to emergency one.

158
00:12:38,110 --> 00:12:41,380
Chief says send the bus to 1381 Elk.

159
00:12:53,710 --> 00:12:56,119
613 to base. I'm inbound with the husband.

160
00:12:56,120 --> 00:12:57,520
We'll need interview one.

161
00:13:00,390 --> 00:13:02,050
Roger that, 613.

162
00:13:04,900 --> 00:13:06,190
613 to base.

163
00:13:06,430 --> 00:13:08,180
Yeah. Go ahead, Molly.

164
00:13:08,240 --> 00:13:10,530
Also, someone should wake those FBI boys.

165
00:13:10,650 --> 00:13:12,150
They're over at Leroy's.

166
00:13:12,250 --> 00:13:14,600
Tell 'em we got developments.

167
00:13:14,770 --> 00:13:16,390
They should meet me at the station.

168
00:13:18,030 --> 00:13:20,540
Roger that, 613. We'll scoop 'em up.

169
00:13:41,870 --> 00:13:43,239
We're awake, right?

170
00:13:43,240 --> 00:13:43,910
Who?

171
00:13:44,490 --> 00:13:45,370
Us.

172
00:13:48,550 --> 00:13:50,350
You're asking if we're awake?

173
00:13:51,340 --> 00:13:51,919
Me and you?

174
00:13:51,920 --> 00:13:53,300
Yeah, I was just...

175
00:13:53,440 --> 00:13:56,259
You know sometimes you're
in the middle of a dream...

176
00:13:56,260 --> 00:13:58,510
Do you say everything
that comes to your head?

177
00:14:02,600 --> 00:14:04,000
Got him in Interview One.

178
00:14:04,430 --> 00:14:05,859
Also, they just called from the scene.

179
00:14:05,860 --> 00:14:08,350
Looks like the wife had plane
tickets in her pocket.

180
00:14:08,410 --> 00:14:09,390
Mexico.

181
00:14:09,450 --> 00:14:11,490
Uh-oh. This could be a dream.

182
00:14:13,250 --> 00:14:14,240
What's he saying?

183
00:14:14,830 --> 00:14:18,390
Coroner's saying a single
shot from close-up.

184
00:14:18,750 --> 00:14:22,460
Said they found feathers
in her head from her hood.

185
00:14:23,410 --> 00:14:24,509
They were stuck in...

186
00:14:24,510 --> 00:14:26,480
So execution-style.

187
00:14:30,480 --> 00:14:31,679
Should've said something earlier.

188
00:14:31,680 --> 00:14:32,729
You heard what happened?

189
00:14:32,730 --> 00:14:35,219
More than heard. Saw the
prowlers scream by.

190
00:14:35,220 --> 00:14:37,809
Lester's sitting not 10 feet
away eating a grilled cheese.

191
00:14:37,810 --> 00:14:40,290
Any chance you can put an
exact time on his arrival?

192
00:14:40,970 --> 00:14:44,590
Not down to the minute,
but that's not why I'm...

193
00:14:45,360 --> 00:14:48,029
You remember you came by with
those FBI fellas earlier,

194
00:14:48,030 --> 00:14:49,600
and I was looking out the glass.

195
00:14:49,790 --> 00:14:51,149
With a peculiar look on your face?

196
00:14:51,150 --> 00:14:53,309
Yeah, well, there was a fella in

197
00:14:53,310 --> 00:14:54,970
just before you got there,

198
00:14:55,560 --> 00:14:57,160
and he was asking about Lester.

199
00:14:58,100 --> 00:14:59,329
- What? - Yeah.

200
00:14:59,330 --> 00:15:01,330
I'm a fool for not saying.

201
00:15:01,830 --> 00:15:04,869
He was maybe mid-50s, upscale-looking.

202
00:15:04,870 --> 00:15:07,500
Silver hair brushed back with a goatee.

203
00:15:07,600 --> 00:15:09,189
Drove a red BMW.

204
00:15:09,190 --> 00:15:10,120
This fella?

205
00:15:13,750 --> 00:15:15,600
Not unless he changed his whole...

206
00:15:17,760 --> 00:15:19,140
Although maybe.

207
00:15:21,090 --> 00:15:22,559
Drove a red BMW you said?

208
00:15:22,560 --> 00:15:23,410
Yeah.

209
00:15:24,470 --> 00:15:26,980
Oh, Molly, we're going in.

210
00:15:29,320 --> 00:15:31,080
Dad, I got to go.

211
00:15:31,870 --> 00:15:34,040
Well, there's two ways of looking at it.

212
00:15:34,890 --> 00:15:36,150
The first is, you got to.

213
00:15:37,720 --> 00:15:39,240
The second is, you don't.

214
00:15:44,690 --> 00:15:47,410
Will you call home for me?

215
00:15:49,280 --> 00:15:50,620
Let Gus know that...

216
00:15:53,330 --> 00:15:54,820
Tell him it's gonna be all night.

217
00:15:58,090 --> 00:15:59,200
Screw that.

218
00:15:59,590 --> 00:16:01,479
Getting my gun is what I'm doing.

219
00:16:01,480 --> 00:16:02,970
Go sit on the front porch.

220
00:16:03,250 --> 00:16:04,930
Make sure my granddaughter's safe.

221
00:16:07,310 --> 00:16:08,350
You're a good man.

222
00:16:58,680 --> 00:17:02,080
Lester, is this what you want?

223
00:17:02,780 --> 00:17:05,570
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!

224
00:17:10,540 --> 00:17:14,399
Is she... Bill, tell me she's
not still lying there

225
00:17:14,400 --> 00:17:16,799
and everyone's just stepping over her.

226
00:17:16,800 --> 00:17:20,300
Mr. Nygaard, these fellas are from the FBI.

227
00:17:23,560 --> 00:17:26,750
The wh... is this ab...

228
00:17:27,520 --> 00:17:29,499
Come on, I told you, I didn't see nothing.

229
00:17:29,500 --> 00:17:31,729
All I did was get on an elevator.

230
00:17:31,730 --> 00:17:33,309
We're not here about Las Vegas, sir.

231
00:17:33,310 --> 00:17:35,139
Well, we... we are, and we aren't.

232
00:17:35,140 --> 00:17:35,990
Okay.

233
00:17:37,050 --> 00:17:40,110
We're here about him.

234
00:17:41,440 --> 00:17:42,869
Based on the hustle of the deputy,

235
00:17:42,870 --> 00:17:44,020
we have a name for him:

236
00:17:44,700 --> 00:17:45,790
Lorne Malvo.

237
00:17:53,430 --> 00:17:54,100
Uh, Bill?

238
00:17:56,610 --> 00:17:57,870
Answer the question.

239
00:18:02,270 --> 00:18:05,219
Um, yeah, I'm now asking for a lawyer,

240
00:18:05,220 --> 00:18:06,150
just for the record.

241
00:18:09,330 --> 00:18:11,039
He's changed his look, hasn't he?

242
00:18:11,040 --> 00:18:12,469
I'm done answering your...

243
00:18:12,470 --> 00:18:15,829
You've obviously made up your mind

244
00:18:15,830 --> 00:18:18,300
that some kind of... and I'm... I'm...

245
00:18:18,650 --> 00:18:21,430
I'm not... my wife is dead!

246
00:18:22,800 --> 00:18:26,349
And there are arrangements to see to,

247
00:18:26,350 --> 00:18:29,540
so you can either lock me up or let me go.

248
00:18:32,110 --> 00:18:33,680
He's not gonna stop.

249
00:18:36,400 --> 00:18:37,790
You know that, right?

250
00:18:40,740 --> 00:18:41,980
A man like that...

251
00:18:43,430 --> 00:18:44,960
Maybe not even a man.

252
00:19:09,900 --> 00:19:10,680
Hey, there.

253
00:19:12,350 --> 00:19:13,230
What's going on?

254
00:19:13,960 --> 00:19:14,720
What do you mean?

255
00:19:15,540 --> 00:19:18,229
Well, I mean, it's 7:00 in the morning,

256
00:19:18,230 --> 00:19:19,539
and you're sitting on my front porch

257
00:19:19,540 --> 00:19:20,510
with a shotgun.

258
00:19:23,510 --> 00:19:27,430
There is some consensus this
Malvo fella may be back.

259
00:19:29,200 --> 00:19:30,070
Where's Molly?

260
00:19:31,190 --> 00:19:32,850
Left her at the precinct last night.

261
00:19:33,380 --> 00:19:35,310
Had Lester Nygaard in custody,

262
00:19:35,320 --> 00:19:36,450
about to talk to him.

263
00:19:38,460 --> 00:19:41,240
I'm going after her. Keep an eye on Greta.

264
00:19:41,900 --> 00:19:43,350
Believe me, I mean to.

265
00:19:48,730 --> 00:19:51,849
Okay, so the plan is, we fan out.

266
00:19:51,850 --> 00:19:54,320
Prowlers on all the main
roads looking for Malvo.

267
00:19:54,330 --> 00:19:56,080
Encircle the town, in other words.

268
00:19:56,870 --> 00:19:58,879
There's pic... yeah.

269
00:19:58,880 --> 00:20:00,799
Well, there are three main roads,

270
00:20:00,800 --> 00:20:04,090
So actually more of a triangle.

271
00:20:06,780 --> 00:20:08,729
There's photos of the
suspect in your packets.

272
00:20:08,730 --> 00:20:10,389
We hear he might have
changed his look, though,

273
00:20:10,390 --> 00:20:12,379
so silver hair now, brushed back,

274
00:20:12,380 --> 00:20:13,720
possibly a goatee.

275
00:20:14,520 --> 00:20:17,579
Drives a red BMW, possibly stolen.

276
00:20:17,580 --> 00:20:18,829
The FBI's sending a team,

277
00:20:18,830 --> 00:20:20,729
and in the meantime, the
two original agents

278
00:20:20,730 --> 00:20:22,560
are staking out Lester's house.

279
00:20:22,790 --> 00:20:24,729
Molly, Gus on one.

280
00:20:24,730 --> 00:20:25,470
Yeah.

281
00:20:25,820 --> 00:20:28,129
I'll be out there with you
coordinating maneuvers, so...

282
00:20:28,130 --> 00:20:29,770
pass those out for me. Thanks.

283
00:20:34,240 --> 00:20:36,190
- Yeah, hon? - Hey, I've been calling.

284
00:20:36,630 --> 00:20:38,539
Yeah, I know. Sorry, it's been...

285
00:20:38,540 --> 00:20:40,450
Is it true? Is he back?

286
00:20:40,810 --> 00:20:43,790
Yeah, I just... I just finished
briefing the guys, so...

287
00:20:44,640 --> 00:20:46,659
We tried to crack Lester,
but he wouldn't flinch,

288
00:20:46,660 --> 00:20:48,569
so the plan is, now we're
gonna use him as bait.

289
00:20:48,570 --> 00:20:49,280
Molly...

290
00:20:51,870 --> 00:20:54,329
Yeah, so things are... they're
real busy here, hon.

291
00:20:54,330 --> 00:20:55,190
Look, hon.

292
00:20:55,440 --> 00:20:56,909
Don't, okay?

293
00:20:56,910 --> 00:20:58,600
I got to ask you not to...

294
00:20:59,040 --> 00:21:00,219
don't go out there.

295
00:21:00,220 --> 00:21:02,469
You, personally, don't go looking for...

296
00:21:02,470 --> 00:21:03,700
It's my job.

297
00:21:04,100 --> 00:21:07,829
Yeah, I know, and you're
amazing and the best,

298
00:21:07,830 --> 00:21:09,879
and I have no doubt that if you wanted,

299
00:21:09,880 --> 00:21:11,579
you could handcuff Al Capone.

300
00:21:11,580 --> 00:21:14,279
But some days, sometimes you get forces

301
00:21:14,280 --> 00:21:15,470
you can't control.

302
00:21:15,960 --> 00:21:17,230
Bad luck, you know?

303
00:21:17,960 --> 00:21:18,889
Bad luck.

304
00:21:18,890 --> 00:21:20,220
Yeah, and this is all...

305
00:21:21,190 --> 00:21:23,960
If it really is him, Malvo,

306
00:21:23,970 --> 00:21:24,710
I just...

307
00:21:26,810 --> 00:21:28,959
with everything we've been
working for, you know,

308
00:21:28,960 --> 00:21:30,239
our family, and...

309
00:21:30,240 --> 00:21:30,789
Gus.

310
00:21:30,790 --> 00:21:32,690
And I know it's not fair.

311
00:21:33,130 --> 00:21:34,130
It's not.

312
00:21:34,460 --> 00:21:36,799
It's your job, and I am just a mailman,

313
00:21:36,800 --> 00:21:39,869
but you've got a precinct full of cops,

314
00:21:39,870 --> 00:21:41,810
and the FBI is there, so I just...

315
00:21:43,840 --> 00:21:46,719
Bottom line, I can't make
her go to another funeral,

316
00:21:46,720 --> 00:21:47,490
you know?

317
00:21:50,760 --> 00:21:51,490
Yeah.

318
00:21:53,880 --> 00:21:56,260
Okay, don't worry. I'll just...

319
00:21:58,840 --> 00:22:00,260
yeah, I'll run things from here.

320
00:22:00,720 --> 00:22:03,580
Okay, good. Good.

321
00:22:04,630 --> 00:22:06,539
I'm in the car, coming over.

322
00:22:06,540 --> 00:22:08,240
No, don't. That's not...

323
00:22:09,360 --> 00:22:10,530
No, just go home.

324
00:22:11,870 --> 00:22:12,790
Be with our girl.

325
00:22:14,660 --> 00:22:15,869
Hey, is my dad there?

326
00:22:15,870 --> 00:22:18,960
Yeah, yeah, he's on the
porch with a shotgun.

327
00:22:21,810 --> 00:22:23,670
Got to love a man who
keeps his word, right?

328
00:22:24,190 --> 00:22:25,220
So you promise?

329
00:22:26,350 --> 00:22:28,949
Yeah, I won't leave the building

330
00:22:28,950 --> 00:22:31,150
until they call and tell
me he's surrounded.

331
00:22:31,470 --> 00:22:33,920
No, until he's dead.

332
00:22:34,780 --> 00:22:36,220
I'll call you in a little bit, okay?

333
00:26:04,510 --> 00:26:05,720
So it's decided.

334
00:26:06,010 --> 00:26:07,729
FBI fella's gonna call for backup.

335
00:26:07,730 --> 00:26:09,419
We're gonna take Lester
home, sit on the house,

336
00:26:09,420 --> 00:26:11,370
see if we can't draw this Malvo fella out.

337
00:26:14,440 --> 00:26:15,350
You okay, Chief?

338
00:26:18,280 --> 00:26:19,830
Hanging it up after this.

339
00:26:21,270 --> 00:26:22,030
What's that?

340
00:26:24,040 --> 00:26:26,210
I quit, is what I'm saying.

341
00:26:27,000 --> 00:26:28,530
Don't got the stomach for it,

342
00:26:29,240 --> 00:26:30,190
not like some.

343
00:26:33,410 --> 00:26:37,450
Wearing the badge, seeing the
lengths people are capable of,

344
00:26:38,100 --> 00:26:39,460
the inhumanity.

345
00:26:42,870 --> 00:26:45,919
What ever happened to saying
good morning to your neighbors

346
00:26:45,920 --> 00:26:47,869
and shoveling their walk

347
00:26:47,870 --> 00:26:50,850
and bringing in each other's toters?

348
00:26:51,840 --> 00:26:54,500
Well, still goes on.

349
00:26:55,610 --> 00:26:58,820
Yeah, but not the same.

350
00:27:00,580 --> 00:27:03,189
I used to have positive
opinions about the world,

351
00:27:03,190 --> 00:27:04,460
you know, about people.

352
00:27:05,200 --> 00:27:06,760
Used to think the best.

353
00:27:07,470 --> 00:27:09,990
Now I'm looking over my shoulder.

354
00:27:10,680 --> 00:27:12,329
An unquiet mind,

355
00:27:12,330 --> 00:27:13,740
that's what the wife calls it.

356
00:27:16,290 --> 00:27:19,520
The job has got me staring
into the fireplace,

357
00:27:20,490 --> 00:27:21,310
drinking.

358
00:27:22,750 --> 00:27:24,269
I never wanted to be the type

359
00:27:24,270 --> 00:27:28,960
to think big thoughts about
the nature of things and...

360
00:27:30,760 --> 00:27:32,410
All I ever wanted was

361
00:27:32,900 --> 00:27:34,940
a stack of pancakes and a V8.

362
00:27:38,190 --> 00:27:41,300
So I'm recommending that
you take over as chief.

363
00:27:43,510 --> 00:27:46,309
Oh, I-I appreciate that, but I...

364
00:27:46,310 --> 00:27:48,910
No, no, you're the real deal.

365
00:27:49,570 --> 00:27:52,080
You got the instincts and the disposition.

366
00:27:52,090 --> 00:27:54,270
I didn't see it before, but now...

367
00:27:54,970 --> 00:27:57,090
and Vern saw it. I know that.

368
00:27:57,870 --> 00:28:00,829
And so I'm hoping that
after you have the baby,

369
00:28:00,830 --> 00:28:04,600
you come back here and take things over.

370
00:28:06,170 --> 00:28:08,770
I-I will think about that.

371
00:28:09,660 --> 00:28:10,440
I will.

372
00:28:12,700 --> 00:28:14,050
Got to talk to Gus, so...

373
00:28:20,160 --> 00:28:22,930
So you're okay with the plan then,

374
00:28:24,910 --> 00:28:27,410
call in the cavalry and set a trap?

375
00:28:29,250 --> 00:28:32,479
Yeah, we're a small-time force.

376
00:28:32,480 --> 00:28:34,170
We're not equipped for, you know,

377
00:28:34,800 --> 00:28:36,259
urban warfare.

378
00:28:36,260 --> 00:28:38,880
Most of these guys can't
shoot a can off a fence.

379
00:28:42,350 --> 00:28:43,120
Okay.

380
00:28:46,730 --> 00:28:47,670
Chin up, chief.

381
00:29:11,210 --> 00:29:11,940
Police.

382
00:29:12,580 --> 00:29:15,810
Yes, this is FBI main. I'm
looking for my agents.

383
00:29:16,130 --> 00:29:19,019
Yeah, they're with a suspect.

384
00:29:19,020 --> 00:29:20,209
I could interrupt.

385
00:29:20,210 --> 00:29:21,680
You want Pepper or Budge?

386
00:29:23,670 --> 00:29:25,879
Uh, negatory. Don't interrupt.

387
00:29:25,880 --> 00:29:28,180
Just tell 'em to call
home when they're done.

388
00:29:43,180 --> 00:29:44,050
FBI.

389
00:29:44,750 --> 00:29:45,929
Operations.

390
00:29:45,930 --> 00:29:46,979
Pass code.

391
00:29:46,980 --> 00:29:49,049
61αθ9
6-1, alpha, theta, 9.

392
00:29:49,050 --> 00:29:49,930
Transferring.

393
00:29:52,060 --> 00:29:53,049
Operations.

394
00:29:53,050 --> 00:29:55,360
Uh, yes, this is Agent Budge.

395
00:29:56,070 --> 00:29:57,249
We've hit a dead end out here,

396
00:29:57,250 --> 00:29:58,900
so we're gonna be heading back.

397
00:29:59,240 --> 00:30:00,079
Say again.

398
00:30:00,080 --> 00:30:01,590
Dead end. Heading back.

399
00:30:01,990 --> 00:30:04,780
Hold on, didn't you just
call looking for backup?

400
00:30:05,200 --> 00:30:06,289
Uh, yeah, my partner...

401
00:30:06,290 --> 00:30:07,719
He kind of jumped the gun on that one,

402
00:30:07,720 --> 00:30:09,780
but looks like local pd
has it under control,

403
00:30:09,790 --> 00:30:11,589
so we're gonna just pack and blow.

404
00:30:11,590 --> 00:30:13,590
Whatever. Get your shit straight.

405
00:30:13,940 --> 00:30:15,040
Cancelling backup.

406
00:30:46,440 --> 00:30:47,230
Help you, sir?

407
00:30:48,490 --> 00:30:50,360
I hope so. I got my eye on this one.

408
00:30:51,250 --> 00:30:52,880
She's a beaut. That's for sure.

409
00:30:53,340 --> 00:30:56,420
V8 engine, only 22,000 miles on her.

410
00:30:57,610 --> 00:31:00,339
I like it 'cause it looks
like an undercover vehicle,

411
00:31:00,340 --> 00:31:01,780
like an FBI car.

412
00:31:03,180 --> 00:31:04,960
Well, sir, I guess she does.

413
00:31:06,000 --> 00:31:07,180
Never thought about it.

414
00:31:08,870 --> 00:31:10,720
You even got the long antenna on the back.

415
00:31:12,620 --> 00:31:14,180
Mind if we take a test-drive?

416
00:31:15,470 --> 00:31:18,820
We... well, we're not officially open yet.

417
00:31:21,430 --> 00:31:23,800
But I don't see why not. Hold on.
I'll grab the keys.

418
00:31:39,570 --> 00:31:40,280
Shotgun.

419
00:31:58,910 --> 00:31:59,700
Okay.

420
00:32:00,640 --> 00:32:01,800
So we're letting you go.

421
00:32:02,880 --> 00:32:03,800
About time.

422
00:32:04,870 --> 00:32:06,609
Yeah, and so the FBI fellas

423
00:32:06,610 --> 00:32:08,150
are gonna drive you home.

424
00:32:09,580 --> 00:32:11,480
Not necessary. I can call a cab.

425
00:32:12,740 --> 00:32:13,979
Yeah, well, like I said,

426
00:32:13,980 --> 00:32:16,019
we're letting you go, but at the same time,

427
00:32:16,020 --> 00:32:18,409
a wanted fugitive has been spotted in town,

428
00:32:18,410 --> 00:32:20,270
and we think he's got
intentions towards you,

429
00:32:20,280 --> 00:32:23,840
so ride home's not really optional.

430
00:32:25,160 --> 00:32:26,830
Well, they're not coming in the house.

431
00:32:28,900 --> 00:32:30,629
Sure, okay, we can play it that way,

432
00:32:30,630 --> 00:32:33,000
but they're still gonna
stick around for a while,

433
00:32:33,870 --> 00:32:35,010
keep an eye on things.

434
00:32:43,070 --> 00:32:44,749
You know, I'm not sure what it is

435
00:32:44,750 --> 00:32:46,910
that you've had against me since day one,

436
00:32:46,990 --> 00:32:52,679
but I am not the person you think I am,

437
00:32:52,680 --> 00:32:54,820
this... this kind of monster.

438
00:32:59,140 --> 00:33:02,600
There was a fella once running for a train,

439
00:33:03,690 --> 00:33:06,080
and he's carrying a pair
of gloves, this man.

440
00:33:06,250 --> 00:33:08,379
He drops a glove on the platform,

441
00:33:08,380 --> 00:33:09,520
but he doesn't notice.

442
00:33:10,660 --> 00:33:14,039
And then later on, inside the train,

443
00:33:14,040 --> 00:33:16,030
he's sitting by the window, and he realizes

444
00:33:16,440 --> 00:33:18,460
that he's just got this one glove left.

445
00:33:19,700 --> 00:33:21,300
But the train's already started

446
00:33:21,310 --> 00:33:23,300
pulling out of the station, right?

447
00:33:25,160 --> 00:33:26,180
So what does he do?

448
00:33:27,540 --> 00:33:28,730
He opens the window,

449
00:33:30,990 --> 00:33:33,180
and he drops the other
glove onto the platform.

450
00:33:34,900 --> 00:33:37,600
That way, whoever finds the first glove

451
00:33:39,380 --> 00:33:40,550
can just have the pair.

452
00:33:45,240 --> 00:33:46,670
So what are you telling me?

453
00:33:49,340 --> 00:33:50,710
Good-bye, Mr. Nygaard.

454
00:34:00,220 --> 00:34:01,380
Good-bye, deputy.

455
00:35:03,110 --> 00:35:04,600
I didn't do this, you know.

456
00:35:06,600 --> 00:35:07,550
Any of it.

457
00:35:09,590 --> 00:35:11,140
That deputy... boy.

458
00:35:12,220 --> 00:35:13,450
She's got a thing for me.

459
00:35:22,460 --> 00:35:24,370
- So, Lester, say you had a boat. - No.

460
00:35:24,560 --> 00:35:27,269
Say you've got a boat,
and you've got a fox,

461
00:35:27,270 --> 00:35:28,990
a rabbit, and a cabbage.

462
00:35:29,320 --> 00:35:30,959
Now, you can only row

463
00:35:30,960 --> 00:35:32,850
one of them across the river at a time.

464
00:35:32,930 --> 00:35:34,370
Now, you can take the cabbage,

465
00:35:34,510 --> 00:35:36,520
but then the fox would eat the rabbit.

466
00:35:36,810 --> 00:35:38,399
Or you can take the fox,

467
00:35:38,400 --> 00:35:39,759
but the rabbit would eat the cabbage.

468
00:35:39,760 --> 00:35:41,659
- What are you asking...
- Same thing on the other side.

469
00:35:41,660 --> 00:35:43,690
You could leave the rabbit there alone,

470
00:35:44,030 --> 00:35:48,080
but what happens when
you bring the fox over

471
00:35:48,490 --> 00:35:49,329
and go back for the cabbage?

472
00:35:49,330 --> 00:35:50,240
Forget it.

473
00:35:50,770 --> 00:35:52,660
My partner doesn't know
what he's talking about.

474
00:35:54,670 --> 00:35:56,890
I already told you, just
eat all three of them.

475
00:35:56,900 --> 00:35:59,780
Can I only row them
across in one direction?

476
00:35:59,790 --> 00:36:00,940
No, no, either way.

477
00:36:04,250 --> 00:36:08,620
Well, then you row the rabbit across,

478
00:36:08,730 --> 00:36:11,160
and the fox won't eat the cabbage.

479
00:36:12,180 --> 00:36:14,220
Then you go back for the fox,

480
00:36:14,870 --> 00:36:17,260
and when you drop him off,

481
00:36:17,710 --> 00:36:20,249
put the rabbit back in the
boat and go get the cabbage.

482
00:36:20,250 --> 00:36:23,709
Only this time, you leave
the rabbit behind,

483
00:36:23,710 --> 00:36:27,019
and then you row the cabbage back across.

484
00:36:27,020 --> 00:36:29,320
Again, the fox will not eat the cabbage,

485
00:36:29,690 --> 00:36:34,020
and then you go back for the rabbit.

486
00:36:38,120 --> 00:36:39,070
That's it.

487
00:36:40,160 --> 00:36:41,310
See, that wasn't so hard.

488
00:37:18,660 --> 00:37:20,409
We feel we need to say again

489
00:37:20,410 --> 00:37:21,999
that your life may be in danger.

490
00:37:22,000 --> 00:37:23,260
Like, a lot of danger,

491
00:37:23,760 --> 00:37:25,510
So we're gonna sit right here for a bit,

492
00:37:26,210 --> 00:37:27,370
keep an eye on things.

493
00:37:28,550 --> 00:37:29,660
Free country, isn't it?

494
00:38:39,870 --> 00:38:41,290
Thanks.

495
00:38:47,340 --> 00:38:50,430
You were police once, Molly says.

496
00:38:50,680 --> 00:38:52,780
State cop, 18 years.

497
00:38:54,580 --> 00:38:56,510
Took a bullet in the hip on a traffic stop.

498
00:38:57,240 --> 00:38:58,610
Retired, full pension.

499
00:39:00,990 --> 00:39:02,290
You ever do this before,

500
00:39:03,270 --> 00:39:04,250
stand guard?

501
00:39:06,090 --> 00:39:09,120
One other time, winter of 1979.

502
00:39:10,450 --> 00:39:11,820
-4 degrees.

503
00:39:13,550 --> 00:39:15,610
Sat on a dark porch from dusk till dawn.

504
00:39:17,200 --> 00:39:19,070
Your stepmom was inside sleeping.

505
00:39:20,050 --> 00:39:21,120
Four years old.

506
00:39:23,540 --> 00:39:24,830
Who did you think was coming?

507
00:39:26,540 --> 00:39:28,160
It wasn't a question of who,

508
00:39:29,510 --> 00:39:30,770
more like what.

509
00:39:32,040 --> 00:39:32,880
Did it come?

510
00:39:36,010 --> 00:39:37,050
Not that night,

511
00:39:38,330 --> 00:39:39,430
but soon after.

512
00:40:06,640 --> 00:40:08,160
What are you planning to do with that?

513
00:40:09,440 --> 00:40:12,180
If he comes, I'll put his eye out.

514
00:40:13,260 --> 00:40:14,450
You can finish him off.

515
00:40:16,730 --> 00:40:17,650
That's my girl.

516
00:40:24,330 --> 00:40:26,460
Yeah, so car 18, checking in.

517
00:40:26,790 --> 00:40:28,040
Over on Bear Patch.

518
00:40:28,470 --> 00:40:29,570
Pretty quiet, huh?

519
00:40:31,410 --> 00:40:33,340
Okay, team, keep your eyes peeled. Over.

520
00:40:38,180 --> 00:40:39,440
Hey, car 6, anything?

521
00:40:40,200 --> 00:40:43,120
Oh, hey. This is car 6 out on 71.

522
00:40:43,350 --> 00:40:45,550
I had a pickup with an unsecured load.

523
00:40:46,190 --> 00:40:47,450
All quiet otherwise.

524
00:40:49,870 --> 00:40:51,450
Yeah, roger that, 6.

525
00:40:52,880 --> 00:40:54,050
Keep me posted, okay?

526
00:41:10,950 --> 00:41:12,850
I'm gonna run over to Lester's,

527
00:41:13,200 --> 00:41:15,419
but give a shout when
the other FBI rolls up.

528
00:41:15,420 --> 00:41:16,610
You think it's safe?

529
00:41:18,980 --> 00:41:20,530
For me, I'm saying.

530
00:41:21,310 --> 00:41:22,140
Here.

531
00:41:23,150 --> 00:41:24,420
With that fella out there.

532
00:41:25,190 --> 00:41:26,820
I mean, everyone else is gone.

533
00:41:29,130 --> 00:41:30,350
Yeah, maybe lock the door.

534
00:41:51,490 --> 00:41:52,980
You still think this is a dream?

535
00:41:53,650 --> 00:41:54,460
What?

536
00:41:54,790 --> 00:41:57,470
This. Today.

537
00:41:57,900 --> 00:41:58,590
No.

538
00:42:01,710 --> 00:42:03,560
What if my whole life has been a dream?

539
00:42:05,590 --> 00:42:07,110
Yeah, but whose dream is it?

540
00:42:12,680 --> 00:42:13,580
Heads up.

541
00:42:26,200 --> 00:42:27,170
What do you think?

542
00:42:31,200 --> 00:42:32,410
Could be our backup.

543
00:42:41,520 --> 00:42:43,460
FBI. Step out of the car!

544
00:42:51,500 --> 00:42:53,150
Out of the car, now!

545
00:43:08,780 --> 00:43:10,170
Let me see your hands!

546
00:43:19,810 --> 00:43:20,890
His hands are taped.

547
00:43:22,150 --> 00:43:22,980
I'm sorry.

548
00:43:24,540 --> 00:43:25,530
This is a dream.

549
00:43:48,050 --> 00:43:48,820
Please.

550
00:43:50,700 --> 00:43:51,850
I got a little girl.

551
00:44:16,940 --> 00:44:18,000
Gosh.

552
00:45:24,840 --> 00:45:25,710
Police.

553
00:45:26,200 --> 00:45:28,180
Yeah, I need the police, please.

554
00:45:28,750 --> 00:45:30,310
Yes, it's an emergency.

555
00:45:35,460 --> 00:45:36,779
Uh, this is Lester Nygaard.

556
00:45:36,780 --> 00:45:39,250
You got to... I think the f...

557
00:45:39,490 --> 00:45:40,900
You need to send somebody.

558
00:45:46,100 --> 00:45:48,860
I need help now. I need you to come.

559
00:45:48,890 --> 00:45:49,710
Please.

560
00:45:51,510 --> 00:45:53,590
My... Les... Lester Nygaard.

561
00:45:55,690 --> 00:45:57,940
Please just hurry up.

562
00:45:59,230 --> 00:46:02,020
I'm upstairs in the bathroom.
There's no lock on the door.

563
00:46:04,100 --> 00:46:06,250
Oh, god. You've gotta hurry.

564
00:46:20,410 --> 00:46:21,690
Oh, shit.

565
00:49:57,960 --> 00:49:59,060
God damn it.

566
00:51:45,560 --> 00:51:46,800
I figured it out.

567
00:51:48,450 --> 00:51:49,620
Good for you.

568
00:51:52,980 --> 00:51:55,059
Your riddle... shades of green.

569
00:51:55,060 --> 00:51:56,370
I figured it out.

570
00:52:03,890 --> 00:52:04,950
And?

571
00:55:07,780 --> 00:55:08,710
Open it.

572
00:55:48,620 --> 00:55:49,229
Yeah?

573
00:55:49,230 --> 00:55:51,690
Yeah, yeah, it's me. It's Lester.

574
00:55:52,640 --> 00:55:56,900
Uh, she's... my wife, she's... oh, hell.

575
00:55:58,840 --> 00:55:59,970
I think I...

576
00:56:01,250 --> 00:56:03,410
She's in the basement dead and...

577
00:56:03,460 --> 00:56:05,069
Look, I'm freaking out here.

578
00:56:05,070 --> 00:56:06,240
I don't know what to do.

579
00:56:07,810 --> 00:56:09,880
Lester, have you been a bad boy?

580
00:56:11,930 --> 00:56:12,840
Jeez.

581
00:56:15,930 --> 00:56:19,079
The hammer and... look, can you come over?

582
00:56:19,080 --> 00:56:22,010
I'm on... I'm on Willow
Creek Drive, number 613.

583
00:56:23,640 --> 00:56:25,530
Sure, Lester. I'll be right there.

584
00:56:57,820 --> 00:56:58,910
I think that's him.

585
00:57:00,610 --> 00:57:01,530
Oh, no.

586
00:57:04,500 --> 00:57:06,250
Get after him! - Come on!

587
00:57:56,170 --> 00:57:57,200
Stop!

588
00:57:58,190 --> 00:57:59,920
It's not safe!

589
00:58:02,670 --> 00:58:04,300
Hey, come back!

590
00:58:04,450 --> 00:58:06,240
It's too dangerous!

591
00:58:09,730 --> 00:58:11,070
Stop!

592
00:59:12,580 --> 00:59:13,520
Solverson.

593
00:59:17,780 --> 00:59:18,740
Are you sure?

594
00:59:23,630 --> 00:59:27,140
Okay, well, let me know
what the divers turn up.

595
00:59:48,060 --> 00:59:49,420
Take the money, right?

596
00:59:49,990 --> 00:59:51,450
No, I say go for it.

597
00:59:51,990 --> 00:59:53,000
What'd I miss?

598
00:59:53,330 --> 00:59:54,659
The lady brought a list,

599
00:59:54,660 --> 00:59:57,260
and dad's being a wuss again.

600
00:59:57,310 --> 00:59:58,789
Oh, stop it.

601
00:59:58,790 --> 01:00:00,180
Scooch over, you.

602
01:00:19,340 --> 01:00:22,560
Hey, so I got a call today.

603
01:00:23,140 --> 01:00:26,520
They're gonna give me a
citation for bravery.

604
01:00:27,310 --> 01:00:28,230
You?

605
01:00:28,930 --> 01:00:30,780
Come on, you're afraid of spiders.

606
01:00:33,890 --> 01:00:35,689
Buzz Aldrin was afraid of spiders,

607
01:00:35,690 --> 01:00:37,280
and he went into space.

608
01:00:50,610 --> 01:00:51,790
Proud of you, hon.

609
01:00:55,180 --> 01:00:57,200
They really should be giving it to you.

610
01:00:58,830 --> 01:00:59,790
No.

611
01:01:02,870 --> 01:01:04,440
No, this is your deal.

612
01:01:07,340 --> 01:01:08,820
I get to be chief.

