♪ Oh I'll twine with my mingles
and waving black hair ♪
♪ with the roses so red
and the lilies so fair ♪
♪ and the myrtle so bright
with the emerald dew ♪
♪ the pale and the leader
and eyes look like blue ♪
Um, why "Irregular"?
Well, they put a ladies' sock
in with the gents'.
Which one's which?
- It's unclear.
- Ah.
Eh, I'll roll the dice.
Uh, how much?
You tell me.
Say again?
The sign says "Best Offer."
What are you offering?
Well, I mean, uh...
Eh, what's fair?
Well, that's not for me to say.
It's three pairs of socks,
half of them ladies'.
Probably not a million dollars.
Uh...
Right.
Well, I don't want
to take advantage.
2 bucks.
Or if that's, uh...
3 bucks?
5.
Tell you what, you give me $55,
I'll give you the socks...
and throw in this 12-Gauge.
Thought you were getting socks.
In the bag.
What the heck are you
gonna do with that?
It's for protection.
Just be careful you don't
blow your own face off.
Not loaded, is it?
Well, if anyone could shoot
theirselves in the face
with an unloaded firearm,
it's you.
Lester!
Yeah!
I...
Ahh...
Yeah?
My wife... she's in the basement, dead.
And, uh, I'm freaking out here.
I don't know what to do.
Lester, have
you been a bad boy?
Ah! Jeez. Yeah.
Can you come over?
What did you do?
You killed her.
Evening, Lester.
What... what do you want?
Well, I suppose
first, I'd like to come in.
Is Pearl home?
Ah, no, no,
she's at my brother's.
Lester, listen
to me very carefully.
I need you to get down
on the ground.
Okay, now, wait...
wait just a second.
Lester, on the ground.
This is not what it looks like.
Look, I'm sorry...
about...
electrocuting you.
I was just...
This is obviously...
a misunderstanding.
'Cause like... like I said,
I'm just an insurance salesman.
Now, that is not...
I got noth...
The stuff that you're mixed up in...
Not... not that you're...
I'm just say... Well...
So you... you see?
- You said "Him."
- What?
On the ice... you said "Him."
You said it was him.
Not you.
Him.
Mm, yeah.
Well... well, I'm... I'm just
guessing here,
but, uh, well, that Hess
was not head-stabbed by a girl.
No, no.
No, you said it
like you had a face in mind.
Uh-uh.
No, wait.
Uh...
Stay with me.
Lester.
- Oh, God, please. Please.
- Stay with me.
- I need a name.
- Uh... huh.
I need a name.
- Again.
- No, wait! Please!
Wait.
God.
- Lester.
- No!
Malvo! Malvo.
Malvo?
Is that a first name?
Gaahh...
- Lester.
- Hmm?
Eventually you just swallow your
tongue and you die like a fish.
Lorne, I think.
It's Lorne, like the fella
from Bonanza.
Lorne Malvo?
Where is he?
I'm gonna throw up.
No. No, you're not.
If you puke in here,
I'll kill you.
- I mean, I'll actually kill you, okay?
- Okay.
- Lester.
- Mm-hmm.
I need a location.
Okay...
He took...
he took my car.
They called me, told me
it was impounded in Duluth.
So he's probably...
I got a picture...
There's a picture of him.
Picture of him up here.
Law enforcement, he had it.
It's from the...
what do you call it? An APB. So...
What?
Lorne Malvo?
- Yeah?
- Mm.
- He killed him.
- He killed Hess.
I-I mean...
Okay.
You two are free to go.
Bail's been paid.
Oh, God.
What if we wanna stay?
Pardon?
I don't know, I mean,
what if we like it here?
Yeah.
That's a good one. On your feet.
You have any doubt
we can find you?
No.
Hey, buddy, you might
wanna have a doctor
look at that hand, though.
Looks like it smarts.
Are some of the
largest snakes found in the world.
Any members
of that python family
are ambush predators.
They remain motionless
before they strike.
It's not common
for them to attack humans
unless, of course,
they're starving.
Now, advancements
in the technological arena
allow us to examine their
existence in the Everglades.
Oh, look ahead, there, there...
No way around it.
- I said, "More sand."
- Back then?
Yeah. Wild goose chase.
Salt's okay.
Hang on. Frank calling.
Well, Chief, there've been some interesting
developments while you were...
Chief, Frank on the line.
New storm data.
Yeah, Frank, what you got then?
This case is, uh, really...
it's heating up.
That much, huh? Jeez.
Saying 2 feet new accumulation.
So, uh, we got the phone dump
back from Lester's
from the night of the murders.
Okay, thanks much.
You too.
Call Hoenecker with State, see
if we can get some more plows,
and, uh, make sure
they're plowing
the Chief's drive
every few hours.
Can't have Ida going into labor
under a snowbound scenario.
Okay. Yah.
Now, what's all this?
I was saying we got
the phone dump back.
And right around
the time Pearl died,
an outgoing call
was placed from Lester's
to Leroy's Motor Inn,
so I made a call.
No one asked you to...
I know, but you were in Duluth,
so I figured...
- Left Knutson in charge.
- Right.
So I made a call, and get this.
Lorraine, the manager...
- Lorraine Abbey.
- Yeah. Yah.
Uh, no, sir, Lorraine Babbit.
Curly hair, looks like she dries
her eyebrows on with a sharpie.
No, sir, this is a severe woman
with hard hair.
Anyway, she IDs a photo
of the suspect
from the naked fella
kidnapping.
Says he stayed one night,
that being the night
Hess was killed.
She got a name for him too.
Lorne Malvo.
And you found this how?
Like I said,
call was placed
from Lester's house
to the motel where
the suspect was staying.
So I talk to housekeeping,
and they say this Malvo fella
left behind some tokens
from The Lucky Penny.
They wanna know how many plows.
At least three, don't ya think?
At least three.
Yeah, he says he can
give you two good ones
and a pickup with baby plow.
Sir.
Yeah, I'm listening.
Okay, good.
So I go and talk to the lady
that Hess was with,
the dancer, right?
- And she says that before
he was stabbed... - Hold on.
Hess was laughing about
this fella that he bullied.
Broke the poor guy's nose,
she said.
The same day.
Chief, is that a yes
on the baby plow?
So right away I'm thinking,
who do we know
who got his nose broke
- the day Hess died?
- No.
- Lester.
- Wait.
- Chief.
- So you see,
Hess breaks Lester's nose.
Lester goes to the Emergency Room,
where he meets our suspect.
That night, Hess gets killed.
The next day, Lester
places a call to the motel
where our suspect is staying,
and shortly thereafter
or abouts,
Mrs. Nygaard
and the Chief are murdered.
Chief.
Yeah. Tell him
I'll call him back.
He's gotta call ya back.
Son of a bitch.
Yes, sir.
So I'm thinking maybe this is
a murder-for-hire
type deal, right?
Where Lester hires this Malvo
fella to kill Hess,
only maybe Lester don't got
the money to pay,
so things get sour.
Listen,
I know it's not my case,
but I'd like your permission
to go back to Lester's house
and see what he has to say.
Not at his house.
Okay.
His work then.
No, I'm saying
he's not at his house.
He's in a holding cell.
Knutson says Lester
took a swing at him.
I'm not sure
if he was drunk or what.
He's in custody?
I told Dougie
to keep him overnight.
You know, let him sleep it off.
Well...
I mean, we gotta talk to him,
don't ya think?
I guess we'd better.
I need to use your computer.
Yeah.
It's on the front.
Uh, computers at the precinct
have it on the back.
Here, let me.
What do ya need?
There's a pastor up in Baudette,
name of Frank Peterson.
A few hits.
A church website, um,
some stuff from the local paper.
There anything with a picture?
Uffda.
What's this for?
A case.
You said there were
other news stories.
Nothing with a picture.
Church fundraiser.
Um, new roof.
That kind of thing.
Check for, uh, uh, Lorne Malvo.
C-could you check, uh...
Nothing.
Okay.
He steals a car,
I pull him over,
he drives away,
car's impounded,
and he stays in Duluth.
He stays in Duluth.
I stop him on the street.
On that street.
On foot.
He was on that street on foot.
Come in, Greta. Over.
Why was he on
that street on foot?
Dad?
- Do you wanna...
- Greta. Come in, Greta.
Oh, yeah, right.
Okay. It's almost bedtime.
And, hey, I may go out
for a bit.
Okay. Come in. Over.
Back for more, huh?
I need a police scanner.
Got a special on
remote control helicopters.
Can you monitor
police activity on it?
Doubt it.
I'll just stick
with the scanner.
Okay.
I got handheld
or dashboard mountable.
Oh, also...
got this one in pink.
Do I look like I want
a pink police scanner?
I don't know.
Could be a gift for a lady.
And in your experience,
uh, police scanners?
Is that a gift
ladies get wet for?
Had an aunt once,
owned a riot shield.
Made her own jerky.
I'll just stick with the black.
'Kay.
Anything else?
Yeah, I need
a walkie-talkie.
Yeah...
'fraid I can't just
sell you one, stretch.
See, they come in pairs.
You know, so you can
chat with a friend.
I don't have any friends.
That's a sad story.
I still gotta sell ya two.
Hey, maybe you could make
a friend and give it to him.
Maybe I could give it to you.
Call ya up late at night.
And you could listen to me
shit on people.
- Oh.
- Where's your phone?
What are you...
Are you supposed to be here?
- The phone.
- Yeah.
In the...
in the kitchen.
Uh...
What's going on?
What's that?
Don't talk.
Are you calling him?
I said don't talk.
This is exciting.
Yeah?
Let me talk to him.
Where were you?
I was hunting.
I heard about the bugs.
You need me to swing by?
It's too late now.
I'm... I'm gonna pay.
The blackmail.
I'm gonna pay it.
Tell me what you said.
It doesn't matter now.
I broke a promise.
Me. So I gotta pay.
Look, I can find the guy,
I just need a few more days.
I couldn't sleep last night.
I kept going over
and over it in my head.
And God brought ten plagues
upon the house of Pharaoh.
Blood and locust,
flies and boils.
And the last is the death
of the Firstborn Son.
What exactly do you
think is happening?
The Firstborn Son.
It's book of Exodus.
God is watching and He knows.
Knows what?
I told Semenchko
to take Dmitri someplace safe
till this all blows over.
He thinks I'm crazy.
You think I'm crazy?
We're only as good
as the promises we keep.
Pick me up in an hour.
We'll get the money.
All right.
So?
He's gonna pay?
- Mm-hmm.
- I ca...
A million dollars?
A milli...
Aw, are you kidding me?
- Do you have a closet that locks?
- Yeah.
Yeah, the pantry locks,
I think.
Oh, my God.
A million do...
Hey, uh, how big is that?
A million dollars?
Does it fit into a suitcase?
Or like... like,
a sack or something?
It's gotta be... it's gotta
be pretty heavy, right?
Hey, can I...
can I lay in it?
You know, I always liked
that part of movies
where the characters,
they just lay in a big pile...
- You got a drill?
- Yeah.
Oh, and then they always...
they always take the money
and they just, like,
throw it up in the air.
And the money just...
Just, like, flutters down
on top of 'em, you know.
Why, God damn, we're doing this.
We're really...
- I got goose bumps.
- Wood screws.
Uh, yeah.
I'm gonna buy
real marble for the spa.
6 inches thick.
I got these, uh...
I got these
French lotions on hold.
They smell like sunflowers.
Uh, these?
- Longer.
- Okay.
So what are we...
what are we do...
just, like, call him
in the morning, you know,
tell him where to...
tell him where to meet us?
- Or... I don't know. These?
- Yeah. Give me a few.
Look at me, I'm sweating.
Here. Oh, man.
Hey, do I get to...
use that voice thing again?
You know, the Darth Vader
super sinister, like,
"Luke, I am your father"?
- Please step in.
- Sure.
Hey, you know, I, uh...
I never even asked ya.
What are ya gonna do
with your share of the money?
I mean, I told ya about...
my, uh...
Uh, yeah, my, uh...
Did you mean to lock me in here?
We got a big day tomorrow.
Get some rest.
I don't want you
getting cold feet.
I'll see you in the morning.
No. No, no, wait, hold on, now.
Heck.
I'm... What am I supposed to...
What... what if I gotta
go to the toilet?
You're a smart guy.
You'll figure something out.
Poop.
Abnormal, it's... it's just
slow now at the shop.
Lester?
It's not my fault.
No, you...
you bought me the tie.
And you...
Is it a cut, or what is it?
Puncture, maybe.
Hard to tell with all the gore.
Mr. Nygaard,
can you hear me?
That's the towel sound.
She's washing towels.
Mr. Nygaard, we're getting you
to the hospital.
Ooh.
What happened to your hand?
Socks.
What about socks?
For 50... $55,
he threw in the shotgun.
I don't understand.
Were you shot?
Mr. Nygaard.
Did you pay Lorne Malvo
to kill Sam Hess?
I never paid him.
Okay, offered to pay then?
Made a deal, and then when he
came for the money...
I never paid.
I didn't pay.
Yeah, okay, but...
arrangements were made,
and then,
I don't know, you tell me.
Things went south?
'Scuse us, miss.
Is that what
you're looking for then?
Two kids.
I'm sorry?
I got two kids and a wife
who thinks out loud.
This is the time I get.
Accidental for me.
Troubled mind.
I'll come to you.
The winters are cold.
But I can't complain.
My socks have holes.
But again, do I complain?
I do not.
The oldest needs braces.
The youngest once sneezed
for three days straight.
But who could complain?
They're gifts.
Children?
All of it.
The cold, the holes.
Hey, so I-I have a question.
Spiritually, I mean.
Or not spiritually,
but I don't know, of a...
of, like, an ethical nature.
Please.
Well...
Let's say I know a person is
guilty who's committed a crime,
only, you know,
I-I can't prove it.
Like he has everyone else
fooled, but... but I know.
What am I sup...
Find the proof.
Yeah, okay,
but here's the thing.
I'm no detective.
I mean, Molly, she's...
amazing, but I just...
And then there's Greta,
you know, and, and...
am I supposed to
put myself in danger,
or do I just...
I don't know, just...
let it go?
A rich man
opens the paper one day.
He sees the world
is full of misery.
Is this a, uh...
It's a parable.
A rich man opens the paper
one day.
He sees the world
is full of misery.
He says, "I have money.
I can help."
_
So he gives away
all of his money.
But it's not enough.
The people are still suffering.
One day, the man sees
another article.
_
He decides
he was foolish to think
just giving money was enough.
So he goes to the doctor
and says, "Doctor,
I want to donate a kidney."
The doctors do the surgery.
It's a complete success.
After, he knows he should
feel good, but he doesn't,
for people are still suffering.
So he goes back to the doctor.
He says, "Doctor, this time
I want to give it all."
The doctor says, "What does
that mean, 'Give it all'?"
He says, "This time
I want to donate my liver.
But not just my liver.
I want to donate my heart,
but not just my heart.
I want to donate my corneas,
but not just my corneas.
I want to give it all away.
Everything I am.
All that I have."
The doctor says,
"A kidney is one thing,
but you can't give away
your whole body piece by piece.
That's suicide."
And he sends the man home.
But the man cannot live
knowing that the people
are suffering
and he could help.
So he gives the one thing
he has left.
_
His life.
And does it work?
Does it stop the suffering?
You live in the world.
What do you think?
So he killed himself
for nothing?
Did he?
Well, I mean...
You're saying...
What are you saying?
Only a fool thinks he can
solve the world's problems.
Yeah, but you gotta try,
don't ya?
Nope.
Keep it running.
Say, dad, I was
talking to the, uh, bug guy.
He's saying
this is all real odd.
The crickets... he's saying
they're not local, ya know?
Not from around here.
He's saying they're the kind
you buy at a pet store
to feed your lizard or...
God sent them.
Yeah. But, well...
So...
So I called around
to all the pet stores,
and wouldn't ya know...
Look, kid, I don't
have time for this now.
Just clean it up.
Then pack your shit, okay?
Wally is coming to take
you to the cabin.
- Yeah, but, dad...
- No buts!
Just do it!
'Scuse me.
Hey, there, Molly.
Hey, uh, Lester okay?
- Well, he's had a bad week,
that's for sure. - Yeah.
- What's this, his third time in?
- Yeah.
On the plus side,
the nose is healing nicely.
- Well, that's a start.
- Yeah.
So, uh, um, listen,
about that hand.
Oh, real mess there.
Super infected.
Nasty stuff.
I drained the wound,
removed the foreign object,
cut away the necrotic tissue,
and filled him full of
IV antibiotics.
He won't lose the hand,
but it came close.
Yeah. Now, when you say,
uh, "foreign object"?
Shotgun pellet, looked like.
Had some fabric attached to it.
It's possible the pellet
passed through something before
getting into Lester's hand.
Yeah, or someone.
Pardon?
Can I talk to him?
Well, he's sedated now
on account
of he was septic
when you brought him in.
So like I said,
real nasty stuff.
Right, yeah, yeah.
Be a while before he can
answer any questions.
Hey, you seen Ida?
Wait, is she here?
Yeah, upstairs.
Just had the baby.
- Holy smokes.
- Yeah.
Girl or boy?
- Bernadette, I heard.
- Oh...
So... girl.
- Yeah.
Dr. Nesbit, call 1-1-8.
Excuse me.
All right.
_
It was the Romans, wasn't it?
Huh?
What are you saying?
Saint Lawrence, your window.
The Romans burned him alive.
They did.
You know why?
'Cause he was Christian.
Maybe.
But I think it was because
the Romans
were raised by wolves.
Greatest empire
in human history,
founded by wolves.
You know what wolves do.
They hunt.
They kill.
It's why I never bought
into The Jungle Book.
Boy's raised by wolves
and becomes friends
with a bear and a panther.
I don't think so.
I knew a guy once,
had a 110-pound rottweiler.
And one night this girl
thought it'd be funny
to get down on all fours
and let the dog hump her.
Dog still had its balls.
Well, the dog gets up there,
but he's not in on the joke.
This is just a bitch in heat
as far as he's concerned.
And he's not leaving
till he gets what he came for.
Well, the girl, too late,
realizes the kind
of mistake she's made,
she wants to get up.
But the dog had other ideas.
Had to shoot it behind the ear
to get it off of her.
I don't, uh...
I don't...
Well, I'm saying that
the Romans raised by wolves,
they see a guy
turning water into wine,
what do they do?
They eat him.
'Cause there are no saints
in the animal kingdom.
Only breakfast and dinner.
So what time do you want me
to pick you up in the morning?
Nah. We're done.
You can stay the night, but you
gotta hit the road come dawn.
Here's what I owe ya.
Sorry it didn't work out.
Grimly.
Hey, ya. It's Molly.
Oh, yeah.
How ya doing, there?
Pretty good.
How things going with you?
Oh, not bad. Just trying
to figure this thing out.
Yeah, so I was wondering.
With this fella I arrested,
how come he was there,
ya know, on the street?
On that street,
I mean, if he is our guy,
and not, you know,
some pastor, actually.
So what'd you come up with?
Well, see, I'm not sure
what I'm looking for
is the problem.
Plus, you know, it's dark out,
so maybe go back out tomorrow.
Oh.
I was thinking I might
drive out in the morning,
take a look at Lester's car.
Thought maybe
after we could get together?
You know,
compare notes on this thing.
Sure. That'd be...
Ah, I'd like that.
Okay, so tomorrow then.
Okay.
What'd ya get for number three?
Uh, X squared.
What'd ya get for four?
A rhombus.
Help you?
You're not supposed to be here.
Oh, no, pretty sure I'm
right where I'm supposed to be.
Hi.
Neighborhood watch.
If you don't move,
I'm gonna have to call the cops.
Well, friend, there's
no need for that.
This is a nice neighborhood.
Children play in the streets.
My children.
We have block parties,
fruit punch.
We don't need a man
in a dark car doing things.
You mean like sitting?
Don't be a nudnik.
This is a community.
People watch
each other's backs.
Someone gets sick, someone dies,
you bring a casserole, help.
Maybe I'm here to help.
No, you have black eyes.
You're trouble.
I'm going inside,
and I'm calling the cops.
Which building?
The one with
the Jew bus outside?
There it is.
Now the truth comes out.
You know, some people think
you don't need alarms
on second-story windows.
Think they can save a few bucks,
you know, and still be safe.
Another way they
save money is they don't
hook up the alarm
to the phone line.
So the bell rings,
but the cops don't come.
Or they come, but only
after the neighbors call.
Which, um, if this community's
tight, as you say,
you know...
just might be quick enough
to save your life...
or your children's lives.
Maybe.
Se'irim.
You're a nice guy.
How come we're all
in the hall then?
Ida kicked us out.
Said we were being too loud.
Ah.
Well, she did just have
a baby, so...
Yeah, we all agreed
it was a good point.
So you're being loud
in the hall instead.
All right, boys,
let's, uh, pack it up.
Call 'er a night.
You're goin' away?
I gotta protect the baby here.
You were making too much noise.
Sorry. You sleeping?
Well, that's a baby, all right.
Smell her.
Okay.
That's what
a new one smells like.
How you holding up?
Me? You're the one
just had a baby.
Yeah, but I get
to lie down now.
Yeah.
I just look tired.
Inside I'm raring to go.
So...
- How much do you...
- I don't need details.
Just tell me you're
taking care of it.
I'm trying, yeah.
Do you want me
to stay the night?
I could sleep in the chair.
Nah. I got
people coming.
My sister and her daughter.
Be around 11:00, she said.
They said, uh, Bernadette.
Vern's idea.
His mother's name.
I wanted Ally.
And now he's dead.
That man always knew
how to win an argument.
I think it's pretty, so...
Good, 'cause you're
the babysitter.
Oh...
Now go home.
Let me sleep.
You do the same.
You look like a raccoon.
Yeah.
I gotta go to Duluth in the AM,
but I'll stop by after, yeah?
Hmm.