Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago the four nations lived
together in harmony
Then, everything changed
when the fire nation attacked.
Only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar,
an airbender named Aang
And although his
airbending skills are great
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
We won't be able
to mount a massive invasion
without the earth king's armies.
But the solar eclipse will still leave
the Firenation vulnerable.
So we're planning a smaller invasion.
Just a rack-tack team of our friends
and allies from around the Earth Kingdom.
It's better for now
that no one knows that I'm alive.
You used to be the pride of the Firenation.
Now look at you.
Look what you've become.
Look, you guys keep telling me
I need to sleep.
But I can't.
The invasion is tomorrow.
You've been training for this
since the day we met.
You can do this.
You're ready.
During the meeting
I was the perfect prince.
The son my father wanted.
But I wasn't me.
Evil and good are always
at war inside you, Zuko.
It is your nature.
Your legacy. Born in you
along with all the strive
is the power to restore balance
to the world.
Book three: Fire
Chapter ten: The day of black sun,
Part 1: the Invasion
Made by elpiedro from
http://santahelp.wordpress.com
Top of the morning, Momo.
- Sounds like you slept well.
Like a baby moose line
I'm ready to face the Firelord.
So what's your strategy
for taking him down?
Gonna get your glow on and hit him
with a little avatar state action?
I can't. When Azula shot me
with lightening
my seventh chakra was locked.
Cutting off my connection
to all the cosmic energy in the universe.
You know what I just heard?
Blabla... spiritual... mombo jumbo
blabla... something about space.
Oh no, Sokka, do you think
the fog will delay the invasion?
No, that is the invasion.
You made it, dad.
Were you able to locate everybody
I told you to find?
I did. But I'm a little worried, Sokka.
Some of these man aren't
exactly the warrior type.
This place ain't nothing like a swamp.
What you recon that is?
Some sort of Firenation exploding trap
would eat you.
It's just a rock, dude.
Well, I'll be.
Is it just me or are those fellows
a little lose in the leafhead.
I just wish they would wear pants.
Pants are an illusion
and so is death.
Hi, Katara.
Haru, it's so good to see you.
Toph, this is Haru. When we met him
his town was controlled by the Firenation.
So, he had to hide his earthbending.
Katara inspired me and my father
to take back our village.
You helped us found our courage, Katara.
No we're here to help you.
No way, is that...
Hypo happy to see blind bandit.
- You guys here for a rematch?
Negatory, the boulder and the hypo
no longer fight for others entertainment.
Now we fight for our kingdom.
Sweet.
Was that a new invention?
Yes, but unfortunately
the incendiary capabilities
of peanut sauce
proof to be a failure.
You're making peanut sauce bombs?
They are destructive
- And delicious.
Were you able to complete work
on the plans I send you?
Yes, I was and I think the Firenation
will be quite surprised.
Aang, my dad and I made this for you.
A new glider.
This is amazing.
And as a special feature
I added a snack compartment.
I'm sure that will come in handy.
I bed you tired of being
in this cell, old man.
Well, too bad. You're never
stepping outside this walls again.
Breakfast.
Careful, Ming. Don't get too close.
His stantial will knock you right out.
I snuck in some yj tea.
I know you like rare teas.
Thank you, Ming. Ever since I was put
in here, you've very kind to me.
Don't worry.
You'll do great.
Good morning everyone.
As you know
today we're invading the Firenation.
I mean I know you know that because
otherwise why else would you be here?
Anyway...
The Firelord palace is here.
Uh, no, uh wait, uh wait,
uh wait, it's here.
There's an eclipse today
and Aang is gonna fight the Firelord.
And the firebenders
won't have any fire to use.
That's good for us.
I'm sorry, let me start
at the beginning.
Katara and I discovered Aang
frozen in an Iceberg.
Now I didn't like Aang at first
but I grew to love him over time.
Then we went to the southern air temple
where Aang used to live.
And then we met Suki as an Kaoshi warrior.
When he says the beginning
he means the beginning beginning.
Got Haru arrested
and now he's wearing a moustache
which you feel looking
at the front row, you can see it.
Thank you, Sokka. It's okay,
why don't you take a break?
Let me just clarify
a few points for everyone.
Today is the day of black sun.
And I want to thank you all
for your self sacrifice and your courage.
There are two steps to the invasion.
A naval stage and then a land stage.
To gain access to the Firenation capital
we have to get past
our first major obstacle here
The great gates of Azula.
Next, we hit the land and we hit hard.
We must fight past their battlements
and secure the plaza tower.
Once we do that,
it's up to the royal palace.
At that point the eclipse will begin.
- Excuse me, the boulder is confused.
Isn't the point
to invade during the eclipse,
when the firebenders are powerless?
The eclipse will only last eight minutes,
not enough time for the whole invasion.
And the royal palace
is heavily guarded by firebenders.
So, that's where we'll need
the eclipse advantage the most.
When this is finished,
the avatar will have defeated the Firelord.
We'll have control over the Firenation
capital and this war will be over.
We've been looking everywhere for you.
The boats are ready to leave.
I messed up Aang.
- What?
The invasionplan was my moment of truth.
And I completely flopped it.
I just fell apart.
That speech wasn't your moment of truth.
That was just public speaking.
And nobody is really good at that.
My dad is, he explained the perfectly
and inspired everyone.
Like a real leader should.
Your moment of truth isn't going to be
in front some map.
It is going to be out there,
on the battlefield.
You seem so confident about everything,
how do you know we're gonna to win?
Because I already failed the world
once at BaSing se.
I won't let myself fail again.
There they are, the great gates of Azula.
- I don't see any gates.
Katara, you and the swamp benders
whip up a fog cover.
We'll sneak by them statues just like
we sneaked by that fire navy blockade.
Keep it up, we’re almost through.
Everyone to low deck.
Let's hope your invention works.
No one is onboard, sir.
- Where did they go?
You really had done yourself
this time, son.
Yeah, congratulations, Sokka.
You managed to invent...
a worse way of traveling than flying.
Helmet?
I just came up with the idea.
The mechanist did all the work.
Don't sell yourself short, my boy.
It was your idea to use waterbending
to make the subs sink and float.
Brilliant, Though your original designs
were a bit difficult to decipher.
Unfortunately, there's one problem
I couldn't fix.
The subs have a limited air supply.
Before we land on the beaches
we'll need to resurface.
Lunch time, general Iroh.
And this time I brought you
an extra bowl of rice.
Thank you, Ming.
Your little gestures of kindness
have made my days in prison bearable.
I think you should take
the rest of the day off.
What?
- You don't look well.
Maybe you should go home and rest.
No, I feel fine.
Trust me, it is better
that you are not here this afternoon.
So, this is it.
Are you ready for the Firenation
to know the avatar is alive?
I'm ready.
I hope you kick
some serious Firelord but, twinkletoes.
Everyone, listen up. The next time
we resurface it will be on the beaches.
So stay alert and fight smart.
Now break time is over,
back in the subs.
Aang...
- Katara, I...
You go first.
We've been through
so many things together
and I've seen you grow up so much.
You're not that little goofy kid
I found in the iceberg anymore.
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
I'm really proud of you.
Everything is going to be different
after today, isn't it?
What if I don't come back.
- Aang, don't say that. Of course you...
Katara, what are you doing?
It's time to submerge.
What? Right, I'm on it.
I'm sorry, Mai.
What do you know?
It did come in handy.
Everyone in position.
Earthbenders, in your tanks.
This is going to be a rough ride.
Ready, the torpedo.
Launch!
We're a man dale.
Where a tornation is you!
Hey, you.
Where have you been?
Communing with nature.
It takes while to collect this much seaweed.
Dad, look out!
Sokka, we've got to take out
those battlements. It's our only chance.
I've got an idea.
You two take out that battlement.
I got this one. Watch each other’s backs.
Dad?
- Dad!
I know I've made some bad choices.
But today I'm gonna set things right.
How does that feel, Dad?
A little better,
I need to get back to the troops.
You're hurt, badly.
You can't fight anymore.
Everyone is counting on me
to lead this mission, Katara.
I won't let them down.
Can't you heal him any faster?
- I'm doing everything I can.
I'll do it.
No offence, Sokka. But you're not
exactly Mr. healing hands.
No, I'll lead the invasion force.
- Don't be crazy, Sokka.
Maybe I'm a little crazy,
but the eclipse is about to start...
and we need to be up the volcano
by the time it does.
You can do this.
I'm proud of you, Son.
I still think you crazy.
But I'm proud of you too.
Listen up everyone,
I want the tanks in wedge formation.
Warriors and benders in the middle.
We're taking that tower
and heading for the royal palace.
CHARGE!
That's strange.
The avatar is back!
Hello?
Anyone home?