Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the fire nation attacked
only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar.
An airbender named aang.
And although his airbending skills are great, he has
a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe, aang
can save the world.
Sokka's your name, right? My favourite
prisoner used to mention you all the time.
She was convinced you are
going to come rescue her.
Of course he never came,
and she gave up on you.
Where.. Is.. Suki?
How are we all gonna escape?
We're not.
You kids have to leave.
You have to escape on appa together.
Bye, dad. We won't be apart
for too long this time.
I promise.
No one can make tea like uncle, but
hopefully I learned a thing or two...
Would you like to hear
uncle's favourite tea-joke?
Sure, I like jokes
bring it
ok, I can't remember how it starts but the
punch line is 'leave me alone, I'm bushed'
well, it's funny when uncle tells it.
Right, maybe that's because
he remembers the whole thing.
Everyone laughs
it's nice to get a chance to relax a
little... it hardly ever happens.
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
So what's up?
If someone was captured by the fire nation,
where would they be taken?
What do you mean? Who was captured?
When the invasion plan failed,
some of our troops were taken.
I just wanna know where they might be.
I can't tell you.
What? Why not?
Trust me. Knowing will
just make you feel worse.
It's mine dad. He was captured too.
I need to know what I put him through.
It's not good, sokka
please
my guess is...
They were taken to the boiling rock.
What's that?
The highest security
prison in the fire nation.
It's on the island in the
middle of the boiling lake.
It's unescapable.
So where is this place?
Why do you need to know?
What do you planing?
Nothing.
Boy, you're so paranoid.
It's in the middle of the volcano
between her and the fire nation.
You guys actually flew right
past it on the way here.
Thanks, zuko.
A-a-a-ah..
Just knowing makes me feel better.
Yeah... I'm sure it does.
Not up to anything, huh?
Fine. You caught me.
I'm gonna rescue mine dad.
You're happy now?
I am never happy.
Look, I have to do this.
The invasion plan was mine idea. It was mine decision
to stay when things when things were going wrong.
It's my mistake.
And it's mine job to fix it.
I have to regain mine honor.
You can't stop me, zuko.
You need to regain your honor?
Believe me... I get it.
I'm going with you.
No. I have to do this alone.
How you're going to get here? On appa?
Last time I checked prisons
don't have a bisons take cares.
We'll take mine war baloon.
What does it say?
Need meat. Gone fishing.
Back in a few days. Sokka and zuko.
One more thing. Aang, practice
your firebending while I'm gone.
Do the twenty of sets of fire fists and ten hot
squats everytime you hear a badgerfrog croak. Zuko.
Nobody else has homework.
One hotsquat, two hotsquats, three
hotsquat, four hotsquat....
Pretty clouds.
Yeah, fluffy.
What?
Oh.. I didn't said anything.
You know, a friend of mine actually
designed this war baloons.
No kidding.
Yep.
Baloon. But for a war.
There is one thing my dad is good at.
It's war.
Yeah.. It seems to ru in a family.
Hey, hold on, not everyone
in mine family is like that.
I know, I know... you've changed.
I met my uncle.
He was more than father to me.
And I really let him down.
I think your uncle would be proud with you.
Leaving your home to come help us.
That's hard.
It wasn't that hard.
Really?
You didn't left behind
anyone you cared about?
Well, I did have a girlfriend.
Mai.
That gloomy girl, who sighs a lot?
Yeah.
Everyone in the fire nation
thinks I am a traitor.
I couldn't drag her into it.
Mine first girlfriend turned to the moon.
That's rough, buddy.
There it is.
There is plenty of steam
to keep us covered.
As long as we quite, we
should be able to navigate
through it without being caught.
We're going down!
Baloon is not working anymore.
The air outside is just as hot as
the air inside, so we can't fly.
So what are we supposed to do?
I don't know! Crash-landing?
How we're gonna get off the island
if the baloon won't work?
We'll figure something out.
I suspected it that it
may be a one way-ticket.
You knew this would happen and
you wanted to come anyway?
My dad might here. I had to come and see.
Uncle always said I never
thought things through.
But this?
Ah, this is just crazy!
Hey, I never wanted you to
come along in the first place.
And for the record... I
always think things through.
But my plans didn't haven't exactly worked,
so this time I am playing it by ear.
So there.
What are you doing?
It doesn't work anyway.
And we don't want anyone to find it.
I hope you know what you're doing.
There is no turning back now.
I hope this disguises work.
We just need to lay low,
and find my dad as fast as possible.
Guards, there is scuffle in the yard.
Come on!
I am going back to my cell.
Stop right there, chit sang!
We can't blow our cover.
I had it with your unruly behavior.
What did I do?
He wants to know what he did.
Isn't that cute?
Ah, very cute, sir.
Super cute.
You didn't bow down, when
walked by, chit sang.
What? That's not a prison rule.
Do it.
Make me.
Tsk, tsk. Firebending is prohibited.
You're going in a cooler.
You! Help me take him in!
Meet back here, in an hour.
A warden will deal with you soon.
Can you believe this guy?
Prisoners, am I right?
Eh.. Tell me about it.
Ha-ha.
Hey, new guy!
I know it's a rule to have
your helmet on all times but
this is lounge... relax.
But if there's an incident?
If I am not prepared someone
can strike me in a head.
Give it a wake. He'll loosen up.
Can a new guy ask you, veterans,
a few questions about a prison?
No you can't date a female guards.
Trust me, you don't want to.
No that's not it.
The boiling rock.
It holds a fire nations most
dangerous criminals, right?
So what about war prisoners?
It's sure looks cold in there.
That's why we call it a cooler
he wont be firebending in there.
It's a warden!
Look alive!
So, chit sang...
I hear you used a firebending
to try to escape.
You shouldn't know better.
I wasn't trying to escape...
He's lying, I saw it with my own eyes!
Noone has ever, ever escaped from here.
I'd sooner jump in a boiling lake
myself, than let that record fall.
Don't forget it.
Now, get back to your shivering.
Hey, there... fellow guard...
How goes it?
Zuko?
Shh!
Listen, I asked around the lounge...
There are no water tribe prisoners.
I am afraid your father is not here.
What?
Are you sure? Did you double-check?
Yeah. I am sure.
No!
No-o-o!
I'm really sorry, sokka
so we came all this way for nothing.
I failed, again.
Augh, what would uncle say...
Sometimes clouds have two
sides... a dark and light.
And a silver lining in between.
It's like a silver sandwich.
Sooo... when life seems hard,
take a bite out of the silver sandwich.
Maybe we haven't failed after all!
That's a spirit.
I can't believe that worked,
I didn't even know what I was saying.
No, what you said made no sense at all,
but look...
It's suki!
Prisoners, back in your cells!
What is it? Did I do something wrong?
You mean you don't recognise me?
You people all look the same to me.
Oh, then maybe you will recognise this...
Sokka! It's you!
The other kyoshi warriors? Are they here?
No.
I don't know where they are.
They locked me in, because
I am their leader.
You won't be here for long.
I am busting you out.
I am so glad to see you, sokka!
I knew you'll come!
Excuse me, I need to get in that cell.
No, you can't go in there.
Eh.. The lights are out.
The prisoner can sneak up on you.
Step aside, fool!..
Hey, hey!.. What are you doing?!
Guard, help!
I think he's imposter!
Arrest him!
Get him off me, and arrest him!
You're under arrest!
Don't worry! I'll figure you out.
Well, well, well.
I never thought I will find you in here
prince zuko.
How did you know who I am?
How could I not?
You broke my niece's heart.
You're mai's uncle?..
I never meant to hurt her.
Quiet!
You're my special prisoner now.
And you best behave
if this criminals will
find out who you are...
The traitor prince who let his nation down.
They will dew you to shreds.
So what's in it for you?
Why don't you just tell my
father and collect the reward?
Oh, in a due time, believe me,
I intend to collect.
Oh, good. You guys have met.
Actually, we met a long time ago.
We did?
Yeah. You...
Kinda burnt down my village.
Oh. Sorry about that.
Nice to see you again.
So listen.
I think I have an escape plan.
I've checked that coolers again.
The whole point of them is to keep
all firebenders contained, right?
Yeah...
So they're completely insolated.
And sealed to keep the cold in.
Well, to keep the cold in,
you have to keep the heat out, right?
Just get to the point, sokka.
It's a perfect boat to get
through a boiling water.
The cooler as a boat?
Are you sure?
I'm telling you... it will work.
I worked around perimter.
There is a blind spot
between two guard towers.
It's a perfect launching point.
I already testid it out.
We will roll the cooler into the water
and just flow with the current.
It will take us straight across.
As long as we don't make a sound.
Noone will notice.
And bing-bang-boom... we're all home, free.
How are you goning to get the cooler out?
Yeah, how are you going
to get the cooler out?
What?
We didn't... we didn't say that.
Yeah, you heard wrong.
I heard you're hatching an escape plan.
And I want in.
There is nothing to get in on.
Yeah, the only thing we're hatching is...
An egg?..
Ok, well I come with you, or a
warden hears about this egg, too.
I guess we have no choice.
Ok you're in.
Now first we need someone
to unbolt the cooler.
From the inside.
Oh, I can get you inside.
Hey what are you, stupid...
Watch where you're going!
Hey, you who you're shoving!
I think you mean whome... I am shoving.
I need backup over here.
No firebending.
Into the cooler.
I can take you back into your
cell if you learned your lesson.
Yes, I have,
completely.
I got suki and chit sang out of
their cells a few minutes ago.
They will be waiting for us at the shore.
Someone's coming.
Yeah, new arrivals coming in a dawn.
Anybody interesting?
Nah, just the usual.
Some robbers, couple of
traitors, some war prisoners.
But I did hear there might be a pirate.
No fooling?
War prisoners.
It could be your father.
I know.
Well, what should we do?
Are we going according to plan,
or waiting another night?
I don't know.
Is it right for me...
To risk suki's freedom,
all of our freedom on a slim chance
that mine dad's gonna show up?
It's your call, sokka.
Took you guys, long enough.
This is mine girl and mine best buddy.
They are coming too.
Fine.
Everybody in a cooler.
Let's go.
Are you sure you wanna go?
You are the one who said that
you want to redeem yourself,
redeem your honor.
Rescuing your dad is your chance.
Your dad?
If would just count my
losses in the invasion.
Maybe we wouldn't be in this mess.
Maybe sometimes it's just better to call it
quit before you fail.
No. It's not.
Look, sokka.
You're gonna fail a lot,
before things will work out.
That's supposed to make me feel better?
Even though you'll probably
fail over and over again,
seriously, not helping.
You have to try every time.
You can't quit because you're
afraid you might fail.
Hey! If you two are done cuddling.
Can we get a move on?!
No, I am staying.
You guys go.
You've been here long enough.
I am not leaving without you, sokka
I am staying too.
Not me, I am out.
Let's row, baby.
We gave up our only chance for escaping.
I hope we haven't just made a huge mistake.
Ahhh, this current is so slow.
I can use this to paddle.
Guards! Secure the perimeter
and lock down the prisoners.
Now!
The plan failed.
They're caught.
Get the fugitives and
throw them in a cooler.
Ah, they are in a cooler, sir.
One makes bolted down
and a flooded in water.
This is lockdown.
We have new prisoners arriving.
Everything must be completely secure.
The gondola is moving.
This is it.
If mine dad is not there, we
risked everything for nothing.
We had to.
Come on, come on.
Is that him?
Mine dad doesn't have nose-ring.
Where is he?
That's it?
That can't be it.
I am sorry sokka.
Oh, no.
Hey, you.
Get off the gondola.
Dad.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk