Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when
the fire nation attacked
only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar.
An airbender named aang.
And although his airbending skills are great, he has
a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe, aang
can save the world.
It's my dad.
He was captured too.
My guess is...
They were taken to the boiling rock.
It's on the island in thew
middle of the boiling lake.
It's inescapable.
We just need to lay low, and
find my dad as fast as possible.
Stop right there, chit sang.
I've had it with your unruly behavior.
You're going in a cooler.
It's suki!
I am so glad to see you, sokka.
I knew you'd come!
I heard you're hatching an
escape plan and I want in.
Well, well, well.
I never thought I would find you in here,
prince zuko.
How did you know who I am?
You broke my niece's heart.
You're mai's uncle?
Yeah, new arrivals coming in a dawn.
Anybody interesting?
Nah, just the ususal.
Some robber, couple of
traitors, some war prisoners.
War prisoners.
It could be your father.
Dad.
Line them up for the warden!
Excuse me, coming through, the
warden wants me over there.
Welcome to the boiling rock.
I am sure you've all heard a horrible
rumours about our little island.
Well I just want to tell you,
that they don't have to true,
as long as you do everything I say.
Look me in a eyes, when
I am talking to you.
No.
Oh, you'd rather look at my shoes.
Then take a look!
I know exactly who you are,
hakoda of the water tribe...
So strong will,
but don't worry we will
get rid of that in time.
Now look me in the eye!
See? Isn't that better?
You all do as I say or... pay the price.
I am fine!
Get this prisoners out of my sight!
Thank goodness you're ok.
If you take one step closer,
you'll see just how 'ok' I am...
Dad, it's me.
Sokka!
My son.
Huh, you know sokka.
You should be more careful
with that guard outfit on.
I almost punched you in the gut.
Yeah, I've run into that problem earlier.
Are you comfortable chit sang?
If you're trying to make me talk,
forget it! I am not a squealer.
Chit sang, I only asked
if you are comfortable.
Well, yeah.
Actually I am pretty comfortable.
Are you still comfortable?
No.
I know you and your cronies are not smart
enough to come up with that little escape plan.
So you're gonna tell me,
who is?
So, where's bato?
Where's everyone else from the invasion?
The others are being held in a
prison near the fire nation palace.
She singled me as their
leader and sent me here.
But before I left I met some young
women who said they knew you/
the oshinama fighters?..
You mean the kyoshi warriors?
That's right.
Their leader suki is here.
And she's gonna escape with us.
Good. We will need all the help we can get.
And you know prince zuko.
The son of the fire lord?
I don't know him but I know of him.
Well, he's here, too.
Sounds like a major problem.
Actually, he's on our side now.
I know, I had the same reaction.
After all he's done, it
was hard to trust him.
But he's really proving himself, and I
would never found him without his help.
So,
do you have a plan?
We had one, but some other prisoners
got involved and ruined it.
I don't if there's another
way out of this island.
Sokka,
there's no prison in the world that
can hold two water tribe geniuses.
Then, we better find two.
Zuko, are you there?
I'm here.
I just got talking to my dad.
We came up with an escape plan together.
What are you doing here?
I was just telling this dirty
low-life what I think of him!
Well, you have to do this
later... he's coming with us.
Why?
Because we have order straight
from the warden, that's why.
Can I get just ten more seconds
to rough him up a bit?
Fine, ten seconds.
Take that!
And this!
Newbie.
We have a new plan, but
we're gonna need a big distraction.
Be in the yard in one hour.
All right, that's enough.
What are you doing?
Where are you taking me?
I didn't do anything wrong!
Come on, zuko. We all know that's a lie.
Mai.
How is he?
I think he's ready to talk.
Have you had enough time to
think about what I asked?
Yes.
And?..
You're right.
There was another person
involved in the escape plan.
Who?
It's guy who disguised like a prison guard
only he's not a prison guard.
He's mastermind, he came up with the plan.
How did you know I was here?
Because I know you so well?
But...
How?
The warden is mine uncle you idiot.
The truth is
I guess I don't know you.
All I get is a letter
you could at least look me in the
eyes when you ripped out my heart.
I didn't mean to.
You didn't mean to?
Dear mai,
"I am sorry that you have
to find out this way,
but I am leaving, .."
Stop!
This isn't about you!
This is about the fire nation!
Thanks, zuko.
That makes me feel all better.
Mai, I never wanted to hurt you.
But I have to do this to save my country.
Save it? You're betraying your country/
that's not how I see it.
Sokka! What's going on?
I don't have much time.
If I am seen with you by the guards,
they might think something is up.
I just talked to my dad.
That's great.
Yeah, and we're escaping
today, on the gondola.
What?
Mine dad and I came up with plan together.
We're come into the gondola
and we're gonna take the hostage
so that they won't cut the lines.
We'll never make it on the gondola.
There's too many guards.
Mine dad already thought of that.
He said we will need a distraction.
That's why we're gonna start a prison riot!
Ok
let's say by some miracle this all
works and we make it on the gondola.
The warden will still just cut the lines.
Even if we have a captive.
Not if the warden is the captive.
I have to go.
I'll find you before we will start a riot.
Hey, you!
The warden wants to see you.
Why?
I don't know, I didn't asked.
Maye I can schedule another time with him?
How's tomorrow?
He wants to see you, now!
Put the in a line-up.
One of you is an imposter who thought he
could fool me.
But now
that person is going to
be in a lot of trouble.
Who is it?
That's him, warden! He's the imposter.
What?!
I am not! He's lying!
He's a liar.
I m telling you.
It wasn't me.
Save your breath.
I know you've been working together
you threw chit sang in the
very cooler he used to escape!
It was all part of your plan.
That was just the coincidence.
Sir, there is someone to see you.
Who told you to interrupt me?
I did.
Princess azula.
It is a honor to welcome you to the
fire nation's most exemplary prison.
I didn't realize you were coming.
Who is this?
He's guard who was involved in a
recent and feeble escape attempt.
It wasn't me!
Quiet, you!
You're wasting your time
... that's not one ot them.
How would you know?
Because I am people person.
Hey, I just got orders.
Let the prisoners out in the yard.
But in the middle of lockdown.
O-oh, ok. I'll just go tell
the warden you said that.
I am sure he will be glad to hear
about you underminig his authority.
What's your name, again?
Wait!
Ehm, don't tell the warden.
I am just a little confused.
Hey, I am confused too.
But the warden in the bad mood and...
Irrational.
So if you ask me. It's best up to question.
And just do what he says.
Yeah, you're right.
We're letting them out!
This is it.
We have to start a riot.
Ok, but how we would do that?
I will show you.
Why did you do that for?
You're hurting my feelings.
Aren't you mad at me?
Ah, normally I would be but I was
ordered to control my anger.
This is not working.
Hey you!
You're lucky, I didn't racked you out.
But mine generousity comes with the price.
I know you're planning another
escape attempt and I want in
actually we're trying to escape
right now, but we need a riot
you wouldn't happen to know
how to start one would you?
A prison riot? Please.
Hey! Riot!
Impressive
forget about controlling my anger,
let's riot, ugh!..
Who let these prisoners in the yard?
This is supposed to be a lockdown
mam, there's a riot going on
I'm here to protect you
I don't need me protection
believe me, she doesn't.
I'm sorry but I'm under direct
order from your uncle to make
sure that nothing happens
get off of me!
Zuko, good.
We're all here.
Now all we need to do is grab
warden and get to the gondolas
and how do we do that?
I'm not sure
I thought you thought this
through.
I thought you told me not
to think everything through
maybe not everything, but
ths is kinda important
hey fellas, I think your
girlfriend is taking care of it.
You wouldn't dare
sorry warden, you're my prisoner now.
We've got the warden
now let's get out of here!
That's some girl!..
Tell me about it
we're almost there
back off, we've got the warden
let's go
everyone in
what are you doing?
I'm making it so they can't stop us.
Way to think ahead.
We're on our way.
Wait, who's that?
That's a problem
it's my sister and her friend
this is a rematch I've been
waiting for
me too
there's the warden I see him
cut the line
he wants us to cut the line
but if we cut the line
there's no way he'll survive
he knows that
they're about to cut the line!
Then it's time to leave
good bye zuko
they're cutting the line
the gondola's about to go
I hope this thing floats
what are you doing?
Saving the jerk who dumped me
who's that?
It's may what is she doing?
Sorry warden
your record is officially broken
well, we made it out now what?
Zuko what are you doing?
My sister was on that island
yeah and she's probably right behing us
so let's don't stop
what I mean, she must've
come here somehow
there,
that's our way out of here
leave us alone
I never expected this from you
the thing I don't understand is why?
Why would you do it
you knew the consequences
I guess you just don't know
people as well as you think you do
you miscalculated!
I love zuko more than
I fear you
no you miscalculated
you shoud've feared me more!
Come on, let's get out of here
you're both fools
what shall we do with them princess?
Put them somewhere I'll never see
their faces again and let them rot!
What are you doing in this thing?
What happened to the war-balloon?
It kinda get destroyed
sounds like a crazy fishing trip.
Did you at least get some good meat?
I did.
The best meat of all
the meat of friendship and fatherhood
I'm new. What's up everybody?
Dad...
Hi, katara.
How are here?
What is going on?
Where did you go?
We kind of went to
a fire nation prison
seriously, you guys didn't
find any meat?
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk