Water
Earth
Fire
Air
Long ago the four nations
lived together in harmony
Then, everything changed
when the fire nation attacked.
Only the avatar, master of all
four elements could stop them.
But when the world needed
him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new avatar,
an airbender named Aang
And although his
airbending skills are great
He has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
You have redeemed yourself, my son.
Welcome home
I know one thing I care
about. I care about you.
A solar eclipse is coming.
The sun will be entirely blacked up by
the moon. The firebenders will be helpless.
That's the day we need
to invade the firenation
The day of black sun.
I've always known that I'd
have to face the firelord.
But now I know I
need to do it alone.
Book three: Fire
Chapter Nine:
Nightmares and Daydreams
Made by elpiedro from
http:/santahelp. wordpress. com
This is it. The official rendezvous
point for the invasion force.
How did you pick this place?
Before we split up my dad and
I found this island on the map.
It's uninhabited and the
harbor is surrounded by cliffs.
Nice choice, Sokka. And we are
here four days ahead at schedule.
Four days?
The invasion is in four days?
Whatever, that's like four days
from now. Let just calm down and...
Sokka has got the right idea, Aang
We are here, we are ready.
The best thing we can do
now is get plenty of rest.
I guess.
Your days eternity
are over, Firelord.
I'm bringing you down.
Really? How do you plan on doing that
when you are not even wearing pants.
Oh no.
It was just a dream, Momo.
I still have my pants.
Well, I better keep training.
Fresh foot, prince Zuko?
May I wash your feet, sir?
Head massage?
Hot towel?
Prince Zuko, is something wrong?
You didn't take the palan key.
I'm just going to Mai's
house. It's not far.
It is not a prince's place
to walk anywhere, sir.
Hey
How long have you been up?
A couple hours.
I've got a lot more skills to
refine if I'm going to fight Ozai.
You know there is such
a thing as overtraining.
You don't get it, do you?
My form is bad, I'm sloppy and I
still don't know any firebending.
Not even the basics.
That's okay, Aang. The eclipse
will block off firebending anyway.
You don't need to know any.
Plus it's a stupid element.
Okay, well, I still have
to work on everything else.
I better spend the
whole day training.
Good night, Katara.
Good night, Sokka.
Good night, Toph.
Good night, Appa.
Good night, Momo.
Good night, Appa and Momo...
- I'm asleep already.
Your days eternity
are over, Firelord.
I'm bringing you down.
And this time I brought pants.
So it seems.
But are you prepared for
your mathematics test?
Math test? Oh no, I forgot
all about the math test.
I've got to be ready.
Aang, it's the middle of the night.
You need to go back to sleep.
But I forgot my pants
and my math test.
Aang, sleep, please. For me.
Tell me, if you can had anything
you want right now, what would it be?
A big fancy fruit tart
with rose peddles on top.
You know, being a prince and all I
might just be able to make that happen.
That would be impressive.
Do you think you can find a
fresh fruit tart for the lady?
With rose peddles on top?
- Excellent choice, sir.
I guess there is some nice
perks to come with being royalty.
Though there is annoying stuff too.
Like that all day war meeting coming up.
War meeting? What
you talking about?
Azula mentioned something.
I assumed you were going too.
I guess I wasn't invited.
Wake up, Aang.
Wake up sleepyhead.
Rise and shine
You overslept. You
missed the invasion.
Sokka, get up. I need
to know what day it is.
What? Who's talking?
Relax, it's still two
days before the invasion.
Sokka, you've got to get up and
drill your wall climbing exercises.
What?
In one of my dreams you were
running from firenation soldiers...
trying to climb this cliff. But
you were to slow and they got you.
But that was just a
dream. I'm a great climber.
Then climb that
cliff. Climb it fast.
Stupid Avatar. Stupid cliff.
Stupid dream. I can climb fast.
Don't drink that.
Why? Is it poison?
In my dream we were right
in the middle of the invasion
and you had to stop to use the bathroom.
We die because your tiny bladder.
And you need to stop wearing your hear up.
In my dream your hear got caught in a train
Aang... I know you
are just trying to help
But you really need to get
a grip. You are unraveling.
You are right. I'm losing my mind.
It is like every time about how stressed
I am, I just end up more stressed.
I'm like a big growing
snowball of nerves.
Of cource you are. That's because
you got to fight the firelord.
The baddest man on the planet and
you better win or we are all done for.
Sokka, you're not helping.
What? It's true. That's
the deal, he knows it.
You know what, I've
got just the thing.
Get ready to be destressafied.
These yoga stretches can really work
wonders if you do them in extreme heat.
Reach up
Reach for the sun.
Feel your t-pads clearing.
Now close your eyes.
How are you feeling?
I feel... really warm.
- Good, good.
Like there's this warm
feeling all around me.
This heat. Like I'm in
the firelord's palace...
and he's shooting a
bunch of fireballs at me.
And the whole world is
being engold in flames.
Maybe your stress is the
kind you need to talk out.
Why don't you get right down to business
and tell me what has been bothering you.
You know what's bothering me. I have
to fight the firelord in a few days.
Tell me more about this firelord.
Why are you so afraid of him?
You said it yourself he's
the baddest man on the planet.
I'm supposed to defeat
him and save the world.
Life does feel that way
sometimes, doesn't it?
Like we are all trying to
save the world from evil.
Okay, but what can
I do to feel better?
Want to try screaming
into this pillow?
Hello Zuzu.
If you come for a royal hair
coming I'm afraid you have to wait.
So I guess there's a big
war meeting coming up, huh?
And apparently I'm
not welcome there.
What do you mean? Of
course you're welcome.
Oh yeah? I guess that's why no
one bothered to tell me about it.
Oh, Zuko, don't be so dramatic.
I'm certain dad wants you there.
You probably weren't
invited because...
it is so obviously that
you supposed to be there.
Well, were you invited?
- Of cource, I'm the princes.
And I'm the prince.
- Exactly.
So stop acting like
a paranoid child.
Just go to the meeting.
- Forget it, I'm not going.
All right, what you need is a good old fashion
back pounding to relieve your stress.
Pound a way.
Toph, I think this is fruzing me.
Sorry, I forgot you have baby skin.
Well, there's one
other thing we can try
Ace pulsar
Zuko, it's just a dumb meeting.
Who cares?
- I don't.
Well good, you shouldn't.
I mean why do you even want to go?
Just think about how things went
the last war meeting you went to.
I know.
You know what'd
make you feel better?
Ordering some servants around.
I might be hungry for a
whole tray of fruit tarts
And maybe a little palan
key ride around town.
Double time.
Thanks for everything guys.
- So, do you feel less stressed?
Ready for a good night sleep?
I kinda think I sort of might
slightly feel a little better.
Maybe.
- Then our work here is done.
What happened, Aang?
It's the nightmares.
They just get worse and worse.
Look like it's time for
another therapy session.
No, that won't help. Nothing helps.
There's only one thing I can do.
I'm going to stay wake
straight trough the invasion.
Invasion.
All aboard for the invasion.
You don't look so good.
You sure you can't just
lay down for a little nap?
I told you I can't go back to sleep
Aang, staying up all night
can't be good for you.
Actually staying up all night
has given me some time to think.
And I realize some
big things, Katara.
What big things?
I see everything so clearly
now. What really matters.
Why I'm really doing this.
I'm doing it to save the
world. But more than that...
I'm doing it for the people I
love. I'm doing it for you, Katara.
Aang, what are you saying?
- I'm saying...
I love you
What are we doing?
What our hearts have been telling
us to do for a long, long time.
Baby, you're my forever girl.
Aang...
I was just saying
you should take a nap.
Oh, I guess I kinda
drifted off into a daydream.
What was your dream about?
Uh, living under water.
Sounds unique.
Price Zuko, everyone
is waiting for you.
What?
The high admirals, the high
generals, the war ministers...
and the princes have all arrived.
You're the only person missing.
So, my dad wants me at the meeting?
The firelord said he would not
start until your arrive, sir.
Put them up, firelord.
Hey, I'm trying to build
Appa some armor here...
so that he doesn't have to
go to the invasion naked.
He's your bison.
Ozai's defense is impeccable. I'll
have to try a different approach.
You think you're untouchable,
don't you mister firelord?
Oi, you're really
starting to lose it kid.
Momo? Did you hear something?
No, but I said something.
You my friend are just a few
plunch short of a fruit pie.
That's more like it.
I'm so tired that for a second there
I imagined you were talking to me.
Oh, Momo let me explain.
Aang?
We are all starting to get
a little worried about you.
You've been awake too long.
And you're acting weird.
You've got to take care of
yourself. You can't go on like this.
Look, I appreciate
what you guys are saying
but the stress and the nightmares
they were just too much.
Staying awake is the best
way for me to deal with it.
Yeah, leave the kid alone.
Hey, who asked you?
Guys, come on.
No, I'm sick of this guy always
mounting off and telling me what to do.
Oh, you don't like it.
Then let's go right now.
Sokka, what should we do?
- About what?
About that
Come on guys, we're
all on the same side.
I just need a jump
in a cold waterfall.
So? How did it go?
When I got at the meeting,
everyone welcomed me.
My father had saved me a
seat. He wanted me next to him.
I was literally at his right hand.
Zuko, that's wonderful.
You must be happy.
During the meeting I
was the perfect prince.
The son my father
wanted. But I wasn't me.
Oh, look another hallucination. An
imaginary bed made out of clouds.
Hey, it's real. We spend
hours working on it.
We made it for you, a good night sleep
will probably take the crazy away.
We hope.
Look, you guys keep
telling me I need to sleep.
But I can't, the
invasion is tomorrow.
Aang..
- No, Katara.
There is still so much I haven't learnt. I
don't need sleep, what I need is practice.
Quick, hit me.
I'm not going to hit you.
You want me to do it?
Listen to me, you've been training
for this since the day we met.
I've seen your progress.
You're smart, brave
and strong enough.
You really think so?
We all do, you can
do this. You're ready.
You're the man, twinkletoes.
Thanks guys.
You know what? I think I'm ready.
Your days eternity
are over, Firelord.
Really? You're going to take me
out? You're not even wearing pants.
No, firelord Ozai.
You're not wearing pants.
My royal parts are showing.
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle f
Subtitle fi
Subtitle fix
Subtitle fixe
Subtitle fixed
Subtitle fixed b
Subtitle fixed by
Subtitle fixed by L
Subtitle fixed by LE
Subtitle fixed by LEO
Subtitle fixed by LEO3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
w
ww
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www
www.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.l
www.le
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo
www.leo3
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33
www.leo33.
Subtitle fixed by LEO33
www.leo33.t
www.leo33.tk