Water,
Earth,
Fire,
Air.
Long ago, the four nations lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all four elements, could stop them.
But when the world needed him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother and I discovered the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang
And although his airbending skills are great
He has a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone.
But I believe Aang can save the world.
Previously on Avatar
Sozin's Comet is arriving and our destinies are upon us.
There's one technique that you need to know before facing my father.
How to redirect lightning.
Even though we don't know where Aang is, we
need to do everything we can to stop the airship fleet.
It's time for this world to end in fire,
and for a new world to be born from the ashes.
I guess we don't have a choice, Momo.
I have to kill the Fire Lord.
Zuko, don't worry. We can take Azula.
I'm not worried about her. I'm worried about Aang.
What if he doesn't have the guts to take out my father?
What if he loses?
Aang won't lose. He's gonna come back.
He has to.
What am I holding?
A cherry pit, princess...
Correct. And what day it this?
It is the day of your coronation...
Yes it is. So please, tell me why on the most important day of my life,
you decided to leave a pit in my cherry?
It wasn't a decision. I was just a small mistake.
Small? Do you realize what could've happened if I hadn't sensed the pit in time?
I suppose... you could've choked?
Yes. Then you understand the severity of your crime?
I understand princess. Please, forgive me.
Oh, very well. Because it is a special day, I will show mercy.
You are banished! Leave this palace immediately!
What are you all looking at? I have two feet that need scrubbing
It's weird to say, but the comet actually looks beautiful.
Too bad the Fire Lord is about to use it to destroy the world.
We're too late! The fleet army's taking off!
And we're taking off too
Where's the closest airship?
It's right... urgh
Ugh!
You sent for us, Princess? Is everything alright?
Actually, everything is not alright.
Do you know how long it took you to get here?
Uhhh, a few minutes I guess?
Five to be precise.
In which time, an assassin could've snuck in,
done away with me and been on his merry way.
My apologies Princess.
Is this how you plan to treat your new Fire Lord?
Retardiness in disloyalty?
The Dai-Li would never betray you!
And I'm sure this is what just you told Long Feng
before you turned against him and joined me.
You're all banished!
But...
Good Bye!
Please send in the next group on your way out.
Shh!
That's how it's done!
Good work Toph. It's time to take control of this ship.
Take the wheel.
That's a great idea. Let the blind girl steal the giant airship!
I was talking to Sukki.
That would make a lot more sense.
What are we gonna do about the rest of the crew?
Take us out close to the water.
I've got an idea.
Attention crew. This is your captain speaking.
Everyone please report to the bomb bay immediately for hot cakes and sweet cream!
We have a very special birthday to celebrate.
Hey, I'm Kwen lee. I work up in communications.
Oh hi. I work down in the engine room.
It's far a long minutes before. Big action, you know?
Yup. So, do you know whose birthday it is?
I can't believe the captain remembered my birthday.
He really does care!
Happy Birthday!
Fire Lord Ozai, Here we come!
Azula, we heard what happened.
Why have you banished all of your servants?
Or your Dai-Li agent? And the imperial's firebenders?
None of them could be trusted.
Sooner or later, they all would've betrayed me.
Just like Mai and Ty Lee did.
Azula, we are concerned for you and your well-being.
My father asked you to come here and talk to me, didn't he?
He doesn't think I can handle the responsibility of being Fire Lord.
And I will be the greatest leader in Fire Nation history.
I'm sure you will, but considering everything that happened today,
perhaps it's best to postpone your coronation.
What? Which one of you just said that?
What a shame, there's only one way to resolve this.
You two must duel each other.
I order you to fight in Agni Kai!
But, we're not firebenders...
Alright, fine. Lou, you're banished. Lee, you can stay.
But, I'm Lee. So who is banished?
Ba Sing Se, The Order of the White Lotus is here.
Here to set you free.
Only once every hundred years can a firebender experience this kind of power.
Alright hair. It's time to face your doom.
What a shame. You always had such beautiful hair.
What are you doing here?
I didn't wanna miss my own daughter's coronation.
Don't pretend to act proud. I know what you really think of me.
'She's some kind of monster'
I think you're confused. All your life you used fear to control people.
Like your friends, Mai and Ty Lee.
But what choice do I have? Trust is for fools.
Fear is the only reliable way. Even you fear me.
No, I love you, Azula. I do.
Urgh.
We're not gonna catch up to him in time.
No...
Momo, time for you to go.
What just happened?
It's Aang. He's back!
After generations of Fire Lords failed to find you...
Now the universe delivers you to me as an act of providence.
Please listen to me. We don't have to fight.
You have the power to end it here and stop what you are doing.
You are right. I do have the power, I have all the power in the world!
Whoo-hoo! Airbending slice!
Shouldn't we be helping him?
The Fire Lord is Aang's fight.
We need to stay focused on stopping that fleet
from burning down the Earth kingdom.
And how did we do that captain boomerang?
I can't see outside of this floating hunk of metal.
Airship slice!
Wow! That's a lot of fire, isn't it?
It's gonna be a rough ride. We gotta get to the top of this thing, fast.
Then what?
Watch each other's back. And if we make it that far, I'll let you know.
Sukkiiii!
I'm OK. Just finish the mission.
No..
Sokka, I think we got it.
By decree of Phoenix King Ozai, I now crown you Fire Lord..
What are you waiting for? Do it!
Sorry, but you're not gonna become Fire Lord today.
I am.
Hahaha. You're hillarious.
And you're going down.
Wait. You want to be Fire Lord. Fine. Let's settle this.
Just you and me, brother. The showdown that always mean to be. Agni Kai!
You're on.
What are you doing? She's playing you.
She knows she can't take us both, so she's trying to separate us.
I know, but I can take her this time.
But even you admitted to your uncle that you'd need help facing Azula.
There's something off about her.
I can't explain it, but she's slipping.
And this way, no one else has to get hurt.
I'm sorry it has to end this way, brother.
No, you're not.
Urgh!
No Lighting today? What's the matter?
Afraid I'll redirect it?
Oh, I'll show you lightning!
No!
Zuko!
Hahaha, You're weak. Just like the rest of your people!
They did not deserve to exist in this world, in MY world!
Prepare to join them! Prepare to Die!