TYSON".
We live on one level of existence.
But there are others.
These hidden dimensions
of reality are everywhere...
...far away, across the light-years,
beneath our feet...
...and even inside you and me.
We are made of atoms.
There are more atoms in your eye...
...than there are stars in all the galaxies
of the known universe.
The same is true of any solid object
larger than the tip of your little finger.
I'm a collection of 3
billion billion billion...
...intricately arranged atoms
called Neil deGrasse Tyson.
You're a similar collection
with a different name.
We don't usually think of ourselves this
way, because that level of reality...
...lies beyond the realm of our senses.
But we're not gonna let that stop us.
We can go deeper into the wonder.
[WIND WHISTLING]
TYSON:
Atoms let matter do funny things.
To understand water, you need to know
what its atoms are doing.
Every molecule of water is composed
of two tiny hydrogen atoms...
...attached to a larger oxygen atom.
That's why we call it H20.
If it's not too hot or too cold...
...the molecules can slide
and tumble past each other.
There's stickiness between the molecules...
...but not enough to lock them
into a rigid solid.
That's what makes something a liquid.
The sun warms the water.
And with more energy,
the molecules move faster.
That's all that temperature is.
Those molecules are moving fast enough...
...to break the weak bonds
that hold them to their neighbors.
That's evaporation.
The air we breathe is made
of nitrogen and oxygen molecules...
...with a scattering of water vapor
and carbon dioxide.
Incoming!
That's condensation.
A dewdrop is the momentary triumph...
...of condensation over evaporation.
And while it lasts...
...it's a little cosmos
with its own worlds...
...creatures, drama.
To explore the far-ﬂung realms
of this dewdrop...
...we're gonna need a ship.
One with twin engines...
...science and imagination.
That's a single-celled
paramecium...
...one of a multitude
of skilled hunter-warriors...
...that roam the dewdrop.
But they too are hunted.
The Dileptus...
...the paramecium's
mortal enemy.
The paramecium might get lucky
and score a direct hit.
Even if it doesn't...
...the recoil from the barrage
will put some distance...
...between the paramecium
and its attacker.
What can I say?
That's life in the dewdrop.
That little guy is a tardigrade...
...an animal smaller
than the head of a pin.
Don't underestimate them.
Tardigrades have been living on this planet
a lot longer than we have.
About 500 million years.
For every one of us...
...there's at least a billion of them.
They can make a living
anywhere on Earth...
...in the frigid peaks
of the tallest mountains...
...in the cauldrons
of erupting volcanoes...
...the deep ocean vents
at the bottom of the sea.
Tardigrades are so tough...
...they can survive naked
in the vacuum of space.
They've survived all five...
...of the most recent
mass extinctions on this planet.
A visitor from another world
could be forgiven...
...for thinking of Earth
as the planet of the tardigrades.
If we're ever gonna get to the bottom
of this dewdrop, better get a move on.
Every leaf and tiny clump of moss
has hundreds of thousands...
...of microscopic mouths called stomata.
Plants breathe through them,
taking in carbon dioxide...
...and exhaling the oxygen
that we need to live.
The plants can survive without us.
But we and all the other animals...
...we'd be toast without them.
The plants make food out of sunlight.
We animals can't do that.
To see how they do it...
...we have to go deeper...
...make ourselves
about a thousand times smaller...
...to get into their treasure house...
...the place where they keep
the good stuff, the chlorophyll.
That's the molecule
that converts sunlight into energy.
Every one of those rectangles
is a plant cell.
And those tiny green vehicles...
...are its energy factories.
If we could steal their trade secrets, it
would trigger a new Industrial Revolution.
But to spy on them,
we're gonna need to go deeper still.
TYSON: What alien world has the Ship
of the Imagination carried us to this time?
It's the cosmos...
...contained within a dewdrop.
We're on an industrial espionage mission.
If we can penetrate the trade secrets...
...of the manufacturing process
in that chloroplast...
...let's just say our whole future
hangs in the balance.
This chloroplast is using sunlight...
...to break water molecules
into atoms of hydrogen and oxygen.
It combines the hydrogen
with carbon dioxide to make sugar...
...and releases the oxygen
as a waste product.
To see how it happens,
we have to go even deeper...
...get even smaller.
We're talking atomic scale.
Bingo.
This assembly line is the heart...
...of the molecular industrial complex.
At the molecular level...
...things happen too fast for us to see...
...so we'll have to slow them down
about a billion times.
Those larger molecules are carbon dioxide.
Each one of them is made
of one carbon and two oxygen atoms.
When sunlight strikes
a green molecule of chlorophyll...
...it sets in motion a series
of chemical reactions...
...breaking apart water molecules...
...and freeing energetic electrons.
And that's just the day shift...
...when sunlight supplies
the incoming stream of energy.
There's a second shift
that works day and night...
...using the solar energy kept in reserve.
The energy of the free electrons
is put to work...
...combining carbon dioxide
with hydrogen from the water.
The end product is sugar...
...which stores the solar energy.
The chloroplast is a 3-billion-year-old
solar energy collector.
This submicroscopic solar battery...
...is what drives all the forests
and the fields...
...and the plankton of the seas...
...and the animals, including us.
The solar-powered biosphere
collects and processes...
...six times more power
than our entire civilization.
We understand on a chemical level
how photosynthesis works.
We can re-create the process
in a laboratory...
...but we're not as good
at it as plants are.
And that's not surprising...
...considering nature's been at this
for billions of years...
...and we've only just started.
But if we could figure out
the trade secrets of photosynthesis...
...every other source of energy
we depend on today...
...coal, oil, natural gas...
...would become obsolete.
Photosynthesis is the ultimate green power.
It doesn't pollute the air...
...and is, in fact, carbon neutral.
Artificial photosynthesis,
on a big enough
scale, could reduce the
greenhouse effect...
...that's driving climate change
in a dangerous direction.
Uh-oh. Place is evaporating.
Time to get out of here.
How fleeting is the life of a dewdrop.
It condenses from thin air
in the cool of the night...
...only to vanish with the heat
of the day.
And what of its inhabitants,
the tardigrades?
They'll be fine.
They can go without water for years.
TYSON: It's hard to imagine, but plants
covered the surface of the Earth...
...for hundreds of millions of years...
...before they put forth
their first flower.
That was about
a hundred million years ago...
...shortly before the dinosaurs
were wiped out.
Our world must've been a relatively
drab-looking place back then...
...dominated by shades of green and brown.
Yeah, there were giant trees
and ferns and other plant life...
...but not the purple of an iris...
...or the crimson of a red, red rose.
Orchids were among the first
flowering species to appear on Earth...
...and they're the most diverse.
Darwin was particularly fascinated
by the comet orchid of Madagascar...
...a flower whose pollen is hidden
at the bottom...
...of a very long, thin spur.
There can be no stronger test
of an idea than its predictive power.
On the basis of his theory of evolution
through natural selection...
...Darwin speculated that somewhere
on the island of Madagascar...
...there must live flying insects...
...with extraordinarily lengthy tongues. ..
...ones long enough to reach the pollen.
No one had ever seen such a beast there...
...but Darwin insisted that an animal
fitting this description must exist.
Few people at the time believed him.
It wasn't until more than 50 years later...
...that Darwin was proven right.
In 1903, a huge hawk moth
called the Morgan's sphinx...
...was discovered in Madagascar.
Attracted by the comet orchid's scent...
...the moth slurps its pollen
with its foot-long tongue...
...exactly as Darwin expected it would.
It's even more amazing
that the Morgan's sphinx was discovered...
...when you consider that more than
90 percent of Madagascar's rain forests...
...have been destroyed.
In the years
since Darwin's famous prediction...
...this moth species could have easily
become extinct with all the others...
...every one of them a unique phrase
of life's poetry...
...written in the atoms
by eons of evolution.
[SNIFFS]
Ah, the fragrance of lilacs.
It's one of those scents that triggers
a whole constellation of associations...
...all those Junes of long ago.
But how does that happen?
How does a smell prompt a movie
to start running in your head?
It's not something we can see.
Could it be a wave of energy, like light?
Or is it some kind of microscopic particle?
It's actually a molecule.
Every odor we can sense, whether it
comes from burnt toast, gasoline...
...or a field of lilacs...
...it's a cloud of molecules.
These molecules have particular shapes.
When I inhale them...
...they stimulate a particular set
of receptor cells in my nose.
An electrical signal then
travels to my brain...
...which identifies this scent as lilac.
Other scents are carried by different
molecules with different shapes.
But when I smell a flower...
...or the smoke from a campfire,
or the grease of a motor gear...
...I'm often flooded with memories.
Why is it that a simple thing,
such as the scent of a flower...
...can trigger powerful memories?
It has to do with the way
our brains have evolved.
Our sense of smell kicks in...
...when the olfactory nerve
in our brain is stimulated.
That nerve is located
very close to the amygdala...
...a structure that is integral
to our experience of emotion.
It's also very close to the hippocampus...
...which helps us form memories.
The network of neurons
that carry the scent signal...
...from my nose to my brain
has been fine-tuned...
...over hundreds of millions
of years of evolution.
It's a survival mechanism...
...that can alert us to danger
or guide us to safety.
If you can detect the predator
before he's near enough to strike...
...or the fire before it
traps you in the forest...
...you have a much better chance
to survive and pass on your genes...
...to the next generation.
That lovely scent from
this field of flowers...
...sets off a unique combination
of nerve signals.
Only that exact combination
can crack the safe...
...where the memory of lilacs
is stored inside my brain.
Wonder who they're for.
Maybe we'll find out later.
But first, there's another hidden cosmos
waiting for us.
[TYSON BREATHING DEEPLY]
The plants are softly breathing...
...inhaling molecules of carbon dioxide...
...and exhaling molecules of oxygen.
And I'm doing the opposite.
Unlike snowflakes and fingerprints...
...atoms or molecules of the same kind
are utterly identical to one another.
With every breath we take...
...we inhale as many molecules
as there are stars...
...in all the galaxies
in the visible universe.
And every breath we exhale
is circulated through the air...
...and, mixed gradually
across the continents...
...becomes available for others
to breathe.
Breathe with me.
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
We all just inhaled
about a hundred million molecules...
...that once passed through the lungs
of everyone who ever lived before us.
Think of it.
This kind of atomic reincarnation...
...is another link
to our distant ancestors...
...including those who first
launched us on our explorations...
...of the unseen universes.
These universes are as real
as you or me...
...and they surround us.
There was a moment when we awakened
to a new way of thinking and seeing.
It happened about 2500 years ago...
...on the Greek islands that lie
between the empires of the East...
...and the West.
There, merchants, tourists
and sailors freely mingled...
...exchanging tales of
great kings and gods.
In Ionian cities and towns like Miletus,
in what is now Turkey...
...the most fundamental elements
of the way we live now...
...first appeared.
TYSON". Here, for the first time,
reenactments of aspects of life...
...created and executed by professionals...
...with the expectation
of touching something
deep within the hearts
of the audience...
...or just making them laugh.
[ALL LAUGHING]
The first plays, dramas and comedies
were performed.
Here also was born a radical new idea...
...government by the people.
The first inklings, imperfect then as now,
of a democracy...
...and the notion that the ordinary citizen
might possess certain rights...
...come to us from this time and place.
But in my view,
the most revolutionary innovation of all...
...to come to us from this ancient world...
...was the idea that natural events...
...were neither punishment nor reward...
...from the capricious gods.
The workings of nature
could be explained...
...without invoking the supernatural.
The first person to express this thought
was a man named Thales.
When the thunder clapped
or the earth quaked...
...it was not because something you did
had somehow displeased...
...the very demanding gods. No.
It was the result of natural processes...
...that we were capable of understanding.
Though none of the books
he is said to have written survive...
...Thales kindled a flame
that still burns to this day.
The very idea of cosmos out of chaos...
...a universe governed
by the order of natural laws...
...that we could actually figure out...
...this is the epic adventure...
...that began in the mind of Thales.
Only a century following Thales' death...
...another genius came along.
And he, more than any other...
...was the first to
discover the existence...
...of the hidden universes
that surround us.
Democritus of Abdera was
a true scientist...
...a man with a passionate desire
to know the cosmos...
...and to have fun.
This is the man who once said,
"A life without parties...
...would be like
an endless road without an inn."
You mean, that's it?
That's all there is?
Just a bunch of atoms in a void?
Yep.
RAUGHS]
Well, think about it.
The world has to be made...
...of countless indivisible particles
in a void.
Otherwise, nothing could
move or grow...
...be divided or changed.
Without atoms and empty space
for them to move in...
...the world would be
solid, static and dead.
So don't be sad, my friend.
Just think of the infinite possibilities...
...that arise from different
arrangements of those atoms.
Here's to the atoms in this cup...
...and in this wine...
...and to the laughter they make possible.
[ALL LAUGHING]
TYSON: Dispersed through the clay of the
cup are microscopic mineral grains...
...different kinds of crystals...
...each with its own distinctive
atomic architecture.
Mineral structures are exquisite...
...but they have a limited repertoire.
A grain of quartz is a lattice
of the same three atoms repeated...
...without variation, over and over again.
Even a relatively complex
mineral lattice like topaz...
...composed of 10 or so atoms...
...can only repeat the identical
atomic structure...
...again and again.
To lift matter to another dimension...
...to free it from the lattice prison
of endless repetition...
...you need an atom that can bond
in all directions...
...with other atoms like itself,
as well as with atoms of different kinds.
Behold, the carbon atom.
The essential element for life on Earth.
Why?
Carbon is special because it can bond
with up to four other atoms at a time.
It can connect with many
different kinds of atoms...
...as well as other carbon atoms.
It can curl into rings
and string together into chains...
...building molecules
far more complex than any crystal.
No other atom has the same flexibility.
Even atoms that have similar
chemical properties, like silicon...
...can't form the amazing variety
of molecules built on carbon.
The carbon-based molecules
we call proteins...
...the molecules of life...
...contain literally hundreds of thousands
of atoms.
Carbon atoms are the backbone
of the molecules...
...that make every living thing on Earth,
including us.
That's the difference between
rocks and living things.
Life can make enormous molecules
of stunning size and complexity...
...freeing matter to improvise, evolve
and even love.
TYSON".
Take it easy, Dad.
He never actually touched her.
In everyday life on our world...
...on the scale of atoms...
...material objects never really touch.
Each atom has a tiny nucleus
at its center...
...surrounded by an electron cloud
of lines of force.
As the atoms approach each other...
...the boy's electron clouds
push away the girl's.
More than 99.9 percent
of the matter of any atom...
...is concentrated in its nucleus.
The nucleus is surrounded
by an electron cloud...
...which produces an invisible field of
force and acts like a shock absorber.
The configuration of the electron cloud
determines the nature of an element.
In the ordinary course of things here
on Earth, the nuclei never touch.
We have a sensation of touching...
...but that's really
just our invisible force
fields overlapping and
repelling each other.
The nucleus is very small
compared to the rest of the atom.
If an atom were the size
of this cathedral, its nucleus...
...would be the size of that mote of dust.
An atom is mostly empty space.
To understand the nature of matter...
...we have to go deeper still...
...to a place 100,000 times smaller
than the atom:
its nucleus.
The simplest and most plentiful atom
in the cosmos is hydrogen.
Its nucleus is a single proton...
...which makes hydrogen
element number one.
The clouds that surround it...
...are the realms where this atom's
lone electron is permitted to roam.
What happens when you have
a nucleus with two protons?
Protons repel each other.
In order to hold them together
in a nucleus...
...you need other particles
called neutrons.
Their job is to keep the proton
from getting out of line.
They overwhelm the protons
with their strong attractive nuclear force.
A nucleus with two protons
is element number two...
“otherwise known as helium.
A nucleus with six protons
is element number six...
...which is carbon,
the fundamental building block of life.
The nucleus of a gold atom has 79 protons.
They attract 79 electrons
in clouds around it.
The way light interacts with those
electrons is what makes gold glitter.
Every additional proton
in the nucleus requires
enough neutrons to
bind them together.
Up to a point.
There's an upper limit to the number
of neutrons you can stuff into a nucleus...
...before it becomes unstable.
I know a place where the
nuclei of different
atoms actually do
touch each other.
The sun looks like a solid object...
...but it's not.
It's so hot that all its atoms
are always in their gaseous state.
The bonds that join atoms
to make solids and liquids on Earth...
...are not strong enough to withstand
the heat of the broiling sun.
Those arcing streams of incandescent gas
that dwarf the Earth...
...are guided by magnetic lines of force...
...that emanate from below
the surface of the sun.
Why is the sun so hot?
Because its own stupendous gravity
is squeezing its atoms together.
The energy of gravity is being transformed
into the energy of moving atoms.
That's what heat is.
The deeper we go into the sun...
...the greater the squeezing
and the higher the temperature.
In the heart of the sun...
...the atoms are moving so fast
that when they collide, they fuse.
Their nuclei touch.
The sun is a nuclear fusion reactor...
...held together by its own gravity.
It's balanced between
the inward pull of gravity...
...and the outward push of its hot gases.
That balance has lasted
billions of years...
...providing stability that made possible
the evolution of life on Earth.
In the sun's core...
...the fusion of hydrogen
into helium releases
nuclear energy in the
form of photons.
These particles of light
slowly work their way to the surface...
...where they're seen as sunlight.
Helium is the ash
of the sun's nuclear furnace.
The sun is a medium-sized star.
Its core is only a lukewarm
1O million degrees.
Hot enough to fuse hydrogen,
but too cold to fuse helium.
There are many stars in the galaxy
that get much hotter...
...because they're more massive
and have more gravity.
Such stars fuse helium into heavier
elements, like carbon and oxygen.
In their old age, they gently
diffuse these elements into space.
Other stars, more massive yet,
live fast and die young...
...in cataclysmic supernova
explosions.
In our galaxy, such stars
go supernova about once a century.
Those explosions are far hotter
than the core of the sun.
Hot enough to transform elements like
iron into all the heavier ones...
...and spew them into space.
The Large Magellanic Cloud...
...is a neighboring galaxy
of our Milky Way.
It's visible in the skies
of the southern hemisphere.
When a supernova explodes...
...its brightness rivals that
of its entire galaxy.
But all that light is only about 1 percent
of the energy liberated in the explosion.
The rest of the energy is carried off
by the most common...
...and the most mysterious particles
in the cosmos.
There are trillions of them
passing through you right now.
And yet tracking down
even one of them...
...will take us to one of
the strangest places on Earth.
TYSON: Stalking the wild
neutrino is the rarest of sport.
The lengths one must go to track them down
is nothing short of astonishing.
Welcome to Super-Kamioka...
...the subterranean Japanese
neutrino-detection chamber...
...more than a half mile
beneath Earth's surface.
You might ask,
"Well, who in their right mind...
...would bury an astronomical observatory
so far underground?"
Those who hunt the most elusive prey
in the cosmos:
the neutrino.
This enormous array
of light detectors
surrounding 50,000 tons
of distilled water...
...is a trap designed to
catch neutrinos only.
Other particles, such as cosmic rays...
...mostly protons and electrons
that rain down from space...
...cannot get through all that rock
above us.
But matter poses no obstacle
to a neutrino.
A neutrino could pass
through a hundred
light-years of steel
without even slowing down.
Neutrinos hardly interact
with matter at all.
That's why you need so much of it
to catch even one of them.
On those rare occasions...
...when a neutrino actually does collide
with a particle of ordinary matter...
...it produces a ghostly
ring-shaped flash of light.
We're lying in wait for a particle
that weighs next to nothing.
Even the miniscule electron...
...has more than a million times its mass.
There!
When the supernova in the Large
Magellanic Cloud blew its top in 1987...
...this is what it would have looked like
in here.
Now remember, the Large Magellanic
Cloud is in our southern hemisphere...
...so the neutrinos didn't come through
that half-mile of rock above us.
They had to pass through the thousands
of miles of rock and iron below us...
...to reach this detector.
But the coolest thing...
...was that those neutrinos hit Earth...
...three hours before
the light from the supernova did.
If nothing can travel faster than light...
...how could that possibly be?
This is a dead star walking.
It may look normal, but deep within it,
something cataclysmic is happening.
This blue supergiant star...
...has already begun to explode inside.
Like rats deserting a sinking ship...
...the neutrinos produced in the heart
of the exploding star...
...race outward at near
the speed of light...
...through the overlying mass
in only a few seconds.
But the shock wave of the exploding gas
plods along from the center of the star...
...at one ten-thousandth
the speed of light...
...until it finally reaches
the star's surface...
...turning it into Supernova 1987A.
It took hours for the
explosion to reach the
surface of the star and
blow it wide-open...
...exposing the superhot core.
The neutrinos had
an insurmountable head start.
That's why the flash of
light arrived on Earth
so much later than the
shower of neutrinos.
Before anyone had ever snared
the wild neutrino...
...it existed in the mind
of a theoretical physicist.
Just as Charles Darwin knew there must be
an extremely long-nosed creature...
...flying around somewhere
in Madagascar...
...a 20th-century physicist
named Wolfgang Pauli...
...was desperately
seeking a particle to
rescue one of the pillars
of modern physics.
The law of the conservation
of energy.
So why didn't I flinch?
Because the laws of science
differ fundamentally...
...from those of
other human endeavors.
In order for an idea
to become a scientific law...
...it has to be unbreakable.
That's why I was willing to bet this face
on the laws of conservation of energy.
Now, if you try this at home...
...take care not to give
the cannonball a push.
That's adding energy...
...and the ball will surely
come back and do some damage.
You just have to let it go, like this:
By lifting the ball...
...you give it gravitational energy...
...which is the potential
to fall and accelerate.
The Cannonball is going fastest
when it's at the bottom of its arc.
At that moment, it's
converted all of its
gravitational energy to
the energy of motion.
As it swings...
...the cannonball is
constantly exchanging one
of these two kinds of
energy for the other.
But the total amount of energy
remains constant.
That's an example
of the law of conservation of energy.
Once the cannonball is released...
...it can never gain more energy
than it had to begin with.
It has no way to fly up
and break my nose.
The energy accounting books
are always strictly balanced.
There's no such thing as cheating.
So in the 20th century...
...when physicists first calculated
the energy of atoms precisely...
...they were startled to discover
an apparent violation of this law.
They found that
in some radioactive atoms...
...the nucleus can spontaneously
eject an electron.
This transforms the atom
into a different element.
The physicists were mystified.
The energy of the escaped electron
plus that of the new element...
...adds up to less than the energy
in the original nucleus.
But the law says, "Thou shalt not
destroy or create energy."
So where did the missing energy go?
In 1930, Wolfgang Pauli predicted
there must be an undiscovered particle.
One that makes off
with the missing energy.
At the time...
...Pauli lamented that
such a phantom particle
might be so minute,
swift and evasive...
...as to forever defy detection.
But that was a rare failure
of his imagination.
Because science is always searching
for a way to go deeper still.
A generation later...
...Pauli's neutrinos were actually
detected for the first time...
...in radiation from a nuclear reactor.
And we've been finding them,
with difficulty, ever since.
There are scientists today...
...who are trying to find a way
to ride those neutrinos...
...all the way back
to the beginning of time.
We'll go as far as they have gone
to come up against the wall of forever.
TYSON".
The wall of forever is nothing new.
Our ancestors came up against it almost
as soon as they first started imagining it.
A million dawns ago,
in the 13th century BC...
...the Egyptians built this temple
at Abu Simbel...
...to honor the pharaoh Ramses II,
depicted here in four colossal statues.
Reigning even above this mighty king...
...is the falcon-headed Ra-Harakhte,
god of the sun.
The temple was designed
so that the light from the rising sun...
...could only enter the sanctuary
on two days every year.
As the rays enter the temple...
...they burnish the statues of the gods
with their golden light...
...before penetrating the sanctuary.
Even then, one god remains in shadow...
...Ptah, lord of creation...
...as if the origin of the universe
must forever be concealed.
Feel the sun on your face.
The energy that warms you began its
journey some 10 million years ago...
...in the heart of the sun.
Unlike neutrinos...
...the photons needed that long to work
their way out from the core to the surface.
Why? Because they were colliding billions
of times per second with the sun's atoms...
...every collision sending them off
in a random direction.
Once they finally reached the surface...
...they were free to dash nonstop
at the speed of light...
...in a mere eight minutes
and 2O seconds from the sun to you.
Ten-million-year-old light on your face.
What was happening
when that light left the heart of the sun?
The cosmic calendar
compresses the entire
13.8-billion-year history
of the universe...
...into a single year.
Every month represents
about a billion years.
Every day, about 40 million years.
The universe is so old
that on the cosmic calendar...
...1O million years ago
only takes us back as far as...
...6 p.m. on the last evening
of the last day of the year.
And what about us?
Humans had yet to evolve.
Ten million years ago...
...our ancestors were anthropoid apes...
...swinging through the trees of Africa.
To us, 10 million years
seems like a long time...
...but it's only the length of an afternoon
on the timescale of the cosmos.
The sun began fusing hydrogen
4500 million years ago.
August 31st on the cosmic calendar.
Our Milky Way Galaxy
is about 10,000 million years old.
The first galaxies
formed a few billion years earlier.
And something keeps me from going
any further back in time.
What is this?
It's the nature of light and time.
Because light travels at a finite speed...
...to look across space...
...is to look back in time.
So the farther we see,
the older the light.
This is as far back in the history
of the cosmos as we can see with light.
It's a baby picture of the universe
when it was only 380,000 years old.
That's 15 minutes into January 1st
on the cosmic calendar.
If we look as far as we can see in any
direction using microwave telescopes...
...this is what we see...
...the glow left over from the Big Bang.
Imagine that all the matter and energy
of the observable universe...
...was concentrated into something
no larger than this.
That's the size of the universe...
...when it was a trillionth of a trillionth
of a trillionth of a second old.
All the matter and energy
of the hundred billion galaxies...
...now splayed out across
the billions of light-years...
...were once pent up
in something the size of a marble.
Can you imagine how tightly packed
that marble must have been?
Far too dense for any kind of light
to move through it...
...but no obstacle for the likes
of neutrinos.
The Big Bang must have produced
stupendous numbers of neutrinos...
...which flew unhindered through
that inconceivable crush of matter.
The very thing that makes them
almost impossible to detect...
...is what allows neutrinos
to sail through the
curtain that conceals
the beginning of time.
Where are they now?
They're here, they're there,
everywhere throughout the universe.
Neutrinos from creation
are within you.
From a marble to the cosmos.
This is the road that Thales and Democritus
put us on some 2500 years ago.
A road of endless searching.
A relentless, systematic hunt
for new worlds...
...and an ever-deepening
understanding of nature.
Who among you will pick up that torch
and take us down that next stretch of road?