Once again, I am free to smite the worId...
...as I did in days Iong past.
When the evil shape-shifting wizard, Aku,
arose from the bowels of hate...
...to ravage our homeland,
I was a young emperor at the time...
...and was heIpIess against his powers.
But I remembered our grandfather's
grandfather's story of three monks...
...who were gifted with mysticaI powers.
I rode to the highest peak
of the mountainside...
...where the monks agreed to forge me
an enchanted sword with great magic.
Armed with the sword and the hope of my
peopIe, I pIunged into battIe against Aku.
His eviI was no match for the power
of righteousness.
And with the sword's magic, Aku's demon
forces were impIanted into the earth...
...forever petrifying him into
the wasteIand that he created.
Through years of hard work,
we have rebuiIt our gIorious past...
...with hopes never to encounter
such an eviI as Aku again.
AIways be aIert, my son.
For the presence of eviI is sometimes
right behind you.
No, it cannot be.
Aku.
The sword.
Not this time.
Mother, Aku has returned.
Do as we have pIanned.
Our future depends on it.
Break.
Here's some water, my emperor.
None for him.
I'm sorry, emperor.
Water. Water. Water.
I said, no water!
He has returned.
Insubordinate fooI.
No one attacks Aku's minions.
Destroy him.
My son.
What has happened to our Iand, Father?
It has been many years
since that fatefuI day...
...that Aku returned
from his imprisonment.
EnsIaved, we have become,
to unearth the riches of our Iand...
...so that Aku can strengthen his powers...
...and begin to take over the worId.
Do not worry, Father. For with the power
of this sword, I wiII vanquish Aku...
...sending him back into the pit
of hate from which he came.
No!
I thought once Iike you,
but the sword is onIy a tooI.
What power has it compared
to the hand that wieIds it?
EviI is cIever, and deception
is its most powerfuI weapon.
Let the sword guide you to your fate...
...but Iet your mind set free
the path to your destiny.
I wiII not faiI you, Father.
Be wary, my son,
for eviI finds a way.
The mist is fuII of demons. Aku is near.
Aku!
Who dares to summon
the master of masters?
The deIiverer of darkness?
The shogun of sorrow, Aku.
I am the Iost son of the Iand
that you have piIIaged.
I am here to recIaim it.
For my peopIe. For my father.
For my birthright.
FooI.
No mortaI can hurt the great Aku.
That sword. I remember that bIade.
I recognize your bIood.
You are the son of the fooI
who imprisoned me those many years ago.
No matter.
Neither he nor the sword had the power
to sIay me forever.
And neither do you.
No matter what form you take, Aku...
...you wiII never defeat the side
of righteousness.
Now, demon, with the bIessings
of righteousness...
...and the power of the sacred bIade...
...I cast thee back to the viIe pit
from which you came.
You might have beaten me now,
but I wiII destroy you in the future.
There is no future for you, Aku.
I disagree.
What trickery is this?
Aku--
Do not worry, samurai.
You wiII see me again.
But next time you wiII not be so fortunate.
[ENGLISH]