Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Charge!
I, aIone, was the onIy survivor.
My entire robot army,
compIeteIy annihiIated!
In my dreams I stiII see arrows...
...faIIing Iike rain!
What does the tower hoId that wouId make
you sacrifice a whoIe army?
Treasure? GoId? Rubies?
Bah! Nothing as materiaIistic as treasure.
At the top of the tower is
a mysticaI weII...
...the weII of King Ozerick.
Those who reach the infamous weII...
...are granted one wish.
Your greatest desire.
Get out of the great Khan's chair!
What are you, teIIing stories again?!
Get swabbing the deck
or I'II toss you overboard! You has-been!
Excuse me.
Is this pIace you speak of reaI?
Of course! As a matter of fact,
we're passing it now.
There!
In the center of that mist-shrouded isIe...
...Iies the treasure of King Ozerick.
Thank you.
Huh? What? Wait!
I beg you, reconsider.
There are onIy three archers,
yet they decimated my whoIe army.
You are just one man!
Do the math. Why attempt it?
That weII couId get me home.
There are other ways to get home.
Not for me.
It's no use.
No one can fight Iike this.
A great warrior...
...must be in tune with aII of his senses.
OnIy then wiII you be abIe to extend
your awareness...
...so that you may fight on any IeveI.
-Try again.
-Yes, sifu.
I must fight on their IeveI.
I am ready.
Where? What?
I can see!
We're restored!
How is it possibIe?
You have broken our curse.
We thank you.
-I have come to make a wish at this weII.
-The weII is yours.
Proclaim your wish, great warrior...
...and it will be fulfilled
beyond your wildest dream.
My quest has finaIIy come to an end.
-Oh, mystic weII, I humbIy wish--
-Wait!
We must warn you.
Any wish granted comes with a price.
It was forever ago, we fought Iong and hard
to reach this weII.
When we arrived, we stood before the weII
and made our wish:
To be the greatest of warriors.
The spirit of the weII did, indeed,
make us great warriors.
But in so doing, robbed us
of our sight and our minds...
...ensIaving us as its personaI guard.
We have Iived cursed Iives untiI now.
EviI spirit of the weII...
...you wiII not cIaim another innocent!
I wish thee destroyed!
The greatest of warriors.
A nobIe spirit.
Such sacrifice.
[ENGLISH]