Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
-Yeah?
-Ricko Benny Giordano.
Come on in.
WeIcome to the BIue Monkey.
WeIcome, friends. And a warm weIcome
to the Buddy Righteous Orchestra.
And without any further ado...
...pIease weIcome
the IoveIy LuIa LiIIywhite.
Okay, mac, that's enough.
Nice and sIow.
That's right, put the butter knife away.
Come on. Move it
before we throw you out.
Wait. Let him stay.
It's okay. Let him go, see?
-You know, we couId use a guy Iike you.
-''We''?
Me and the boys, see?
Stitches, Mr. Shine,
Mr. PibbIes and KnuckIes.
-Yeah. WeII, actuaIIy, my reaI name is Joe.
-Mr. PibbIes.
What exactIy does your organization do?
Why, me and the boys sort of run things
around this town. Know what I mean?
Say, how'd you Iike to--?
It's aII right.
You can put them down now.
How'd you Iike to be a member
of the most feared gang in the city, see?
What activities does your gang
participate in?
Stitches, break it down for him.
We fix things. Know what I mean?
Make sure money goes to the right pIaces
around here: the horses, casinos, banks.
You foIIow?
You are invoIved in crime.
Now, did I say that?
Enough has been said.
Your activities are of no interest to me.
I wish to be no part of your group.
So a prima donna, eh?
Get out of here. Go on.
Beat it, aItar boy.
What are you, crazy?
You out of your mind?
What's up with this guy?
WeII, what are you aII
standing around for?
We got a deIivery to make for Aku.
-Do you mean the great and powerfuI Aku?
-Of course.
The master of darkness, the shogun
of sorrow, the big boss himseIf: Aku.
-And you have deaIings with Aku in person?
-Sure. AII the time.
-What's it to you anyway?
-PIease forgive me. I thought you were--
-SmaII time?
-WeII, no. I--
Oh, so now Mr. Goody-Two-SandaIs
feeIs Iike taIking, eh?
PIease understand. I have spent my Iifetime
preparing to come face to face with Aku.
FuIfiIIing this goaI wouId
forever change my Iife.
Okay, boy. We'II give you a shot.
But you gotta pass
a IittIe test first, see?
You know, to prove
you got the stomach for it.
Here's the skinny.
It's not a hard job, but your heart's
gotta be in the right place, see?
One of our clients, see, hasn't
been paying his protection money.
So he needs to be rubbed out.
You tell him the Society for the Preservation
of Animal Love has sent a surprise gift...
...as a token of appreciation
for his ongoing love of animals, see?
Then you got 20 seconds
to hightail it out of there...
...and then it's "bang. "
The gift that keeps on giving.
-WeII, kid, how'd it go?
-It went exactIy as pIanned.
The oId man took the package.
I said my Iines exactIy
as I was supposed to.
He never suspected a thing.
After which,
I immediately left the premises.
He never knew what hit him.
You shouId not be concerned with any
further payment probIems with your cIients.
Pretty coId-bIooded, kid.
I'm impressed, see?
A price must be paid for disobedience.
I Iike this guy.
Boys, meet ''Jackie the BIade.''
Looking pretty good there, huh? Yeah.
Nice-Iooking suit. Sure.
-Terrific.
-I Iike the shoes.
With aII the accouterments, see?
Yeah, great.
How come he gets the cooI name?
AII right, you knuckIeheads, Iisten up.
We're here to taIk about a very big job.
One of very speciaI interest
to the big boss himseIf.
-Aku?
-That's right, Jackie.
Now, nobody's ever puIIed
this one off, see?
But with you on our side,
we'II smoke it.
And we wiII get to meet Aku?
Not onIy wiII you get to meet him,
but if we puII this off successfuIIy...
...the big boss wiII make us richer
beyond our wiIdest dreams, see?
Boys, say heIIo
to the PubIic Works and UtiIities BuiIding.
HeIIo.
It's a weII-kept secret
that deep inside this buiIding...
...Iies the Iegendary Neptune JeweI, see?
And it's our job to get it out.
You mean, we gotta fit
inside that IittIe thing?
-What is the importance of this jeweI?
-Here's the short version, Jackie.
Long before you was born or I was born
or anybody was born...
...the Neptune Jewel was kept inside
this mountain, see?
Legend has it, it was placed there
by an ancient spirit...
...who gave the jewel special powers
to control all the waters of the world, see?
Naturally,
Aku wanted the jewel's power...
...so evil could control the world,
which it should.
But then, this no-good, goody two-shoes,
good-for-nothing got in the way, see?
I don't know how she did it,
but she beat our boss.
And she summoned
the forces of nature to guard it:
Earth.
Wind.
And Fire.
And so Earth, Wind and Fire have guarded
the jewel for centuries, see?
Making it impossible for Aku
to get his hands on it.
And since the big boss himself
couldn't close the deal...
...it's been centuries since anybody's even
thought about it. So you see, see?
You'd have to be pretty nuts
to try to swipe the Neptune JeweI.
At Ieast that's what I thought,
untiI I saw Jackie here in action.
The way you cIeaned up them robot thugs
at the BIue Monkey...
...made me think we're just nuts enough
to puII this one off.
So are you game, Jackie?
To stand in Aku's presence,
I wouId consider no feat too great.
Way to go, Jackie. That's pretty cooI.
You know what you're doing.
AII right, here's the pIan, Jackie.
We strike this Sunday at midnight, see?
You wiII never possess the Neptune JeweI.
You wiII not escape.
-Come and get me.
-InsoIent fooI!
Hey, Iook.
He did it.
Way to go there, Jackie-boy!
What do you know about that?
That's reaIIy something.
Who dares to summon--? Oh, it is you.
Yes. You see--
Do you forget that you are forbidden
to come here?
Yeah, boss, I know.
But this time we reaIIy got something.
Something big, see?
What can you possibIy have...
...that the aImighty Aku cannot attain?
-The JeweI of Neptune.
-What? It cannot be.
The power to controI
aII the water of the worId.
OnIy for you, my Iord.
Yes. It truIy is the magicaI jeweI.
But how did such an eIusive treasure
come into your possession?
WeII, it wasn't easy, master. But we got
a IittIe heIp from our newest member.
-Come on out, Jackie.
-Jackie?
-ActuaIIy, it's Jack.
-You!
What the heck is going on, man?
You wiII not defeat me so easiIy.
Yes. It won't be easy,
but it wiII be worth the effort.
The sword!
Why is Jackie
fighting the big boss, boss?
I don't know, see? But we'd better save
Jackie before he ain't no more.
No tricks wiII save you this time, Aku.
Aku!
Easy there, Jackie-boy.
What? Where am I? What happened?
Can you beIieve this guy?
What happened, Jackie,
is that we saved your Iife.
You what?
You see, you Iost your mind back there
and started to duke it out with the big boss.
So we naiIed you over the head, man.
Lights out. And here we are.
Yeah. We saved you before Aku
had a chance...
...to put you out of commission
permanentIy.
I cannot beIieve this!
What's not to beIieve?
We saved you Iike you saved us.
No! You do not understand!
You must take me back immediateIy!
Aren't you Iistening, Jackie?
We can't take you back.
Aku wouId destroy you, see?
Besides, we couIdn't even if we wanted to.
When we dragged you out,
Aku's castIe disappeared.
Who knows where it'II pop up next.
Hey, what's aII this about anyway?
You got some death wish or something?
No! You don't understand!
I have deceived you.
-Hey. You mean, you ain't one of us, man?
-No.
You are criminaIs.
It is not honorabIe.
You see, Iong ago this Iand was good,
its peopIe honest.
But then Aku came....
It does not matter. My quest continues.
I am sorry about the deception,
but it had to be done.
Now, if you pIease, the jeweI.
We don't have it, see?
We gave it to Aku.
Mr. PibbIes?
Yeah, you know, during
aII the commotion, I kept it.
You know, for safekeeping.
Thank you.
I must return it to its proper pIace.
-Wait, Jackie. Let us do it.
-Why?
WeII, aII this crime business has suddenIy
put a bad taste in my mouth, yeah.
Yeah, we're going Iegit, see?
For our first gig,
we're gonna return the jeweI.
It's the honorabIe thing to do.
I feeI you wiII be happier
on the path of righteousness.
Goodbye.
Yeah, I think we wiII too.
Sucker.
Step right up.
Get your water right here.
OnIy 500 smackers per ounce.
[ENGLISH]