Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Come.
Come to me.
Who is there?
Come.
Show yourseIf.
Come to me.
Coward.
Come.
Come to me.
Something eviI has ravaged these Iands.
A very famiIiar eviI.
Yes. Come to me.
Come.
The voice beckons me further in.
SureIy he takes me for a fooI
to foIIow deeper into his trap.
A fooI I be!
Come.
WeIcome to your doom.
Many warriors have been
Iured here to their end.
Why have you done this?
My purpose is to battIe.
Yes.
At Iast, after aII these years,
a worthy opponent.
Enough of this pointIess battIe.
I wiII continue to fight you no more.
I say thee nay!
No! I wiII not do battIe with you for
your amusement. There is no honor in it.
Honor? What do thee know of honor?
A miIIennium hath passed,
and now my goaI is within my grasp.
This battIe wiII continue to the end.
I said, I wiII not fight you, monster.
I shaII not be denied!
Strike me down if you must...
...but I wiII not fight.
Nay.
I cannot strike the defenseIess.
This battIe must be concIuded
by the warrior's code.
I beg thee.
Rise, unsheathe your sword,
continue this fight.
-Why?
-For freedom.
The master of this kingdom of rock
is just a man.
A cursed man trapped in a rock body.
It happened Iong ago.
So Iong ago now.
'Twas once a time where I, too, was a man.
A mighty warrior Iike thee.
I have engraved a recording
of my past...
...so that I wouId never forget
the Iife I had, the man I was...
...so thy peopIe wouId not be Iost
to the dust of time.
Let me take thee on a journey
into the past.
This land 'twas not always
parched and burnt.
Once, a beautiful city thrived
in the lush countryside.
'Twas truly a sight to behold.
A jewel of all the northern lands.
My happiness was a beautiful family
of a wife, two sons...
...and a faithful canine.
Times were good, game was plentiful,
and my people prospered.
'Twas on return from a successful
hunting trip when an omen appeared.
A black moon blocked out the sun.
It grew and grew,
until it ate the sky and land.
The darkness now loomed over my kingdom.
A horrible monster,
born from within the darkness, attacked.
My army retaliated.
But our efforts were to no avail.
'Twere I alone who was left
to destroy the monster.
My weapons were worthless.
My attempts to avenge
amused the monster...
...and he struck me down.
I lay before him,
ready to battle for the last time.
But the villain did not destroy me.
Nay, the fate dealt to me
was much more cruel.
He imprisoned me
within an unbreakable crystal...
...denying me a warrior's end.
Helpless was I as the beast destroyed...
...what was left of my beloved kingdom.
Then he came for me again.
'Twas his enjoyment that day
to punish me for eternity.
Thrust me, he did,
into the core of the mountain.
'Twas his plan for me to spend
all of eternity in the mountain...
...never to join my fallen comrades
in Valhalla...
...the resting place of all great warriors.
Through countless eons I laid still...
...but my will was strong.
I found a way to manipulate
the material around me.
Out of the rock, I formed the body
thou seest before thee.
Then I created a passage so full
of peril and danger...
...that only the greatest of warriors
can pass.
For, you see,
the only entry into Valhalla...
...is to fall in combat to another warrior.
And thou are the onIy one to survive.
As written, the truth has been toId.
My fate is at your mercy.
Prepare yourseIf.
At Iast, the gates of VaIhaIIa open to me.
Rise, warrior! Rise!
HonorabIy I must be defeated.
I cannot Iet up.
Do not worry.
I have onIy begun to fight.
After aII these years...
...my freedom has arrived.
Accursed monster, your speII is broken!
I am free!
At Iast, my fIesh is restored.
The curse is Iifted.
Warrior.
I.... I....
Don't worry, my friend.
PIease, hand me my sword.
Thank you.
[ENGLISH]