I love when the car place
puts that paper mat on the floor.
Like they're so obsessed
with cleanliness.
They don't even want their shoes
to touch the carpet.
The mechanic comes out,
he looks like Al Jolson.
He's covered in goo from head to toe.
You can't even see him.
I prefer that to when they have the
lab coat, the clipboard, the glasses.
Now you know
you're getting screwed.
"Can I see it?"
"You better not.
It's idling quietly right now.
I think it should stay overnight.
We want to keep an eye on it,
and want to keep the bill running up."
Tell the players that
I reimbursed the trainer...
...for the cigarettes and shakes.
- The players will be reimbursed?
- The trainer.
Tell the players
I reimbursed the trainer.
This is the third time
I've had to repeat myself.
- Sorry.
- Sorry doesn't cut it.
We're running
a ball club here, George.
You've got to pay attention.
I know. It won't happen again.
Let me see.
I had an assignment for you.
Let me... Let me think here.
Elaine.
Hi, Mr. Peterman.
You know what a huge fan
I am of John F. Kennedy.
I do.
The Peace Corps gave me
my start in this business.
Clothing the naked natives
of Bangtubesh.
The Pygmy pullover.
Sotheby's is having an auction
of JFK's memorabilia.
One item in particular
has caught my eye.
The presidential golf clubs.
To me, they capture that indefinable
romance that was Camelot.
Whatever.
Unfortunately, I will be
out of town with my lady...
...and therefore unable
to bid on the lot.
I was hoping you would go
in my stead.
Oh, yeah. I'd be happy to.
How much do you want this thing?
How high are you willing to go?
I would see no trouble in spending
up to, say, $10,000.
Have my secretary give you a check.
- When you're done, George,
and bring it directly to me.
Mr. Steinbrenner is
very interested in this.
- Yes, sir.
- Yes, George.
I want you to make this project
a top priority.
I will, sir. Top priority.
- Top priority, George.
- Top priority.
So he walks out of the stall.
He's been talking the whole time.
- He pulled an LBJ on you.
- LBJ?
Lyndon Johnson used to do that
to his staffers.
- No kidding?
- Oh, yeah.
He'd hold national security
meetings in there.
He planned the Hanoi bombing
after a bad Thai meal.
I don't know what
I'm supposed to do.
I don't even know
what my assignment is.
Ask him to repeat it.
Tell him there was an echo.
I can't. He's been on me
about not paying attention.
It's too late.
I already told him I heard him.
You know what you do?
Ask him a follow-up question.
Tell him you're having trouble getting
started, and you want his advice.
Yeah, follow-up question.
That'll work.
- Hey, bud.
- Hey.
- Can I have my keys...
- Yeah.
- Back please.
- You should have come, Jerry.
- We made quite a haul.
- Where did you go?
- Price Club.
- Why didn't you take your car?
- Oh, the steering wheel fell off.
I don't know where it is.
What are you doing?
Don't throw that away.
Well, I'm not paying the 5 cents
for that stupid recycling thing.
You don't pay 5 cents.
You get 5 cents back.
Read the label.
"Vermont, Connecticut,
Massachusetts, New York.
Refund, 5 cents."
- Refund?
- Yeah.
Well, what do you think
the hobos are doing?
I don't know. They're deranged.
Listen. Can you give me
a lift back to my place?
No, I can't. I've gotta pick up Elaine.
I'm taking her to this Kennedy auction.
- All right. I'll see you later.
- All right.
- What is this "MI, 10 cents"?
- That's Michigan.
In Michigan you get 10 cents.
- Ten cents?
- Yeah.
Wait a minute, you mean you get
5 cents here and 10 cents there?
You could round up bottles
and run them to Michigan.
- No, it doesn't work.
- What do you mean?
You get enough bottles...
You overload your inventory, and you
blow your margins on gasoline.
Trust me. It doesn't work.
You're not talking that Michigan
deposit-bottle scam?
- No, I'm off that.
- You tried it?
Oh, yeah. Every which way.
Couldn't crunch the numbers.
It drove me crazy.
You keep an eye on each other?
- No problem.
- You bet.
Are you sure you didn't hear
my car making a funny noise?
I know those two idiots did
something to it.
No, I didn't hear anything.
Oh, my God. Look who's here.
Sue Ellen Mischke, the braless,
Oh Henry! Candy bar heiress.
Well, hello, Elaine, Jerry.
- Hi, Sue Ellen.
I'm surprised to see you here.
Come to catch a glimpse
of high society?
No, no, I'm actually here to bid,
Sue Ellen.
I mean,
that is if anything's to my liking.
I'm here to catch
a glimpse of high society.
Well, I hope you find something
that fits your budget.
I hate that woman.
I don't understand.
You fill an 18-wheeler.
No, an 18-wheeler's no good.
Too much overhead.
You got permits,
weigh stations, tolls.
Look, you're way out of your league.
I wanna learn.
I want to know why.
Oh, those are handsome.
Look at that set.
Yeah, think I might bid on those.
Lot number 745.
We have a full set of golf clubs...
...that were owned
by President John F. Kennedy...
...as seen in the famous photo of the
president chipping at Burning Tree...
...on the morning
of the Bay of Pigs Invasion.
The set is in perfect condition,
and we will start the biding at $4000.
Four thousand dollars?
Do I have $4000? I have $4000.
Do I have 5? Five thousand dollars?
I have $5000. Do I have 6?
Six thousand dollars
for this set of beautiful clubs.
Six? I have $6000.
Can I have 6500?
Sixty-five hundred
to the dark-haired person on the right.
We are at 6500.
Do I hear 6600?
The president's own golf clubs.
Leisure life at Camelot.
Sixty-five hundred going once.
Eight thousand.
Eight thousand. We have 8000.
The bid is now $8000.
What is she doing?
She's starting in on the biding now?
Eighty-five hundred.
- We have 85.
- Nine thousand.
Nine thousand dollars.
I think she wants those clubs.
Do I hear 95?
Ninety-five hundred.
- Ninety-five hundred.
- Ten thousand.
Ten thousand
to the shapely woman on the left.
Ten thousand going once.
- That's you're ceiling.
- Ten thousand going twice.
- Eleven thousand.
- Twelve thousand.
- Thirteen thousand.
- Fourteen thousand.
Fifteen thousand.
Peterman is gonna kill me.
I really thought
you had her there at 17,000.
Why didn't you stop me?
Do you hear this clunking?
A little.
Oh, you know what?
I'm gonna grab these from you later.
You'll take care of them.
Okay? Okay.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Alrighty. Bye.
- Bye.
What is going on here?
Oh, my God.
Oh, you idiots!
So we could put the bottles
in a U-Haul.
- Go lean and mean.
- Newman, it's a dead end. Come on.
- Hey, there he is.
- Hey.
You put your groceries under
the hood of my car?
Oh, that's right.
We forgot about those.
That's where my missing soda is.
And your crab legs?
And a thing of cheese?
The AAA guy said I was close to
sucking a muffin down the carburettor.
- What were you thinking?
- We ran out of space.
Now I gotta take the car to Tony
and get it checked out.
- He's good.
- He's real good.
But he's so obsessive
about the car.
He makes me feel guilty about
everything wrong with it.
I gotta get it washed before
I take it down or he'll yell at me.
- Choke?
- No, thank you.
Oh, yeah.
I remember this car. Beautiful car.
Yeah, so anyway, the engine's been
idling a little rough.
I thought it might be time
for a check-up.
There's nothing wrong on the inside.
The shift knob is loose.
You know about that?
- No, I hadn't noticed.
- Have you been picking at it?
Have I been picking at it?
No, you know,
it's just wear and tear.
Wear and tear, I see.
The engine's the only thing
that needs checking.
- You been rotating the tires?
- Try to.
You don't try to. You do it.
Fifty-one percent of all turns
are right turns.
That's right.
Twenty thousand dollars?
Elaine, that's twice the amount
I authorized you to spend.
I know, Mr. Peterman,
but once I saw them...
...I just couldn't stand to let anyone
else have them, you know.
Certainly not some
stuck-up candy-bar heiress...
...who flaunts herself in public
without regard...
Well, where are they?
They should be here today.
- Mr. Wilhelm.
- Yes, George.
Hi, I was just...
I just had one little question
about my assignment.
Well, I trust things are
moving smoothly.
Mr. Steinbrenner's counting on you.
Yes, yes, very smooth,
super smooth.
But I really want to attack this thing.
You know, sink my teeth into it.
So I was just wondering...
...what do you think would be
the very best way to get started?
Get started?
I don't understand, George.
- I was wondering...
- You haven't been to Payroll?
- No, I haven't done that.
- What's the problem?
Now, come on, George. I told
the big man you were moving on this.
Now, don't let him down!
Payroll!
Hello there.
I'm George Costanza.
Yes.
Assistant to the travelling secretary.
I'm working on the project.
- What project?
- The payroll project.
Wilhelm?
Big, big payroll project.
You're gonna have to fill me in.
You know what?
I'll look around for awhile.
- I'll just browse around.
- Hey, wait. Excuse me.
You can't come back here.
I'm under direct orders
from Mr. Wilhelm.
If you have a problem,
you just take it up with him.
Well, maybe I will.
You know what?
I urge you to take it up with him.
Go ahead. Give him a call.
He'll tell you what I'm doing here.
Then you can tell me.
Mr. Wilhelm,
this is Lafarge in Payroll.
There's a Costanza here,
says he's working on some project.
Oh, I see. Interesting.
Well, that's quite a project.
All right. Thank you.
I'm sorry that I doubted you.
Whatever you need,
just make yourself at home.
So he explained it all to you?
Yes, he explained it all very clearly.
- What did he tell you?
- Look, you were right, I was wrong.
You don't have
to humiliate me about it.
Damn.
Oh, Mother's Day.
Wait a second.
Mother's Day.
Yes!
Come on, Kramer!
- What?
- It's the truck, Kramer, the truck.
Look, Newman,
I told you to let this thing go.
No, no, no, listen to me.
Most days, the post office sends
one truckload of mail...
...to the second domestic regional
sorting facility in Saginaw, Michigan.
But on the week before holidays,
we see a surge.
On Valentine's Day,
we send two trucks.
On Christmas, four,
packed to the brim.
And tomorrow,
if history is any guide...
...we'll see some spillover
into a fifth truck.
- Mother's Day.
- The mother of all mail days.
And guess who's signed up
for the truck?
A free truck?
Oh, boy, that completely changes
our cost structure.
Our G and A goes down 50 percent.
We carry a couple of bags of mail,
the rest is ours!
Newman, you magnificent bastard,
you did it!
Let the collecting begin!
So did you go down to Payroll?
Yes, Payroll. Yes, I did.
Very productive. Payroll paid off.
Then I guess
you'll be heading downtown, huh?
Oh, yeah. Downtown, definitely.
I'm very interested
to see how this thing turns out.
You said it. Excuse me, Mr. Wilhelm,
do you really think...?
Well...
Is this downtown trip really necessary,
you know, for the project?
Oh, no, you've got
to go downtown, George.
It's all downtown.
- Just like the song says.
- The song?
There's your answer, "Downtown."
The song "Downtown"?
The Petula Clark song?
Yeah.
You're sure he didn't mention it
because you were going downtown?
I think he was trying to tell me
something, like it had some meaning.
Okay, so how does it go?
When you're alone
And life is making you lonely
You can always go
Downtown
Maybe you know
Some little places to go to
Where they never close
- Downtown
- Wait a second.
Little places to go that never close.
What little place never closes?
- 7-Eleven.
- Maybe.
Just listen to the music
Of the traffic in the city
Linger on the sidewalk
Where the neon lights are pretty
Where the neon lights are pretty.
The Broadway area?
No, that's midtown.
Midtown.
The lights are much brighter there
You can forget all your troubles
Forget all your cares
Just go
Downtown
Things will be great
When you're
Downtown
I got nothing, Jerry, nothing.
Well, don't hang around
and let your troubles surround you.
There are movie shows.
You think I should come clean?
What do you think?
You think I should confess?
How can you lose?
Yeah, Jerry,
it's Tony Abado at the shop.
Look, we gotta talk.
You better come down.
Anytime after 4.
- Hello.
- Hi, it's me.
- Oh, hi.
- Listen, I need to come over...
...and pick up the clubs.
- Oh, you know what?
- Oh, no. What?
No, it's no big deal.
I left the clubs in the car.
You left them in the car?
- How could you leave them in the car?
- I forgot.
Oh, go down and get them.
I can't.
The car's at the mechanic's.
Oh, this is great.
All right. Where's the mechanic?
I'll just go and pick them up myself.
No, no, you can't.
He's working on the car right now.
You cannot disturb him
while he's working.
I'm going there in an hour
if you wanna meet me there.
You know the place.
It's on 56th Street.
Oh, okay. All right. Fine.
Hey, Tony.
- Thanks for coming in, Jerry.
- Sure.
I think I know what's going on here,
and I just want to hear it from you.
But I want you
to be straight with me.
Don't lie to me, Jerry.
You know that motor oil
you're putting in there?
It's from those
quickie-lube places, isn't it?
- Well, I change it so often. I mean...
- Motor oil is the lifeblood of a car.
You put in a low-grade oil,
you can damage vital engine parts.
Okay, see this gasket?
I have no confidence in that gasket.
- Tony, I really don't...
- Here's what I wanna do.
I wanna overhaul the entire engine.
But it's gonna take
a major commitment from you.
You're gonna have to keep it under
60 miles an hour for awhile.
You gotta come in, and you gotta get
the oil changed every 1000 miles.
How much money is
this gonna cost me?
I don't understand you.
It's your own car
we're talking about.
You know, you wrote
the wrong mileage down on the form.
You barely know the car.
Don't know the mileage,
the tire pressure.
When's the last time you checked
the washer fluid?
- But the washer fluid is fine.
- The washer fluid is not fine!
You know what...
...I just wanna take my car and
I'm gonna bring it someplace else.
- What do you mean?
- Just can I have my car.
I'm gonna to pay my bill
and be on my way.
- Well, the car's on a lift.
- Well, just get it down.
All right.
Okay. Well, wait here and I'll...
I'll bring it around.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Hey, where's the car?
- He's bringing it.
- Good.
Okay. Thank you.
So, what did they say?
They're sending
a detective tomorrow.
What the hell were you thinking
leaving my clubs in that car?
Well, I didn't count on my mechanic
pulling a Mary Beth Whitehead, did I?
Well, what kind of maniac
is this guy?
He's a very special maniac.
- What do I tell Mr. Peterman?
- I don't know.
Why couldn't
you take better care of that car?
- Well, are they here?
- Mr. Peterman...
...there seems to be a bit of a snag.
Snag?
It seems that
a psychotic mechanic...
...has absconded
with my friend's car.
What does that have
to do with my clubs?
They happened to be
in the back seat at the time.
What was the suspect wearing
at the time of the incident?