I'm flying over the Great Rift Valley
in East Africa.
And below me is a landscape in turmoil,
torn apart by the twisting
and buckling of the Earth's crust.
It's also a landscape
of huge and unpredictable change
that forces animals day by day,
season by season,
to gamble with their lives.
But for those who win,
this is one of the most fertile
landscapes on Earth.
Nyiragongo, the largest lava
lake in the world.
Bubbling up from nearly 10 miles
beneath the surface.
Nowhere takes you closer
to the fiery heart of the planet.
Mount Nyiragongo is one
of the most active volcanoes in Africa.
Its eruptions can be seen from space.
As magma churns below the Earth's crust,
the land to the east of here
is being torn apart.
Volcanoes like this are continually
changing the face of Eastern Africa.
The volcanoes here
may have a violent side,
but life flows from these infernos.
Fertile ash from countless eruptions
carpets the land,
creating the ideal conditions
for grasses to flourish
on an immense scale.
And with the grasses,
come animals in numbers
found nowhere else on Earth.
Wildebeest.
Nothing stands in their way.
All this just to reach fresh grass.
The ever-travelling herds
are only one element of life here.
Look closer and there
are new stories to tell.
Living on the savannah
is about making the most of the hand
the landscape deals you.
But here it's always a gamble.
Everything may change tomorrow.
From their vantage point,
agama lizards wait
for the arrival of the herds,
ready to seize their moment.
It's pay day.
Over a million wildebeest
on their doorstep.
And with the wildebeest
come flying insects.
Billions of them.
Food,
if only they could catch them.
Time for a rethink.
This agama lizard
has spotted an opportunity.
Only one thing attracts more flies
than the wildebeest.
Lions that have eaten wildebeest.
Lions are famously-bad tempered.
They could swat the lizard
like the flies he's hoping to ambush.
He will need to pick
his target carefully.
Not her.
Or her.
Maybe.
But no.
To be within striking distance,
he's got to hold his nerve.
Got one.
Now, he's getting his eye in.
But this might be a bit ambitious.
It may take courage to hunt
on the back of a lion.
But it takes sense
to know when to run away.
The wildebeest won't stay for long.
And when they leave,
most of the flies will follow.
Change is everywhere in East Africa.
This grassland was once
covered by a forest
that ran unbroken
from west coast to east coast.
Today, high above the plains,
swirling clouds
hide mountains that tower
three miles into the sky.
These frozen summits now form
part of a mountainous barrier
separating the ancient jungles
in the west
from the savannahs of the east.
Up here lies the largest
glacier in Africa,
just a few miles north of the equator.
These are the legendary
Mountains of the Moon.
The height of these peaks
means they create their own weather.
The local name for these mountains
is Ruwenzori, "the rainmaker. "
Meltwater flows down from the glaciers.
And on the lower slopes,
all this water supports thick jungle.
Remnants of the dense, steamy forests
that once dominated
the whole of East Africa.
But driven by a drying climate
beyond the mountains,
the forests began to wither away.
Today, only small pockets
of upland jungle remain,
home to animals who once roamed
the ancient forests.
The largest living primates on Earth.
Mountain gorillas.
This little one's ancestors
have lived in forests like these
for millions of years.
But all around, the world has changed
to swamp and savannah.
This is the furthest
these mighty giants now venture
into Eastern Africa.
They're marooned on their islands
in the African sky.
Below the highlands,
vast wetlands cut swathes
through the open savannah.
Bangweulu Swamp is huge.
Its name means
"where the water meets the sky. "
Hidden amongst this maze of waterways
is a creature like no other.
A giant prehistoric-looking bird.
A shoebill.
Standing well over a metre tall,
she roams these swamps
trying to catch catfish.
Not exactly what she was after.
Deeper into the swamp
lies the reason for all this fishing.
This chick is just three weeks old,
and a little bit wobbly on its feet.
Its vast bill
means it has trouble balancing.
It won't be able to fly
or even walk properly for several weeks.
It's entirely reliant on its parents
for food and water.
There is also a smaller chick,
who isn't doing so well.
The larger chick
pesters its mother for a drink.
While she goes off to fetch water,
it reveals a dark side
to the relationship with its nest mate.
It's three days older
than the other chick
and has always won the race
for food and attention.
This is more than just a scrap
between two siblings.
As the mother returns,
she sees what the larger chick has done.
The smaller chick
seeks its mother's comfort.
But she has already made her choice.
Only her first born will get to drink.
Shoebills very rarely raise
more than one chick.
The younger chick
was only ever an insurance,
in case the elder didn't make it.
Now it's old enough,
the adults know that they're better off
putting all their efforts
into bringing up just one
fit and healthy youngster.
The swamps changing water levels
mean fishing is too unpredictable
for them to gamble
on trying to raise two chicks.
Nothing here stays the same for long.
This is the time of year
when Eastern Africa is beginning to dry.
The rivers and waterholes are shrinking.
The land continues to dry out.
Tensions rise.
Hippos seek what relief they can.
This time of relentless drying
is also when another force
of change ravages the land.
Without warning, fires rip through
these tinder-dry plains.
The flames sweep across the savannah
at 50 miles an hour,
reaching temperatures
of nearly 1,000 degrees,
consuming everything in their path.
Each year, an area larger than Britain
goes up in smoke.
But this destruction
can bring opportunity,
if you're prepared to take a risk.
Drongos, bee-eaters and rollers
bravely pluck fleeing insects
from amongst the flames.
There's little better
than a char-grilled grasshopper.
These fires may appear devastating
but they are, in fact,
part of a natural cycle
that is essential for the regeneration
of East Africa's grasslands.
But sometimes the cycle is broken,
just when a change is most needed.
Here, on the plains of Amboseli,
in the shadow of Mount Kilimanjaro,
the seasonal rains have failed
for the last two years.
And this year,
they are already long overdue.
It's the hardest drought
for half a century.
Amboseli is usually
a haven for elephants.
These plains should be green
and covered with grass.
Now, there is nothing but dust.
This family is forced
to travel constantly,
searching for anything they can eat.
The young must keep up.
Sometimes, there's not even
time to suckle.
With the grass gone, all the elephants
can scratch from the dust
is withered twigs.
The adults might just survive on this,
but it will not support a calf for long.
Every mother in the herd is struggling
to provide milk for her calf.
The search for food
is increasingly urgent.
As the herd moves on,
this female faces a terrible choice.
To carry on with her family
or stay behind with her calf,
who's becoming too weak to even stand.
They will soon be out of sight.
But her instinct is to stay.
She won't abandon her baby.
With the calf's last breath,
she knows that her battle is lost.
There are places
even more hostile
than the dust-choked plains.
These alien landscapes are actually
the sun-baked salt crusts
of a chain of lakes
that run through East Africa.
The face of these soda lakes
changes day by day
as the sun evaporates the water,
leaving the salts behind.
The waters here are toxic,
poisoned by volcanic springs.
But life does exist, even here.
The strange colours are created by algae
specially adapted
to live in this corrosive liquid.
And it is these algae that attract
one of the most astonishing animals
found in East Africa.
Among the steaming geysers
of Lake Bogoria,
over a million lesser flamingos
bathe and feed in the caustic water.
They gather whenever the algae bloom.
These huge numbers create one of the
greatest wildlife spectacles on Earth.
Almost all the world's lesser flamingos
live on this chain of lakes,
moving from one lake to another
as the amount of algae in each changes.
All along the lake shore,
volcanic vents are a reminder
of the forces
that continue to change this land.
And a streak of colour on the horizon
signals that relief
for the parched plains is on its way.
At last, countless storms
drench the thirsty ground.
Rain changes everything yet again.
A crowned eagle
has been desperately waiting
for what she hopes the rain will bring.
Food for her hungry chick.
Nesting here has been her biggest gamble.
A chick's life depends
on the arrival of creatures
from the far rainforests of the Congo.
Her wait will soon be over.
The largest mammal migration in Africa
is on the move.
10 million fruit bats
are drawn to this tiny forest
on the edge of the eastern savannah.
The bats flock here
to gorge themselves on fruit.
It's what the crowned eagle
and her chick have been waiting for.
But they're not alone.
Other eagles
have flown in from miles around.
Fish eagles,
martial eagles,
and they're all after the bats.
The gamble the crowned eagle
took months ago by nesting here
has paid off.
She is the only eagle
to actually nest in this forest.
The only one
who took the risk to breed here
well before the trees came into fruit
and the bats flooded in.
She only breeds once every two years,
so her timing must be perfect.
In a few months, the bats will leave,
but her gamble means her chick will have
the best possible start in life.
These grasslands
have been grazed and burned
and have endured
the harshest drought in generations.
But with the rains,
they're beginning to recover.
And on the once dust-choked
plains of Amboseli
there is a return to the good times.
The drought here
killed hundreds of elephants,
but the survivors
are now returning home.
And with them, there's a surprise.
A newborn.
Surrounded by food,
the youngster can concentrate
on more important things.
Like chasing egrets.
The bulls also return.
This bull has waited many years for his
chance to father the next generation.
Now, he must fight his way to the top.
But his rival is massive.
Each of their heads
weighs as much as a car.
They have been duelling for days.
Now, in its third day,
the contest is reaching a climax.
Soon, one will be forced to concede.
The power of these clashes
can even shatter tusks.
Three days of battle is at an end.
The victor has won the right
to the females.
The process to replace
what the drought took away has begun.
Soon, the elephants
will be at full strength again.
Every day the animals of Eastern Africa
gamble with their lives.
But despite
the continual changes they face,
their extraordinary adaptability
just tips the odds of survival
in their favour.
East Africa may seem very cruel,
but there's nowhere else
that provides such rich opportunities
for those that are prepared
to take them.
And in the end, it was these
ever-changing savannahs
that produced
the most adaptable species of all,
ourselves.
Filming in East Africa
would take the team on both
a physical and emotional journey
through the extremes of this landscape.
These are the legendary
Mountains of the Moon,
towering over 5,000 metres
into the African sky.
Just miles from the equator,
they're the highest mountain range
on the continent
and home to the
largest glacier in Africa.
To reach the summits,
the team had to travel on foot,
the same way as climbers did
when they first reached the top
just over 100 years ago.
It would take more than two weeks,
climbing over 3,000 metres
from the valleys below.
Six days into their trek,
still well below the summits,
the team come to realise why Ruwenzori,
the mountains' other name,
means "the rainmakers".
Just after we set off it started
raining, then it started hailing,
um, and the idea had been
that we'd stop here for an hour or two
and do some shots,
but as you can probably see,
there's not a great deal of view.
Brilliant shots
of rain and hail and fog.
Beyond that, we're pretty stuffed.
So, it's becoming a bit of a theme.
For the crew and over 75 guides and helpers,
it's hard going carrying nearly a ton
of kit through the marshy valleys.
Mud. Mud. There's a little bit more mud.
But it's not just the bogs
they have to deal with.
There was a fairly small
but slightly disconcerting
earthquake last night,
so, let's hope we don't get
any of those below any rocks.
The team continue to climb
and before long, the rain turns to snow.
They eventually arrive
at the highest hut,
surrounded by ice
and nearly three miles up.
This will be base camp for the crew.
We've got a kitchen over there.
Um, over there down a
really treacherous precipice
is the toilet,
which is just a shack
with a big hole in the floor.
From here, they'll make
the hardest part of the ascent
right up to the glaciers.
Well, this is, believe it or not,
one of the better viewpoints.
So we're gonna hang around here
for a little while,
to wait till the fog clears.
But the weather isn't on their side.
So much for hoping the weather
was going to get better.
All that optimism
now seems completely ill-founded.
With the storm clouds closing in,
the team are forced to retreat.
This enormous weather front's come in,
as isn't entirely unusual.
So we're just coming down
as the thunder bursts around us.
So just trying to get back
and go and get inside the hut
and hopefully weather it out.
After days of climbing
and finding the peaks hidden by fog,
filming the summits
is looking increasingly impossible.
It can be pretty
frustrating at times.
The group of, maybe, 70 people that
we've involved with doing this directly
and you get all the way
up here and then,
and then we can't film anything
because of the weather.
So, it is just a matter
of sitting it out and waiting.
And you have to sort of
hope that things come right in the end.
The rainmakers are certainly
living up to their name.
But by complete contrast, other parts
of East Africa were gripped by drought.
At the beginning of the production,
Mark Deeble travelled to Amboseli,
just a few hundred miles
from the Ruwenzoris,
to film the plight of the animals there.
Well, I've never seen
anything quite as bad as that drought.
When we talked to some
of the Maasai elders,
they said it was the worst drought
they'd seen in 50 years.
Amboseli is famous
for its huge herds of elephant,
but the drought had dispersed them
far and wide.
Those that remained were struggling
to find what little food was left.
When we first saw the group,
we could tell instantly that they...
They were in a really serious condition.
They were thin and obviously starving.
Mark knew that many of the calves
would not survive.
Although desperately painful to witness,
nothing would convey
the cruel power of the drought
more than this mother's struggle
to keep her baby alive.
The thing about filming
a situation like that,
you know, when an elephant calf dies,
is that when you're actually filming it
you're so caught up in the moment.
But it was only after filming,
when I put the camera away
and I looked there
and there was this dead calf
and the mother sort of standing there,
grieving,
that the full impact
of what I'd just filmed hit me.
People often say to me, you know,
"Could you not have intervened
in a situation like that?"
There are times when you can help.
But in that time in Kenya
there was no food available.
Now, you have to also
consider the mother.
If we'd gone in there
and tried to take the calf away,
it would've been absolute mayhem.
She'd have got incredibly stressed
and that would probably
have jeopardised her survival.
In that particular situation,
when everything around us was dying,
there was absolutely nothing
we could do to help that young elephant.
Although too late to save the calf,
a few months later,
the rains did finally return.
When we returned, it was amazing.
It was lush and green again.
And the elephants, in the rains,
they all tend to come together.
So it was like all of these groups
which had been dispersed,
which had been just somehow
coping on their own,
all got back together again.
It was almost a sort of
festival type atmosphere.
That was when, essentially,
they come together,
they mate, and then after that
lots of young calves being born.
Since the end of the drought,
over 220 calves
have been born in Amboseli,
and that number is still rising.
It's the biggest
elephant baby boom on record.
I think what's lovely to see
in that situation is that, having...
Having been through
such a terrible drought,
to see the way in which, you know,
if you let things alone
they, you know, they do have incredible
capacity to bounce back.
Back in the mountains, and
several failed ascents later,
the team were still battling
through the white-out.
They try one last time.
There's cloud below us
and cloud above us.
It somehow seems slightly,
like we're heading nowhere, slowly.
Then, as they reach the top,
finally the clouds begin to part.
It's absolute magic here.
We've just come through
the densest, densest cloud,
having absolutely no idea
what's surrounding us.
The past few days have just been
rain and cloud and rain and cloud.
And, as if by magic,
there's the most spectacular view
of ice and glaciers and mountains
that you just wouldn't think
was on the equator.
It's just amazing.
It's the most spectacular
mountain scenery I've seen.
And to think it's in Africa
is just mind-boggling.
These mysterious mountains
have finally unveiled their secrets.
And on the plains beyond,
the elephants have returned to their home.
Despite having been explored
by filmmakers for over a century,
East Africa still has the power
to enchant and surprise us all.