Roman
What do you want to know?
The truth
Are you sure?
Yes, that's why I've come to you
How many women have you had
in your life?
You know, women, girls or
whatever you call them
Eight... nine...
I don't know, maybe fifteen
That's enough
I've been married for ten years now
And frankly...
That's enough, too
Are you sure I don't ever be able to
make love to any woman?
I'm afraid you won't, the findings are
typical, and so are the symptoms
What's your wife like?
She's wonderful
Take a divorce
Romek
I heard your car
Come on
You didn't want to meet you,
did you?
I did
Your suit is dripping wet
Don't you want to know
why I went to Krakow?
Why, you have friends there
Just one
Why don't you tell me about Zagreb?
I delivered several lectures
I assisted during several operations
On three occasions, I operated myself
I got paid and by the tim
I was leaving, the money I got was only
worth a half of its original value
Are you tired?
No
I say, Hanka darling...
Mhm... Not now, please
Tell me everything
I'm not afraid anymore
I went to Krakow to meet Mikolaj
He's a friend of mine
I told you about him once, didn't I?
That son of a bitch, I remember
Well, he examined me and
had all the analyses made
He was quite frank
I haven't any chances
Today, tomorrow...
Or ever...
I don't believe it
These are facts
Do you love me?
Well, do you or not?
You're afraid to say you do
although you do love me after all
Love is not just panting in bed
for five minutes once a week
It is that, too
It's just biology
True love is situated in one's heart
and not between the legs
What matters to me is what we have
and not what we haven't
You're young and...
I can manage
You'll have to find yourself a lover
That is, if you haven't found one yet
I haven't
Some things are better left unsaid
Oh no
All right, so you've been frank with me
You won't ever be able to make love to me
At least that's what the doctors say
I'm telling you this
I want to be with you anyway
I love you
May I cuddle up to you?
Yes
Tightly, O.K.?
You asleep, Hanka?
No
We've never wanted a baby
It would perhaps be easier now
if there was one
Perhaps
Can I help?
If you're so kind...
Just hold the funnel, will you?
May I join, Doctor?
Make a decision
It's not very good for you
But not fatal
The ward head told me he found it rather
difficult to come to terms with you
Really? But it's perfectly simple
You see, Doctor
I have a voice
How's that?
A singing voice
My mother is a hard-working woman
She wants me to be somebody
I wasn't admitted to the school
of music because of my heart
I shouldn't sing, my heart's too weak,
but Mother wants me to become a singer
What's your specialty?
Bach and Mahler
Do you know Mahler?
And... van den Budemayer?
No, I don't know that one
His works are... well, difficult
But I can sing them
Mother wants me to make a career
abroad or at least here
This is what that operation's for
Mother wants the ward head to operate
on me or better still, you
Do you want it, too?
I want to live, that's enough for me
I don't have to sing
Besides, I'm scared
I guess the ward head wanted you to
reassure me to tell me
it isn't dangerous
I'll be able to do everything
afterwards...
Well, go on, tell me
Know what, it's not that simple
Such operations are usually
carried out to save, I mean...
They are the last resort,
when nothing else can be done
Which is not the case with me, right?
Frankly speaking, that's what I mean
Various people have different needs
Mother wants me to have everything
...while I only need this much
Good afternoon
May I speak to Hanka please?
I'm afraid she's out
Oh, I thought she was
Thank you
Want me to give her a message?
No, thanks
I'll try to reach her later
What is it?
Van den Budenmayer
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes
I once heard it before
I took a call to you
Who was it?
Beautiful, really
I've bought something for you
Care to try it on?
It's for you
Hello, Hanka, at last!
Hanka...
I must see you
You didn't come at four
All right
Hanka darling
All right, I'll be there
Yes, it's better this way
I see
Yes, sure, O.K.
Can you hear me?
Why, hello, Mum
When could you send it to me?
We fly on Thursdays
and Saturdays now
Fine, go to my flat and find that
black shawl and umbrella
All right
Please come in
I've been thinking about you
After we'd talked yesterday,
I bought a record
What record? Van den Budemayer?
In Dutch, it's wonderful
Remember anything?
Your singing's beautiful
A pity you don't want it for a career
That's what Mother says
And rightly, too
What did you dream about
when you were my age?
I wanted to become a doctor,
a surgeon
And what about having home, a family?
Didn't you dream about that?
I never thought about it
Mariusz Zawydzki, Physics
Eleven... Twenty-three...
Forty-five...
Oh, I forgot
Mother phoned
She wants her umbrella and shawl
Why don't they sell shawls in shops
where she is?
Don't you know her?
She wants to have her own one
When is the plane due?
At twelve, a few minutes past
I don't operate until the afternoon
I may go to the airport,
I'm free for an hour
You're a dear
Oh, give me the key
The umbrella is on the coat-stand
A black folding one
The shawls's black, too, it's in
the chest of drawers in the bedroom
I'll find it
It's me
Do me a favour, will you?
Never call me on the phone at home
unless you have to
Anything wrong?
No, phone me at the office,
it's better that way
Ten to six, right?
And ten to eight
on Thursdays and Tuesdays
As you wish, Madam
Have you been to your mother's flat?
I send a postcard to you saying
I love you and will keep our date today
A postcard?
Yes, a silly one, with the Pope
on the reverse side
When did you mail it?
After our last meeting, as usual
Haven't you got it?
No, bye
May I speak to Mr. Mariusz, please?
It's the right number, isn't it?
Mariusz! For you again!
Hallo
It's me, so you're there?
Yes
I tried to reach you but the number
was engaged all the time...
I've just come in
You must have got the number wrong
Hurry up, Roman, don't rummage the flat
Mother doesn't like it
Hope I can still make it,
they haven't taken off yet,
I'm free at six
You can have the car
Oh, but what about you?
I've got time enough
That's great
I'll come to fetch you
I'll be free at nine
Is it comfortable?
Yes
No mail in Mother's flat?
Ah, I didn't check, you should have
told me to when you phoned
I didn't think about it
Well, be seeing you
Roman
The registration card?
It's in the glove compartment
See you in the evening
I can't sleep
You were good at physics,
...weren't you?
Tell me how that law goes
The loss of weight of
a floating body
...is equal to
How does it go?
The apparent loss of weight
...is equal to the weight of water
that body has dislodged
Something like that
I think...
You've had a bad day
Was it an operation?
Yes
Someone died, right?
Yes... don't
Who was it?
Don't touch me
Sorry
It's me
Why, hello, Hanka darling...
I must see you
This is what I've been
telling you all week long,
but the last two days you refused
Now I want it
I miss you
All right,
is Thursday all right with you?
Any time will be fine
At six on Thursday, then
Is anything wrong, darling?
At six
Are you there...
Roman?
Yes
No, don't take it off
I have very little time
I've missed you so much
No... don't
O.K. Not now
And never again
This is the last time we meet
That's what I wanted to tell you
But Hanka...
Go away now
All right, we don't have to go to bed
But don't make me go, please
It's not that, but go now
I love you
We never talked about it
And we're not going to
Did he find out about us?
We're not going to discuss him, either
He hasn't found out and
he won't ever find out
Button you jacket up and go
You're looking swell
Well, go away now
Come out
Come out, will you?
Come out!
Why have you done it?
Tell me, why?
You wanted to see me having
fun with him in bed?
You should have come last week,
you'd have seen everything
I was here last week, too
How's that?
I was sitting
on the steps and listening
Open the door
Perhaps you'd like me
to marry you...
You know, you could
get a divorce and
Roman
Please take me in your arms
Take me tightly
I can't
Please
Oh please do
You're not going to walk out on me
...just because I went to bed with...
I didn't know... I know you well
enough but I never thought...
I didn't know how much
I'd hurt you
I have no right to be jealous
I can't demand it from you
Of course you have the right
You were right about that
other thing, too
Nothing should be left unsaid
I'll never lie to you again
I don't want to hide behind a wardrobe
I had an extra key made
You won't ever have to
We should have a child, adopt one
You were right
We need a rest from each other
Yes
All right, take a holiday
And I'll talk to some lawyer in the
meantime about that adoption
No, I want you to go away
I won't have that physicist...
Good
Not too short?
They're my wife's
Could you tell me...
How much is a ticket to Melbourne?
Go away
I just wanted to ask how much
is a ticket to Melbourne
Janusz
This gentleman will tell you all
you want to know,
Melbourne is his department
What can I do for you?
It takes longer if you want a boy,
and much shorter with a girl
The lawyer was very nice
It would be fully confidential
All right, but how long does it take?
Well, several months with a girl
Everybody wants a boy
You'd just have to provide
a certificate of sterility
I might get it from Mikolaj
Tell me, Roman
Is it what you really want?
Yes
Want me to phone you every day
from Zakopane?
No, don't do it
But you do trust me, don't you?
How are you?
I hate you
Why, you agreed, didn't you?
Yes... But I didn't want it
Has anything happened?
What's wrong?
Nothing yet, but I know I'm a
different person now
What do you mean?
I want to sing
And to have a large audience
Hallo?
Good evening
I couldn't get a connection at an
earlier hour... Mariusz, please?
He's away
Who's speaking, please?
A friend from the university
My son went away to Zakopane to ski
Do you want me to give him
your message?
The tickets for today are sold out
The booking-office does not sell
tickets in advance for tomorrow
It's open daily from
seven thirty a.m.
Passengers are invited
to come back tomorrow
Two for ten thirty
What are you doing here?
I was told you went
for a skiing holiday
I thought, maybe you are
in Zakopane So I came here too
I forgot
Hold this a minute, I forgot
Is this the hospital?
Yes, may I help you?
This is Hanna Nycz speaking from
Zakopane, is my husband there?
No, Doctor Nycz isn't here today
He phoned he wasn't coming
Yes
Would you please do me a favour?
Should my husband phone the hospital,
Please tell him
I'm leaving for Warsaw
on the first train or
bus I manage to catch
I'll be home in the evening
Will you tell him?
Yes
I'll tell him
Thank you
I'd like to make another call,
please
It won't take long
It's a local call
Right here, at the refilling station
No, just what I needed
They're perfect
Your ticket, please
Put the skis in the luggage-carrier
Your tickets, please
Your ticket, Madam
I have no ticket
But I must get to Warsaw
Roman...
Yes... Where? I see
Can you hear me?
Your wife is not in that hotel
in Zakopane
She left for Warsaw in the morning
Thirty-two...
fifty-six... thirty-six...
Hanka darling
You're all right
Oh God, you're all right
I am