Excuse me
Yes?
I'd like to return my book
of registration
Aren't you going to appeal?
This is your last year
"No, expelled is expelled"
Ten pages are missing
"I tore them out, they concerned the"
exams during the last two semesters
What country are you going to?
Canada
To your family?
"No, acquaintances"
This is your passport
But if you want to take the child with
"you, you'll need the mother's consent"
"I know, I just wanted to check"
whether the passport's ready
It is
I think I'd better collect my own passport
and provide that consent the next time
You'll get the passport
straight away then
Ania!
Ania! Ania!
Go away
Ania dear...
Get out of here
Mother...
You don't know how to hush her
Get out!
"Ania baby, it's all right, Ania"
What happened?
Dreamt of wolves?
Hasn't Mummy told you
there aren't any wolves?
Ania... There aren't
"It's all right now, isn't it?"
It's all right
"Now you're going to sleep, O.K.?"
My dearest little one
Dad...
I can't stand it
"There, there, Majka"
"You used to cry like this, too,"
when you were a baby
But why does she tell her
about wolves?
I believe you're to be up early
"There, there..."
Listen
Ania
"You're free, Princess"
How did that magic spell go?
"Do you remember, children?"
Abrakadabra...
May the cave open!
You're all invited to the wedding
party!
"Are we hiding, Majka?"
"No, we're running away"
Shall we play a trick on Mummy?
I have no coat
I've brought it with me
Madam? A child's disappeared
My daughter...
"Christ, don't you understand?"
My child's gone...
Ania
Shall we have a ride?
On what?
Look
Have you kidnapped me?
What?
You've kidnapped me
Like in that book
"You're a big girl now, aren't you?"
Mummy says I am
Exactly
Now look at me...
"You see,"
Mummy isn't your mother
And I have no mother at all?
"Oh yes, you have"
Your real mother
"You see, I am your mother"
"Yes, we have"
"Even two... Yes, two tents"
and two mattresses
Majka went to the Bleszczady Mountain
An excursion from the University
"Phone next week, O.K.? I believe"
someone's just entered the flat
Ania? Ania...
Ewa? Ewa...
You...
It's Ania...
She disappeared
What is it?
"I must go to the toilet, Majka"
"All right, go"
I'll be on the look out
Is it her?
"Yes, she's rather excited"
That's why she has to pee
What do you want?
May we come in?
I took her with me and
ran away from home
"You ran away, and?"
Hi
A lot has changed
So it has
We haven't seen each other for
"Father died, three years ago"
And you?
""Teddy bear maker""
I made teddy bears
What happened to your former plans?
"The University, the things you wrote?"
I gave it up
What about this?
What anything to eat?
Or maybe some tea?
She's asleep
Perhaps I'd better take her to bed?
"No, she's happy"
Just look at her
Do you still remember me?
No
I paid a lot for it
But it's all right now
Do they know?
No
I picked her up at the theatre
Mother was running about like crazy
Stumbled against a step
Nearly fell down the stairs
Why are you speaking of her like this?
You should be glad to hear it?
It started some time ago
I think I hate her
"You haven't changed, or maybe"
there are just the two extreme
Just the two
"For today, the situation is that I took"
"Ania with me, I won't give her back"
I first thought about it some
three or four years ago
I'm not a good girl in a drak-blue
skirt anymore
The girl who fell in love with her
Polish teacher...
just because what he said
was different
You still have lots of chances
You haven't stolen anything
or killed anybody
Is it possible to steal
your own property?
I don't know
I guess not
This means I haven't stolen anything
That's a fact
"Yeah, and as for killing"
"Yes, I think I could kill her"
It isn't much that you know
about your mother
I've only just learned quite recently
What?
Why she's like that
"After I was born,"
she could have no more children
This means it was because of me in a way
But she always wanted children
I know that
"And then, when Ania was born"
"You see, this does explain a thing or two"
"There was another person, too"
"who agreed to that arrangement, you"
I was only sixteen then
Jeanne d'Arc hadn't been much older
You said that before
They said they meant well
I should finish school and so on
It's only now that I know they were
really after the baby
"And there was that scandal at school, too"
"She was the headmistress,"
"I was a young teacher, and you went"
to that same school
But you mattered most
The moment you ought to have said you wanted
"that baby to be ours, you said nothing"
I couldn't
You couldn't?
"You were involved, too"
"Mother said, "If you don't want"
"trouble for seducing a minor,"
if you want still to be a teacher
"...keep quiet"
Am I right?
Is that what she told you?
I overheard her say that to Father
"It's just like her, you knew she'd do it"
She said it to your father?
Yes
Was she lying?
To be frank...
I never though this could be arranged
like that in Poland:
That your own child is officially
registered as somebody else's...
Of course it can be arranged
All it takes is a doctor you know
He did not know what he was doing
I usually take a nap in the afternoon
An hour or so
"O.K., take it"
There's no reason why you should
change your routine
Now I think it's good she agreed then
"This way, I have my peace"
Yes
And I won't trouble you too long
Are you going away?
"Yes, I'm making an excursion"
"to Romania, in summer"
"Let me see your passport, it's a long"
since I've seen such a document
Here
What's this?
A certificate stating that I gave
birth to a baby six years ago
What about your mother?
Is she willing to give you the girl back?
Mother?
"Yes, mother"
She'll have to
You'd never believe it
I never knew she could be so tender
and loving
She never gave that to me
Let me tell you something
Something that I should never tell
to anybody
When Ania was still a baby
"about six months old, she was..."
I returned from a holiday camp
...somewhat earlier than planned
They always send me to such camps then
"Well, I came back..."
I saw Mother feeding Ania
"So what? It's normal, isn't it?"
"No, she was breast-feeding"
Why...
She had no
"But she gave suck to Ania,"
and Ania sucked
She won't let you go now
What happened?
"Nothing, I just cut my finger"
It won't hurt anymore
"Go to sleep no, Ania"
"Sleep, my baby..."
I'm going out
Take care of Ania
What do you want to do?
Annoy Mum just a little
I'm going to the telephone booth
"No, wait"
"Here, use this"
"Oh no, not from your place"
They certainly notified the police
Your phone might be tapped
I'll phone from the booth
Want me to go with you?
The booth is at the station
Are you going to leave Ania
all along?
Want me to read you a story?
About...
your mother and
...your grandmother
"The Italian film"
...mother and daughter
...some scenes that
...I can touch
...around me
Hush...
Got the bears?
Yes
Who's this?
My daughter
Don't come here a day or two
I might be in trouble
Because of her?
Dad?
I have her with me
What are you planning to do?
Let me speak to Mother
Tell me
"You can't help me, Dad"
Mother cried all the time
She's taken a pill or something
and I believe she's asleep now
Who is it?
I have her with me
"Oh God, she's with you..."
Have you notified the police?
"Yes, but it doesn't matter"
Where are you?
"Call it off, tell them you"
"found her, that's for one thing"
Of course I will
Where are you?
We're coming to you
Stefan
"Well, where are you?"
We'll be there in no time
"We're somewhere, I won't tell you where"
You've got to change everything
What?
What do you want me to change?
Everything
Ania's got to be mine
She can't
She has to
But nobody knows anything
So what? I'll tell them all
I can prove it
You can prove nothing
"Ania's mine, she's registered"
as my daughter
Only Jadwiga know you're actually
"Ania's mother, but Jadwiga won't tell"
Where are you?
"Father know, too"
"Father know nothing, nothing at all"
And Wojtek
Don't count on Wojtek
I'll tell you about it when I'm retired
Now listen to me
You stole my baby
You stole my baby and
my motherhood...
My love... You stole myself
Everything...
You have two hours time to decide what
"to do, then I'll tell you what I want"
Where's Majka?
She had to go out
She'll be back soon
What woke you up?
I often wake up like this
Majka says I have no mother
You must have got her wrong
Of course you have a mother
And a father?
"You have the father, too"
Majka says you are my...
Aren't you sleepy anymore?
Want me to show you how
Teddy bears are made?
Yes
"I say, did you know she was"
going to kidnap Ania?
No
I haven't got any spot
"Oh, but you have... here"
And here...
"Ah, that's right... Great"
Are you a wizard?
Yes
No
I once was a wizard
"A great one, and"
very very wicked
Wicked?
Know any more tricks?
Sure
Show me
Why are you up?
She woke up
Majka...
He says he's a wizard
You were to call me Mummy
"Say Mummy, please"
"No, Mummy"
"Please, Ania"
"Say Mummy, Mummy"
Do you hear?
Please call you mummy Mummy
Please
Please call me Mummy
Do you hear?
Who?
"Ah yes, now I know"
It's all right... No
I have no idea
I haven't seen her six years long
All right
They're looking for you
I know
He know nothing
He was asleep
We woke quite a lot of people up
They won't kill them
We know nothing
about our own child
"About her friends,"
where she might be now
We lost her
I never thought she
might do this to Ania
She loves Ania
You've got to give her back
I can't
Majka was always your little daughter
Ania was mine
Majka couldn't have been
your little daughter
You always exacted too much of her
You wanted she can't cope with it
She knew she had to become
worthy of your love
And that day when you saw her
in the bathroom
With the traces of bandage across
"her belly, she was six months gone then"
You started streaming
I knew that was the end
She didn't say anything
Now don't tell me the history
"of our family, I know it"
But you think Majka doesn't
She does all right
"I say, Stefan"
She wants to take Ania away forever
To take her far away...
"If you know what I mean,"
"Far, far away..."
Once and for all
Where to?
Canada
She got an invitation
A fictitious one
I thought perhaps it was all
"for the better, let her go..."
Let us stay here
with the little one
Let her go and never come back
But she's thought it all out
They're both going
Do you hear?
We'll lose both of them
We've got to find them
Go some place!
Where to?
You used to have such
a lot of friends
"Yeah, I don't have them anymore"
Grzegorz
Phone Grzegorz...
"I beg you, Stefan"
"Wake up, Ania"
It's all right
It's all right now
Can you sleep?
It's all right
"All right, now"
She screams nearly every night
It's been going like this for years
"She dreams of something, but she's"
never told us about her dream
I wonder that she might be afraid of
Of the future
If you're planning to take her away...
Where to?
Anywhere... Far away...
"Well, she won't stand it:"
"Your shouting at her, knocking her"
"about, your hysterics"
She's too sensitive
You seem to have taken scare?
"No, you can stay here"
as long as you like
No
No?
You're going to ruin your own child
"She's your child, too"
You should go back home
I see
She needs a normal home
"Her own toys, her bed, milk"
at supper... don't you see?
"Yes, I see..."
What do you see?
That she needs a home
You're right
A fellow I know has a car
He delivers the Teddy bears
You'll be back in Warsaw
before it dawns
"All right, go get him"
But you can live here
I'll move away
"No, you're right"
Go get that car
"Wake up, Ania"
We're going away
"Get up, and put our clothes on"
Where's Wojtek?
Wojtek doesn't want us
But he said to give you
this Teddy bear
Have I woken you up?
I'm sorry
It doesn't make any sense
"But it's Ewa, you know her"
She kissed my hand to make me
come to you
Yes?
I'm afraid
All of this is...
There isn't much I can do
I might try and announce it
...on TV tomorrow
And if she hasn't collected her
"passport yet, we could stop it"
I'm really sorry
I hope I haven't roused the kids?
"No, they're asleep"
I feared this might happen
She's away
What shall we do?
"Well, two hours have passed"
"Yes, two and a half actually"
Now listen to me
You're bringing Ania back
Father will sell the car and his organ
You'll buy a flat for yourself
You'll see Ania whenever
you'll like...
"You'll take her with you on all Sundays,"
to the cinema or no matter where
Ania will be mine and yours
"After my death,"
she'll be yours only
Want anything else?
"Yes, your authenticated consent to"
Ania's going abroad... to Canada
I need it for tomorrow
Do you understand?
Majka...
Please... I can't
"In that case,"
you won't ever see us again
Ania's asleep in my arms now
And I don't care
This night I understood...
I only have her and nobody else
in the world
"I'm counting five, if you don't say yes"
"you can say good-bye to us, forever"
"one, two..."
"three, four, five..."
"Majka, I agree!"
Yes!
I agree! Majka?
"Come back, Majka"
"It's me, Wojtek"
Who?
Wojtek
Yes
You lied to us before
"Yes, I did"
Is she there?
She was
She ran away taking the girl with her
Where is she?
She said she didn't care anymore
She couldn't have gone too far
I'll start looking for her...
To the left of the track
You check it to the right
Near your place?
"Yes, the neighborhood of Josefow"
Want to pretend the sticks are boats?
Yes
"Kiss me, Ania"
Give me a hearty kiss
Do you love me?
Yes...
Nothing?
Nothing
I'm afraid...
We did it all wrong
Let's check the railway stations
It's too early for the first train
Today is Sunday
"Our family brings you bad luck,"
Wojtek dear
I'll drive that forest road
to Otwock...
Go now
When does the train leave?
Where to?
Anywhere
In two hours
It's Sunday
A husband?
"You've run away from your husband,"
eh?
From everything
Come on in
"It's warm inside, I've got a blanket"
You can get some sleep
Have you seen a girl with a child?
Have you?
"A young girl, wears glasses..."
Had a big bag on her shoulder
And the child is a girl of six
"Yes, she was here"
But she went away some two hours ago
Where did she go?
"No idea, she asked about the road"
I don't know
Ania...
Mummy!
Ania baby...
My dear little girl
"My darling, my baby..."
Majka!
Majka baby!