You shall murder!
You shall covet everything
all week long
And on Sundays...
You shall beat your father and mother,
...your sister and your juniors
You shall steal
Because everything around
you is yours
Everything is yours!
He sacrificed everything
passion, his family, his career...
Perhaps even his emotions...
Taking leave of our late friend today,
...the winner of eleven international
gold medals
...and participant of many exhibitions
I would like to offer
...my condolences
...to his family
I bow down before this grave
Farewell, my friend
Just take a look at this
tin-plated door, damn him
Well?
Wait a minute, let me see it
Right, an alarm device
Stop yelling
Shit, look
Ah well, starved to death
Get a strainer
No good, it's been nailed up
But why?
What do you mean, why? Why the
alarm device,
why the padlocks and bars
Don't you know what kind of man
Father was?
Not too well, and what about airing?
No idea
He probably never aired it
No, thanks
I have business later on
Come on, it isn't much
To Father
Cheers!
How much is it worth, I wonder?
I don't know, but the stamps
are expensive nowadays
Well, some three or four thousand,
I guess
Yeah, this is our poverty
Mother's wasted life...
No decent meals, no money...
Oh come on
I say, he didn't even own
a decent suit to
be buried in,
I had sacrificed one of mine
Tell me, what is it that makes one so...
So greedy? So set on possessing
You should know,
you like to own things
No, I just use them
I like to be comfortable
But I couldn't understand the old man
for a long time
I say, it's ages since we last met
Yeah, over two years?
Hey, look
He collected press cutting about you
May I?
Yes
My name's Bromski
Are you the son?
Yeah
I'd like to talk to you...
I know this is not the best
moment possible,
but you see that's
how it is with business
All right, what is it?
Your father and I were friends
I have here...
Your father owed me
...two hundred twenty thousand
...zlotys
He never told me
I ought to get the money back
in a few days
Well, I know a funeral coasts a lot...
But perhaps...
I could find an equivalent here,
if you know what I mean
To save you the trouble
Here's my phone number
Phone me in five days
I'll try to raise the money for you
Thank you so much
If I get you right,
You aren't going to get rid of
the collection for the time being?
Of course, you certainly have
your reasons
In your place, I think
I'd do the same
Well, sorry for bothering you
Dad owed a fellow two hundred
twenty thousand
That one was the first to come...
As yet
Nothing but rags
Look, this was his way
to iron pants Under the sheet
What's this?
Those cuttings about you
And I thought he never
even knew my name
I say, I've heard such guys have
a market or something, well?
Would you like to have a try?
What about that lame fellow
who was here?
No, he's too clever
And what about your kid?
Doesn't he collect stamps?
Uh-uh, he only likes planes
Then why not give him these?
Balloons or something
Zeppelins
All right, Zeppelins
It's a series
Polarfahrt, this means they're German
Uhm... 1931
Which one's yours?
This one here
The first tenants
Quite nice, and tell the kid
I have an LP for him
He's not really a kid anymore
Well, bye, then
To the Riviera Club, please
I'm glad we met
I'm sorry, I couldn't make it
We'll go tomorrow
Artur and I started talking after the
funeral and we quite forgot the time
I haven't said anything
No reception tomorrow
Well, the day after tomorrow then
I'll ring him up
I'm sorry, really
I haven't said a word
That's true, you haven't...
Your slippers
This is from Grandpa, as a souvenir
Gee, they're nice
Grandpa died, you know
He was buried a few hours ago
Hey, what's that? You crying?
Not really, I've cried already
Mum told me at dinner
I'm sorry about Grandpa
Have you had toothache?
No...
I couldn't make it
Mum was angry
She shouted at me all day long
Good morning
I'd like to have this priced
And possibly to find a purchaser
Are you Korzen's son?
Yes
This is but a fragment of his collection
I could sell more, I don't know...
perhaps the whole of it
Could you please wait a moment, sir?
Our president would like to talk to you
May I trouble you a minute, please?
Why, of course
There are two of you,
if I remember right
Yes
Could we perhaps meet at
your father's flat?
Of course, I'll write the address
down for you
I know the address
Well, gentlemen
What are you planning to do?
We'd like to sell it
We need money
How much of it?
Doesn't matter, just money
I see
Well, you can buy a 126 Fiat
for this one
And this one will get you two cars
with Diesel engines
And this series would be enough
to buy a flat
I believe you don't realize
Well, and what is the value...
of the whole lot?
Millions and millions
Your father wanted to insure
his collection...
...for two hundred fifty million zlotys
You see, your father put all his life
...in it
It would be criminal to waste thirty
years of somebody's life away
Even if that somebody was
...just one's father whom one hardly
knew at all
Good-bye, gentlemen
Good-bye
Bloody hell
Yeah, quite a surprise
Hush, Mum's asleep
Have you been at the office?
Yeah, in the morning
But then... I met Artur
Mum tried to reach you several times
Why?
Are these autographs?
Yes
See what Artur wrote here?
For Peter to make his life happier
I say, what have you done with
those Zeppelins?
I exchanged them for these
Look how many I got
Whom...
...did you give them to?
Tell me
All right, which one was it?
The one with glasses
Stay here
Don't go anywhere
I have some business with you
Yes, sir
Not here
It's confidential
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Careful, Mister, or...
You've cheated a kid
One has to make a living
He's my son
Ah well, nearly everyone has
parents nowadays
I want that series with Zeppelins back
I sold it
To whom? Out with it!
To that fellow in Wspolna street
Thank you
I have an unpleasant business with you
A boy from Swietokrzyska street
offered you a series of stamps
You bought it for forty thousand
I'm afraid that stamp cheated
my son out of
those stamps and gave
him rubbish instead
I don't know
what you're talking about
I see
Say I'd like to buy something
in your shop...
Well, a series of German stamps,
Polarfahrt with the Zeppelins in them
From 1931...
Could we perhaps...?
Do you want to buy?
We may...
...discuss it
Is this what you mean?
Yes
Well, it's for sale
How much?
Er... Two hundred forty thousand
The price isn't high
Well, if that's so, the next time
I'll bring the police here
I'm sorry
It's all right
You can use my phone, sir
Well, do you want to
...use the phone or not?
I've got a receipt here
The former owner of the series was
...going abroad and sold the stamps
to me for
...one hundred sixty-eight thousand
Here's the stamp duty
And this is my license
Take a look, please
That was your favourite group
NAME?
And now a short break
You'll catch a cold
I'm free now
Things have turned out badly
with the Zeppelins
Those men are gangsters
Ah, that fellow phoned me,
Father's creditor,
you know, I'm to meet him on Sunday
Two hundred twenty thousand, eh?
Precisely
Well, I have some ninety thousand,
I was saving to buy Peter some furniture
What does your wife say?
She suspects me of having an affair
Now I have to stay in town on Sunday
And it's sure to strengthen her
suspicious Have you got the money?
Where from? I'm not the saving kind
But I might sell the amplifier
Don't you need it to play?
It's not an instrument
I paid about fifty dollars for it,
I guess
I should get some seventy
thousand back
Yeah, that's it
And the rest of money?
The stamps?
Well...
I don't know...
I'd rather that we don't sell them
for the time being
I mean, not until we have to
I feel the same
Good
Let them stay where they are
God damn you!
I thought it was some stranger
What the hell are you doing here?
Looking at the stamps
I was here yesterday, too
I didn't know
I've been here today morning
What's the matter?
Have you been fired?
No
I'm anxious about this flat
You know, all those safety devices
are nothing, actually
Anybody could have entered the flat
just as you did
Besides, I'm registered as tenant here
Why, of course
I'll feel better, too
Hey, take a look at what I found
The only series in Poland
And it's incomplete
The blue one, the yellow one...
The red one's missing
Now listen, this is what the
old man wrote
Red Austrian Mercury of 1851
Stolen during the celebrated
robbery in 1965...
Appeared for a short time in Krakow,
at J.'s...
Was it sold or exchanged?
In 1968, before J. Left Poland
News from K.B.R.
It's now in Southern Poland
Could M.W. have it?
Is there a chance?
Just a sign, not money...
Half the note book is taken
by such notes
Figures, symbols...
Most of it, I just can't make out
I've been reading for several hours
The red Austrian Mercury
It would look swell together with
the other two, wouldn't it?
It's red...
They just slip down a rope...
...or jump down
...and there they are
It's just a few metres
You mean, a grating?
Yes, in both windows
The ideas the old man had,
nailing them up
A pane's just a pane, it's enough
to break it and you're inside
I say, Arthur...
I forgot I ever had any problems
I forgot everything
Know what? I feel the same somehow
Like many years ago,
...when we were just kids and didn't care
about the grown-ups' problem
It's the same now
...as we sit here like this
Nothing matters anymore
Yes, one forgets... lt's children
But nice
Oh yes, very...
Maybe the rest of your life
simply isn't there...
...if you don't want it to pester you
Hey, I've just thought of something
Find a stamp for me,
...worth say about 200 thousand
But it must be an official price,
printed in catalogue or something
Two hundred thousand?
Yes
With pleasure, wait a moment
I found this
How much is it worth?
Where have you found it?
At home
Your own?
Possibly
Well, it's worth...
Say, fifteen thousand
I can buy it from you
For three thousand...
No, five
Four
It's stolen property
Ah well, O.K.
Here you are
Thank you
What are you doing?
Shall we listen to it?
Check the recording, you know
It's worth, say, fifteen thousand
I can buy it from you
for three thousand
No, five
Four, it's stolen property
All right, let's come to brass tacks
What do you want?
Three German stamps with Zeppelins,
issued in 1931
I'm giving you four thousand for them
and a brand new Sony cassette
The recording only takes the first
few metres
And it's a ninety-minute cassette, see?
Clever, that
I had an inkling when you came in
You should have followed your instinct
Yeah, a fellow came to me
to the other day...
My brother
Not as clever as you
He didn't know everything then
He didn't know you
Do you want money, or the stamps?
The latter
I see
You're...
...the sons of...?
Who is it?
It's me
Jerzy
A moment
What's that beast you have there?
Wait a minute
What was that?
A dog, I locked him in the bathroom
My key doesn't fit the lock, damn it
I changed the lock
They say you should do it
from time to time
Who says so?
Friends of mine who know a thing
or two Here's your new key
The next time would you please
tell me in advance
I've spent half a day wandering about
and trying to reach you on the phone
And what about that dog?
Just a dog
Does he ever stop?
Those friends told me to get one,
so I bought him, shall I let him out?
O.K.
I'm afraid he might bite you
But you've got to do something
about him He should know I'm not a thief
I'm scared of him myself
Lokis! To heel! Halt!
To heel, Lokis?
Gee, do something
This is Jerzy, a friend
He's a friend
Just look at him
Jerzy is a friend
Isn't he nice?
What about the Zeppelins?
It's all right, I've got them
Over there
Good doggie, good doggie
Stroke him
Good doggie... Down, Lokis!
No, that's good
On my way here, I came across
that fellow with a limp,
Remember him?
The one Father owed money
What did he want?
He was glad to see me He said
he had friends in the neighborhood
Did he come here?
No, why?
Sit down
Let him have it
What if he bites?
He won't
Hey, what's that?
Uhm... perhaps you should try
with the left
Good, doggie, good Lokis
See, he only accepts what you give him
with your left hand, he's your friend now
The left hand or the right?
Come on, risk it
Who's that?
Get him, Lokis!
Good doggie, keep guard
Some beast, that dog
I say, I might stay here for the night
He'll get used to me this way
Sure
Where are the Zeppelins?
The shop-owner's quite a fellow
Is he?
Yeah, wants to talk to us
Now, gentlemen
Have you already
come across the problem
...called the red Austrian Mercury?
Well, we have
Do you know...
...its value?
All we know there's one such stamp
in Poland
And I know
...who has it
Your father tried to find out
but couldn't... all those years
As far as I know,
he was very particular about it
If you gentlemen are interested, too...
We're rather out of cash, my brother
here even sold his car, but...
Oh no, money's not the problem
Well, what is the problem then?
You see, gentlemen...
I'd like us to meet again
to discuss it
Only you'd have to have
some tests made
What tests?
Nothing special
Blood group, sedimentation, urine...
Ye-es...
As I told you,
this is not a financial problem
The man I was telling you about
lives in Tarnow
You know, the owner of
that red Austrian Mercury
And what does he want?
Just two stamps, a tiny series...
...owned by a serious
Szczecin businessmen
Well, what about him?
That's a good question
He in turn needs...
...a small and inconspicuous stamp
Which we have, right?
But why on earth you needed
our blood groups?
No
You haven't that stamp
Who has, then?
It so happens that... I do
You're the one
Why not me?
He's got the right blood group
You see, gentlemen...
the red Austrian Mercury
...is worth over two million
But it's not for sale
All of the parties involved
care for an exchange only
What about you?
Is blood what you want?
No
A kidney
My daughter is seriously ill
A girl of sixteen
I've been looking for someone
Your father was too old
Hell, what am I supposed to do?
Let them
remove one of my kidneys
to get a blood stamp?
To get the red Austrian Mercury
You're right, why, you have a family,
wife and son
No, I didn't mean that
Why, it's a part of myself
That's true
In your place,
I wouldn't hesitate a minute
What do I need that bloody kidney for,
I've got another one to live on
A guy I know had his kidney removed
over twenty years ago
...and he lives a normal life,
likes his liquor
and women and so on, no problem at all
And there's another thing!
I would also think about that girl
to save the life of a young girl
It's so humane
Artur...!
Come on, I'm not trying to persuade you
It's your kidney
But it's our stamp, too
I don't want anything from you
But I don't want...
...a thing from you,
And I won't give you a thing
I don't know who you are
But I don't want
...anything from you
Hopeless
He'll improve
Couldn't you go with us after all?
Such a tour...
I can't
You've been trapped, eh? A girl?
Some girl
Great
Good morning
Yes?
You see, I...
Are you from the City Death?
Actually, yes
Gee...
I'm looking for my brother
He's having his kidney removed
right now
Yes, I've been there
It'll be all right
I say, sir...
May I touch you?
Sure
Are you sure there's no danger?
Doctor?
How are you?
I'm fine as if nothing happened at all
Really?
Have you got it?
Of course
Christ... At last
When did you get it?
Ah well, about a week ago
Then why haven't you visited me
to let me see it?
I've been waiting all the time
I feared he could have cheated us
or something
Or that you've decided to keep it for yourself...
I couldn't come
What's the matter?
Out with it
During that operation, you know
I stayed in the hospital and
waited for news
You see, we've been robbed
What?
Robbed of everything
Bloody fool of a dog?
They locked him in the bathroom
I told you he should be poisoned
Move!
Get out!
What the hell did you go
to the hospital for?
They could manage without you
Does it ache?
Hey, did you report it?
Here
My brother's just been released
from the hospital
And how do you feel?
How shall I feel in these circumstances?
Do you know what was in this flat?
Yes, I know well enough
I'd like you to come over
to the headquarters
Why, with pleasure
By the way, sir... your brother
didn't know for sure
The alarm apparatus in the window
and balcony door...
...had been disconnected
From inside the flat
I did it
It hooted every time I put the grill on
You know, to be able to
open the window
I thought the girl was enough
I see, your brother wasn't sure
Well, good-bye, gentlemen
We'll get in touch with you, sir
Here's my phone number in case
you should want to see me
You never told me about
that alarm device
I forgot
This is all...
...we have
It's yours
Why?
The kidney was yours
Besides, I don't want it
Where are you going?
What business is it of yours?
I'm moving away
I've found a job in a bar
Leave me alone, will you?
I don't care a damn about this here
You wanted to see me, sir?
Yes
Well...
It's rather...
It's rather difficult to say...
You're sure to think the worst of me...
Don't worry about it
I think you should...
...well, check my brother
That dog, you know
Only my brother could touch him
...and yet the robbers managed
to lock him in the bathroom
He says he spent many hours in the hall
while I was operated on
That's right, he sat there all the time
Later, he even lay in the nurses' duty room
No, I didn't mean he did it
But some of his friends, perhaps...
You know, the company he keeps
Thank you
You've helped me a lot
Take care
Sorry I'm late
You wanted to see me?
Well, yes
You think I'm crazy?
No, why?
Well, we spent so much time in each
other's company, and now
I've invited you to have coffee
with me
Quite natural
It's confidential, isn't it?
Exactly
You see, we've talked a lot but...
I just couldn't say it
I suspect...
I suspect my brother might be involved
...in this robbery
Oh God, what have I said
You said...
You believed your brother
might be involved
I feel somehow
Well, I don't really know
It might be intuition only
Oh yes, intuition is not to be neglected
as you very well, know yourself
Well, you've helped me a lot
Just like they say in the movies
But it's a fact
Yes
Can I help you?
Thanks, I'm looking for new stamps
Have you any?
Oh yes
Fortieth anniversary of the police and
Security Force, sixty zlotys
A stamp with a seal on it, thirty
And world Championships
in Wrestling, twenty-five
I'd like one of each
How much are they?
One of each?
One hundred and five zlotys
I didn't expect you here
And I didn't expect you
Shut up, will you?
Arthur...
I did something horrible
So did I
I thought it was you
Jerzy
What's this?
Ah, I went to the post office and
bought these
It's a series
Ahk!
Darkness, darkness and jeer
Jeer and lies
Lies all week long,
All week long
You're the only hope
The only glimmer
You are everything
Because everything is...
...inside you