It's...
Monty python's flying circus.
I know you're down there.
Hey, did you see that?
Hmm?
Did you see somebody
go past the window?
What?
Somebody just went
past the window, that way.
Oh.
Another one.
Hmm?
Another one
just went past downwards.
What?
Two people have just fallen
Out of that window
to their almost certain death.
Fine, fine, fine.
Look!
Two people...
Three people
Have just fallen
Past that window.
Must be a board meeting.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, that was wilkins
of finance.
Oh, no,
that was robertson.
Wilkins.
Robertson.
That was wilkins.
He was a good,
uh, good golfer, wilkins.
Very good golfer,
very good golfer.
Rotten at finance.
It'll be parkinson next.
Bet you it won't.
How much?
What?
How much do you
bet it won't?
Fiver?
All right.
Done.
You're on.
Fine.
Come on, parky.
Don't do it, parky.
Jump, parky, jump. come on, now,
be sensible, parky.
Dear sir,
I am writing to complain
About that sketch about people
falling out of a high building.
I have worked all my life
in such a building
And have never once...
Parkinson!
Johnson!
My god, this is terrible!
Would somebody please stop it?!
Lord knows that.
Let's try it this way.
Alakazam!
Alacadabra! alakazam!
Alacadabra...
Hello!
tonight, spectrum looks
at one of the major problems
In the world today--
The whole vexed question
of what is going on.
Is there still time
to confront it
Let alone solve it,
or is it too late?
What are the figures,
what are the facts?
What do people mean
when they talk about things?
Alexander hardacre
of the economic affairs bureau.
In this graph
This column represents
23% of the population.
28% of the population
And this column represents
43% of the population.
Telling figures indeed,
but what do they mean to you?
What do they mean to me?
What do they mean to
the average man in the street?
With me now is professor tiddles
of leeds university.
Professor, you've
spent many years
researching into things.
What do you think?
I think it's too early to tell.
Too early to tell,
too early to say.
It means the same thing.
The word "say" is the same
as the word "tell."
They're not spelled the same,
but they mean the same.
It's an identical situation
we have with "ship" and "boat"
But not the same as we have
with "bow" and "bough"--
Different spellings and
meanings, but sound the same.
But the real question remains:
What is the solution,
if any, to this problem?
What can we do?
what am I saying?
Why am I sitting in this chair?
Why am I here
and what will I say next?
Here to answer this is
a professional cricketer.
I can say nothing at this point.
You were wrong.
professor?
Hello.
So, where do we stand?
where do we sit?
Where do we come?
where do we go?
What do we do?
what do we say?
What do we eat?
what do we drink?
What do we think?
what do we do?
Sorry!
Hello.
Mr. and mrs. johnson, isn't it?
That's right, yes.
Well,
come on in.
Excuse me not
shaking hands
But I've just
been putting
A bit of lard on
the cat's boil.
Very nice.
Well, you
must be tired.
It's a
long drive
From coventry,
isn't it?
Yes, well, we usually
reckon on 51/2 hours
And it took us
six hours and
53 minutes
With a 25-minute wait
at frampton cottrell
To stretch our legs
Only we had to wait
half an hour
To get on to the m5
near droitwich.
Really?
There was
A three-mile queue just
before bridgwater on the a38
Only normally we come
round on the b3339
Just before bridgwater,
you see.
Really?
We risked it
Because they say
They're going
to widen it there.
Are they?
Just there
At the intersection
where the a372 joins up
There's plenty of room
to widen it there.
There's only
the grass verges.
They could get
another six feet
Knock down that hospital.
Then we took the coast road
through williton
And got all the taunton traffic
on the a358
From crowcombe and stogumber.
Well, you must be dying
for a cup of tea.
Well, wouldn't say "no,"
not if it's warm and wet.
Well, come on
in the lounge.
I'm just
about to serve
afternoon tea.
Very nice.
Come on in,
mr. and mrs. johnson.
Oh, this is
Mr. and mrs. phillips.
Good afternoon.
It's their third
year with us.
We can't keep
you away, can we?
And over here
Is mr. hilter.
Ah, good time,
good afternoon.
Planning a little excursion
Are we, mr. hilter?
uh, ja, ja!
We make a little...
was ist ruckweise
bewegen?
"hike."
Hiking.
We make a little
hike for...
For bideford.
Oh, well, you'll
be wanting
the a39 then.
No, no, you've
got the wrong
map there.
This is
stalingrad.
You want
the ilfracombe
And barnstaple
section.
Ah, hein... reginald
You have the
wrong map here
You silly old
leg-before-wicket
english person.
i'm sorry, mein fuhrer.
I did not...
mein dickie, old chum.
Lucky
mr. johnson
Pointed that
out, eh?
You wouldn't
have had
much fun
In stalingrad,
would you?
I said you
wouldn't have
had much fun
In stalingrad,
would you?
Not much fun in stalingrad, no.
Oh, I'm sorry
I didn't
introduce you.
This is ron...
ron ribbentrop.
Oh, not
von ribbentrop?
nein! nein! nein!
Oh... no, he different
other chap.
No, I in somerset
am being born.
Von ribbentrop is born
in gotterammerstrasse 46
Dusseldorf,
west eight...
So they say!
And this is the quiet
one, mr. bimmler.
Heimlich bimmler.
How do you
do there, squire?
Also I am not minehead lad
But I in peterborough,
lincolnshire house
Was given birth to
But stay in peterborough,
lincolnshire house
All during war,
owing to nasty running sores
And was unable
to go in the streets
play fussball
or go to nurnberg.
I am retired window cleaner
and pacifist
Without doing war crimes.
And am very glad england
win world cup
Bobby charlton
and martin peters
And eating lots
of chips and fish
And toad in the holes
And dundee cake
on piccadilly line
Don't you know, old chap
And was head of gestapo
for ten years...
Five years!
oh! no, no, nein
I was not head
of gestapo at all.
I make joke.
Oh,
mr. bimmler
You do
have us on.
Oh, excuse me
I must just go
and answer that.
Uh, how long you
down here for,
mr. hilter?
Just the
fortnight?
Why do you
ask that?
You a spy
or something?
Get over there
against the wall,
britischer pig.
You're going to die.
Take it easy,
dickie, old chum.
I'm sorry,
mr. johnson.
He's a bit
on edge.
He hasn't slept
since 1945.
Shut your cake hole,
you nazi.
cool it,
fuhrer cat.
The fun we have.
Haven't I seen him
On the
television?
nicht, nein,
nein... oh, no.
Television
doctor?
No! no!
Telephone,
mr. hilter.
It's that nice
mr. mcgoering
From the bell
and compasses.
He says he's found a place
Where you can hire bombers
by the hour.
If he opens his big mouth again,
it's lampshade time!
Shut up!
Hire bombers by the hour.
What a laugh he is,
that scottish person!
Good old norman.
He's on the telephone
the whole time nowadays.
In business, is he?
Soon, baby.
Course, it's his
big day, thursday.
Oh, they've been planning
it for months.
What happens
then?
Oh, it's the north minehead
by-election.
Mr. hilter's standing as a
national bocialist candidate.
He's got wonderful plans
for minehead.
Like what?
Well, for a start
He wants to annex poland.
Oh, north
minehead's
Conservative,
isn't it?
Well, they get a lot of people
at their rallies.
Rallies?
Well, their bocialist meetings
Down at the axis cafe
in rosedale road.
achtung, achtung!
uber alles!
die eltern im mittelalter
und die jungen
alles muss mit dem
mittelschmerz gestoppen sein!
I... am not a racialist...
but-- und this is a big "but"--
We in the national
bocialist party believe
das uberleben...
muss gestammen sein mit der
schneakyarmstrong-jones.
historische taunton ist
volkermeinig von meinhead.
Mr. hitler...
Hilter... he says
that historically
Taunton...
Is part
of minehead already.
He's right,
do you know that?
und bridgwater ist
die letzte fuhlung
das wir haben in somerset!
sieg heil! sieg heil!
What do you think
of mr. hilter's policies?
Well, I don't like the sound
Of these here
boncentration bamps.
Well, I gave him my baby to kiss
and he bit it on the head.
Well, I think he'd do a lot
of good for the stock exchange.
No, no.
Oh, yes, britischer pals
he is wunderbar... ful, ja.
I think he's right
about the coons
But then I'm a bit mental.
I think he's got beautiful legs.
Well, speaking
as conservative candidate
I just drone on and on
and on and on
Never letting anyone else
get a word in edgewise
Until I start foaming
at the mouth
And falling over backwards.
Foam at the mouth
and fall over backwards.
Is he foaming at the mouth
to fall over backwards
Or falling over backwards
to foam at the mouth?
tonight's spectrum examines
the whole question
Of frothing and falling,
coughing and calling
Screaming and bawling,
walling and stalling
Galling and mauling,
palling and hauling
Trawling and squalling
and zalling.
Zalling?
is there a word "zalling?"
If there is, what does it mean?
If there isn't,
what does it mean?
Perhaps both, maybe neither.
What do I mean
by the word "mean"?
by the word "word"?
What do I mean
by "what do I mean?"
What do I mean by "do"
and what do I do by "mean"?
What do I do by do by do?
And what do I mean by wasting
your time like this? good night.
Good night.
Good evening, I wish
to report a burglary.
Speak up, please, sir.
I wish to report a burglary.
I can't hear you, sir.
I wish to report a burglary!
That's a little
bit too loud.
Could you say it
Just a little
less loud than that?
I wish to report a burglary!
No, I'm still
not getting anything.
Uh, could you try it
in a higher register?
What do you mean,
What?
I wish to report a burglary.
That's it, wait a moment.
Now, a little
bit louder.
I wish to report a burglary!
Report a what?
Burglary!!
That's it, now keep it there.
Hello, sarge!
Evening, charlie.
I was sitting
at home
With a friend of mine
from camber sands
When we heard a noise
in the bedroom!
We went to investigate
and found £5,000 stolen!
Well, I'm afraid
I'm off duty now, sir.
Uh, could you tell
sergeant foster?
I was sitting at home
With a friend of mine
from camber sands!
Excuse me, sir, but, uh,
why the funny voice?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I'd just got used to talking
like that to the other sergeant.
I'm terribly sorry,
I can't hear you, sir.
Could you try speaking
in a lower register?
What? oh.
I wish to report the loss
of £5,000.
£5,000? that's serious.
You'd better speak
to the detective inspector.
What seems to be the trouble,
sergeant?
Well, this gentleman, sir,
has come in
To report that he was sitting
at home with a friend
When he heard a noise
in the back room
Went round to investigate
And found that £5,000 in savings
had been stolen.
I see.
Where do you live, sir?
121 halliwell road,
dulwich, se21.
Another halliwell road
job, eh, sergeant?
Yes, I can't
believe it.
I thought the bloke
who'd done that
Was put inside
last year.
Yes, in parkhurst.
Well, it must have been
somebody else.
Thank you, sergeant.
We'll get things
moving right away.
You take over here,
sergeant.
Alert all squad cars
in the area.
Hello, darling
I'm afraid
I shall be late.
Calling all squad cars
in the area.
I think that's
in very bad taste.
Some people do talk
in the most extraordinary way.
Good afternoon, and welcome
to hurlingham park.
You join us just as the
competitors are running out
Onto the field on this
lovely winter's afternoon here
With the going firm underfoot
and very little sign of rain.
Well, it certainly looks
As though we're in
for a splendid afternoon's sport
In this, the 127th "upper-class
twit of the year" show.
Well, the competitors
will be off any moment
So let me just identify them
for you.
Vivian smith-smythe-smith
has o-level in chemo-hygiene.
Simon-zinc-trumpet-harris
Married to
a very attractive table lamp.
Nigel incubator-jones--
his best friend is a tree
And in his spare time,
he's a stockbroker.
Gervaise brook-hampster is
in the guards
And his father uses him
as a wastepaper basket.
And finally, oliver st. john-
mollusc, harrow and the guards
Thought by many to be
this year's outstanding twit.
Now they're moving out
to the starting line.
There's a jolly good crowd
here today.
Now they're under
starter's orders
And...
They're off!
Oh, no, they're not.
No, they didn't realize
they were supposed to start.
Never mind,
we'll soon sort that out.
The judge is explaining it
to them now.
I think nigel and gervaise
have got the idea.
All set to go.
Oh, and they're off.
And it's a fast start this year.
Oliver st. john-mollusc running
a bit wide there
And now they're coming
into their first test--
The straight line.
They've got to walk
along this straight line
Without falling over.
And oliver's over
at the back there...
Uh, simon's coming through
quite fast on the outside.
I think simon and nigel...
Both of them coming through
very fast.
There's nigel there,
number three, I'm sorry.
And on the outside,
there's gervaise
Coming through just out of shot.
And now, the positions:
Simon and vivian at the front
coming to the matchbox jump--
Three layers
of matchboxes to clear.
And simon's over and
vivian's over beautifully.
Oh, the jump of a lifetime--
If only his father
could understand.
Here's nigel...
he's confused.
No, gervaise is over.
He's, uh... nigel is over...
He's only just hit the top.
And now it's gervaise.
Gervaise is going to jump.
Is it... no, he's jumped
the wrong way.
There he goes.
Nigel's over beautifully.
Now it's only oliver,
oliver and gervaise...
Oh, bad luck.
And now it's
"kicking the beggar."
Simon's there,
and he's putting the boot in
And not terribly hard
But he's going down,
so simon can move on.
Now vivian's there.
Vivian is there and waiting
for a chance.
Here he comes.
Oh, a real pile driver,
a real pile driver.
And now simon's at number one;
vivian, two;
Nigel, three; gervaise at four;
and oliver bringing up the rear.
Uh... there's oliver,
there's oliver now.
He's at the back.
I think he's having
a little trouble
With his old brain in jury.
He's going to have a go...
No, no, bad luck.
He's up, he doesn't know
when he's beaten, this boy.
He doesn't know
when he's winning either.
He doesn't have any sort of
sensory apparatus known to man.
He's now standing up...
oh, bad luck.
Oh, there's gervaise
putting the boot in there.
There's no need for him
to do this.
He's got the beggar down.
The steward's giving him
a little bit of advice.
Yes, he can move on now.
He can move on
to the hunt photograph.
There's gerv... I think he's...
yes, he's off.
Gervaise is there,
and oliver's still at the back
Having trouble
with the matchboxes.
Now, here's
the hunt ball photograph.
And the first here is simon.
He's going to en joy a joke
with lady arabella plunkett.
She hopes to go into films.
And vivian's through there
And nigel's there
en joying a joke
With lady sarah pencil farthing
vivian steamroller
Adams pie biscuit aftershave
gore stringbottom smith.
And there's... and there's simon
now in the sports car.
He's reversed
into the old woman.
He's caught her
absolutely beautifully.
Now he's going to accelerate
forward there
To wake up the neighbor.
There's vivian, I think...
no, vivian's lost his keys...
No, there's vivian!
He's got the old woman,
slowly but surely
Right in the midriff,
and here he is.
Here he is to wake up
the neighbor now.
Simon right in the lead,
comfortably in the lead
But he can't get this neighbor
woken up.
He's slamming away there
as best he can.
He's getting absolutely
no reaction at all.
There! there, he's woken him up
and simon's through.
Here comes vivian...
vivian to slam the door.
And there we are
back at the hunt ball.
I think that's gervaise.
Yes, that's gervaise
going through there.
And here... here comes oliver,
brave oliver.
Is he going to make it
to the table?
No, I don't think he is.
Yes, he is.
Oh! what a great twit!
And the crowd are really rising
to him there.
And there, I can see...
who is that there?
Yes, that's nigel.
Nigel has woken the neighbor.
My god, this is exciting!
Nigel's very excited,
he's going through.
Here comes gervaise.
Gervaise...
oh, no, this is, uh...
Out in the front there is simon
Who is supposed
to insult the waiter
And he's forgotten.
And oliver has run himself over.
What a great twit!
And there...
now here comes vivian.
Vivian to insult the waiter,
and he is heaping abuse on him
And he is humiliating him there.
And he's gone into the lead.
Simon's not with him.
No, vivian's...
has hit the bar.
Now they've got to get
over this bar.
This is extremely difficult
As it requires
absolutely expert coordination
Between mind and body.
No, they're hitting it there.
Here we go again.
Simon's fallen backwards.
Here's nigel, and he's tripped.
Nigel has tripped,
and he's under
And simon fails again.
Now here is gervaise,
going to jump through
And simon is through
by accident.
Here's gervaise
to be the last one over.
Here we are.
Here's nigel right at the head
of the field
And now he's going
to shoot the rabbit.
These rabbits have been tied
to the ground
And they're going
to be a bit frisky.
And this is only
a one-day event.
And they're blazing away there.
They're not getting quite
the results that they might.
Gervaise is in there
Trying to bash it to death
with the butt of his rifle.
And I think nigel's in there
with his bare hands
But they're not getting
the results they might
But it is a little bit
misty today
And they must be shooting
from a range of at least a foot.
But there's a couple
of hits there, I think.
Yes, they've had
a couple of hits
And the whole field is up again
and here they are.
They're coming up to the debs--
Gervaise first, vivian second,
simon third.
And now they've got to take
the bras off from the front.
This is really difficult.
This is really
the most difficult part
Of the entire competition.
And they're having a bit
of trouble in there, I think.
They're really trying now and
the crowd is getting excited
And I think some of the twits
are getting rather excited, too.
But anyway, vivian is there,
vivian is coming through.
Simon's in second place and...
oh, there's oliver.
He's dead, but he's not
necessarily out of it.
There goes nigel.
No, he's lost something.
And gervaise running through
to this final obstacle.
Now, all they have to do here
to win the title is
To shoot themselves.
Simon has a go--
bad luck, he misses.
Nigel misses.
Now, there's gervaise,
and gervaise has shot himself.
Gervaise is upper-class twit
of the year.
There's nigel--
he's shot simon by mistake.
Simon is second
and there's nigel.
Nigel's shot himself.
Nigel is third in this fine
And most exciting upper-class
twit of the year I've ever seen.
Wait-- nigel's clubbed himself
into fourth place.
And so the final result: the
upper-class twit of the year--
Gervaise brook-hampster
of kensington and weybridge;
Runner-up-- vivian smith-
smythe-smith of kensington;
And third-- nigel incubator-
jones of henley.
Well, there'll certainly be
some car door slamming
In the streets
of kensington tonight.
Dear sir, how splendid it is
To see the flower
of british manhood
Wiping itself out
with such pluck and tenacity.
Britain need have no fear
with leaders of this caliber.
If only a few of
the so-called working classes
Would destroy themselves
so sportingly.
Yours, etc.
Brigadier mainwaring
smith smith smith, etc.
(deceased, etc.)
P.s., etc. come on, other ranks,
show your stuff.
Yes, sir, I'll do me best, sir!
No, not
good enough.
No, still
not good enough.
Yes, that's better.
Hallelu jah, hallelu jah...
Okay, all clear.
Now, I understand
That you want to
marry my daughter.
That's right, yeah, yeah.
Yes, you realize,
of course
That rosamund is
still rather young?
Daddy, you make me feel
like a child.
Oh, yeah, you know...
Get them when
they're young, eh... eh?
You know what I mean?!
I'm sure you know
what I mean, mister...
Uh... shabby, ken shabby.
Mr. shabby, I just
want to make sure
That you'll be able to
look after my daughter.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I'll be able
to look after her,
all right, sport.
Eh? you know
what I mean, eh?
And, uh...
What job do you do?
I clean out public lavatories.
Is there a promotion involved?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
After five years,
they give me a brush.
I'm sorry, squire,
I've gobbed on your carpet.
And, uh... where are
you going to live?
Well, round
at my gran's.
She trains polecats
But most of them
have suffocated
So there should be
a bit of spare room
in the attic, eh?
Know what I mean?
I see.
And when do you expect
to get married?
Oh, right away, sport,
right away, you know?
I haven't had it for weeks.
Well, look,
I'll phone the bishop
And see if we can get the abbey.
Oh, diarrhea.
the story so far...
rosamund's father
has become ensnared
by mr. shabby's extraordinary
personal magnetism.
bob and janet ha ve eaten
mr. farquar's goldfish
during an oxfam lunch
and mrs. elsmore's marriage
is threatened
by doug's insistence
that he is
on a different level
of consciousness.
louise's hernia
has been confirmed
and jim, bob's brother, has run
over the editor of the lancet
on his wa y to see jenny,
a freelance pagoda designer.
on the other side
of the continent
napoleon still broods
over the smoldering remains
of a city he had crossed
half the earth to conquer
whilstmary,
roger's half-sister
settles down
to watch television.
there now follows
a party political broadcast
on behalf of the wood party.
Good evening.
We in the wood party
feel very strongly
That the present weak drafting
of the local government bill
Leaves a lot to be desired
And we intend to fight.
Hello?
Hello?!
I'm afraid the minister's fallen
through the earth's crust.
Excuse me a moment.
Hello?
Hello.
Are you all right,
minister?
I appear to have landed
on this kind of ledge thing.
Shall we lower down
one of the bbc ropes?
If you'd be so kind.
What length
of bbc rope
Will we be likely
to need?
I should use
the longest bbc rope.
That would be a good idea,
I would imagine.
Okey-doke, chief.
Tex, get the longest bbc rope
and bring it here pronto.
In the meantime, since
I am on all channels
Perhaps I'd better carry on
with this broadcast
By shouting about
our housing plans
From down here
as best as I can.
Could someone throw me down
a script?
The script would appear
To have landed
on a different ledge
Somewhat out of my grasp,
don't you know.
Well, perhaps when
the rope reaches you,
minister
You could kind
of swing over
To the ledge
and grab it.
Good idea.
Well, I'm going to carry on
If I can read the script.
Good evening.
We in the wood party...
Feel very strongly about...
The present weak drafting
of the local government bill.
And... no, it's no good,
it's not working.
I think I'll have to try
and make a grab for it.
Ah! there we are.
Good evening.
We in the wood party feel very
strongly about the present...
Oh, dear.
Hello!
Look, I must look
a bit of a chump
Hanging upside down like this.
Don't worry,
minister.
I think, love, if we turn
the picture upside down
We should help
the minister, then.
Oh, good.
Look, I'm sorry about this.
There seems to be
a few gremlins about.
I think I'd better start
from the beginning.
Good evening.
We in the wood party
feel very strongly about...
Oh, bloody heck!
Oh!
Oh, dear.
Terribly sorry about this...
About saying "bloody heck"
on all channels, but...
There's another
script on the way
down, minister.
Oh, good, good.
Well, um... good evening.
Well, how are you?
Oh, look, I don't want you
to think of the wood party
As a load of old men that
like hanging around on ropes
Only i... oh...
Thank you.
Good evening.
We in the wood party
feel very strongly
About the present
weak drafting...
Look, I think we'd better
call it a day.
Is this the furthest distance
That a minister
has fallen? robert.
Surprisingly not.
The canadian minister
for external affairs
Fell nearly seven miles
During a liberal conference
in ottawa about six years ago.
And then quite recently
The kenyan minister
for agric. and fish
Fell nearly 12 miles
During a nairobi debate
in parliament
Although this hasn't been
ratified yet.
How far did the filipino cabinet
fall last march?
Well, they fell nearly 39 miles
But it's not nearly
so remarkable, as that was due
To their combined weight,
of course, robert.
Yes, well, thank you, robert.
Well now, what are your
reactions to all this? robert.
Well... well, robert
The main thing is
that it's terribly exciting
Tremendously exciting.
You see, the minister is
quite clearly lodged
Between rocks we know terribly
little of, terribly little.
Of course, the main thing is
we're getting color pictures
Of an extraordinarily
high quality
Extraordinarily high quality.
But the important thing is...
The really exciting thing is
The minister will be bringing
back samples of the earth's core
Which will give us a tremendous
Really tremendous, tremendous,
tremendous clue
As to the origins of the earth
and what god himself is made of.
Oh, oh, I needed that.
Thank you, robert.
Well, that seems to be
About all
we have time for tonight
Unless anyone has
anything else to say.
Has anyone anything else to say?
No.
Nope, nope.
No!
No.
Bloody fairy.
No!
Uh... no.
No.
nein... no.
No, no, no, no.
What do we mean by "no"?
What do we mean by "yes"?
What do we mean by "no, no, no"?
tonight spectrum looks at the
whole question of "what is no?"