What do you think
of Darren Jarvis?
At CBS?
He wants me to be
a correspondent.
It's not
worth your time.
What about Greer Fisher,
at MSNBC?
Stick to writing,
do TV on the side.
You're more than
a talking head.
How about Slugline?
What's Slugline?
If I said Politico wanted to
hire me, what would you say?
I would say that
that piques my interest.
Six months from now,
Slugline will be
what Politico was
a year and half ago.
Everyone at Politico
reads it
because Slugline's breaking
stories before they are.
I wonder why I've
never heard of it.
Everyone's
a free agent.
And they write whatever they
want, wherever they are.
Most people write
from their phones.
Well, if freedom and exposure
are what they're offering,
I would say that is
a meeting worth taking.
This Hammerschmidt
thing is blowing up.
I think he might
get fired.
There's got to be
a thousand tweets here...
People defending me,
people trashing me.
There's even a hashtag,
GoZoe.
Hmm.
Hey!
We mustn't leave
any trails.
All of my contacts
were in there.
Then it's time for you
to get some new contacts.
Don't worry. I'll get you a phone.
I'll get you two, in fact.
One for work
and a burner for play.
Expect them
this afternoon.
Oh, and... Go, Zoe.
The reporter?
Yes.
Just this once?
I'm not sure.
What does she offer us?
A mouthpiece,
when we need one.
She's been
very useful so far.
What does she want?
Access.
A seat at the table.
Sounds like she's getting the
better side of the bargain.
She can be controlled.
Are you sure?
She can.
I promise you.
Okay, if you say so.
The moment you
want me to end it...
I know, Francis.
I should get
ready for work.
Hey...
I didn't think
you'd be in until later.
This is your
agenda for the day.
Here's your schedule
for the rest of the week.
These are papers that need
to be approved or signed.
Over here are your one-sheets
for committee meetings
and briefs on upcoming
legislative action.
I filled Ashley in. She can cover
until you find a replacement.
Christina.
What?
Thank you.
For getting
all this in order.
Ashley can call me if you have any
questions about what's on your desk.
He here yet?
I put him
in your office.
Marty Spinella. Head lobbyist
for the teachers union.
He wants to rip my head off
and peel it like an orange.
Why? Because I lied to him.
But what choice did I have?
When the truth would have ended
the conversation before it began?
I'll call you back.
Marty.
You fucking lied, Frank?
No, no, no.
You lie to my fucking face?
Marty, I did not lie. What
do you mean you did not?
We spent a whole
weekend in that room
poring over this bill
line by line.
And nowhere did it say anything
about collective bargaining.
Let's calm down and sit down.
And we will discuss this.
I will explain everything that's
going on and we will talk it out.
No matter how long it takes.
No. No more.
This is gonna be
a very short meeting.
'Cause only one of two
things are going to happen.
Either you assure me right
now that amendment is out,
or I am walking out that door and I
am gonna start launching missiles.
The amendment was never
intended to stay in the bill.
It's just there for leverage.
That's all.
You threaten to cut federal funding
from union school districts?
That's not a poker chip, Frank,
that's a goddamn dirty bomb.
Look, the amendment
is not staying in the bill.
I just need you to work with
me on performance standards.
Performance standards?
Are you fucking kidding me? You
agreed that they were already out.
You can't just put it back in now, Frank.
Marty, look...
I have a reputation
to uphold.
I am the one that made the
union reps stay here for you
while you're in Gaffney playing
with your fucking Peachoid.
Marty...
You tell me right now,
is that amendment
in or out?
There is a middle ground here, Marty.
We just have to find it.
I take that as a no.
Okay.
Marty, do not start a war
you know you're gonna lose.
You fuck me,
I fuck back.
Stamper!
Marty and I have a good
working relationship.
Or used to.
You could see
he has a temper,
but I can usually cut through
that and reason with him.
But I may have pushed him too far.
Which is worrisome.
Friends make
the worst enemies.
How'd it go?
What'd you hear?
A lot of fucks. Well,
that pretty much says it.
Let's think
this through...
No, we've got the DNC
leadership meeting.
What?
I'd say you could skip it, but
Birch just dumped it on us.
When? It's here. In 12 minutes.
Why here and not
the DNC headquarters?
The DNC is doing renovations, they're
gonna be green-energy efficient.
That's a charming
use of party funds.
We've only been in this
space about three months.
It's cool.
Not exactly
The Herald, is it?
Have you been to those offices?
Yes.
Wrist-slitting
was in order.
So, who else
is courting you?
A few people.
You mean everyone.
There were a lot of
emails this morning...
That's not surprising.
You're having a moment,
people are interested.
I'm one of them.
But if eight minutes passes
on anything, I get bored.
In eight minutes, I could be bored with you.
Unless you keep me interested.
I think you can,
and I think this
is the place for you
to keep the rest of
the world interested, too.
It's your call.
I won't chase you.
I'm definitely tempted...
Take as long as you
want to look around.
Email me your figure. I'll
call you back with a counter.
This is our top priority. Ohio,
Florida and Pennsylvania.
We need all of them or
Walker's a one-term president.
Pennsylvania is why he picked
Matthews as a running mate.
But now we have to
find a replacement.
The special election
is this November.
Patricia Whittaker.
DNC chair.
A rare example of someone
whose head is in the game
instead of
up their backside.
Competence is such an
exotic bird in these woods
that I appreciate
it whenever I see it.
Now, this also
affects the House.
The new Governor will
oversee redistricting.
We lose seats here,
that means we could lose
our majority in Washington.
Well, the RNC is backing Jack
Swofford, ex-mayor of Pittsburgh.
He's got state-wide
name recognition
and campaign machinery
in place...
It's been three months
and we don't have dick.
What about the A.G.?
Ben Pluckett?
No, Ben's got his eyes set
on the Senate in '14.
Yeah, which he'll lose because he
botched a sex offender sting last year.
Well, there's always McHolland.
He's 78.
When's the last time he held office?
When Carter was president?
Reagan,
but same difference.
Well, he has dignity.
He has gravitas.
I mean, if you need someone
to fill Matthews' shoes...
You can't fill Jim Matthews' shoes.
So we shouldn't even try.
We need a fresh face.
The state has
a weak bench.
Well, let's go through all the
sitting Congressmen one by one,
and see if anybody
sticks out from the crowd.
All right. I got the list right here.
Okay. Go ahead.
Pennsylvania's first
district, Peter Russo.
Cross him off. He's no good.
No experience. No chops.
Okay, moving on. Second
district, Gwendolyn Pierce.
Gwen's too controversial.
Very vocal on abortion...
And, Caroline?
She's good.
Yeah? How're the boys?
All fuckin'
four of them?
You feed 'em.
You got any pictures?
On your phone?
Come on. Let's cut the
shit, Pete, will ya?
What are we gonna do
about the shipyard?
BRAC had their hearing.
They slated it for closing.
Yeah, and why
didn't you testify?
We're talking
12,000 jobs here.
My hands were tied, Paul.
People wanted it closed.
I was under a lot of pressure.
From who?
People high up the food chain.
There's nothing I could do.
That's bullshit. You go back to BRAC.
You talk to the DOD.
You talk to the Secretary of the Navy.
You do something...
It's not gonna happen.
Okay, why not?
I told you,
it's political.
Okay, so I'm supposed to go back
to the Shipbuilder's Association
and say what now,
exactly?
That they're out of work because
Pete Russo's playing politics?
I mean, Jesus, Pete.
We're the ones who got you fuckin'
elected in the first place.
Now you're gonna
turn your back on us?
You should go.
Seriously?
I just got here.
You're kickin' me out now?
Hey, I'm fuckin'
talkin' to you.
I thought we
grew up together.
But this guy, sitting
behind his big desk,
I don't even know
who the fuck he is.
Where's the Pete Russo who
knew how to throw a punch
when his back was
against the wall?
That guy was my friend.
Every teacher in the country?
A month before school ends?
He doesn't need
all of them.
Fifteen, 20 states.
That's all.
But the AFT and the NEA
can't agree on anything.
You underestimate
Marty Spinella.
So which one
do we target?
We have a better
chance with the NEA.
You think Chuck Sloan
will bite?
Cooperate, we give your people
protection and a place at the banquet.
Fight us, we break you.
He'll bite.
Get him on the phone.
It's after 2:00.
Spinella's potentially mobilizing
the largest teachers' strike
in United States history.
Nobody's sleeping.
I'll call him
right now.
I'm sorry.
Are we being too loud?
A little.
What are you working on?
The gala.
There's so much to do.
Did Nancy
send you my list?
She did.
And what'd you think?
It's a good list.
Thanks for inviting them.
Is something wrong?
It's still not anywhere near
what Remy brought to the table.
SanCorp offered
1.5 million, Francis.
I'm adding up the numbers and
we're only at half a million.
I got Chuck on the phone.
In a minute.
I can make
more calls...
Enough to raise
1.5 million?
Well, I can at least
get us closer.
I'm going to bed.
Don't move
any of this around.
Claire... We made the
decision to turn Remy down.
No one forced you. I thought
we were okay on this.
You're right.
Good night, Francis.
This is Adam.
Leave a message.
Hi, Adam, it's me.
I know it's late, but...
Well, I was really just calling to
thank you again for the photographs.
I'm sure they're gonna be
a big hit at the auction.
Hope you're well.
I'm sure they're gonna be
a big hit at the auction.
Hope you're well.
Right this way,
Mr. Hammerschmidt.
He's here.
Good afternoon, Tom.
Legal?
Did you say it
or didn't you?
To you and to
anyone who asks...
Yes, I did.
Do we really
need them?
Not unless I should
expect a fight.
You shouldn't.
Give us a few moments.
It's not what
you called her.
It's that you let her
leave the building.
I know how to run
a paper, Margaret.
What I don't know how
to do is run a paper
staffed with people
I can't control.
Was she really
out of control?
To my understanding, she simply
turned down a new position.
It's her attitude. It's the
way she turned it down.
Did you think to ask her what
she'd rather do instead?
Is it my job to pander
to all my employees' wants...
My employees.
And if they have something
to offer that you don't,
yes, it is your job.
We've been
through this, Tom.
The paper's operating at a loss.
We need people like Zoe...
I'm very aware of how much
we're hurting, Margaret.
Staff reductions,
dip in circulation,
each one of those faces
and every subscriber we lose,
they keep me
awake at night.
Now I... I won't argue
the business side of things.
It's neither my place
nor my area of expertise.
But know this,
Zoe Barnes,
Twitter, blogs,
enriched media,
they're all surface.
They're fads.
They aren't the foundation
this paper was built on,
and they aren't
what will keep it alive.
We have a core readership
that thirsts for hard news.
Those are the people I work
80 hours a week for.
And I won't be distracted
by what's fashionable.
That's your
resignation letter.
Hand it to the lawyers
on the way out.
I'll give you
some privacy.
No, no, stay,
it'll be quick.
We'll get a drink.
We're gonna launch
right here in Washington.
We'll see how
Congress likes it
when the streets are teeming
with unsupervised school kids.
Then we'll phase out
the rest of the country.
Everybody, hold on for one minute.
What's up?
The NEA is out.
What?
They pulled out.
Why?
He wouldn't say.
Hold on for
one more minute.
Chuck Sloan? Get him on
the phone right now.
I've got him right here.
Is he muted?
Yes.
Hey, Chuck, it's Marty.
Listen, you can't do this.
If we don't stay united now,
we don't have a...
You hired me to represent
your interests, right?
How could I possibly
lobby for the teachers
when Congress
sees us splintering
before we even
put up a unite...
All right.
Did Underwood
get to you?
Frank is dishonest
and manipulative.
You've seen that
he's lied to us already.
Wait, Chuck?
Chuck, Chuck? Chuck!
Son of a bitch!
Where are you?
I'm at the office.
False.
You don't believe me?
Not for a second.
Where are you?
About to walk
into a meeting.
With who?
Someone I have to punish.
Give me a name.
No names.
What did this
person do wrong?
Lie to me.
How will you
punish him?
What makes you
think it's a him?
Hold on.
I have to take this.
Where are you?
Me? I am...
Not at the office.
You're gonna give me a new
one of these every week?
Well, I can't
continue to...
Not without protection.
Nobody tells me when
to work and when to play.
I'm not being
unreasonable, Zoe.
If you can't trust me, we
shouldn't be doing this at all.
Well, then how do we
establish our trust?
I have been very discreet.
Professional
discretion, yes.
But this is
new territory.
You have a camera
on your phone.
Pictures.
The kind I wouldn't
want my father to see.
Well, I'm gonna
need more than that.
Lie back.
Use your imagination.
I want everything
packed for tomorrow.
We checked already, Dad.
Did you? Those are my pink
Nikes on the kitchen counter?
And you, Autobot, what is Optimus
Prime doing under my bed?
He better transform himself
into your backpack
before you have
to leave tomorrow.
Hey, Dad,
is Christina coming back?
I don't... I don't
think so, buddy. No.
Oh.
I liked her.
Me, too.
She's cool.
Yeah, she is cool.
Now, you guys
gotta brush your teeth.
And then check
the rooms again.
And then it's
time for bed.
Got it, pumpkins?
Dad, you know I hate it
when you call us pumpkins.
Go. Before I turn you
into a pie.
Peter Russo.
He's a drunk.
He is at the moment.
A very functional one.
Imagine if he was sober.
Even so,
you run him for Governor,
people are going
to dig into his past.
Well, we turn that into an
asset, not a liability.
Here's who I was,
here's who I am now.
You saw how they dismissed him in three
seconds at the Leadership meeting.
Patti Whittaker is very open-minded.
And I am very persuasive.
You think Russo
even wants it?
Any kid who's made it from
the streets of South Philly
to the Capitol
rotunda is ambitious.
We just need
to tap into that.
Surround him with the best people
and then build the machine
and push the "go" button.
So you think
he could win.
I think he can be
a contender.
Okay, let's say we pull off
a miracle and he wins.
What do we gain by it?
Isn't it better to be holding
the reins in this race
than watching
from the stands?
Your wife
is on the phone.
Put her through
in here.
I understand
that Pennsylvania's
important for
re-districting...
No, no, no, this isn't just
about this race, Doug.
Expand your thinking. Who
else is from Pennsylvania?
No, no, no,
not in Congress.
The executive branch.
The Vice President.
Hello, my dear.
Nancy had my tux dry-cleaned
so I won't embarrass...
The Cotesworth
canceled on us.
I'm leaving right now. I'll come get you.
I've gotta go.
What's going on?
The hotel,
for tonight's gala,
they refuse to let
Claire into the ballroom
because their
employees are union.
Spinella.
Yeah, he can go after me all he wants.
But to go after my wife?
No class.
Meet me
at the Cotesworth.
You got it.
Why can't we just move
it to another place?
I looked into that.
Everything's booked.
You have to reserve these
things weeks in advance.
I got Stamper online looking
for another venue somewhere.
Francis, the delivery trucks
are already at the Cotesworth.
I can't have people showing up
at a different place
in case they
don't get the email.
All right. This is my fault.
I feel awful.
There's a half a million
on the line here.
I realize that.
And I can't keep
having my work
take these hits
on behalf of yours.
It's more than
just an inconvenience.
I know.
We'll solve it.
Hey, I just got
your email.
What'd you think?
You don't have to send me
things before you post.
I thought you might
want to take a look.
The goal here
is for everyone
to post things faster than I
have a chance to read 'em.
If you're satisfied with the
article, you just put it up.
Okay.
Are you satisfied?
I think so.
Okay, you are
or you aren't.
Whatever hoops The Herald
made you jump through...
I know.
Let them go.
It's okay
to be opinionated, Zoe.
And it's okay to go outside
and get your hands dirty.
You're no longer
tied to a desk.
Or to that pillow for that matter.
I'm not gonna post it.
Midterm predictions, they're not news.
They're bullshit.
Well, I agree.
I can do better.
I think you can.
Feel free to blow my mind.
If we do this event,
the whole staff walks out.
I've got 300 guests...
You signed a contract
with my wife.
We'll refund your
wife's organization
and pay for whatever the
cost of moving the event
to a more
appropriate venue.
And we would have to refund half
a million dollars in donations.
Can you pay
for that, too?
'Cause I'm pretty sure there's
cause for damages here.
I truly apologize, sir.
Who's your boss?
I spoke with
the owners,
and they authorized me
to do what I think is best.
And do they realize that
they are shutting the door
on 41 members of
the United States Congress?
Yes, sir. They do.
I had to make a very
hard judgment call.
Well, I seriously
question your judgment.
You know, word travels
fast in this town.
All those luncheons
and conventions and dinners,
it's gonna be a shame to lose
all that work, isn't it?
Congressman,
you are absolutely right,
but if my staff
walks out, I...
Please understand
the predicament I'm in.
I got an idea.
I know what
we're gonna do.
Honey, they're not gonna
let us have it inside,
we're gonna
have it right here,
on their front steps.
Picnic style.
What do you
need from me?
I need your manpower.
Yes, sir, I'm on it.
Okay, everybody, stop what
you're doing and listen up.
Yeah?
Hey, Frank.
Listen,
I need a favor, a large one.
How soon?
In about three hours.
How many people we talking?
Just 300.
The florist is gonna send
over whatever he has.
Great.
Francis,
where are we with food?
I've got hot dogs, pizzas,
and soul food coming.
Maybe something else.
Girls.
Here's what I want.
I want four bars, two on each level.
The food can go there.
The silent auction
goes here.
And cancel the string quartet.
Let's get a DJ.
Doug,
how are we on booze?
Kegs are on their way now.
Great.
And call Denise
at the office
and have her bring every
donation envelope she can find.
Okay, messages, people.
Congressman Russo's office. Yes, can
you hold one minute? Thank you.
Congressman? People keep
calling about the shipyards.
We don't know
what to tell them.
We just say we'll
give you the message.
Keep saying that.
Okay, here they are.
The messages and all the
emails we've gotten to.
Do you want me to...
Have a good night.
Who'd we reach?
Herald, The Times,
USA Today.
All right, I want affiliate
stations and cable news.
I want satellite trucks out there.
I want this on live TV.
Okay, I'm on it.
You can't
do this here.
Zoe, 8:00 p.m. tonight,
Hotel Cotesworth.
Benefit for
my wife's charity.
No. Wash your face
and let your hair down.
This is
work and play.
See you.
I can tell you right now
I'm gonna need two dozen.
Paul, I'm gonna need those
by tomorrow, okay?
Your guests are
your problem, not mine.
Julian.
I'll close the gate.
You know, I'm no
expert in fire code,
but I would imagine
that locking your guests in
is a bigger violation than
having them walk around us.
This is trespassing on private property.
You're breaking the law.
All right. Okay.
Let me get Barney Hull
on the phone here for you.
Here you go.
It's ringing.
Who's Barney Hull?
Police Commissioner.
Commissioner Hull's office.
Hello? No? Okay.
You'd rather talk
to him in person?
That's great.
He's coming to the party.
I'll be sure to introduce
the two of you.
Thanks for
your hospitality.
What do you want me to do?
I can't lock the gates.
And they've got
the police on their side.
Unbelievable.
Hold on.
Cassandra. I need 200 teachers
at the Cotesworth Hotel.
Right now.
I need a full picket.
Two hundred?
I don't know if we can
get that many on... I don't want to hear it.
Just get it done.
All right. I don't give a fuck if
they're teachers or not, frankly.
Just get me 200 bodies.
Call the Teamsters,
maybe they'll help us.
We'll give them glasses if we have to.
Tell the guys to look smart.
Charlie, get off the phone. I need
signs right now, at least 100.
You know what?
Let them set it up.
It's actually better
for us that way. They...
This way they
can't hide from us.
You've put me in
a terrible situation.
Thank you very much
for all your help.
Much appreciated.
Here, we've got the signs right here.
Let's hand them out fast.
Everybody, single file, right down the
street, this way and that way, okay?
Well, at least
he spelled it right.
Teachers protesting the Education
Reform and Achievement Act
have descended upon the Hotel
Cotesworth in Washington, D. C.
Union lobbyist, Marty Spinella,
organized the demonstration.
Teachers deserve respect!
Now, I knew you'd show up and you'd
bring that beautiful wife of yours.
Hello, it's a pleasure,
thank you for coming.
Come on in,
the drinks are on the house.
Felicity.
The party can begin.
This is Spinella.
He got us shut out
by the union,
so we had to have a party
out here on the steps.
I'm gonna take you
up to a bar right now.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you. Welcome.
Teachers, yes! Unions, yes!
Hi.
Thanks, again,
so much for coming.
Adam's here.
You came.
Looks wonderful.
You're gonna have
to move over
because I have to serve
this wonderful couple myself.
This is fabulous. Only Claire
could have thought of this.
I don't suppose you have
anything single-malt back there?
Frank, it's worth every penny
to see you on keg duty.
Well then, don't you think that this
is worth just a few extra pennies?
Let's break out
the checkbook, Charles.
Did you RSVP?
I assumed
it didn't matter.
It doesn't.
I'm glad you're here.
When I heard
your message...
You know, I shouldn't
have left that, Adam.
Why not?
Maybe we should
talk at some point.
Make that check with a
lot of zeros, won't you?
Here we are.
Cheers.
Now I'm going to ask a huge
favor of you since you're here.
You want to
put me to work.
Yes, please.
My pleasure.
Come.
So these are some wonderful photographs
by an amazing photographer...
Gillian...
Adam Galloway.
Nice to meet you.
I've heard lots about you.
And to you.
And this is the photographer himself.
Hello, how are you?
Freddy.
I just wanted to thank you so much.
Such a success tonight.
My pleasure, my pleasure.
He's the best.
I see Adam's here.
I didn't know
he was coming.
Well, guess what I got. Another
check from the Holburns.
For $60,000.
Come on, praise me
like you should.
If Frank Underwood and the
United States Congress...
Hi, my name is Zoe Barnes.
I'm with Slugline.
...think that they can dismantle the
rights of the American teacher,
well, then they are going to hear
our voices wherever they are.
Hi, why protest here?
Congress has to
take this seriously.
We're here for the teachers.
We're here...
Thank you.
We're not asking
for the world.
And Congress needs to step
up and get this done.
Excuse me,
just a moment.
Well, that dress
looks familiar.
It's the one I wore
to the symphony.
Yes, the mutual
admiration society.
That's right.
So. What do you
have for me?
What do you mean?
Well, you're surrounded
by Washington's elite.
Are you saying
you've overheard nothing
that could be useful
to either of us?
I'm covering
the protest.
The rest of the world
is covering the protest.
You may not have noticed,
but you're the only
journalist inside the party.
I've been
feeding you plenty,
information is a two-way
street, Ms. Barnes.
Hello...
Claire, this is Zoe Barnes, you
met her one night at the house...
Yes, I remember. You work
for The Herald, right?
Not anymore. I actually
work at Slugline now.
I've heard of it. You read
it, don't you, Francis?
Religiously.
Well, you seem like a very ambitious
young woman. I like that.
Doing my best.
It's good
to see you, again.
Please,
enjoy yourself.
I will. Thank you.
Take care,
Ms. Barnes.
And she
looks gorgeous,
but really she's thinking,
"When can I go the fuck home?"
I'm off.
Already?
I've done my duty,
I believe.
You know me. I always have to
be the first to leave a party.
How much did you raise?
$750,000.
Eighty of that was your photographs.
Fantastic.
Write a check for 250,
we'll break a million.
Nice try.
Thank you for coming.
And everything that you did.
Call me sometime.
I will.
Teachers should
be getting more!
So what does
a Clean Water gala
have to do with
teachers unions?
Well, we have over 50 members of
Congress gathered in one place.
But the fact that
these members of Congress
are promoting pouring money
out of the country
while neglecting their teachers
at home is precisely the problem.
But this is private money,
not public tax dollars, so...
But we're not
protesting the cause,
we're protesting the Congressmen
and women themselves...
Are these even
teachers picketing?
Sure, some of them. And
some of them are people...
Excuse me...
Frank... What you... Don't take the food.
We'll feed you later.
Don't take this food. Marty,
you know that old saying,
"The most dangerous
spot in the world is
"to come between
a Teamster and free food."
Don't take the food,
we're feeding you later.
I'll take it.
She'll take it.
Who else is hungry?
There you go.
Pass it back.
Plenty more coming, guys.
I know you've all been
out here for hours.
Thank you, Freddy!
The best ribs in D.C.
Marty, come on. You've said your
piece, you got on the news.
Come and enjoy yourself.
I respect you, Claire,
you know I can't do that.
Doesn't matter what side you're
on, everybody's gotta eat.
You can have a plate of ribs.
Yes, you can.
Come on. Yes, you can. I can't.
Thank you, Claire, but I cannot.
You can do it.
Come on, Marty!
Come on.
I can't. Thank you.
Thank you.
Freddy's.
You should go to Freddy's.
Several dozen
union sympathizers,
led by labor lobbyist,
Martin Spinella,
attempted to disrupt the gala.
They need to step
up to the plate
and take care of our
teachers and our children.
The protest dissipated
when fundraiser attendees
offer food and drink
to picketers.
Doesn't matter what side you're
on, everybody's gotta eat.
Turn it off.
It's unclear
whether protest will continue.
What now?
Call the union leadership
and the chapter presidents.
See if they're ready
to the pull the trigger.
If they are, we strike
at midnight tomorrow.
You were
extraordinary.
Tomorrow, people
who weren't there
are gonna lie
and say they were.
What are you reading?
She can write.
She can.
And you can
raise money.
Always,
for a good cause.
Thank you.
Wait in the car, please.
Hold on.
I know who that is.
Hello, Peter.
I am starving.
I forgot to eat.
Would you like something,
Peter?
No, thanks.
You should eat.
Don't fight.
She'll win.
I will.
Okay, yes.
You want
some coffee?
Yes, thanks.
Do you have
any children?
Two. A son and a daughter.
Married?
Divorced.
What are their names,
your kids?
There's Sarah. She's 11,
and Kevin is eight.
Do you have any pictures?
Fuck!
I lost my phone...
Sorry, I should...
I gotta go...
Peter, sit down.
You're gonna
enjoy your sandwich,
have some coffee
and stay the night.
Milk and sugar?
Black.
Some fresh towels.
There should be
soap and toothpaste,
everything you
need in the bathroom.
Thank you so
much for doing this.
It's nothing.
Sleep well.
What's going on, Peter?
Talk to me.
You think fresh towels
changes anything?
Changes what?
The shipyard.
If I was home and you pulled that
shit, I'd beat the fuck out of you.
I would crack your skull
on the pavement.
That's why I came
over here today.
To fuck you up for
what you made me do.
I don't care how nice
you're being to me.
I don't give a shit.
I'm gonna
wake up tomorrow,
and all these people,
all my friends,
are still fucked.
And I'm still fucked.
You fucked all of us.
But I'm gonna
get blamed for it.
So, now I have to carry that
weight on my shoulders.
You fucked me, Frank.
I shouldn't have let you
do it, but I did...
Are you done now?
Get up.
No.
I said get up.
And follow me.
Now.
Get in.
Take off your clothes
and get in.
Do it. Now.
There was a DNC meeting earlier this week.
About the Governor's race.
Your name came up as someone
we might want to run.
Aspirin. Go ahead.
Everyone in that room wanted
to cross you off the list.
I said no.
I stuck up for you.
I said, "Peter Russo,
he's got potential.
"He's young, he's capable,
he's going places."
I made them keep you
in contention.
You're still
on that list.
You show up at my house in the middle
of the night, drunk, to whine?
To try to shift
the blame on me?
Instead of taking responsibility
for yourself and your own actions?
Maybe they were right
in that meeting.
Maybe you are worthless.
I'm the only person who
believes in you, Peter,
but maybe
that's one too many.
The hot water will
open up your capillaries.
The aspirin you just took
will make your blood thinner.
It's up to you, Peter...
And if you do decide to
take the coward's way out,
cut along the tracks, not across them.
That's a rookie mistake.
Morning.
You need a lift
to the Hill?
I should go home
and change my clothes.
No, no,
we'll drop you.
You want some coffee?
Frank?
One month.
Hmm?
One month sober.
I can give you that.
Not for me. For you.
Has the seed
been planted?
Only Peter can
answer that question.
He has a choice.
Will he wither?
Or will he thrive?
Only time will tell.