Three weeks to let me visit?
Be careful. These motherless fucks
listen to everything.
A nephew's visiting his uncle,
who loves him.
I got nothing to say.
So many tragedies to those
close to you, huh?
Don't be so smart. Things could
have gone the other way, nephew.
Yeah, but they didn't.
What's this shit I'm hearing
about your heart?
This problem you and me had...
...your mother had nothing
to do with it.
- She's dead to me.
- She's a sick woman.
Who are you kidding?
It kills you that people are talking.
That an old woman
made an ass out of you.
Not half so bad as certain rumors
floating around about you.
How Tony Soprano fluffs his mother's
pillow so she can get her sleep.
- Who said that?
- Want to make this nonsense disappear?
Make peace with her. No bad blood.
It'll be good for all of us.
No fucking way.
Tell Bacala to come out of his hole.
I want to see him tomorrow.
What for?
Black men industrialized the North,
but we still fight for jobs.
That's right!
Over 25 joint-fitters on this site,
not a black man to be found.
- Tell it, reverend! Why?
- I'll tell you why.
Black joint-fitters have been
shut out of the unions.
Yeah! That's right!
Out of work while their
white joint-fitter...
...fills his stomach.
My father put his life on the line
for this country.
Come on up here, Papa.
Somebody help my papa on up here.
This is my papa!
Fought in World War II,
against tyranny.
Came home to establish
his own tabernacle.
But when he came home... I said,
when he came home...
...he had to fight a different
kind of war all over again!
Talk to them, Papa! Talk
to the people, Papa!
Since then, we have spilled
our blood in Korea...
...Vietnam and Iraq.
Every time, I say, "Sweet Jesus,
let them do right when they get back."
But somebody forgot to tell the Man.
- You know what I mean!
- Tell him, reverend!
Oh, yes, I'm gonna tell him!
I'm gonna tell him, no more cutting
us out of the dream!
No more!
- No more!
No More!
You hear that, Mr. Massarone
Brothers Construction?
No more!
- Somebody tell me what we want!
- Jobs!
- When do we want it?
- Now!
- What do we want?
- Jobs!
Hey, Med!
I'm gonna visit "She who
can't be named." Want to come?
Grandma? You mean like now?
I'd really like to, but I gotta study
my French. Stupid verbs.
No biggie.
Hey! I want to talk to you.
What were you doing with that sign?
- I wanted to talk to you about that.
- I'm selling Ma's house, understand?
Now put the sign back in the ground!
End of discussion! Period!
You're so left-brained.
The house is still for sale.
The agent still has a listing.
What was the sign doing in your car?
- Don't try to deny it!
- I'm trying to save a little money.
Do you remember Cathy Fiola?
She was in my class,
with the birthmark.
- What about her?
- She's in real estate and charges...
...three percent commission.
That's half, Tony.
Thousands of dollars.
Maybe Ma could use it.
Yeah? Fuck her!
Next time you disappear,
park that piece of shit on the street!
This isn't a hotel!
We're out of cran-apple.
Is plain apple okay?
Oh, sure, doll. Oh, honey?
Could you get me some
strawberry ice cream?
They can't expect me to eat
this tapioca.
I'll see what I can do.
She cracks me up.
Well, I can't believe it.
It's my daughter from California!
- Seattle, Ma.
- Would you like some of my tapioca?
- Good morning.
- Oh, you reek of cigarettes. Ugh!
Look at you, all dressed, out of bed.
Yeah, but you see my hand?
It's all black and blue...
...where they stuck in the needle.
It's how you get better.
You don't care.
You weren't here five minutes.
I went to the city for a few days.
I'm pitching my self-help video.
"Lady Kerouac," or, "Packing for
the Highway to a Woman's Self-Esteem."
You could never stand it here.
You could never stand yourself.
- And that's why you ran away.
- Let's not go there today, Ma.
You think it was easy for me?
- You don't know how your father was!
- What do you mean?
Nobody knows!
Nobody knows what I went through.
What about Daddy?
One thing I could tell you.
It would kill him to see me now.
Here's your ice cream.
Then we can take our walk.
Leave me alone, please.
Open the window and just
push me out.
- I can't take this anymore.
- Mrs. Soprano, what's wrong?
- What happened?
- She just started crying.
You! I know why you're here!
You don't fool me for a second!
- You want to take my house!
- Ma!
You don't know
what goes through my mind.
- Well, that's for fucking sure!
- Someday, I hope you have children...
...and they treat you like this.
- I gave my life to my children.
- This is bullshit.
Talk to me.
These activists, they're killing me.
They're picketing my place 24-7.
Three days I'm down.
- Who?
- A hard-on, Reverend Herman James, Jr.
"Not enough minorities
doing the joint-fitting."
- That's under my uncle's jurisdiction.
- I know.
But you could talk to him,
maybe send some guys down...
...and make it uncomfortable
for these people.
- Like you did, with your unions.
- It's gonna cost you.
You're already raping me
with those no-show jobs.
You're not such a citizen
when you want a bid to go your way.
Take it easy.
I'll see what I can do.
In the meantime, call animal control.
Watch you don't get followed
meeting me.
You're late.
Bobby Baccalieri,
the last man standing.
- I'm not saying nothing.
- Don't want to get in trouble.
A lot of funerals in your corner
of the world, huh?
Fucking our boost, what, you refinance
your house?
Look at me, not the floor.
Talk to that bald cocksucker
who calls himself my father's brother.
Tell him I'm gonna let him keep on
earning. Subsistence level.
He'll be able to pay his lawyers.
Let me say for him, thank you.
You're gonna hear some high-end shit.
And A: I hope you understand it...
...and B: I hope you keep it
between this room and Junior.
If you don't, they're gonna find
pieces of you in different dumpsters.
I inherited Junior.
You got no reason to talk to me
this way. I always liked you.
Bullshit.
But we'll assume you do now.
Tell my uncle he gets to keep 5%.
5% of his shy...
...the sports betting.
Same with the coke.
The Joint-Fitters Union,
it's all his, okay?
Listen. This is very important.
He also gets to keep his stripes.
As far as the feds are concerned,
they've got the boss in jail.
Hearing different creates confusion.
Got it.
As far as the rest of everything
that Junior owned...
...it's now mine.
I'll get this to him, Tony.
That's it.
"To the victor belongs the spoils."
Get out of here before I shove
your quotations book up your fat ass!
Mr. Bompensiero, is your wife
here to drive you home?
Skip.
Skip?
- How we feeling?
- Fucking great.
He's gonna be out of it
for an hour or so.
It went great. You'll feel the
difference in your back in a few days.
Buzz me when he feels ready to leave.
Yeah, we'll buzz you, honey.
Buzz. Buzz. Buzz...
My back don't feel one iota different.
It'll take a couple of days
for the steroids to kick in.
I gotta get in my Jacuzzi.
Too much stress in your life, Sal.
- Tony doesn't know you're back yet?
- Jesus Christ, no.
I didn't go see him yet.
- You're all alike.
- We've seen guys drag their dicks.
Take advantage of the government's
generosity, playing both ends.
Will you give me a window over here?
He's already suspicious.
I gotta be careful.
Altieri ate the pill for you.
Any suspicions went to the grave
with Jimmy Altieri.
- I've known Tony 30 years, now this?
- Spare me, okay?
You been on our tit since '98.
Chauffeur to and from the doctor
that we found for you.
We let you back on the street.
We want results.
He tried to suffocate his own mother.
His own uncle wanted him whacked.
You said he's been shitting on you
for years.
- I know what I said.
- Plus he's been crying to a shrink.
You don't owe him dick.
Don't take a bullet for a yuppie
who thinks you're his errand boy.
Your Honor, this man should not be
released for medical reasons.
Every time we get an elder
Mafioso incarcerated...
...we get the same bag of tricks.
Your Honor.
I take offense at the characterization
of my client as a Mafioso.
Mr. Soprano has not been found
guilty of anything.
- He's awaiting trial for allegations.
- Noted.
With all due respect to the state's
medical facilities...
...in his condition,
Mr. Soprano has every right...
...to seek the best medical care
he can afford.
Mr. Soprano has a benign illness.
A few clogged arteries, Your Honor.
I'm leaning towards releasing
this man from lockup.
Unless you can demonstrate
a serious flight risk.
Mr. Soprano.
If I approve this, you will
be under house arrest.
You understand this concept?
Not really.
It means that you must remain
in your residence. You cannot leave.
Except for doctor's appointments,
food shopping.
Your Honor, the government asks
for an electronic bracelet.
Your Honor, while we certainly agree
to house arrest...
...we are asking that Mr. Soprano...
...not be further persecuted
for yet-to-be-proven allegations.
He shows no prior arrest since 1968.
He pays his taxes and he's a veteran
of the Second World War.
Mr. Soprano, do you have any problem
with wearing an electronic bracelet?
It sounds like Nazi Germany to me.
Obviously you need
a history lesson, sir.
I don't think that we, you and I...
...should let our shared sorrow
or biases...
...enter into this, judge.
He's wearing a bracelet...
...to avoid any risk of flight.
- Who are you?
- Jesus, you scared the shit out of me.
Jesus ain't got nothing
to do with it.
What do you want?
I'm looking for your son.
Is he around?
- You a friend?
- Is he around?
He'll be back here soon.
Well, come on in.
You were a good-looking guy
back then.
Still am. Still got the same teeth
as in that picture.
Oh, yeah?
Go ahead and laugh. That picture
was taken 57 years ago.
So that makes you...
- Old.
- Come on. How old are you?
- 75.
- Add eight more and you got it.
83.
Get the fuck out of here!
- What do you want with my son?
- Gotta discuss a little business.
If you say so.
So you're 28 years old
when World War II starts.
That's a little long in the tooth.
In '43 they was taking everyone,
no matter how old or ugly.
They even took a fat boy I knew.
He was already 34.
Wasn't no good to nobody,
except he could cook.
I swear he was more dangerous
with that...
...stove than he was with that rifle.
You ever watch the History Channel?
- Television?
- No, the History Channel.
I think you'd like it.
They even do a lot of that Bible shit.
Only shit in the Bible came out
of Pharaoh's ass...
...when Moses parted the Red Sea.
Parted the Red Sea, praise his name.
Never underestimate a man's
determination to be free.
I'll come back at another time.
Break it, you pay for it.
If I'd known you were getting out, I
wouldn't have talked to that calzone.
He gave me the message.
Well, don't fucking pout.
Be grateful I'm letting you earn.
What's on your mind?
How'd you swing this?
- Dr. Schreck, he's Monty's kid.
- The bookie's son is a cardiologist?
- It's not bad.
- Feds can't bug your doctor's office.
Lets me use this place sometimes.
To conduct business.
You hear about Massarone Construction?
Bacala is taking care of it.
They know he speaks for me.
- It's gotta go 60-40, my way.
- Did you do what I asked?
- What did you ask me to do?
- You know, make peace.
Listen, that's enough with that shit.
That woman is dead to me.
You let it go!
Why? She's my brother's wife.
She doesn't realize half the time.
Let's put our cards on the table.
I heard the tapes the feds made
at Green Grove.
So she's crazy half the time.
Which half did you listen to?
The half that makes no sense, or
the half that played you like a child?
Nobody played me. She didn't know
she was setting you up to get popped.
That's right! Your uncle
isn't as dumb as you think!
You and that miserable fuck, Altieri.
All of my capos
meeting behind my back!
Now you let sleeping dogs lie, okay?
I have my reasons.
I'll tell you one dog you left
barking, that fucking Freddie Capuano.
That motherless, money grubbing
little son of a bitch that runs a...
The guy who owns Green Grove?
He's like an old lady, going around...
...telling Soprano business
to anybody who'll listen!
He's the one saying you tried
to whack your mother.
Even implied that me and her...
That hairpiece motherfucker!
Did everybody take a vow of silence?
Got anything to report?
I gotta write a report
on DNA for biology.
Isn't that interesting?
I just saw, on Inside Edition...
...how there will be no more
unknown soldiers because of DNA.
- They can identify all casualties.
- Pass me some more of that macaroni.
Tony, I know you don't like
to talk about her but...
...that woman is impossible.
She's a complete narcissist.
I mean, "me, me, me."
Really, kudos. You are a saint.
You're right, I don't want
to talk about it.
You talking about Grandma?
She pushes those buttons.
She's a big baby, you know?
Excusez-Moi.
Tony.
This is my house.
How many times I gotta say it?
Thank you, II Duce.
Got something to say,
"the little girl who might...
...want to use one of those cars
in the next 100 years"?
It's my fault, Med.
I was insensitive to his feelings.
Thank you.
You see that?
See how easy that was?
So, Mr. Delegated Power of Attorney...
...have you given it any thought?
Can my girlfriend have the listing?
To the house?
As long as it gets sold...
...I don't give a fuck who lists it.
- What did one prick say to the other?
- You see that?
You see what happens with you
cursing at the dinner table?
Thanks. It's hard to find people
over 25 to drive with.
Don't tell them you drove me
to buy pot. Which should be legal.
Only thing that works for my hands.
Med, wasn't that a stop sign?
I hate the way he talks to you.
It's so obnoxious.
He's insecure. He's afraid
to leave New Jersey...
...and threatened by freedom.
It's too pathetic.
How about Grandma in that center?
I'm dying to go see her, but
I've had so much homework...
...plus community service I have
to do to get into a good college.
I bring food to homeless shelters.
You know Grandma pretty well?
I guess.
What is she into?
- I don't know. Negativity?
- But seriously.
There must be something.
Isn't there anything she likes doing?
My dad used to find her these
old records, these sisters.
Oh, the De Castro Sisters, right.
The Andrew Sisters would've
been too easy.
- He'd take her that Mario Lasagna guy.
- I hated that shit.
Your glasses will be ready
on Thursday.
Oh, Thursday, that's good.
Did you see me on TV?
- You were on TV? What show?
- The evening news.
Oh, yeah, that. What about it?
Well, how'd I look? Be honest.
You looked, you know, like you.
You looked good.
I didn't like the way I looked.
Maybe I should get new frames,
what do you think?
What's wrong with them?
- How much did those frames cost?
- Insurance pays.
- I never see the bill.
- Nice country.
- I got cataracts.
- My father told me, "Never get old."
I should've listened.
Yeah.
A Chinaman goes to see the eye doctor.
Doctor says, "I see the problem."
Chinaman says, "What?"
Doctor says, "You have a cataract."
The Chinaman says,
"No, I have a Rincoln Continental."
You don't get it?
I get it. He drives a Lincoln.
What?
Excuse me, where's the men's room?
Left, through the doors.
You're awake.
What, what is that?
That music.
Non Ti Scordar Di Me, Pavarotti.
Did you bring it?
I remember how much you liked
a good tenor.
Remember when we saw Mario Lanza
on TV?
You and me and Daddy on the sofa...
...watching Ed Sullivan.
We never missed a Sunday.
Oh, my God.
My children!
Music has charms, Ma.
Thank God, huh?
I think it's time for you to
start considering salads.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
I mean, get off my car before
you flip it over, you fat fuck.
Junior wants to know when.
Tomorrow morning.
We're short a few guys,
so make sure you're there.
Consider it exercise.
Fat fuck?
Look in the mirror sometime,
you insensitive cocksucker.
Tony, we're sitting down!
Ma, DNA, it's invisible...
...but guess how many nucleotides
per strand?
Just tell her.
- A hundred million.
- Wow, that's amazing.
She knows when we eat.
Don't be setting a plate for her
if she's not here.
Anthony, Jr., want to do the honors?
Bless us our Lord,
and the gifts we are about to...
Hello! Oh.
Good. You guys started without me.
And bless us our Lord, amen.
Janice, if you're gonna be late,
call. Or you're not gonna eat.
Don't send me to bed hungry, Daddy.
Everybody, guess who passed
her driving test?
- She learned from the best!
- Hey, go, girl!
- Congratulations.
- I was nervous, parallel-parking...
...the guy had a clipboard and stuff.
Oh, wow, fascist martinet.
Salsice, Janice?
Oh, I forgot, you don't eat pork...
...in that way.
Oh, I get it.
There's nothing to get.
She's a vegetarian.
I miss the fireflies out West.
That's why I moved out here.
A little bit of nature.
Ever drive by Jimi Hendrix's house
in Seattle?
You know, Tony, I know it's not
your favorite subject, but...
...we had some really great news
about Ma today.
Her therapist says
she's making great strides...
...and soon they'll release her.
How can she make strides...
...when nothing's wrong with her?
It's called FaceSaving Therapy.
The patient believes
they're in therapy.
Medicare's not gonna pay for it
if it's not real, would they?
And the taxpayer foots the bill.
It's not much longer now.
But she's gonna need a place to stay.
She's out on the street.
- Tony, it is her house.
- Dead people don't have houses.
Daddy bought that house.
Tell you what...
...take her back to Green Grove.
What? The nursing home?
- "Retirement community."
- I don't have that kind of money!
Fuck you.
- What do we want?
- Jobs!
- When do we want them?
- Now!
Should've seen that blimp's face
when I told him he had to be here.
Bacala's always been lazy.
You can't get nobody good anymore.
They're either on drugs
and compromised...
...or young and don't listen.
Please.
It's all "me, me, me."
I hope you don't feel that way
about me. It's just this back.
You've done plenty.
You paid your dues.
- Tony Soprano.
- Yeah.
- What the fuck?
- Hey, Tony!
This is what I mean.
Am I supposed to be seen here?
Idiots!
- Shit!
- Now we look like jerk-offs.
- What do we want?
- Jobs!
- When do we want them?
- Now!
- What do we want?
- Jobs!
- When do we want them?
- Now!
Get out of the way!
- When do we want them?
- Now!
We want to talk to the foreman.
- Talk to the foreskin?
- You a wise-ass motherfucker.
Keep your mother off the streets
and I won't fuck her.
Come on! Come on!
Do not bow down, brothers and sisters!
Motherfucker, come on!
Do not bow down!
Hi, Ma!
Oh, Nicholas Antonelli.
"Dead at age 73,"
of heart failure.
MMM...
Ma, you're gonna be getting
out of here soon.
Want to go home?
Home?
Back to the house.
My house?
Uh-huh.
No, I don't think so.
I'll go back to the other place.
The nursing home? No, that's for
people who don't have anybody.
It's not that bad. And they give
you fresh towels every day.
Barbara said you hated it.
- But it's too much trouble.
- No, Ma, you can't go back there.
- Why not?
- Because.
Because it's dangerous there.
What are you talking about?
The owner...
...is missing.
Mr. Capuano.
They suspect foul play. Yeah.
Ma? Ma, you okay?
Nurse! It's my mother.
What is it?
What's the matter?
Are you okay, Mrs. Soprano?
Take a deep breath.
Breathe.
- Why do they make cookies that way?
- You scared me, Ma.
Would you just stop it?
Stop it.
Just give me a minute!
Go, go, stop hovering!
This may be a good time to talk
about this.
There's no emergency provision
on file.
I tried to talk about a DNR,
and she got very agitated.
- DNR?
- Do Not Resuscitate.
It's to save the family anguish
and decisions at a difficult time...
...when there is no quality of life.
Janice!
Where are my glasses?
I can't find the tissues!
Janice?
I'm sorry, Tony, but the hospital
needs a decision on this.
- Auxiliary B, what the fuck?
- If you have power of attorney...
...you have to act like one.
Who gives a fuck, DNR, no DNR?
Okay, great.
What if she's in a coma and has to
live on tubes and machines...
...because you won't sign a DNR?
What? When she's a vegetable
she's not gonna care!
To deprive your mother
of a place to live.
To deprive me of my chance
to make peace with my mother.
You know what? Take her.
You can have her.
The two of you in that house deserve
each other. It's worth watching.
It'll be like
"Whatever Happened to Baby Janice?"
I'll give you your DNR!
Mom, I can't find the keys.
Keys to what? To the car?
You got a license to drive, not
carouse around on a school night.
I was going to take Anthony
to visit Grandma.
You said we could visit.
You can drive if you want.
Now you want to visit Grandma?
Can we, Mom?
No funny business.
You go to the hospital and back.
The level of trust in this family!
Check the mileage if you want. God!
Go ahead, I'll be back later.
- Where are you going?
- Hunter's upstairs.
That's not fair.
- I'm just gonna say hello.
- I'm telling.
And I was gonna let you drive
in the IBM parking lot this Sunday.
Look who's here!
Anthony, come over here!
Give your Grandma a kiss.
Oh...
Ah...
I thought you were Janice.
She comes over every day
to play pinochle with me.
Daughters take better care
of their mothers, that's why.
She's home, I think.
You didn't ride over here on your
bicycle in the dark?
No, Meadow drove me.
Meadow? Well, where is she?
- I don't know.
- She's another one.
They don't care about you, Johnny.
No, they stick you away
and forget you ever existed.
I guess.
Oh, have a torrone.
- I don't like those Italian candies.
- Oh, go ahead. Take one.
He's not even washing his hands.
You know, Louisiana food
isn't really spicy, it's well-seasoned.
Don't they season everything?
Absolutely. So, what we're gonna do
is, I got a little cayenne pepper.
Grandma, what's DNR?
- Who?
- DNR, it's initials. Like...
...I did a report on DNA...
...but Dad and Aunt Parvati
was talking about your DNR.
So is that, like, similar?
Aunt? You mean Janice? Janice?
- They were talking about me?
- About your DNR.
Cause that's what's confusing.
Like, DNA, everybody's got that.
She thinks I should have a DNR?
Or that Dad should give it to you.
Because, what if you went into a coma?
But DNA doesn't prevent comas,
does it?
I don't know.
I gotta do this report by Monday.
Very good, Livia. That's perfect.
I know my alphabet.
Guess what, Ma?
I got great news.
Tony's not gonna sell the house.
When you're released,
we're gonna take you back home.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna live with you.
Why?
So you can "not resuscitate" me?
So I can what?
I've seen that movie
with Richard Widmark.
- Movie, Ma?
- Oh, Mrs. Soprano.
No, take this one.
She gets her ballet shoes...
...she sells them and takes
the money to Newark...
...and she buys amphetamines.
She was a child then.
I think you should live
with your daughter, Mrs. Soprano.
I think I'm gonna leave
all my money to you, honey.
What are you talking about, money?
I've gotta catch up on some charts.
Janice...
...what did I tell you last week?
Where did I put my money?
You know this is very important.
I must have put it somewhere.
Come on, Settimia.
You don't fool me.
I know what you're thinking about.
My name's Janice.
Janice, Ma. You named me.
It's something else
you threw away of mine.
Are you sure...
...I didn't say where
I put that money?
Let's not worry about that.
Let's just get you better...
...so you can go home
and I can take good care of you.
And if it's there...
...we'll find it.
Your sister's cunt!
- That was wonderful, reverend.
- You call us if you need anything.
Thank you.
Good night.
What's all this?
My father has passed away.
I was just talking to him.
He lived well.
God blessed him with longevity.
What are you gonna do?
We all will have our time.
My father didn't know about
our business arrangement.
- He wouldn't have approved.
- I got that feeling.
- And your parents?
- Pop's been gone for years.
Mom?
She's still around.
She's too miserable to die.
That generation's almost all gone.
When the last one goes, we become
the old folks at the family functions.
What are you saying?
We're still kids.
Don't you believe it, Tony.
When the last one dies, it signals
the start of the last stretch for us.
Don't get me wrong, I'm not looking
to go anytime soon, it's just...
Just feels funny now, being...
...an elder.
Your end of the demonstration bust-up.
Your guys went a little too far.
Rasheen almost lost an eye.
Yeah? How'd you do overall?
Massarone gave me five no-shows.
- Two and a half each.
- Three-two.
It should be 3-2, my way.
I gotta kick upstairs to Uncle Junior.
- Two and a half each.
- All your guys are in on this shit.
People find out I'm making money
on their blood, it's my ass.
- Hell, no. Three-two.
- I'll think about it.
What about the asbestos
removal project at the school?
Just waiting to see who gets the bid.
All right.
Hey, rev.
Sorry about your old man.
Hello?
He did? Where is he now?
- Oh, you're home!
- How dare you call here.
I called now on purpose.
I know Johnny's at work.
"Anthony," your son, Anthony.
He harbors resentment...
...against me, and to this day
I don't know what I did.
I'm hanging up.
I just want you to know...
...what pennies I have
I leave to the children.
Your children and Barbara's children.
I raised three children of my own.
I did a pretty good...
pretty good job on two.
- They are all unhappy.
- Sure, you listen to that Janice.
Be very careful.
She's a real snake in the grass.
She has no work ethic.
Why is that?
If anything happens to me...
Hello? Hello?
Oh.
Where is he?
Did you call an ambulance?
- I don't need no fucking ambulance.
- See?
Yeah, sure. Look at you.
- We're going to the emergency room.
- Fuck that. I'm all right.
Why not go down there and make sure?
Uncle Jun?
Hey, you still here?
No fucking ambulance.
I'll drive you. Bacala will come.
- Yeah, sure.
- We'll all go.
Help me up.
Can you walk?
- I think he broke his hip.
- Aw, fuck you!
Hold on a minute.
I'll be okay.
Give me a minute to catch my breath.
All right.
What are you doing?
What do you want, a piggyback?
Get the door.
Anthony!
Don't let me go to my grave
with this guilt.
Listen, you old prick.
You're not going anywhere.
Make things right with your mother.
Please.