50 years have passed.
But I do not age.
Time has lost its effect on me.
Yet the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Got to get back ...
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
5x04 - "XCV"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Aaagh!
- Murderer!
- Killer!
Killer!
Murderer! Killer! Murderer!
Murderer! Murderer!
Killer!
- Murderer! Murderer!
- No.
- Killer! Killer!
- Murderer!
No.
Murderer!
No!
They chose the path!
They chose!
Die! Die!
Why won't you die?!
Scum!
Aku will be triumphant!
I will undo the evil
that is you, samurai!
I will kill you!
As long as I have
breath in my body,
I will strike you down!
Long live the glory of Aku!
You are very troubled.
And very confused.
Aku is the evil one, not me.
I've met machines
that are programmed
with such hate and lies,
but never a human.
Deceiver!
Worm! Scum!
Now you're
just repeating yourself.
I wonder if it is possible
for her to ever believe
- that Aku is the evil and not me?
- Lecherous snake!
Mm, perhaps not.
Are you kidding me?
Whew.
My Lord and master, Aku,
may it please you for all eternity ...
the samurai is dead.
Um...
I'm right here.
Fool! We've been swallowed
by a monolithic creature.
You're dead.
I've been inside giant creatures
before. I'll find a way out.
Stop. Enough!
No! I will never stop!
Yes, yes, I know ...
till your dying breath.
But once you see
how misguided you are,
you will see the truth about Aku.
Be still!
Crazy woman!
Can you not see
that I am saving your life?
Aaaaaagh!
Uh, hello?
Ashi?
Kill the samurai!
Jack?
What are we doing, Jack?
Waiting.
Waiting for what?
You know the way out.
Let's just go.
No.
She's another innocent.
"Innocent"?
Are you mad?
She's pure evil.
She's lost her way.
You'd know
about that, wouldn't you?
I don't want to talk
to you anymore.
Well, then, maybe you'll talk to me.
Leave me alone.
I don't want to talk to you, either.
I don't know why
you keep bringing this up.
Look, why do you
always have to get involved?
She chose her way,
and now she has to live
with the consequences.
You'll never understand
that it's all my fault!
She's here because of me.
- She's gone.
- What?
Okay, well, that's that.
Lets get out of here.
No.
Ugh, you're going to save
her life again, aren't you?
Yes.
You're welcome.
I'd be happier
as that creature's excrement
than be grateful to you.
What did you expect,
a hug and a kiss?
By Aku's will, you will die in here.
There is no hope for you,
foolish samurai.
Aku is the master of masters
and will end you!
No matter
what you have planned for me,
I will never buckle,
never waiver.
Your death is certain!
Aku desires it!
Aku has made
a world of wonders,
and you have soiled it!
Aku is the father of all fathers!
His greatness cannot be measured!
You are a parasite, samurai,
feeding off Aku's generosity!
Aku, my master,
this fool knows not
of your greatness,
your kindness,
- your understanding!
- Enough!
Every thing,
every word,
every thought
that you know... is wrong!
Aku ... Aku is the one
that has laid waste
to the beauty of this world!
He has destroyed
mother nature!
Where do you think we are?!
Aku has unleashed
these monstrosities
upon our world, and they
feed off his carnage.
- Liar!
- Believe what you may.
But if you open your eyes
and let go of the hate,
you will see the truth.
Die.
Rain?
Well, um...
I guess we should
get this over with.
You know, uh, many
people pay money for this.
It's called acupuncture.
Never mind.
Whew.
- I like the back fur.
- You look hideous.
From you, "hideous" is
quite acceptable. Thank you.
We're close.
Even in the bowels
of the darkest of creatures,
there is beautiful light.
Seems simple enough ...
use the flying creatures to escape
and not fall into the
pool of acid. Right.
Whew.
We're slowing down.
No, please, faster.
Faster!
Wait!
Ashi.
These frivolous distractions
are poisons for your mission.
They are not part of Aku's order.
Not part of Aku's order...
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Got to get back ♪
♪ Back to the past, Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~