50 years have passed.
But I do not age.
Time has lost its effect on me.
Yet the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Got to get back ...
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
5x08 - "XCIX"
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
- Incredible.
- We should eat.
This is going to be
a long journey.
- This looks good.
- Have you had it before?
Yes, of course.
Many, many times.
Or something very similar.
Yah, yah, all very good.
Very good for you.
See?
It is even good for you.
This one especially.
Mmm, mmm.
Mmm. Delicious.
- Please, have some.
- No! Thank you, heh.
I'll just try something over here.
Woman ...
who understands them, yah?
Yes... I guess.
I don't feel so good.
- Maybe it was something I ate?
- Yeah, that might be it.
Ah, that's better.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
- It's a little, uh... crowded.
- Yes.
Oh!
Something's poking me.
Oh! I'm so sorry.
- Sorry, I ...
- No, I ...
♪ Ba, da-da-da ♪
♪ Ba, da-da ♪
♪ Ba, da-da, ba-da ♪
That was quite humorous,
the way we were trying
to grab the pole
- but our hands kept... touching.
- Ha ha... ha.
♪ Ba-da, ba-ba-ba-ba ♪
♪ Ba, ba ♪
The temperature seems to be rising.
♪ Ba-da-da, ba-da ♪
♪ Ba, da-da ♪
♪ Ba, ba-da ♪
♪ Ba, ba ♪
♪ Ba-da, ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba ♪
♪ Ba, da-da ♪
♪ Ba-da, ba ♪
♪ Ba-da ♪
♪ Ba-da, da-da ♪
_
Ashi...
...we are not alone.
- Oh! Sorry, I ...
- No, I-I'm sorry!
- I didn't see you! Look out!
- Look out!
♪ Ba-da-da, ba-da ♪
♪ Ba, da-da-da ♪
- Should we leave, perhaps?
- Yeah, I think that's a good idea.
Hey!
We have to find some shelter!
Where?!
What is that?!
There!
- What is this place?
- I don't know.
But it is big.
Ashi, be care...
- ...ful.
- Did you say something?
No.
Never mind.
- Some kind of writing.
- Look up.
Very confined space.
- This is some kind of prison.
- Prison?
But where are its prisoners?
Are you all right?
It's spreading!
- What was that?
- I don't know, but we should leave.
The way we came in
should be up ahead.
Oh, no.
It should've been right here.
- We have to keep going!
- Jack, I'm sorry, I ...
No, please, I thought it was
this way, also.
What madness is this?
I'll choose this over
whatever is chasing us.
- We're lost!
- We have to keep moving!
- It's another prison cell.
- Yes, a very big one.
And I'm afraid its occupant
has returned.
Ashi, look out!
- We got to get out of here!
- I agree.
Scan initiated.
Non-prisoner life-forms detected.
Access granted.
Multiple prison-cell breach
detected.
Containment protocol initiated.
Quadrant III ... breach detected.
Prisoner Lazarus-92.
Extremely dangerous multiple
regenerating organism.
Emergency protocol instructions.
Neutralizing weapon model X-49.
Once Lazarus-92 has entered
the weapon vicinity,
weapon sequence
initiating directions follow.
Step one ...
Sorry.
And only after that proper
weapon initializing sequence
can Lazarus-92 be terminated.
Wait. What?!
Lazarus protocol concluded.
No, please, I ...
But how does one initiate it?
- I am ready.
- As am I...
- What is that?
- Well, it is a weapon
designed specifically
to kill the creature.
Excellent.
- Yes...
- Let's go.
It's coming.
- Get ready the weapon.
- Yes...
Now, Jack!
Jack? Jack?
Why aren't you
using the weapon?!
- I... don't know how to use it!
- What?!
There's an initiating sequence,
and I do not know it!
- Maybe I can try?
- Um, okay...
Ashi, catch!
- What's wrong?!
- I can't get it to work!
- Ashi, you're naked!
- So?
Well, I mean, you know,
men and women
are different and...
private things are personal.
You're not making any sense!
Jack!
What are you doing?
Uh, you need protection
from the creature.
And your robe
is gonna protect me?
Actually it's a gi.
And, yes!
- You're acting weird.
- Me? Weird?
- Me?! Ha ha! Ha!
- Okay...
- What are you doing?
- It is the only way. I have to try.
Cover me for as long as you can!
J-a-a-ack!
I can't hold it anymore!
Sequence initiated.
Jack!
Ashi!
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
♪ Everybody loves somebody sometime ♪
♪ Everybody falls in love somehow ♪
♪ Something in your kiss
just told me ♪
♪ My sometime is now ♪
♪ Everybody finds somebody
someplace ♪
♪ There's no tellin'
where love may appear ♪
♪ Something in my heart
keeps sayin' ♪
♪ My someplace is here ♪
♪ If I had it in my power ♪
♪ I'd arrange for every girl
to have your charms ♪
♪ Then, every minute... ♪