50 years have passed.
But I do not age.
Time has lost its effect on me.
Yet the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Got to get back ...
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
5x07 - XCVIII
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Oh!
Hello, little friend.
I don't suppose you know
if there is a time portal
atop this mountain, do you?
No?
Yes?
Aku has destroyed many.
I worry that
there are none left.
Phew!
That was close!
I didn't think
you'd get here so fast.
Fool!
Oh, fun fact ...
that was the last remaining
time portal in existence!
Ooh, so angry!
Be careful, Samurai ...
so much stress
will give you a heart attack.
Ooh!
What am I saying?
Please continue!
Never mind what I said!
Whoa!
Ho, ho!
Not so fast, Samurai.
I know better than to mess
with that sword!
But before I go, I'll leave
you someone to play with.
And so...
I was not able to find it again.
There!
We are here.
- It's not here.
- Could someone else have taken it?
No.
I realize now that...
I did not lose the sword...
but the sword left me.
- Thank you, friend.
- Yes, thank you.
I do not know
how long this may take.
- I'll go with you.
- You cannot.
It is something that
I must do on my own.
Wait, I...
Oh. I guess I'll just...
wait here?
- Are you lost?
- Yes.
Good.
Come make tea.
Hold it.
Where do you think
you're going?
Up the mountain, to kill the samurai.
What's it to you?
I'm going to stop you.
Hey, why have we stopped?
What's so funny?
It's a girl!
She says she's going to stop us.
- What did he say?
- Something about a squirrel.
I love squirrels!
Is it lunch already?
So a little thing like you
is gonna stop
this whole army, huh?
Yep.
We're gonna rip you apart
in a bunch of pieces,
and then we're gonna
take those pieces
and rip them apart
into even more pieces!
- I'm waiting.
- Hmm?
- Huh?
- Mother?
- I knew you would fail us.
You were the strongest,
but the most unfocused.
Always distracted,
questioning everything.
But all that can change.
You can still honor
our Lord Father.
Destroy the Samurai, Ashi.
No.
You were wrong about everything.
- Jack showed me the truth.
- Then you, too, will die.
How could you betray your family?
He killed your sisters!
And you let him live!
No, you killed them!
We were made for one purpose ...
to kill!
Our fate was sealed
the day we were born!
The samurai
is our mortal enemy.
He must die at any cost.
No!
This is terrible.
- Really?
- Yes. Yes, quite terrible.
This tea has all
the necessary ingredients...
but it lacks
the most important one ...
balance.
I see why your path to the sword
remains clouded.
This isn't the path?!
I-I don't understand.
- Then you must show me the way!
- I cannot.
It is not for me
to show you your path.
That's fortune cookie nonsense!
He knows where it is.
He just won't tell you.
Please, you must tell me.
That is something you must earn.
Earn?!
After everything we've done,
everything we've been through ...
the death, the loss,
the suffering!
Who are you to deny us
what is rightfully ours!?
Enough.
We have lost the sword
because of you.
I have kept us alive!
He's the one
who has taken it from us!
He knows where it is!
No.
I've let you consume me
for far too long.
You're in my way.
You.
You are the one who has
kept the past hidden.
Your anger, your frustration.
You're a fool!
You have blinded us,
but now I can see.
You need me!
Now you are balanced.
Like your father,
you have been chosen.
To stop a force of ultimate evil.
You are worthy.
Ashi.
- Jack?
- Yes. It is me.
You got your sword.
- And a shave and a haircut.
- Hmm, yes.
And you...
you have been very busy.
Ow...
Thank you.
- So, what next?
- Aku!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Got to get back,
back to the past ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~