50 years have passed,
but I do not age.
Time has lost its effect on me.
Yet the suffering continues.
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
present, and future.
Hope is lost.
Gotta get back,
back to the past.
Samurai Jack.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
Master, new arrivals
have come to offer tribute!
Oh, great Shogun of Sorrow,
Master of All Masters,
you have allowed us
to inhabit this world,
and for that, we are forever grateful.
- We offer you a special tribute.
- Stop!
Look at what you're doing!
You're getting yourselves
all over the floor.
- Uh...
- I just had it vacuumed.
Out. Out!
Get out!
Master...
Master, we've done it.
May I introduce
the most epic version
of the beetle drone yet!
- And I care because?
- B-B-Because the Samurai?
You've wanted to kill him
since forever.
He's the bane of your existence.
Oh!
That was the old Aku.
This is a new Aku.
And he really doesn't care
about a pathetic samurai
who wanders around like a mad fool.
It's hilarious, really.
Look, I tell you what ...
you want to destroy him,
go ahead.
Who cares?
I certainly don't,
not one bit at all.
So, tell me
what's been bothering you.
Well, you see, Doc,
it's been over 50 years already.
- It's been that long?
- Yes.
You see,
that's the actual problem.
Once I eradicated
all the time portals,
I thought I would just wait it
out and then the Samur...
We don't say his name here.
It is a safe place.
Yes. Sorry, Doctor.
Well, I-I just assumed
that eventually
over time he would just
- Di-i-i-i-e!
- di-i-i-i-e!
But he hasn't even aged.
I mean, like, at all.
He just grew
that stupid beard.
It looks like
he'll be here forever!
I-I just don't know
if I can handle that.
Yes. It seems that
the initial time travel
has affected the aging process.
- It's quite the conundrum.
- Yes...
What is that again?
Just a confusing
or difficult problem.
Yes. Problem.
I wish there was someone who
can dispose of my problem.
- Yes. One can hope.
Ahh!
It's time to end it,
don't you think?
Never.
They are just machines.
I'll find a way.
I always have.
When you have the sword,
but now it's gone.
There's no hope!
I've been doing fine without it.
Well, listen to you.
And what are you going to do
when Aku finds you
and realizes you have no sword?
Aku doesn't know, and he hasn't
shown himself in years.
He keeps thinking that one of
his machines can defeat me.
Maybe he's right.
You haven't faced anything
so powerful.
How much longer
can you keep this up?
It always seems bad at first,
but then I find a way.
They're just nuts and bolts,
just nuts and bolts.
Who cares anymore?!
There's no way home.
There's nothing to fight for.
There's no more honor.
Come to think of it, the only
honorable thing to do is ...
- Quiet.
- No!
I won't spend eternity
in this forsaken time!
What do you want from me?
I want it to end.
Aren't you tired?
Wouldn't it be great
to be free of all of this?
Our ancestors are waiting for us.
They want you to join them.
- There.
- You'll never make it!
They'll get you!
I'll make it.
Ahh!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Back to the past ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~