...but I realized that there was no reason
good enough...
...to keep me from spending
the rest of my life with you.
Kind of steps on the toes
of what I was going to say.
I'm sorry, David,
but she really has to know this.
All right, but after this,
I want to see you outside.
If the rain stops.
You're the most incredible woman
I've ever met.
How could I lose you?
Now, I don't actually have a ring.
- I have a ring.
- I wouldn't brag about that, big guy.
But, Phoebe...
...will you marry me?
No.
Ha-ha.
I love you, but I never needed
a proposal from you.
I just needed to know
we were headed somewhere.
- That we had a future.
- We can have any future you want.
Okay, well, I'm gonna take off.
David, I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
Just so I know,
if I had asked first?
Yeah, I might have said yes,
but that would've been wrong.
Please, you don't have to explain.
I mean, perhaps if I hadn't
gone to Minsk...
...things would have worked out for us,
and I wouldn't have ruined my career.
Or lost that toe to frostbite.
It was a good trip.
- Is it okay if I hug you now?
- Oh, yes.
Because of our meddling! All right?
Oh, isn't this nice? It's so quiet.
I could just lie here all day.
Oh, I know.
- Open your drapes! Open your drapes!
- So glad we got adjoining rooms.
- The sun is out!
- Hey! Remember when I had corneas?
Go to the pool and reserve chairs.
- I will get the magazines and the lotion.
- Ladies? Ross' speech is in 45 minutes.
- No!
- Damn it!
Walls are pretty thin, guys.
"Then we have to weigh the data from
recent MRI scans and DNA testing...
...which call into question information
gathered from years of carbon dating."
Look at the woman sitting out
by the pool getting tan.
She's all leathery and wrinkled.
I'm so jealous!
"Finally, factor in the profusion
of new species recently discovered.
Giganotosaurus.
- Argentinosaurus."
- Not to mention Coldsaurus.
"And that's just the herbivores. I'm not
even gonna discuss the carnivores.
Their heads are already too big.
Which is ironic, considering
their stunted cerebral development."
Really?
"But all kidding aside,
in much the same way...
...that Homo ergaster is thought to be a
separate species from Homo erectus..."
- What?
- He said "erectus."
- You're kidding, right?
- No, he really said it.
"And while there are certainly
vast differences...
...between these Mesozoic fossils
and the example of Homo erectus..."
Erectus?
- Homo.
- Right.
"In a very real way, we can bring
the Mesozoic Era into the 21 st century."
Thank you.
- Really great.
- Thanks, guys.
I thought it was wonderful.
Jarvis Oberblau. Cornell.
I mean, the ideas you put forth,
and from someone so young and...
Okay, now we're just holding hands.
Alrighty. We're gonna hit the beach.
That was really great.
- Oh, thank you.
- Yeah. Oh, and so funny.
- Take it easy.
- All right, thanks. Thanks so much.
I can't tell you how much it means
that you were here.
You kidding?
We wouldn't have missed it.
Oh.
I'm back.
Okay. Well, excuse me?
Hey.
- Well?
- You were incredible.
You blew them away.
I can't tell you how great it was
to look in the crowd and see your face.
I mean, did you know you were
mouthing the words along with me?
- I was not.
- No, it's okay.
It made me feel like a rock star.
Oh, my God. I'm your groupie.
Hey, I better not find you naked
in my hotel room.
Look, I took it too far.
I can't believe it's raining again.
It's so unfair.
Well, on the bright side,
now we won't have to see...
...all these paleontologists
with their shirts off.
Not you guys.
You've got it going on.
- What will we do today?
- They have a game room downstairs.
They have Ping-Pong and stuff.
Ping-Pong?
Honey, they have Ping-Pong.
- Let's play.
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
- You know how competitive you get.
And while I say it's cute,
others disagree, and I'm lying.
- I'm not always that bad.
- Oh, yeah?
What happened when we played
last time?
I punched you.
- And?
- Phoebe.
- I clunked your heads together.
- There you are.
- Hey. Listen.
As soon as it stops raining,
we have got to go snorkeling.
Some kid told me about this sea turtle.
If you blow bubbles in his face...
...he chases you.
I'm sorry, I can't. I'm running
a discussion group all afternoon.
Oh.
That's okay.
I'll find someone else to do it.
I'd do it alone, but, uh...
...I don't know what happens
if the sea turtle catches you.
You know, I feel so bad.
I haven't seen you this whole trip.
Especially last night...
Don't worry about it. It was fine.
I had the best time with Rachel.
I just felt bad for you, stuck
in that room working on Ross' speech.
Actually, it turned out to be a lot of fun.
Oh, well, at least
we're both having fun, right?
- Is it weird that it's not with each other?
- Yeah.
A little bit, yeah.
I think we need to talk.
Yeah, I think we do.
About what?
- Come on, you guys, it'll be fun!
- All right.
- I'll play if we don't keep score.
- Well, then how do we know who wins?
- Nobody wins.
- So we're just four losers. Super.
- Well, I'm not playing with her.
- I'm out.
- I'll play you.
- Okay.
- You don't know what you're doing.
- She gets crazy.
This scar? That's from Pictionary.
I think I'll be all right.
- You want to volley a bit for serve?
- Sure, if you want to.
Ho!
Oh, by the way, I'm awesome.
Oh, dear God, there's two of them.
- You ready to play?
- Hell, yeah.
- Did you know this about him?
- No idea. I thought he was soft like you.
- Want to make it more interesting?
- How much you thinking?
- Ten bucks a game?
- Make it 50.
- I'll make it 100.
- One thousand...
Okay!
We'll flip to see who goes first.
You got a quarter?
No. Either of you girls got a quarter?
Honey, try to focus the trash talk
on him.
- Monica, you call it.
- Heads. No, tails! Heads!
- Tails.
- Oh, what are the chances?
- Hah! My point!
- Oh, no, I don't think so.
Standard rules: If at any time a player
uses his nonracket-bearing hand...
...to touch the playing surface,
he or she forfeits the point.
He was a lawyer.
All the East Coast
is having beautiful weather.
In New York, it's 72 and sunny.
Oh. Weather bitch.
It's open.
- Hi, Joe.
- Hey.
- What? Is everything okay?
- Charlie and I broke up.
No. Why?
Well, she said
we have nothing in common.
That's crazy.
No, it's not.
We have nothing in common.
- Yeah, that's true.
- Yeah.
I mean, she should be with someone
more like Ross.
You know, I mean he uses
all those big words too.
- Man, smart people are dull.
- Well, hey!
Okay, Rach.
I feel so stupid, you know? Why do I
keep going after the wrong girls?
- What are you talking about?
- Oh, come on.
I mean, there's you, then there's Charlie.
It's like... What the hell's my problem?
I just...
Okay. Maybe you're not
always going after the wrong girl.
I'm telling you, Rach,
Charlie is not right for me.
- I'm not talking about her.
- Well, then, who?
The waitress I went out with last month?
- You know what? Forget it.
- No, no, no, no.
- Who are you talking about?
- No, I don't...
I actually don't know who
I'm talking about, so...
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Well, I'm gonna go see
if I can get a room for tonight.
- And I'll see you later.
- Yeah, sure. Okay.
- You like me?
- Okay.
- Let's not make a big thing about this.
- It's a huge thing!
Okay, not working with me, Joe.
Look, here's the thing.
Lately, I have been having thoughts.
Musings, if you will.
- Well, for how long?
- Oh, only like a month.
- A month?!
- Well...
Dial it down. Listen, maybe they're
crazy thoughts, but sometimes I do.
I have been thinking about,
you know, us.
- Okay, dial it up a little.
- Oh, you're right. Okay.
- I just have a question.
- Shoot.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm not trying to do anything.
It's just, we have such a good time
when we're together, you know?
And I mean, aren't you just
a little curious what it would be like?
Am I curious?
I mean, I'm as curious as...
...George!
Who?
- Curious George!
- Oh!
You know, the monkey and the guy
with the yellow hat.
- Of course. I remember.
- He had a paper route.
Yeah, he did.
- See, this is what I'm talking about.
- No, I know. We're great!
But, Rach, no, this can't happen.
Can't it just happen a little bit?
- No! It can't happen at all!
- Why not?
Because, look, no one wants
this to happen more than me, okay?
I have gone over this moment
in my head 100 times...
...and not once did I ever say no.
I couldn't do it to Ross.
- But that wasn't gonna stop you before.
- I know. I know...
...but I've thought about it a lot
since then, and it just wouldn't be right.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
- Oh, God, I shouldn't have said anything.
- No, no, no, no. Hey, we'll be fine.
- Like you said, it's no big deal.
- It's not a big deal.
- No big deal.
- It's so not a big deal.
- I'll see you later. All right, hey.
- Okay, great.
Okay... Oh!
Oh, I'm sorry, I think...
I think that may have missed the table.
- Oh, do you?
- Yeah.
- Do you?
- Yeah!
- You really find this attractive on him?
- Oh, yeah.
Are you telling me you're not even
a little turned on by Monica right now?
This is the first time in our marriage that
I've felt like the more attractive one.
All right, come on, Mike.
You can beat her.
Knock that dog off her head.
- Oh, damn it!
- I sleep with him!
- Game point.
- Don't get too cocky.
Remember, I won the last one.
Oh, by the way,
how did that feel, losing to a girl?
You should look in the mirror
before you call yourself that.
- No! No! No!
- And that's how it's done.
Okey-dokey.
You've each won a game, and I've lost
what's felt like a year of my life.
Everybody goes home a winner.
- Best of three?
- What I'm thinking.
Should I use my invisibility
to fight crime or for evil?
- Serve the ball, chump.
- "Serve the ball, chump."
Okay, better comebacks, Mike.
Better comebacks.
I'm just saying,
I have a cabin in the Adirondacks.
If you ever want to get away
from the city, well, that'd be...
...just nifty.
Well, I've kind of got a lot
on my plate right now.
Not that I wouldn't love a weekend
in the country with a strange man.
- Jarvis?
- Oh, you're back.
- This is my wife, Nancy.
- Well, get out!
Ross? Can I talk to you for a minute?
Yes, please.
So, what's going on?
Well, Joey and I broke up.
- Oh, my God. What happened?
- Joey is a great guy...
...but we're just...
We're so different.
I mean, like, during your speech,
he kept laughing at "Homo erectus."
I knew that was him!
Anyway, I just...
I think it's for the best.
- Hey. Hey, you okay?
- I guess.
There was...
There was another reason that I thought
it was time to end it with Joey.
I started to realize that I was
having feelings for someone else.
Okay, Geller.
Last day of the conference.
You know what happens
to the keynote speaker.
Professor Klarik, we're in the middle
of a conversation here.
- Can't you throw him in the pool later?
- Or we could throw you both in now.
Okay, gentlemen, please.
Aren't we a little old for this?
I mean, we're scientists, all right?
We're academics...
...and most importantly
you will have to catch us first.
Go! Go! Go!
Okay, so it's tied again,
41 to 41.
- Okay, look, enough is enough.
- No.
- I just have two more points to beat him.
- Monica, that was also true an hour ago!
I mean, please, look at you.
Your hand is blistered, you can
barely stand, your hair is inexplicable!
You've already proven
you're just as good as he is.
We missed our dinner reservation,
let's go upstairs...
...order room service, take a shower
and shave your head!
I can't just walk away.
I've put in four hours.
You knew this about me
when you married me.
You agreed to take me in sickness
and in health.
Well, this is my sickness!
- What about the obsessive cleaning?
- That's just good sense.
Ow!
- You okay?
- No, honey, I'm okay.
Shake it off. Oh, no shaking.
No shaking. No shaking.
Oh, my God. I can't play.
- So you forfeit?
- Mike wins?
I can't believe it. I lost.
- No, you didn't.
- What?
- Because I'm gonna play for you.
- You can't do that.
It's okay.
I don't care which of them I beat.
Okay, we're taking that paddle home,
mister.
- Honey, you don't have to do this.
- Yes, I do.
I may not understand why
you have to win so badly...
...but if it's important to you,
it's important to me.
Because I love you.
But you suck.
You're welcome, sweetheart.
All right, let's get this over with.
Sudden death.
- Whoever wins this point, wins.
- Okay.
- Oh, my God. You're good.
- It's like watching porn.
And that's how it's done.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
That was so amazing.
Well, when did you...?
Hold on, I almost forgot. Loser.
- When did you stop sucking?
- I never sucked. I just didn't want you...
...to know how good I was.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Well, this is so great.
- Now we can enter doubles tournaments.
- That's why.
- They still looking for us?
- Yeah.
The bartender said they split up
into two search parties.
The herbivores and the carnivores.
You know, we, as a group,
are not the coolest.
Oh, look out.
- I don't think they saw us.
- I don't think they did.
So I started to tell you
something earlier. Um...
There was another reason that I realized
it was time to end it with Joey.
I kind of realized I was starting
to have feelings...
...for someone else.
Oh.
And can I ask who?
I think you know.
I think I know too, but I've been really
wrong about this stuff in the past, so...
- I'm sorry, we can't.
- All right. All right.
I mean, you just went out
with my best friend, you know?
I just think it would be a really,
really bad idea.
Or not. I mean...
What?
Oh.