A good man's dead 'cause we pushed him,
knowin' we didn't like him for it,
seeing how he was
takin' it. We did that.
I'm thinking about Tom.
Thinking about that note.
You see him type anything?
So, you don't know nothin'?
You just makin' your money,
and milkin' they pain.
Looks like this man with one
eye gave Julie a doll in 1980.
Do you know who these people are?
Two ghosts?
In 2012, two former Louisiana
State Police stopped
a serial killer
associated with some kind
of pedophile ring.
I think what happened
to the Purcell children
was connected. With the cousin's help.
I think their parents sold them off.
Hoyt. He got something for kids.
Now it's all gone! Done!
Whatever he knew, gone!
I need to know everything.
You gotta just trust me.
Detective Wayne Hays.
Edward Hoyt.
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --
"What will become of you and me...
besides the photo and the memory?
This is the school in which we learn.
That time is the fire in which we burn.
What is the self amidst this blaze?
What am I now that I was then,
which I shall suffer and act again?
The children shouting
are bright as they run.
This is the school in which they learn.
What am I now that I was then?
May memory restore again and again...
the smallest color of the smallest day.
Time is the school in which we learn.
Time is the fire in which we burn."
Tourin' backroads?
I've seen 'em all.
Wanted privacy.
My hope being that we could
resolve this situation,
just the two of us.
What situation is that?
Don't do that.
You got in the car. You
know what this is about.
Ahh.
You were army, correct?
Recon.
Saw combat?
Many times.
Mm.
I was 7th Infantry.
Korea.
Chosin.
We took all the casualties so
the Marines could turn tail.
Thirty below zero.
Lost about 5,000 men.
I wouldn't imagine a man like you
meets a man like me
to trade war stories.
We're both soldiers.
You understand triage.
My man Harris James.
I want to know what happened to him.
Somethin' happen to him?
Spoke a couple days ago
up at your offices.
Don't start off by
lyin' to me, Mr. Hays.
The last time I saw him,
all we did was talk.
What'd you talk about?
Julie Purcell.
That's the girl went missin',
been in the news again recent.
What'd he say about her?
Can't talk details since it's ongoin'.
But you think Harris had
something to do with this girl?
Yes, sir, I believe he did.
Him and some others.
And you got no idea where he might be?
Might be he took off...
we got him worried.
Cameras all around corporate.
Access roads to the plant, everywhere.
Video of Harris's car
pullin' out of the gate.
Followed a minute later by your cruiser.
Just had to follow up
with some questions.
Man's a hell of a talker.
I give you chance after chance
to speak plainly to me,
and you keep throwin' shit in my face.
You know, sir...
I've always respected
you and your family.
Family.
That's what it's...
We only had the one.
Then Ellen got sick.
Now our child's gone too.
Somethin' you want to get
off your chest, sir?
Nobody's gonna hear it but us.
Mr. Hoyt.
You wanna tell me about Julie Purcell?
I don't know about Julie Purcell.
I'm in the fuckin' dark.
And, well...
I guess Harris didn't
talk enough after all.
We know about the kids' uncle.
The phone calls from the mother, Lucy.
Harris goin' to Vegas,
same time she OD'ed.
What I know?
Harris's work beeper, newest thing.
Has a little computer chip
keyed to our corporate system.
Includes a GPS signal.
And I have exact coordinates
where Harris last was
before it went dead.
Now, you bein' the law,
and me an interested party,
should the two of us
go out to those woods,
see if we can't find Harris James?
And can you tell me, Mr. Hays...
are we gonna need fuckin' shovels?
You wanna swap confessions?
Just what is it you think I did?
That's why you bring me here.
So you could see how much I know.
Word is your investigation ended.
So we're done now.
They can do what they want
with the investigation.
That's not gonna stop me from lookin'.
You heard that hotline call.
Sounds like she doesn't
want to be found.
Maybe, Mr. Hays, best thing you
could do for that young woman
is leave her in peace.
Hard walkin' away knowin'
people mean to do her harm.
Well...
if the police ain't lookin' for her,
and you're not,
can't imagine anybody else'd be.
In fact, I can practically guarantee it.
Otherwise...
could be you're givin'
these people you mention
reason to find her.
See?
You don't drop it...
there's others can't either.
What happened?
Just tell me what happened!
I don't know what happened.
Do I look like a man
with fuckin' answers?!
Maybe one day I'll come see you.
Try havin' this talk again.
That you hopin' to get your balls back?
Or truly wantin' me to
regard you as a threat?
Think about what that'd
mean to your family...
you bein' a murderer and all.
Think about what it'd
mean for that girl.
Mr. Hays, do you want
me to feel threatened?
Ahh.
I'll let you find your own way back.
No way Harris woulda run off.
He loved his family.
He was a wonderful father.
I'm sorry 'bout that.
Wonderin' if maybe
you could speak toward an old
associate of your husband's.
Was a black man with one eye.
You ever see your husband
with someone like that?
Know who it might be?
Why are you asking?
We're trying to find a person
in connection with somethin' else.
Description come up a few times,
we can't get a name.
You sure you never saw a man like that?
A man like that came by the house.
Few weeks after Harris disappeared.
I don't like to think about it.
I was upset at the time.
He had, uh, one white eye and a scar.
He said he knew Harris.
He upset me.
Did he want somethin'?
He asked did I know if
Harris had found the girl.
I thought maybe... maybe he meant Harris
hadn't been faithful to me. I...
- I ran him off.
- Tell you his name?
He introduced himself
as Junius somethin'.
He upset me. I made him leave.
Junius.
You wanna bet that's Mr. June?
Makin' his name Junius Watts, maybe?
Worth a try.
I checked with a gal from state records
about the Hoyt place.
Been held in trust by the estate.
Nobody's livin' there.
So?
The old maid... the other day?
She talked about some
area they couldn't go.
I wanna look at it.
Well...
I guess you're lead
detective now, Lieutenant.
Goddamn right I am.
You couldn't help yourself, could you?
Sir?
"Purcell Investigation
Brought to False Conclusion.
Sources Say Case Far from Solved."
And what sources, Detective Hays,
could this headline be alluding to?
I-I didn't know...
We're lookin' at suin'
your little girlfriend.
I haven't read the papers.
"An anonymous source
in the investigation
insists that there are a number of clues
and suspicious facts of the Purcell case
that are being ignored in
favor of a hasty conviction
of the West Finger shooter."
Your man here, he's suggested
you got taken advantage.
Like you're too pussy-struck to
have known what she was doin'.
We think you owe the
department your own op-ed.
You're gonna write a statement
explaining that fragments of hearsay
were used without your consent,
facts were misrepresented,
that the woman who wrote this
did so without your cooperation.
I'm not much of a writer.
Well, we'll write it for you.
All you gotta do is sign.
- Purple! Think about it...
- Say "thank you," Wayne.
Just make it right, man.
You got carried away. Walk it back now.
If I don't?
D Company needs a new
Public Information officer.
Administration.
You'll never work another
Major Crimes investigation.
Or... you could just quit.
You are one lucky mother.
You know how hard I had to work,
get them to give you another shot?
- Appreciate it.
- Yeah.
Hey, uh, listen to me.
You don't ever do any kind of
shit like this to me again.
I can't figure what you were thinking.
Hey.
What the hell are you doing?
You heard 'em. I'm done.
What?
I get them to give you a
pass, and y-you're quittin'?
- Oh, I'm not quittin'.
- You can't.
This is pride, Wayne, and
it's fuckin' you up.
Take a breath, count to ten,
and sign their goddamn paper.
- No.
- Public Information?
You hate the public. You're a detective.
You don't do shit like this.
Anything anybody mighta
said about you...
- What'd they say about me?
- That you're a professional.
I mean... they used to say that.
Got away from me, man. I was pissed off.
Didn't really think it through.
It's not like me, you're right.
OK. All right, there we go.
I mean, you just sign their statement,
and let's you and me move on.
Except then... I'd be burnin' her.
Callin' her a liar.
She didn't really do nothin' wrong.
She didn't lie,
and I'm not sayin' she did.
So what? This is your job.
Our job.
You're my partner.
That's it? You're just
gonna go be a typist?
Probably a lot less bullshit.
Couple years, maybe it all blows over.
I can outlast 'em.
What about us?
What you talkin' 'bout?
Grab a beer, go to a game.
Not like we're not gonna
see each other, man.
Suppose somebody catches us?
We're old and confused.
This is where they kept her.
This is where she ran away from.
Twenty-five years.
And we just...
All this...
All this goddamn time.
What the hell have I...
What the hell were you doin'?
Thought it was the right thing.
I had a family.
Now, that must be nice.
I find you burnin' your clothes
in the middle of the night.
This morning you disappear
after a phone call.
If you've got somebody else,
I can take it, just say so.
No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
It's the case.
It was only ever the case.
And it's over now.
What part of the case
made you burn your suit
at 3:00 in the morning?
The bad part.
Can I get you a... a drink?
I'd prefer a straight answer.
I know what you'd prefer.
But supposin' that answer
would be dangerous to you?
I'll take a hard truth
over a nice lie any day.
We never really established this,
'cause when we met...
I told you too much.
And then for a long time,
I wasn't really a cop.
But there are aspects of my job...
things I've seen, things I know...
it's not for sharin'.
And this...
wouldn't do anything but cause harm.
Maybe it's not for you to decide
what's harmful or not for me.
Except I already did.
It's something we
should decide together.
No, we shouldn't.
And that is my whole point.
I might have a problem with that,
because this morning you said
you'd tell me everything.
That was a mistake.
And I just realized now...
that I want your approval,
and sometimes I do the wrong thing
because it's what you want.
I'd like to stop that goin' forward.
Are we going forward?
How do we with this big
secret between us?
Maybe that's what we're
really talkin' about.
There's always been this
big secret between us.
And it's that you and me...
who we are together, this
marriage, our children...
it's all...
tied up in a...
dead boy and a missin' girl.
I'll take that drink now.
Bud and a shot of Jack.
- You got a problem, little man?
- No. No.
No, sir. No problem here.
Then put your fuckin'
eyes somewhere else.
What it is...
I'm just a fan of romance.
May I ask you a question?
She look like that before
you rode her cross country?
What the fuck did you
say, you little midget?
See, I always wondered,
all this butt-faced
human pieces of garbage
out there walkin' the earth...
who's makin' 'em?
I mean, what kind of
Frankenstein monsters
are out there copulatin'
to create all these
hunks-of-shit people in the world?
Then I come in this bar,
here's you two, givin' me the answer
I've been lookin' for
my whole fuckin' life.
Unhh! Unh.
You done buckin', cowboy?
Thank God it was you hit me
instead of that woolly
mammoth you're fuckin'.
Last night, listening just now...
I've wondered: maybe we don't
really know each other.
Because you're right,
what you said about us
and the Purcell kids.
We never really talked
about it in that way.
What it meant for us.
But it's ten years later.
You write a story,
you get past the start...
it's important to know
how you want it to end.
You were pregnant yesterday.
And now Henry's nine and...
I blink, he'll be out the house.
If we get there, I don't wanna
wonder how it all happened.
I don't think one date night a month
is gonna get us where we need to be.
I'm writing this sequel,
you're on Major Crimes...
They tanked the case again.
Same as '80.
I oughta quit.
I've thought you should
quit for ten years.
- Why?
- "Why?"
Why wouldn't I want you to quit?
I don't think you realize this, Wayne,
you could have been good
at just about anything.
But what you think you
are, it made you stuck.
I never went to college.
Or California.
I listened to my Ma.
I was in the army, and then PD.
Maybe I...
got too good at doin' what I was told.
I always think about why you
said you joined the army.
Didn't have money for
school, or no job...
No, you told me...
you said you figured that if you died...
that your mom would be rich,
because the government
would give her $10,000,
and that's why you ended up joining.
Uh...
I think we both...
we want somethin', we
get real single-minded.
This new thing... that's
not why you write.
It's all the work I've done, I
don't want to see it wasted...
But it's not you.
You wanna write your
real book, write it.
It'll be great.
I probably won't read it,
but it'll be beautiful.
And I think that...
I think maybe I should quit.
You should too.
I walk away, you walk away.
And...
let's put this thing down.
It's not ours.
And like you said, we're
past the beginning.
You could really quit?
We'll both, together.
You go and write the books
you want to write, and...
I'm gonna...
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
But the smartest person I know
told me I'd be good at almost anything.
Get outta here.
We're...
Come here, buddy.
Ahh...
Old gal I knew still works at the DMV
helped us out with an address.
Junius Watts.
Might be less crazy than I thought.
Don't get carried away.
Ch-ch-ch-ch-ch!
I been waitin' on you all.
Since the night you saw my car.
Probably shouldn't'a drove off, but...
you had that baseball bat.
Y'all here to kill me?
Walk back in the house.
This is you.
Usually if PD or state want a statement,
they'll just drop it by.
If we get an information request,
then we'll just connect it to you.
You all set, hon?
Yes, ma'am. Thank you.
I worked with Mr. Hoyt on
his first chicken farm.
Been there since he started.
Lost the eye in a line
accident, one of the hooks.
That ain't the part of your
history we're interested in.
I was sayin'.
After he expands,
he moves me to his place,
I started managin' his
household for him.
Him and Miss Ellen, they had Isabel.
Miss Ellen got sick.
I helped him raise his daughter.
Isabel. She was a delight.
She go to university
and meets a young man,
and they have a little baby girl. Mary.
They was happy. Mr. Hoyt, he happy.
Then there was the... the accident.
Her husband and her daughter
skidded off a mountain
on their way to meet her at Bull Shoals.
She gets very, very sad.
Worse than sad.
Won't talk, won't leave the house.
Has to take medicine. Lithium.
This little girl I helped raise
was so sad she can't talk.
Mr. Hoyt, he can't stand
seein' her this way.
So he starts travelin' again.
Then one night... she snuck off from me.
Took her car and smashed it all up.
This patrolman, Harris James,
he help us keep it quiet.
Then for the first time
in almost three years,
somethin' stirs her.
Employee picnic, '79.
She sees this family there
with this little girl,
- and she runs out and tries to grab her.
- Mary!
Hmph. Miss Isabel,
she keep talkin' about
that girl she saw.
Sayin' she's just like Mary.
Says she wanna see her again.
So I take the mother Lucy aside,
back when she worked on the line,
and I talked to her about
maybe lettin' Miss Isabel
play with her daughter a bit.
She was good with that?
Well, she say OK, but she want money.
And she wanted the little
girl's brother along,
keep an eye on her.
And that was OK.
Well, for a little while we meet 'em,
a little spot in the woods,
and we just played.
And Miss Isabel, she get
back to bein' her old self.
Except what?
Well, we had an idea.
Miss Isabel want to adopt the girl.
She have a better life,
we thought, and...
well, the father, we'd just
have to figure somethin' out.
But... eh...
Miss Isabel, she...
she confused.
She'd stopped takin' her
medicine, I-I didn't know.
She'd been callin' the girl
"Mary" since we arrive.
I heard it. I oughta knowed
somethin' was too wrong.
Well, we's playin' hide-and-seek,
- and Will was off lookin' for us.
- Will!
Julie!
I guess Miss Isabel had other plans.
We have to go home.
No. Mary...
I told the girl her brother OK.
He just bump his head, that's all,
and he'd wake up soon.
But she said we can't leave him there.
And she can't calm down.
So I brought him up to the cave.
It was just... just a bad accident.
Mr. Hoyt, he don't know none
of this, 'cause he on safari.
So I call the man Harris James,
he help us out before.
When that Woodard man went crazy,
Harris brought that boy's
backpack up to his place,
and the girl's shirt.
What about the mother...
Lucy?
Harris talked to her.
Explained things, the accident.
Offered her a lot of money.
Showed her the best thing
was for her to take it
and let Miss Isabel have Julie,
just like we talked about.
Only, it just happened this way...
The little one, Julie.
Time we get home, she
calm with everything,
no trouble.
She happy to be there.
We seen the girl is happy. She is.
- How's the castle?
- And for a time it was workin'.
- Couple years.
- Good.
The little one, she thinks
she's Isabel's daughter,
'cause Isabel's been
tellin' her stories.
I'm just tryin' to take
care of 'em best I can.
I swear, the little one was happy.
I thought she was happy.
I didn't realize till later
what'd been goin' on.
She'd been feedin' that little girl
lithium since she was ten.
That was why the girl
didn't have no problems
once we left Devil's Den.
Musta started then.
That's why she wasn't sure
about her own history.
She'd been drugged half her life,
told some fucked-up fairy
tale by this woman.
And Miss Isabel was gettin'
sicker and sicker.
The girl is gettin'
more and more confused.
Then she growed up. She wants to leave.
She asks questions...
memories, her brother.
I want to help her.
You helped her run away.
Yeah.
I make sure that the door is unlocked
and Miss Isabel was in her bath.
And I gave her a map how to
get to a place I had nearby.
But she never showed.
And I was lookin' for her ever since.
Tryin' to save what I could.
That's real heroic of ya...
you cyclops motherfucker.
What happened to Isabel?
After the girl run off...
she had another break.
She put on her weddin' dress...
she took all her pills...
she go to sleep
and never wakes up.
Did ya ever find her?
'Ninety-seven.
I'd been passin' Julie's
picture around for ten years.
This runaway girl tells
me about this shelter
nuns in Fort Smith run.
The girl says she saw Julie
workin' there at the convent,
and they say her name is Mary,
which I knew it must be her.
Mary July.
"Like summertime," she said.
She didn't have any ID.
She stayed for three and a half years.
First getting help, then helping others.
She'd been in bad shape
when she arrived.
She had what's known as
disassociation issues.
I believe she found a home here.
But her time outside,
things she'd done...
She had HIV, it turned out.
We took care of her in the infirmary
when she got sick.
A few months, she was gone.
I was too late.
Something she'd done
out there on her own
got her real sick.
And I told her... I told
her that I would meet her.
I drew her a map.
But she wasn't there.
It's always too late...
whatever we do.
That's why I's sittin'
outside your house.
I was just tryin' to get up the nerve.
Tryin' to tell you what happened.
So... you can kill me or take me in.
I want it.
I don't wanna live with this no more.
Take me in.
We don't have the authority.
You don't wanna live with it...
fuckin' don't.
Hey!
Y'all come back here!
Y'all punish me!
I need y'all to punish me!
Your name was Julie Purcell.
I'm sorry I didn't do
a better job for ya.
I'm real, real sorry for that, miss.
Failure was mine.
You deserved better than this.
Better than me.
Oh!
- Sorry, mister.
- There you are.
All right, that's enough
runnin' around, Lucy.
Why don't you go ahead
and jump in the truck.
OK.
I'm sorry 'bout that. She
likes to run around.
No problem.
You been takin' care of the place long?
Oh, yeah. My dad started the business,
and he used to do the convent for free.
And I kept doin' the same.
That's nice of you.
Y'all have a good day.
Thank you, sir.
You too.
All right, Lucy, let's
get your seat belt on.
That's enough.
I'll get the rest tomorrow.
Yeah.
I oughta throw it out now.
But it's all hers.
Maybe we'll write a book about it.
Have to keep startin' over.
We got an ending, I guess.
But I don't, uh...
Hmm.
Do you feel like any kinda closure?
I don't.
Me neither.
Talkin' to your boy.
I's been wantin' to get closer to town,
and we were thinkin', uh...
How'd you feel, me crashin' here
with you a few nights a week?
I guess so.
I keep a neat house,
though. I'm just sayin'.
I'll keep the dogs out back.
Hey.
Your little girl's comin' here tomorrow.
Oh, that's right. I remember.
Henry mentioned you're
all havin' dinner.
Invited me over.
Good. You should come.
OK.
You be all right tonight, buddy?
I'm good, brother. I'm good.
OK.
Hi.
Hey. Tell me what we're doing.
You're not talkin' to me,
don't return my calls.
We're playing games now?
I don't play.
Is this about what I wrote?
You read it. You... encouraged me.
What's going on with you? What happened?
Wait right here a minute.
That's all your stuff.
That's how you say
"I don't think we should
see each other anymore"?
What the hell is wrong with you?
You don't like how I am,
get out of my house.
All right, give it to me then.
I want a... clear picture
of who I've been spending time with.
Clear picture is, I don't
wanna see you anymore.
And I'm not the asshole here.
You're the asshole.
Me?
- How?
- You used me.
Fuckin' around with me so you could
hear what the police are doin'.
Like you're better than me. Right?
When I landed back in the States,
some high yellow bitch like
you called me a baby killer.
I'm sorry that happened...
Shit, you're whiter than my partner.
Former partner.
What's the matter with
you? What happened?
I'm fucked's what happened!
Twelve years on the job, and
I'm a fuckin' secretary now.
So you got in trouble. What did they...
Is that why you're doing this?
I'm tryin' to pull my head out
my ass, regards to you. You...
I don't know. Maybe you
didn't mean it all the way,
maybe it just happened,
but you was workin' me.
Always askin' questions,
always talkin' about the case.
That's not what I did. You
know that's not what I did.
No, I don't!
But I just about decided...
that you don't know
what you're really up to
most of the time, do you?
Bein' a good-lookin' woman
like you are, I mean.
People don't really expect
you to take responsibility.
You're just like a pretty bird,
flyin' around, shittin'
on people's heads.
I don't need one of them.
I was doin' real good without
no head-shittin' birds in here.
You're a mean drunk.
But it's good to see how
weak you really are.
You've got a badge and a gun,
couple of other things
that you learned from watching movies.
But there's nothing here.
They wanted me to burn you down.
Sign a statement sayin' you were lyin'.
That you took pieces of what you heard
and made up all that shit you wrote.
You should.
I don't want you in trouble.
I don't want anything from you, ever.
Go ahead, sign their statement.
I'm gonna be fine.
I don't need the rest.
I don't want this shit in my house!
"Among the children who knew her,
a ten-year-old named Mike Ardoin
seemed to take Julie's
disappearance hardest.
I knew Mike to be a shy, artistic boy,
and he often played with Julie,
or at least sought out her company.
His father ran a small
lawn servicing business,
and when he spoke about Julie,
the boy's lip trembled
and his eyes flooded.
My attempts at comfort were
completely insufficient,
but I tried to let him
talk about his feelings.
He started crying.
He said he always thought
he'd marry Julie
when he grew up."
"Tell me a story.
Make it a story of great
distances, and starlight."
No. Please.
Please.
What if the ending isn't
really the ending at all?
What if Julie did find a
life at that convent?
Friendship, love.
And what if that little boy
who loved her so much,
that little boy whose
daddy, and later himself,
took care of the yard at that convent?
What if he recognized her?
"'If you knew time as well
as I do,' said the Hatter,
you wouldn't talk about wasting it.'"
What if he knew her...
even if she didn't know herself?
And what if those nuns
who cared about her,
those women who knew
she'd had a hard life...
they knew bad people
were looking for her?
What if they wanted to protect her?
Protect her how?
The only way they could...
by telling a story.
And...
And then...
Oh!
Sorry, Mister.
The little girl...
that was her.
Oh... my God.
What if there's another story?
What if something went unbroken?
All this life, all this loss,
what if it was really one long story
that just kept going and going
until it healed itself?
Wouldn't that be a story worth telling?
Wouldn't that be a story worth hearing?
Information.
I need a address for Northwest Arkansas.
Uh, Mike, uh, Ardoin.
Um, that's, um...
um...
A-R-D...
O-I-N.
Ardoin Landscaping.
Just a moment.
Pop, what's up? I was
about to come get you.
I, uh...
Henry... uh...
- think I'm lost.
- What do you mean?
You on foot?
Uh...
I'm in my car.
I don't know where I am.
I don't recognize it.
Dad, Becca came in,
you were comin' here for dinner.
And I'm tellin' ya, I
don't know where I am!
Hey, hey, hey, it's gonna
be all right, Pop.
We'll come and get you.
Just take a beat.
Is there someone around you
can ask where you are?
You see anybody around?
Mom.
I'm sorry to bother you, miss.
I, uh...
I have this, uh...
I'm sorry, uh, I'm lost.
Can you just tell me where I'm at?
Oh, of course. You're in Greenland.
This is Allegra Lane.
Uh...
Allegra Lane, in-in Greenland.
House at, uh... 1-2-0-8.
Greenland? What are you doin' out there?
I don't know. I...
I was... I don't know.
All right, it's OK.
Stay at your car, Dad.
We're comin' to get you, all right?
Keep your phone handy.
OK.
Thank you, son.
Yeah...
my son's comin' to get me.
I, uh...
have this condition.
I forget things, and...
Thank you. Thanks for your help.
Glad I was out here to help.
Uh, would you like
some water or anything
while you wait for your son?
Actually... if it truly
wouldn't be any trouble,
I'd be grateful for some water.
Throat's dry.
Lucy, will you get this
man some water, please?
Yes, ma'am.
Uh...
Beautiful day, isn't it?
Yeah.
Sure is.
Oh. Thank you, miss.
You're welcome.
Well, uh...
I-I'll let you get back to it.
Thank you much.
You're welcome, sir.
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- Mm-hmm.
It's OK.
Dad?
Hey, Dad!
Hey.
It's different than I remember.
I'm surprised, it feels different.
Maybe you could stay longer.
Maybe.
Did I lose you?
No. No, Dad.
How could you?
I don't know.
Seems like I'm losin'
the hour and the day.
Oh, I sure missed you.
I miss you too, Dad.
I miss you right now.
I haven't... I haven't really...
I don't...
Had this in my pocket.
I... don't know, uh...
Eh.
It's nothin'.
Go play with your grandkids, Pop.
Throw Papa the ball.
Wait. OK...
- Oh, he did!
- It's what you call a slow break.
Uh-oh.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
You doin' all right?
Yeah, yeah, man, how are you?
Still upright, baby.
Real glad to see you.
Glad to see you too, pal.
Mr. West,
this is my wife, Heather.
- Hello.
- Welcome.
Oh. Thank you, ma'am.
Come on, hurry up!
Come on!
Thank you.
This what you settled
on doin' with yourself?
I don't recall you mentionin'
time in the armed forces.
I don't let people talk
to me the way you did.
A few women, no men at all.
- OK.
- I want you to understand that.
You don't strike me as tolerant
of that sort of behavior.
No.
That was the point, wasn't it?
But I'm trying to remember that a
few weeks ago your friend was shot
and you almost died.
You want a do-over?
I guess I want to know if you meant it.
If you meant what you said.
I want to know if you want us to stop.
That's all.
I don't know.
Wayne, what do you want?
You want to yell at me again?
You want me to tell at you?
No.
I'm sorry for what I said to you.
I-I haven't been myself.
You want me to leave?
You want me to stay?
I don't know.
You're gonna have to decide.
I, uh...
I'm not myself.
I don't know. I don't like this.
But I want...
I think I wanna marry you.
I didn't think that'd happen for me.
I didn't let myself...
I didn't expect this.
You.
And how would you make that happen?
Guess, uh...
Guess I should sober up, for a start.
For a start, yeah.
I mean it.
Then let's get you home.
You can think about how
you're gonna propose.
I can think about if I'm gonna accept.
I'll do it.
Get on my knees, with a
ring and everything.
I ain't messin' with you. I don't play.
No, I know you don't.
♪ I went down ♪
♪ To St. James Infirmary ♪
♪ And I saw my baby there ♪
♪ Stretched out on a
long white table, yeah ♪
♪ So sweet ♪
♪ So calm, so fair ♪
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --
♪ Well, folks ♪
♪ This is the end of my story ♪
♪ And if anyone should ever ask you ♪
♪ Nnn-nnn-nnn-nnn ♪
♪ Just go on ahead and tell them ♪
♪ That I had the St. James ♪
♪ Infirmary ♪
♪ Blues ♪