You can put those away.
They will sleep for hours.
BATMAN: But I won't.
- What did he want?
- I'm not sure.
But it appears he left us a present.
He's moving toward the airfield.
That autogyro he's using
isn't a long-range craft.
He must be planning on rendezvousing
with a bigger plane.
- There.
- BATMAN: "Lazarus."
It's too easy. He wants us to find him.
Let's check this out.
RA'S: I anticipated meeting you
tonight, Detective.
I hope the story I have to tell you may
cause you to reconsider your pursuit.
The year was 1883.
Your government
was ruthlessly expanding westward.
What will it be, stranger?
Water, ma'am, in a clean glass.
Horse done give out on me 10 miles back,
and I'm hotter than
a shaved coyote with a heat rash.
Another thing, ma'am.
You by any chance seen this feller?
You a bounty hunter?
Just to pay for my piano lessons.
I know that two-bit skunk.
He hurt one of my girls real bad.
If you could point me in his
general direction, I'd appreciate it.
That I can and will.
And this one's on the house.
SHERIFF: Well, well.
Jonah Hex, his own bad self.
Been here five minutes and you ain't
killed nobody nor set nothing on fire.
Slipping, ain't you?
I'm still a little bushed.
Fact is, you look a little past it, Hex.
Not tired, just all used up.
Well, if I get pushed,
I can still shoot a fly out
from between its wings,
provided the light's right, of course.
And it's a big, plump fly.
I ain't got nothing on you, Hex. Yet.
Just remember them wanted posters say,
"Dead or alive."
You might try "alive" this time.
First time for everything.
Be back here around midnight.
I can help you then.
Duvall comes into town now and then,
starts fights, bothers my girls,
challenges men to duels.
I'm aware of his habits, missy.
What I ain't aware of is
where he's holed up.
Strange thing, that.
He ain't staying at the hotel,
and the next town's 50 miles away.
Sounds like he likes to sleep on
the ground with the rest of the snakes.
He ain't the type.
More the clean-sheet sort.
And he first showed up in town
about the time folks started seeing
the sky monster.
The what?
No one knows what it is,
and the sheriff's too yellow
to investigate.
It only comes out at night,
like a big boat or a log in the sky.
About the same time it showed,
folks started seeing lights in the-
Get down.
Way I figure, that glow might some way
tie in with the sky monster and Duvall.
Reckon so.
I think you'd better
start back now, missy.
Got a feeling things might get loud
and busy soon.
Good luck, Jonah Hex.
Right nice sentiment, ma'am.
But I never cottoned much to luck.
I like to make my own.
I'll remember that when I see you next.
All right, hurry up
with that crane up there.
All right, a little lower,
a little lower.
Work, you lazy good-for-nothing!
I've told you repeatedly,
this is not how I do things!
I beg your pardon, sir.
I was hoping to expedite
the completion of the airship.
Commendable, but not at the expense
of my workforce.
Good men are hard to find
in these parts,
and there is still much to be done.
The government's western expansion
is destroying this land.
Drastic steps must be taken
to preserve the wilderness.
And Ra's al Ghul is the one to do it.
Who better than I?
I'll destroy the railroad and bomb
other railroad junctions
as I move eastward toward Washington.
Once Washington is in flames,
I'll force the United States government
to declare me master of America!
Whatever you say.
It would appear we have ourselves
a government spy.
A rather disreputable-looking one
at that.
Well, Mr. Spy,
I'd say your plan has failed
and the railroad is doomed.
I ain't no spy.
I'm Jonah Hex, and I don't give
a tinker's cuss about no railroad.
I've come to get you, Arkady Duvall,
on account of what you done
to that girl back east.
You mean to say
you've tracked me
across 12 states because of that?
Well, there's also the matter
of a $200 reward.
That part don't hurt my feelings none.
You're either a liar or a fool.
I've been known to be foolish,
but ain't nobody calls me a liar
and goes to bed happy.
Give him a lead bath.
Perhaps we can make both sides match.
Stop!
You are becoming quite bold, Arkady.
Whipping my men, disposing
of interlopers without consulting me.
He's a spy, sir, a railroad spy.
He looks more like a saddle burn to me.
Imprison him. I will question him later.
And you, Arkady, will make no more
decisions without my approval.
Understood?
What?
GOVERNOR: Today on this momentous period
in history,
we link our great western lands
with the east.
Before this great enterprise,
envisioned by myself,
there was nothing here but wilderness.
And from it, with bare hands,
hard work and dedication,
we have hewn a civilized land.
And so it gives me great pleasure
as the territorial governor
to drive the golden spike
which will connect
these two great sections
of the North American continent.
RA'S: Run, if you value your lives!
Clear the area! Maintain at your peril!
Fire!
Run for your lives!
Don't shoot, you fool!
This ship is full of hydrogen gas!
Do you want to blow us all to atoms?
You! I don't believe it!
Guess I'm just a bad penny.
Why are you doing this?
Because I don't like you or your kind.
Excuse me.
No! The hydrogen cells!
What happened?
It was that scarred man.
He turned our own cannons on us.
Now, let's you and me dance.
You cannot defeat me.
I am a Heidelberg fencing champion.
My heart's all aflutter.
I'll chop you to pieces.
Talk, talk, talk.
Order the men to abandon ship.
Aye, sir. But what about Duvall?
Leave that fool to his fate.
5000 in gold.
Take it. Leave me be.
It ain't about money, boy.
It's about justice,
and I aim to serve you some.
Let me live. Please.
I will, only because
it's too much trouble
to haul your stinking carcass back east.
I'm getting too old for this.
Great story. But what's it got to do
with that rest home?
I think I know.
I assume you listened
to my account, Detective.
Yes.
Duvall.
It can't be. He'd be over 100 years old.
He was sentenced to 50 years
of hard labor.
Of course, no one expected him
to live out that sentence.
No one but me.
The Lazarus pit.
When he was a young man,
though even its powers cannot
restore him now.
When his sentence was completed,
Arkady simply wandered away.
The privations he had suffered
had left his mind shattered.
I had lost track of him until he
turned up in that rest home.
You left Duvall to his fate
a century ago.
Why come back for him now?
Did you really think, Detective,
that in my 600 years of life,
I would've sired only one offspring?
Even before the Phoenix debacle,
I had come to realize
that Arkady was too unbalanced and cruel
to wisely rule my empire.
- But you couldn't forget about him.
- What father can ever forget his son?
Come now, Detective.
I've still a few good years left.
We will cross swords another day.
But for now, let me take my boy home.
English - SDH