I read in a book somewhere
about a rich guy who goes broke.
When he's asked how it happened,
how he had lost everything, he answered:
"Slowly at first.
And then... all at once."
For Pablo Escobar,
"all at once" had finally come.
His empire in shambles,
his army all dead or in jail,
Escobar did the one thing
he could still do: A disappearing act.
One month, 14 days and seven hours...
with no sightings, no intercepts, nothing.
While we waited
for his eventual reemergence,
the machine built to capture him
found itself idle.
And that brought
a different kind of danger.
One that comes
with too much time to think.
Some started to look inward
at the path we had taken to get here...
asking, "How much of this blood is on me,
and how do I get clean?"
Under mounting political pressure,
Gaviria finally publicly denounced
Los Pepes.
And Los Pepes responded
with their own press release.
They said their job was done.
They were packing up and going home.
But Los Pepes wasn't something
you could turn on and off.
Its members were looking to the future.
One without Escobar.
And they each had their own version of it.
Los Pepes had knocked Pablo
out of the narco business
and that had created a vacancy
for a new cocaine king of Medellín.
Or, depending on who you asked,
maybe a queen.
Los Pepes may have disbanded,
but that didn't mean they were done.
The story of a vigilante army taking down
Escobar made for great headlines.
And while no one was named, it's not
to say it wasn't cause for concern.
Yes, ma'am, as far as I know.
No, we're, uh, crystal clear on that.
- Messina.
Yeah. Uh, he just got in.
- Hey, boss.
- Murphy fill you in?
Yeah.
This article's getting more traction
than we thought.
International news outlets keep calling,
want a statement from the ambassador.
- Are we giving one?
- No. Nobody is.
But we're watching it closely.
I don't need to tell you
it could look very bad for us.
I want to make sure we're covered.
Well, Los Pepes is disbanded.
It's basically over.
Look, I tend to agree. But the press may
shake a few more trees, see what falls.
What if someone talks?
The only people that are gonna
talk about Los Pepes is Los Pepes.
And they're not talking.
So we're covered.
We better be.
- Peña.
- Javier.
What's going on?
Nothing that's my problem anymore.
Where you going?
I just want to make sure.
Fuck it. I don't want to know.
And you can go fuck yourself.
Best way to make a bad story go away
is to come up with a better story...
and sell it hard.
This is one of the cornerstones
of American foreign policy,
and one we learned through years
of trial and error in Latin America,
Chile, Guatemala, Panama.
Getting caught with your pants down sucks,
but if at the same time
you give the folks a big win,
like, say, dismantling the second biggest
drug cartel in the world,
well, then nobody's paying attention
to the bad story.
They're too busy patting you on the back.
Risky plan? Yes.
But pressure will force you to take risks.
It'll force you to do a lot of things.
Don Berna!
Where's Peña?
What do you need?
I got a tip. A guy.
He says he may have a lead, man.
Yeah, well, why don't you, uh,
give it to Martinez?
Or you could give it
to your Los Pepes pals.
He wants to give it to an American.
Yeah, what's he got? Who is this guy?
He's a guy I know.
Come on, Murphy. He's safe.
He knows I work with you.
What, he doesn't trust you?
All right. Bring him in.
He's in Bogotá.
So I gotta go to Bogotá
to meet your friend? Forget it.
Come on, Murphy.
You want Escobar, don't you?
Please, talk to him.
It's really important.
- All right. Set it up.
- Okay.
In English, please!
Those are the codes and frequencies.
Pablo is using a radio.
That's the way he communicates
with his wife.
And these are the codes, Murphy.
Yeah? Where did it come from
and how did you get it?
Lugo is a fiscal at the Tequendama.
He guards the family.
What do you want for this? Money? Visa?
It don't work that way, bud.
So? What do you think?
Javi, he's given us everything.
We got codes, frequencies.
- I think it's real.
- Take it to Martinez.
I'm at the embassy. I gotta call you back.
What you doing at the embassy?
What's going on?
Nothing I can't handle.
I'll fill you in when I can.
- Javi, let's get on this.
- Murphy, take it to Martinez.
I'll call you later.
Peña's in Bogotá?
Yeah, Javi's into something. Shit.
I'll take the codes back.
You stay with Peña, okay?
No fucking way. The codes are staying
with me. I'll take it to Martinez.
We give Judy immunity,
take her testimony and we are covered.
Don't lie to me again, Peña.
This is a tier-one narco who's
ready to flip on other tier-one narcos.
She's been in the business for 30 years.
She knows Cali's operation.
It's not intel anyone can provide.
She has leverage over you.
Her information on Escobar
crippled his business.
She'll do the same to Cali,
only this time for us.
The moment she goes on record,
her leverage is gone.
She doesn't get immunity
until after she talks.
Get her on record
and we'll see what she's got.
Nobody seems to want to take on Cali.
They've been off-limits,
but this may do the trick.
And Peña. Be discreet. Tell no one.
There are people in this building
who won't like it.
Going down?
So... how's it going?
All right, say he picks up
the phone. How close can we get?
If Pablo talks in Medellín,
we'll know every word he says.
- Can you get his exact location?
- If it's within range, yes.
All right, if Pablo uses the phone
outside of Medellín with the same codes,
can you hear him?
No. The antenna is not that strong.
Fuck!
Limón.
- No.
- No. No.
Jhon!
She's on her way.
Hey, man. How's it going?
Everything good at the safe house?
- Where's Messina?
- Oh, she's gone.
Reassigned. Headed home.
Likely to spend the rest of her career
busting meth labs in Indianapolis.
Something about chain of command.
- And Judy?
- You didn't hear?
Judy has an interview
with the Miami Herald in, uh...
oh, about five hours.
Now I can't be certain,
but I bet she has a story to tell
about the involvement of a certain
DEA agent with Los Pepes.
All I know for sure is,
whatever Judy has to say,
it won't be pointed in my direction.
You should've stayed in your lane.
Wow.
And Cali too, right?
They get a pass?
How much do they pay you
for your protection?
Pay me?
Let me tell you something, Agent Peña.
Maybe it'll make you feel better,
but maybe not.
We're gonna get them someday.
But not your way.
For everything you know, you're, uh...
extremely naive.
Anyway, I've enjoyed this.
The laughs.
Um... Oh.
I think the ambassador wants to see you.
I guess word about this Miami Herald thing
is spreading like a prairie fire.
And bring your passport.
I think you're going home, but...
you didn't hear that from me.
Tata?
Pablo?