Pablo! Pablo! Pablo!
Look up "magical realism"
in the dictionary,
and it'll describe a literary style
incorporating fantastic
or mythical elements
into otherwise realistic fiction.
Colombia is where it began.
And anyone who's spent real time here
knows why.
It's a place where the bizarre
shakes hands with the inexplicable
on a daily basis.
But just like in the novels
of Gabriel García Márquez,
the weird shit usually pops off
at certain critical moments.
When the whole place is on edge.
When everything's about to change.
Of all the people who had
a vested interest in nailing Escobar,
Javier Peña deserved to be there
when it went down.
No American had given more or done more.
Well...
To, uh...
the Drug Enforcement Administration?
I'll drink to that while I still can.
You're a fucking lifer, Javi.
Well, it doesn't take a genius
to figure out which long-term DEA agent
was linked to the Los Pepes death squad.
Well, the Board of Professional Conduct
has never been accused
of being geniuses, so...
Yeah, and who reads
the Miami Herald anyway, right?
Murphy, listen.
I meant what I said.
Anyone starts asking questions, just
tell them what they want to hear, okay?
- It was always on me.
- Fuck you, Javi.
And anybody who comes around asking.
Well, you do me a favor. You...
You get him.
Attention passengers.
We will now start boarding Flight 464
to Washington, D.C. at Gate Two.
All right, well, I gotta...
I can't finish this. It's...
I gotta go.
Take care of yourself.
All it took was the whiff of a scandal
out of the mouth of an exiled drug queen
and Peña was gone, like fucking magic.
# Happy birthday to you #
# Happy birthday, dear Pablo #
# Happy birthday... #
This signal is coming from Medellín.
- Pablo's come home.
- I think so.
Hopefully he will
speak to them again tomorrow.
Pablo...
Hermilda.
Nelson Mandela?
- Yeah!
Tata?
Pablo?
Captain.
Perez!
This is the house.
Pablo.
Pablo. Pablo.
Go, go, go!
All that time hunting him...
and just like that,
I'm looking down at Pablo fucking Escobar.
For years I'd been building
this son of a bitch up in my head.
What a monster he'd be.
But here's the thing.
When you lay eyes on him,
the devil's a real letdown.
Just a man.
Beard grows if he doesn't shave.
Fat and shoeless.
You take a good long look at evil,
and it reminds you of one...
Sir, do I need a lawyer?
You're the review board, right?
Professional conduct or some bullshit?
We're not the review board.
So who are you?
We're from Operations.
What do you want from me?
In 1992, do you know how much cocaine
we estimated came into the US
from Colombia?
311 metric tons.
And in 1993, during the hunt for Escobar,
372 metric tons.
Now that piece of shit is on his last leg.
Every one of his labs has been shut down.
And cocaine production goes up.
Can you imagine what happens next year?
Now the king is dead. Long live the kings.
Agent Peña, how much do you know
about the Cali cartel?