You threaten a man's family,
and you find out what he's made of.
Pablo Escobar was made of rage,
revenge and terror.
Unable to lash out directly
at his enemies in Cali,
he went after their prized
legitimate business,
their beloved chain of drugstores.
And he blew them to shit along with anyone
unlucky enough to be standing nearby.
We're talking dozens of bombs.
He put the city of Bogotá on edge
and the Colombian government on notice.
Continue to ignore Los Pepes, refuse to
acknowledge their crimes, and you're next.
But terror brings more terror,
and Los Pepes responded
with their own special brand.
We came up with a name for their displays.
- Colombian folk art.
Like I said, you can't make this shit up.
The point of all this?
Psychopaths sending a message...
No matter how far you go...
...we'll take it one step further.
The gates of hell were officially opened.
And everyone was scrambling
to get out of the fire.
Or climb into it.
Tata.
Hey, I need you
to run a trace on this name.
- Okay.
- Find this guy.
All right? You look tired.
Pablo was right. The government
couldn't stop his family from leaving.
But if you remember, he had
some bad history with Avianca Airlines.
And they made sure as shit
that everybody knew
the Escobars were trying to fly the coop.
What we know is that Escobar
bought tickets for his family
on eight different outgoing flights
from Bogotá.
Destinations ranging
from Barcelona to Toronto.
Mr. President,
we need to prevent that from happening.
We need to keep the family in play.
If they're allowed to leave Colombia,
we're gonna lose leverage
in the hunt for Escobar.
Legally, there's no way we can stop them
from flying out of the country.
By applying pressure behind the scenes,
we can prevent the family
from being accepted upon arrival.
And if they're kept in Colombia,
he's gonna be worried about their safety.
He'll be more likely to make phone
contact, more likely to... make mistakes.
Because they're more likely
to become victims of Los Pepes.
Mr. President... if the family gets safe
haven, there's no telling what comes next.
Maybe Escobar surrenders,
maybe he goes to war.
The family is leverage. We have to use it.
I agree.
I want one of your people with them
giving us updates, running interference,
and have them find out
where they're going. And stick with them.
- Murphy.
- Hey, it's Messina.
I need you to grab your passport
and head to Bogotá International.
Where?
The Escobars are trying to flee the
country. Wherever they go, follow them.
- Yeah. When?
- Now. Once you spot them, check in.
- And Murphy, keep this under wraps.
- Yes, ma'am.
Who was that?
Messina.
- Where you going?
- Going out.
- With your passport?
- Yep.
- Oh, that's all I get?
- Uh, I'd like to get some tickets, please.
- For... which flight, sir?
Let's see. Madrid, London...
It's Murphy. Get me Messina.
- Messina.
- Hey, it's me. It's the Frankfurt flight.
Germany. Shit.
Yes, Mr. Foreign Minister, but I'm not
talking about some Turkish date farmer
looking to drive a taxi in Berlin.
I'm talking about Pablo Escobar's family.
No. No, they haven't committed any crimes.
Due to events in their fairly recent past,
Germany had some of the softest
immigration standards in Europe.
If you had a pulse,
they tended to let you in.
Now maybe that was good for mankind,
and it was certainly good
for the Escobars.
It was very bad for us.
Got a bump on your guy.
About an hour ago.
Credit card belonging to Fernando Duque.
Used twice, restaurants.
Here, here, a couple streets over.
Check this out.
Ran him through the CNP database.
A complaint got filed this morning.
Your boy's wanted.
- For what?
- Kidnapping and car theft.
Filed by his ex-wife. It's a blue Volvo.
He's running. And he's taking his kid.
He's 14 years old. Fuck.
Peña.
- Peña?
- Messina.
- Hey, boss.
I think Fernando Duque's on the run.
He's got his kid with him.
If he's that scared, maybe he's willing
to drop privilege and cooperate.
Yeah, that's what I'm thinking. I...
I might have an idea where he's holed up.
If he comes through for us, you think
we can get him out of the country?
- If he'll cooperate, yes. Look into it.
- You got it.
- And Peña.
- Yeah.
How did all this come up?
My CI knows a girl he sees.
Kind of fell into my lap.
- Mmm-hmm. Get on it.
- Yeah, boss.
Okay.
Attention, ladies and gentlemen:
We will be passing around
immigration cards.
Foreign ministry isn't cooperating.
We need more time.
Don't let them leave the airport.
- They do, it's over.
- Right, right, right. Talk to you soon.
Sir, I'm with the United States DEA.
There's passengers on this flight
who can't be allowed into this country.
Heard of Pablo Escobar? Cocaine? That's
his family. You can't allow them in.
Unless there is a problem with
their passports or any type of contraband,
they may enter Germany.
What about if they're transporting
a large amount of foreign currency?
- You would be certain of this how?
- I saw it. I saw it with my own eyes.
I work with the DEA, been with
this family, I've been tracking Escobar
for a long goddamn fucking time.
It is in that bag.
- In which item of luggage?
- The maroon bag.
...Perdón?
- Do you speak English?
- No.
I'm a hundred percent certain.
That burgundy bag.
Fucking hell.
- Hello. Pablo Escobar? Familia Escobar?
- Sí.
- You speak English? German?
- No.
Come with us.
To be honest, I'd never actually
seen any cash in the bag.
But I knew Pablo
would never let his wife go anywhere
without some serious walking around money.
- Please come now.
- Shh.
Fernando Duque.
Javier Peña.
While the authorities were using
all the political pressure they could
to keep Escobar's family in play,
Pablo was practicing
his own special form of diplomacy.
...First, he called the German embassy
in Bogotá.
Then he threatened to bomb
a couple of Lufthansa planes.
Then he dialed up President Gaviria.
Who couldn't take the call.
Because he was already on the phone
with the German ambassador.
And then, Pablo did something
he'd never done before in his life.
He called a cop and he asked for help.
Not just any cop,
but the top cop in the country:
Attorney General De Greiff.
Agent Peña.
I don't think Don Berna's
gonna make it tonight.
What is this?
Just a friendly chat.
You're making some very scary people
pretty nervous, Javier.
Which puts me in a spot because...
I'm the one who suggested
they approach you in the first place.
Now, I don't know what you know
about what it is I do,
but understand this:
I have our nation's
long-term interests in mind.
That's the beat I walk.
And sitting here tonight,
that means making sure the right folks
are left standing when Escobar
gets his bullet.
So do Uncle Sam a solid.
Don't complicate that.
These folks are prone
to emotional decision-making.
Which can lead to bush league nonsense
like... killing a federal agent.
By the way, they found the lawyer.
Even without your help, so...
Trujillo!
You follow me to the fucking hotel?
Huh?
You can't treat us like criminals.
- DEA!
- Get on the ground!
220 pounds of C-4.
Same as a bomb on an F-16.
Dozens were killed.
Scores were injured,
many of them children.
Pablo never took credit for the bomb.
He didn't have to.
Elena?
Elena!