Pablo Escobar said, "Sometimes I'm God.
If I say a man dies,
he dies the same day."
In his career, this asshole
killed thousands of police officers
at a rate of over 400 a year.
With numbers like that staring you
in the face, you have to ask...
what possesses a man to put on a uniform
that all but
guarantees his days are numbered?
Most of them were just kids,
raised to reach a fork in the
road and choose the right path.
Fight for the good guys.
They were young,
they were full of hope...
and they thought they were invincible.
_
And those that were left behind
would feel their loss the most.
Everybody's got a breaking point,
when shit sickens them so much
that they just have to act.
For Pinzón, that
breaking point meant resignation.
_
But there were those
who couldn't resign,
who couldn't just walk away.
Presidents have breaking points, too.
And Gaviria had finally found his.
_
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
_
- We're safe!
- Pass me the ball.
- Here you go.
- Here it is.
_
This is Gilberto Rodríguez Orejuela.
And if you've never heard of him,
it's because that's exactly
the way he wants it.
Ask him what he does for a living
and he'll tell you that he's a banker,
and that would be true.
In fact, he and his brother Miguel
controlled their own bank.
Or he might tell you that he
and his brother owned and operated
one of Colombia's
largest chains of drug stores.
The brothers could also tell you they
ran their own soccer
team. Which they did.
América de Cali, one of
the best teams on the continent
and a fierce rival of Pablo's
Atlético Nacional.
But what they'd never tell you is
that these businesses were a front
and that the Rodríguez brothers
were the second biggest
cocaine traffickers in the world:
the leaders of the Cali cartel.
Like Pablo and the Medellín cartel,
they started out as run-of-the-mill
criminals, bank robbers.
And with all that money
they scored from their heists,
they quickly
graduated to smuggling weed.
And when they realized
that ten pounds of blow
was worth as much as a ton of marijuana,
they jumped headfirst
into the cocaine business.
These guys were no
piece of shit street dealers.
They planned meticulously,
maximizing profit, minimizing risk.
As the business grew, a young
ambitious Colombian kid,
a guy you might know named
Pacho Herrera, was such a good earner
that the brothers eventually
promoted him to partner.
But they had a competitor,
and not just any competitor.
One that wasn't interested in
abdicating the
throne as the king of coke.
- Don Pablo.
- But Gilberto was smart.
He didn't care that Escobar
wore the crown.
_
So they went to him with a proposal, Miami,
the cocaine capital of the world,
would remain Pablo's territory,
and in return, the Rodríguez brothers
would make do with a little territory
in the northeast called New York City.
The extra 1,089 miles may have made it
a little harder to get to, but it
turns out the folks in New York
were just as head over heels
for cocaine as the folks down south.
And while there were
1.8 million people in Miami,
there were seven million
in New York City.
As much as the Cali guys loved money
and the finer things in life,
they hated the wrong kind of attention.
For the "Gentlemen of Cali," it was
about appearing like legitimate
businessmen.
And business was good. But that didn't
mean that it couldn't get better.
_
This was one thing that the Cali
guys and the DEA could agree on.
As controversial as
Colonel Carrillo's methods were,
he was the only guy
that Escobar was afraid of.
And returning command
of Search Bloc to him
was exactly what we needed.
The president has offered us every available
resource to defeat Escobar.
All we have to do now
is manage it properly.
So I'm still gonna rely
on intelligence from you.
But we're gonna do things
a little bit differently.
No more large-scale operations.
Search Bloc goes back
to small-scale tactics.
- Amen.
- Stealth operations, surprise raids,
that sort of thing. We change the game.
But there's one thing that we
need to do first. Trujillo.
_
A hundred men? That's not exactly
small-scale tactics.
First thing is, we let Pablo
know that we're back.
[Steve] Now you can bet that
the second a convoy of a hundred men
and six marked police
trucks leave that base,
that Escobar's army of spotters
would be burning up the phone lines
just to tell Escobar all about it.
_
And you'd be right.
But that was the point.
You see, these spotters made it
impossible for us to operate
in the secrecy we required.
So we needed to blind them.
And the first step to blinding
someone is getting them to open their eyes.
_
Probably this rooftop here.
Once those signals went
up, we could pick them up,
get a fix and get a
location of each one.
_
And I guess you could say that the
second part of Carrillo's plan
was to show Pablo that
the sheriff was back in town.
And he did that the best way he could.
_
Hmm.
- We got 'em.
- Keeps going like that
until you reached Barrio Pablo
Escobar. We captured six radio transmissions.
But we haven't pinpointed
the exact location.
- No, sir.
- So our best bet
is to corner each of these buildings.
This time, we hit the ground.
_
Peña, you're with me.
Murphy, Jacoby, you stay
here to guide us.
Careful out there.
_
Oh, we got one. Spotter One is down.
- _
- Shut up, kid.
_
- _
- Tata.
_
Javi, where are the fucking spotters?
Carrillo went a different way.
He, uh... he cut them loose.
Oh, we're letting people go now?
Yeah, Murphy, we're letting people go.
And what does that mean?
- Don't worry about it, man.
- Hey, fucking talk to me.
- Let go of my fucking arm.
- What the fuck happened?
Carrillo put a gun to the
kid's head and he pulled the trigger.
To make a fucking point.
We good now?
Yeah, we're good.
_
I'd like to talk to you
about what happened tonight.
- What do you think happened?
- I know I got left behind on purpose.
For your own best interest.
You don't know a goddamn thing
about my best interest.
You know, Murphy, what happens
out there isn't really for everyone.
- But it is for Peña?
- You're not Peña.
- 'Cause I'm a damn gringo.
- Because I trust him.
Why don't you try me?
This fight against Escobar,
you want to win it.
These guys aren't fighting by the
same rules, so why should we?
- You know what that means?
- Oh, I do.
So whether this is about protecting me
or protecting you, stop icing me out.
_
Peña.
This is Moncada's biggest lab.
It'll have to be inventoried
before it's dismantled and moved.
How you know that?
- One of my CI's.
- Hell of a tip.
It's a hell of a CI.
Look, you want
Escobar's men, there they are.
- Let's do it.
- All right.
Get up! Move! Move!
Get up!
_
Your CI hooked us a pretty big fish.
Yeah, he's a winner.
_
Wonder if he'll give us Escobar.
- Don't know, we'll see what Carrillo gets.
- Yeah. We'll see.
Carrillo told me that he talked to
you. He thinks he can trust you.
Yeah, he can.
- That's not what I mean.
- Ahh.
Let's go.
I'm a big boy. I can handle it.
Yeah.
_
- You get anything out of him?
- Something.
Not everything. Are you coming?
I'm in, yeah. Let's go.
- _
- Pablo.
_
Hello?
- Steve?
- Hey, baby.
What time is it?
Uh...
It's late.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm... good. I
just need to hear your voice.
I wanted to call, Steve. I...
It's okay. You don't have to explain.
What's happened?
Tell me.
I'm good, baby. I'm... Don't worry.
You have to go.
Let's talk tomorrow. Okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Good night.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --