Hey! Anyone here?!
Answer me, Al!!
Where the hell am I?!
Dammit...
Lin!
Stupid prince!
Who are you calling stupid?
Lin!
Is that any way to speak to a prince?
You're safe!
You...
What?
You're not actually Envy disguised as Lin, are you?
Come on...
Do you want me to recite the entire room service menu?!
Okay, you're not fake.
You're not a fake either, are you? You pea--
Who are you calling a pea-sized runt?!
Okay, you pass.
But seriously, where are we?
If I recall, we were swallowed up by Gluttony, and...
Yeah, but there's no way his stomach could be this big.
But...
Look.
It's the deserted house we were just in.
And this...
The Lieutenant's car?
I think it's safe to assume that all this fire came from the Colonel.
Yeah.
Which means...
...we're really inside Gluttony's stomach?
No idea.
But I can at least tell you we're not in Heaven.
Let me see this.
What's up?
Lin, look at this.
Isn't that Al's?
If we can only find his arm,
that means Al wasn't swallowed with us.
Thank goodness.
I bet Al is worried sick.
We've got no idea where we are, either.
Now's the perfect time for them to awaken!
My telepathic abilities!
Elric telepathy!
Hear me, Brother!
Have fun with that.
I see a lot of buildings and corpses,
but they're all from different times...
Is there even an exit to this place?
I don't know. And if there isn't, I'll make one.
And where are you going to make one?
All right, throw that stick in.
I see what you're up to.
There.
I don't think it's hit the bottom yet...
A wall! Let's look for a wall!
Yeah! No matter how big the place is, we'll eventually reach the edge if we just keep moving forward!
We should be able to find the exit, too!
I couldn't find her...
Where did you go, Shao May?
Maybe it got eaten up by a stray dog or something?
A stray?
That was a joke! I'm sorry!
She...
Shao May is a panda who has had a minor disorder since birth, which prevented her from getting any bigger.
I found her after she was abandoned by her parents...
...and we've been raised like sisters ever since.
My clan, the Chang, barely has any authority in Xing, making us one of the weakest clans.
Maybe that's why.
How can I put it... we were both attracted to each other because of our similar standings...
Yes. It may have been sympathy at first...
...but we were raised like family, carried the same burdens...
...and she eventually became someone irreplaceable to me.
There are lots of things I was able to go through, just because she was there.
I wouldn't have been able to cross the desert without her.
I don't think you really had to cross it in the first place.
Why would you do all this for something uncertain like immortality?
If I don't bring back the method of immortality...
If I don't present it to the Emperor and earn his favor...
My clan will die out at this rate.
That's why I came here with her...
With her...
Shao May!
Stop crying! I'm begging you!
Master.
We still have some time before the sun rises.
There shouldn't be alot of military police on-duty at this time.
Huh?!
You'll help me look for her?
You're such a nice person.
His people died out in that civil war.
So maybe he's empathizing with you and your weak clan?
What's wrong? Aren't you going to look for her?
Okay! I'm coming!
Having to walk in all this really drains your stamina, doesn't it...
Yeah. And no signs of an exit, either...
I'm so hungry...
If we manage to get out, I'll let you eat all you want.
Eat all you want, sleep all you want, and...
Lin?
I can't take this anymore...
Come on, giving up already?
You're pathetic.
You going to collapse here, too?!
Get up! Walk!
I'm leaving you behind, dammit!
Then go...
You weakling!
I'm going!
I can't die here.
I'm really going to go ahead!
Not joking, you know!
Didn't you say you were going to go ahead?
I definitely don't want to die with you.
But you've got people waiting for you, too, don't you?
Hey, if you have the strength to talk, then...
If only we had something to eat...
Did you know, Lin?
Leather goods are edible.
Should be done by now...
Here.
You don't have athlete's foot, do you?
Do I look like I do, dumbass?!
What a meal.
Sorry about all this.
What do you mean?
If you hadn't tried to save me back then...
Forget it.
This is nothing compared to the training I went through as a kid.
It's kind of annoying we don't know where we are,
but we can search for the exit now that we've had our beans.
An optimist, are you?
I'm just relentless about staying alive.
If I even thought about giving up,
I'd get beaten and scolded by Al.
What's wrong?
Something's coming.
That's...
Oh, it's you guys.
Envy, just as I thought!
Please, tell us where the exit is!
That's pathetic, Edward Elric!
Shut up! Humans would do anything to live!
Despicable!
Unfortunately...
Shut up!
You're despicable!
...there's no exit.
Shut up! Shut up!
You really had to do that, didn't you?
Even I got dragged in because of you.
Where are we?
Are we really inside Gluttony's stomach?
We're inside his stomach, and at the same time, we're not.
Fullmetal ru-
I mean, Fullmetal Alchemist, shouldn't you have realized where we are by now?
Now that you mention it,
when I was sucked in by Gluttony...
I recognize that sensation...
Don't you?
Since you've gone through it in the past.
The Gate of Truth!
But this isn't how it was.
It was all white, and there was a gate...
Oh, so that's how the real one is.
"Real"?
Gluttony is the result of Father's unsuccessful attempt at recreating the Gate of Truth.
What... did you say?
A poorly-made Gate of Truth that even Father couldn't get right.
I guess it's safe to call this place the crevice between reality and the truth.
The crevice?!
There's no exit, nor a way to get out of here.
All we can do now is to wait until
the span of our lives comes to an end.
All we can do...
...is wait until we die here.
No...
No way in hell I'll let that happen!
Don't screw around with me!
Envy!
Hey!
There's no exit?
We're going to die here?
Hey... Hey...
Hang on.
If I die here, what will Al do?
I promised him...
I promised him we'd get our bodies back together.
Dammit!
Who the hell is this Father guy that tried to recreate the Gate?!
Führer President Bradley?!
Bradley?
Not even close.
He's just a Homunculus.
I knew it...
Research Laboratory 5.
Using people's lives.
Philosopher's stones.
Homunculus.
If the Führer President is also a Homunculus, then that means it was you guys who started the Ishbal conflict...
Ishbal?!
That was the most amusing task I'd ever been given!
Do you know what started that civil war in the first place?
If I recall, an army officer accidentally killed an Ishbalan child...
That's right.
I'm the one who shot the kid dead.
Umm...
I heard about Ishbal from Yoki.
That felt amazing.
Watching the civil war spread indefinitely from a single bullet.
Man, it was really refreshing!
Oh, by the way.
I disguised myself as a moderate officer who was against the military intervention of Ishbal.
Hear this!
He couldn't even give an excuse for it and was sentenced to death by court-martial!
Humans are so easy to manipulate.
So it was you...
The one who shot an innocent child dead...
The one who destroyed our hometown... The one who drove away the Ishbalans...
The one who created Scar, a vengeful murderer...
The root cause...
...of what killed Winry's parents...
You bastard!!!
What?
He didn't give an inch...
You brats want to fight?
Ed, pull back!
We're all going to die here anyway.
I'll show you something cool as a final gift.
Did you look beneath his feet when you were fighting him in the woods?
No.
That means...
He may not look like it, but he weighs quite a bit.
His true form must be...
Dammit...
What the hell is this?!
How could that be a Homunculus...
An artificial human?!
What...
...should I do?
Hell if I know.
What should I do... I'll...
I'll get yelled at by Father!
Father? You have a dad?
I do.
The one who created the Homunculi?
Yes.
What happens to the mass you swallow...
Is there a trick to it?
Think... Think!
We decided we'd get our bodies back together!
I can't give up here!
Gluttony, take me to your Father.
Okay.
You're a human sacrifice, right?
Y-Yeah, that's right. I'm a human sacrifice!
What the heck does he mean by that?
The only ones currently confirmed as such are the Elric brothers.
What about Doctor Marcoh?
You would think that it's about time...
There's Kimblee, too.
He doesn't have the nerve to open the Gate.
Well, what about Mustang, the other sacrifice candidate?
The Führer President wants to have a long chat with him.
Why are you letting me live?
To make you understand where you stand.
Since when has the military been beholden to the Homunculi?
It has been set up that way ever since this country was first reformed.
So you've been smiling with glee, watching us struggle.
Your hands that were shaking during Brigadier General Hughes' funeral...
Was that just an act?!
Everyone makes too big a deal out of the death of a soldier.
They should have known his military uniform might become his burial attire.
Brigadier General Hughes' daughter was so annoying during the funeral.
She really got on my nerves.
If I recall, you also have a child.
How could you say such a thing?
Are you referring to Selim?
He's a good boy.
I wonder how he'd react if he were to find out that his father, a man of utmost standing, is a Homunculus.
Are you trying to blackmail me?
It is futile.
He won't become my weakness.
But you're different.
She'll become your weakness.
Lieutenant Hawkeye!
What is it?
Someone from the personnel bureau dropped by earlier.
I was transferred to Southern Headquarters.
What?!
Not just me, either.
Second Lieutenant Breda was transferred to Western Headquarters,
and Warrant Officer Falman was transferred to Northern Headquarters.
You're Lieutenant Hawkeye, correct?
Yes, sir.
I'm Yakovleff, from the personnel bureau.
Personnel bureau...
I'm Shtolhi, an assistant to the Führer President.
Take this.
Is this a transfer order?
Correct.
Please allow me to review it.
This is...
What is with this insane personnel change?!
Where were you assigned?
"Starting tomorrow, Lieutenant Riza Hawkeye will be stationed at Central Headquarters..."
"...as an assistant to the Führer President."
And that's how it is.
Colonel Roy Mustang.
How delightful!
Damn, this isn't delightful at all.
Not the least bit.
Lin!
Ed!
Can you make a weapon?
Leave it to me!
We're in a sea of blood.
There's plenty of iron here!
You have bad taste.
How so? I think it looks cool.
Can you do it?
I don't know...
Look at that figure.
And to top it off, that earlier attack broke a few of my ribs.
Same here.
But I won't be satisfied until I give him a good beatdown!
Gluttony, are you sure we're going the right way?
Yeah.
But this way... we're headed toward...
Your Father is in Central?!
Is the soul acting in the shadows a guidepost to the future?
Fight, boy,
if you are to see the truth and discover the depth of darkness.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 26, Reunion.
I won't say farewell...
...because I believe we'll meet again.