Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
Matsuda! This isn't child's play.
Don't joke around.
Okay.. -
This is the Kira case!
Take it seriously!
Sorry.
Matsuda!
I mean, Mr. Matsuda, please stop.
Matsuda...?
I don't want to be dead weight.
Ryuzaki!
Is there anything I can do
besides being a manager?
Could you get me
another cup of coffee?
What?
I want to play a more active role!
MATS U DA
I love you.
So please...
don't say you're going home.
Stay by my side, forever...
Oh! Mr. Director...
I have a boyfriend.
Can we cut the love scenes please?
Wait a second!
Where is this coming from?!
Can't we fake a kiss?
We can't make a movie like that!
If I say no, then it's no!
Yotsuba Group's Tokyo head ofﬁce...
Today is Friday.
Deaths that are beneﬁcial to Yotsuba
are concentrated around the weekend.
I don't want to be dead weight here.
Mr. Mogi's been amazing
since the beginning.
Matsuda! This isn't child's play!
Take it seriously!
Matsuda is a natural at that.
Could you get me
another cup of coffee?
Matsuda!
NISHINAKA GROUP
Hey, Matsu!
He went off somewhere.
Huh?!
So...
Please check this list.
Understood.
Would I punish evil-doers
if I could kill
just by seeing
someone's face and name?
Indeed, there are people that
the world can do without...
But I don't think that
I would become a murderer: -.
just to change the world...
I'm thinking too hard about this.
There's no way that anyone
could murder so many people...
- and not have any memories of doing so.
- What's wrong?
You're staring at me...
You're angry that I'm
the only one eating cake, aren't you?
No, that's not it...
- Here.
- I wasn't envying you.
Ryuzaki.
What is it, Watari?
Detective Era/do Coil has been
asked to uncover L's identity.
Isn't Eraldo Coil the man who's
the next greatest detective after L?
Who in the world would
send such a request?
The person who requested it is the V.P.
of the rights and planning department
of Yotsuba Group's main ofﬁce,
Massahiko Kida.
So it was Yotsuba!
Yotsuba is linked to Kira.
If they want L's identity,
then that means they
probably want to kill him.
That's not good.
We're already shorthanded,
and now we have to worry about Coil too?
It's all right. The detective known
as Eraldo Coil is me.
The three top detectives in the world,
L, Coil, and Deneuve...
are all me.
People who are trying to uncover me
usually fall for this.
I'll give you a strawberry,
so please keep it a secret.
As I expected of you, Ryuzaki.
Maybe I should leave
while I have a chance.
No, then there would have been
no point in coming here.
Should I wait until everyone's gone
and search the ofﬁces?
No, if I were caught doing that...
It's probably better if I leave...
Not that again.
I'm exhausted...
At least it's before the weekend.
We don't know how long
these secret meetings last.
If these were on a Monday, I'd get
depressed about coming to the office.
Secret meetings? All right!
The nineteenth ﬂoor!
I've come this far!
I'm going to do this!
Okay. I just have to get
close to him, right?
Leave it to me.
I just have to make it possible to get
around the security cameras and systems
at the Yotsuba Tokyo main offices,
where this guy works, right?
Yes... It is safe to assume that
Kira and Yotsuba are connected.
We're going to check Yotsuba
to see who and how many
have the power.
It is important that we gain
a clear understanding quickly.
We must not allow Yotsuba to
figure out that we are
investigating them.
If someone notices, please assume that
we'll no longer be able to catch Kira.
Damn it. I can't hear them clearly.
If I could only hear one thing,
something important...
Rather, he's in the way.
Let's kill him and split up his stocks.
I just heard them say, "kill"!
Damn it, Kira sure is...
Kira! There it is! Kira!
There it is! What?!
"Let's have Kira kill him"?
I heard it!
They're really working with Kira...
I did it... I did a great job!
Who are you?!
Please be sure not to act
out of panic or haste.
And don't take matters
into your own hands.
Ryuzaki...
What is it, Watari?
Matsuda has sent
an emergency signal from his belt...
From where?
Well, it seems it's coming from within
Yotsuba Tokyo's main offices.
My name is Taro Matsui.
An agent with Yoshida Productions!
How would you like to use
our top multi-talented star, Misa Amane,
as the new spokeswoman for
your company and for your commercials?!
Forget about everything I just said.
We'll need to rethink our strategy.
Matsuda, you idiot!
Yoshida Productions...
Taro Matsui...
He doesn't have anything
suspicious on him.
And he doesn't seem to
be a corporate spy.
Yes, well, please...
Please take Misa-Misa
into consideration.
These two are only lookouts...
The rest of them must be talking about
how to dispose of me.
Am I going to be killed?
I wonder if the emergency signal
was received...
Anyway, I wonder if
Ryuzaki will save me.
What's gonna happen to me?
You can answer it.
Don't say that you're here.
Hold it away from your ear,
so we can hear.
Okay.. -
Hello?
Hey, Matsui!
Ryuzaki!
It's me... Asahi.
Been a while!
Oh... Asahi, it's been a while.
You don't sound like you're out.
You home already?
Yeah...
Are you by yourself?
Yeah... I'm by myself.
What's up?
Misa Amane is somewhere else.
Matsuda is alone.
Wanna go drinking?
What? Now?
Sorry, I'm gonna have to pass...
What the hell?
Don't tell me you're going through
money troubles again?
"Troubles?"
Yeah, my finances are totally
in trouble. That's obvious.
Matsuda's totally in trouble.
Oh well.
I'll ask you out again
some other time. Later...
So what do you think
about Misa-Misa?
I think she'll be great
for your company.
If you're going to pitch someone,
shouldn't you bring them with you?
Are you really her manager?
Well, right now she's filming
a movie nearby.
I'll call her here once she's finished.
Please make her the spokeswoman
of your company!
I better keep stalling...
Misa's phone is on voice-mail.
I left her a message to call us.
What are we going to do, Ryuzaki?
Well...
If Matsuda dies, that would justify
the suspicion against Yotsuba.
Let's just watch the situation
for a while.
What shall we do?
The question is whether
he heard us or not.
There is a possibility.
We've got to kill him.
But did he really come to
pitch his client to us?
Could he be a police officer?
He can't be.
The Japanese police have completely
withdrawn from the Kira case.
It doesn't matter who he is.
We have to kill him.
It might be good to have her
as the face of our company.
Right? Her shoot will finish soon,
so please wait a moment.
I'm tired.
A message from Light!
Misa...
Light... Sorry I've been
working so much.
I'll be ﬁnished soon.
Misa, you're not
with Matsuda, are you?
He's horrible!
He just abandoned me here...
Oh, I'm getting a call
on my work phone.
It's from Matsu.
Misa got a call from Matsuda.
Tell Misa to let us listen in as well.
Misa-Misa, when you're ﬁnished with the shoot,
come to Yotsuba's main Tokyo ofﬁces.
You may be able to appear
in Yotsuba's commercials.
I'm negotiating with them right now.
What? Really?
That's amazing, Matsu!
So that's what you've been up to!
I'll do my best!
Yeah. It's a short trip by taxi.
Light, we may be able to
save Matsuda.
But we'll need Misa's help.
I'm sure she'll listen to you.
I'm Misa-Misa!
I don't do nudes,
but swimsuits and lingerie are okay!
Pleased to meet you!
She's really cute in person.
That's not the problem right now,
don't you think?
Matsu, since this is for Yotsuba,
I got the okay from the offices
to have a special reception.
Hm? Special?
Good evening!
Pleased to meet you!
We'll be entertaining you with
all the girls from the agency tonight!
Hey, don't you think this is
headed in a weird direction?
It can't be helped.
Right now, we can't leave
that manager alone.
Since we're here,
I'm just going to enjoy myself.
Ryuzaki and the others
can see us from here.
I might be saved...
Here! Please drink! Drink!
This is heaven.
Misa's pretty good at this.
Now then...
I'm going to the restroom.
Ryuzaki, are you watching?
Yes.
Umm, sorry, I...
Never mind that already.
Yes.
The eight who are here,
were having a meeting
to determine
who they would get Kira to kill.
I heard it clearly.
It's definitely them.
It's probably true.
But if you did overhear them,
then they should be trying to kill you.
I figured that...
Is there anything I can do?
Luckily, you're still alive,
so we may be able to save you.
But for that to happen...
You must die before they kill you.
What?
I want you to listen to me very closely.
You can't mean...
That's impossible!
Isn't that so?
In other words...
No, there are some exes
that I still think about.
Our company is still expanding.
What's going on?!
Man... I am so drunk.
It feels good!
Hey, is everyone having fun?
That's no good.
You should be enjoying yourselves...
Now, everyone...
The thing you've been waiting for!
Showtime with Taro Matsui!
Hey, what are you doing?
Go, Mr. Matsui!
Alley oop...
Hey, you're drunk!
That's dangerous.
It's all right...
I always do this.
- Stop it! It's dangerous!
- You idiot!
It's all right...
He fell!
This is bad...
Oh no!
I heard a thud so I came out,
how horrible!
- Call emergency! Call Emergency!
- Man, this role sucks...
Everyone, leave this to us and go home.
What? But...
It's all right. But please consider me
for the commercial.
Hurry. It will be bad if
the press sees us here.
Yeah.
What's going on?!
Did someone jump?!
Well, it's good that we saw him
die right before our eyes.
Hey!
I know we're shorthanded,
but I don't like doing this.
Matsuda, you idiot.
Misa Amane's manager dies...
UNKNOWN NUMBER
Yes?
You're Masahiko Kida, V. P. of
the Rights and Planning Department...
at the Yotsuba Group's main
Tokyo branch, aren't you?
Yes, that's right.
Who are you?
My name is Eraldo Coil.
I'd like to discuss my terms with you.
A $2 million advance and
$8 million upon completion?
Are you out of your mind?
And even if we don't
commission him,
we have to pay him $2 million
to keep him silent.
Hush money, huh?
We should assume that
Coil knows quite a bit already.
That's pretty bad.
I want out of these meetings!
I don't know who Kira is,
but I don't want to get wrapped up
in this and get myself arrested!
Hatori...
You're going to be dead tomorrow.
Wait! I was just joking!
I'll do it.
I'll stay and do it!
So what are we going to do?
Coil is willing to accept our job
despite what he knows.
He'll become partners
with us as long as we pay him.
That's what it means.
We need to have someone
as skilled as Coil on our side.
That's right. Pay him.
It doesn't matter how much it'll cost.
That's right, pay him!
All right, we'll contract Coil.
Any objections?
No objections.
L, are you listening?
I'm so disappointed.
The security level here is horrible.
They only have a contract
with a security company.
There weren't even any
wiretap detectors.
It's been one week since I snuck in.
Things seem to be
moving very smoothly.
We're almost there.
One of them...
is Kira.
Now then,
let's commence our regular meeting.
There only appears to be
seven of them instead of eight.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
Even after I catch
the current Kira...
do you think that I could
become Kira, a murderer?
Do I look like that kind of person?