Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
DECISION
I relinquish ownership
of this notebook.
Take care of Misa.
Mister Stalker...
Hey, Mister Stalker,
where are you?
Let's stop playing this game...
"Stalker?" What does this mean?
Her attitude completely
changed all of a sudden...
Just as I thought.
So as long as I have Ryuk's notebook,
even if! relinquish Rem's notebook,
my memory of Rem doesn't disappear...
But Rem, all these troubles are
happening to me because...
you brought another notebook
to the Human World...
You really sure about this, Light?
Yeah...
I never thought that the notebook
I gave you
would end up buried in the ground...
Listen Ryuk, I'm just hiding it
there in the ground.
I won't get rid of it until...
the next time I say, "get rid of it. "
When I say it,
regardless of the context,
assume it means I want to
get rid of the notebook.
Got it...
Mister Stalker, this is illegal. Stop it.
Please, Mister Stalker!
She's been acting like this
ever since she passed out and
regained consciousness...
Honestly. Does she think
she can act dumb like this?
Okay, I know.
Could you at least take off
my blindfold?
I really want to see
what you look like...
Mr. Matsuda...
Give Mr. Mogi a call.
Huh?
Oh...
Here...
When you apprehended Misa Amane,
you told her that we suspect
that she's the Second Kira, didn't you?
Yes... I did as you told me.
I covered her eyes and mouth from
behind and told her so she could hear,
"You're under arrest on suspicion
of being the Second Kira. "
She didn't seem to struggle
even when I put handcuffs
and the eye mask on her.
She seems to have given up.
I'll give you an autograph or
shake your hand...
That's it! I'll give you
a kiss on the cheek!
Please! I won't run away...
We'd made so much progress with her.
Why is she suddenly talking
about a stalker?
Misa Amane.
What, Mister Stalker?
Are you planning to release me?
You were quiet before you fell asleep.
You asked us to kill you.
Are you trying to give us trouble now?
What are you talking about?
You're the one who knocked me out
and brought me here, aren't you?
So what? Do you want to
play "investigation"? Is that it?
Do you know why
you're tied up right now?
Why? Because I'm an idol?
You're the first stalker
who's ever gone this far.
Hey?! Amane, quit fooling around!
This is scary... W-What is this?
I can't stand it anymore!
Let me go! Let me go...!
Oh yeah... I have to go to
the bathroom again.
I want to go to the bathroom...!
It's been only four minutes since
you last went. Please bear with it.
What's with that?!
That's the only way you'll untie me!
You'll get to see me pee again.
Isn't that what you want? You pervert!
I'm... a pervert?
Amane, let's seriously talk more about
what happened before you went to sleep.
Do you know Light Yagami?
Why did you approach him?
Huh? There's no way
I wouldn't know my own boyfriend...
She was so tight-lipped
about it earlier,
but now, she nonchalantly
says that he's her boyfriend?
What's going on?
It's from Light.
Please turn the AV off.
Yes.
Yes... Yes... Yes, I understand.
We're in room K2801.
My son's coming here?
Ryuzaki, I told you
over the phone, but...
I think I might be Kira.
That's impossible!
Light, what are you talking about?!
What's wrong?! Tell me!
There's no proof that
Light Yagami is Kira,
but... for him to say that
he may be Kira?
It's all an act...
It's not that you "might be" Kira,
but that you are Kira...
What are you planning?
Dad, if Ryuzaki is L,
then he is unquestionably
the best detective in the world.
If L has decided that I am Kira.
Therefore, I must be.
What are you talking about, Light?!
The people Raye Penber,
the FBI Agent in Japan,
was investigating before he died...
The people that went to
Aoyama on May 22nd...
And the first person
the alleged Second Kira, Misa,
approached in the Kanto region...
It's all me.
If I were in L's place,
even I would say that I'm was Kira...
See... I may be Kira.
I just might not know it.
Light...
I see... You're not conscious of it, huh?
I'm not sure of anything anymore...
Even if I have no memory...
there could be another me
who's killing people as I sleep.
That would be impossible.
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?
Actually, there was a time when
I put surveillance cameras
in your room for five straight days.
Cameras?
Yes. You slept normally at night...
Criminals who were broadcasted,
that you didn't know about were dying.
But I decided that,
even if you were Kira,
you wouldn't give yourself
away on camera.
"Won't give myself away," huh?
That may be true...
Well, up to a certain point,
I believe that some
major criminals should die...
I think that anyone who has
such thoughts could become Kira.
Light! I believe the same thing!
I've thought it would be better
if quite a few people were dead.
But, even so,
we can't really kill people, right?
Besides, criminals were dying
while you had no knowledge of them.
The surveillance cameras proved that!
N- No...
We were short of investigators then
and we only watched him
when he was at home...
It's also not as if we were watching him
every hour during those five days...
There might have been a way for him
to kill while he wasn't at home.
Is this all part of your plan,
Light Yagami?
But if we restrain you for
a long period like Amane,
and criminals
still continue to die...
Is Yagami Light no longer
Kira at that point?
Is this what you're aiming for?
I don't like where
this is going but...
Fine.
Light Yagami will be restrained
and placed under confinement.
W- What..?!
You're going to detain... Light?
If we're doing this,
we have to do this now.
You will not be allowed to
leave my sight before then.
T- This is crazy.
There's no way that my son is Kira...
My son wouldn't...
It's fine, Dad.
Light...
There's no way I'll be able to
pursue Kira if I suspect myself.
In exchange, Ryuzaki,
until you decide that I'm not Kira
or you agree that I'm not Kira,
don't let me go, no matter what I say
or whatever condition I'm in.
Understood...
Mr. Yagami, are you able to
come up with an excuse
for Light's absence for your family?
Actually, please just do it.
Well, I'm not too sure
I can so suddenly...
But why does my son have to be
thrown into a prison?
You're being stubborn, Dad.
I can't be fully satisfied with myself
unless I do this.
Are you serious, Light?
Yeah. By taking away
my freedom,
I'll be able to defeat the fear of
Kira that lies within me.
Mr. Aizawa, I leave him to you.
Yes...
FIRST DAY OF CONFINEMENT
Does this mean I won't
be able to eat apples again?
Ryuzaki...
Please take me off
of the investigation.
Chief!
We're holding my son as
a suspect in this case...
I shouldn't be here.
Regardless of whether
we should investigate him,
when we were talking
about confining him,
I let my personal feelings
get in the way...
That's true.
Personal feelings shouldn't be involved.
A- And, if my son really is Kira...
I don't know what kind of
actions I may take.
Yes. I can imagine that you would...
kill your son and then kill yourself.
I agree that we shouldn't
have you here.
Ryuzaki!
Could you confine me as well?
I'm calm now, but...
I don't know what I'll do
when my feelings for my son...
I thought you might
say something like that,
so I've had Watari make arrangements.
However, even though
you'll be under confinement...
please keep your cell phone on as usual.
Maintain regular contact with your family
and people from the outside.
We won't tell Light about this.
And if Light wants to talk to you
we'll have you talk to him as if
you're right here, inside HQ.
Also, we will give you
continuing updates
of the what's going on
in the investigation.
Is that okay?
I am indebted to you, Ryuzaki...
THIRD DAY OF CONFINEMENT
Mister Stalker,
I want to take a bath.
You know where I live, don't you?
Bring me a change of clothes...
This has gotten crazy...
I feel so sorry for the Chief...
Ryuzaki, what's happening?
Have any new criminals
been broadcast
that Kira would target
in the last couple days?
Did Kira kill anyone?
Quite a few criminals have
been broadcast,
but since you've been detained,
none of them have been killed.
No one's been killed? Really?
Yes.
I see... Maybe I am Kira...
Oh man, I wanna eat an apple...
What's going on?
I thought that the murders would continue
even with Light Yagami confined,
but in reality,
they've completely stopped...
It seemed like Light Yagami
wanted to be confined, but...
this would mean that
Light Yagami is Kira...
Now the question is whether
he was conscious of being Kira...
If he is Kira..
Does he think he can
get away with saying
That he wasn't conscious
of what he was doing?
It's not like Light Yagami...
No, it's not like Kira...
FIFTH DAY OF CONFINEMENT
I can't take it, Light...
If I don't eat an apple soon...
Anyway, I just have to
get through it...
even if there's nothing to do...
Mister Stalker, your video won't sell
if I'm just sitting...
Mr. Yagami looks even worse
than Light or Amane..
Of course. It's been five days
since Light's been imprisoned.
During that time, not a single criminal
who's been broadcast has died.
In times like this,
I suppose it's harder
for the parents than
the suspects themselves...
Especially since now, it's almost
definite that Light is Kira.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it? Is it good news?!
Bad news?!
Uh, no... Try not to work
yourself up too much...
You won't accomplish anything
by mulling over things.
The outcome will remain the same.
Perhaps you should rest...
somewhere more comfortable.
Out of the question!
There's no place anywhere
that would be relaxing in this situation.
In the state I'm in now,
this is the best place for me.
No matter what the result,
when I get out of here
I'll leave with my son!
I understand...
SEVENTH DAY OF CONFINEMENT
Light, it's only been one week,
but you're looking worn out...
Are you all right?
I've come this far,
I think it's about time...
Yeah... I know I probably look
pretty bad in here, but...
this pride, I'll just have to...
get rid of it...
Got it.
Later.
What am I doing here?
Ryuzaki...
I know I agreed to be detained
and chose to do this...
But now I just clearly realized that
doing this is meaningless!
It's because I'm not Kira!
Get me out of here quickly!
I can't do that.
We promised that no matter
what you said,
I wouldn't let you out until we decided
on whether or not you were Kira.
There was something wrong
with me then!
Do you really think that
Kira would be able
to operate without being
conscious of it?
I don't remember committing
Kira's crimes, so I'm not him!
I also don't believe that
Kira has been acting without
self-awareness all this time.
But if you are him
everything matches up.
As soon as you were detained,
murders by Kira stopped...
Listen Ryuzaki, hear me out...
I am not lying... I'm not Kira...
I can only think
that I've been framed!
What's wrong... Light Yagami?
What you're saying doesn't
make sense...
But... for some reason it feels
like it's the truth...
Hurry and get me out of here.
We're wasting time!
No. / can '1' let you out'.
Damn it... How did this happen?
What's going on?
This isn't like Light...
He's taking back what he said earlier.
It's not logical.
We can't release him now
that the murders have stopped...
Even I know that.
Well, whatever anyone says...
can't we just decide that
Light Yagami is Kira,
and that the case is solved?
FIFTEENTH DAY OF CONFINEMENT
Two weeks worth of criminals
were murdered all at once yesterday!
Yeah... Kira is back.
Did you tell the Chief?
No, not yet...
Chief, Kira has started killing again!
What?!
Kira was just taking a break.
He's started punishing criminals again!
Is that true, Matsuda?!
Then my son...
I shouldn't be happy that
the murders have occurred, but...
now, suspicion of my son will be...
No, knowing Ryuzaki...
He won't say he's completely
cleared just yet...
Well then...
He's in the grey.
Did you hear that, Chief?!
Yeah, he was pretty much
guilty up to now...
Thank goodness...
It's probably a grey that's
one shade closer to being clear.
Then I'll tell Light, too.
Matsuda! I mean, Mr. Matsuda,
please stop.
"M-Matsuda?"
Don't tell Light.
W- Why?
Light.
What is it, Ryuzaki?
It's already been over two weeks.
There haven't been any new killings.
Won't you just give up and
confess that you're Kira?
Don't say stupid things
like that, Ryuzaki.
You're wrong.
I can understand why you deduced from
the investigation that I'm Kira,
but it's a trap.
I'm not Kira! Zoom in or something
and look at my eyes!
Are these the eyes of
someone who's lying?
Amane... You're really sure that
you don't know who Kira is, do you?
Huh? That again?
That's what I want to know!
Kira is a hero of justice who
punished the burglar who
killed my parents.
I don't understand what's going on...
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacrifice
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the flooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
If I die here,
we'll never uncover the truth!
Do you believe L over me?
Dad!