Within the spreading darkness
I pledged a vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
I'm going to change
The future that
the forbidden fruit foretells...
I'm going to change
The dream into reality
The ending
That everybody wants
Within the spreading darkness
I pledged our vow to the revolution
I can't let anybody interrupt it
Someday I'll show you
A bright and ideal
World
UNRAVELING
lam L.
He's L?
He's different
from what I imagined...
I am Detective Superintendent Yagami
of the National Police Agency.
Uh, I'm Matsuda.
I'm Aizawa.
- I'm Mogi.
- I'm Ukita.
I'm sorry we're late.
These five are our current...
Bang!
What...?
Is this some kind of joke?
Mr. Soichiro Yagami,
if I were Kira you would be dead.
You already know that all Kira needs
is a face and a name, don't you?
Please don't give out
your names so carelessly.
Let's value our lives.
I've heard about him needing a face,
but I haven't heard anything
about him needing a name?
Criminals whose names were unknown or
whose names were broadcast incorrectly
were all spared.
It was discussed at
task force headquarters.
Let's not stand around and chat,
please come right this way.
Oh, yes.
Please turn off
all cell phones, laptops,
and other electronic devices and
place them on that table.
L, do you think that
we'd have our phones on
to leak information?
Just do as he says.
I know he's cautious, but...
I still can't tell if he trusts us or not.
No, I just can't stand it when people's
cell phones go off when I'm talking.
Let me start by saying...
Please do not take any notes on anything
we say here at this headquarters.
Keep all of it in your head.
Please, sit wherever you like.
Okay.. -
Um, L...
When you refer to me from now on
I wish to be called Ryuzaki, not L.
Just to be safe.
Oh, then, Ryuzaki...
If you know that a face and
a name are needed,
then couldn't we cut down the number
of victims by censoring crime reports?
If we do that, then ordinary people
would be killed.
- Ordinary people?
- Why?
Kira's childish and hates to lose...
Childish...?
And hates to lose?
Yes. I'm also childish and
hate to lose... That's why I know.
Ryuzaki...
Could you explain that
a little more clearly?
When I used the TV broadcast
to challenge Kira...
...up until then, we thought that
Kira only went after criminals.
But he didn't hesitate
to kill my double.
Also, as soon as I said
he was in the Kanto region...
He started concentrating on
and killing Japanese criminals
as if to say, "So what if I am?"
He's met each of my challenges
without flinching.
What do you think would happen
if we tried to use media restrictions to
hide criminals from someone like this?
Well...
"if you won't give me your criminals,
"then I'll kill those who've commited
lesser crimes or even the innocent!
"The whole world is my hostage!
I'm not the evil one.
"Those who oppose me
and hide evil-doers are!"
That is Kira's mental process.
Speaking of the mass media,
let's think of ways we can
use it to our advantage.
For example?
How about this...
"U.S. furious over deaths of FBI agents. "
"World outraged over Kira's antics,
"the leading nations send a total
of 1,500 investigators into Japan. "
It would be different from
his recent experience with the FBI.
He would begin to see everyone
as a threat.
When he's feeling cornered,
it should illicit some sort of response.
T- That's interesting...
When in reality there's only seven,
we make him think there's 1,500?!
And unlike the FBI agents,
they don't exist and they can't be killed!
This could work!
Well then, I'll tell you my thoughts
on the Kira case.
Kira works alone...
He was accessing inside information
from the investigation before...
Why do you believe he's working alone?
Aizawa, wait.
Let's listen to Ryuzaki's
entire theory first.
Kira needs a name and face to kill.
To a certain degree, he can even
control the victim's time of death
and the actions the victim
takes before their death.
With all of that in mind...
Please listen closely to the following.
On December 14,
twelve FBI agents
entered Japan.
December 19...
Kira began using prisoners
to conduct tests
on the actions a victim
can take before death.
12/19 TEST 12/14 FBI ENTER JAPAN
Because he didn't know
their faces or names,
in order to eliminate
all of the FBI agents...
He had to see how far he could
control the deaths of his victims.
Finally, on December 27...
After making sure the FBI agents
received the ﬁle
with all the names and faces
of the other agents,
I succeeded in killing all of them.
It is nearly impossible to
ﬁgure out whose ﬁles Kira saw...
But...
I can't let anyone know that
I made contact with Raye Penber.
12/20 BUS
Huh? You're not using
the Death Note today?
Are you studying
for the entrance exams?
It's no use studying
for those at this point.
Oh? So what is it?
I worked the most between
December 19 and 27.
Within this time, 23 people died
of heart attacks as we all know.
They were all wanted criminals,
ex-convicts...
And people who were
suspected of crimes.
People obviously different
from those Kira usually targets.
Indeed.
It means that in order to
kill the FBI agents,
he needed to control those
with even lesser crimes.
He killed 23 people,
so we couldn't tell who he used.
He actually probably only used a few.
He left eight days after the tests
to allow the FBI to gather
information on other suspects.
He wanted to draw attention
away from himself.
Thus, I suspect that Kira
was one of the people
who was being investigated by the FBI
between the 14th and the 19th.
This is data from the FBI.
It contains other important information.
You can't take these out
of this room, but...
Amazing!
This is amazing!
If we have this much information,
we can do more
than enough on our own.
Let's split into two groups.
One will trace the FBI agents,
and the other will investigate
the heart attack victims.
There are only a few people who
had access to info from HQ,
and who were beings investigated
by the FBI in the first five days!
Yeah...
So, does anyone have any questions?
Well then, Ryuzaki,
I have a question.
You said earlier that you hate to lose.
But you've shown us your face.
Doesn't that mean that you've
already lost to Kira?
That's correct.
The fact that I've shown my face
and that I've sacrificed
twelve FBI agents are both losses.
But I will win in the end.
This is the first time
I've laid my life on the line.
Let's show Kira that
we're willing to risk our lives...
Because justice will definitely prevail.
T- That's right...
Justice will prevail!
Let's give it our best!
Let's do this, Ryuzaki!
When I ﬁrst saw him,
I was suspicious, but...
There's no mistake.
This man is L.
First off, in order to make sure
Kira isn't among us,
I would like to talk to each of
you individually.
Huh? Oh, yeah.
So he doesn't trust us...
It's understandable.
If Kira was in the task force HQ
in the beginning, gathering info...
chances are high that
he's still here.
' get n!
And if he remained
he's seen Ryuzaki's face.
Even this is a risk, huh?
Things have been going well so far.
If only I had one more thing,
just one more decisive clue...
If there was just one thing I missed...
Just one piece of evidence
that would come to light...
It could cost me my life.
- Just one thing...
Did you finish studying?
Yeah.
It's all right.
There wasn't anything I missed.
My biggest gamble was
the bus-jacking incident, but...
It is impossible to
connect it with Kira.
The police and L don't know
that Kira can kill people with
means other than heart attacks.
But if anyone were to
discover that fact,
it would be a huge problem for me.
What? Right now?
Dad's been pulling all nighters.
He needs clean clothes.
You've got to give this to him.
I promised I'd go to the first
New Year's Shrine Visit with my friends!
I'll go.
I could use a break.
How lucky!
Thank you, Light!
That means that you can
spy on the Police Department.
I'll only be able to go as far as
the reception though.
Oh? You're bringing a page?
Killing someone out there?
Lately, I've been doing
this when I go out.
Just in case.
That day...
Raye said that he was going to
go to Shinjuku.
On that same day,
there were four heart attacks
in the Shinjuku area.
And... a bus-jacking...
It's not a coincidence.
Kira can...
NATIONAL POLICE AGENCY AND
NATIONAL PUBLIC SAFETY COMMISSION
kill in ways other than heart attacks.
The number you have just dialed...
That's unusual for Dad...
NATIONAL POLICE AGENCY AND
NATIONAL PUBLIC SAFETY COMMISSION
Please...
I must speak directly to someone
from the task force.
I've told you already,
there is no one in
the Kira Task Force Headquarters.
There's no one at headquarters?
Dad's phone is off...
What's going on?
Is there any way I can contact them?
It's something very important
regarding the Kira investigation.
The Kira investigation?!
Well, I'll try to call their headquarters
once more.
I'm Detective Superintendent
Soichiro Yagami's son, Light.
I brought a change of clothes
for my father,
but it doesn't look like he's here,
could you hold on these for him?
Sure. Light, I haven't seen you
around in a while.
Oh... sorry.
Umm...
Remember? We solved that
insurance murder with your advice.
I was the receptionist then, too.
Really, I'm sorry...
I just write my name here, right?
Does this mean that you're
going to help outwith the Kira case, too?
Yes, if all goes well,
I may be able to beat L.
Beat L?
Nobody's at headquarters.
Please trust me on this.
I'll be sure to give them
your message.
That won't do.
It must be in person.
Excuse me...
My father is the chief leading
the Kira investigation.
Do you want to leave
a message with me?
His cell phone is off,
so I can't tell him immediately.
But they're probably busy.
A bunch of FBI agents were killed,
and a lot of detectives quit the case
because they were afraid of Kira.
Light, you shouldn't be
telling civilians that...
People are already talking about it.
Besides, this person is trustworthy.
I can tell by looking at her eyes.
She's a very wise and careful person.
You've heard about the FBI incident,
and you figured out that
there's a problem within
the Japanese police force itself.
That's why you want to speak
directly to headquarters.
Did I get that right?
I'll probably get a call
from my father
once he gets the message
I left on his phone.
You can talk directly
to him at that time.
Is it all right?
Of course!
I can't give you my father's
cell phone number,
but you can use my phone.
Of course, it's no use if
you don't trust both of us...
Who is this cheery guy?
Thank you.
You've managed to lead
her along well, Light.
You're pretty brave.
To involve yourself in the Kira case.
Not at all...
You think that Kira is...
Um, may I ask what your name is?
My name is Light Yagami.
Light as in the character for "moon,"
and Yagami as in "night god. "
It's a strange name, isn't it?
I'm Shoko Maki.
Shoko for "shining child,"
and Maki as in "space" and "tree. "
Ms. Maki, right?
Ms. Maki, I think that Kira's powers...
enable him to control
his victims before he kills them.
I- I thought so too...!
That's exactly what I was thinking!
Kira can control the actions
of a person before death.
But that's not all...
If my analysis is correct...
Kira can also kill people in
Ways other than heart attacks.
Who is this woman?
I don't think anyone's noticed yet...
But I think this is what's
going to catch Kira.
I hadn't even thought about that.
But if that's the case,
Kira would make sure not to
give his victims heart attacks
when he's intent on hiding a murder.
Yes, someone I know
may have met Kira.
Met Kira?!
Sorry.
Meeting Kira is definitely something
that the police would have
a hard time believing.
Yes, that's why I have to
explain it in detail to
someone from
task force headquarters.
But wouldn't it be better if
that person spoke to them instead?
That person is no longer alive.
He was one of the FBI agents
who came to Japan.
An FBI agent who met Kira...
C- Could it be?
He was also my fiancé.
He said that he witnessed
a bus-jacking incident.
He probably met Kira
on that bus.
Raye Penber!
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
I'm sorry your fiancé's passed away.
So... what makes you think
he met Kira?
Eight days after the bus-jacking...
He died, along with
the other FBI agents.
That hijacker robbed
a bank two days earlier.
He died in an accident...
an unusual and rare set of events...
I think that Kira set up
the hijacking
to steal information from my fiancé...
in order to kill the FBI agents
who had come to Japan.
The hijacker died in an accident.
In other words, heart attacks aren't
the only way that Kira can kill.
The hijacker didn't die
of a heart attack.
So that's why you think that Kira can
kill by means other than heart attacks?
Yes.
I think that's a bit of a leap...
No, it's not.
I can't help but think that
the hijacker was being controlled by Kira.
Why?
I've been wondering about
the hijacking ever since
my fiancé told me about it.
I asked him about it more
when he was relaxed.
He didn't name any names,
but he did tell me this.
What did he say?
That he reluctantly showed
his FBI ID to someone.
It was a top-secret investigation
that the FBI kept secret from
the Japanese police.
He wasn't supposed to show his ID.
So whoever saw his ID was the one
who let slip that the FBI was in Japan.
She really knows what
she's talking about!
So this would be the "one thing"
that Light was worrying about!
I see.
It's a conclusion you came to
with your singular knowledge
and your desire to avenge your fiance.
You believe that Kira can
murder his victims
by means other than by heart attacks.
Yes.
You have some
amazing deductive skills,
but you can't deny you have
personal interests in this case.
Your argument seems a bit forced.
But... this theory is definitely
worth investigating.
Your testimony will be
very important to the case.
Y- Yes.
If what you said is correct,
Kira should be caught soon...
Because...
Kira was the one your fiancé
showed his ID to on that bus.
Yes.
That was close...
If this woman had told the police
all this before she told me...
It seems like a god other
than a Shinigami
is on my side.
TO BE CONTINUED
I dreamed a dream
that no one could see,
I threw away everything
that I didn't need
I'm holding these feelings
That I can't give up in my heart
Even if my feet fall victim
to the shackles of sacriﬁce
In between reality and my ideal
I can't hold back
the ﬂooding impulses
Because I have a strong desire
To accomplish
I'm not weak enough to believe
Any of these negative perceptions
I'm a trickster
who doesn't know solitude
PREVIEW
I want to see how
this woman dies,
but I can't be caught
following her.
Go on, hurry to your death!
OVERCAST