Captions made possible by
HOME BOX OFFlCE
A Division of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
STANDlNG lN THE DOOR
I COULD SEE...
THE LlGHTS
ON THE DROP ZONE,
AND I HAD TO ASSUME
THAT WAS OUR DROP ZONE,
WAY lN THE...
AHEAD OF US.
AND SO THAT
WE HAD THE RED LlGHT,
I HAD EVERYBODY STANDlNG UP
READY TO JUMP,
SO, WHEN THE PLANE
STARTED TO GET HlT,
AND SUDDENLY THE PlLOT
GlVES ME THE GREEN LlGHT,
I'M OUT THE DOOR,
lMMEDlATELY.
WE GOT SUCH A OPENlNG BLAST
FROM THE OPENlNG SHOT,
FROM THE PROP-BLAST
THAT lT BROKE THlS CHlN STRAP
THAT WE HAD ON
THlS HELMET OF MlNE,
AND THAT'S WHEN I LOST
THlS FAMOUS LEG-BAG,
THAT EVERYBODY
TALKS ABOUT,
JUST FROM THE SHOCK
OF THE OPENlNG.
IT JUST FLEW
RlGHT OFF MY FOOT.
WE CAME FROM THE SKY.
WE HlT, AND lN ANY
DlRECTlON YOU WENT
THERE WOULD BE ENEMY,
YOU KNEW lT.
AND THAT WAS ALL PART
OF WHAT YOU ACCEPTED.
HOW DO YOU PREPARE
YOURSELF, MENTALLY?
EACH MAN MUST
DO THAT HlMSELF.
EACH MAN MUST PREPARE
HlMSELF MENTALLY,
TO MAKE THAT JUMP.
AT THE BACK OF YOUR MlND YOU,
YOU KNOW, YOU WONDER
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
AND ALL THAT.
YOU KNOW YOU'VE BEEN TRAlNED
AND TRAlNED AND TRAlNED
AND WHAT YOUR JOB
lS GONNA BE,
AND WHAT YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO DO AND...
OH, THAT'S WHAT YOU
GOTTA THlNK ABOUT, YOU KNOW?
AND WE LOST A LOT
OF PEOPLE THAT NlGHT,
BUT YOU TRY TO PUT lT
ALL OUT OF YOUR MlND.
GlVE ME A LlGHT.
LlP, DlD EVANS MAKE lT?
YES, SlR.
HE'S lN LlEUTENANT
MEEHAN'S STlCK, SlR.
LlEUTENANT MEEHAN!
LlEUTENANT MEEHAN.
WlLL COULD
USE SOME HELP.
WlLL.
WlLL, HEY.
WlLL, I NEED
YOUR HELP HERE.
( radio )
GET READY!
STAND UP!
HOOK UP!
EQUlPMENT CHECK!
SOUND OFF FOR
TEN OKAY!
NlNE OKAY!
ElGHT OKAY!
SEVEN OKAY!
SlX OKAY!
FlVE OKAY!
FOUR OKAY!
THREE OKAY!
TWO OKAY!
ONE OKAY!
JESUS CHRlST!
LET'S GO, LET'S GO!
DOES THAT LlGHT
LOOK GREEN TO YOU?
NO, LET'S GO!
I'M HlT!
AHH!
JESUS, TELL MEEHAN
TO GET THEM OUT OF THERE!
AHH...!
2:00!
OH, JESUS CHRlST!
GO!
I WANNA JUMP, SlR!
NOW, LlSTEN TO ME
STAY ON THE PLANE,
YOU'RE NOT JUMPlNG!
HE'S OKAY.
NO SlR, NO!
ALRlGHT, SONOFABlTCH.
WHERE'S THE
GODDAMN D.Z.?
MAYBE lT'S THREE
MORE MlNUTES
ON THlS BEARlNG!
WE GET ANY LOWER,
WE AlN'T GONNA NEED
ANY FRlGGlN' PARACHUTES!
SLOW DOWN!
WE GOTTA GET
SOME ALTlTUDE!
THEY CAN'T JUMP
AT THlS SPEED!
WE THERE?
OH GOD!
OH, NO!
OH!
LET'S GO!
( gunshots )
FLASH!
SHlT!
I DON'T THlNK
THAT'S THE CORRECT
REPLY, TROOPER.
I SAY "FLASH",
YOU SAY "THUNDER".
YES, SlR,
THUNDER, SlR.
MUSETTE BAG.
COACH?
SlR, lT'S HALL, SlR.
I WAS ON THE
BASKETBALL TEAM.
LEG-BAG?
PROP BLAST GOT lT, SlR,
AND MY RADlO AND
BATTERlES WlTH lT.
MlNE, TOO.
MlNE ARE SOMEWHERE
BEHlND THOSE TREES.
OKAY.
FOLLOW ME.
( gunshots )
TO HELL WlTH THAT!
WAlT UNTlL THEY RELOAD.
GO.
AREN'T YOU
"D" COMPANY?
ABLE, SlR.
GUESS THAT MEANS
ONE OF US lS lN THE
WRONG DROP ZONE, SlR?
YEAH, OR BOTH OF US.
DO YOU HAVE
A WEAPON, SlR?
JUST MY KNlFE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY lDEA
WHERE WE ARE, SlR?
SOME.
SO, YOU'RE
A RADlO MAN?
YES, SlR.
WELL, I WAS UNTlL
I LOST MY RADlO
ON THE JUMP.
I'M SURE l'LL GET
CHEWED OUT FOR THAT.
WELL, lF YOU WERE
lN MY PLATOON,
I'D TELL YOU YOU
WERE A RlFLEMAN FlRST
AND A RADlO MAN SECOND.
WELL, MAYBE YOU
COULD TELL THAT TO
MY PLATOON LEADER
WHEN WE FlND HlM.
IF WE FlND HlM.
IT'S A DEAL.
FlRST, I NEED
YOUR HELP.
WE'LL LOCATE SOME
LANDMARKS TO GET
OUR BEARlNGS.
KEEP YOUR EYES PEELED
FOR BUlLDlNGS, FARMHOUSES,
BRlDGES, ROADS, TREES.
I WONDER lF THE
REST OF THEM ARE
AS LOST AS WE ARE.
WE'RE NOT
LOST, PRlVATE.
WE'RE lN
NORMANDY.
WHO'S THAT?
LlEUTENANT WlNTERS,
lS THAT YOU?
GET lN HERE,
SlT DOWN.
ANY WEAPON?
NO, SlR.
AS SOON AS l
HlT THAT PROP BLAST,
SO LONG LEG-BAG.
ALL I GOT lS THlS
KNlFE AND SOME TNT.
THESE 82nd BOYS
GOT THElR M-1 s, THOUGH.
OH, MAN,
82nd, WHERE THE
HELL ARE WE?
SlR, I SAW A SlGN
BACK THATAWAYS,
SAlD, "SAlNTE
MERE-EGLlSE".
FLASHLlGHT.
RAlNCOAT?
YOU GOT A RAlNCOAT?
YEAH.
WE'RE ABOUT SEVEN
KlLOMETERS AWAY FROM
OUR OBJECTlVE.
AND FOUR HOURS
AWAY FROM WHEN WE NEED
TO HAVE lT SECURED.
SO, WE GOT A LOT
OF WALKlNG AHEAD OF US.
YOU MEN WlLL STlCK WlTH US
UNTlL WE FlND YOUR UNlT.
LET'S GO.
HEY, SARGE,
WHERE ARE WE GOlNG?
CAUSEWAY NUMBER TWO,
UTAH BEACH.
THE GERMANS FLOODED
THE FlELDS lNLAND.
WE DON'T CLEAR THOSE ROUTES,
OUR BOYS AlN'T GOlNG NOWHERE.
FlVE OF US AlN'T
GONNA SECURE A ROAD.
THAT LOUlE DON'T EVEN
HAVE A WEAPON.
I DON'T REMEMBER HEARlNG
ABOUT ANY RAlLROADS
NEAR OUR OBJECTlVE.
I'M TELLlNG YOU,
THlS lS THE SPUR
LlNE THAT RUNS
PARALLEL TO THE RlVER.
WE SHOULD BE
COMlNG UP TO A ROAD
AND BRlDGE AHEAD.
YEAH, HOW WOULD
YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE I STUDlED
SANDTAlLS, ALRlGHT?
PROBABLY A
FRlGGlN' TRAlN OR--
SHH.
FLASH.
THUNDER.
LlEUTENANT,
lS THAT YOU?
MALARKEY?
SlR.
GLAD TO SEE YOU, SlR.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
NlCE TO SEE YOU GUYS.
GUARNERE.
SlR.
YOU AND HALL UP FRONT.
WHO THE HELL lS HALL?
( horse neighing )
LlPTON.
GO.
GUARNERE.
( horse neighing )
WAlT FOR MY COMMAND.
THAT'S ENOUGH,
GUARNERE!
EVERYONE OKAY?
YES, SlR.
NEXT TlME I SAY
WAlT FOR MY COMMAND,
YOU WAlT FOR MY
COMMAND, SERGEANT.
YES, SlR.
( gunshot )
HERE YOU GO,
LlEUTENANT.
KRAUT WEAPON.
FlNE, QUAKER.
WHAT'S THAT
GUY'S PROBLEM?
GONORRHEA.
REALLY?
HlS NAME,
DUMMY, GUARNERE,
GONORRHEA, GET lT?
SO BESlDES
HAVlNG A SHlTTY NAME,
WHAT'S HlS PROBLEM?
NONE OF YOUR FUCKlNG
BUSlNESS, COWBOY.
( Lieutenant )
ALRlGHT,
LET'S MOVE OUT.
SlR.
QUlETLY.
DlD YOU SEE HlM?
HE JUST SAT THERE.
HE DlDN'T
HAVE A WEAPON.
WHAT'S HE GONNA DO,
SHOUT AT 'EM?
SHOUTS AT ME
FOR KlLLlNG KRAUTS.
HE JUST WANTED
YOU TO WAlT
FOR HlS COMMAND.
JOE, HE DON'T
EVEN DRlNK.
LlPTON, WYNN
ANYBODY NEED SUPPLlES
OR AMMO, NOW'S THE
TlME TO GET lT.
MCDOWELL, YOU OKAY?
YES, SERGEANT.
THEN LET'S GO.
HEY, I PROMlSED
MY KlD BROTHER l'D
FETCH HlM BACK A LUGER.
SO I GOT
FlRST DlBS, OKAY?
CHECK THAT ONE.
( planes soaring )
IT'S THE NAVY.
THE LANDlNGS HAVE
STARTED, LET'S GO.
LET'S MOVE lT OUT.
RlGHT ON TlME.
YEAH, TELL THAT
TO HlM, COWBOY.
MY NAME'S HALL.
THAT SO?
LET'S MOVE OUT.
YOU JUST GOTTA
LEARN TO RETURN
HlS FlRE lS ALL.
YOU GOTTA REALlZE
lT AlN'T ABOUT YOU.
HE JUST HEARD
HlS BROTHER--
MALARKEY,
SHUT YOUR YAP.
HlS BROTHER GOT
lT AT CASSlNO.
FOUND OUT
BEFORE WE JUMPED.
MORNlNG, SlR.
BATTALlON SURE WlLL BE HAPPY
TO SEE YOU GUYS.
WHERE?
AT THE FARM, SlR.
TOP OF THE MORNlNG
TO YOU FELLAS.
ENJOYlNG THE WAR?
WHERE ARE
YOU FROM, SON?
EUGENE, OREGON.
EUGENE?
YOU GOTTA BE
KlDDlNG ME.
POPEYE, DlD
YOU HEAR THlS?
I'M FROM ASTORlA.
YOU DON'T SAY.
YEAH, ORANGE STREET.
WHAT GlVES?
WHAT, WHAT ARE YOU DOlNG
lN A KRAUT UNlFORM?
VOLKSDEUTSCHE.
COME AGAlN?
MY FAMlLY
ANSWERED THE CALL.
ALL TRUE ARYANS SHOULD
RETURN TO THE FATHERLAND.
JOlNED UP lN '41.
YOU'RE SHlTTlNG
ME, RlGHT?
( male )
HEY, MALARKEY, STOP
FRATERNlZlNG WlTH THE ENEMY.
GET OVER HERE!
WHAT GOT YOU TO EUGENE?
I WAS BORN lN EUGENE.
REALLY?
POPEYE.
HEY, POPEYE.
HEY, HARRY.
CARRY ON.
OH, "EASY COMPANY".
WELCOME.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
AND THlS HERE'S
HALL, ABLE COMPANY.
KNOWN AS COWBOY.
YOU FROM TEXAS?
MANHATTAN.
HEY BOSS,
HOW YA DOlN'?
WHAT'S GOlN' ON?
WHAT'S THE HOLD UP?
NOT SURE.
FlVE'LL GET YOU 1 0,
lT'S GOT SOMETHlNG
TO DO WlTH THAT.
YEAH.
IT'S GOOD TO
SEE YOU, DlCK.
YEAH, YOU
TOO, BUCK.
WHAT'S THE SlTUATlON?
AH, NOT GOOD.
90 PERCENT OF THE
MEN ARE STlLL
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
LlEUTENANT MEEHAN?
NO, NO ONE'S SEEN HlM,
OR ANYONE FROM HlS PLANE.
YOU KNOW,
lF HE lS MlSSlNG,
WOULDN'T THAT PUT
YOU lN LlNE TO BE THE
NEXT COMMANDER OF "EASY"?
HEY, LlEUTENANT SPElRS.
HOW MANY MEN
HAVE DOG COMPANY
GOT ASSEMBLED?
A HANDFUL,
MAYBE 20.
YOU THE ONLY
OFFlCER THAT
MADE lT?
SO FAR.
STlLL WAlTlNG
FOR ORDERS.
YOU GOT
SOME ClGARETTES?
HERE.
HEY, KEEP THE PACK.
YEAH, SO I WAS
lN THE PLANT lN '39.
THAT'S WHEN I WAS
AT MONARCH TOOLlNG
PROPELLER SHAFTS.
NO KlDDlN'.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF THAT, HUH?
YOU AND ME 1 00 MlLES
FROM EACH OTHER,
WORKlNG AT PRACTlCALLY
THE SAME JOB, GEEZ.
HEY, MALARK,
WE'RE WAlTlNG ON YOU.
YEAH, l'M COMlNG.
WELL, I GOTTA RUN,
l'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
YEAH, SEE YOU AROUND.
ZlGARETTEN?
HERE YOU GO.
DANKE.
THANK YOU.
( gunshots )
SHlT.
"EASY COMPANY"?
"EASY"?
HEY, ANY OF YOU GUYS KNOW
WHERE "EASY COMPANY" lS?
YOU SEEN
LlEUTENANT MEEHAN?
NO, NOT YET.
WELL, MAJOR STRAYER
WANTS "EASY COMPANY'S"
C.O. UP FRONT.
WELL, I GUESS THAT
MEANS YOU, DlCK.
C'MON.
SONOFABlTCH.
HEY, MALARK, WHERE'S
THE BEST CHOW?
IN BERLlN.
ROUND THEM UP.
AND THE MGs?
I'D SAY RlGHT
AROUND HERE, SlR.
I CAN'T BE SURE.
THERE'S SOME
KRAUT 88s UP AHEAD.
UP AHEAD AND TO THE RlGHT
ABOUT WHAT, 300 YARDS?
UP THROUGH
THOSE GARDENS.
NOW, THEY'RE RlGHT
BETWEEN US AND
CAUSEWAY NUMBER TWO.
FlRlNG ON TO THE BOYS
LANDlNG AT UTAH.
THlNK "EASY"
CAN HANDLE lT?
YES, SlR.
'CAUSE MY GUESS
lS THEY'RE DOlNG SOME
TERRlBLE DAMAGE THERE.
THE 88s WE'VE
BEEN HEARlNG,
HAVE BEEN SPOTTED
lN A FlELD, DOWN
THE ROAD AWAYS.
MAJOR STRAYER
WANTS US TO
TAKE 'EM OUT.
THERE ARE TWO GUNS
THAT WE KNOW OF,
FlRlNG ON UTAH BEACH,
AND PLAN ON A THlRD
AND A FOURTH,
HERE AND HERE.
THE GERMANS
ARE lN THE TRENCHES,
WlTH ACCESS TO
THE ENTlRE BATTERY,
AND WlTH MACHlNE-GUN
COVER lN THE REAR.
WE'LL ESTABLlSH
A BASE OF FlRE
AND MOVE UNDER lT
HARD AND FAST WlTH
TWO SQUADS OF THREE.
HOW MANY KRAUTS THEY
THlNK WE'RE FAClNG?
NO lDEA.
NO lDEA?
WE'LL TAKE SOME
TNT ALONG WlTH US,
TO SPlKE THE GUNS.
LlPTON, YOUR
RESPONSlBlLlTY.
YES, SlR.
LlEBGOTT, YOU'LL TAKE
THE FlRST MACHlNE-GUN
WlTH PETTY,
A GUNNER.
PLESHA, HENDRlX,
YOU TAKE THE OTHER.
WHO DOES
THAT LEAVE?
COMPTON, MALARKEY,
TOYE, GUARNERE.
OKAY.
WE'LL BE MAKlNG
THE MAlN ASSAULT.
UNDERSTOOD?
YES, SlR.
ALRlGHT, LET'S
PACK lT UP, BOYS.
SHOULDN'T YOU BE
OUTSlDE WlTH THE OTHER
ABLE COMPANY GUYS?
SEE YOU
AROUND, HALL.
LlPTON, WHEN YOU SEE
WE'VE CAPTURED THE FlRST GUN,
I WANT YOU AND YOUR TNT
AS FAST AS POSSlBLE.
YES, SlR.
OKAY, JUST WEAPONS AND AMMO,
DROP EVERYTHlNG ELSE.
GOT ANY SPARE AMMO
lN A PACK OR A MUSETTE BAG,
BRlNG lT ALONG.
LlEUTENANT, SlR?
I WAS WONDERlNG, SlR,
YOU NEED AN EXTRA HAND?
AlN'T YOU SlNK'S
JEEP DRlVER?
SO?
OH, SHlT.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
TROOPER?
LORRAlNE, SlR.
YOU'RE WlTH ME,
LORRAlNE.
COMPTON, SECOND SQUAD.
YES, SlR.
ALRlGHT, YOU HEARD THE WORD,
LET'S MOVE, LET'S MOVE.
THREE CANNONS.
( cannons firing )
PETTY, WE'VE
GOT FlRE.
RlGHT, LET'S GO.
STAY DOWN.
MG-42s.
I'LL DRAW THElR
FlRE TO THE RlGHT
FROM THE TRUCK.
TAKE TWO MEN
AND HlT 'EM
FROM THE LEFT.
OKAY, GO.
RlGHT.
TAKE RANNEY,
ENVELOP RlGHT,
GlVE COVERlNG FlRE.
LORRAlNE,
ON THE MACHlNE-GUN.
DON'T GlVE AWAY
YOUR POSlTlON
UNTlL YOU HAVE TO.
AND I WANT THAT TNT
AS SOON AS YOU
SEE WE'VE CAPTURED
THE FlRST GUN.
GO.
YES, SlR.
I CAN'T SEE NOTHlNG.
( shouting in German )
C'MON, BUCK.
OH, SHlT!
LET'S GO!
FOLLOW ME!
OH, FUCK!
IT JUST GOT MY ASS!
SORRY, SlR.
JESUS CHRlST!
FUCKlNG JEEP JOCKEY.
SHlT, l'M SORRY, SlR.
I SCREWED UP.
GRENADE!
JOE, JOE,
ROLL ON, ROLL ON!
GOD!
SHlT.
YOU ARE ONE
LUCKY BASTARD, JOE.
GUARNERE, MALARKEY,
LORRAlNE, SECURE
THAT GUN!
COMPTON,
COVERlNG FlRE.
YES, SlR!
WHERE ARE
YOU HlT, POP?
I CAN'T BELlEVE
I FUCKED UP.
MY ASS, SlR.
YOUR ASS?
OH, SHlT.
HEY, POPEYE,
HOW BAD lS lT?
I'M SORRY, SlR,
I DlDN'T MEAN TO FUCK UP.
I DON'T THlNK
lT'S TOO BAD.
YOU THlNK YOU
CAN MAKE lT
BACK YOURSELF?
I THlNK SO, SlR.
LET'S MOVE OUT.
RlGHT,
HERE WE GO.
DROP YOUR
WEAPON, POP,
DROP YOUR WEAPON.
YEAH.
C'MON!
ONE, TWO, THREE!
GET DOWN, DlCK,
GET DOWN!
POP!
POPEYE, GET DOWN!
WlNTERS,
1 :00!
GRENADE!
TOYE!
LET'S GO!
GET OUT OF THERE!
TOYE!
JOE!
JESUS CHRlST.
FUCKlNG TWlCE.
JESUS CHRlST!
LORRAlNE, THROUGH, GO!
MALARK!
RANNEY, LET'S MOVE!
THEY'VE GOT
THE FlRST GUN.
THERE'S THE SECOND GUN.
GRENADES FlRST.
THEN KEEP GOlNG, GO!
RlGHT.
OKAY.
NlCHT SCHlEBEN!
BlTTE, NlCHT SCHlEBEN.
NO MAKE DEAD!
SHUT UP.
NlCHT SCHlEBEN!
SHUT THE FUCK UP!
NO MAKE DEAD.
STAY DOWN, STAY DOWN!
COMPTON!
ALRlGHT, COVER FOR ME.
WE MUST BE DOlNG
SOMETHlNG RlGHT.
LOOK, WE GOT 'EM
SO CONFUSED THEY'RE
FlRlNG ON THElR THlRD GUN.
WE BETTER BLOW
THlS THlNG BEFORE
THEY FlGURE OUT
WHAT THE HELL'S
HAPPENlNG.
I'M GONNA GO AND SEE
WHAT'S KEEPlNG LlPTON.
ALRlGHT.
TOYE,
COVER LlEUTENANT!
I THlNK ONE OF THOSE
DEAD KRAUTS HAS A LUGER.
SO WHAT?
KEEP YOUR HEAD LOW, PETTY.
C'MON, MOVE lT!
HAVE A LlTTLE SUPPRESSlNG
FlRE, WHY DON'T YOU?
JESUS CHRlST!
MALARKEY!
NOW YOU STOP FlRlNG?
BEAUTlFUL.
SHlT.
CHRlST, THEY MUST
THlNK HE'S A MEDlC
OR SOMETHlNG.
HE'S GONNA NEED
A GODDAMN MEDlC.
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
MALARKEY!
GET LOW!
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOlN', C'MON!
FORGOT YOUR
FRlGGlN' LUGER?
YOU WANT I SHOULD GO GET lT
FOR YOU, YOU STUPlD MlCK?
WHERE'S LlPTON
WlTH THAT TNT?
DON'T KNOW, SlR.
YOU'LL BE ALRlGHT,
POPEYE.
I'M SORRY,
I MESSED UP.
DON'T BE SORRY.
HEY, SARGE?
YOU THlNK THlS lS
A TlCKET HOME?
MAYBE.
SHlT, l
JUST GOT HERE.
HlYA, COWBOY.
SHUT YOUR FUCKlNG
GUlNEA TRAP, GONORRHEA.
HE'S ALRlGHT,
THAT KlD.
JESUS, YOU GOT A WHOLE
KRAUT PLATOON OUT THERE.
PROBABLY MORE,
CAPTAlN.
YOU NEED HELP?
I NEED AMMO, SlR,
LOTS OF lT!
AND TNT!
I'VE GOT TNT, SlR.
GOOD JOB,
PRlVATE.
HALL, READY!
SlR, I DON'T
HAVE ANY WAY TO
SET lT OFF, SlR.
FlRE lN THE HOLE!
PLESHA,
COVERlNG FlRE.
THlRD GUN, HERE!
LORRAlNE, GRAB SOME MORE
OF THOSE POTATO MASHERS
AND FOLLOW ME.
MALARKEY, HALL,
YOU TWO, GO
RUNNlNG A LlTTLE LOW
ON AMMO, SlR.
HOW ABOUT YOU,
MALARKEY?
OKAY.
THlNK YOU GOT ENOUGH
TO TAKE THE THlRD GUN?
WE'LL SOON
FlND OUT, DlCK.
MALARKEY, LET'S GO!
TOYE, COVER!
OKAY, HALL,
KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN.
HALL!
LEAVE YOUR TNT!
FlRE lN THE HOLE!
MALARKEY,
COVER THE FRONT!
GO TO THE CANNON, GO.
HEY, SARGE.
I'M LOOKlNG FOR
BATTALlON HEADQUARTERS.
ARE YOU KlDDlNG?
IT'S BACK THAT AWAY.
YOU MEAN OVER--
FlRE lN THE HOLE!
( German radio )
TNT!
DON'T NEED lT.
WHAT?
DON'T NEED lT!
HALL!
HALL?
WHERE'D HE COME FROM?
WlNTERS, HESTER SAlD
YOU NEEDED AMMO!
MALARKEY!
AS MUCH AS YOU
CAN, EVERYONE!
YOU MlND lF "D"
COMPANY TAKES A SHOT
AT THE NEXT GUN?
ALL YOURS.
LET'S GO,
DOG COMPANY!
UP AND AT 'EM,
"D" COMPANY.
COMPTON!
WHO lS THAT, SPElRS?
WHAT'S HE DOlNG
OUT OF THE TRENCH?
OH, WHAT THE HELL'S
HE DOlNG?
OH, JESUS.
SlR, HAD A LlTTLE TROUBLE
GETTlNG THROUGH
THAT FlRST FlELD.
OH, CHRlST.
WE'RE GONNA NEED lT
AT THE NEXT GUN.
ONCE lT'S BLOWN,
TELL 'EM TO PULL OUT.
GO!
YES, SlR.
COMPTON, POLlCE THEM
BOTH, THEN PULL OUT!
LORRAlNE, TOYE,
MOVE OUT!
MOVE lT OUT!
MGs FlRST.
FALL BACK TO YOUR
ORlGlNAL POSlTlONS.
EVERYONE ELSE,
MAlNTAlN YOUR BASE OF FlRE.
OKAY, BACK
TO BATTALlON!
GO, GO!
THEY WERE 1 05s,
NOT 88s, SlR.
WE DlSABLED THEM
AND PULLED OUT.
I FlGURE THERE'S
MAYBE 40 OR SO KRAUTS
STlLL MANNlNG THREE
MG-42s TO THE REAR.
HEY, POPEYE.
40?
YES, SlR.
WE KlLLED
MAYBE AROUND 20,
SO, YEAH, PROBABLY
THERE'S 40 LEFT.
I THlNK WE
NEED ARTlLLERY,
OR MAYBE MORTARS
MlGHT DO THE JOB.
GOlNG MY WAY?
SURE.
SlR.
CAREFUL, DON'T
HURT YOURSELF.
NlCE RlDE YOU
GOT HERE, NlX.
STRAlGHT
FROM UTAH BEACH.
WE SHOULD PUT 'EM TO WORK
BEFORE THEY'RE MlSSED.
( Winters )
BY NlGHTFALL,
2nd BATTALlON HAD SECURED
SAlNTE MARlE-DU-MONT,
AND ELEMENTS
OF THE 4th DlVlSlON
WERE BEGlNNlNG TO MOVE
MEN AND MATERlAL lNLAND.
MOST OF THE 1 01 st AlRBORNE,
lNCLUDlNG "EASY COMPANY",
WERE STlLL SCATTERED
ALL OVER NORMANDY,
AND THE SUCCESS OF THE
lNVASlON WAS FAR FROM CERTAlN.
WE HAD AN HOUR TO REST
AND SCROUNGE
WHATEVER FOOD WE COULD
BEFORE WE HAD
TO MOVE SOUTH
AND SECURE THE TOWN
OF COUP DE VlLLE.
( male )
I DON'T WANNA DlE lN THE BACK
OF THlS DAMN TRUCK, lS WHAT.
C'MON, YOU'RE
STEPPlNG ON MY LEGS.
JESUS, LET ME OUT OF HERE.
LlGHT, LlGHT DlSClPLlNE.
GUARNERE,
CLOSE THAT FLAP.
LET THE KRAUTS COOK
THElR OWN GODDAMN FOOD.
HOW ARE WE
DOlNG, MALARK?
WE'RE DOlNG GOOD.
DOlNG GOOD?
YEAH.
WHAT THE HELL DO
YOU KNOW ABOUT
COOKlNG, YOU'RE lRlSH.
SlR, lF YOU HAVE
A RESERVATlON
SOMEPLACE ELSE--
JUST START
DlSHlNG lT.
THANK YOU.
SHlT.
JESUS CHRlST,
GlVE ME SOME AlR.
EVENlNG.
HELLO, SlR.
DlD SOMETHlNG
DlE lN HERE?
YEAH,
MALARKEY'S ASS.
ANY WORD
ON LlEUTENANT
MEEHAN YET, SlR?
NO, NOT YET.
DON'T THAT MAKE YOU
OUR COMMANDlNG
OFFlCER, SlR?
YEAH, lT DOES.
SlR?
JOE, THE LlEUTENANT
DON'T DRlNK.
IT'S BEEN
A DAY OF FlRSTS.
DON'T YOU THlNK,
GUARNERE?
YES, SlR.
CARRY ON.
GOODNlGHT, SlR.
OH, SERGEANT?
SlR?
I'M NOT A QUAKER.
IF HE'S FROM
LANCASTER COUNTY, HE'S
PROBABLY A MENNONlTE.
WHAT'S A MENNONlTE?
HEY DlCK,
WAlT UP!
WHAT?
YOU KNOW THAT
MAP YOU FOUND?
IT HAD EVERY
KRAUT GUN lN
NORMANDY ON lT.
OH, YEAH?
YEAH.
HERE.
DON'T EVER
GET A CAT.
WHAT'S ON
YOUR MlND?
I LOST A MAN TODAY.
OH.
HALL.
THANKS.
A JOHN HALL,
NEW YORKER.
GOT KlLLED TODAY
AT BRECOURT.
I NEVER KNEW HlM.
YEAH, YOU DlD.
RADlO-OP,
506th BASKETBALL
TEAM, ABLE COMPANY.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
MAN...
NOT EVEN OLD ENOUGH
TO BUY A BEER.
NOT HUNGRY.
HEY, DlCK.
I SENT THAT MAP
UP TO DlVlSlON.
I THlNK lT'S GONNA
DO SOME GOOD.
( Winters )
THAT NlGHT I TOOK
TlME TO THANK GOD
FOR SEElNG ME THROUGH
THAT DAY OF DAYS,
AND PRAYED I WOULD MAKE lT
THROUGH "D PLUS ONE".
AND lF, SOMEHOW,
I MANAGED TO GET HOME AGAlN,
I PROMlSED GOD,
AND MYSELF,
THAT I WOULD FlND A
QUlET PlECE OF LAND SOMEPLACE
AND SPEND THE REST
OF MY LlFE lN PEACE.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOX OFFlCE
A Division of TlME WARNER
ENTERTAlNMENT COMPANY, L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNlCATlONS CENTER