Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Watch--watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!
Shinichi!
Shini--
Oh! Ohh!
Shinichi!
l do not understand...
why it must be you
to carry out this task.
My duties are clear.
As the emperor,
this problem is my responsibility.
What of your family?
Do you not have
a higher responsibility unto them?
Do not speak of such nonsense.
You are most important to me.
But the people and our land
are also my family.
l must go.
l cannot let this evil destroy us all.
My lord, the elixir is ready.
lt is the key to extinguishing
this devilry.
My lord...
Oh!
You!
Thank you!
No!
My intention was to destroy you!
Oh?
But it was your poison arrow...
and your hocus-pocus
that set me free.
Whoa!
Fool!
Nothing of this world
can harm me...
for l am Aku,
the Shogun of Sorrow...
the Deliverer of Darkness--
your new master...
and you will bow to me!
Oh!
Human fool.
l see that l must show
your world who is master.
Now gaze your eyes...
upon the full wrath
of the mighty Aku!
No!
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch--watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch--watch out
Gotta get back
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!