Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku,
the shape-shifting master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil...
but a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fools seeks to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch--Watch out
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Excuse me. l--
Uh, wait. Please.
Wait!
What?
Hello?
Hello!
Please, show yourself.
l mean no harm.
Very well.
l am leaving your doll here...
right on the--the, uh, the--
Good-bye.
Whoever you are.
Did l scare you?
Um, no.
lt's just that...
this place--
What are you doing here?
ls this your home?
Uh, what is wrong, little girl?
Nothing.
l do not think we should be here.
l think we have been here
too long already.
Ah, here we are.
lt will be good to breathe
the night-time air again.
lmpossible.
What is this?
There was a door here!
Come with me.
No!
The window's gone!
There was a window here!
And here! And here!
And here! And here! And--
l just do not understand.
How can...
l'm tired and cold.
You are right.
l, too, am feeling uncommonly weary.
Perhaps after some rest...
we shall find our way
out of this strange place.
Oh! Excuse us.
Please, won't you join us?
No! There is something wrong.
l don't understand.
Come. Have tea with us.
This is--is some sort of illusion!
Like everything in this house!
There is absolutely nothing to fear.
We are all quite real.
And you, little girl, are you an illusion?
Come. Drink the tea
if you don't believe we're real.
Please.
This is my daughter Kuni...
my son Tobi...
and my wife Yamiko.
Why, this is quite good.
Yes.
lt comes from the southern part of Edo.
Yes. l am familiar with Edo.
My family and l spent our summers there.
What has happened to your home?
And why is this room so impeccable?
Uh, there was a storm, a terrible storm.
Ah. Oh, yes. That's right.
And we have tried
to make the best of it.
lsn't that right, Tobi?
Shy children.
Tobi, why don't you tell our guest
about your studies?
Must not be feeling well.
l'm sorry.
You're alive!
Yes. lt seems l have beaten the demon...
that possessed this house.
Kuni, l am sorry.
l saw your family...
but l was not able to free them.
- Kuni?
- Papa?
Papa!
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
- Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Watch out
- Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack