Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Watch--watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!
ln appreciation
for saving our humble tribe...
from extinction
at the hands of the evil Aku...
we give you this map.
lt reveals the hidden location...
of a great source of power...
that Aku keeps locked away...
a power that can end
your quest...
and return you
to when you belong.
Many have sacrificed
to bring us this information.
You must use it wisely...
for this power source
is sealed in a fortress...
a fortress stocked
with countless guards...
to protect it against
the finest warriors...
and filled with
an array of booby traps...
to defend it against
the most cunning thieves.
Be careful...
beware...
be victorious...
if you dare.
Halt, you are under arrest.
l wouldn't do that if l were you.
You're liable to vaporize
your hands.
Who are you?
Funny. l was gonna
ask you the same.
They call me Jack.
Samurai Jack.
4,000 years...
and still every wannabe
super spy in black tights...
has to use that same old tired joke.
Ooh, l'm a dark ninja.
Sneaky-sneaky! Whoo!
You can't see me! Huh!
A little respect for the j-o-b.
Excuse me.
This thing is alarmed.
Trip the alarm...
and none of your fancy-schmancy
kung fu moves...
would have saved you.
Uh, excuse me, but--
What?
Voila! Piece of cake.
Wonderful. Thank you.
Whoa, man.
This isn't yours.
Yes, it is.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
No, it's not.
There are too many!
You got that right.
Nice meeting you.
No!
Give me the diamond.
You got to be kidding me.
Hurry. They're activating.
Wait! ln here.
Coast is clear.
Yes, it is.
This is too much.
We got to get out!
- Go!
- Cover me!
Jack!
l'm sorry.
No!
Hey, Jack!
You're welcome.
You must give me the diamond.
Can't do it, pal.
- You must.
- l can't.
Oh, boy.
Whoo!
All--all that beautiful money...
gone.
Watch out!
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!