Long ago in a distant land, l, Aku...
the shape-shifting master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Watch--Watch out
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Shh!
l'm going to get you guys.
What is that?
l do not know.
l was just going to find that out.
lt looks like some kind of tomb,
and there's a story on it.
lt says that long ago,
the evil overlord, Set...
came and unleashed
his evil minions upon the land.
None of the Great Pharaoh's armies
could stop the minions...
as they brought terror to all.
The pharaoh then called upon
a great power...
to imprison the minions here,
in this tomb...
where they will stay forever.
- Whoa!
lf the evil minions of Set were
ever to be freed of their prison...
the only salvation would be to--Wha!
What are you children
doing down here?
You know better than
to be playing in the temple!
You should be studying.
Where are your teachers?
They know you're not allowed in here,
and so do you!
Now get out of here.
Run! Go! Study.
We have found it.
Yes.
Yes. Yes!
Whoa.
Ooh.
The ancient prophecies were true.
You are most impressive...
minions of Set.
But now that l, the great Aku,
have freed you...
you owe me a service.
A samurai warrior
approaches this temple--
destroy him!
lt seems so familiar...
this place.
The minions of Set!
These creatures are more powerful
than anything l have ever encountered.
But there must be a way to destroy them.
The prophecy!
Where is it? Where is it?
Ah!
''lf the evil should ever be freed...
''your only salvation will be to summon
the protector and call the sun.
To do this, you must--''
''You must look for it
at the seat of evil.''
Seat of evil? Could it be?
Seat of evil, seat of evil.
What could that possibly be?
The statue of Set!
The scarab. lt is the key.
But how to get it?
''Look for the other half where
the moon hits the sea of reeds.''
What?
Sea of reeds?
What could that mean?
Reeds!
Sea of reeds!
That's it!
One piece remains.
You must look for your salvation
in the crown of the Great Pharaoh.
Uh, excuse me.
Thank you for destroying
the minions of Set...
but, hmm...
do you happen to know...
where there's a--ahem--time portal?
Guess not.
Accursed samurai...
you have succeeded again
in eluding my effort...
but l am not worried.
For one day, you will fail.
- Watch out
- Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch--Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out