Long ago
in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow
was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back
Back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
- Samurai Jack
- Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Watch--watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!
ls this a lodging facility?
Y-Yes.
l wish to lodge here.
OK.
Oh! This is the bed.
And this is the bathroom.
And--and this...
is the window!
ls there something wrong?
The music.
Music?
Olivia!
No, Olivia! Please!
Aw, honey,
don't you recognize me?
Olivia!
lt's me, your father.
Please snap out of it, dear.
No, honey! No!
This isn't who you are!
No, wait!
They're children!
No, Olivia! Don't go!
Come back!
Who were they?
The children...of Aku.
Aku!
Truly his evil has spread...
through even
the youngest of souls.
Yes.
My daughter was innocent once--
but she came home with this.
My little girl...
was never the same
since that night.
She became...
one of them.
Wait. Where are you going?
To free your daughter
and the rest of the children...
from Aku's evil grasp.
Somebody scream
lt's the ultimate,
l can't go for it
it's the--
Welcome...
brothers and sisters!
Can l get a kazaam?!
Kazaam!
l, DJ Salvatore...
am once again here
to drop upon you all...
the majestical,
sounderrific beats...
of the master...
Aku.
Skizz, yeah!
Let your ears feast
to the flavor...
of the Aku-stic sound!
Children of Aku!
Samurai Jack is in the house!
Jack...
And for public enemy
number one...
the scratch in Aku's groove,
Samurai Wack...
let's mix it up
with a taste of the bass...
beats in his face...
the brand-new hard-core track...
Jack Attack!
There are too many!
l must stop the music.
Oh, no!
lt won't be that easy.
Music-maker man...
your beats are bad.
That's right. They're bad!
Not bad good, bad bad!
Whatever!
Aku's control
on these innocents will stop!
Aku will never be silenced!
Let the sounds
form your ultimate destruction.
Ooh!
No!
Aku's evil music...
will be no more!
You have been
pawns of Aku's evil.
But now you are free.
Return to your homes...
and never dance
to this evil beat again.
Father?
Olivia?
- Father?
- Olivia?
Father?!
Olivia!
l'm so happy!
Thank you, stranger.
Thank you!
Watch out!
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back,
back to the past
- Samurai Jack
- Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back,
back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out