Long ago in a distant land, l, Aku...
the shape-shifting master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future,
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Watch--Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Hmm. Hmm.
Samurai, samurai.
Why won't you die?
Foolish, unknowing, innocent samurai.
Little do you know
that the path l have chosen for you...
will lead you to your doom!
Hello?
Wait, child.
Excuse me.
l don't mean to startle you...
but is it not unsafe
for you to be out so late?
Who's there?
Ha ha!
You! You there.
Wait.
l have a bad feeling about this.
Perhaps l should leave.
l am sure this is the way l came.
l will eat your soul!
What?
No!
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
The old, powerful blade of the samurai...
the only power that can harm me.
Yes, samurai.
l shall destroy this sword...
and become truly invincible.
But not before l smite thee.
Fool!
How fitting indeed...
to be destroyed by the blade
of your worthless father.
Now prepare for your destruction.
Oh, samurai.
Where are you, samurai?
You can run, but you cannot hide,
because l can smell your blood.
Forgive me, father. l have failed you.
How? How?
Even l had forgotten that the sword
was forged in purity and strength.
lt can only be used for good.
ln the hand of evil,
it can never harm an innocent...
and so, Aku, it cannot harm me...
but it can harm you.
l will get you yet, samurai!
- Watch out
- Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
- Watch out
- Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Got to get back
Back to the past, Samurai Jack
Watch--Watch out
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Watch out
Got to get back
- Jack, Jack, Jack
- Samurai Jack
- Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
- Watch--Watch out