Long ago in a distant land...
l, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior...
wielding a magic sword...
stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
l tore open a portal in time...
and flung him into the future...
where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
and undo the future that is Aku.
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Watch--watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack
Samurai Jack
You have been chosen.
A force of ultimate evil...
has resurrected itself on thy world.
This evil must be destroyed.
Only through the strength
of the human spirit...
and the virtue
of human righteousness...
can this evil be vanquished.
This blade was forged...
from the righteous energy
within thee.
lt possesses the power
to destroy this evil force.
But be warned--
this evil is not
of the human world.
lt has magic beyond
your understanding.
Trust not what you see,
but what you feel.
What is this?
What form of insect is this?
lt is you.
Yes, Aku.
Your evil cannot abolish
the power of righteousness.
Your evil grasp on my land
and its people ends now.
Have you learned nothing?
Your mortal blade cannot harm me.
How can this be?
This sword was forged...
from the strength and power
of the human spirit.
lt represents all that is good.
lts purpose is to destroy you.
Bah!
You will not escape.
Now let the sword forever banish
this evil abomination.
l will return!
We must learn from this day.
We must be prepared
should this evil ever return.
We must have a plan.
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back, back to the past
Samurai Jack
Watch out!
Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack
Gotta get back
Samurai Jack
Watch--watch out!