-No!
-Vandalay!
Say Vandalay!
No, you're way, way, way off!
Yeah, that's the right number,
but this is an apartment.
-No, say--
-Vandalay! Say--
Vandalay Industries!
Yeah, no problem, no problem.
How did you know who they wanted?!
And you want to be
my latex salesman.
Just sign here, please.
I know who it was too.
It was the guy that interviewed me.
He was very threatened by me.
Why else wouldn't he hire me?
-I could sell latex like that.
-Just sign that.
-Who is this?
-It’s my daughter.
This is your daughter?
My God!
I hope you don't mind my saying,
she is breathtaking.
You think so?
Would you take this picture away
from me? Just take it away.
Get it out of here.
Take it away, and put it away.
Let me just sign this and go.
You know...
...she doesn't even have a boyfriend.
Okay. Okay.
Who do you think you're talking to?
You trying to make a joke,
Mrs. Sokol? It’s not funny.
I can tell you that.
I’m serious. She doesn't.
You know, it's one thing to not
give me the extension.
But to tease and
to torture me like this...
...there's no call for that.
Would you like her phone number?
Mrs. Sokol,
I don't know what to say.
-Where should I sign this thing?
-No, no, no, no. Don't worry about it.
Unemployment, it's a tough thing.
Even if you get a job after
you've been unemployed...
...they take unemployment out
of your check every week...
...and show it to you in that little box.
How good can it be for your
confidence that every paycheck...
...has the word ''unemployment''
on it?
Can't get it out of your mind!
You just got the job!
They're already getting ready
for you to be laid off.
I have a friend who's unemployed.
He's collecting unemployment
insurance.
This guy has never worked this hard
in his life to keep this thing going.
He's down there every week waiting
on the lines and getting interviewed...
...and making up all these lies
about looking for jobs.
lf they had any idea the effort
and energy that he is expending...
...to avoid work, I’m sure they'd give
him a raise. I’m sure of it.
The guy is doing a tremendous job...
...not working.
So tell me more
about this game six.
Well, there was two outs,
bottom of the tenth.
We're one out away
from losing the series.
Hello. How are you?
So, what do you think?
Do you love her?
Yes, I do love her.
You have a very nice place here.
So who do you think she looks like?
Lyndon Johnson.
What? Lyndon Johnson?
He's joking.
No, I’m not joking.
She looks like Lyndon Johnson.
Jerry, I can't believe it took you
so long to see the baby.
I kept saying to Michael, ''When is
Jerry going to see the baby?''
I was saying the same thing.
Take a picture.
Michael, get the camera.
-You don't have to take a picture.
-I don't know where it is.
It’s in the bottom drawer
of our dresser.
Hurry up!
He's such an idiot.
Jerry, you want to pick her up?
-I better not.
-I’ll pick her up.
No!
Thank you for a wonderful time,
George.
Glad you enjoyed it.
I haven't had a Big Mac
in a long time.
Billions and billions.
Would you like to come up?
Would I like to come up?
I would love to come up.
I’m...I’m fighting not to.
Fighting.
Unfortunately, l...
...I have to get an early start tomorrow.
Gotta get up and hit that pavement.
But it's Saturday.
All the offices are closed.
I got me an appointment
with a hardware store.
I’m not saying I want to do it
for the rest of my life...
...but hardware fascinates me.
Wouldn't you love to make a key?
Will you call me as soon
as you get home?
-Tonight?
-Yes.
Will I call you when I get home?
What do you think?
You kill me. You really kill me.
Well, good night.
It was an accident. Right, Jerry?
It was an accident.
Oh, she's gonna be all right.
Here, baby. Here.
Here, baby.
Baby, baby, baby.
Who's the baby?
I have a friend who's got a baby.
''Gotta see the baby.
You've got to come over
and see the baby.''
Nobody ever wants you to come over
and see their grandfather, do they?
''You've got to see my grandfather.
You've got to see him.
He's so cute.
1 68 pounds, 4 ounces.
I love them when they're this age.
He's 1 000 months.
You know, the mid 80s is such
a good time for the grand-people.
The mid 80s, you gotta see them.
He went to the bathroom
by himself today.''
You know what's tough about seeing
people when they have a baby...
...is that you have to match
their level of enthusiasm.
You know what I mean?
They're always so excited.
''What do you think of him?''
I’d like to meet a couple that goes:
''You know, we're not that happy
with him, frankly.
I think we really made a big mistake.
We should have got an aquarium.
You want him? We don't even
want him. You want him?''
Thanks for a nice evening.
This was really fun.
Yeah, it was.
Gosh, should I kiss her good night?
Is he going to try and kiss me?
-I love Cajun cooking.
-Really?
You know, my mom's
one-quarter Cajun.
Oh, my father's half-drunk.
Maybe they should get together.
Go ahead. Kiss her.
I'm a baseball player, damn it.
What's he waiting for?
I thought he was a cool guy.
Come on. I won the MVP in '7 9.
I can do whatever I want to.
Well, this is getting awkward.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Who does this guy think he is?
I'm Keith Hernandez.
Who else?
Mookie. Mookie was there.
You know him?
Well, I don't know him.
I know who he is.
He's such a great guy.
You should meet him.
-He's the one who got that hit--
-I know. He got the hit in game six!
So then what happened?
Nothing. The he took me home.
So did you two...
...have....
What?
You know.
Milk?
-No.
-Cookies?
Did he kiss you good night?
I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know?
All right. He kissed me, okay?
Well, what kind of a kiss?
Was it a peck? Was it a kiss?
Was it a long make-out thing?
Between a peck and a make-out.
So you like him.
I don't understand.
Before you were jealous of me.
Now you're jealous of him?
I’m jealous of everybody.
Hello.
Oh, hi. What's happening?
What?
Sure.
Yeah, okay.
Then.... I’ll see you then.
Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Bye.
-Who was that?
-That was Keith.
-What's going on?
-He wants me to help him move.
Help him move?
Move what?
You know, furniture.
So, what did you say?
I said, yes, but I don't feel right
about it.
I mean, I hardly know the guy.
That's a big step
in a male relationship.
The biggest.
That's like going all the way.
And you feel you're not
really ready for--
Well, we went out one time.
Don't you think that's coming on
a little too strong?
Hey.
What's going on?
Keith Hernandez just asked me
to help him move.
What?
Well, you hardly know the guy.
What a nerve!
You see? Wasn't I right
about this guy? Didn't I tell you?
Oh, you're not gonna do it, are you?
-I said, yes.
-You said yes?!
Don't you have any pride
or self-respect?
I mean, how can you prostitute
yourself like this?
Are you gonna start driving him
to the airport?
I’m not driving him to the airport.
Oh, boy. I don't know.
-Kramer, do me a favor, would you?
-What?
Don't mention it to anybody.
I wish you never mentioned it to me.
I had a great time tonight, Carrie.
And I will call you
as soon as I get home.
Don't bother.
Bother? What kind of bother?
I would prefer it if you didn't.
-Why? Is anything wrong?
-It’s over, buddy. Done.
Finished. So long. Goodbye.
Adios. Sayonara.
-Why?
-I’ve been thinking about it.
You got no job.
You got no prospects.
You're like Biff Loman.
I went to the hardware store
interview.
You think I’m going to spend my life
with somebody...
...because he can get me a deal
on a box of nails?
I thought we were a team.
lf I ever need a drill bit, I’ll call you.
Carrie, could you do me a favor?
Could you not mention this
to your mother?
You know, I hate to brag...
...but I did win 11 straight
Gold Gloves.
I wouldn't have brought it up,
but since you mentioned it.
I didn't mention it.
Well, I won them anyway.
Well, so what? I mean...
...you played first base.
I mean, they always put
the worst player at first base.
That's where they put me,
and I stunk.
Elaine, you don't know the first thing
about first base.
Well, I know something
about getting to first base...
...and I know you'll never be there.
The way I figure it,
I’ve already been there.
And I plan on rounding second
tonight at around 11:00.
Well, I’d watch the third-base coach
if I were you...
...because I don't think
he's waving you in.
You know, I hate to say this...
...but I really think that
we're hitting it off.
-Get it? Get it?
-Clever.
-What are you doing?
-What's that?
-You smoke?
-Yeah.
I didn't know you smoked.
Is that a problem?
She likes him.
I mean, she really likes him.
-How do you know?
-Who wouldn't like him?
I like him, and I’m a guy.
I suppose he's an attractive man.
Forget that. He's a ballplayer.
MVP, 1 9 79.
I’m making wisecracks in some
nightclub. This guy was in game six.
They're a perfect match.
They go together.
Like one of these brother and sister
couples that look alike.
I hate those couples. I could never be
one of those couples.
There are no bald women around,
you know.
I know this sounds a little arrogant,
but I never thought she'd find...
...someone she liked better
than me. But, you know...
...I guess I had my chance.
And that's that.
You know what I’d like to do?
I’d really like to have sex
with a tall woman.
I mean really tall, like a giant.
Like 6'5''.
Really?
What was the tallest woman
you ever slept with?
I don't know, 6'3''.
Wow! God!
See, this is all I think about:
Sleeping with a giant.
It’s my life's ambition.
So I guess it's fair to say you've set
different goals for yourself than...
...say, Thomas Edison, Magellan,
these type of people.
Magellan? You like Magellan?
Oh, yeah. My favorite explorer.
Around the world. Come on.
-Who do you like?
-I like de Soto.
-De Soto? What did he do?
-Discovered the Mississippi.
Oh, like they wouldn't have found
that anyway.
All right. I gotta go down
to the unemployment office.
-You want to take a walk?
-No, I got some stuff to do.
I gotta meet Keith at my apartment
at 3. I’m helping him move.
What?
The guy asked you to help him move?
Wow!
-I know. Isn’t that something?
-Why doesn't he just pay a mover?
He's got some valuable antiques.
He's worried they'll break something.
Soon he'll have you driving him
to the airport.
I’m not driving him to the airport!
I gave. I gave everything I could,
Mrs. Sokol.
-Nothing was good enough for her.
-Sign here, please.
I don't know who she's looking for.
I don't know.
I’ll tell you, she's very particular,
your daughter. Very particular.
Is she looking for some
big hotshot businessman?
Well, I’ve got my pride too.
I’m not gonna beg her.
All right. Just sign it.
People are waiting.
You like baseball?
That was autographed
by the '86 Mets.
I saw every inning that year.
It’s funny, because I happen to be
very good friends with...
...Keith Hernandez.
You know Keith Hernandez.
Know him?
Would you...like to meet him?
Oh, come on. Come on.
I can produce Keith Hernandez,
right here...
...within the hour.
All right.
You got one hour.
All right, Mrs. S.
I and my good pal
Keith Hernandez...
...will be right back.
1 29 West 81 st Street, and hurry.
Or not.
You better bring your gloves.
It’s freezing out there.
It shouldn't take too long.
I’d say maybe, oh, four hours.
Really, Jerry, there's not that much.
First, we got the bedroom.
We got two dressers and the bed.
-Is there a box spring?
-What's that?
-A box spring?
-Yeah, there's a box spring.
But it's attached to the headboard,
and we'll have to take that apart.
Then we got the couch.
-Is that a sectional?
-Yeah, 1 2 pieces.
-A marble coffee table.
-Is that a thick marble?
Three inches thick.
Got it in Italy.
But the big problem is gonna be
the convertible sofa.
When you move it,
it tends to open up...
...so it's going to be difficult
getting it downstairs.
Stairs?
-There's no elevator?
-No, it's a brownstone. Three floors.
-I’m sorry, I can't do this.
-What?
I can't do it! I can't!
It’s too soon.
I don't know you.
I can't help you move, I’m sorry.
I can't! I just can't.
-Hello.
Oh, you don't remember me.
-No. Should l?
-Yeah, yeah, you should...
...because I certainly remember you.
Let me refresh your memory.
June 1 4th, 1 98 7.
Mets-Phillies. You made a big error.
Cost the Mets the game.
Then you're coming up
the parking lot ramp.
You said, ''Nice game, pretty boy.''
-You remember.
-And then you spit on us.
-Hey, I didn't spit at you.
-Yeah, right.
-No, no. Then who was it?
-Look, the way I remember it...
...I was walking up the ramp.
I was upset about the game.
That's when you called me
''pretty boy. ''
Hey, that ticked me off.
I was turning to say something...
...and as I turned around...
...I saw Roger McDowell behind
the bushes over by that gravelly road.
Anyway, he was talking to someone,
and they were pointing at you.
I tried to scream out,
but it was too late.
It was already on its way.
I told you.
-It was McDowell.
-But why? Why McDowell?
Maybe because we were sitting
in the right-field stands...
...cursing at him in the bullpen
all game.
He must have caught a glimpse of us
when I poured that beer on his head.
-It was McDowell.
-Oh, boy.
-Look, Keith, we're sorry.
-Yeah, I couldn't be sorrier.
Guys, don't worry about it.
-Well, I guess I better get going.
-What are you doing?
-I gotta move.
-You want any help?
-I’d love some. You sure?
-I’d love to help you.
Yeah, me too!
Okay, guys. We got to be careful
of one thing.
Some of the stuff is very fragile
We'll have to handle it like a baby.
Hey, no sweat.
Hello.
Oh, hi, Elaine. What's going on?
No, he just left.
You broke up with him?
Me too!
What happened?
Oh, smoking. You know, you're like
going out with C. Everett Koop.
Me? No.
I couldn't go through with it.
I just didn't feel ready.
So, what are you doing now?
Oh, great idea. Okay.
I’ll meet you there in, like,
30 minutes.
Okay, bye.
Keith! Keith!
-What happened? Where's Keith?
-You just missed him. He just left.
What do you need him for?
Keith! Keith! Up here!
Look, could you do me a favor?
I need you to go to the
unemployment office with me!
l-- I’m Jerry's friend!
The guy from the locker room!
I’m the chucker!
It'll take five minutes!
Wait! Wait!
Well, Biff...
...what's next?
I don't know.
Excuse me.
I was walking behind you, and you...
...dropped your wallet.
When you're moving,
your whole world becomes boxes.
That's all you think about,
is boxes. Where are there boxes?
You just wander down the street,
going in and out of stores.
''Are there boxes here?
Have you seen any boxes?''
I mean, you can't even talk to people
because you can't concentrate.
''Shut up! I’m looking for boxes!''
So after a while, you become
really into it. You can smell them.
You walk into a store:
''There's boxes here.
Don't tell me you don't have boxes.
Damn it! I can smell them!''
You become, like, obsessed.
'‘I love the smell of cardboard
in the morning.''
At a funeral, everyone's crying around.
You're looking at the casket:
''That's a nice box.
Does anybody know where
that guy got that box?
When he's done with it,
you think I could get that?
It’s got some nice handles on it.''
And that's what death is, really.
It’s the last big move of your life.
The hearse is like the van.
The pallbearers are close friends.
The only ones you could really ask
to help you with a big move like that.
And the casket is that great,
perfect box...
...you've been looking for
your whole life.
The only problem is
once you find it, you're in it.