Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
lt is impossible.
That is my hat.
Yes.
Thank you.
May l ask where you are headed?
lt appears very difficult.
Yes.
What is at the peak of this mountain?
Truth.
Truth?
Legend has it there lies a great power
at the summit of Fatoom.
We three have trained for a lifetime
to climb this mountain...
...and achieve its power.
That is, of course, if it exists.
You see, no one has ever reached
the summit of Fatoom.
Not yet.
You go on and collect your rocks.
l will handle this.
Goatman, please let us pass.
Good. lt is all clear.
The path is clear.
lt is all right to contin--
Wait, please.
Wait.
Wait for me.
lt is impossible.
Do you give up?
Will you abandon their hope?
Can you not feel their desperation?
Will evil forever rule the world?
Have you forgotten?
No. l have not forgotten.
Thank you, mountain monks.
Thank you.
Aku!
l will never give up!
l will return to the past and destroy you!
[ENGLlSH]