Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Turn back while you still....
Poor unfortunate creature.
-l'm not poor!
-What?
l might be unfortunate,
but l'm not poor.
Look at my necklace.
That's genuine fox tooth, that is.
-You're alive.
-Of course l'm alive...
...but that's no reason to call me poor.
Tell me, where is this horrible stench
coming from?
You must mean the stench
that ruined our crops...
...that rendered generations
of backbreaking labor...
...completely and utterly useless, that--
Yes, that stench.
They say.... They say it comes from--
Oh, mother of mercy....
To the shelter! To the shelter!
Tell me, villager.
How far is it to this shelter?
Right around the next block. Hurry!
lt's right over here.
Oh, good gracious, help us out!
The shelter, it's full!
Mother of mercy....
Scissorsmith. Scissorsmith!
How can you be so cheerful
while your town lives in such misery?
Somebody say something?
l was simply wondering how you--
Never mind.
A customer. Top of the morning to you.
-Actually, l--
-Right this way. Right this way.
Just keep that door shut.
Keep that miserable smell out.
Fresh sausages,
only three for a ninepence.
No, thank you. Actually,
l was wondering about that smell outside.
Then it's a rag you want.
We've got burlap ones, flannel ones,
seersucker, gabardine!
Have you had your palm read lately?
Got any pets who need grooming?
How about some flint and tinder?
Never know when you'll need some fire--
Fire! Rhymes with liar!
Liar!
Quiet, you!
-Your pet speaks very well.
-My pet? That's my wife!
Never sell a wizard
an expired fishing license.
How about some pickled camel feet?
No, thank you. l just want to know
where that stench is coming from.
Then it's information that you're after.
-So you'll tell me?
-For a price.
But the lives of your fellow villagers
are at stake.
Come with me.
Look up there.
Now, do you see the words
''free information'' anywhere on that sign?
-No.
-Try using this magnifying glass.
-See it now?
-No.
Well, that's because
l don't sell free information!
Enough of this foolishness! You will tell me
where the stench comes from, now!
All right, l'll tell you for a loaf of bread
and a ride on a wagon.
Wagon! Rhymes with dragon! Dragon!
Quiet! You'll give it all away!
Give what away? What dragon?
Nothing. There's no dragon.
Dragon! Dragon!
The smell comes from a dragon!
Why, you....
So where does this dragon live?
Nowhere. l'll never tell.
You're beginning to arouse my ire.
Spire! Lives on top of the spire!
You mangy pigeon,
l'll have you for dinner!
So tell me, wise crow,
where might l find this spire?
You ungrateful beast.
You'd better keep that beak shut.
l mean it!
Looks like that shut her up.
Beast? Beast?
The spire lies to the east!
To the east!
That's it!
You've squawked your last squawk!
-Get back here, you mangy bag of germs!
-So the spire lies to the east, eh?
Wait! Warrior!
Warrior, wait!
l have something for you!
Warrior, do you really mean
to fight this dragon?
lf l have to, yes.
Then you'll need this.
l've had enough of your bartering.
This one's on me.
Sheep's bladder.
lt'll help you breathe up there
in those fumes.
Place it over your head like this
and breathe calmly.
lf you have any small children with you,
secure your mask first, then the child's.
You will find exits located
to the east and south end of the cabin.
Beverages will be served shortly.
Thank you?
Just take care of that dragon.
Years ago,
l lost a daughter to that beast.
At the fork in the road,
follow the rocky path.
lt will take you to the dragon's lair.
-Where will the other one take me?
-''Space Ace'' !
Whoa!
The pain.
You can talk?
Yes.
You must help me.
Yes, l will help you, dragon.
l will put you out of your misery.
No, wait.
You don't understand.
There's something inside me
that is causing this.
lnside of you?
Those poor....
Those unfortunate people.
All right, dragon, l will help you.
Yes.
You have to enter me...
...and destroy
whatever is responsible for this.
Dragon?
Am l near the source of the problem?
No. You must go lower.
lt's a baby.
A baby dragon.
Please hurry.
l cannot stand much more.
Thank you.
Look!
Huzzah!
Well, l gotta hand it to you, robed one.
l never thought you'd get rid
of that stench.
Hooray, the smell is gone!
We're saved!
Hooray! At last, we can breathe again!
Now all l have to do
is put out these fires.
For the right price,
l can tell you how to put out this fire.
Liar! Fire rhymes with liar!
Why, you....
You rotten, dusty bag of germs!
l'll tear every feather out of you!
[ENGLlSH]