Long ago, in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
l just crushed your dumb old car
with my super-cool bike.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Come on. Everyone knows a bike
could never smash a car, dumb.
Time out, dudes!
Now, you listen here, dudes.
We got a respect-for-private-property
thing going on here...
...that don't involve flying around
at top speed...
...on them motorcycles,
smashing windows.
What's this? A hero?
l like him. He's got spunk.
Release him.
Who in the--?
You have insulted my footwear.
My sandals don't like to be laughed at.
Get him!
That's right. Come to--
Come on, boys.
This fool isn't worth our time.
Nice moves, dude. l like your style.
l can honestly say that l have never seen
anyone champion the ideals...
...of shoemanship with such
heartfelt ''game,'' if l may.
l gotta confess, l'm kind of feeling
a kindred spiritual kind of bond...
...kind of thing here with you. Because l,
like you, understand the importance...
...of the proper footwear
in our everyday performance.
And if l might be so bold, you, sir,
are in need of a new pair.
Since you were such a bro
about helping me out of that jam...
...l'll give you for free, at no additional
charge, your pick of any shoe...
...at the world-famous Foot-Chalet.
Get a load of those legs!
Hey, good-looking, we'll be back
to pick you up later.
-Check out them stems.
-Say, sweet thing, let me get your number.
-Oh, my goodness. Oh, my goodness.
-Oh, no, she didn't. Do you believe that?
Oh, girl, look at you.
Baby, baby!
Oh, baby, you looking good.
l'm gonna have to lose weight
or something.
Shoot, l ain't mad at you, sweetie.
Do your thing, girl.
That's right, girl. You gotta work
what you got. You know what l'm saying?
Any luck, dude?
l almost forgot about these.
They just arrived.
Utilizing the latest technologies.
Air foam, transposit shock-absorbing
double-wishbone...
...5.1 -digital-surround suspension--
Well, whatever, dude! They're the newest,
latest ones. Let's try them on.
Easy now.
Make me proud, brother.
Those-- Where did you--? How--? Wait!
Excuse me. Pardon me. Young boy, wait!
Boy! Come back! Wait!
l saw Samurai Jack! l saw Samurai Jack!
-Excuse me. l--
-No, no. Sorry. Shop is closed.
You come back tomorrow. lt is dinnertime.
l am closing shop. We open at 6 tomorrow.
You-- You.
You are the samurai.
Samurai Jack.
lt is an honor that you
would grace my humble garage.
-To what do l owe this great privilege?
-l don't mean to trouble you...
...but l was wondering--
Where to find dinner?
Right here, my friend.
My wife is cooking as we speak.
Thank you, but there are villains
at large that l must deal with.
Oh, there are always villains. But you
cannot defeat them on an empty stomach.
Now, come. lt will be a great honor
if you'd join my family for dinner.
Come, come.
l saw Samurai Jack! l saw Samurai Jack!
l saw Samurai Jack!
Did not. Like, l'm sure.
l know. He's such a little dorf-norb.
lt's like--
Ladies.
Oh, my gosh. He's so handsome.
Dear, set another place at the table.
We have a guest.
Did you bring home another
oily jet-car pilot again? l swear, if you--
-Oh, Samurai Jack.
-Madam, please excuse my intrusion.
No, no. Please, please.
Welcome to our table.
Thank you. Your home is wonderful.
Perhaps this is the time machine
l have been seeking.
We feel it is important
to remember the old ways.
We try to honor our ancestors
by keeping traditions from the old land...
...and by retelling the old stories.
And the new stories.
Yeah, your stories.
He came back, back from the past
Samurai Jack
We know you'll beat Aku someday,
Mr. Jack. You're the greatest.
Yes. Your legend is an inspiration
to all who live under the heel of Aku.
Please, if there is any way
we can help you, just ask.
Well, l wanted to ask
about your son's shoes.
Thank you so much, my friend.
l wish l could repay you some--
[ENGLlSH]