Long ago in a distant land...
...I, Aku, the shape-shifting
master of darkness...
...unleashed an unspeakable evil.
But a foolish samurai warrior
wielding a magic sword...
...stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck...
...I tore open a portal in time,
and flung him into the future...
...where my evil is law.
Now the fool seeks
to return to the past...
...and undo the future that is Aku.
Long ago, he came to us
in our time of need.
His name was Jack.
Nothing would be the same.
-You have won.
-No, we have not.
Come. We go to meet the king.
My lord.
My king.
Did you hold the right flank?
We suffered many casualties,
but held our position.
Your numbers have dwindled.
l fear you will not survive
another attack.
No, my king. We will never give up.
We will fight.
Yes. l know you will not fail me.
Brotok, who is this you bring before me?
My king, this is the stranger
who aided me in battle.
This battle is of no concern to you.
Why did you fight?
l saw this warrior outnumbered.
l meant no disrespect. l apologize.
Wait! These years of war have made
my words harsh and my tone insolent.
Any man brave enough
to face these monsters is a friend.
What is this war?
Long ago, a mechanical beast
went mad...
...and waged war against all in its path.
It feeds off the land itself...
...growing larger, powerful.
All the neighboring kingdoms have fallen.
We are the last.
The beast desperately wants our lands...
...for our home is beautiful...
...peaceful...
...rich in resources.
The beast and its robots
would have destroyed us ages ago...
...but our land is protected
by the tallest of mountains...
...and a narrow ravine
is the only entrance.
It was there, with only 300 men,
that we stopped the beast,s armies.
The position was easy to defend...
...and their superior numbers
were made worthless.
Year after year, the war went on.
But the battle became a stalemate...
...for this creature strips
the battlefield clear of its fallen...
...to rebuild its army again and again.
And so it goes.
And I am the fifth king
to defend this gateway.
And tomorrow will bring the same.
There is another way.
What do you mean?
There is a path through the mountains.
-What?
-How?
-Tell us about it.
-How can that be?
How wide is this path?
Wide enough to move through sideways,
weapons held in front and behind.
-How long to complete the journey?
-Half a day.
-Will you show us this path?
-Of course.
This war ends now!
Fifty of my best men will join me
in a strike against the beast itself...
...while the rest stay here
and defend our position.
While the monsters attack us,
we will attack them!
You must stay.
But l must be at your side.
l need you here.
For if anything should happen to me,
you will be king, my son.
l will not fail you, Father.
Forward, my brothers!
Look. There.
The last of its army has left.
Our time has come!
Spears ready!
Fire!
Porcupine!
Disperse!
The war was finally over...
...but the warrior was gone.
His shield was all that was left.
This stranger who became a brother...
...aided us in our time of need
and made a difference.
His sacrifice, and that of the others...
...defeated our enemy, saved our lands
and ensured our freedom.
They will be honored
and remembered forever...
...the 300 plus one.
But l believe the one survived.
A warrior that great...
...could not be stopped so easily.
[ENGLlSH]