Only one creature has carved a life
for itself in every habitat on Earth.
That creature is us.
All over the world, we still use our
ingenuity to survive in the wild places,
far from the city lights,
face to face with raw nature.
This is the Human Planet.
(DOGS BARK)
At the top of our planet lies
one of the most remote places on Earth.
The Arctic.
In winter, the region is frozen
and dark for months on end.
There are no trees
and there are no plants to eat.
We humans weren't built to withstand
a landscape as hostile as this.
And yet four million people live here.
Their survival relies upon
an intimate knowledge of this,
the most hostile habitat on Earth.
(SHOUTS)
(HOWLS)
The beginning of a new arctic year.
After months of winter darkness, the sun
finally returns to this frozen land.
(BELL CHIMES)
For the Inuit of Saattut, Greenland,
the sun's return marks the beginning
of their hunting calendar.
Now that the residents have enough
daylight, a world of opportunity opens up.
They can embark on expeditions
far from town...
...travelling across the thousands
of kilometres of sea ice
that lead to their hunting grounds.
(HOWLS)
Today, Amos Jensen and his son
Karl-Frederik have to feed their dogs.
(DOGS HOWL)
Their dogs are essential.
At this time of year, the dogsled
is their only means of transportation.
Because their hunting trip
could take some time,
father and son will need
a few comforts of home,
or even home itself.
To find the most nutritious dog food,
Amos and Karl-Frederik need to travel
many kilometres across the sea ice.
What they're after is a real-life
arctic sea monster, a Greenland shark.
To support their weight, the ice
only needs to be five centimetres thick,
about two inches.
This ice is nearly a metre thick,
and it could support a jumbo jet.
- (THEY PANT)
- (DOGS BARK)
Amos knows that Greenland sharks
are partial to whale meat.
And he also knows
they live in the deepest waters.
Now, both men and dogs have to wait
for something to take the bait.
(DOGS WHINE)
As temperatures plummet
to -35 degrees Celsius,
the dogs'thick fur keeps them warm.
(HOWLS)
But without their hut, Amos
and Karl-Frederik would freeze to death.
(DOGS BARK)
It's time to check
if the dogs will eat today.
From the vibrations
he feels on the fishing line,
he knows they've hooked something.
But he won't know if it's a shark
until they pull it up.
It's down so deep
they have to stretch their fishing line
along the ice in hundred-metre lengths.
They pull their catch up
a staggering 800 metres,
nearly twice the height
of the Empire State Building.
They've caught the Greenland shark
they were hoping for.
The Greenland shark
is the only native arctic shark.
It's one of the largest predators
in these seas.
Researchers have found caribou
and even polar bears in its stomach.
(CHUCKLING)
The shark has accidentally wrapped
the fishing line round its tail.
It's not the normal way to land a shark,
but a catch is a catch.
(CHATTER)
Amos and Karl
can't lift the shark by themselves
so they enlist the help of the dogs.
(DOGS BARK)
(SHOUTS)
This shark is four metres long,
weighs over half a ton
and is the largest they've ever caught.
But it will only feed their 20 dogs
for two weeks.
(DOGS BARK)
For Greenlanders,
it is essential to have well-fed dogs
if they're to continue
hunting and fishing.
Here in the Arctic, the bond
between man and dog is so important.
It's unlikely we would have colonised
this habitat without our best friends.
As the year moves on,
so does the quest for survival.
Even though it's March, the Arctic Ocean
is still dominated by sea ice.
An area four times the size
of the United States is frozen over.
The ice connects Europe to Russia,
and Russia to North America.
And here in the Canadian Arctic,
people have a unique insight
into what lies beneath the ice.
In Kangiqsujjuaq, northeast Canada,
Lukasi Nappaaluk is watching the tides.
Tomorrow, the spring equinox will create
the most extreme tides of the year,
and a spectacular opportunity for a meal.
The neap tide literally opens a door
for a garden of seafood
just below the ice.
You just need to know where to find it.
Lukasi and his friends
prefer snowmobiles to dogsleds.
And they don't bother
to bring along a shelter either.
Everything they need to protect
themselves from the elements
is right beneath their feet.
Even if it's -45 degrees Celsius outside,
body warmth can heat an igloo
to a balmy +1 6,
a full 60 degrees warmer.
Cosy inside their igloo,
Lukasi and his friends must now wait.
Before they can hunt,
something extraordinary has to happen.
Underneath the sea ice,
the tide is going out...
...and out.
The floating ice drops a staggering
1 2 metres, nearly 40 feet,
exposing the seabed, and,
hopefully, the bounty they're after.
Lukasi and his friends try to get
under the ice as quickly as possible.
They have just half an hour
before the tide comes back in.
The world beneath their feet is unstable.
The giant blocks of ice
are no longer supported by water
and could collapse at any moment.
This is the only place on Earth
where the tides are extreme enough
to allow people to dare venture
under the sea ice.
And in a chamber
that moments ago was underwater,
they find what they're looking for.
Mussels.
All they could hope for.
Now they have just minutes
to gather all they can carry.
The returning tide
is an unstoppable force.
As the sea steadily flows back,
it lifts the huge blocks of ice
over their heads.
Even as they escape,
the ice shifts around them.
The ocean reclaims its secret garden.
Lukasi can only harvest mussels
for the few days of extreme tides.
Mussels are a delicious way
to break up a diet
that during winter
has been mainly seal meat and fish.
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER)
But summer is on the way,
and everything is about to change.
By June, the sun finally pushes
temperatures above zero.
The sea ice begins to melt.
(BIRDSONG)
And as it breaks apart,
it triggers an annual summer migration.
(WHALE SONG)
(GROWLS AND GRUNTS)
Animals that have spent
the winter far offshore
follow the melting ice
into the bays and fjords.
For arctic hunters,
this creates a unique opportunity.
(HUNTERS SHOUT)
Mamarut Kristiansen,
and his brothers Mikele and Gedion,
are Thule Inuit from northern Greenland.
They're rushing to keep the most important
appointment in their hunting calendar.
They must be punctual.
In just a few weeks, the sea ice
they're travelling on will melt away.
Their goal is the most precious food
in the Arctic.
Narwhal.
These legendary whales
are looking for a way into the bay.
This is a mythic creature...
(SHOUTS)
...but it is also a source
of the rarest vitamin in the Arctic.
Vitamin C.
In a landscape
with so few edible fruits or plants,
the Inuit don't have alternatives.
(BIRDSONG)
Spotting narwhal is hard enough.
Even scientists who study them
rarely see them.
But if Mikele is going to catch one,
the narwhal will have to swim
a great deal closer than this.
It could be weeks before
the three brothers see narwhal again.
But they have to stay alert,
and there's plenty to prepare.
In this region, the law states that
hunters can only use traditional methods.
This means travelling in kayaks, a craft
the Inuit invented thousands of years ago,
and using the avatak, a buoy
made from the skin of a ring seal.
Even though it's midnight,
the sun still shines.
In June, the sun simply circles the sky,
never dipping below the horizon.
It's vital that one of them
stands guard at all times.
But Gedion isn't just looking for narwhal.
He's watching the ice.
(DOGS BARK)
Already it's thinning and breaking apart.
If they're not careful,
the brothers could find themselves
adrift on a melting piece of ice.
Mamarut and Gedion know not to panic.
Narwhal are extremely skittish,
so the hunters enter the water with care.
The three brothers work as a team.
They're afterjust one whale.
It's an ambush.
The narwhal pass
within 50 feet of Mikele...
...but still all three hunters wait.
If he strikes too soon,
the whole pod will dive.
His eye is on the stragglers
bringing up the rear.
Especially in the final approach,
Mikele must be silent...
...and directly behind his prey.
(SHOUTING)
(CHATTER)
Their success will benefit
the whole community.
The single narwhal will feed
their families for weeks, if not months.
The most prized part
of the narwhal is the skin.
They call it muktuk.
It's their primary source of vitamin C.
Ounce for ounce, narwhal skin contains
almost as much vitamin C as oranges.
Without narwhal,
it's doubtful the Inuit would ever
have survived in this part of the Arctic.
It's now July,
and the sun finally wins its battle.
The sea ice melts into open ocean.
To find food,
man turns his attention to the land.
Siorapaluk, Greenland, is the northernmost
native settlement on Earth.
Every year, Maassannguaq Oshima
is treated to a spectacle.
Millions of little auks on migration.
They come here to breed on the cliffs.
And for predators,
there's a mouth-watering supply
of protein whizzing overhead.
If you can reach it.
Thousands of years ago,
Maassannguaq's ancestors worked out how
to make nets out of sinew and driftwood.
And they created the same hiding spots
he uses today.
On a good day, Maassannguaq
can gather up to 500 birds.
But he won't eat them now.
He'll take his cue from a fellow hunter.
Arctic foxes often stuff
a few birds underground,
so that when times are lean,
they'll have food to fall back on.
The birds can be used to make kiviak,
a dish that you save for a rainy day.
The recipe is thousands of years old,
and it goes like this.
Take one seal skin.
Stuff as many little auks inside it
as you can.
At least 500.
Sew it up.
Make sure you press all the air out.
Seal fat repels flies,
so be generous when coating the seams.
And finally, use a big rock
to make sure no more air gets in.
Maassannguaq's kiviak
won't be ready for three months,
but the frozen ground
is a natural refrigerator.
Come winter, he and his family
will have a vital supply of food.
It's now September.
Days are getting shorter
and temperatures are plummeting.
The few plants that have managed
to grow over the short arctic summer
are dying back.
This is exactly what is happening
on Arnoy island, northern Norway.
3,000 reindeer
have been grazing here all summer.
But now they have to move,
because their winter food source, lichen,
can only be found 450 kilometres away.
And to get to it, they'll have to
cross this, the Arnoy strait.
(SHOUTS)
Elle-Helene Siri is in charge of leading
these reindeer across the water.
She belongs to a family
of Sami reindeer herders.
Before the migration begins,
Elle helps split the deer
into smaller groups
so they can give them vital medicine.
(SHOUTS)
On the day she was born,
Elle was given a portion of this herd.
Now aged 20, and a recent graduate
of Norway's reindeer college,
it's up to her to make sure they all
survive the perilous journey ahead.
It will take nearly a month for these deer
to migrate to their winter pastures.
But today is the toughest day of all,
because the deer have to swim two
and a half kilometres across the channel.
(COWBELLS CHIME DULLY)
(REINDEER GRUNT)
These chilly arctic waters
are only just above freezing.
Even for adult reindeer
this is a long swim.
But for this year's calves,
which have never been in the water before,
it's a marathon.
(SHIP HORN BLARES)
As the young calves approach
the halfway point, exhaustion sets in.
For Elle, it's a tense moment...
...because if one calf turns around
and swims back, the rest could follow.
A baby female is in trouble,
and suddenly, she turns back.
Elle must stop her
or the whole migration could derail.
She's done it.
The migration remains on track.
After an hour of hard swimming,
Elle and her reindeer reach the mainland.
It won't be long
before Elle's deer will be grazing
on the lichen they need
to get them through the winter.
And it's not just animals
looking for a meal at this time of year.
(CHATTER)
In Greenland, Maassannguaq and his father
are already breaking into
the caches of little auks
they stored up in the summer.
The birds have now fermented and have
become the Inuit delicacy known as kiviak.
It's easy to tell if your kiviak is ready
by the aroma.
It should sting the nostrils.
This is why it's polite
always to serve kiviak outdoors.
The flavour should resemble
extremely intense Gorgonzola cheese.
Nothing is wasted. Everything is edible.
The Inuit of northern Greenland
love kiviak so much
that it's the dish of choice
for birthdays and weddings.
And it's nutritious,
full of vitamins and minerals
that will sustain people
over the winter months ahead.
As September gives way to October,
winter returns to the Arctic.
The ocean ices over once again.
One of the first places to freeze
lies along Hudson's Bay
near the town of Churchill, Manitoba.
Every year, the 1,000 human residents
must share their town
with one of the few predators on Earth
that actively hunts human beings.
(GROWLS)
From September to November,
as many as 300 ravenous polar bears
descend on Churchill
on their way back to hunt on the sea ice.
(GROWLS)
Bob Windsor is in charge
of protecting the residents.
He belongs to a special task force -
the Polar Bear Alert team.
BOB: Polar bears are pure predators,
so they kill other animals to eat.
That's how they survive.
Knowing that, you have to give them
a little more respect
because you could also be
a potential meal for them.
(OVER RADIO) This is one nine zero.
Just to let everybody know
that there's a bear coming towards town.
(SNARLS)
(VEHICLE HORN BLARES)
HURT: As a first line of defence,
Bob tries to frighten the bear
back into the wilderness.
- (SNARLS)
- (GUNSHOTS)
(SNARLS)
But this skirmish isn't necessarily over.
(GUNSHOT)
Desperate for something to eat, bears
often return under cover of darkness...
- (WINDCHIMES)
- (DOG BARKS)
...which is bad news for Bob,
because tonight, more than
any other night, fills him with dread.
BOB: Halloween is probably the busiest
night of the year that we work,
just by the sheer number of people
that are out and about that evening.
(DOG BARKS)
So, the potential for something bad
to happen is definitely there.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
HURT: At the same time
as the trick-or-treaters hit the streets,
people at the Royal Legion
gather for their weekly meat raffle.
The prize for winning
is prime Canadian beef.
Next ticket...
number 440.
- Ha-ha-ha-ha! Yeah!
- (APPLAUSE)
This may seem cavalier,
but the residents of Churchill
refuse to live in fear.
And the protection of the polar bear
patrol makes them feel safe.
However, in the past,
bears have mauled and killed people
right here on Main Street,
and Bob is all too aware of the risks.
(CHATTER)
BOB: You always hope and pray
that nothing bad is gonna happen.
Keep your eyes open,
be aware of your surroundings
and always be thinking
that there could be a bear nearby.
They'll move around. You won't hear them.
Hi! Trick or treat!
We kind of refer to them
sometimes as ghosts,
cos they'll just disappear on you.
They'll be there, and then, ''Where
did it go?''A little spooky that way.
They're amazingly fast, amazingly agile,
and amazingly stealthful.
- (SCREAMS)
- Trick or treat!
- Hi, guys! How you doin'?
- Trick or treat.
Trick or treat?
- Have you seen any bears?
- No, it's been good tonight.
There was a bear in town earlier today.
- But there's been nothing tonight at all.
- Did you hear that? We're safe.
You have a good night tonight, OK?
Keep your eyes open
for polar bears too, OK?
- Thank you, guys.
- Bye-bye!
- Happy Halloween!
- See you, little bear!
Happy Halloweenie!
HURT: Tonight the residents
of Churchill are safe,
but it was a closer call
than many of them realised.
Inside this bear trap is proof
trick-or-treaters weren't the only ones
stalking the streets last night.
Lured into the cage by seal meat,
this male weighs over half a ton.
This bear is sedated and will be flown
at least 60 kilometres outside of town.
In the past,
an average of 75 bears per year
have been transported out of Churchill.
But in recent years,
the number of invading bears has halved
because in this part of the Arctic,
polar bears are in decline.
They have timed the sedative
so that it wears off soon after they land.
This is done so that bears can protect
themselves from other bears in the area.
For Officer Windsor, it means working fast
before this bear fully wakes up.
A single swipe from a male this size
could be fatal.
BOB: It's a great feeling
cos here it is, you're letting them go.
You can't help but wonder
where's it gonna be going,
how is it gonna make out.
Very satisfying to see a bear
actually get up and go on its way.
(HELICOPTER ROTORS WHIRR)
Wish them well and hope for the best
and hope to never seem 'em again in town.
HURT: With the sea ice forming fast,
it won't be long before this polar bear
can roam far and wide in search of food.
But for people, moving around the Arctic
is about to get a lot more treacherous,
because the sun is deserting them.
It's November in Ilulissat, Greenland, and
the sun no longer rises above the horizon.
The residents won't see daylight
for another 54 days.
They try to live their lives as normal.
They still hunt and fish.
Adults go to work.
(CHATTER)
Children go to school.
But it's all under the cover of darkness.
As the dark days drag on,
everybody yearns for the sun to come back.
(DOG BARKS)
(CHATTER)
Finally, on January 1 3th,
they get their wish.
The entire community
comes out to celebrate
the first sunrise of the new year.
With every new sunrise,
the Arctic is warming up.
And the seasonal opportunities
that have made life possible
may not be here in years to come.
However, the people of the Arctic
are born survivors.
If there's anyone who can adapt to the
changes on the horizon, surely it's them.
For the arctic team, the narwhal hunt
was always going to be a challenge.
The hunt happens in the spring,
when the sea ice
is at its most fragile and dangerous.
(SHOUTING)
Even knowing the risks,
no-one could have foreseen
quite how much drama they would face
in this treacherous place.
Day one on the ice,
and the experienced crew,
including polar cameraman Doug Allan,
are busy loading the sleds.
This is what you need to take six people
out onto the ice for about a fortnight.
It's a hell of a lot of stuff, isn't it?
MAN: We've probably got
about 400 kilos between six people.
So, to say we're travelling light
is possibly a little understatement!
With the kit and a person on board,
each dogsled is having to carry
about 1 00 kilos of freight,
which is quite a lot, really,
between 1 2 dogs.
But this is what these dogs are bred for,
and they're in their element.
They set off across 2 7 kilometres
of sea ice to open water.
Three brothers,
Mamarut, Gedion and Mikele,
lead the crew on their quest for narwhal.
(SHOUTS)
After only a couple of hours,
the expedition encounters
their first sign of danger.
DOUG: You can quite distinctly
see the movement here.
The swell's coming in from the open ocean
and it's just breaking it up.
And this little crack here,
which you can put your finger down,
maybe 1 5 minutes from now,
it's gonna be this wide.
Half an hour,
it will be too wide to cross.
So, you really have to be careful.
This ice is on the move all the time.
The Inuit hunters
decide the ice is too unstable
and the expedition
is forced back to the safety of land.
After five and a half hours of travelling,
we've come all the way across
the...the inlet.
The ice edge is still unstable
so I think we'll wait the night out here
and then maybe
have a look-see tomorrow.
The next morning,
they pick their way
across broken tidal ice to the sleds,
to check out the situation.
I'm pleased that the hunters made
the decision they did, because overnight,
we've lost three or four kilometres
of the ice shelf,
which is now disappearing
rapidly in that direction.
As we were coming into the fjord just now,
we actually crossed our tracks,
and they disappeared off into the water,
which was quite a sobering thought.
When they do reach the edge,
they can't believe their luck,
as Mamarut quickly spots some narwhal.
We've just seen some narwhal
further along the ice edge,
so the guys are getting the kayaks ready
because if the narwhals come close,
they might try to hunt them.
Doug's ready to capture the action.
But just when Gedion is in position
to harpoon, the narwhal dives.
They wait and hope
for the whales to resurface.
It's now one o'clock in the morning.
We've been here for about 1 2 hours.
The narwhal have gone
but the hunters are still pretty sure
that they're going to come back,
and we're still waiting,
and we're all getting very tired.
24-hour daylight
melts the ice from above,
and ocean swells
stress the ice from beneath.
It's not the safest place to camp,
but they must wait at the edge
for the narwhals'return.
The days start to run into weeks
and the crew have to extend their shoot.
It's almost three weeks now
that we've been on location
and this...this is the problem - ice.
And somewhere under here are the narwhals.
It's really frustrating.
Next, it's the weather
that turns against them.
(LAUGHS) It's just one thing
after another, isn't it?
(SHOUTING)
Oh!
(SIGHS) I'll tell you how bored I am.
- How bored are you?
- I moved my tent this morning.
That was the most exciting thing
I've done in three days.
And I moved it six feet.
But it kinda gave me a sense of
satisfaction, cos I'd done something!
As the days pass, the temperature rises
and the ice thins, increasing the chance
of something going wrong.
Did you hear it? Did you hear it?
Oh, listen, listen!
It's cracking... It's cracking
right underneath us right now.
You can't see it cos there's snow
on top of it. There was like, ''Crunch!''
(DOGS HOWL)
It's perfect narwhal conditions,
perfect light, perfect everything,
and what's happening, we've got swell.
The swell can fracture
the sea ice literally anywhere.
That's not good news. So, it's time
to leave here and head to safer ground.
The normally laid-back Inuit
up their pace,
and the crew realise
the situation is serious.
Go! Go!
Gotta go.
(SHOUTING)
They are all now
cast adrift on an ice floe.
I don't know how the hell
we're gonna get off this now!
They're facing an emergency
and everyone's focus turns to survival.
Stop this, please.
The whole expedition is now
floating away at an alarming rate.
There are 1 3 people, 54 dogs
and six sleds of kit to get to safety.
(SHOUTING)
SIMON: Gedion has got into his canoe
and is paddling furiously across the lead
with a very fine trace wire,
onto which, by the looks of it,
they're going to put a much thicker rope,
to physically haul from the other side
the sleds across,
which is very clever,
cos they float - amazing.
Speed is of the essence,
as the wind blows the team
further and further from land.
The sea temperature here
can kill in minutes.
It pays not to rock the boat.
(CHATTER)
DOUG: Get the important stuff on!
Well, the guys have done great. Very
impressed. No flap. They knew what to do.
After four hours ferrying, the kit
and crew reach the other side safely.
But that still leaves 54 water-shy dogs.
(DOGS WHINE)
(CALLS OUT)
On the other side,
they're still far from home
and on ice that's breaking up around them.
It's a race against time,
as there's more than ten kilometres before
they reach the safety of the village.
Within sight of home, an inexperienced
dog team makes a serious error.
(SHOUTING)
An unseen crack has opened up
just metres from the village.
Any wider and the fully laden sledge
would sink to the bottom,
dragging the dogs under.
There's a dog trapped under the sledge
but, miraculously,
even this one emerges unharmed.
Doug and the rest of the crew spot
the problem and find a better route home.
It was another week
before the ice was safe enough
for the crew to film
the full narwhal hunt sequence.
This shoot, more than any other,
highlights the importance
of the complete trust
between the Human Planet crew
and the local Inuit,
in a place where knowing your environment
is the key to survival.