Only one creature has carved a life
for itself in every habitat on Earth.
That creature is us.
All over the world we still use our
ingenuity to survive in the wild places,
far from the city lights,
face to face with raw nature.
This is the Human Planet.
The jungle is nature at its most vigorous,
complex and mysterious.
It may appear bountiful,
but for humans, this is a surprisingly
hostile environment.
Though, through history,
great civilisations have arisen here,
none have stood the test of time.
The jungle refuses to be tamed
and it punishes those
who don't live by its laws.
Yet even today, there are some
who guard the secrets
of surviving in this wild world.
These are the remarkable stories
of the people who call
the rainforest home.
Tropical rainforests coverjust
2% of the planet's surface...
...but they're home to half
of all species on Earth.
The problem is, much of this life
is in the tree-tops,
a world way out of our reach.
Exploiting the canopy's riches from
the forest floor is so challenging,
getting enough protein
is a daily struggle.
The Matis of Brazil
are highly skilled hunters
but for the past week there's been
barely enough meat to go round.
Benin is hungry and he's determined
today's hunt will be more successful.
Administering tree-frog toxin into
his bloodstream purges his body,
preparing it for action.
The Matis also drop a noxious
plant juice into their eyes
to sharpen their senses
and focus their minds on the hunt.
Benin and the others summon
the power of the animal spirits.
Hunting canopy animals
from the ground
requires formidable fire power...
...a four-metre long blowpipe,
precision-made to a design
honed over thousands of years.
Spotting animals in the dense
vegetation is so hard,
the Matis rely on hearing
to locate prey...
...and use mimicry to lure them
into range.
They can imitate all ten species of
monkey found in these forests.
(IMITATES MONKEY CALL)
(MONKEY CRIES)
A howler monkey responds.
30 metres up,
monkeys are feeding in a fig tree.
Scoring the darts with piranha teeth
ensures the poisoned tip breaks off
in the victim's body.
Unlike guns, blowpipes are near silent
and can be fired
without spooking the monkeys.
Benin makes the first hit,
and now the monkeys scatter.
Once shot, the monkeys
must be tracked
as the curare-vine poison takes effect.
This monkey's already weak,
but it's hiding, and must be flushed out.
They shoot again.
But it's stuck in a vine now, and
there's no choice but to go and get it.
One down, but it's just the beginning.
As one of the swiftest hunters,
it's Benin's job to pick off
any escaping monkeys.
He shoots another, but misses.
Benin fires again, this time on target.
The monkey finally stops...
...and Benin takes aim one last time.
Eight monkeys. It's been a good day.
But all too often
they return empty-handed.
Hunting in the canopy is so difficult,
people must find most of their food
closer to the ground.
But scratching a living
on the forest floor is hardly any easier.
The complex nature of this mysterious
world is so hard to master,
the lessons have to start early.
Orlando's from the Piaroa tribe
of Venezuela.
He's like any other kid,
only life in the jungle has already
forced him to fend for himself.
But this childhood adventure takes
them deep into the jungle underworld.
As only 2% of sunlight
reaches the forest floor,
surprisingly few plants grow
and this means few animals.
There's less protein here
than in the desert...
and much that is here is poisonous.
Distinguishing dinner from danger
is an essential life skill.
Few creatures have a more sinister
reputation than the one they seek.
The goliath tarantula,
the size of a dinner plate,
the largest spider in the world.
It's hard to imagine
a less appetising meal,
but picky eaters don't last long
in the jungle.
Besides, Orlando says
they're delicious,
and handling dangerous animals
comes with the territory.
From about five years old,
Piaroa children know exactly
where to hunt for spiders...
...and in a couple of hours
can catch enough for a decent meal.
But they have to be careful
of both the huge fangs
and of the hairs they kick
towards any attacker.
If they contact the skin or are inhaled,
they cause a nasty reaction.
Orlando's come off worst.
But growing up in the jungle,
he's used to a little discomfort.
Tarantulas are best served toasted,
like marshmallows.
All the hairs must be singed off
so they don't catch in the throat.
And when they start squeaking,
which is just air escaping from
the joints, they're almost done.
Tarantulas taste a bit like crab
and, with a little seasoning,
they go down a treat.
Orlando's and his friends'survival
depends upon embracing
every opportunity in the forest.
Jungle people rely so heavily
on their surroundings,
they become a natural part
of the forest
and form extraordinary bonds
with nature.
Very few people live more intimately
with animals than the Awa Guaja
of the eastern Amazon.
Nurturing a wide range of creatures
from the forest,
the Awa are obsessive pet keepers.
And there are some animals
they cherish above any others.
Like the Matis, hunting monkeys
is vital to the Awa's survival,
providing nearly half their protein.
But this relationship
provides far more than food.
Emwi not only eats monkeys,
she loves them.
Almost all Awa families
keep a number of monkey pets.
There are eight different species
in the village.
The Awa show extraordinary
tenderness for the little monkeys,
believing they're more human
than animal.
Emwi is a devoted mother,
both to her children and her monkeys.
For Emwi and the other Awa,
breastfeeding monkeys is simply
a natural way to help an orphan in need.
Caring so intimately for an animal
they regularly kill
may appear contradictory,
but the Awa believe for everything
they take from the forest,
they have to give back.
When our lives are so deeply
entwined with animals and plants,
they inevitably become
a great source of inspiration.
Perhaps the most spectacular case
of culture imitating nature
is found amongst the people
of Papua New Guinea.
Deep in the forest,
a male superb bird of paradise struts
his stuff for a rather drab female
but she isn't the only one watching.
Geling is a bird of paradise hunter,
and it's the highly prized feathers
he's after.
These coveted plumes are passed
down through generations
but occasionally damaged ones
need replacing.
Birds of paradise are so hard to hunt,
however, that Geling's enlisted help.
Peke is after the long tail feathers
of the Princess Astrapia,
and he's using fruit to lure them in.
Tomorrow is a big day for Geling.
His clan will be performing
at a Sing Sing,
where his reputation
and the honour of his village
will be judged on the quality
of his feather collection.
Sing Sing events are all about competing
to see who's the best-dressed,
and Geling knows not a plume
can be out of place.
In both birds and humans,
it's the most eye-catching
who gets the most attention,
though Geling might be
overstating his conquests.
(CHANTING)
The Mount Hagen Sing Sing
is the world's largest jungle-themed
fancy-dress party.
Attended by hundreds of tribes,
it's one of New Guinea's
biggest national events.
Amidst the mayhem, Geling's putting
the finishing touches to his outfit.
In New Guinea, male vanity
is something to flaunt.
Though each clan has its own style...
...almost all wear bird of paradise
feathers as their crowning glory.
In their looks,
and even their courtship dances,
the parallels between man and animal
are unmistakable.
They're birds of a feather.
Both use these precious plumes
to display fitness and beauty.
Taking centre stage,
it's Geling's turn to show off.
This deep connection with birds of
paradise began 40,000 years ago...
...and it shows few signs of fading.
Geling's getting on a bit,
and his female admirers aren't quite
as plentiful as they used to be...
...but he's not going to let that
ruffle his feathers.
The diverse nature of the rainforest
influences the people who live here
in endless ways
and it often leads to
breathtaking results.
For the Bayaka tribe
of Africa's Congo basin,
it's the sounds of the jungle
that most inspire them.
(RHYTHMIC BEAT)
Whether using a river as a drum kit...
...or incorporating animal calls
into their work songs...
...the Bayaka consider music to be
their greatest gift from the forest.
(SINGING)
But there's something else found here
that the Bayaka prize just as highly.
So highly they're prepared
to risk their lives for it.
Tete and Mongonje are on the hunt,
but it's not meat they're after.
Honey is liquid gold to the Bayaka,
and they go to extraordinary lengths
to gather it.
Using a special vine,
Tete makes a harness to help him
get to grips with this 40-metre tree.
Climbing like this requires skill,
strength and stamina,
especially in the tropical heat.
While Tete climbs, Mongonje prepares
a bundle of smoking leaves
to help pacify the bees.
An hour's passed and Tete's
making impressive progress.
But he's still got a way to go.
News that honey's been found
has spread quickly,
and Tete's wife and kids
come to watch.
Tete's finally made it
to the crown of the tree
but to go any further he'll have to
leave the security of his vine.
Tete's fully aware how dangerous
honey gathering is,
but the Bayaka believe it's bravery
that makes the man,
and sugar is so scarce in these forests
that honey is the best nutrition
Tete can provide for his family.
40 metres up, and unattached,
Tete can't put a foot wrong.
And now the bees
are beginning to attack.
He's made it to the hive,
but he's got to get at the honey
before being overcome by bees.
The smoke helps,
but Tete's still being stung.
Finally Tete strikes gold.
The first basket goes down
to Tete's family...
...and even thousands of angry bees
can't stop the feast.
Tete takes time to savour his success.
He's done enough to keep
his wife sweet, treat his children
and earn respect from his tribe.
For forest people, simple things
can hold extraordinary value,
but it's the trees themselves that are
most in demand all around the world.
Logging is one of the greatest threats
facing the world's rainforests.
Yet there are a few places where
its effects are far less destructive.
The jungles bordering India and Burma
are harvested
using one of the most forest-friendly
methods of all.
And it involves harnessing the raw power
of the mightiest creature in the jungle.
This is Ramprasad - five-and-a-half tonnes
of bull Asian elephant.
And this is Sumir, his mahout.
Before nightfall, they have to drag
a two-tonne log
three kilometres out of the forest.
Ramprasad is the mightiest elephant
in the camp,
but it's still a mammoth test of
brute strength and communication.
Sumir steers Ramprasad
with over 1 00 different commands.
He can be operated in Hindi,
Assamese
and he even understands
a little English.
And Sumir's pretty fluent
in elephant too.
Unbelievably strong
and surprisingly nimble,
elephants are far superior to
logging machines in this tangled terrain.
And most importantly, the forest
doesn't have to be completely cleared
just to access a few selected trees.
There's no need for expensive spare parts,
and elephants run on 1 00% green fuel.
But, unlike a machine,
Ramprasad has a mind of his own
and must be treated with respect.
It's essential to break elephants in
before they're put to work,
but they're still wild at heart,
and keeping control of such raw might
is a fine balancing act
of command and compassion.
Sumir and Ramprasad make it
to the collection site in good time
and help load the trucks.
Transporting logs to the sawmill
is the only mechanised part
of the entire process.
But they're not out of the woods yet.
Once again, underjungle conditions,
elephants out-perform engines.
Job done, time for a well-earned wash.
The jungles of East India and Burma
form the largest area of rainforest
left in Asia
and provide sanctuary for the last
healthy population of Asian elephants.
Ramprasad and these other elephants
have lost their freedom,
but this way of logging helps secure
the future of their species
and their home.
It's through partnerships with nature
that people manage to live within
the jungle without destroying it.
But in most areas of tropical rainforest,
the picture is not so harmonious.
In just 50 years, half the planet's
tropical forest has been cleared.
As many as 1 00 rainforest species
go extinct every day...
...often before
they've even been discovered.
And it's not just animals and plants.
We're also losing human cultures
that we know almost nothing about.
Even in the 2 1st century,
there are still people who exist
in isolation from the rest of humanity,
and virtually all live in jungles.
These vast, unexplored forests
are the only places left on Earth
where entire communities
can live undetected.
Brazil is thought to be home
to around 70 isolated tribes,
around two-thirds of the world total.
Jose Carlos Meirelles works for FUNAI,
a government agency that protects
Brazil's indigenous people.
Today he's hoping to encounter
one of these uncontacted tribes.
He needs to get to them
before others do.
Logging and mining
are encroaching on these forests
and there are some who want to deny
that uncontacted tribes
live here at all.
Meirelles needs evidence.
The fight to protect these people
depends upon proving
and publicising their existence.
This is the very first aerial footage
of an uncontacted community.
Very little is known about their
way of life or even their language,
and Meirelles would rather
it stays that way.
He's dedicated 40 years to protecting
isolated tribes from the outside world,
but this isn't as simple
as just leaving them alone.
Using a stabilised zoom lens,
it was possible to film
from a kilometre away,
minimising disturbance.
Meirelles believes the more people
are aware these tribes are here,
the more effective the fight
to preserve their way of life.
Humans have survived here
by becoming part of the forest,
but it's this specialisation
that leaves them so vulnerable
in these changing times.
These people are the guardians of
a wealth of knowledge and skill
that enable humans to forge a life
within the natural world.
And there are very few
whose existence remains
as intimately connected
with the rainforest
as the remote tribes of West Papua.
The Korowai are so adapted to life in
the jungle, they've taken to the trees.
(SHOUTING)
This clan is building a new house...
...but it will be no ordinary one.
All materials must be sourced on site,
and much of the cutting is still done
using stone-age tools.
It's an ambitious project.
The plan is to build their new home
in a tree 35 metres up.
Just as well they've chosen an ironwood,
the strongest tree in the forest.
The first step is to build
a ladder to its crown.
These are the only tribes in the world
who live in tree houses...
...and they do so for a number of reasons.
It's an escape from the floods and
the biting insects on the forest floor.
It offers protection
from enemy attack,
but most of all, it's a display
of theirjungle prowess.
For the Korowai, the higher the house,
the greater the prestige.
The Korowai's skills may be exceptional,
but builders are the same the world over.
As one of the clan's
strongest climbers,
Wayo is the foreman overseeing
the most dangerous jobs.
Thinning the branches keeps the house
from shaking apart in the wind.
A fall would mean certain death,
but teetering in tree-tops
is second nature to the Korowai.
(WHOOPING)
As the house goes up,
more trees come down.
But they have to fall
in the right direction.
Activity on the building site is intense.
The rainy season is fast approaching
and the roof still needs to go on.
Everyone's pulling their weight
to complete on schedule.
The roof is tiled with sago-palm leaves
and rolls of tree bark
make the floor and walls.
In two weeks, with 42 workers,
countless felled trees,
30 bundles of palm leaves, 1 6 rolls
of bark and 5 kilometres of twine,
the new home is complete.
It's time to move in.
As always, modesty dictates
a strict entrance policy.
Everything must be carried up,
even family pets
and it's a long way back down
if you forget something.
The first fire is ceremonially lit,
an interesting way to bless
a wooden tree house,
but health and safety regulations
have yet to reach these parts.
Parents are surprisingly relaxed
as their children explore their limits
in the new home.
Through knowledge, skill and ingenuity
rainforest people
have mastered their environment.
They live in tune with their surroundings
and show it a respect
that's being lost elsewhere.
Their remarkable lives remind us
that we are nothing without nature.
Documenting the Papuan
tree house build
was the most challenging shoot
for the Jungles team.
They came prepared for two weeks
filming in the tree-tops,
but when things went wrong, it was
the Korowai who saved the day.
This shoot took cameraman Gavin
Thurston, researcher Rachael Kinley
and producer Tom Hugh-Jones
to some of the least explored
jungles in the world.
We're about five days into the trip,
we had a safe flight in, we had
a very good welcome committee,
and I believe it's about
a three-day walk from here.
No going back now.
Though local porters
help lighten the load,
trekking through the swampy jungle
proves tougher than expected.
Well, I thought, if he's going in,
we've got to show willing, haven't we?
I was going to come and help,
but I've just fallen in.
But with only two weeks'filming,
they have to push on.
The crew eventually arrive at
Lahayu's village to a warm welcome,
Korowai style.
This is Ninkana, and we are beginning
the five minutes of handshake
that seems to be necessary
when you meet someone.
Then it's time to talk business.
Gavin's already spotted
some local wildlife in unusual places.
This is Nasai,
if I've got his name right.
He's got these amazing, um,
apart from an amazing hornbill...
penis sheath,
he's got these feathers
on the side here.
Yakob. I think that's
the sulphur-crested cockatoo.
(IMITATES COCKATOO)
Noisy, yeah?
What else?
Mambro.
(IMITATES PIGEON)
Pigeon?
And the hornbill?
Pfff...
There we are, so that's
today's nature lesson!
The crew go to inspect the ironwood tree
the Korowai have chosen.
Well, the Korowai
have found a really good tree.
It's probably about 70 feet
up to where they plan
to build the tree house.
It's looking good.
A line is fired into a nearby tree
to rig a camera position
but the rope gets caught.
One of these guys
has just shinned right up there.
It's an unbelievable bit of climbing.
All I can say is, if that was
anybody else up there,
my heart would be in my throat,
but he just looks so at ease.
Problem solved, thanks to the Korowai.
Now the ropes are up,
it's Gavin's turn to impress.
I think these guys are fascinated
by how much paraphernalia
we need to get up a tree.
Especially when I can't do it properly.
The Korowai begin building
at an astonishing rate,
leaving Gavin struggling to keep up.
Just as he gets into the swing of things,
rain stops play.
It's been raining for 1 7 hours solid,
I can't believe it.
When it's this wet
it's not safe for them to climb,
the logs are really slippery.
The water table has risen so much now
we've got standing water everywhere,
and the other detail
you probably don't want to know
is that the long drop too
is completely full.
With work at a standstill,
the crew are invited for a social visit.
It's a childhood dream.
It's one of my first memories -
when I was about six or seven,
building a tree house
about four foot off the ground
in an apple tree in the garden
and here I am coming to film
the world experts.
All Korowai houses
are split into gender zones...
...and, on the women's side,
Rachael's attracting a lot of attention.
They seem to be wanting to get me
to dress a bit like them.
Before long she's going native.
A little more than expected.
With the skirt safely fastened,
all that's left is for her
to lose her trousers.
We've had two hours of bonding
with these people.
It's just been really nice to sit down
and get to know the tribe
and to share some jokes with them,
let them laugh at us
and see a bit of their life.
When the rain stops,
the Korowai get going
but Gavin's being encumbered
by all his gear.
I wonder if anybody's ever filmed
a heart attack on a rope before.
Once at the top of the tree,
Gavin's kit comes into its own.
This is quite a clever device,
called a tree pod.
It's got a couple of spikes
and when you strap it to the tree
you get a really good solid base.
The camera goes on top of there.
The tree they've chosen
to put the tree house in,
turns out it's the tallest tree
for a good few hundred metres.
And one of the things we wanted to do
is be able to see the tree house
in its environment, up in the canopy,
and give a sense of height.
It must be getting on for ten storeys high
and just made out of sticks and rattan.
It's quite an incredible
bit of engineering.
The whole time
they've been building this tree house,
there've just been really scary moments.
Right now there's quite a large tree
they're trying to fell
but they are worried it might fall
towards the tree house
and take out the ladder.
So instead of everybody getting out,
there's three guys with long poles
just pushing it out the way
and they've got two more down here
with a bit of rattan
pulling it, in the hope that
it will go away from the platform,
but if it goes the wrong way,
those three guys are going to die!
(WHOOPING)
Another tree falls. This time
it's a little too close for comfort.
Well, luckily they judged that one right
and it didn't come our way.
The building's near completion, but
Gavin still has to shoot the big reveal.
We've set up a line
from the tree the tree house is in
across to where I was filming
from the tree pod.
We're going to put the cable dolly on
and get a really nice pull back
to reveal the tree house
right up in the canopy.
(BEEPING)
Please, baby.
It won't go anywhere.
- What has happened?
- (BEEPING)
It's died!
For the first time ever.
Oh, (BLEEP)!
Yet again the Korowai
come to the rescue.
Traditional Korowai craftsmanship,
a stick with another little bit of stick
tied on the end.
Come on, baby!
Gavin retrieves the camera dolly
in time for supper.
Food supplies are running low
so the Korowai serve up a local delicacy.
Sago grubs.
They're basically giant beetle grubs
that live inside the sago palms.
And they are a delicacy.
The crunch at the end when you chew
their teeth perhaps isn't the best.
But other than that
they are all right.
GAVIN: You kept saying
you wanted protein.
He's gagging!
RACHAEL: I think they taste like caviar.
It's got that pop in your mouth.
- Do you like them?
- Mmmm.
- You can have the rest, then.
- Ah! Thanks. Some more!
GAVIN: The verdict on the sago grubs is,
they are edible
but they are actually
pretty disgusting!
I'm still chewing!
It's the final day and Gavin's last chance
to shoot the grand finale.
Today, it's all come together.
The sun's shining,
the guys are being really helpful
and the cable dolly is behaving itself
and hopefully this is the end shot
for the sequence and the programme.
It's just been incredible
seeing the whole process
of how they build the house
this high up in the canopy.
They all seem to have settled in
very well. Most of them are asleep now.
I'm knackered as well, actually.
Spending time with the Korowai
has given Gavin
a different perspective on life.
I find I judge my own inadequacies
against their expertise and knowledge.
You come here and you've got
boots on in case of snake bites,
you've got sun cream on
because of the sun,
you've got twin safety ropes
to make sure, if one fails,
you are caught on the other one.
And these guys, OK,
maybe they have a higher mortality rate,
but they're much freer
in their lifestyle.
You know, they're shinning
up and down these trees.
I think I'd much rather live a shorter,
fuller life, like they do out here.