You should've
just rang the doorbell,
brendan. Come on.
Hey, you! Yeah, you!
What are you doin'?
We found this truck
on the side of the road.
There might be some
transmission trouble.
You might wanna check it out.
What's goin' on here?
Hey, that's the truck.
The one stolen in newark?
Hey, what are you doin'
with the truck, asshole?
It's a gift
from tony soprano.
Let's call the cops.
Those are the fucking guys
that killed hector.
I don't fuckin' believe it.
We just returned the biggest
score of my whole year.
Listen, you fuck.
Uncle junior's been
breakin' tony's balls'cause
you hijacked that truck.
You're lucky tony doesn't
shove the cab up your ass.
What else
did comley say?
Nothin' much.
There was some stuff
missing from the truck,
but he didn't give a fuck
as long as the thing's back.
Then he said to tell tony
thank you, and if there's
anything tony needs, call.
Tony?
Those fuckin' junkie fucks,
they work for tony,
they hijack carmine's truck,
i get it back,
and old man comley's
thanking tony?
Well, i think
you should've taken care of this
christopher moltisanti thing...
the minute
it first happened.
You should've sent
a clear- cut signal:
You fuck with junior soprano--
take it easy.
We're not making
a western here.
Fuckin' family.
I bought his kid
a $400 surfboard
for his birthday.
Mr. Soprano?
How you doin'?
What's that,
a trick picture out there?
- Which?
- The barn.
And the old tree,
all rotted out inside.
It's just a picture
i bought, um--
i- i remember--
in a little gallery
in provincetown.
That is a special- made
psychological picture,
like that, uh,
that what- do- you- call- it test.
The "korshack."
You think
i want to trick you?
- Oh, no.
- What does that picture
say to you?
It says,"hey, asshole,
we're from harvard.
What do you think about
this spooky, depressing barn
and this rotted- out tree?"
It's depressing
and scary to you?
Not to me.
But it's got that
built right into it.
How are things?
Good.
Had a real good week.
Friend of mine's
in the hospital.
That's never pleasant,
but otherwise
i'm having a good week.
What's he in for?
First they thought
it was an ulcer.
Then this, then that.
You worried about him?
Jackie?
Jackie's so fuckin' mean,
he'll scare that cancer away.
Your friend has cancer.
Dr. Stevens, dial 107.
Hey, jackie,
when they hook you up,
do you watch to make sure they
don't have air in your veins, or
do you think this is bullshit?
What do you mean?
This is a good hospital,
sweetheart.
Nothing like that
is gonna happen here.
Air in the line'll
kill ya.
Know who else--
hey.
Know who else
has cancer?
Tommy dipalma.
He's got it much worse
than you, though.
It's eatin' his brain away.
Is somebody havin' a baby
or what?
Hey!
How you doin'?
How are ya?
How you feelin'?
Good. Good.
Hey, hesh, good to see you.
Thanks for comin'.
Jackie.
Lookin' well, pal.
Hey, thank you.
Here, ro.
Jackie.
You're beautiful.
This is a surprise.
Mikey, nice to see you again
in men's clothing.
I think i should grab
a fire extinguisher.
Heard a friend of yours had
a spontaneous combustion
in his restaurant.
I'm going to the cafeteria.
You want anything?
- Yeah, a plate of braciole.
-
you look good.
They got grappa
in this thing?
I wish.
See you later.
I got some errands, jackie.
Give junior my love.
I will.
Hey, tell my uncle
i sent back
the fuckin' truck.
Now give me that quart
of vinegar peppers
he owes me.
Sure.
Oof.
Thank god he left.
He's a nice guy, but he's
like the grim fuckin' reaper.
It's like he knows every guy
with a fuckin' cancer cell,
and he can't wait to tell ya.
You know, jackie,
you might be a candidate
for clinical trials.
These, uh,
stump cell therapies--
paulie, don't you listen?
He don't wanna hear
no more cancer talk.
Get the fuck outta here.
Trust me, you caught a break
bein' jewish.
See what
i gotta deal with?
Jews. Jews, that's right.
I knew there was somethin'.
You know that guy teittleman?
Owns all that property.
Got a motel down the street
from the club.
The jew with the black clothes
and the curls and everything.
They're called hasidim.
Hasidim,
but i don't believe'em.
What's he want,
this teittleman?
- A divorce for his daughter.
- What are you talkin' about?
Teittleman's son- in- law will not
give teittleman's daughter
the consent...
unless teittleman gives him
50 percent of his motel.
They call it a "get."
Why don't he just, uh--
uh, it's, it's taboo
for their religion.
You know
about this shit?
Run, huh? Trust me.
You don't want to do business
with these people.
He said there's 25 large in it
if we can get him this here,
uh, this here "get."
There's an old saying
amongst jews:
When a jew gets a divorce,
even the altar sheds tears.
All right, i heard enough.
Hey, look, i'm gettin'
kinda tired here.
- Let's go get a cup of coffee.
- We'll see ya later, jackie.
Good night, jackie.
Yeah.
That crash you all heard
was meadow soprano
jumping her cue.
Miss marris,
we're really exhausted
from studying for s. A. T. S.
We were up past 2:00
last night.
- Are you her lawyer?
- No.
Why they'd schedule the s. A. T. S
the same week as our recital--
- sameday.
- What?
Get kicked out
of concert singers...
and there goes
our best extracurricular.
Good- bye, berkeley,
hello, glassboro state.
I cannot wait until the
whole north american land mass
is between me, tony and carmela.
New jersey blows.
I want to go to berkeley
so bad.
The whole east,
i can't deal anymore.
So we don't sleep
till after the s. A. T. S.
Don't mind the mess.
I wasn't expecting company.
I couldn't wait.
I had to see the new house.
Where's king arthur?
Oh, he's downstairs.
This plumbing--
here?
Yeah.
Oh, i love
the coziness.
Welcome
to the neighborhood.
Well, the school district,
anyway.
Carm, you did not
have to do this.
I mean,
we don't see each other
like we used to, and--
i want that to change.
- Could this be artie bucco?
- Hey, capitan.
Place looks good.
Ah, it needs a little work,
but we'll get there.
You need some start- up cash
until the insurance settlement
on the restaurant comes--
ha!
Insurance.
There'll be an italian president
before i see any
insurance money.
I thought that was settled.
Join the club.
They're putting us through
a second arson investigation.
Do they think you're mobbed up?
You're a working stiff.
It doesn't make any sense.
Who would burn down
a perfectly good restaurant?
It's stupid.
Insane.
I'm sorry, artie.
Life goes on, no?
I could always be
a plumber, no?
Only one concept to master.
Shit runs downhill.
Yes, it does.
Come in the kitchen.
I'll buy you a beer.
Mr. Soprano.
Mr. Teittleman.
My pleasure.
Please,
have a seat.
Thank you.
Silvio you know.
Paulie.
Paulie,
how are you?
This is my son.
- Does he have a name, or
do we have to give him one?
- Oh, i'm sorry. It's hillel.
You know the story
about my daughter
and her husband?
Yeah, he knows.
- Do you have a daughter,
mr. Soprano?
- Yes.
Call me tony.
What would you do
if your daughter was
abused by her husband?
Talk to him.
Yeah,
in ball- peen hammer.
I think you understand
my anger.
He's not only harming
my daughter, but he's mocking
our laws of marriage.
Look, let's
understand each other
from the get- go here, okay?
I'm in the carton and
waste- management business.
I'm only here because
i'm a friend of silvio's,
you're a friend of silvio's.
You may be having
a family problem
that i can help you with,
and if i can do it,
that'll make me happy.
- What's your fuckin'
problem, pal? -
please finish.
- You're being shaken down
for 50 percent of your motel.
- Correct.
And the rabbi goon squads
who used to smack these husbands
around to get the divorce?
They've been put out of business
by the d. A. 's office.
All right, 25 percent.
He wants 50, we get 25.
- I don't understand.
- That's'cause
i'm not talking to you.
You get me what i want,
mr. Soprano,
and you have a deal.
It's done.
Put these people in our motel,
and you'll never get them out.
That's a commercial,
isn't it?
Julio, before lunch
i want you to do
bedding inventory.
Si, si, si.
Half hour.
And nocervezas,
please.
Yes,
may i help you?
That depends.
Are you ariel?
That also depends.
Are you a bill collector?
What is this, the catskills?
Shecky greene, we got here.
- We want to talk to you
about your father- in- law.
- I'm sorry, he's not here.
We know he's not here,
but we want to talk to you
about him and you,
him...
and this little problem
that you're having.
Look,
i don't know who you are,
but any problem i may or may not
be having with my family
is none of your matter.
So get out of here, huh?
Now, now, look,
shlomo is a friend of mine.
And you're bragging this?
Oh, this guy--
listen, listen.
You couldn't
possibly understand
what's going on here.
Shlomo is an arrogant,
ignorant control freak.
Look, i know him
since before i had hair
on mypetzel.
I made this place.
The flyers,
the car rental drop- off,
the business breakfast,
it was me, not him.
I sweated blood
into this place,
and he owes me,
and i intend
to get what's mine.
So please,
don't embarrass yourself
any further.
Just leave.
I'm not embarrassed.
You embarrassed?
Listen to me,
you weirdo fuck.
You give shlomo
whatever he wants,
and you forget
this 50 percent shit.
You got nothin'
comin' to ya.
You understand me?
Nothin'!
Fuck you!
Bupkes.
Say"bupkes,"paulie.
What?
That's how they say
"nothin'."
Fuck that.
This is how i say "nothin'."
How's that
for nothin'?
You know what?
Probably not.
The fund- raiser
of pediatrics hospital?
I'm gonna hire
artie and charmaine
to cater it.
Come on, this fund- raiser.
Since when do we open our house
to strangers?
Oh, you're right.
Let's just move back
to italy.
We'll live
in a little hill town,
just like our ancestors,
put a big wall
around it,
and we'll throw burning oil
at all the travelers
that knock at the gate.
Poor charmaine.
I tried to find nice things
to say about that house.
It wasn't that bad.
It just needs a little work,
that's all.
Those two are so broke.
That fire.
If that insurance'd
get off its ass--
- do you think
it could've been arson?
- What's the matter with you?
Hey!
Yeah, put matt on.
Hold on.
What's going on
in here?
You trying to damage
your inner ears?
We're studying.
These are just
practice tests,
and they're brutal.
Your parents know
you're here this late?
Yeah.
They don't care.
She's sleeping over.
Can hunter
please sleep over?
Start sleeping, then.
Study time's over.
We still have
six more chapters left.
Then can you keep
the decibel level
down, please?
For my husband.
Matt,
i'm serious, you guys.
Matt, if we can't
score some crystal,
we're dead.
Okay, with this budget
we can do three waiters
for the passed hors d'oeuvres,
two for the champagne.
It's such a load off,
you're helping.
The whole party has me
at sixes and sevens.
Pediatric hospital's
such a worthy cause.
Oh, no.
Oona!
There is fingerprints
all over the breakfront.
I want this place
to sparkle.
She's usually very good.
From poland.
Please get in the car,
sir.
Come on.
Like the cop would be callin'
this asshole "sir" if the
fuckin' cameras weren't around.
I saw this one anyway.
So why don't you call tony
so he can call junior and see
if we can change the channel.
Get that,
will ya, babe?
Sure. I'm the only one
who has to go to work
around here.
Yeah, restaurant hostess.
Real tough work.
It's your little cousin.
Hi, adriana.
Hey.
How you doin'?
- What are you doing here?
- Hello to you, too.
And hunter,
what are you doin'?
Don't mind him.
His brain is fried.
You want a soda
or somethin'?
How'bout a beer?
Yeah, right.
Just kidding.
I'll have a coke,
if you have one.
- So, what do you want, meadow?
- I think she wants
somethin' from me.
In your dreams, brendan.
So, if you don't want somethin',
what do you want?
I want to cop.
Here you go.
What do you mean,
"cop"?
Score.
We want to score
some crystal.
- Yeah? You got money?
- Shut up!
You ain't givin' them shit.
- Why not?
- For starters, your father'll
put a bullet in my head.
Since when do you
take speed, anyway?
She doesn't.
I need it to study for exams.
Yeah, right.
Hunter needs it.
Forget about it.
No fuckin' way.
- What?
- He just craves attention,
hunter.
Fine. Just thought i'd ask you
before we went down
to jefferson avenue.
Those moolinyans'll rob you,
rape you and leave you
by the side of the road.
I don't know
what you see in him.
Money.
What do you think?
Fuck you.
See ya,
christopher.
I got my own money.
What about me?
Nobody's gonna say
good- bye to me?
Bye.
- Bye. -
bye, guys.
You can't let her go down
to jefferson ave.
They'll sell her ajax.
She's not gonna go down there.
She's just tryin' to get me
to give her some speed.
Isn't it better if she gets it
from you, with all that poison
that's floatin' around?
Kids. You think
you can protect'em,
but you can't.
As the rainy season
approaches,
the chimps will alter
their eating habits.
You watchin'
that nature shit again?
Hey.
What are you doing here
so late?
My kid stepped on a nail.
Had to get him a shot.
Where is he?
The emergency room
with carmela.
So, uh, whatever happened
with the jew at the motel?
We reached out to him,
he wasn't receptive,
they're going back.
Want me to leave?
No problem. Just looking
for my nurse's pen.
Uh, i think you got
the wrong room there, hon,
'cause you are not my nurse.
I know,
but i made up the bed.
No, sweetheart,
i have not been out
of this bed all day.
I'm sorry.
I just need to check
some vitals.
Hey, what are you doin'?
Hmm. That seems
to be working fine.
Look at these flowers.
Nobody sends flower arrangements
like new york.
Let me just check his--
this--
this damn-- this damn i. V.
Damn-- i got it.
Oh.
- I seem to be having
a problem here. -
- do you mind if i borrow
one of your gowns?
-
it's okay.
It's a private party.
Thank you. Thank you.
Have a nice night.
Oh, maron.
Oh!
Ahh!
I got you, you prick!
You shoulda seen your face!
You prick!
"I ain't been out of bed
all day, honey."
- Look at your face.
- Wha-- who the hell is this?
Relax, mr. Aprile.
It's time
for your sponge bath.
She's a friend of mine
from the club.
Nice girl.
I joined'em later on.
We got a little booze.
You know.
That was nice of you
to have a party
for your friend.
Yeah.
Tufts medical school.
Mm- hmm.
You're a doctor.
What do you think?
About jackie.
I'd have to know more
about his condition.
I told you
He's got cancer.
- What kind of cancer?
- It's in the intestines.
There was a tumor,
and they took it out.
That's recurred.
But you said he might go home.
They're not operating?
It's next to
somethin' vital.
- I see.
- You see.
- From what you're telling me,
it doesn't sound very good.
- From what i'm telling you.
- What the fuck do i know?
I'm not a doctor.
- You're angry. Who with?
Let me tell you somethin'.
This man has had chemo every day
for three fuckin' weeks,
and he still has
every last hair on his head.
Every last hair on his head,
and he's got
a beautiful head of hair.
So don't tell me how it sounds,
'cause you don't know him,
you don't know me...
and you don't know
what the fuck
you're talkin' about.
We're getting closer to you
confronting your true feelings
about what's going on here.
Wait a minute.
I just told you
my true feelings.
You tell me
what's really goin' on.
The tree in the painting.
Rotted out, you said.
There's nothing in that picture
to indicate that.
The fuckin' painting--
i knew that painting
was a fuckin' scam!
You remember your dream?
The ducks?
It took on
another meaning.
What happens to a tree
that's rotted out?
Trees, ducks.
What the fuck are you,
ranger rick?
Some job
you shrinks got.
You think everybody's
lying to you while you're
pullin' scams on them!
Fuck you!
Uh- huh.
There's 37 definites.
We got another 13 maybes,
plus the whole
pediatric hospital board.
Right.
Are you sure we ordered
enough champagne?
Right.
Jean says they
shouldn't be too sober
for the silent auction.
If anyone ever finds out
you got this from me--
yes!
Look at me.
This is no joke.
You and me don't always
get along, but i don't think
you want to see me dead.
I gotta call hunter.
You're the best.
Hey. I'm serious.
Just this once.
Okay?
I'm no drug dealer.
I just don't want to see you
get poisoned.
You father
ever finds out--
god, doesn't anyone
ever knock?
Look, tell brendan
that hunter would rather die
than go out with him.
Brendan?
Keep that asshole
away from that child.
You understand me?
The guy asked me to
do him a favor, i did it.
You delivered the message.
Now let meadow study.
Two goombahs from
the old neighborhood.
What, they think they're
gonna name the soprano wing
in the new hospital...
with the bulletproof glass
and the--
you're just jealous
of their money.
Me?
Yeah.
Okay,
but explain to me this:
The guy offers us
two tickets to the caribbean
out of pure friendship for me,
you won't take'em
'cause they're tainted.
But for some snob- ass party,
it's all right i take his money
to clean his toilets.
First of all, arthur,
this is a paying job
and not some cruise.
And why do you always
have to exaggerate?
You're not cleaning his toilets.
You're a chef.
Good.
So you don't mind
that he fronts me some money for
a new place, 'cause he offered.
Look at that face.
Oh, god, arthur, don't tell me
that you took money
from tony soprano.
How is it different?
Howis it different?
I'm a chef.
I need a place to cook.
How?
I'm giving carmela my support,
that's how.
And it's for
a very reputable cause.
But to have
that man as a partner--
trust me, artie,
that would be insane.
It would mean
the end of everything.
At least
he made the gesture.
Name me another fuckin' person
who offered us anything
except the sopranos.
You wanna watch
what you're doin'?
You're squeezin' the quail.
Do you like the food?
I was so busy schmoozing,
i barely had a bite.
You are not gonna miss
those little veal "tonatas."
Charmaine!
Not in the car!
Please, not in the car!
Shut up!
Let me go,
you sons of--
shut up!
Get in that fuckin' car!
Get in there, you--
no!
You miserable
fuckin--
i can't get used to havin'
all these strangers
in my house.
Why'd you invite them?
Try one of these.
You're a fuckin' great cook,
artie.
I cook like this,
it reminds me
of what i lost.
Havin' my restaurant
ripped from me--
i can't tell ya.
It was like losin' a limb.
Sometimes i lay
in bed at night--
okay, enough already.
Why don't you
forget about the past.
Look to the future.
I am sick of hearin'
about your fuckin'
restaurant.
Shut up about it,
you depressin' fuckin' jerk.
What the fuck
do you know about it?
Don't--
you motherfucker.
Uh- huh.
You fuckin' jerk!
Come on.
Give it up.
See what you get?
You fuckin' son of a bitch.
Get up,
you stubborn fuck.
Please!
Too late for pleases,
you stupid fuck.
All this because you won't
say "yes" to a divorce?
It's not that simple!
Why not?
You sign your fuckin' name
to a piece of paper.
I don't like you.
Yeah? Well, i don't like you.
How's that?
- You believe this prick?
-
what do i get, huh?
You work for nothing?
I don't think so!
I say we force- feed him
his sombrero.
She wants to go to israel,
i send her.
She wants something done
to her body, i pay.
I feed her, clothe her,
put a roof over her head.
On top of that, i work
for her father for 20 years
and put up with his abuse.
I should walk away
without a nickel?
That's it. Stand up.
We don't care.
Tough fuckin' luck.
Aaah, you fucker!
Silvio!
Motherfucker.
This guy's a bull.
Paulie, if we don't
kill this prick,
we should put him
to work.
Yaaah- oooh!
Time's a- wastin'.
You're lucky
i could get out at all
with that party tonight.
Shit!
Hello.
Tony, sorry
to bother you down there.
This thing isn't working out
the way we'd hoped with our
friend with the funny sideburns.
Don't say no more
on the phone--
i'm comin' down.
Shit!
I gotta go.
You just gotten here.
Hey, i know.
But i gotta go.
What's that painting
mean to you?
Nothing. I just reminds me
of david hockey.
You want somethin'
to munch on?
What, are you
fuckin' kidding me?
You know, most guys i know
would be happy to get rid
of their wife.
I tried explainin'
the realities here.
This guy's as stubborn
as a fuckin' mule.
He says it's principle.
I think we gotta--
you know.
That's why
we called you.
I promised
the father- in- law
i wouldn't.
I didn't know
what else to do.
You're a stupid motherfucker.
You know that?
I've heard it said.
What,
are you proud of it?
You kill me,
and a dark cloud
goes over shlomo's house.
Either way,
there'll be no get
unless restitution is made.
You really would let me
kill you, wouldn't you,
you sick fuck?
You ever heard
of the masada?
For two years...
900 jews
held their own...
against 15, 000
roman soldiers.
They chose death
before enslavement.
And the romans,
where are they now?
You're lookin' at'em,
asshole.
"Yea, though i walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
i fear no evil,
for thou art with me."
Yeah. Hold that thought.
Yeah?
Hesh.
I'm here with my
non- shellfish- eatin' friend,
and i'm tapped out.
This guy won't
listen to reason.
Didn't i tell ya, huh?
Didn't i warn you to keep
away from those fanatics?
He's leavin' me no options.
This man's willing
to go down with the ship.
Well, here's a thought.
Maybe he's willing to go
to the world to come,
but if he's stuck here
on this earth...
i know one thing
that no man wants
to go through life without.
What?
Oh.
That's a fuckin'
brilliant idea.
Make like amohel, huh?
Finish his bris.
Yeah.
Paulie, get the bolt cutters
from out of the trunk.
Ariel,
we're goin' to plan "b."
The phone has been ringing
all morning.
The rotellis, the trillos--
he's got something to do
with computers.
They're a wonderful couple.
She invited us to brunch.
Really?
Yep.
But it was the food,
mainie.
Everybody raved about it.
Cynthia ricci said,
"oh, i just love those
little rice balls,"
like she never had
arancin' before.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
It meant so much
just having you here.
It made it so much fun for me.
Mainie, is somethin' wrong?
You got somethin' on your mind
or somethin'?
What could be wrong?
Listen, sweetie,
i know it may not seem like it
right now, but you guys'll
get back on your feet again.
Carmela,
i'm fine where i am.
I know.
That's not what i meant, i--
carmela, i never wanted
to tell you this.
It happened
so long ago.
You and tony,
you weren't even married.
- It's probably silly for me
to even bring it up now.
- What?
You were down at the shore
with your parents that summer.
You and tony were on the outs.
- He called me.
- He did?
One thing led to another,
we started dating each other--
carmela, i slept with him.
You slept with t--
with tony?
Really, it wasn't for me.
Carmela,
what i'm trying to say is,
stop worrying about me.
Really.
We both made our choices.
I'm fine with mine.
I'd like you to consider this.
I'm disgusted with you.
Don't try to give me that.
Why'd you page me?
This fuckin' guy's tryin'
to pull some bullshit, tony.
Hey, zz top.
The guy gave you
the get, didn't he?
But not because of you.
You threatened him
with castration,
but it was business
that brought him around.
He wanted 50 percent,
you wanted 25 percent,
so i split the difference.
I gave him 15 percent,
he gives my daughter
the divorce, and, uh--
it's business.
It worked out.
Walk with me,"shmolo."
Yes.
Listen, don't worry.
I- i've taken
good care of you.
Here.
W- what's that?
For your considerable
trouble.
As the talmud says--
i don't give a shit
what he says.
Now you listen to me.
You wanna give
your son- in- law 15 percent
of the motel? Go ahead.
It comes out
of your end.
Now, we got you your get,
you get us our 25 percent.
Got it?
My son was right.
Yeah?
You're mud,
godless clay--
i created
a living golem!
What the fuck
is a golem?
It's a monster!
Frankenstein!
Get the fuck outta here,
before i take
that asshole son of yours
and shove him up your ass!
Shut up!
Hey.
Hey, how ya doin'?
One second.
Got some good news.
We're in the motel business.
How do you like that?
Read this.
102. 7.
Maybe they should
take my temperature
with the other machine.
- Paulie thinks he broke
his hand on the guy's head.
- Digital.
- We're threatening
to cut his dick off.
- I should call the nurse.
He's mumblin' and prayin',
i'm tryin' to get
his pants off--
i think they should
take my temperature again.
Yeah, yeah, call'em.
Poor jackie.
God has his reasons.
Livia, he looked
twice as old as me.
So, what's really
on your mind, corrado?
This christopher moltisanti.
Christopher.
What about him?
Him and his little,
uh,"friend,"
they're slappin' me
in the face...
and they're hiding
behind tony.
Well, tony always
loved christopher like a son,
and so do i, junior.
He put up my storm windows
for me one year.
Good.
But what do i do?
I just let him
and this filone kid
piss on me in public?
And how far do i go...
before i light a friggin' match
under that hotheaded son
of yours?
Maybe christopher
could use a little talking to.
You know.
The other one, filone...
i don't know.
You got a lot of sense
for an old gal.
No.
I'm a babbling idiot.
That's why my son
put me in a nursing home.
He didn't even care
i was there.
It was just him
and that fuckin' cancer.
It's like
he's already gone.
Yes.
Ehh.
Somebody called me
a frankenstein today.
Really?
This hasid
i'm doin' business with.
These hasids,
they're out there,
but they got their beliefs,
you know.
They're not afraid
of death.
At least
this one guy wasn't.
Maybe they have the belief
because they are afraid.
I'm not afraid of death.
Not if it's...
for somethin'.
You know, a war,
somethin' like that.
A reason.
But jackie--
to see this--
this strong,
beautiful man...
just wither away
to nothin'.
And you can't do nothin'
about it.
And you--
you can't fight it.
Do you envy the hasids
and their beliefs?
All this shit's for nothin'.
And if all this shit's
for nothin',
why do i gotta think about it?
That's the mystery,
isn't it?
The mystery of god,
or whatever
you want to call it,
of why we're given
the questionable gift
of knowing we're gonna die.
Do you feel
like frankenstein?
A thing...
lacking humanity,
lacking human feelings?
Say hello to freddy,
all right?
You fuck--
listen, you're friends
of tony's, right?
Listen, meadow
wanted the crystal.
If i didn't get it to her,
she woulda went down
jefferson avenue!
Tell tony
they woulda beat her!
They woulda raped her!
I don't wanna die now!
I didn't mean it!
I am sorry!
Listen to me!
I was tryin' to save her!
You speak english?
No, we don't.
Don't shoot me!
Don't shoot!
Fuck!
Hi, jack.
Bye, jack.