You woke up this morning
got yourself a gun
your mama always said
you'd be the chosen one
she said
you're one in a million
you've got to burn
to shine
but you were
born under a bad sign
with a blue moon
in your eyes
when you woke up
this mornin'
all that love had gone
your papa never told you
about right and wrong
but you're, but you're
looking good, baby
i believe that
you're a- feelin' fine
shame about it
born under a bad sign
with a blue moon in your eyes
so sing it now
woke up this morning
you got a blue moon
got a blue moon in your eyes?
?
Yeah
you say you
woke up this morning
the world turned
upside down
lord above, things ain't
been the same
since the blues
walked into town
but you're, but you're
one in a million'cause you
got that shotgun shine
shame about it
born under a bad sign
with a blue moon
in your eyes, yeah
woke up this morning
got yourself a gun
talk it through.
Talk it through the opening.
Little left.
Little left on your end.
All right!
Open the door!
Any hinky shit,
and you'll be refrying beans
with pablo escobar again.
This is all a message
to your friends.
Stay away from port newark.
Don't even drive
out to jersey.
Not even on sundays.
I'll tell them.
They've been told.
Twice.
Now i'll tell them.
Here.
Holy shit.
Ha, ha.
Bingo!
We can't fit
all this shit
in the carton.
Fuckin' crackheads
and their small bills.
This is just a little token
of my appreciation....
for recommending
dr. Melfi.
She's a good shrink.
I'm not always
a model patient--
what, what?
You didn't have to.
These are monte cristos.
These are cuban.
Yeah, they're
the best, right?
- They're illegal, aren't they?
- They're cigars.
Oh, they're dreamy, ton'.
You're a good
neighbor, bruce.
Hey, look, i'm a doctor.
I make referrals all the time,
tony. You don't have to--
- no biggie.
- I bet these motherfuckers
were hard to come by.
Yeah, they fell off
a truck.
Excuse me.
- Hello?
- It's done.
And it's the biggest
fucking refrigerator
you've ever seen.
How about
the other thing?
Juan valdez has been
separated from his donkey.
You know, ton',
i've been meaning to say,
i've been watching you
out back with your putter.
You ever play at the club?
No, i play minnisink,
the public course.
You know, you ought
to come to the club
and play sometime.
Nah, you know, it's--
come on.
It's a wicked back nine.
And besides,
some of the members,
i think you'd like them
very much.
Yeah, maybe, you know.
We'll see.
Here we go.
Fresh champagne,
gentlemen.
Oh, that's beautiful.
I love a mixed salad.
I can stare
at it for hours.
A score like this happens
once in a lifetime.
Gotta make this work for us
out in the open, legit.
Find a nice i. P. O.
Keep it spinning.
Live off the juice.
- I. P. -- who?
- Go on in.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I. P. O. -- initial
public offering.
Stock. We gotta find
some insider market
trading shit.
Understand?
Where's my baby?
Paulie, baby,
get that big dick
in the jacuzzi now.
Whoa- ho!
Whoo!
Taking off.
We're gonna celebrate,
just me and adriana.
Mother of mercy.
Could this be
the end of rico?
Maybe.
Just maybe.
Have fun.
Say hello to the broad.
Say hello to your girl for me.
Thank you so much
for taking me to the theater.
Rent.
Fuckin'
broadway musicals.
I mean, we're all
supposed to get all
fuckin' weepy- eyed...
'cause they turned off
the heat in some guy's loft?
I'm hummin' the scenery,
chrissy.
Fifth- row, center,
and dinner at la cirque?
Yeow!
I'm embarrassed
to be hungry again.
Thank you.
Let's just say,
after how many years
with tony soprano's crew,
some shit has finally
worked out.
Just when i was starting
to wonder if, you know--
whose fuckin' welfare check
you gotta cash to get
a burger around here?
Shut the fuck up!
Wouldn't it be cool
to own a restaurant
like la cirque?
Come on with the careers.
- That black guy over there--
he look familiar?
- You have my money.
Why don't you just
forget about workin'
and be with me?
Oh, yeah. And be
one of those wives
like carmela soprano?
Breast- feed a bunch of rugrats
and then spend the rest
of your life...
at the gym, just you
and your stretch marks.
You're right.
Cousin's always had a brain,
but what does she use it for?
A husband who can't
even tell you where
the money comes from.
Yo, hair net central,
what am i back here,
mark fuhrman?
You a dick!
- Would you chill?
It's fuckin'
discrimination already.
Hey.
'Bout time.
Bold men make
bold statements.
Why'd they send you over?
I'm lookin' for a burger,
not converted rice.
- Your woman looks embarrassed. -
come on, eh?
Give me a couple
of burger baskets.
He's only bold
because he's semi- hooked up
with the tony soprano crew.
What's with the attitude,
christopher?
If it's not the blacks,
it's somebody else.
Whoa!
Nice.
Must belong to the homie
with the blue hat.
Yo!
Donnie brasco!
Yeah?
My name is orange j.
I'm down with massive genius.
That's who it was.
That gangsta rapper.
I told you to shut up.
We're having a party
at g's crib.
Englewood cliffs.
You interested?
And i get served
with black- eyed peas
tomorrow?
I know what time it is.
Massive's heard of
the fuckin' crew you with.
There's business
to be done.
This is a beautiful,
beautiful home.
Smaller than my hamptons crib,
but that's bigger than steven's.
That's italian contractors,
obviously.
Look at all these
gold records!
Whoa!
What do we have here?
You like that shit?
A christmas present
to myself.
Isn't that
a sight to behold?
I do so love a good
firearm in my hand.
You people are
all right.
Godfather?
I seen that movie
200 times.
Godfather iiwas
definitely the shit.
The third one--
a lot of people
didn't like it,
but i think it was
just misunderstood.
So what kind of business
you want to discuss?
Mr. Herman rabkin.
Hesh.
I don't know him personally,
but i know his history.
In the late'50s and'60s,
he owned f- note records.
I don't know what
it was called, but, yeah,
hesh was in the music business.
Little situation here.
A distant- but- deceased
quasi- cousin
on my mother's side--
little jimmy willis;
'50s legend--
two seminal hit records
was his legacy--
drug tragedy.
"Such a fool"--
oh, i love that.
They play it all the time
on oldies radio.
Old herman?
He's just another
in a long line...
of white motherfuckers
stealing royalties
from the black man...
that made them the money
in the first place.
Jimmy's mother out
in san bernardino
who i call my aunt...
is owed that money.
Hesh is the world's
sweetest guy,
but i've heard his opinions
on givin' back pieces
of israel.
I can only imagine
what he's gonna say
about this shit.
Feel free
to enjoy the food...
and any other enjoyments.
Champagne, sir, ma'am?
Yeah.
That guy's a gangster?
I'm a gangster.
I'm an o. G. Original
gangster, not him,
fuckin' lawn jockey.
And he's got the fly
hamptons house,
alec baldwin comes over,
whitney houston--
what do i got?
I sit in the fucking
pork store, for christ sake.
But the moolies,
they got it goin' on,
and they're on tv.
- They don't take no shit.
- Soprano crew, it's always
"secret this, omertathat."
Fuckin' gets on my nerves.
Junior, with his
moldy old sweaters,
and he's a fuckin' boss.
And you were just feeling
so good about yourself.
Our thing once ruled
the music business.
Did you know that?
No.
We bankrolled acts.
Blacks, everybody.
Paid the deejays or busted
heads to get em' played
on the air.
There was some great
italian singers.
Fuckin' a.
Frankie valli.
Dion. The rascals.
That whole philly thing.
My dad used to talk
about those guys.
Now?
Fuckin' drum machines,
some ignorant poetry,
and every fuckin'
fourth- grade dropout ditsoon
is chairman of the board.
- Gangsters.
-
talk aboutpaisanpride.
Go joey!
Shot to the heart
and you're to blame
you give love
a bad name
bad name
oh, you're home.
Hey.
Barb wagner called.
Remember her from
the fund- raiser?
- The mayonaisses up the street?
- They invited us to a barbecue
over at their house.
All right.
Didn't think so.
Are you still
with the brochures?
Can you believe how much
it costs for a college
education for four years?
We got enough.
I know we got enough,
but how much is enough?
I mean, god forbid, what if
something should happen?
You dig up my blue suit.
You call up old man coletti.
You tell him not to put
too much makeup on my face.
Don't joke around
about this, tony.
You'll be taken care of.
You're always telling
me the same thing.
I'll be taken care of.
By who?
What is with the look?
Did you just make a score?
No. I wish.
You know, tony,
it's a multiple- choice
thing with you.
I can't tell
if you're old- fashioned,
you're paranoid...
or just
a fuckin' asshole.
So what do i tell the wagners
about this barbecue?
You want to go?
Sure.
Cusamano asked me to play
a little golf with him
at his club.
Sorry.
All right. Fine.
Prick. The maitre d' is
really on the rag tonight.
I'll talk to him.
Remember richie santini?
Yeah, you used to fuck him.
That really
sums it up.
I knew him
since we were three.
He lived next door.
Yeah, we had
our little phase.
What about him?
You've heard his band.
Defiler?
I'm not into that
headbangin' shit.
You were talkin' about
the good old days.
Italians running
the music business.
And here's richie,
this musician who you know.
They're not
a hair band anymore,
and they're really good.
You said yourself
how much money
there was in this thing.
You mean like, uh,
richie santini?
You think massive genius
would be interested?
It's a whole
different thing: Black.
But he's got a company.
Massive g productions.
Shit, they make
movies, even.
Massive does owe me
a favor.
I'm arranging a sit- down
for him with hesh.
I was thinking about--
okay.
I know this sounds
kind of funny.
Music management.
Huh.
And working here,
i have met people,
important people.
Learned people skills.
Had to deal with big egos.
Solved problems.
And with my love
of all kinds of music--
maybe alec baldwin would
come to our house.
You know who we are
you know what we do
we're comin' to defile
defile you
stay out of our way
and don't be so gay
we're comin' to defile
defile you
my- y- y lord
- it's just an old demo.
- No. You know what?
Fuck it.
Let's set you up.
What?
I got money.
You're right. With how much
you listen to the radio,
you'd be good.
I can't believe it!
But i get to pick
what you wear.
Dress you up.
I like that.
This place has
the flava.
That gelding,
name is sidney.
So how come you never wrote
a song about him?
When you and little jimmy
were writing partners
on all his hits,
did you write the music
and him the lyrics,
or the other way around?
We, uh, we had
our own process.
So that "ooh, wacka- do,
wacka- dooley- do,
i'm so blue,"
that spring from
your experience,
or the little brother's?
One could write a song
about a horse.
But in order for it to be
a hit with your target audience,
he'd have to have a mounted
cop on him and ripped up the ass
with a mac ten, no?
So you bought horses
with your royalties.
And little jimmy's royalties,
whatever became of those?
He bought horse.
Music business back then,
we were breaking all the rules.
Makin"em, breakin"em
as we went along.
You mean rapin'
and pillagin'.
Things haven't changed
much, huh?
Were we hard- nosed?
Yeah.
But we gave a lot
of kids their start.
A lot of negro youth.
Took'em out of the ghetto,
kids with talent,
put'em on the stage.
Herman, ordinarily,
i'd be more than happy...
to stroll down
memory lane with you.
But it's reparations
that i seek.
Why don't we call this
what it is: A shakedown.
Your own father
was a silent partner
in f- note records.
Made sure that
the records got airplay,
isn't that right?
Yeah, that money
built my house
on the jersey shore.
What do you want to do,
hesh? I'm guided by you.
- He's got to do the right
thing, that's what.
- Ohh!
Hey. You're way
our of line, kid.
Let's get some cold fucking
fizzy water on your head.
Thank you, jen.
Let's get right
to the point, huh?
What's in this for you?
If you read
chuck d's book,
you know he advises
that reparations be made...
by the jewish studio moguls
in hollywood...
on account of the way
black folks have been
portrayed in film.
Now, that's only germane to
this argument inasmuch...
as i feel that the grievances
in the music business
are far worse.
You're talking to the wrong
white man, my friend.
My people were the white man's
nigger when yours were still...
painting their faces
and chasing zebras.
And as far as louie b. Mayer
is concerned, what are you,
fucking nuts?
My lawyers have done
a little research.
I think that the final figure
is somewhere around...
four hundred thousand dollars.
Now, a cashier's check
made to mrs. Idella willis...
will set
the record straight.
Or what?
What was it
that she called him?
Oh, yeah.
"That nice man,"
i think she said.
So how's your neighbor,
the one with no neck?
The sopranos? Well, there's
a new car in the driveway
every other week,
but besides that--
he gave me a gift
of some excellent
cuban cigars.
- And you accepted them?
- Mmm- hmm.
See? Eroding
the neighborhood values.
He was thanking me
for referring him
to a physician,
which he's very happy with.
Really?
What does that do
to property values,
having a gangster
living next door?
Are you kidding? Safest block
in the neighborhood.
- And bein' a gangster--
what does that mean, anyway?
- Yeah, that's true.
Some of the shit i see
in the boardroom, i don't know
if i'd make a distinction.
Oh, will you please?
It's not the same thing.
Bugging? Bribes?
I don't know.
Sometimes i think the only
thing separating the american
business from the mobs...
is fuckin' whackin'
somebody.
Listen to you.
Whackin'.
What?
He hangs around
with tony soprano
for 15 minutes...
and it's "fuckin'" this
and "fuckin'" that.
We were over there
for that fund- raiser.
I didn't see
any guns anywhere.
Oh, but that bar
with the goombah
murano glass?
I like murano glass.
Those monte cristos?
What do you say?
After dinner?
Just jaded
tired and bored
right or wrong
i ain't strong
like i used to be
i want to
erase myself
i know it ain't
your type of music,
but--
i like any kind of music
that turns shit green.
Richie's been through
a lot. It's deep
in his writing.
As a metal band,
they were fuckin' great.
But this, as far
as i am concerned,
blows away matchbox 20.
- What do they all themselves?
- Used to be defiler.
Then some personnel changes--
bass and drums.
But richie and vito are still
the core of the band.
Now they're called
visiting day.
Mom and dad
had left me down
and now i want to
erase myself
this is some loud shit.
Oh, we are alone
yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah
whoo!
- Take me away
- that's richie.
And that's vito.
I don't want
to stay
- fuck you!
- Sit the fuck down,
you mullethead.
This isn't the right place
for them.
You suck!
You know, without
the right help from you,
visiting day could end up
in the miscellaneous
"v" section.
Don't be sad
it's not bad
- nobody cares
- you interested?
I want to
erase myself
yes!
That scene where pesci
sticks the guy's head
in a vise,
and then he fuckin' pops
his eye out-- i mean,
i thought i was gonna die.
I'll be right back,
okay?
Excuse me.
It's this way, right?
Yes.
Thank you.
I don't know.
What?
Richie. Guy's 30,
still lives with his parents.
It's because of
the accident.
Richie had third- degree
burns from trying
to grill that trout...
with a downed
power line.
At the same time,
being electrocuted
turned his life around.
Well, you did some
ace fucking selling.
You think?
Yeah.
Thing is, though,
music is not something
you can hold in your hands,
you know,
like football betting cards
or coke.
It's art.
Berry gordy, whatever,
he had to see it
in the supremes.
It's an instinct.
I see it in richie.
Yeah.
Probably is.
I'm really fuckin'
doin' it!
And it's all
thanks to you.
I got to make a demo cd,
like massive advised,
and then-- yeah!
My wife thinks i need
to meet new people.
So?
Come on. You're italian.
You understand.
Guys like me, we're brought up
to think themeddigan
are fuckin' bores.
The truth is,
the average white man
is no more boring...
than the millionth conversation
over who should have won,
marciano or ali.
So am i to understand that you
don't consider yourself white?
I don't mean white,
like caucasian.
I mean a white man,
like our friend, cusamano.
Now, he's italian,
but he's ameddigan.
He's what my old man woulda
called the wonder bread wop.
Eats his sunday gravy
out of a jar.
You seem to want
to branch out.
What's stopping you?
The guys.
What they'd think
if i started hanging out
with themeddigan.
I was in your neighborhood
last night, at the cusamano's.
- Oh, yeah?
- Dinner party.
Shoulda stopped by.
Live right next door.
You didn't hear any
strange noises last night
in your neighborhood?
Noises?
Like someone
screaming in pain?
Uh, no.
Probably
a television set.
You saw my house?
Mm- hmm.
Oh!
This looks good.
Mmm. Mmm, mmm, mmm.
That sausage, huh,
where'd you get it?
- Little place in garfield?
- Honey, where'd we get
the sausage?
That little place
in garfield.
You know,
the only thing better
than a little sausage
is a pair of tits.
I don't know about that,
but it's a hell
of a piece of meat.
Sausage is kind of
a phallic thing.
Whereas tits--
so, jack, you're
a stockbroker, right?
Mmm.
Any changes
in the market comin'?
They're always changing.
That's what keeps us
coming back.
Oh, by the way, rand,
you hear from ross
on dexplex?
No, not yet,
but the buyout is
definitely goin' down.
Just give me a little
warning. I need
to call the islands.
Dexplex?
Oh, it's a little company.
It's going public, maybe.
Hey, hey. Come on.
Come on, will ya?
The sun is shining.
It's a beautiful day.
Let's not talk business
for once, huh?
American biotics.
Barb, our stock guru.
She thinks american biotics
may be a good investment.
It's supposed to be close
to a side- effect- free
anti- impotence drug.
You guys play
the stock market?
We don't just play.
We win.
Friends say i'm crazy
she's gonna make me cry
but none of them know
the way we
steal a little kiss
and my, oh, my
fools follow angels
wanna believe she's mine
all mine alone
why am i such a fool
friends say i'm crazy
she's gonna make me cry
but none of them know
the way we
steal a little kiss
and, oh, my
fools follow angels
wanna believe she's mine
all mine alone
why am i such a fool
erase myself
are we alone
yeah, yeah
take me away
i don't want to stay
there must be
another way
that's take 62.
We oughta just bag it.
Okay. We're baggin' it.
We shoulda bagged this
two days ago when it was
fucking perfect.
I wish i had
thought of that.
It's good.
You know, not bad.
I think it's as good
as we're gonna get
right now.
Oh, it wasn't too bad.
It was kind of good.
Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What are you saying?
Is something wrong?
No, i'm sure
we're all trying
our best here.
I just think
we hit a brick wall.
Maybe some rest.
Hey, hey, fuck that!
I paid for three days'
studio time already.
It's only gonna cost me
more money to pack it up
and come in again, isn't it?
I don't get it. We got through
the instrumental tracks
with no problem.
Ah, i'm fuckin' beat.
What do you say we finish
this shit? Three days now
we been slammin' our hams.
Look,
kinkos gave me five days off.
It's not the end of the world.
Kinko's?
Buddy, this is costing me
300 bucks an hour.
Here. Try this.
Dude, i don't do drugs
anymore, okay?
Well, hats off.
But for all the dynamic
excitement in these songs,
maybe we should get another
downed power line in here,
let you suck on it.
- Christopher!
- What you just heard...
was our balls- out,
most introspective song.
- It's not supposed to rock.
-
it'll be our first single.
No, dude, second.
"Sharon's chair" will be
the one that busts out.
I like "melt."
Come on. Go shoot the crank,
let's wrap this up, all right?
- What?
- You heard me. Spike up.
- No fucking way.
- Christopher,
i'm producing these sessions.
Go take the fucking drugs.
I'm not fucking around
anymore.
Look, the problem,
christopher,
is that the bass
and the drum tracks...
were miked wrong from
the fucking beginning.
Whoa, hey, king of rock,
you're out of your depth.
Look, let me tell you
something, dude.
Thank you, but i've
recorded in denmark.
Okay. You want to know
what the problem is?
Where are
the fucking choruses?
All your songs,
you got no choruses.
Your choruses are basically
just another verse.
I mean, what happened to
"she loves you," huh?
- "She loves you"?
- Yeah, the song.
Started with the chorus.
There is structure.
That's how you build
a song.
The beatles,
the beatles,
the beatles.
Look, that's been
40 fucking years now.
It makes me sick.
- What is he, nuts?
- Fuck this, man.
Where are you goin'?
I'm goin' to a. A. ,
you fuckin' jerk- off.
- Get back to work.
- Ooh, okay.
- Huh? Huh? Come on.
- Ooh, big man, huh?
Fuck!
You all right?
What? What?
Get back in the booth!
So we take it
from the top.
We'll use a ukulele.
I can't believe you.
Yeah, yeah.
Five thousand shares.
American biotics.
Can you place
the order today?
Okay, great.
I'll have the money
to you by tomorrow.
Okay.
Thank you.
Bye bye.
- Are you spying on people now?
- I live here.
Are you playing
wall street now.
Women are better
savers than men,
and we are nurturers.
What do you know
about the stock market?
I keep
my ears open.
Cnbc is a very
interesting channel.
Listen, your father,
god bless him,
he does very well.
But who knows,
you know?
What if something
unforeseen should happen.
What if he gets
hit by a truck.
I mean, then what?
I got you kids
to think about.
I don't know, mom.
Well, when you get
married, you will know.
A woman's got to keep
her sense of individuality.
This here is
a life lesson.
Okay. Let's go to
georgette klinger's.
Massage, facial,
joie de "beau- tay."
On me.
Sure.
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa!
It's a lily.
Now, that's a shot.
Ball runs like
a frightened fawn.
W. C. Fields.
That thing's
still runnin'.
I gotta tell ya,
this is a nice place.
Didn't i tell ya?
We oughta see about
making you a member.
Tony, you ever play
that place in orlando?
No, i never get
down there.
Well, disney world.
You know, al's place.
Mount plymouth?
- Al capone built it.
- No shit?
Capone was a golf fanatic.
That's right.
- So you guys watch a&e.
-
tony, uh, let me
ask you a question.
If i'm stepping
on any toes, tell me.
How real wasthe godfather?
I mean,
in your opinion.
What do you mean, real?
Authentic or not.
I don't know.
How would i know?
It was the'50s, right.
No, it was 1972.
What he means is the story
took place in the'50s.
I wanna know if you really
had to cut your finger
and take an oath.
Like gridlock on times square
on this golf course today,
isn't it?
This traffic in manhattan's
gotten worse since
"don't block the box."
You got a lot of friends
in new york, tony?
Yeah.
You ever go down
to little italy?
- You know, san gennaro,
the feast, with the kids.
- Tell the truth.
What's the first thing
you think of when you hear
"mulberry street"?
Umberto's.
Hey, did you ever see...
that picture
of gallante dead...
with a cigar hangin'
out of his mouth?
- No.
- It's a fuckin'
beautiful hit, huh?
Sorry, tony.
You probably knew
the guy, huh?
- How old you think i am?
- You don't have to answer this
if you don't want to,
but i gotta know.
Did you ever meet
john gotti?
Yeah.
I knew john.
Whoa! Fuck!
What was he
really like?
- Remember bungalow bar?
- The ice cream trucks?
Like good humor,
except the trucks had
bungalow roofs on'em.
Was gotti a silent partner
in all that thing?
I don't know nothin'
about that.
Just know that
when the company folded...
and they were auctioning off
the last bungalow bar truck,
the one with the peaked roofs--
you're right, cooze--
cooze.
Well, they're auctioning off
the last bungalow bar truck...
and i wanted it
as a souvenir.
Gotti outbid me.
Gave me a ride home.
You know,
he rang that bell...
the whole way home?
Oh! They're wavin'
at us.
Meow
meow
i love this part.
Now i've lost
my inner child
i should hope
yeah, this is good.
He ain't been defiled
i am just
that's some good guitar.
Listen to that shit.
A tortured soul
they got it goin' on.
Makin' money
yeah.
Is an empty hole
meow
so?
I think it's, uh,
not good.
Want to be a little
more specific?
There's good and there's
not good. This is not good.
Okay, maybe it's not your era.
No offense.
Music is music.
Talent is talent.
I don't care who you are.
And i've seen them all.
I saw heavy metal invented
by hendrix at the cafe wha.
Kid just came out of the army.
I said to him,
"kid, i don't know
what you call it--
talent, charisma, magic--
but you've got it."
These kids, they don't.
Sorry.
You're just pissed
that i went against you
at the sit- down.
Get the fuck out of here
and stop wasting my time.
This vito is a great
fucking guitar player, hesh.
Fine. Great.
He's a great guitar player.
However, there's one constant
in the music business--
a hit is a hit.
- And this, my friend,
is not a hit.
- Why?
Christ. For reasons we couldn't
comprehend or codify,
you pathetic schlepper.
Fuckin' massive is a genius,
so what the fuck was he
talkin' about?
I remember when i was a kid,
there was this guy
in my neighborhood.
We used to call him
jimmy smash.
He wasn't retarded,
but we thought he was because
he had one of these, uh,
whatchamacallits.
Hey, how the fuck
are ya?
What do you call that?
Cleft palate.
Yeah.
Well, we was kids, right?
So what the hell
do we know?
Every time he opened
his mouth, we'd piss
ourselves laughin'.
But jimmy didn't mind,
because he got to hang
out with us.
Popular crew.
Although we only called him
when we were bored.
Called him, said,
"hey, jimmy.
Sing'mack the knife'."
And because he wanted
to hang out with us,
he'd belt it right out.
We'd fuckin' roll
on the floor laughing.
And then, you know,
when the laughs got old,
we stopped callin' him.
Wasn't till years later that
i found out the poor prick
was goin' home every night...
and cryin' himself
to sleep.
When i found out,
you know, i--
i felt bad.
But i never really
understood...
what he felt.
To be used, you know,
for somebody else's amusement
like a fuckin' dancin' bear...
till i played golf
with those guys.
Well, you thought
cusamano was your friend.
You live, you learn.
Do you mind if i
ask you a question?
Whatever happened
to jimmy?
Jimmy smash?
He's doin' 20
for robbery.
Wasn't too hard for the cops
to figure out who it was.
He goes up to the bank teller
with a mask, he goes,
"give me your money."
Some fucker's
on the phone for you.
Good morning, herman.
I'm listening.
Good.
I wouldn't want you to miss
anything i have to say.
I've been thinking about it.
- Go on.
- You'll have to find another
schmuck to have a moment with.
You do know
what this means, herman.
Stupid enough to say it
over the phone, let's hear it.
I don't threaten, herman.
I act.
Genius,
you're getting yourself in
way over your head here.
Why don't you think about
backin' up a little bit?
You know,
let sleepin' dogs lie.
Hey, soprano.
Let me share with you
what i suspect about
this gangsta rap shit.
I think you probably got
a degree in sociology
from the city college.
I grew up in the projects.
Delta 13.
Killed a man.
Later on,
i got a degree.
But urban planning.
You were close.
Now, when it comes to
which is mightier,
the pen or the
motherfucking sword,
i let the situation
dictate.
- Don't press it.
- I'm gonna do my part...
to keep mr. Rabkin's
people working.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Expect to hear from
goldstein, baum and woronov.
They'll be representing
miss willis in the lawsuit.
- You gonna sue?
- With what i pay in retainers,
fuck, yeah.
I hear that.
Yeah, well.
Listen, be advised...
that on your artist
scratch's last single,
you sampled
a backing vocal...
from the chablis'
1968 song,"riff with it,"
for which f- note records
controls the master
recording rights.
No shit?
Yeah, shit.
I would of course
have to counter sue.
I'll see you in court.
Fuckin' legal fees.
What kind of moolies
are these?
They call themselves
gangsters.
It's a new fuckin' day.
Fuckin' depressing.
Okay. Now this
is a donatella versace.
- Nice.
- You like it better
than the alaia?
- Keep'em both.
- Christopher, $2, 400!
- I don't think
you really like it.
- I like it. I like it.
Huh?
Mtv awards?
- What?
- Nothing.
I thought we put
that fight behind us.
You want me to take
all this back, i will.
No problem.
No. Fuck, i want you
to have it.
You know how i use
the technique of
positive visualization?
I know you talk about it.
You're fairly negative
a lot of the time.
Well, i think you should
mentally prepare...
for the fuckin' possibility
that visiting day sucks.
- What?
- I think the only reason you've
gotten this far with massive...
is he wants to be
in your pants.
Boy, oh, boy.
I let some experts
listen to the demo.
They shit all over it.
I'm sorry.
Experts?
Who, hesh?
That old fucking
synagogue cantor?
Silvio.
He owned rock clubs
in asbury.
You heard what squid said.
He's a professional engineer.
What about my opinion?
That it's good,
that it's special?
His eyes are on your ass,
adriana, 98% of the time.
You know that.
This is just a way
for you to keep me down.
- Aw, that ain't fair.
- I don't want these clothes.
What's wrong with it, huh?
What's wrong
with visiting day?
I don't know,
but it's a problem
that you don't know.
Richie, he'll sing
anything.
You just don't want to believe
that i could have a relationship
with a man...
like massive that wasn't
based on fucking.
That was based
on intelligence,
respect, talent.
I'll shut up.
You sayin'
i don't have talent?
I've branched out,
made new friends,
new horizons,
and you can't stand that.
Yeah.
Go silent. That's you.
Either screaming your head off
or fucking dead.
I don't think i can
stay here anymore.
I love you.
That is such a lie.
Hey, carmela!
In here.
I need a finger.
What's in the box?
Sand.
I'm fuckin' with
cusamano.
Tony--
beautiful.
You look kinda cute
when you're bein'
a bad boy.
You're awfully chipper
today.
So what are you
gonna do with the box?
Give it to him. Tell him to--
"hold on to it for awhile."
Oh, tony!
That is so evil!
Yeah, i know.
That's why it's
so much fun.
Oh, good.
Cooze. Cooze.
Cooze.
Come here.
Hey, ton'.
How ya doin'?
Good.
How you doin'?
Fine, thanks.
Listen, ah,
you know,
that, uh, nickname--
what, cooze?
Cusamano.
Yeah, it's got that
other connotation that--
no, not anymore.
Listen, pal,
i need a little solid.
I need you to hang on
to this for a while for me.
Hang onto it a little while.
I'll come get it when i need it.
How long?
A month, you know.
Maybe more, maybe less.
Okay?
Thanks.
Yeah, sure.
Oh, the club. I meant
to ask you about the club.
What's going on?
Oh, the club.
I'm sorry, ton'.
Membership's closed.
Closed?
Yeah.
No new members
until old members die.
Nobody's dyin'?
Nothin' anybody
could do anything about.
No biggie, cooze.
Thanks.
You sure?
I mean, because--
naw.
I'll live.
And all temptations
i resist
and nothing can compare
to this
oh, nobody loves me
nobody loves me but you
and for that
i'd love to find
i'd give it all away
in gratitude
now, uh,
that's a hit.
And all temptations
i resist
nothing can compare
what is it?
Heroin?
Shit, jean,
i don't know.
A weapon?
I don't know.
Could be anything.
Uh, uh!
Don't touch it.
You know who we are
you know what we do
we're comin' to defile
defile you
stay out of our way
and don't be so gay
we're comin' to defile
defile you
my- y- y
lord
ford is a rocket
stop the crush in the midst
of a rock show
i'm on the radio, yeah
and know who we are
and know what we do
we're comin' to defile
defile you