Freaks and Geeks S01E07 Carded and Discarded (VO)
There's 2 ways you can look
at anything in this life.
Take my job, for instance.
I could get up
every morning and go...
"I don't wanna go and help
a bunch of kids.
I'm tired." But I don't.
I get up and put on
my shirt and my tie,
and I say, "hot dog, let me at 'em!"
Do you actually say
the words "hot dog"?
Yes, I do.
I know you're struggling.
That's what they made guidance
counsellors for... To help you.
I understand you've just
been through puberty.
You guys are tall.
I'm surprised you fit through
that door, quite frankly. OK?
A lot of times you might see, maybe
you're taking a shower or something,
and you go,
"What are these?" "What's that?"
But you feel alone and confused,
and you don't think
anyone understands.
Well, I do.
Lots of people do,
even Mr. Alice Cooper.
Bet you don't think
he's a square, do you?
No, man.
Alice Cooper rocks.
Do you know this song?
Lines form on my face and hands
Lines form from the ups and downs
I'm in the middle without any plans
I'm a boy - or girl -
and I'm a man - or woman.
I'm eighteen
I get confused every day
Eighteen, I just don't
know what to say
Eighteen, I gotta get away
Come on, Nick, fill in
those drums there, will ya?
You guys know what I'm talkin' about?
Is this making any sense at all?
I think it is.
- Oh, my god.
- That was brutal.
I've never hated Alice Cooper
as much as I do right now.
Guys, Mr. Rosso's really
good at the guitar.
Some of those chords are hard.
What? You're not gonna
sing again, are you?
No. I was having fun in there,
but I'm worried about you.
- Why?
- Because you're not one of them.
You're a different breed.
I'm just worried because,
before you know it,
you're gonna have to start
applying for colleges.
And if you keep going
the way you're going,
some of those colleges
may not want you.
Well, maybe I don't want them.
You know, not everybody
in this world has to go to college.
You know who didn't go
to college? Einstein.
Thomas Edison.
Frank.
- Frank who?
- The dude who pumps my gas.
Just saying.
Lindsay, aunt Judy and uncle Gary
sent you a birthday card.
What is it?
Oh, my god.
They sent me $300
for my college fund.
Through the mail?
She's lucky that wasn't intercepted
by some junkie working
for the post office.
Kids, your dad has a little
treat for us tonight. Harold?
Oh, yes. I was visiting
Mr. Prieh at his store today.
And he was selling a game
that my family and I used to play
when I was a kid...
Every Friday night.
Pit.
Sounds like fun.
It is.
It's a stock-trading game.
We all yell at each other
trying to get the other players
to trade stocks with us.
We sit around the table
and you yell at us?
You do that every night.
I think it sounds like fun.
Well, have a good time.
I'm gonna go out on Friday night.
Me, too.
You know what?
I'm sick and tired of you two
acting as though you don't
belong to a family.
You act like you're
staying at a hotel
and we're your employees.
Well, guess what?
We are not your employees.
We're your parents.
Now, we created you,
and we deserve respect.
We respect you.
Oh, you can hardly stand
to be around us.
When you two were kids,
you used to run around naked
and lay in bed with us all night.
We bathed you,
and we cleaned your butts,
and we loved it.
Now we try to pat you on the head,
and you run for the hills.
Well, I'm fed up.
We are gonna be close from now on,
whether you like it or not.
We are gonna spend
quality time together,
and we're going
to enjoy it, damn it!
The Weirs are playing pit
this Friday.
Get used to it.
Natural selection is a process
in which weak and inferior genes
are weeded out of the gene pool.
Many of you may know this concept
by its more popular nom de plume...
Survival of the fittest.
That might be Mr. Darwin now.
I'm Maureen Sampson.
I'm a transfer student.
Well, grab a free seat.
Always room for another head
on the chopping block.
I saw Ronald Reagan kissing
a monkey on TV last night.
On the news?
No, no, no. It was in a movie.
He's a pretty good actor.
So was the monkey...
I'm sorry.
Is this your table?
Well, we don't own it,
but we kinda sit here every day.
- I can sit somewhere else.
- No, please.
Join us.
So. Where did you come from?
Florida. My dad was transferred here
to work for General Motors.
Really? My dad drives
a Coupe deVille,
so we're practically related.
So, are people nice here?
Sometimes.
You gotta be careful
who you hang out with.
There are a lot of
characters in this school.
So, we saw you in our biology class.
How did you like it?
It was OK. Teacher seemed
kinda weird, though.
Once he ran over an old lady,
and then he blamed it on his car.
He said the accelerator got stuck.
Really? We had this teacher
at our school,
this guy broke into his house,
so the teacher shot him.
- With a gun?
- Yeah, but he didn't go to jail,
'cause I guess if someone
breaks into your house,
you're allowed to shoot him.
Our shop teacher got his
hair caught in a lathe
and then he got his whole scalp torn
off and now he has to wear a wig.
Our shop teacher got his pinky
cut off by the radial arm saw.
When they tried to sew it back on,
it didn't fit.
So now everyone calls him
Pinky Tuscadero.
I'm really glad I sat here.
You guys are nice.
You're really nice.
Would you mind showing me
the ropes around here?
Sure. We could...
Show you the ropes.
But if I start bugging you,
please, be sure and let me know.
Oh, don't worry.
We'd never let you bug us.
Every old person thinks
they're so smart.
What, there's, like,
no old dumb people?
I just wanna be older
so I can go to bars.
Everything fun in this world
happens in bars.
No kidding, man.
I hear there's this kick-ass band
called Feedback
playing at the Rusty Nail
tomorrow night.
But they're gonna card, so I can't...
What can I do?
Well, maybe I'll go.
You'd better shut up.
Just 'cause you got a fake ID,
don't go lording it over the rest of us.
You have a fake ID?
Yeah. You wanna check it out?
It's my cousin's
old driver's license.
Oh, my god.
This looks exactly like you.
I know.
Except it says you're 24.
So?
I look mature.
Nobody ever stops me.
Daniel, do you have one?
Some stupid bouncer asked
what my star sign was.
I didn't know, so he snagged it.
Aw. It's capricorn!
Cancer!
Capricorn!
Dude, I hate astrology.
What, everybody born in the same
month is gonna have the same life?
Hey, you guys.
We should get fake Ids
and go see Feedback.
Howie Gelfand sells fake Ids,
but they cost like, a ton of money.
I ain't got that kind of cash.
Well, it just so happens that...
I came into a little bit of cash.
I could lend you guys some.
Well, well, well.
I don't know why, but I'm liking
her more and more every day.
Join the club.
What are you... I'm just saying...
Hey, Harris. Hey, Gordon.
You met our new friend Maureen?
Are you new at our school?
Stop by the AV room.
We got a new beta machine.
Thank you, Harris.
But we're late.
Maureen, tomorrow's
pizza day in the cafeteria.
It's made out of real
tomato sauce and everything.
So, what are you guys doing after
school? Want to do something?
OK. Great. I don't have
to be home until dinner.
I don't have to be home ever.
Howie?
You come and take care
of these fine young people.
We need some fake Ids.
I work here.
Come here.
I mean, we need some slacks.
Hello? All right.
How many do you guys need?
Four.
Didn't I just get you one?
You lose it already?
Yeah. I'm not into astrology, OK?
Astrology.
It's not astrology.
It's you, man. It's facts,
it's who you're supposed to be.
June, cancer. Libra, october.
Capricorn, december.
Know it. 1958.
You are them.
You gonna give us the IDs or not?
Who's the chick?
Hey, her name is Lindsay, all right?
Sorry, Bill Laimbeer.
You got some good timing.
Just about to get a shipment of
genuine Canadian drivers' licenses.
Canadian?
I need to look at your faces,
memorize them... So I can find a match.
Brown eyes, brown hair.
Brown eyes, lovely brown hair.
OK. I got it.
It's a 100 bucks.
Half in advance.
Half of what?
I got it.
A chick with money.
You got good taste, stretch.
Excuse me. Hey, gelfand.
You know what?
There's a box of Parisian
nightsuits in the back,
and they're not gonna
unpack themselves.
I'll be there in one second.
I'm just helping these customers.
These look great, sir.
I'll see you guys at 11:00?
Great. Thanks a lot.
Had to bring
the big rocket, didn't you?
What?
So I got a big rocket.
What am I supposed to do,
cut it in half?
There she is.
She is beautiful.
I can't believe she's
gonna hang out with us.
What if I'm asleep right now
and this is just a dream,
and any moment Maureen
and I are gonna make love?
Then what are we doing here?
Maybe this is my nightmare.
Oh, my god, she's running
to get to us.
Hi, guys!
- Hey, Maureen.
- Your rockets look great.
God, Bill, your rocket's huge.
Oh, it is?
I hadn't noticed.
I never launched a rocket before.
This is gonna be fun.
Cape Canaveral, ready for lift off.
Ready to launch this thing?
Heck, yeah.
So, going to
the Rusty Nail with Nick.
This is gonna be, like,
your guys' first real date, huh?
I don't know.
Not really.
We're not going out or anything.
Yeah, but you're definitely
more than friends.
I don't know.
We only kissed once, and it's not...
It's not a big deal.
There's a real connection, man.
I'm telling you guys, she likes me.
So are you guys, like, a couple now?
We're not into labelling things,
you know?
We have a more mature
relationship than that.
Let's just say we have
an understanding.
Well, I'm glad you have
an understanding,
'cause I don't know what
the hell you're talking about.
So, is this what having
a girlfriend is gonna be like?
She's your best friend
and she's beautiful
and you can say and do
anything in front of her?
My dad always says that's what women
want you to think before marriage.
That's how they suck you in.
She's the kind of woman
you could cut the cheese in front of.
Oh, yeah, Bill, that's
what love is all about.
It is.
I mean, you couldn't be in love
with someone if you couldn't.
Think about it.
That is true.
You have to sleep with your wife
every night of your life.
If you couldn't blast one in bed,
you'd get physically ill.
Oh, come on, guys.
You can't fart in front of a woman.
You think you get up and run outside
every time you have to let one rip?
You'd never get any sleep.
I think I might like Maureen, too.
I thought you liked Cindy Sanders.
I mean, I do, but, you know,
Maureen talks to us.
She's not as scary.
No. I'm asking her out.
She clearly likes me best.
How do you know?
You see the way she looks at me?
She can barely contain herself.
You just happen to be looking at her
every time she's thinking about me.
OK. We're all in love with her,
and Maureen likes all of us.
So all we have to do now
is decide who gets her.
How do we do that?
The same way we decided
who had to stand in line
for The Empire Strikes Back tickets.
I'll get the hat.
Sam, excited about
the big pit game on Friday?
Well, I guess I have to be.
Honey, can you
come in here for a minute?
- I like pit.
- You don't even know what pit is.
Honey,
you cannot force these
kids to spend time with us.
Did you know that in some cultures,
if your children shame you,
you're allowed
to have them executed?
- Well, I feel shamed.
- Oh, Harold.
I'm not swinging an ax.
I just want them to play pit with me.
Is that so horrible?
Honey, it's like that old saying...
If you love something, set it free.
Maybe if we try not to force it,
they'll come to us.
- Well, all right.
- There you go.
They're free.
Let 'em free. Let 'em go.
- See?
- Get back here.
- All right, Bill, you pick.
- Wait. Why does he get to pick?
Because I don't trust you.
Just pick fast. Don't try
to feel around for your paper.
I'm not. I'm just
trying to pick one.
Quit being so paranoid.
OK. Now, we know that
the words on this paper
could potentially change our lives.
I don't want any...
Come on.
Just open the paper.
Oh, no. Not him.
I'm the happiest man in the world.
Great, Bill. Now you can
go and fart in front of her.
You'll make quite the impression.
Wait a minute.
He wet his paper with spit.
What?
That's how he wins every time.
He just feels for the wet one.
Mrs. Maureen Haverchuck.
Has a nice ring to it,
don't you think?
How are we this morning?
I've got some brochures
from some ivy league schools.
Several are in color.
Why can't you just leave me alone?
Because it's my job.
I'm a guidance counselor.
I'm trying to guide you.
Well, guide someone else.
I heard the words,
but your eyes said something else.
They said, "I'm lost.
I need your help.
Don't listen to me.
Guide me."
I don't need your help.
Tell you what. Why don't I just come
and visit you then in the prison...
Where you'll be living...
And give you some really good advice,
like should you get shanked
in the yard or the dining hall?
When you have your baby, which prison
guard should take care of it?
That'd be a great way to do my job,
don't you think?
Only time will tell.
See you at the prison yard.
All right. Ready to get yourself
a new girlfriend?
Never been readier.
What are you gonna say to her?
I don't know.
I'm just gonna let the love... flow.
God, this is so unfair.
Here she comes.
I gotta get something
out of my locker.
What are you doing?
Go on.
I told you guys. That's why
you should have let me have her.
I know what to say to a woman.
She's... talking to Vicki.
How do you like it?
It's great. I've met
some really nice people.
- What's wrong?
The minute she starts getting with
that crowd, we'll never see her again.
You think she'll hang out with us
after all those jocks and cheerleaders?
- Why wouldn't she?
- Because they're pod people.
It's like Invasion of
the Body Snatchers.
They'll make her one of them.
We'll see her in a week,
and she'll be all...
Oh, man!
We've gotta get her away from Vicki!
What're we gonna do?
Oh! Eli!
Eli, come here.
Oh, hi! Hi, Bill!
Hi, Neal! Hi, Sam!
Vicki Appleby told me she doesn't
think Three's Company is funny.
But it's the funniest show on TV!
I know. That's what
I told her, but...
I'm gonna go talk to her.
Do you cheerlead?
- No, I...
- Excuse me.
Three's Company is
the best show on TV.
- Really?
- Yes.
The Ropers don't want Jack
living with 2 girls
because he doesn't want any dirty stuff
going on in his apartment building.
There was this scene where
Jack had lost his voice...
Maureen, do you wanna
come to class with us?
Oh. Sure.
Talk to you later, Vicki.
So, which class are you headed to?
- Social studies.
- Cool. We're going there, too.
Cool.
Congratulations, everybody.
You're all of age.
Who the hell is "Jesus H. Garcia"?
It's "hey-zoos".
It's your new identity.
Tell me that picture
doesn't look like you.
This picture doesn't
look like me, man.
Sure it does.
Well, it's gotta be better than mine.
Mine looks kinda Chinese.
Yeah. Hey, mine looks Chinese, too.
What's going on with that?
There's a big Vietnamese
community up there in Alberta.
This says I'm 29.
That doesn't matter. Mine says I'm 34.
I have no problems. It's fine.
Why don't you give us
the money back?
That's top-grade stuff.
You don't get refunds.
Give us the money back, all right?
All right.
It's hard to find matches for you guys.
No one in Canada looks like you.
You know what?
I think I'm gonna go with Jesus here.
I think I can pull it off.
Finally, a sane man.
God, this is...
Oh, guys, by the way...
Tomorrow, at Silverman's,
we're having a big sale,
half off on all dress shirts.
Maybe you guys come by,
I'll hook you up. Be nice.
- Oh, thanks, Howie.
- Yeah. Thanks for nothing.
Wait. That's it?
We don't have IDs,
and the band's playing tonight.
- That was my only connection.
- Yeah. I don't know anybody.
Wait. I think I might.
Maybe we can split up the day
so at least one of us
is with her between each class.
That way we can make sure
she doesn't talk to anyone but us.
It's Vicki.
Where's Eli?
Sam, quick,
go talk to her about Three's Company.
Maureen!
You wanna come sit with us?
Oh. Yeah.
I'll talk to you in algebra.
Oh, you got pudding.
I like pudding, too.
I like it when it's been
sitting around for a while,
and it gets that skin on the top.
Hi, Maureen.
Good to see you again.
How's your day going?
Great. I've met tons of new people.
- What are you doing this weekend?
- Vicki invited me to a party.
That's gonna be fun, huh?
Wasn't that nice of her?
Hey... Millie...
What's going on?
Nothing. Just going
to mathlete practice.
Having a scrimmage against
Mount Clemon next week.
You wanna come?
No, thanks.
Do you ever talk to
your cousin Toby anymore?
No way. Not since he went to jail.
- He's in jail?
- He was.
He got caught stealing
hood ornaments off of cars.
They weren't gonna lock him up,
but he called the policeman a bad word.
Does he still make fake IDs?
I don't know.
My family doesn't talk to him anymore.
He was dropped on the head
when he was a baby.
That's why we think he's a bad seed.
Why do you want a fake ID?
So you can go get loaded?
No. Millie, I just wanna
hear this band play.
That's why there's records.
Do you have his number?
I'm not gonna be
an accessory to this crime.
You know where he lives.
Do it yourself.
I heard the drinking age is
something like 10 in Idaho.
Well, I don't think that's right.
Wait. This is it.
How'd you say you know this guy?
He's Millie's cousin.
I used to know him
when I was really little.
I think he's kinda scary now.
I think we can handle it.
The pharmacy's closed, all right?
I don't got nothin'.
I got no stuff. Nothin'.
Go home.
We're here for the IDs?
Oh, the IDs. The IDs, yeah.
All right. Only one person
is allowed in at a time.
One person.
You, McMurphy, you come in.
You two stay.
- All right.
- Hey, babies.
Don't play with that rooster!
Don't play with that rooster.
That's not a nice, petty-pet rooster.
- I'm sorry.
- No. You're the one who'll be sorry.
Very dangerous.
I understand.
I'm sorry.
Hey, man, you got a lot of stereos.
Where'd you get all this?
Don't bother with that.
Get away from there.
Get away from there, man.
Don't even look at that stuff.
Oh, cool, man!
What's this?
I got a green thumb. Don't worry
about it. Sit down.
Relax.
Oh, cool.
That looks pretty accurate.
It's a masterpiece.
What, you just made
a stencil and put that on?
Yeah, you know.
You just go to any art supply store,
you could get that stuff, huh?
And then you just... You need
the laminating machine, right?
No, you can't just buy
a laminating machine.
You can't just go into a store
and buy one like it's a toaster.
Only corporations have that stuff.
It's very expensive.
All right, man, it's show time.
You can't just get
a laminating machine.
What, you wanna go to jail?
Now this is the hot spot.
All right...
And, you know...
There's a window here, right?
There isn't actually one,
but pretend that there is one,
and don't put your face out
further than that, all right?
All right, not like this,
you know, back.
Come back, you know?
There you go.
Good. And the hat, take the hat...
You know, what's with the hat?
Good. Look like you've been
waiting on line for 2 hours.
Look like you don't want
to have your picture taken.
Well, what are we gonna do?
Why should I help you guys again?
You weren't gonna share her
with me the other day.
Would you share her with us?
- Touché.
- So? What do we do?
She's gonna be at
Vicki Appleby's party on Saturday.
You need to hang out
with her on Friday.
Then, if you show her the time of
her life, maybe... just maybe...
she will continue to base that life
out of your lunch table.
What are our chances?
You don't want to know.
Where do we take her?
Well, there's only one thing that could
compete with the Vicki Appleby party.
All-u-can-eat night at
the Iron Horse restaurant.
- Of course.
- So obvious.
To me it is.
My god, you...
You are a beautiful girl.
- A woman.
- Thanks.
When we were kids,
you were really cute,
but, mean, I never thought
you would turn out this hot.
You go to McKinley?
It's a pretty good school. I almost
graduated from there a few years ago.
Oh, really?
You hungry or something?
I have some Freihoffer's cookies.
Those are really hard to get,
from the east coast.
- You want one?
- No, thanks, I'm not hungry.
- Is this gonna take a long time?
- Hey, be cool, man.
The laminating machine's
gotta warm up.
You're not even
supposed to be back here.
Broke my "one person
at a time" rule.
All right, sorry.
Hey, wanna go see Yes at Cobo?
I got tickets, I got...
You know, Richie Blackmore's Rainbow
is opening up. We could catch up.
I don't think I can.
Yeah, you can, just...
All right,
give me your phone number.
I'll call you up.
Well, um...
Hey, you know, actually,
she's my girlfriend, man,
so do you think maybe
you could stop hitting on her?
No, no she's not.
Yeah, I am his girlfriend.
Hey, man, that's not cool.
That's not cool.
You know, now you make me feel like
a fool for asking for your number.
No, you can have my phone number.
It's just that I have a boyfriend.
I don't need to ask. I could just
get it from my cousin Millie, you know?
I was just being polite.
You know, let's just
get this over with.
It's 75 each.
I thought you said it was 40 each.
- Did I?
- I think so.
100 each.
Let's just do it
and get it over with.
Look at how much hotter
you look in this one
than in your real driver's license.
Whoa, is this one fake, too?
No, why?
Because it says you're 18.
So, was left back one year.
Well, I know.
But still, it wouldn't make you 18.
All right, I was left back twice.
OK, are you happy now?
There's no secrets between us.
All right.
18, that makes me jail bait.
You better watch out.
I'm gonna call the cops on you.
Officer, I didn't know,
look at her,
she looks like she's 30.
No I don't!
2-2-2-2-2-2.
2, 2 you want, 2 you have.
I have cornered
the market on Barley.
What happened to the corn?
I'm looking for corn, here.
I don't know where the corn went.
Hey, you two, come on,
pull up a chair.
We have a lot of high-stakes trading
going on right here in the pit.
- Dad, I told you I'm gonna go out.
- Yeah, me, too.
See you later.
Have a good night.
- Don't worry, we will!
- Be careful, OK?
Let the trading begin.
I told you. We should have
forced them to stay with us.
You want to keep playing pit?
No. This is a terrible game
with just two people.
Nobody's home.
You wanna have a little sex?
Sex?
Well... OK.
Let's go.
In the bedroom.
So, how does this all work?
Well, we order a lot of food,
and then keep asking for more
until they go out of business.
My mom says it takes a little while
for your stomach to tell your brain it's
full. So you should eat really fast.
Yeah, but the only problem is,
the service is really slow.
Yeah, they take forever on purpose,
so you'll get full while you wait.
Watch how much bread they bring us.
Yeah, well, I'm here to eat ribs,
lots of ribs.
Good evening.
Welcome to the Iron Horse.
I hear service here is really bad
'cause you don't want us to eat much.
What? I don't own the place.
I don't care how much you eat.
Are you sure?
No, actually, I'm a millionaire
and I just do this for fun.
Really?
We just want our money's worth.
I'll bring 'em faster than you
can eat 'em, but I want a 20% tip.
20? I thought 10 was the norm.
15 is standard.
20 is classy.
20 it is. Why are we still talking?
I want some ribs.
This is gonna be
the best night ever.
I hope so.
Oh, I forgot your bread.
See?
You see that show Different Strokes?
That little Gary Coleman,
"what you talkin' 'bout, Willis?"
He used to crack me up.
Man, I'm nervous.
Just do it like we discussed it.
It's OK.
Hey, Jimmy, what's up?
- Hey, man.
- Let's see some ID.
Really? OK.
I didn't know you guys were carding
tonight. I hope I brought it.
The suspense is killing me.
There it is.
Being a sagittarius,
I'm always forgetting these things.
- Go on.
- Yeah, thanks.
Where's your mustache, Jesus?
It's hay-soos, and I shaved it.
Too bad. You looked better with it.
Gracias.
Se}or.
It's great you guys are carding.
Makes me feel like a kid again.
Thank you.
Hey. How are you?
All right, come on in.
Do you want to see my ID?
No, you're good.
Those IDs look nuts!
Business must be pretty bad if
we're supposed to let them in.
Where's the waitress
when you need her?
Got to take advantage
of this evening.
Oh, man, I'm excited.
We wouldn't be here without you.
So thanks a lot, all right?
Good evening, everybody.
Are you ready to rock?
Ready! Yeah!
Always ready to rock!
Then put your hands together
for a little band we like to call...
Feedback!
I hope there's a lot of party
people out there tonight,
'cause we are gonna party!
Jeez, I wonder if we'll
ever see her again?
Sure, we'll see her plenty.
Sitting at the popular table.
No way.
She's cool.
We'll be friends with
her for a long time.
I hope so.
That's my dad.
Better get going.
Thanks again.
You sure you don't want any money?
No, no, no, it's on us.
I had a really good time.
We should do it again.
Yeah, that would be great.
See you guys later.
Specials are good.
How are we not supposed
to be in love with her?
They're not bad.
All right! All right.
Hey, everybody!
I've got a great group
of hard-working rockers
behind me right here, and I'd like
to introduce them all to you, but first,
we have some special guests in
the audience I'd like to introduce.
All the way from
McKinley high school,
we've got the key members of another
smokin' band we like to call "Creation."
Daniel Desario, Ken Miller,
Nick Andopolis, Kim Kelly,
and their manager,
miss Lindsay Weir.
Give 'em a big hand.
Hold on, sue, hold on.
I can't let you serve
our guests plain old beer.
Why don't you bring them
some of your finest pop,
on the house.
Finest pop.
Perfect.
Thanks.
I was just starting
to like that guy, too.
The moment of truth.
Hey, guys.
Hey, do you mind if I go over
and sit with those guys today?
No, no, not at all.
Do you want to come and sit with me?
Over there?
You don't have to sit here forever
if you don't want to.
Yeah, but we like it here.
Yeah, go have fun with your friends.
We'll be here if you need us.
OK.
Oh, wait, before you do...
Just remember,
the jocks are only after one thing.
And be careful around Vicki.
She's a wolf in sheep's clothing.
And remember,
don't believe everything they say
about people in the school.
'cause they don't always take
the time to get to know everyone.
Guys, I'm just sitting 3 tables over,
I'm not moving back to Florida.
Well, we know.
- See you in biology class?
- See you in biology class.
Excuse me, is this seat taken?
It is, by you, my good man.
Did you guys happen to see
Three's Company last night?
It was so funny.
What happened?
I don't really remember,
there was a lot going on.
Joyce DeWitt is really hot.
If I was Jack,
I'd have a very hard time
choosing between
the 2 lovely ladies on the show
because, you know,
one's a brunette, one's a blonde...