Freaks and Geeks S01E09 We've Got Spirit (VO)
Hey, lindsay,
Do you ever think about heavy stuff?
"Heavy stuff"?
Like...death and the meaning of life?
Well, yeah.
When my grandmother died,
I was pretty depressed.
I took it pretty hard.
Yeah, yeah. No, yeah.
I knew that u were like me.
I can't even talk to those otheruys.
Ken and daniel,they don't think aboutand
they don't they're jokethink about...
Why we're here
And they don't think
about the they don't think-
The point of it all.
Are you stoned?
A little bit.
Do you wanna smoke?
No, thanks.
Oh, ok.
Oh. Hey, you know whatwhere
is john bonham i'thright now?
I don't
- john bonham?
I thought d, but what i'm saying
Is that where is he?
Like, is he in the ground
rotting away somewhere,
Or maybe he's up in heaven...
Partying with jimi and janis.
Look at you. you were so cute.
Yeah. That's the, uh...
That's the year i won mvp.
Well, who's this?
That's me.
No.
Who's this girl?
That's heidi henderson.
I went out with her for a while
Before you came along.
Who's lincoln?
Our rivals.
We made regionals. isn't that cool?
In what?
Basketball.
Will you stop jerking it out of my hand?
You're gonna rip it.
God.
Hey.
Did you guys hear about the basketball game?
Pretty exciting.
I'm so sick of all this
rah-rah crap everywhere.
These jocks think they're such badasses,
Walking around like they cured cancer.
They're just monkeys.
Hey, guys.
Hey. hey.
Where's lover boy?
Nick? I don't know.
I thought you two re joined
at the tongue or something.
Hey, kim, can i talk to you for a second?
Woo... woo...
Are you pregnant?
Hey! no!
Don't be such a pig.
God. She wants to talk to me.
Excuse us.
So...are you pregnant?
No.
I'm thinking of breaking up with nick.
Why?
I like him, but he's just...
He's really intense, kim,
And he's always stoned.
I just don't...
Something just isn't right.
Don't do it, lindsay.
What?
Let me straighten him out.
I'll beat some sense into him.
It'll be fine.
No. Kim, don't.
I'll figure itut. it's not a big deal.
Ok, just don't break up with him.
The last time nick got dumped...
He kinda went a little berserk.
You mean with heidi henderson?
He told you about that?
No.
What happened?
No, nothing. Nothing.
I don't even know, really.
Hello.
I've been looking all over for you.
Well, here i am.
I'll see you guys later, then.
Ok. Bye. ok.
Hey, cindy.
What are you doing?
We decided to decorate the players' lockers
To pump them up for the big game.
Ok.
If this was your locker,
would you be pumped?
Yeah, i'd be really pumped.
Do you think todd will be pumped
'Cause it's his locker.
Well, i think it looks really good.
All the other girls wanted to do it,
So i had to beg them to let me.
Oh, my god. here he comes.
Hey, todd.
Me and all the cheerleaders
Wanted to pump you up for the big game.
Cool.
Um, i'll take that. sorry.
Later.
He didn't seem very pumped.
If i were him, i'd be really happy.
I think it was really nice what you did.
Thanks, sam. you're sweet.
Do you remember how i told you
I had a crush on todd?
Yeah.
Well, i don't.
You don't?
No.
It's not, like, a crush.
It's, like, an obsession.
Chewin' tobacco, chewin' tobacco
Spit, spit, spit!
We make lincoln look like
Shift to the left
Shift to the right
Stand up, sit down...
The mascot is depressing me.
Look at him. he's running in place.
What is that?
Is that supposed to be funny?
He's trying to get us excited.
Well, i'm not excited.
I wish he'd sit down. he's blocking cindy.
Hey. Take 5, all right?
We haven't made regionals since 1971.
All right? Saturday is an
important day for our school,
So i expect to see some butts
in those bleachers saturday, huh?
Now i wanna bring up my team captain-
Todd schellinger.
Come on up here, son.
It's always todd schellinger.
Thanks, coach.
This season's been fantastic.
I wanna thank coach fredricks
And god.
Why does cindy like him? he's such a jerk.
He's not even nice to her.
Cheerleaders have to date athletes.
It's the law.
I wanna see all you guys
out there this saturday
To watch us destroy lincoln.
All right!
What do we need?
Spirit!
Whado we got?
That's
s-p-i-r-i-t!
That's spirit!
For victory!
To win this game!
Come on, norsemen!
Put lincoln to shame!
See?
He can't even fall funny.
Good job, man!
Whoo!
comin' through! comin' through!
oww! somebody get the head off!
Somebody get the head off this kid.
I heard that stevie wonder was jewish.
You're thinking of sammy davis jr.
Hi, sam.
No. I read it in the newspaper.
Hi, cindy. how's everything?
Not good.
Our mascot broke his arm,
And he got a concussion, too.
Now his mom won't let him go to bed tonight
'Cause she's afraid he's
gonna slip into a coma.
My cousin slipped into a coma once.
And then when he woke up,
He spoke fluent spanish.
Anyways, um...
We're all freaking out.
I mean, we really need a mascot.
All right, well, i'll see you guys later.
Bye.
Sam, i think that was a subliminal message.
She wants you to be the new mascot.
What?
"We really need a new mascot."
I really need a new mascot.
I really need sam to be the new mascot.
You really think i should try out?
Open your eyes, sam.
That was the biggest
come-on i've ever seen.
She was practically feeling you up.
Neal: HEY, GUYS.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna be the new norseman.
No. No, sam's gonna be the new norseman.
But sam's not funny.
Oh, yeah, i am.
And cindy asked me to do it.
If i could just spend some time with her,
Then she'd start to like me.
You wanna deny the school big laughs
Just so you can hit on a girl?
This is my chance.
You know how important this is to me.
You know how important this is tome.
Being the school mascot
has always been my dream.
Yeah, since lunch.
Come on, neal.
I don't know.
Help me, obi-wan kenobe.
You're my only hope.
You had to go and quote
thestar wars,didn't you?
All right. Sure.
Yes!
Thank you.
At the cafeteria today, the school
mascot fell and broke his arm.
It was pretty scary.
Yeah. They oh, poor thing.
Need a new mascot for the game,
So i think i'm gonna audition.
Oh, that'll be fun.
You know how i love to
watch you kids perform.
You're notoing to the game, are you?
Of course we are.
It's a big community event.
So?
So i'm expected to be there.
I'm a community leader.
Since when?
Heh heh...
It's just a dumb basketball game, dad.
I know why you don't want us to go.
You have a date with your
new boyfriend, nick andopolis.
I mean, we're gonna get to
know him sooner or later.
Why don't we just all go together?
Mom...no.
I'm a member of the rotary, you know.
And the masons.
And councilman applebee, just last week,
Asked me to run for the school board.
That's great, dad.
Boy, i could be the mayor,
I wouldn't get any
respect around this house.
What are you doing here?
But my parents...
Go home.
Hey.
Nick...what are you doing here?
I couldn't stop thinking about you.
I just had to see your face.
Ok.
Well, i don't wanna get you in trouble.
Sleep tight.
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
Good night.
Bye.
Hey, sam, i heard the mascot
Has to change with the cheerleaders
in the girls' locker room.
Really? That doesn't sound right.
Hey, cindy.
Hey, sam. hey. Uh...
Guess what? what?
I'm gonna audition for the school mascot.
Really? yeah.
Sam, being a mascot's a
lot harder than it looks.
I mean, you have to be super coordinated.
I'm really coordinated.
You'd be surprised.
All right, cool.
Not up to me.
Vicki's head cheerleader.
Ok. Can you put in a good word for me?
Ok. But it's not like vicki
and i are best friends.
She's kinda bossy.
I'll do what i can, though.
All right. see you at auditions.
Ok. bye.
You thin
There's a subliminal
message in there somewhere?
For your sake, i hope not.
Hi, heidi.
I'm lindsay.
I'm in your spanish class.
Um, you went out with nick andopolis, right?
Don't remind me.
Do you mind if i ask what happened?
What, are you dating him or something?
Sort of.
You better ditch him. he's crazy.
What do you mean?
Breaking up with him was, like, a nightmare.
He started stalking me.
he broke into my house.
He got in this insane fight with my dad.
Oh, god.
Hey.
Why were you talking to heidi?
Because we're in the same spanish class.
What were you guys talking about?
Spanish stuff.
Well, you know, just be careful with her
Because she's a liar.
She likes to screw people over.
Um...i'm gonna go to woodworking.
I'll see you.
Ok, boys, i wanna see the funky chicken.
How funky is your chicken?
How loose is your goose?
Sam's pretty good, isn't he?
Yeah, but he's not very funny.
Well, at least he's
better than the old mascot.
That guy was as funny as a car wreck.
I-i-i was
just kidding.
Hey, herbert, you didn't fall
asleep last night, did you?
No. My mom's not gonna let
me sleep tonight, either.
Yeah, well, if you feel
yourself start to fall asleep,
Pull out a nose hair.
it'll wake you right up.
So come on, everybody
And shake your caboose
You're pretty good, sam.
You should try out for the
musical. We're doingfiddler.
You could be a dancing yeshiva student.
Ok, um...
This was not an easy decision for me.
The norseman head could've fit nicely
On any one of your shoulders.
But, um, the next school mascot will be...
Sam weir.
It's all politics!
Sam, you are so coordinated!
I had no idea.
This is gonna be so much fun.
I'm gonna teach you all
my cheers and everything.
Cool! When do we start?
Assassinate Lincoln !
This place is turning into a cult.
These jocks, they put
a ball through a hoop-
Whoop-de-freakin'-do.
My par
Ents are making me go to the game with them.
They're really into it.
I'm going.
What? really?
Yeah. I heard we're gonna lose, right?
I kinda think it's funny
when the jocks cry, you know?
"Ooooh, they cheated!"
Ha ha ha!
Here comes nick.
Hey, lindsay... What's up with you and nick?
Nothing.
Nothing? K
Im says you're gonna dump him.
So it's true?
Lindsay, don't.
Hey, lindsay.
Hey, nick. i'm great.
Thanks for asking, though.
Hey, ken. hey, guys.
Nick, could you give me a ride home ?
Ok.
See you guys later.
See ya.
Hey, lindsay.
Don't do it. Please.
See you, man. good luck.
I'd hate to be that guy's drum set tonight.
Get those arms up there!
get that crowd to cheer!
...Spit! Spit! Spit!
Give me more! i want more energy, sam!
You're a norseman! i wanna see power!
Come on, sam! i need to see it!
Be strong! Be powerful!
I want pep!
I need a bigger ending, sam.
All right, girls, funky
chicken. Let's see it.
All right, hit it!
How funky is your chicken?
Come on, sam! flap those wings!
I wanted to be funny.
Vicki didn't want comedy.
...Your caboose!
Not funky enough, sam.
Ok, that was really good, girls.
It'll be better when you have your head on.
Yeah. Can i try that on today?
Um, no. It's still being fixed.
Now, are you ready to try the pyramid?
Uh...yeah.
Um, ok.
It's pyra-time, girls.
Uh-oh. Pyramid.
He's gonna need some pointers, right?
Hey,am, see, uh... when
you're climbing them,
Be careful not to pull their hair
'Cause they'll jerk up, and you'll fall.
Ok? And when you're climbing them,
Be careful not to pull their bra straps...
'Cause they'll wiggle, and you'll fall.
All right. all right.
Now, if you fall, be
careful to cover your head
So you don't break your neck, ok?
Herbert! do you mind?
Sam, it's pyramid time. let's go.
Ok, girls, hit it.
Gimme an "m"! "m"!
You got your "m"! you got your "m"!
Gimme an "h"! "h"!
You got your "h"! you got yourh"!
Gimme an "s"! "s"!
You got your "s"...
Man, i love the smell of gasoline.
Yeah? It gives you brain damage.
You guys go to mckinley?
Yeah.
Norsemen suck!
Aah!
Dammit! i'm soaked!
Will you do something, daniel?!
What do you want me to do, blow on you?
That better have been water.
That's all i'm sayin'.
Oh, eww! Man!
I think he'd be cute with
that mask on and everything.
It would be so funny.
Hello?
Oh, hi, nick! how you doin'?
I'm not here.
Oh...yeah-no. you know, she's not.
She's, um...
Uh, out with her father.
Yeah. I don't know what they're doing,
But they're out there doing it.
Ok. I'll let her know you called.
Bye-bye, sweetie.
Lindsay, i don't like to lie.
Mom, i know. i'm sorry.
You gonna let me know what's going on?
Mom, it's complicated.
I see.
I wanna break up with nick.
You do? Why?
It's just...it's going too fast, you know?
I need my space.
And every
Time i try to do it, mom, i chicken out.
I'm afraid i'll hurt his feelings.
You don't keep going steady
with a boy just to be nice.
If it's not gonna work out,
You need to muster your
courage and let him know.
Yeah.
Yeah?
No. I gotta go call him.
I gotta go do it right now.
Hmm.
Hello.
Hello?
Ken, if this is you, behere an hour ago.
I don't like having to wait around.
I got other stuff to do.
Are you gonna answer me, keennn?
Hello-
Hey, how'd it go?
Well, i think i should tell him in person.
Ye dot you?
Ah. Remember, you have to
do what's right for you.
I'm just gonna tell him
tomorrow before the game.
Ok. Night, sweetie.
Oh, and...if there's anything
else you want to talk over,
I'm always here for you.
Fine. If this isn't ken,
You better not call back here...
Or i'll find you.
Hey, harold. what is it?
I just had a conversation with
lindsay about her love life.
She doesn't like her boyfriend.
She's gonna break it off.
Oh, praise god.
She confided in me, harold,
and she took my advice.
I feel like... a mother, you know?
Yeah.
You're on my leg.
Oh, oh. I'm sorry.
I just
- i'm so tickled!
Hey, lindsay, you wanna drive
With your father and i to the game?
Yeah. I'd like to introduce you
to the pillars of the community,
Also known as my friends.
Well, i have to take
care of something first,
So i'll just meet you guys there, ok?
Oh, that's right. What will you say to him?
Mom, i don't know.
Why don't you tell him he's a greasebucket,
And you deserve better?
Harold. dad!
I'll see you guys there.
Ok. Good luck, honey.
What's wrong with you?
I'm sore.
I had mascot practice yesterday.
Um, dad?
I think cindy sanders likes me.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I got to form a human pyramid on top of her.
Well, that'll do it.
No. I mean, nick's cool, you know?
It's just that when he gets a
girlfriend, he just goes psycho.
Maybe he just gets so horny,
his brain fries, you know?
No. Dumbest thing you can do...
Let a girl know how much that you like her.
Then they just run.
Oh, is that why you're such a bastard to me?
Yeah. Well, you're still here, aren't ya?
Oh, man, there's that car!
Those jerks from Lincoln
that nailed ud, that's them !
Go. Go. Go. Go. before they get away!
Go. Go. Go!
How funky is your chicken ?
Flap your wings!
I want 'em harder!
So come on, everybody
You see that phony sword?
That is a great prop.
Sam's not even using it.
What do you do with a phony sword?
A million things. You fall
on it. You stab yourself.
You stab the other mascot.
That's not funny.
It is if you do it right.
So come on, everybody and shake
The norseman should be doing schtick,
Zany dance moves, like this.
How funky is your chicken?
How loose is your goose?
Why is that funny?
'Cause i'm a norseman in a chorus line.
Or-or wait, this one.
How funky is your chicken?
Hula dancer norseman.
Yes. A norseman in hawaii. That's funny!
I can't be seen with you.
How funky is your chicken?
How loose-
Hey !
Your dad let me in.
Look
Nick, i don't have much time
because i told my parents
I was gonna meet them before the game.
Um, i wanna talk to you. Ok?
Will you sit down for a second, please?
Please?
I just-i want-i want to
tell you what happened
With me and heidi henderson.
Yodon't have to do that.
I know. I know i don't have to,
But i want to, ok?
All right.
I had this really huge crush on her.
And, uh, when she broke
up with her boyfriend,
We went out for, like, a week.
I wrote her poems...
Lots and lots of poems.
It turns out that sheand she was trying to
was just on the rebomake her boyfriend jealous,
And she wasn't even really
interested in me at all.
So when she got back
together with her boyfriend,
She started showing him
all of my poems, right?
An
She's just showing everybody my poems.
And it w r
Ul.
Because i want to get
those poems back, right?
And her dad catches me,
and he starts yelling at me.
And then the cops came. it was-
The whole thing just got blown...
Totally out of proportion.
But the thing is, it just-it all
made me end up feeling really...
Really, really insecure...
About girls.
Nick, i would never show
your poems to anyone.
You rule...
So hard.
Let's go to the game.
Shelley, you have a
huge stain on yourweater.
I told you guys not to
wear these when you eat.
Hey, cindy, you'd make a
really great head cheerleader...
Much nicer than vicki.
Thanks, sam.
She's just so rude sometimes.
I mean, we're all here
to have fun, you know?
Hey, cindy.
Hey Todd have a great game.
Thanks. Thanks.
Uh, hey, i-i need to ask you something.
Yeah.
Schellinger! You wanna
quit chattin' up the ladies
And get over here?
Yeah. Uh, it wasn't important anyway.
All right.
Good luck!
Oh, my god.
What do you think he wanted?
Do you think he was gonna ask me out?
I don't know. i don't think so.
Yeah, but what if he was going to.
Maybe i should talk to him after practice.
Oh, this is gonna drive me crazy.
I'm not gonna be able to
remember my cheers or anything.
Cindy, he probably has a
lot of other girlfriends.
Sam, don't say that.
Todd is a really popular guy.
I just don't want you
to get too hung up on him
Just in case, you know, he won't
go out with you or something.
I guess. maybe you're right.
I'll talk to you later.
I saw 'em. Do it.
Why don't you do it?
'Cause i'm a girl.
Just hurry up, man, ok?
What are you doing?
Uh-
We're giving your car a new paint job.
What are you gonna do about it, huh?
Th what the hell?
At's what you get, water balloon boy.
Yeah man ! Thanks a lot.
Yo, something-something
tells me it's time to go.
Yeah, kim, let's go.
These losers are from mckinley.
Look what that bitch just did to my car.
You're the bitch, man!
Come on, daniel, kick his ass.
Kick my ass?
Tell my mother that i love her.
Here's your head.
Please don't break it. it costs like $600.
Jeez. It's heavy. It's gonna be
harder to do the cheers with this on.
No duh. That's why you better stay focused.
Why don't you put it on
And walk around with it for
a while to get used to it?
Yeah.
Ok. oh, man.
Whoa.
Hey, watch it!
Sorry.
All right. See ya.
Hey, man. Give me 5 for
the big game, all right?
Oh, my god, sam. You are never
gonna believe what just happened.
He todd asked me out.
Said that he liked me, and then
i told him that i liked him back,
And then he kissed me.
And then he said that he
didn't have a girlfriend.
So see? You were wrong.
Todd's a jerk.
What?
He's a jerk. I hate to
say it, but it's true.
He's not even nice to you.
He's all cocky.
Sam!
It's jusstupid that you like him.
I mean, just because you're
a cheerleader and he's a jock.
It's so obvious.
Sam, just because you're
nervous about the big game,
It doesn't mean you should
take it out on me and todd.
Triplets.
When i try to do it-
Come over here.
Well, no, i'll be right back.
Like you to meet a few
very good friends of mine.
This is councilman appleby,
Stan miller of stan miller motors,
and sheriff macgruder.
This is my daughter lindsay.
It's a pleasure to meet you, lindsay.
Your father has told us all about you.
Nice to meet you.
Sam, what are you doing?
Get dressed. the game's about to start.
Cindy kissed todd schellinger.
Sam, who cares ?
You're the school mascot.
Now's not the time to get all weepy.
You gotta go out there and be funny.
Well, i don't feel like being funny.
You think steve martin
always feels like being funny?
No, but he goes out on
that stage every night
With his arrow and his banjo, and he kills.
I'm not going out there.
Then give me that head.
Don't do it, sam. He's only
worried about getting laughs.
Sam, hand me the head of that norseman.
So, uh, dale, do you think i
should be running for school board?
Definitely. We could use a man like you.
Oh, my god. Wh-what happened to you guys?
We got jumped by some boneheads at lincoln.
Yeah. why?
We trashed their car.
They had it coming.
Dad, you remember daniel
and kim, and this is ken.
Hey.no hey, how's-
. I don't believe i've had the pleasure-
Yeah. Mr. Weir. You remember.
How's mrs. Weir doing?
Oh, well, she-she's ok. look, uh, lindsay,
Why don't you just run along
with your friends now, ok?
Ok.
Go, norsemen!
GO, mckinley!
Te lindsay: bye, dad.
Enagers. what are you gonna do?
Oh, hey, nick. Hi.
lindsay's mom, remember me?
Of course. Hi. Yeah. mrs. Weir. Hi.
Yeah. How are you holding up, huh?
Ok.
Yeah. I am so sorry about everything.
You know, lindsay really
does care about you.
She told me so last night.
She just feels overwhelmed right now.
She needs her space, you know?
Is that what she said?
Uh, didn't-didn't lindsay talk to you?
Yeah. She talked to me.
Oh, good.
Um, it was nice seeing you.
You-you, too, nick.
Hey!
Honey, didn't you talk to nick this morning?
Why, what did you say to him?
Well, i was just trying to be nice.
And, uh...
Mom, did you break up with my boyfriend?
I don't-no, i just,
uh- oh, my goodness.
I knew i shouldn't have told you anything.
You know, from now on, just
stay out of my life, please.
Hey, honey.
Oh, hey.
Hey. Are you all right?
Yeah, i'm fine.
Are you sick?
No. It's just nerves.
Hey, you're that new mascot, right?
Yeah.
You know, you were really funny, man.
We saw you doing the funky
chicken. Were all cracking up.
Thanks.
You zone that area, and then
you can bring in the business-
Harold, i think that
lindsay's upset with me.
Jean, shh. The game's about to begin.
GO, mckinley! Shut them down.
Lincoln, you suck!
Yeah, todd! way to go, buddy!
Get down there! get down to defense!
Way to go! all right. Hands up.
Schwartz, get your hands up.
Ugh. Man alive, this thing is heavy.
GO, mckinley!
Whoo!
Man wi neal: watch out.
Th a big head coming through.
It's show time, folks!
Sam, get over here. sam!
Weir, get off the floor!
What are you doing? are you crazy?
Wild and crazy!
Come on. Heads up! heads up!
Time out. Time out! time! Get over here!
All right. Time out.
let's do the funky chicken.
All right Funcky Chiken !
Hey. Hey, watch out.
Whoo hoo hoo hoo!
All right. funky chicken!
Sammy is so cute!
Well, he may be cute, but
that mascot head is disturbing.
How loose is your goose?
So come on, everybody
And shake your caboose
Look out. Sam, move!
How funky is your chicken?
How loose is your goose?
Sam, if you're mad at me,
This is a really obnoxious
way of showing it.
Ladies, keep your hands off the hat.
I can't understand
anything that you're saying.
Norsemen
Watch it !
"Lincoln, lincoln, i'm just thinking,
What the hell have you been drinking?"
Yeah! Nothing but net, baby. Whoo!
In your face, losers!
Kill lincoln!
Yeah. that's the spirit, guys.
You rock.
Let play some "d"
It's called defense, feldman, come on.
What's in there ?
Mmm. Tasty.
Cry at night
No one in sight
And we got so much to say
Cindy, where's sam? We're
about to do "chewing tobacco."
He's over there.
Oh, i stabbed myself!
Oh, my god. he's gonna die.
Help me. I'm dying.
You are in so much trouble, sam weir.
Uh-oh.
Ugh. Thank you, sir. may i have another?
Hey, nick.
Hey.
Well, i wa
S looking all over for you.
Listen, uh...
I've been, um, thinking a lot.
I really like you...
But we've been spending so
much time together, you know?
Um, i
can't-i-
I haven't beenand i
hanging out with my friends,
Haven't really been spending
time on my drumming at all.
And so, i sort of thought that
Maybe you and me should
take a break for a while.
Good.
Great.
No hard feelings, right?
Right.
All right, well i'm gonna go, um...
Practice, or
- i'll see you on monday.
Nick.
Foul! that's a foul!
Come on! Come over here! come over here.
Get over here!
Spirit
Come on !
Put Lincoln to shame.
They're loving it!
Ow! Vicki: what is your deal?
That girl just punched my little boy!
Ok, girls ! It's pyramid time
I don't know what your problem is,
But you'd better get to the
top of that pyramid, now!
I mean it!
Ok girls, hit it !
Give me an "m"! "m"!
You've got your "m"! you've got your "m"!
Gimme an "h"! "h"!
Neal: ELEVATOR, GOING UP!
Girl: HEY, THAT'S MY BRA STRAP!
Neal: NO, IT'S THE TEAM'S BRA STRAP!
Nooo!
Oh, my god, honey! Oh!
Oh, he's all right. he'll be all right.
Sam, you've ruined everything!
Where am i?
Who the hell are you?
Neal schweiber, at your service!
You're dead.
Nate schweeber, you're a jerk.
It's neal schweiber!
The song is over
It's all behind me
I shoulda known it
She tried to find me
I'll sing my song
To the wide open spaces
I'll sing my heart out
To the infinite sea
I'll sing my visions
To the sky-high mountains
I'll sing my song to the free
To the free
Fredricks: ALL RIGHT? COME ON!
Boy: LET'S GO, GUYS. 1...2...3...
Norsemen!
Come on! relax, buddy!
Get the norseman off the floor!
Woo! woo!
Yeah!
Cindy. Hey.
Sam, what's going on?
Why weren't you out there?
I just got really nervous.
I didn't mean to take
it out on you and todd.
He's all right.
That's ok.
Look, i gotta go, all right?
Ok. bye.
Bye.
Keep yourself alive
Come on, keep yourself alive
You take your time and take my money
Keep yourself alive
Come on, keep yourself alive
All you people
Keep yourself alive
Neal, that was incredible.
You're the funniest mascot i've ever seen.
Thanks, bill.
No, no, you're a comic genius!
Uh, did you see when she
hit me? Wasn't that funny?
You guys should be, like, a comedy team.
Ha ha ha ha.
There he is. get him, girls!
Oh, no. Here.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Come on, please! Let's talk about this!
Yeah we'll take !
No ! Oh God ! I'm a bleeder