Freaks and Geeks S01E01 Pilot (VO)
Come on, ladies,
let's see some hustle.
Excuse me.
Is our little practice bothering you?
Get out of here.
All right, let's work.
Squib it, come on.
You seem so distant
these days, Brad.
Is this something I did?
Cause if it is,
I want you to tell me.
Ashley, it's just...
I'm ready to work through whatever
It's that we need to work through.
But we need to communicate.
I need you to talk to me.
Ashley, it's just that I...
I love you so much...
It scares me.
Oh, man,
you wanna hear something way messed up?
You know that Molly Hatchet
shirt I was wearing the other day?
The one with the executioner guy
holding that bloody axe,
under his foot, the severed head...
That's my shirt.
Yeah, so...
My mom, she makes us go
to church every week.
I gotta dress up.
So I get there, and this stupid
priest says I can't come in.
You can't wear stuff like that
in church, man.
Why not, man, it's church!
Supposed to forgive people there.
"So, you hate my shirt,
forgive me, let me come in!"
Yeah, I believe in God, man.
I've seen him. I've felt his power.
Plays drums for Led Zeppelin
and his name is John Bonham!
Here you go, here you go.
"Hey, Lisa,
here are those biscuits you ordered."
"And here, Cinderella story..."
"A former greenskeeper..."
"50 yards!"
"It's in the hole!
It's in the hole!"
Damn Weir.
You really like Bill Murray,
don't you?
Yeah, he's great.
Bill Murray sucks, man.
- No, he's cool.
- Really?
What's he, your boyfriend?
Sam Queer?
- It's fighting time, man.
- Leave me alone, Alan.
I'm sorry, I don't speak geek.
I've always wanted to know what
it's be like to fight a girl.
I'm a girl.
Wanna see what it'd
be like to fight me?
Weir's sister has to protect him?
I'm not protecting him. Just trying to
figure out why you need to pick fights
with guys who weigh less
than 100 pounds.
Watch out, Alan.
I think she's high on pot.
Yeah, and I just go psycho
when I am.
Wanna try me?
You're dead, alright?
As soon as your freak sister
isn't around, I'm gonna cream you, man.
You know, you really didn't need to
do that. I could have handled it.
Yeah, I know.
And by the way, I weigh 103 pounds.
Sorry.
Man...
I hate high school.
I don't give a damn 'bout my bad reputation
Livin' in the past, it's a new generation
Go and do what you want to do
And that's what i'm gonna do
And i don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
Not me. Me, me, me, me
Whah! No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no
Not me
Me, me, me, me
I don't give a damn 'bout my bad reputation
I've never been afraid of any deviation
And i don't really care
if you think i'm strange
I ain't gonna change
And i'm never gonna care
'bout my bad reputation
Not me!
You know, I ran into
Mrs. Patton today,
at Farmer Jack,
and she said she saw you smoking.
Well, she's crazy. Mom.
I can't believe it. You seriously
think I would start smoking?
I had a friend that used to smoke.
You know what he's doing now?
He's dead.
You think smoking
makes you look cool,
let's go dig him up now,
see how cool he looks.
Daddy, if i started smoking,
I would tell you.
Oh, good. Now I don't have to worry.
Hey, Dad.
They're showing Monty Python
and the Holy Grail Saturday night.
Neal, Bill and I are gonna
watch it twice in a row.
Great.
Sam, isn't the homecoming
dance Saturday night?
- Are you going?
- No, why would I do that?
- You're sister's going.
- No, I'm not!
Alright, kids.
High school is for learning.
But it's also where you should
be learning how to socialize.
That's what the high school
dances are all about.
No. It's a chance for popular
kids to experience sex in their cars.
Lindsay!
I mean, if that's what you want me
to do, then I'd be happy to go.
You know...
There was a girl in our school...
She had pre-marital sex.
You know what she did
on graduation day?
Died!
Of an overdose. Heroin.
Are any of your friends alive?
The smart ones.
I'm sure there are plenty
of kids who are just
dying for someone to ask them.
Mom, that's the stupidest
thing I've ever heard.
Honey, it's stupid
until you consider how happy
it'll make somebody
who really wants to go.
Nobody I know wants to go.
- Dad.
- Honey.
Great. No, that works out perfect.
I'm having a midnight madness
deer hunting sale at night,
and you can wait on
all those nice hunters.
Choice is yours.
Thanks, Carl.
Hey, Eli...
I think Carl needs a hug.
My buddy!
- You're such a jerk, man.
- Eli likes you. Congratulations.
- Hey, Mr. K.
- Mr. Schwieber.
It's Schweiber.
Mr. Bones, Mr. Spock,
may I join you here,
in the Enterprise vessel?
I'm so hungry I could eat a Tribble.
I don't get it. Who's that?
John Wayne.
Why does my mom always
put a note in my lunch?
It's so embarrassing.
At least she doesn't write it
on the bag.
Are you guys going to
the homecoming dance?
I really don't see that happening.
I'm sorry,
did I crush your Twinkies?
What did you do that for?
What are you gonna do,
go crying to your sister?
Sam Rear?
No. No, I'm not.
Mr. Kowchevski,
Alan smashed my Twinkies.
My God, you're such a woman.
Alan. You don't have anything better
to do than to squash Mr. Weir's dessert?
I was just bending down
to talk to him,
and I accidentally leaned on it.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you go
and buy him some new ones?
Oh, yes, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Kowchevski.
Sam, want some advice?
Be a man.
You shouldn't let
Alan do that to you.
I don't see you doing anything!
My father tells me to stay out of
fights that don't affect me directly.
It'd be nice if you guys
backed me up once in a while.
My sister does and she's a girl.
Yes, but if we do,
Alan is gonna terrorize us, too.
Listen, you guys have got to help me.
He's never gonne leave me alone.
- Hey, Daniel.
- Hey, Lindsay.
What's up? Where you been?
I've been... around.
Come on, let's hit the patio.
The smoking patio?
It's all right, they don't bite.
Don't touch me.
I'm sorry.
Your butt was calling to me.
- Hey Nicholas, you got those M80's?
- Don't know, man, you got the money?
You guys know Lindsay?
You were in my English class
last year, right?
You're that chick who got an A.
Yeah, well, what are you gonna do?
I don't know, what are you gonna do?
Are you guys going to
the homecoming dance?
I beg your pardon?
That's funny. That's a joke, right?
My dad's kind of making me go.
Your dad is making you
go to the dance?
What's that all about?
Who is your dad? Hitler?
I just thought maybe
you guys were gonna go.
To make fun of people.
- That could be funny, right?
- I would go...
but I have a prior engagement.
My cousin just sent me a bunch of
mushrooms and I'm gonna eat them.
Look. I mean, you know
they're gonna play disco, right?.
Disco sucks. I hate disco.
I'd rather make out
with Principal Farber.
Again?
Shut up, man.
Oh, my god, man.
I can't wait til
you're not paying attention.
- Check it out.
- What does she want?
- Linds!
- Friend of yours?
"Linds"?
I'll be right back, OK?
Millie, what are you doing out here?
What are you doing out here?
This place is for freaks.
Millie, go away.
Today is the deadline
to enter the Academic Decathlon.
Mr. Rosso said you didn't
turn up your application.
What? Millie, I'm not entering.
But you are our best mathlete.
Can we not talk
about this right now?
Lindsay, what's wrong with you?
There's nothing wrong with me. I just
don't wanna do Decathlon this year.
Aren't you at least gonna help the soda
refreshments at the homecoming dance?
We're trying to raise money to buy
the school computer.
Gentlemen, here's my advice.
Listen to Neal.
You should handle Alan
the same way Han Solo
dealt with Jaba the Hut.
- Avoid him.
- Just avoid him forever?
Just for 4 years.
There's Cindy Sanders.
Dream on, Sam.
- Oh, man.
- Hu-oh. Incoming.
Sam, I've been looking all over
for you. Is this your jacket?
You left it in science,
I didn't want it to get all dirty.
Thanks, Cindy.
That was really nice of you.
Yeah, well, I'll see you later.
Sam, you are so in.
What?
She brought you your jacket.
She saw it,
she remembered it was yours,
she picked it up
and carried it through the halls.
People probably saw her with it.
I wonder if she has
a date for the dance.
Cindy Sanders is
in love with you, man.
- Do you really think Cindy likes me?
- Hello... the jacket.
There's no way.
We're not her species.
Just do me a favor. Ask around,
see if she has a date for the dance...
Who should I ask?
OK, the dance is tomorrow.
She is a cheerleader.
You've seen Star Wars 27 times.
Do the math.
I know,
but my dad says the prettiest
girls usually don't get asked out
because guys are too afraid
to ask them.
Really? Maybe I should ask out
Farrah Fawcett Majors.
Maybe I should ask out Bill's mom!
- Oh, you better not!
- Just ask around, OK?
Don't even think about it.
- The chemistry exam you ordered.
- Alright, good job.
- Where are the answers?
- You just said to steal the test.
Good work, genius.
Why don't you use your brain?
Who's got gum?
Oh, yeah, that's real great.
Why don't you blow your nose in
some bread and make me a sandwich?
Why is everyone
calling up my butt today?
Because you're an moron?
Hey Kim, I got some.
What's she doing here?
She is our friend.
What, are you doing her? So she'll
help you with your math homework?
Lay off.
- Kim...
- I wasn't not talking to you, brain.
Don't you have a test or something?
Would you be cool? Please?
Did I do something to you?
You're here.
I have as much right
to be here as you do.
Hey, brain...
I shoplift in your daddy's store.
You're just some rich kid
who's trying to piss off her parents.
You think you can hang with these guys?
You think that's gonna make you cool?
I don't know what to tell you.
You know, I'm sorry.
Let's be friends.
There, now we're friends.
See you at the mall.
What are you, on your period?
If you wanna hang around with
your little poser friend here
and pretend with her,
that's your waste of time.
Just keep her away from me.
That is exactly why
I don't carry a purse.
I gotta get to shop class.
It's the only way I can pass it.
Here.
And... sorry.
Don't you have to get to class, too?
I'll survive.
These shorts aren't very flattering,
are they?
No, you look good.
How come your sister
is dressing so weird now?
What do you mean?
I mean, she's been wearing
your dad's army jacket.
I don't know.
She's been acting weird
ever since our grandma died.
You're dead, Weir.
- Alan?
- What?
What's the point of all this?
The point?
The point is, you're dead too.
Little man.
I kind of wish I didn't
come to school today.
Would you go to
homecoming dance with me?
I would,
but I already have a date, so...
Will you go to
homecoming dance with me?
- Eli, there a bee on your book.
- Where?
I'll get it.
What's the matter with you?
Jerk.
Sorry, didn't mean to upset
your husband.
What if he was my husband?
That's be some kind of joke to you?
It's no joke to me,
I think you two make a good couple.
Maybe we do.
Do you wanna go to
the homecoming dance with me?
Yes, I do, really, please.
I will go.
Alright, fellas,
I just wanna let you know
that in honor of the big
homecoming game tomorrow,
I'm gonna give you guys the day off.
Can we go home?
Schweiber, don't be an idiot.
We are going to do something fun.
I'm gonna let you guys...
play dodgeball.
Can somebody please tell me
what's supposed to be fun about this?
We just let ourselves get hit,
and we can sit down.
Let's just pretend to get hit.
Nobody will know.
I don't think we can.
Ladies, put down the mascara,
and get in there, play.
I can't take it, man,
I gotta get out of here!
Look, little man is running away!
Hey, only my mom
is allowed to call me that.
OK, now it's time to sneer Weir.
- Sam, get away from me.
- We need to stay together.
- Are you crazy?
- Hey, kid!
Soddleman, that's illegal.
You're out of it.
Schweiber, come on, walk it off.
Sit down, you nugglehead.
There's nowhere to hide, Weird.
Kid, get away from us.
That psycho is after you.
Nice throw, wuss.
He caught my ball! I'm out!
Go Sam! Go!
White, take a seat.
Come on Weir, throw it back.
Catch it, come on.
Dodgeball is kind of
a stupid game, isn't it?
You just signed your death warrant.
Man, that chick totally likes me.
It's funny.
That Jimmy Carter,
he's some president, right?
He's doing a hell of a job.
He's doing a hell of a job!
But I'm a little concerned his handling
of the economy, aren't you?
I'm a little concerned. Maybe.
Maybe I'm a little concerned.
Come on, Eli. Give him a break. Look
what he has done in the Middle East.
In the Middle East.
The Middle East.
The middle of the East.
- You'd make a good president.
- President Eli?
OK! President Eli!
Hey, you guys, cut it out.
Leave him alone.
What? We're having
a political discussion.
Yes, we're political.
You don't have to talk to them,
they're just being mean.
No, but they're my friends.
My friends!
Yes, we are his buddies.
Isn't that right, Mr. President?
- No they're not, Eli.
- I'm making them laugh.
Yeah. Not this way.
There's a good kind of laughing
and a bad one. This is bad.
Eli, they're only laughing at you
because you are retarded.
I'm not retarded, I'm special.
- I'm special! Just special.
- Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry. I know you're special.
- They're being mean to you.
- I'm not retarded...
- You're retarded!
- I'm sorry!
I'm not retarded! I'm special!
I don't wanna go
to the dance with you!
Sorry!
And I'm the mean one?
How does that work?
What's going on here?
All I... I was trying
to do something nice
in this stupid school where
nothing nice ever happens
but instead,
Eli broke his arm and...
I feel like the biggest idiot
in the world.
No, why aren't you taking part
in the academic Decathlon?
We need you,
you are our best mathlete.
Oh, God, please don't say that word.
Are you having
some problems at home?
No, I'm not.
- Is it a boy?
- No.
You can tell me...
I know it seems square to actually talk
with your guidance counselor,
but I was a kid once, too.
And not that long ago.
Mr. Rosso, there is nothing to tell.
Trust me.
I see the problem here.
Let's just rap... as people. OK?
From now on,
I'm not Mr. Rosso, guidance counselor.
- You're not?
- No.
I'm just Jeff,
your friend who cares.
Jeff?
Exactly.
And you're not Ms. Weir,
high school student,
You're Lindsay, a girl
who seems like she needs a friend.
So, come on, Linds,
talk to your buddy Jeff.
I've never felt better
in all my life.
Then maybe someone
should tell your face.
Ah, yes, interesting problem...
Freshmen bullies.
He's obviously acting out of insecurity
in a new environment.
If you can disconnect emotionally,
it's really quite sad.
In his own way,
he's reaching out for a friend.
Not that you should feel sorry for him,
his kind should be destroyed.
So, what do we do?
I recommend the Cresman conundrum.
What the hell is that?
Tom Cresman, my freshman tormentor.
The idea was,
if you fight your bully,
afterwards, whether you win or lose,
they'll tend to leave you alone.
Did it work?
He broke my tailbone,
but the result was effective.
He got expelled.
- It's a good plan.
- It's a terrible plan.
I'm not fighting Alan,
he's not my tormentor.
I know every hall he takes to each
class. And I avoid those halls.
It's that simple. Just start living
at the janitor store, like I do.
- Are you looking for a fight, dork?
- No, sir.
Well, you're gonna get one!
Tell me about that stupid
Cresman conundrum.
Are you... I don't... Are you OK?
Is it just me
or does the whole world suck?
Alright, after class,
you and me are cutting out of here.
Cutting?
I've got something
to show you that...
it's gonna make you feel better.
I guess, the first thing we're
gonna do is get him on the ground.
How are we supposed to do that?
Cut his legs off?
Should I wear a cock for this?
That's between you
and your God, Bill.
Hey, geek.
Got a problem?
No, I was...
I was just looking
at a friend of mine.
Are you telling me that I look like
a friends of yours?
Kim, I think he likes you.
Is that true?
Do you like me?
Do you love me?
I like you like a friend.
I don't think so.
I think you like me like me.
I think you want to kiss me.
Do you wanna kiss me?
I don't know.
Come on.
Just one little kiss.
I'll be your girlfriend.
In your dreams, geek.
Maybe we should get her
to beat up Alan.
Go.
Wait for me, man.
Be prepared to have your mind blown!
Check it out, man.
That's fourteen mounted toms,
eight floor toms,
four splashers, two gongs,
ten Caravelles, four rides,
five snares, man...
a roto tom rack!
And it's all mounted on my infamous
quadruple kick drums system.
Six more pieces, and I got a bigger kit
than Neal Perth drums from Rush.
That's great, Nick.
Look, these teachers
want us to work, you know?
And I say, fine. I'll work.
But you gotta let me do
the kind of work I want to do.
And for me, Lindsay,
it's my drum kit, man.
This is my passion, you know?
This is the essence of who I am now.
But before I had this,
I was lost, too.
You see what I'm saying?
You need to find...
your reason for living.
You gotta find your big,
gigantic drum kit, you know?
Maybe I'll buy a clarinet.
If you're not going to the dance,
I thought you could come over my house.
A bunch of guys who play guitar
are gonna come.
We're gonna try playing
"Dark side of the moon".
Just tell your dad you went.
I can't lie to my dad.
Really?
Why don't you tell your dad
you got a date?
I'll put on a suit.
I'll come pick you up,
talk nice to your dad,
and then I'll take you to the school.
We can walk up to the door of the dance,
and then we can take off.
Then you can tell your dad you went.
You wouldn't be lying.
You'd really do that?
Absolutely.
Hello, there.
Hello Jeff.
Guess who's in trouble.
Here's the deal.
If you get take part in
the academic Decathlon,
I'll forget this ever happened.
You're forcing me to a mathlete?
That is so not fair.
The world is not black and white.
It's gray.
And I really think
it'd be good for you.
I really do can't that.
Fine, Ms. Weir.
Maybe it's time for some tough love.
How about I call your parents?
And let them know
that their daughter is turning into
a burnout who skips class.
You know what,
I can't make you be a mathlete.
But I can make you work
the refreshment table
at the homecoming dance.
I'll see you Saturday at 7 pm.
You know who used to cut class?
Jimi Hendrix.
You know what happened to him?
He died!
Choking on his own vomit.
Dad, I skipped Latin.
Oh, I can understand why you
wouldn't want to learn about that.
It's only the building block
of our language.
I'm just glad your grandmother
wasn't alive to hear about this.
You can't cut corners in life.
You know who cut corners?
Kennedy.
Kennedy cut corners when
he was running the Bay of Pigs.
A lot of good men lost
their lives because of it.
You know who else cut corners?
Janis Joplin.
Dad!
What are you talking about?
You don't make any sense!
I just cut class and guess what?
Everybody's still alive.
Just leave me alone.
You understand what I'm saying,
don't you, Sam?
Good. Pass the rolls.
Can I come in?
Do you think that me,
Neal and Bill could beat up Alan?
Just Alan?
Alan and his buddies...
- No to maybe.
- That's what I thought.
Why are you throwing your life away?
Did Dad tell you to ask me that?
No, Millie did.
You tell her to mind
her own business.
Just because
she asked me to ask you,
doesn't mean I was gonna
tell her what you said.
They ever told you that I was
the only one with Grandma when she died?
No.
They went down to the cafeteria
to get some coffee.
Grandma looked so terrified.
I didn't know what to do.
She grabbed my hand,
and told me she didn't want to go.
She looked so scared, Sam.
So I said, "can you see...
God, or a heaven or a light
or anything?"
What did she say?
"No.
There is nothing."
She was a good person all her life,
and that's what she got.
So...
you do think we could beat up Alan?
He's a goner.
Where is Sam? It's almost 3 pm.
Alan is gonna be here soon.
I bet he forgot his math book.
I'm sure he is coming.
Collin! You came to help us?
No way, I just came to watch.
Should be exciting.
Because we are going to win?
Either way.
Oh, man, where is Sam?
Can't talk, gotta fight Alan.
Where is Sam? It's three o'clock.
Don't let Alan hit any
of your pressure points.
If he does, you're not gonna feel
anything but you'll drop dead in 3 days.
- My stomach hurts.
- Bill, you'll be fine.
No, it really hurts.
I think I should go home.
This is how Houdini died.
Always guard your face.
If he hits in the nose, it could
drive the nose bone into your brain.
Then you'll release
your bowels and die.
Shut up, would you.
He's right. There are a lot
of ways to die in a fight.
Maybe we should put this off.
There is Sam.
Stop, you moron!
It's not Sam, it's Alan!
- So, what are you doing?
- Just going home.
- And you?
- I'm cheerleading the game.
Well, you're dressed for it.
What are you losers
doing on my street?
- Nothing.
- We're kind of here to beat you up.
- Really?
- He is just kidding.
I'm not talking to you, dork.
- What are you laughing at, pinhead?
- I'm just here to watch.
Really? Well, watch this.
You are so dead!
I gotta get out there. I'll see you!
See you.
I was wondering...
Do you wanna go to
the homecoming dance with me?
I'm already going with Dan Lewis,
he asked me two weeks ago.
I just thought I would ask just in case
you didn't have anyone to go.
I gotta go, so I'll see you.
If you're there,
I'll save a dance for you.
See you.
That could be good.
Get off me, you psycho!
You ripped my shirt.
You're gonna buy me a new shirt!
You guys are all dead, man!
Really dead!
I got punched in the nose,
but I'm still alive.
I guess the nose bone
must have missed my brain.
Yeah, my stomach
does not hurt anymore.
Mine does.
Did you see me? I was taunting him.
He was terrified.
Did you see me? I had his arms.
Totally shut him down.
I had his shoes.
Wait a minute.
You guys fought Alan.
No, we got hit by a car.
I'm so sorry.
I was talking to Cindy.
- You stood up for me.
- You should see how he looks.
We tore his shirt.
So what did she say?
She's got a date.
But she's saving a dance for me.
So you're going?
You got a slow dance.
Yes, definitely slow.
Thanks. You know,
I'll be there the next time.
Oh, God,
I hope there's not a next time.
Look, I know you're not
happy about this, but...
don't make me the bad guy, here.
If the worst thing in your life was
somebody making you to go to a dance,
then I'd say you have
a pretty good life.
I was wondering...
You said you would save
a dance for me, so...
can I have it now?
I mean, if you're not busy.
I'm not busy.
Come on, Sam.
What are you thinking about,
Lindsay?
I think I'm gonna dance with Eli.
I'll be right back, Jeff.
Oh, Linds...
Maybe you should start
calling me Mr. Rosso again.
That's the perfect couple.
They've got some chemistry.
- Shut up.
- What did I do?