Freaks and Geeks S01E11 Looks and Books (VO)
Hey, um...
My friend was wondering, uh...
If i gave you a joint,
would you have sex with me?
What?
I can't believe you did it.
Lindsay!
Hey! hey, guess what?
We got a gig.
Yeah. Stroker's brother's
gonna let us play at his party.
Uh, he's even gonna loan us
A marshall stack and a peavey bass cabinet.
It's, like, total pro equipment.
Yeah. We're gonna blow
the roof off his garage
In a most rock-tagious way.
Wow. That's really great, you guys.
So we just need your parents'
station wagon to pick up the amps.
What? You guys can't use my parent's car.
They're insane about it.
My dad even calls it betty.
Lindsay, please.
I mean, we need to get
those amps. Don't be lame.
I'm not being lame, daniel.
My parents are never gonna let us
Borrow their station wagon.
Well, didn't you say
That your mom plays bridge
or something on tuesdays?
Yeah, so?
So, she won't even know it's
gone. Just grab the keys.
We'll be back before she
finishes the first hand.
I don't know.
Oh! Squirrel!
Lindsay, whoa ! Jeez, my neck !
Just run over the stupid squirrel, linze.
Lindsa lindsay: aw.
Y, you are a terrible driver.
Shut up, daniel.
You are.
How far is this place, Japan ?
No. We're almost there.
it's on the next block.
No, daniel, i told you.
It's not on hancock. it's on warren.
It's on hancock. i was just there.
Hey, could you put on some real music?
I hate this new wave crap.
No. No. Leave it on,
man. that's joe jackson.
His bass player's unbelievable, man.
Hey, there's valerie's house, you guys!
You guys, i'm telling you,
we're going the wrong way.
Lind no, we're not.
Y, please drive like a normal person.
I am driving nice.
Yeah. Yeah. roll down the windows
'Cause i got a big one a-brewing.
Oh, no. Please don't.
Ew. Ken, you better not.
Ken: it's coming! lindsay: ew!
Those miller farts are unbelievable.
Lindsay, that's it!
That's the house over there! Right there!
Where ?
Watch out!
Oh, my god!
Oh, my god.
I hate being in school after it's out.
Makes me feel like a janitor.
Janitors are cool.
I'd like to be a janitor.
Why? So you can show up with the red sawdust
After a kid throws up?
No. 'Cause janitors make
way more than teachers.
It makes up for all that
gross stuff they have to do.
Todd: why? cindy: oh, you.
Because i'm a girl.
Come on, girls can call guys.
Girls do not call guys.
Sure, they do.
No, they don't.
Come on.
What's so great about him anyway?
It's the hair.
Oh, come on !
She likes him because of his hair?
Of course. He's got the
feathered thing going.
Girls love that.
Yeah. All the men my mom dates
Have feathered hair.
I heard
Her talking to her girlfriends.
She said any guy with
feathered hair is foxy.
But it's just hair.
I mean, why would girls
care how you comb it?
That's women.
They get turned on by weird stuff.
My god, look at my car!
What were you doing?
What were you thinking about?
I am so, so sorry.
What is wrong with
You? Didn't you see me
pulling out of the driveway?
Hey, lady, she said she was sorry.
You know, we're all a little upset here.
Don't talk to me now. do not talk to me.
Barbara, could you call the police?
The police?! come on, lady!
Calm the hell down, all right?
Kim, knock it off!
God, this is all your fault!
What? Lindsay, how is this my fault?
Oh. "that's the house!"
that's when you were-
Hey, hey, hey, guys!
Take it easy. it's both your faults.
What? This is not my fault, daniel.
You're the one who talked me into this.
I didn't talk you into anything.
Do you have any idea how
much trouble i am gonna be in?
You are gonna pay for every last
cent of this damage, young lady.
Hey, lady. There's something
you might not have heard of.
It's called insurance.
Oh, please. You just stay
away from me. Just stay away.
Yeah. Who wants to be near
you anyways. You're too sexy.
Oh, please. Oh, man.
Olice.you know that?
I could call the police
And report this as grand theft auto.
I can send my own dyou know that?
I'm so sorry, daddy.
You know what?
Lieve anythingyou say anymore.
Why should i?
You're grounded.
I can't even tell you for how long.
You'll be coming homeand
sitting in your room.
No stereo, no radio,
No tv, no nothing.
And you are not to hang out
With those burnt-out friends of yours...
Ever again.
Ever! Do you hear me?
Don't worry.
I won't.
You'd beer not.
Hey, lindsay.
I saw the smashed car in your driveway.
Just wanted to make sure
Are you ok, lindsay?
Yeah.
No.
It was so terrible, millie.
It just didn't sound like
anything you've ever heard.
It was just this thud.
It was so scary.
Who was in the car with you?
Who do you think?
Sorry, lindsay.
If y
Ou want, i can go get my uno deck.
No. I'm fine.
Did you hear what happened
at the mathlete scrimmage
Against north lake?
Katie got so nervous when
she went up to do her round
That she got a bloody nose.
And then, she didn't know it.
She had to sneeze, and she
blew blood all over the place.
She looked down, and
she saw it on her shirt,
And she fainted.
Uh-uh.
No, she didn't.
Well, no, but...
She was gonna.
It was pretty funny.
So, how's the team doing this year?
They, uh
- it's been cool.
Not as fun as last year.
I really miss you, lindsay.
All the mathletes do.
I've got my clipboard, textbooks
Lead me to the station...
Oh, man.
How am i gonna get this on
without messing up my hair?
Gonna run till my feet are raw
Slip kid, slip kid...
Man!
I'm a soldier at 13
Slip kid, slip kid, realization
There's no easy way to be free
No easy way to be free
Boy, i can just imagine how much
those pirates are gonna charge me.
Just pretend you know a lot about cars.
But i don't.
They can smell it, the bloodsuckers.
Yeah-
What's the matter?
Lindsay, you want some bacon?
No, thanks, mom.
I'm just gonna have some juice.
Oh, my goodness.
What?
Sam.
Hey, dad.
Sammy, you look so handsome.
Just like one of the hardy boys.
Thanks.
Hey, sam, wait up.
Bye, mom.
Bye, dad.
Wow.
My goodness.
Don't the weirs look nice today?
Thank you
See you.
See you, sam.
Ha ha ha ha!
What, did you just come from church?
So, how'd things go with your dad?
Was he pissed?
No. Not at all. he was really happy
That i stole his car and smashed it.
Hey, if it makes you feel any better,
The party got moved till tonight.
You know what, daniel?
That doesn't make me feel any better
'Cause now i'm grounded, so i can't go
To any of your stupid parties, ever.
Why don't you just sneak out?
Why don't you just go to hell?
Whoa.
God, lindsay.
Oh, shut up, kim!
I'm sick of you guys getting
me in trouble all the time.
I'm sick of you guys, period.
Maybe you're just on your period.
Yeah, daniel, that's exactly it.
I'm on my period. you figured it out.
It was a joke.
Oh, sorry.
It's hard to pick up on
the subtlety of your wit.
What's up your butt, princess?
You are, daniel! i'm tired of you using me.
You're the most selfish people
I've ever met in my life.
Look, i know you don't
care about being smart
Or going to school or anything else,
But just because your
lives are such lost causes,
Don't keep assuming that mine is.
What was that all about?
I don't know,
But it was pretty funny.
Shut up.
You know, who asked her to
hang out with us anyways?
Like we need her little
judgments all the time.
My life ain't a lost cause, you know?
Hers is.
She's just a big baby.
I told you guys that from day one.
It's like hanging out with my grandma.
Yeah. Well, little miss perfect doesn't know
What i'm gonna do with my life.
She doesn't know what my plans are.
What the hell are your plans?
I got a lot of plans.
Like?
Who are you, my guidance counselor?
What areyougonna do?
I'm gonna wait for my dad to die
So i inherit his company.
Then i'm gonna sell it and move to hawaii.
Great plan.
I don't hear anything
better coming out of you.
Well...
I'm gonna be, like, a lawyer or something.
I'm gonna put the pole on trial.
I'm gonna get guys out of jail and stuff.
You know?
Yeah. Maybe you can
break daniel out of there.
Screw you, man. i'm not going to jail.
Ok. what will you be doing?
Plenty.
Now if you're done grilling me, mr. Rosso,
Why don't you give me a dollar
so i can get some sno-balls?
Ok.
You guys, i'm telling you,
This-it's not about the accident.
Lindsay's really depressed
that i broke up with her.
She's got to get over it though, you know?
Yeah, nick. Sure.
So, i guess you're gonna be, like,
A psychiatrist or something.
No. I'm gonna be a deejay, man.
And maybe, um, a lumberjack.
The name of the company
is texas instruments,
But i heard it's made in taiwan.
Hey.
Is it ok if i sit here?
Yeah. Sit down, lindsay.
Hi, carey.
Hi.
Hi, erin. hi.
Look, lindsay. erin got a new calculator.
It graphs and everything.
I got it for my birthday.
That's cool.
Do you have a calculator, lindsay?
No. My dad won't buy me one.
He says einstein did fine
without one and so should i.
You don't need one, lindsay.
Yeah. remember that judge
At the intra-districts last year?
He called you the human calculator.
Oh, yeah.
I think I had a crush on you.
What?
Ew, he was, like, 40 years old.
That's so gross.
Hey, lindsay,
I'm having a slumber party friday night.
All the mathletes are gonna
be there. You wanna go?
Well...
Yeah, i would, but i'm grounded.
Oh, yeah.
Well, you should ask your dad.
It's just across the street.
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
Yeah?
Well, it maybe.
'S an interesting look, sam.
Naw. Your hair's not long
enough to be feathered.
I think it looks weird,
Like you're trying to be
all fancy or something.
I don't think you should
worry with how you look, sam.
My mom always says that you should be happy
With what the good lord gave you.
Well, the good lord gave you a lot, gordon.
Neal & sam: bill!
My whole family's big-boned. it's genetic.
Besides, the world loves jolly fat guys.
Burl ives, jackie gleason...
Santa claus, uh, curly, raymond burr.
No. Raymond burr's not jolly.
Well, he was extremely nice to me
At last year's auto show.
Hey.
Do any of you guys have
a pencil i could borrow?
Oh, hey, cindy. how's it going?
It's ok. today in chemistry,
I sat on a piece of chocolate
And had to go home and change my pants.
Oh. Yeah.
Sam, did you wear a hat today?
Because your hair looks kind of flat.
Got one.
Thanks
I'll bring it right back.
You better.
Oh, man.
You can't just comb your hair different
And expect cindy to start liking you.
You have to dress different, too.
I dress ok.
Sam, you look like your mother dresses you.
Hey, well, at least i don't dress
like a ventriloquist's dummy.
Don't kill the messenger.
I know i look good. i dress well,
And i groom myself properly.
Look around.
The whole school dresses better than you do.
Change your clothes, change your life.
Pirates.
We live right outside detroit,
And they can't find a fender?
Now i get 2 weeks of driving around town
Looking like some kind of hillbilly.
Hey, dad, can i borrow some money?
Hmm?
Uh, i wanna buy some new clothes tomorrow.
Oh, sammy, i'll take you to the mall.
We'll use my credit cards.
And then we can go to
magic pan and get crepes-
Oh, no. Mom! You always
get me something stupid,
Like garanimals or something like that.
I wanna buy my own clothes.
Good idea Sam.
A man has to learn to dress himself.
You know, you got to cut
those apron strings sometime.
Dad?
I was thinking of going
back to the mathletes...
And i'll have to stay
after school for practice.
Is that ok?
Lindsay: DAD?
Well, yeah. i suppose it would be ok.
But if this is some kind of ploy,
Then heaven help you.
It's not a ploy. and thanks.
Ok.
Ok. What's the gag?
There is no gag.
I thought you wanted me back on the team.
I'd love to have you back on
the team if you're serious.
I'm serious.
That's great.
There's just one problem, lindsay.
I'm gonna have to put you in the reserves.
Really? Aren't there any open blocks?
No. It's a big team this year.
Look, why don't you
start coming to practices
Until you get caught up,
And maybe in a couple of weeks,
We'll see what we can do. all right?
Yeah. Ok.
All right.
I got to go to class.
No. Come on. let's get out of here.
Dez gave me the keys to his place.
We'll go earn some extra biology credit.
What's your problem?
I told you. i have to go to class.
Oh. Ok, lindsay.
You know what? shut up, man!
I thought you were the guy
that had all these big plans.
Yeah. I went to all my classes yesterday.
I could barely stay awake.
Then drink a cup of coffee
And get it together, daniel.
I'm out of here.
So, carl sagan say "that's not a cosine.
You don't know your asymptote
from a hole in the ground."
Oh, hi, lindsay.
Hey, shelly.
I hear that
You have to be on the reserves.
That's too bad.
You know, shelly,
If you give up first block,
Then lindsay could have
her spot back on the team.
Millie.
Just kidding.
Don't kid about first block.
Sorry.
You know, m.i.t. looks way more
carefully at your application
If you've been a first block.
I just can't believe that you
would give up being first block
Just to hang out with freaks.
God, shelly!
It's true! i'm not putting her down.
I mean, they're the ones who made
her get into that car accident.
I bet you they were all high.
Nobody was high.
Oh. Was that kim girl with you?
She's pregnant, you know.
My neighbor works at the free clinic,
And he said that he sawer
over there the other day.
Just because a girl chooses to live
her life differently than you do
Doesn't mean she's automatically
barefoot and pregnant.
I didn't say she was barefoot.
I mean, don't get all mad.
Anyway, you know her better than i do.
Mr. Kowchevski, i nt you
to make me first block.
Nice to see you, too!
Look, at least put me back on the team.
I am the best person at math in this school.
Well, actually, i think that i'm the
best person at math in this school.
Ok. But, come on,
Let's cut the crap, kowchevski.
Ok. you're right, lindsay,
The team needs you desperately. I mean,
If it wasn't for shelly,
we'd be in the toilet.
I cannot bounce anyone from this team.
They've been coming every day,
lindsay, it wouldn't be fair.
This is the mathletes,
not the football team.
What is the difference? it's still a team.
So if you're gonna have a team,
You might as well have a winning one.
Otherwise, what the hell
is the point of competing?
Looks like a disco.
Hey, guy, you can't eat in here.
I'm not done.
I can't throw it away.
Well, i can't have you getting mustard
All over our garments.
Yeah, maybe you should wait outside.
No, no, no.
There. All gone.
Excellent. Well, uh,
What can i help you gents out with today?
Yeah, uh, i wanna buy some new clothes.
Something that'll make me look like
The best-dressed kid in school.
Well, i've got a question for you.
You wanna be a stud,
Or do you wanna be a super stud?
Super stud, sam. go for super stud.
All right, then. walk this way.
All right, guys. check it out!
It's the latest thing in.
It's the hottest thing going
In europe right now.
What is it?
This is a parisian nightsuit,
And i predict every trendsetting guy
In this city's gonna own one.
Wow.
Really?
Really is right.
Buy this garment, and i guarantee
You'll be perceived as a man
of distinction by the ladies.
I don't know.
Hey, guys, look at me.
You know, i'm not a handsome man,
But i learned how to style my hair,
Started wearing some of these clothes.
It's been pretty cool.
All right, gang. I've had
to make some tough decisions
About who's gonna be competing tomorrow,
And some of you are not gonna like that.
Lindsay, you're on the team.
She rejoins and gets into
competition in one day?
That's not fair!
No, shelly, it's not fair,
But if we lose against lincoln tomorrow,
We're gonna blow our home
advantage for the rest of the year.
This is just a little insurance.
Well, then, who's gonna get bumped?
Well, that's strictly a decision based
On the last few practices.
Millie, would you mind sitting out tomorrow?
Oh.
No, mr. Kowchevski.
That's fine. i don't mind.
No, mr. Kowchevski, i-i
don't think millie should-
No, lindsay. that's cool.
The team really needs you.
No, we don't!
This is completely unfair to you, millie.
I said it's ok, shelly.
Care
DOESN'T MATTER. SHE'S NOT-
This is unfair to all of us!
You know, mind your own business!
This is my business!
No, it's not. shelly, i'm not trying-
Ladies, ladies !
This is just
For tomorrow's scrimmage.
This isn't the last chopper out of saigon,
So can we please just crank
down the drama a notch, ok?
Ow!
Hey, cindy, what's happening?
Hey! Hey, cindy!
Hey, cindy, what's up?
Hey, ouch! Ow! Ow!
Oh? Oh!
Well, she's a flame
Fla-a-a-ame
Flamethrower, she's a...
Let's you and me get outta here.
She's a flame
Fla-a-a-ame
A red-hot blower, she's a
Flamethrower tonight
Ow!
Jeez, millie, don't you
ever clean your room?
I just did.
I'm really glad mr. Kowchevski
Kicked me off the team so you can be on it.
He didn't kick you off the team, millie.
He just put you on the reserves.
Yeah, i know. don't worry.
How much does shelly know about trig?
Is she good at it?
I think so
. We don't have too many trig questions.
Yeah, but when you do,
does she get 'em right?
I don't know. i forget.
Millie! Come on, think!
If i'm gonna blow shelly out of the water,
I gotta know this stuff.
Think mr. Kowchevski'll
move you to first block?
He'd better.
If i'm gonna be the mathletes,
i'm gonna be number one,
Or else i'm not gonna do it.
Hey, mom. hey, honey.
I think i'm gonna eat in my room
so i can cram for the scrimmage.
Oh, lindsay, you've been studying nonstop.
Why don't you take a little break?
Mom,
I can't. not if i wanna win.
Lindsay, there is more
to life than competition.
Not if you want to wipe out shelly weaver.
Ah. Is she from lincoln?
No, she's on our team.
Oh. Hey, lindsay?
What?
Are you having fun?
Yeah. Course i am.
Hi.
Hey.
Ok what you say...
Hey!
Hello!
Go on and laugh at me 'cause you don't see
That i got something going right here
You gotta look sharp
And you gotta have no illusions...
What the hell is this?
Oh, man. whoa!
Hey, henson, look!
It's the new disco ken doll!
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, pull the string and make him talk!
I'm telling you, you can light them
It's methane.
Yeah, but what if the
flame goes back inside you?
Do you
- do you explode?
Hey!
Oh, my god.
I guess elvis hasn't left the building.
Hey, don't make fun of him.
Th
At's a parisian nightsuit,
In case you didn't know.
Hey, you guys-
A parisian? ooh la la!
No, no. it's a jumpsuit.
My grandpa in fort lauderdale
Be wears them all the time
Cause he's too lazy to put on pants.
Listen! I gotta get out out of here!
Head for the front door.
Hey, hey, what t-
Why did you buy that?
Hey, you were the one that
said i should dress better.
Yeah, i didn't say you should
dress like evel knievel.
Hey, guys, i think we're directing
More attention toward us by doing this.
This is cool.
I feel like i'm in the secret service.
Get me to the front door.
Test.
Hey, what are you doing?
W-we gotta go.
We got a pop quiz in
whitman's class, remember?
Oh, man! Ok, uh...
Ok, tell whitman that i missed the bus.
Ok.
'Scuse me. where you going?
Yeah, uh, i was just gonna
go outside to get something.
Yeah? Well, unless you're
going out to drive a bus,
You'd better turn around
And get your butt to class.
Sorry.
Nice dud junior.
Ok, now,
Who wants to take a crack at identifying
All the prepositional
phrases in these sentences?
No takers, huh?
Ok...sam.
Do you want to come up
here and give it a shot?
Come on, sam. make me proud.
My, don't you look nice!
Homo
Hey, hey, hey!
Now-now if sam wearing something different
To express his individuality
Makes him a "homo,"
Well, then, i guess we should all be proud
To be "homos."
Now you go ahead, sam.
You're not gonna beat me up, are you?
No.
What are you reading?
The, uh, the monster manual.
It's adungeons and dragons handbook.
Do you play?
No.
You should.
You'd make a goo
D dungeon master. I can tell.
Yeah?
Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Can i ask you something?
Sure.
What do you make of me?
Excuse me?
Well, if someone asked you...
"What do you think of daniel
desario?" what would you say?
Would you say he's a loser?
Um, um, no.
No, you're not a loser, 'cause you have sex.
But, if you weren't having sex,
Then we could definitely debate the issue.
Right.
You get good grades, huh?
Yeah, don't you?
No. I get terrible grades.
I don't even like thinking about school
'Cause i think about
how bad i'm really doing.
I was even left back once.
Ouch. Well...
Today is the first day
of the rest of your life.
Someone sent my dad a card with that on it
For his 65th birthdays.
You're dad's 65?
70 now.
When i'm 45 he'll be 100.
You know, you're a pretty
interesting guy, harris.
Yeah, i mean, you do your own thing.
You're comfortable with yourself.
You got it pretyeah, i guess i do.
I don't have sex, though.
Ok, people, listen up. let's not get cocky
Just 'cause we have the
home-field advantage.
Now you all know your stuff,
So just stay clearheaded,
and we blaze through this.
Now let's go kick some lincoln butt!
Come on! Let's go.
Good luck, everybody.
Good luck, shelly.
Thanks. Same to you.
Good luck, lindsay.
Even though i know you don't need it.
Go, first block!
Nick?
Oh, what are you doing here?
What areyou doing here?
I
Was just, um, killing some time.
All right, i gotta get going.
Mrs. Amendella?
Hi, it's sam from next door.
Yeah, my mom's not home.
do you know where she is?
Oh, ok. All right, well, i'm at mckinley.
You think you could pick me up?
'Scuse me. Aren't you danny
terrio fromdance fever?
No, i told you, it's
chrissy fromthree's company.
Ha ha ha ha!
What do you want, alan?
I just wanna know something.
Exactly how queer are you?
Shut up.
No, really, really, i'm serious.
You know, just when i think
He's as queer as he can be,
You go and do something even queerer.
Let me alone, alan! i'm sick of you!
Oh, my god. it's go time!
Hey!
Alan, how many times a day
To be cool?
I'm just trying to talk to sam.
Yeah, yeah, it looked like you guys
Were having a regular meeting of the minds.
What's this all about, sam?
Mr. Rosso...
I need a ride home.
If the hour hand of a clock
Moves k radians in 48 minutes,
Then k equals...
Theye a tough team.
You nervous?
I don't get nervous.
Wow. that's great.
I wish i was that confident.
It comes with being first block.
Yeah, i remember.
0.4.
Correct.
Well, guess i'm up. wish me luck.
Woo hoo!
Question one:
If the longer diagonal of a rhombus is 10,
And the large angle is 100 degrees,
What is the area of the rhombus?
42.
Correct.
Woo! woo hoo!
You ok, sam?
I thought you were gonna change.
Do i have to go back to school?
I mean, i'm sick of
everybody laughing at me.
So? Let 'em laugh.
Who cares?
Sam, when i was about 20,
I was hanging out in
this honky-tonk down south
When a big bunch of rednecks surrounded me.
Started making jokes about my fringe vest,
My hair.
Calling me a hippie, a woman.
They dragged me into an alley,
Made me dance,
Told me to bark like a dog.
Did you do it?
Yeah.
Pretty much had to, there was 10 of them.
Heh. What happened?
It doesn matter.
What matters is that i
never lost pride in who i am.
Mr. Rosso,
I dressed up just to impress cindy sanders.
Sam, some of my friends
Are the dirtiest, stinkiest
guys you'll ever meet,
But they date more women
Than you or i could ever hope for.
It's all about confidence.
It's true.
If i say i'm the coolest guy in the world
And i believe i'm the
coolest guy in the world,
Then suddenly i become
The coolest guy in the world.
I'm telling you, it
sounds weird, but it works.
But i'm not cool.
You're not?
No.
Hmm.
Well, then take a look at this kid.
Because that's a cool kid.
One horizontal and one vertical asymptote.
Correct. well done, mckinley.
"If arcsine x equals 2 arc cosinex,
Thenx equals..."
Damn, i've never felt so stupid
In my whole life.
0.9.
Correct
Perfect round to mckinley.
You were great, lindsay.
You were so great.
You're a born mathlete.
Ok, shelly, come on.
Let's give them that old
mckinley one-two punch.
Good luck, shelly.
"A sphere is inscribed in a cube.
"The ratio of the volume of the sphere
To the volume of the cube is..."
Come on, shelly.
We just went over this last week.
0.52:1.
Correct.
Did you guys see shelly
When she missed that square root problem?
She started sweating like a pig.
Hey Millie,
Now maybe kowchevski.
Will kick her off the team,
And you can get your block back.
I guess. i hope so.
I mean, i kind of felt
bad for shelly, though.
Forget her. she had it coming.
Hey, you guys, come here.
You've got to see M.I.T.'s dorms.
If i think i'm cool,
Then people will think i'm cool, too.
Yeah, that's what mr. Rosso said.
Yeah, and he's cool.
Yeah, but i already think i'm cool.
Maybe that'sso am i. but nobody
ebecause you're noti'm really cool.
You know what, sam?
You actually do seem cooler all of a sudden.
I think it's working.
Mr. Rosso's some kind of genius.
Lindsay
Where are you going?
Millie, i gotta go home.
What's the matter?
Are you gonna go use your own bathroom?
No, it's...
I just can't do this.
Yeah. I mean,
It's been great hanging out with you,
But it's just not where i'm at anymore.
Things are different now.
Whatare you gonna do ?
I don't know,
But i don't think i want to be a mathlete.
That's ok. I understand.
But can we still play uno sometimes?
I mean, when you've got nothing else to do?
Yeah, we can always do that.
Millie, we'll always be friends.
I'll see you around tomorrow, ok?
Hey do you guys want to
maybe go see a midnight movie?
I think there's a foreign film playing
At the state theater.
A foreign film? Is that
the kind you have to read?
What's the point?
The point is trying not to be a dumb ass
For once in your life, that's what.
That's the point, apparently.
I'll go.
Thank you, babe.
It just better not be
about a guy who talks a lot.
Hey.
What's up?
Nothing. What are you guys up to?
Nothing.
Actually,
We were just about to go see a foreign film.
Cool.
You know, just because.
Can i come with you guys?
Sure.
Can we borrow your dad's car?
Aww.
Shut up, man.
Come on, linze, you can
ride with kim and me.
Come on.
Let's go.
Hey, lindsay?
I just wanted to tell
you that i'm really glad
That you're feeling
better about our break-up.
I think you're handling it really well.
Uh, thanks, nick.
I think i'll be ok.
Hey, I didn't get all gussied up.
To sit here alone, man.
I'm coming, let's go.
Follow me me, cause
You're going down Desario