TYSON".
The age and size of the cosmos...
...are written in light.
The nature of beauty
and the substance of the stars.
The laws of space and time.
They were there all along...
...but we never saw them...
...until we devised
a more powerful way of seeing.
The story of this awakening
has many beginnings...
...and no ending.
Its heroes come from many times
and places.
An ancient Chinese philosopher...
...a wizard who amazed the caliphs
of 11th-century Iraq...
...a poor German orphan enslaved
to a harsh master.
Each one brought us a little closer...
...to unlocking the
secrets hidden in light.
Most of their names are
forever lost to us...
...but somewhere, long ago,
someone glanced up...
...to see light perform
one of its magic tricks.
Who knows?
Maybe that quirk of light
inspired the very first artists.
Where did all this come from?
How did we evolve
from small wandering bands...
...of hunters and gatherers
living beneath the stars...
...to become the builders
of a global civilization?
How did we get from there to here?
There's no one answer.
Climate change,
the domestication of fire...
...the invention of tools, language,
agriculture...
...all played a role.
Maybe there was something else too.
In China more than 2000 years ago...
...a philosopher named Mo Tze
is said to have observed...
...that light could be made to paint a
picture inside a locked treasure room.
This was the description
of the first camera.
The camera obscura...
...the prototype
of all image-forming cameras...
...including the one
that's bringing you this picture.
Taking advantage of this funny thing
that light does...
...resulted in what could be called
the first movie.
Mo Tze, master of light,
worked against all forms of darkness.
A military genius who only used his talents
to prevent violence...
...he was legendary for traveling
among the kingdoms of the warring states...
...employing ingenious strategies...
...to talk kings out of going to war.
He was one of the first
to dream of universal love...
...and an end to poverty
and other forms of inequality...
...of government for the people...
...and to argue against blind obedience
to ritual and authority.
In his writings, you can find early
stirrings of the scientific approach.
By Mo Tze's time, the Chinese had already
been recording their thoughts in books...
...for at least a thousand years.
Still, our knowledge of him
is only fragmentary.
It consists largely of a collection of
essays attributed to him and his disciples.
In one of them, entitled "Against Fate"...
...a three-pronged test
for every doctrine is proposed.
Question its basis. Ask
if it can be verified...
...by the sights and senses
of common people.
Ask how it is to be applied...
...and if it will benefit
the greatest number.
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
TYSON".
Mo Tze was extremely popular...
...but a few hundred
years after his death...
...Qin Shi Huang, the first emperor...
...and unifier of China, took power.
He took a continent
and turned it into a nation...
...that now bears his name: China.
[GRUNTS]
TYSON: Most of us know Emperor Qin for
the army of 7000 terra cotta warriors...
...that guard his tomb.
In Emperor Qin's drive to consolidate
his far-flung empire...
...he took drastic measures to standardize
everything within it.
This included mandating a single coinage...
...making uniform
all weights and measures...
...the widths of carts and roads...
...as well as the precise way
the Chinese language was to be written...
...including what you were allowed to write
and think.
Emperor Qin's philosophy,
the only one permitted...
...was called "legalism"...
...which was just what it sounded like:
Do as the law says or else.
It's a philosophy that's not highly
conducive to questioning authority.
[MAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH] "That
all the books of the
Hundred Schools of Thought
shall be burned...
...that anyone who uses history
to criticize the present...
...shall have his family executed."
[ALL GASP]
TYSON". The works of Mo Tze and Confucius
and other philosophers...
...were destroyed
in the world's first book burning.
Hundreds of scholars bravely resisted...
...by trying to preserve
the forbidden books.
They were buried alive in the capital.
Science needs the light of free
expression to flourish.
It depends on the fearless questioning
of authority...
...the open exchange of ideas.
Sparks of curiosity in the writings
of Mo Tze and his disciples...
...were effectively stomped out.
It would be another thousand years
before the next movie.
Luckily, our ship of the imagination...
...can take us anywhere in space and time.
The ancient Chinese and
Greeks observed that
light could be made to
do wonderful things.
But no one asked that question favored
by small children and geniuses alike:
Why?
Until a thousand years ago.
In the city of Basra, Iraq,
there lived another master of light.
lbn Alhazen had a passionate desire
to understand nature.
He questioned everything...
...especially those things
that everyone else took for granted.
"How do we see?" he asked.
Some of the great authorities
who came before him...
...had taught that rays
come out of our eyes...
...and travel to the objects we see
before returning to our eyes.
But Alhazen reasoned...
...that the stars were too far distant
for something in our eyes...
...to travel all the way to them
and back in the blink of an eye.
Excellent reasoning,
but Alhazen didn't stop there.
He searched for ways to compel nature
to divulge her secrets.
His culture was open to new ideas
and questioning.
It was the golden age of science
in the Islamic world.
One that stretched from Cérdoba in Spain...
...all the way to Samarqand
in Central Asia.
Christian and Jewish scholars
were honored guests...
...at the research institutes of Baghdad,
Cairo and other Islamic capitals.
Instead of burning books,
the caliphs sent emissaries...
...around the world in search of books.
The caliphs lavishly funded projects
to translate, study...
...and preserve them
for future generations.
Much of the light of ancient Greek science
would have been...
...permanently extinguished
without their efforts.
The reawakening to science
that took place in Europe...
...hundreds of years later
was kindled by a flame...
...that had been long tended
by Islamic scholars and scientists.
The Arabs also imported ideas
from India to the West...
...including the so-called Arabic numerals
that we all use today.
And the concept of zero.
Which comes in handy when you wanna
write "billions and billions."
Arabic astronomy was so influential...
...that we still call most of the
bright stars by their Arabic names.
And the "als" in "algebra," "algorithm,"
"alchemy" and "alcohol"...
...are just some of the traces left...
...from the time when Arabic
was the language of science.
In the 11th century,
lbn Alhazen set about trying...
...to test his ideas about light
and how we see.
So he devised an experiment
to determine how light moves.
He erected a tent in full daylight...
...and sealed it tightly
so that only a single ray of light...
...could pierce its inner darkness.
With little more than his brains
and a straight piece of wood-- A ruler.
--Alhazen had accomplished a great leap
forward in the history of science.
He discovered that light moves
in straight lines.
But he was just getting started.
Alhazen figured out that
the key to forming any image...
...whether you're talking about an eye
or a camera obscura...
...is a small opening
to restrict the light
that can enter an otherwise
darkened chamber.
That aperture excludes the chaos
of extraneous light rays that surround us.
The smaller the aperture, the fewer
directions that light can come from.
And that makes the image sharper.
So instead of being blinded by the light...
...we can see everything it has to show us.
Alhazen made his own camera obscura
and dazzled the caliphs.
A camera obscure works
best in bright light.
The stars of the night sky
are way too dim for this.
We somehow need a bigger
opening to collect light...
...but we also need to maintain focus.
A telescope collects light
from any spot in its field of view...
...across the entire lens or mirror...
...an opening much larger
than the camera obscure hole.
This is one of the first telescopes...
...the one that Galileo
looked through in 1609.
With it, he pulled aside
the heavy curtain of night...
...and began to discover the cosmos.
The lens made it possible...
...for a telescope to have a much
larger light-collecting area...
...than our eyes have.
Big buckets catch more rain
than small ones.
Modern telescopes have larger
collecting areas...
...highly sensitive detectors...
...and they track the same object
for hours at a time...
...to accumulate
as much of its light as possible.
Space-based telescopes
such as the Hubble...
...have captured light from the most
distant and ancient galaxies...
...giving us vastly clearer pictures
of the cosmos.
Alhazen discovered how images
are formed by light.
But that was far from
his greatest achievement.
Ibn Alhazen was the first person ever...
...to set down the rules of science.
He created
an error-correcting mechanism...
...a systematic and relentless way...
...to sift out misconceptions
in our thinking.
Finding truth is difficult...
...and the road to it is rough.
As seekers of the truth, you will be wise
to withhold judgment and not simply put...
...your trust in the
writings of the ancients.
You must question and critically examine
those writings from every side.
You must submit only to argument
and experiment...
...and not to the sayings of any person.
For every human being is vulnerable
to all kinds of imperfection.
As seekers of the truth,
we must also suspect and question...
...our own ideas
as we perform our investigations...
...to avoid falling into prejudice
or careless thinking.
Take this course,
and truth will be revealed to you.
TYSON".
This is the method of science...
...so powerful that it's carried
our robotic emissaries. ..
...to the edge of
the solar system and beyond.
It has doubled our life-span...
...made the lost worlds of the past
come alive.
Science has enabled us to predict events
in the distant future...
...and to communicate with each other
at the speed of light...
...as I am with you, right at this moment.
This way of thinking has given us powers...
...that Alhazen himself
would have regarded as wizardry.
But it was he who put us on this rough,
endless road.
And now it has taken us to a place...
...where even light itself
is enshrouded in darkness.
TYSON: Light has properties unlike anything
else in the realm of human existence.
Take the speed of light.
The basic particle of light,
a photon...
...is born traveling
at the speed of light...
...as it emerges from
an atom or a molecule.
A photon never knows
any other speed...
...and we've not found another
phenomenon that accelerates...
...from zero to top speed
instantaneously.
Nothing else can move as fast.
When we accelerate other particles
closer and closer to the speed of light...
...they resist more and more, as though
they're getting heavier and heavier.
No experiment yet devised has ever
made a particle move as fast as light.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
What was that?
You hear something?
Where was I? Oh, yeah.
I don't know anything else in life
that behaves like light.
I cannot reconcile its
strange properties...
...with everything else my senses tell me.
Our urge to trust our senses overpowers
what our measuring devices tell us about...
...the actual nature of reality.
Our senses work fine for life-size objects
moving at mammal speeds...
...but are ill-adapted for the
wonderland laws of light speed.
We don't even know why
there's a cosmic speed limit.
Time stands still when you're traveling
at the speed of light.
What is light, anyway?
Isaac Newton's enduring fascination
with light...
...began when he was a child.
In this very house.
By the time he was in his 20s,
Newton became the first person...
...to decipher the mystery of the rainbow.
Newton discovered that sunlight,
or white light...
...is a mixture of all the
colors of the rainbow.
Major discovery.
He named the displays of colors
a "spectrum"...
...from the Latin for "phantom,"
or "apparition."
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
MAN:
Begging your pardon, Master Newton...
...the cook frets
that your dinner will spoil, sir.
TYSON". No, Isaac, don't put
the magnifying glass down.
Something even more amazing
is hidden in the light.
A code, a key to the cosmos.
Isaac Newton didn't miss much,
but that one was a beaut.
He just walked right past the door
to a hidden universe.
A door that would not swing open again
for another 150 years.
It would fall on another scientist,
working in the year 1800...
...to stumble on a piece of evidence
for the unseen worlds that surround us.
By night, William Herschel
scanned the heavens...
...with the largest telescope of his time.
By day, Herschel performed experiments.
From Newton's work,
it was known that sunlight...
...is a blend of different colors.
And everyone knew,
just from being outside...
...that sunlight carries heat.
William Herschel asked whether some colors
of light carry more heat than others.
The nature of scientific genius
is to question...
...what the rest of us take for granted
and then do the experiment.
The thermometer that Herschel
placed outside the spectrum...
...was his control.
The control in any experiment...
...always lacks the factor being tested.
That way, you know if
what you're testing is
really the thing responsible
for the observation.
In Herschel's experiment,
the relationship between...
...color and temperature
was being tested...
...and so his control was a thermometer
over the part of the white sheet...
...that was not illuminated
by sunlight at all.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
TYSON".
There's that sound again.
What is that?
Okay, red light is warmer than blue light.
Interesting discovery
but not exactly revolutionary.
No, there's nothing wrong
with your thermometer.
You've just discovered
a new kind of light.
Herschel was the first
to detect this unseen presence...
...lurking just below
the red end of the spectrum.
That's why it came to be called "infrared."
"lnfra" is Latin for the word "below."
It's invisible. Our eyes are not sensitive
to this kind of light...
...but our skin is. We feel it as heat.
Now, that's a really big discovery.
But far greater secrets were still hiding
deep inside the light.
TYSON". At about the same
time that William Herschel...
...was discovering infrared light
in his parlor in England...
...a young boy named Joseph Fraunhofer...
...was trapped in hopeless drudgery.
He stood over a caldron
of toxic chemicals...
...and endlessly stirred.
Joseph had been orphaned
at the age of 11...
...and given to a harsh master
named Weichselberger...
. . . the royal mirror-maker.
He prevented Joseph from going to school.
Instead, Joseph labored...
...in the glassmaking workshop by day...
...and tended to the master's
household chores by night.
WEICHSELBERGER:
Hurry up, stupid!
And remember, no reading.
[DOOR CLOSES]
TYSON".
Until Joseph got his big break.
Weichselberger's house collapsed.
[ALL CHATTERING]
TYSON".
Maximilian, the future king of Bavaria...
...hurried to the scene of the calamity
to see if he could help.
Maximilian was known
for taking an interest in his subjects...
...which was highly unusual for its time.
In attracting the concern
of the future king of Bavaria...
...young Joseph Fraunhofer found an
aperture into a different universe.
And not just for himself.
Prince Maximilian gave Joseph money...
...and asked his privy councilor...
...to provide further help to the boy
should it be needed.
Weichselberger continued to exploit him...
...and prevent him from attending school.
But the prince's councilor intervened...
“offering Joseph a position
at the Optical Institute.
This small gesture of kindness
really paid off.
By the time he was 27...
...Joseph Fraunhofer
was the world's leading designer...
...of high-quality lenses...
...telescopes and other
optical instruments.
His firm was housed here,
in the old Benediktbeuern Abbey.
In the early 19th century...
...this was top-secret,
ultra-high technology.
The Benedictine monks of earlier times...
...had taken a vow of secrecy.
This local tradition...
...and the ability to restrict access
to Fraunhofer's laboratory...
...allowed him to maintain control...
...of trade and state secrets.
Fraunhofer was experimenting with prisms...
...to find the best types of glass
for precision lenses.
How, he wondered,
could he get a better look...
...at the spectrum that a prism produced?
Friedrich, bring me the theodolite, please.
Okay, while Fraunhofer
sets up his theodolite--
It's a kind of telescope.
--I wanna show you something
in another part of the abbey.
Sound waves are so beautiful to hear.
Imagine how beautiful they'd be to see.
You ever wondered why organ pipes
have different lengths?
I press a key... [PLAYS NOTE]
...it sends compressed air
into a particular pipe...
...producing sound waves.
If we could slow the sound waves
down a few hundred times...
...they would look like this.
[TYSON PLAYING NOTE ON ORGAN]
The length of the pipe...
...determines the length of the sound wave
that can fit inside it.
A short pipe gives you a short sound wave.
[TYSON PLAYING NOTE ON ORGAN]
TYSON: Short sounds waves have high pitch,
or frequency.
Let's stop the waves for a better look.
[PLAYS NOTE]
TYSON:
The distance between adjacent waves...
...is called the wavelength.
A long pipe gives you a long sound wave...
...with a low pitch, or low frequency.
[PLAYING J.S. BACH'S
"MINUET IN G-MAJOR"]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[STOPS PLAYING]
[PLAYING "CARM I NA BU RANA"]
The medieval manuscript
of this music, Carmina Burana...
...was discovered in this very abbey.
Sound waves can't travel through a vacuum.
They need matter to ride on...
...like molecules of air or water or rock.
But light waves fly solo.
They can move through empty space,
and fast.
A million times faster
than sound waves in air.
And the wavelengths of the light we see...
...are so much shorter than sound waves...
...about 50,000 light waves...
...would fit right in here.
Oh, yeah.
Fraunhofer.
Just in time.
We didn't miss it.
Just as the wavelength of sound
determines the pitch that we hear...
...the wavelength of light
determines the color that we see.
But how does a prism...
...spread out the colors
concealed in a beam of sunlight?
When light travels through air or space...
...all its colors move at the same speed.
But when it hits glass at an angle...
...the light slows down
and changes direction.
Inside the prism,
each color moves at a different speed.
In glass, violet light...
...which is carried
by the shortest waves we see...
...slows down more than red light...
...which has the longest waves.
These changes in speed...
...pry the colors apart...
...sending their waves off
in slightly different directions.
That's how a prism works.
If I seem unduly emotional about this...
...it's because Joseph Fraunhofer
is about to do...
...what Isaac Newton could've done
but didn't.
And it'll have a powerful effect...
...on the course of my own life.
You are witnessing the marriage
of physics and astronomy...
...the birth of my own field of science:
astrophysics.
Written in the light...
...in those vertical black lines...
...is secret code.
Fraunhofer looked at them, and wondered:
Why?
TYSON". A code that comes to
us from an alien universe.
TYSON: What is the message written
in these dark vertical lines?
It took a hundred years of thinking...
...questioning, searching to decipher it.
Lovely, isn't it?
Why?
There are many layers
to the fine structure of beauty.
The chemistry of the Earth
and its atmosphere...
...the evolution of life.
Many distinct threads.
Let's just examine one at the surface:
The colors of nature that dazzle us.
What's really happening?
How does the red, the blue...
...the astonishing palette
of nature's colors...
...how do they happen?
Light waves of different lengths
from the sun strike the Earth.
The petals of these particular flowers...
...absorb all the low-energy,
long red wavelengths of light.
But the petals reflect the shorter,
high-energy blue wavelengths.
That interaction
between starlight and petal...
...or water, or van Gogh...
...is what makes blue.
The longest waves...
...the ones we see as red...
...have the lowest energy.
Color is the way our eyes perceive
how energetic light waves are.
A sunset...
...a flag...
...the eyes of your beloved...
...that shiny new car.
The feelings they inspire...
...happen when something inside you...
...is triggered by a
particular variation...
...in the frequency and
energy of light waves.
And the secret message?
Those black vertical lines
in Fraunhofer's spectrum?
What makes them?
They occur when the light waves...
...of those particular colors
are being absorbed.
It happens on another level of reality...
...far smaller than the world
we're used to operating in.
To get there, we'll need to become
10 billion times smaller than we are.
We could pick any one of these atoms.
But let's go for the hydrogen atom.
The hydrogen atom is the most
plentiful kind of atom in the cosmos.
And the simplest.
It has only one electron.
And only one proton.
We've entered the quantum realm.
It doesn't correspond
to ordinary human experience.
Common sense is no help here at all.
Take the hydrogen atom's electron,
for example.
In an atom, an electron doesn't exist
between orbitals.
It disappears from one orbital
and reappears in another.
It's as if you took an elevator
from the second floor to the fourth ﬂoor...
...but ceased to exist in between.
And another thing. Quantum elevators
only stop at certain floors.
The sizes of the electron orbits
are strictly limited...
...and different
for the atoms of every element.
That's why the elements are different.
The chemistry of anything
is determined by its electron orbits.
The force that holds an electron in orbit
has nothing to do with gravity.
It's a force of electrical attraction.
The electron dances a wavy ring...
...around the central nucleus
of a hydrogen atom...
...and makes quantum leaps
from orbit to orbit.
Up or down.
The larger the orbit...
...the greater the energy of an electron.
An electron has to get energy
to leap to a larger orbit.
And it has to lose energy
to jump back down.
Every upward leap is caused by...
...an atom absorbing a light wave.
But we have no idea what causes
the downward leaps.
What we do know is that such leaps
always produce a light wave...
...whose color matches
the energy difference...
...between the orbitals.
The sun's surface
radiates light waves of all colors.
If you look at sunlight through a prism...
...you'll see its spectrum.
When you magnify the spectrum
with a telescope...
...as Joseph Fraunhofer did...
...you raise the curtain
on the electron dance within the atom.
When the energy of the electron flags...
...and it drops to a lower orbital...
...the light wave it emits scatters.
Most of it doesn't reach us.
That leaves a dark gap...
...or black vertical line in the spectrum.
These dark lines are the shadows...
...cast by hydrogen atoms
in the atmosphere of the sun.
Sodium atoms cast different shadows.
Their electrons dance to a different tune.
A grain of table salt is composed
of sodium and chlorine atoms.
Ten million billion of them...
...doing their crazy dances...
...in a single grain of salt.
And a single iron atom with 26 electrons...
...is like a great big production number
in a Broadway musical.
When you look at a star
with a spectroscope...
...you see the dark lines
from all the elements in its atmosphere.
Show me the spectrum of anything...
...whether here on Earth
or from a distant star...
...and I'll tell you what it's made of.
Fraunhofer's lines
are the atomic signatures...
...of the elements writ large
across the cosmos.
As with every other major revelation
in the history of science...
...it opened the way
to newer and deeper mysteries.
And to the revelation
that there were many more secrets...
...hiding in the light.
When Joseph Fraunhofer
combined a prism with a telescope...
...and turned it toward the skies...
...he brought the stars much closer to us.
When he was only 39,
he contracted a fatal illness...
...perhaps as a result of his early
and long-term exposure...
...to the toxic chemicals of glassmaking.
You never know where
the next genius will come from.
How many of them do we leave
in the rubble?
The prince and his kingdom
were immeasurably enriched...
...by that act of kindness
to a poor orphan.
Fraunhofer's discoveries
transformed Bavaria...
...from a rural backwater...
...to a technological powerhouse.
As he lay dying,
the government was desperate...
...to preserve every shred
of his precious knowledge...
...about the high technology
of optical glass.
But it could only be divulged...
...to a person with top
security clearance...
...the director of the mint.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
TYSON". The government
kept Fraunhofer's
technology for making
perfect optical glass...
...a state secret for
another hundred years.
This would prove to be
a major obstacle...
...for someone we'll meet later
in our journey.
But Fraunhofer would allow
no such secrecy...
...where his pure scientific research
was concerned.
He knew that science requires
openness to flourish...
...that our understanding of nature
belongs to the world.
As soon as Fraunhofer discovered
the spectral lines...
...he published everything
he knew about them.
And the reverberations
of his momentous discovery...
...echo still.
His spectral lines revealed
that the visible cosmos...
...is all made of the same elements.
The planets...
...the stars...
...the galaxies...
...we ourselves, and all of life...
...the same star stuff.
He made it possible...
...for us to know what's in the atmospheres
of other worlds...
...and in galaxies
millions of light-years away.
Spectral lines revealed not only
the composition of far-off objects...
...but also their motion
towards or away from us.
Using them, we discovered
that our universe is expanding.
But perhaps the greatest revelation
of spectroscopy...
...is the discovery of
the thing it cannot see.
A hidden universe of dark matter...
...six times more massive
than the familiar cosmos.
It's made of some mysterious substance...
...that does not emit, reflect
or absorb any kind of light.
We only know it's there
because of its gravity...
...which pulls on all the galaxies...
...and speeds up
the visible stars within them.
There are many more kinds of light
than our eyes can see.
Confining our perception of nature
to visible light...
...is like listening to music
in only one octave.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
There are so many more.
They differ only in wavelength...
...but over a huge range.
For instance, infrared light.
The kind that William Herschel discovered.
Or x-ray light.
Or radio light.
Or in gamma-ray light.
These are not just different ways
of seeing the same thing.
These other kinds of light
reveal different objects...
...and phenomena in the cosmos.
In gamma-ray light, for example,
we can see mysterious explosions...
...in distant galaxies
that we would otherwise miss.
And in microwave light,
we can see all the way back...
...to the birth of our universe.
We have only just opened our eyes.