Boxing tonight comes
from the empire pool, wembley
And features
the main heavyweight bout
Between jack bodell, british
and empire heavyweight champion
And sir kenneth clark.
It's the first time
these two have met
So there should be
some real action tonight.
This then is the height
Of the english
renaissance
The triumph of classical
over gothic...
He's down.
Sir kenneth clark is down
in eight seconds.
But he's up again,
he's up at six.
The almost ordered facades
of palladio's villas reflect...
And he's down again
And I don't think he's going
to get up this time.
No, so jack bodell has
defeated sir kenneth clark
In the very first round
here tonight.
And so this big lincolnshire
heavyweight becomes
The new oxford
professor of fine art.
Thank you.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
And now...
It's...
Monty python's
flying circuseses.
Stand and deliver!
Drop that gun!
Let that be a warning
to you all.
You move at your peril
for I have two pistols here.
I know one of them
isn't loaded anymore
But the other one is, so
that's one of you dead for sure
Or just about
for sure anyway.
It certainly
wouldn't be
Worth your while
risking it
Because I'm
a very good shot.
I practice
every day.
Well, not absolutely every day
But most days in the week.
I expect I must practice
four or five times a week...
At least... at least
four or five
Only some weekends,
like last weekend
There wasn't much time
So that brings the average
down a bit.
But I should say
It's definitely a solid
four days' practice every week
At least.
I mean, I reckon I could hit
that tree over there--
The one behind the hillock.
Not the big hillock,
the little hillock on the left.
You can see the three trees--
The third
from the left
And back a bit,
that one--
I reckon I could hit that
four times out of five...
On a good day.
Say, with this wind, say...
say, seven times out of ten.
What-- that tree there?
Which one?
The big beech
With the sort
of bare branch
Coming out
of the top left.
No, no, not that one.
No, no, he means
the one over there.
Look, do you see
that one there?
Yes.
Well, now go two
along to the right.
Just near
that little bush.
Well, it's the one
just behind it.
Ah, the elm!
That's not an elm.
An elm's got sort of great
clumps of leaves like that.
That's either a beech
or a, um... a, uh... a hornbeam.
A hornbeam?
No, not a hornbeam.
What's the tree that has
A leaf with sort of
regular veins coming out
And the veins go
all the way out to the...
Serrated!
To the serrated edges?
A willow.
That's right.
That's nothing like a willow.
Well, it doesn't matter anyway.
I could hit it seven times
out of ten-- that's the point.
Never a willow.
Shut up!
This is a holdup,
not a botany lesson.
Right! now, my fine friends,
no false moves, please.
I want you to hand over
all the lupins you've got.
Lupins?!
Yes, lupins, come on, come on!
What do you mean-- lupins?
Don't try and play for time.
I'm not.
You mean the flower lupins?
That's right.
Well, we haven't
got any lupins.
Honestly.
Look, my fine friends
I happen to know
that this is the lupin express.
You must be out
of your tiny mind.
Get out of the coach.
Come on, get out!
Just as I thought.
Not clever enough,
my fine friends.
Come on, concorde.
Well, so much for the lupins.
Dennis moore, dennis moore
Galloping through the sward
And his horse, concorde
He steals from the rich
And gives to the poor
Mr. moore
Mr. moore...
Here we are,
I'll be back.
Mr. moore.
Morning,
mrs. trepidatious.
Oh, I don't know
what's good about it.
My right arm's hanging off
something awful.
Oh, you want to
have that seen to.
What-- by that dr. morrison?
He's killed more patients
than I've had severe boils.
What do the stars say?
Well, petula clark says
burst them early
But david frost...
No, the stars in the paper
You cloth-eared heap
of anteater's catarrh.
The zodiacal signs,
the horoscopic fates
The astrological portents
The omens, the genethliac
prognostications
The mantalogical harbingers,
the vaticinal utterances
The fratidical premonitory utterances
of the mantalogical omens.
What do the bleeding stars
in the paper predict
Forecast, prophesy,
foretell, prognosticate...
And this is where
you at home can join in.
Forebode, bode,
augur, spell...
Foretoken, presage, portend
Foreshow, foreshadow, fore-run
Herald, point to, betoken,
indicate?!
I don't know.
What are you?
I'm nesbitt.
There's not a zodiacal
sign called nesbitt.
All right,
derry and toms.
"aquarius, scorpio, virgo,
April 29 to march 22,
even dates only."
Well, what does it presage?
"you have green, scaly skin
"and a soft
yellow underbelly
"with a series of finlike ridges
"running down your spine
and tail.
"although lizardlike in shape
"you can grow anything
up to 30 feet in length
"with huge teeth
that can bite off
"great rocks
and trees.
"you inhabit arid
subtropical zones
And wear spectacles."
Hmm, it's very good
about the spectacles.
It's amazing!
Hmm, what's yours,
irene?
Basil.
I'm sorry, what's
yours, basil?
No, that's my
star sign-- basil.
There isn't
a star sign...
Yes, there is.
"aquarius, sagittarius,
derry and toms
Basil-- june 21 till june 22."
Well, what does it say?
"you have green, scaly skin
"and a series of yellow
underbellies running down
Your spine
and tail..."
That's exactly the same!
Oh! try another one.
What's aquarius?
It's a zodiacal sign.
I know that!
What's it say in the paper,
mrs. flan-and-pickle?
All right.
Oh! it says,
"a wonderful day ahead.
"you'll be surrounded
by family and friends.
"roger moore will
drop in for lunch
"bringing tony curtis with him.
"in the afternoon, a substantial
cash sum will come your way.
"in the evening, petula clark
will visit your home
"accompanied by
the mike sammes singers.
"she will sing for you
in your own living room.
"before you go to bed,
peter wyngarde will come
And declare
his undying love for you."
Both:
eww!
What's scorpio?
Oh, that's very good.
"you will have lunch with a
school friend of duane eddy's
"who will insist
on whistling
"some of duane's greatest
instrumental hits.
"in the afternoon,
you will die.
You will
be buried..."
Good morning.
Oh, morning, doctor.
And how's the old arm
this morning, mrs. ikon?
Oh, it's still hanging off at
the shoulder.
Good, well, let's have
a look at it, shall we?
Oh, damn!
Oh, damn this
wretched little bag.
Oh, damn, this wretched,
bloody little bag.
If there's one thing I hate
about being a doctor
It's this wretched,
bloody little bag.
Oh, damn this wretched,
bloody little bag!
Damn it!
Damn that wretched
little bag.
Damn you wretched
little bag!
There, right.
What's that doing in here?
Right! well...
Hand over the money.
Come on, all of it.
Thank you.
Yes, that seems
to be okay.
I'll just test
your reflexes.
Everything seems
to be okay.
I'll see you
next week.
Keep collecting
the pensions
And try not to spend
too much on food.
Thank you, doctor.
Morning, mr. henson.
How are we today?
Not too bad, doctor.
Okay, take it easy.
Expecting any postal
orders this week?
No.
Righto.
Ah, mr. rodgers,
have you got
Your unemployment
benefits, please?
Right-- well,
can you write me
A check then, please?
Thank you very much.
Soon have you
down to nothing.
Ah, mr. millichope.
Hmm... two hours
left to do.
Ooh, lovely!
Dinner's ready, dear.
Sorry, your time's up,
mr. spewm.
I'm afraid you lose
both the 3p suite
And your youngest daughter.
Hello.
Should there be another
television channel
Or should there not?
On tonight's program,
the minister for broadcasting
The right honorable
mr. ian throat m.p.
Good evening.
The chairman
Of amalgamated money tv,
sir abe sappenheim.
Good evening.
The shadow spokesman
For television, lord kinwoodie.
Hello.
And a television critic
Mr. patrick loone.
Hello.
Gentlemen
Should there be a fourth
television channel or not?
Ian?
Yes.
Francis?
Nope.
Sir abe?
Yes.
Patrick?
No.
Well, there you have it--
Two say "will," two say "won't."
We'll be back again next week,
and next week's great debate
Will be about government
interference in broadcasting
And will be canceled
mysteriously.
Just starting on bbc 1 now,
victoria regina
The inspiring tale of
the simple crofter's daughter
Who worked her way up
to become queen of england
And empress of the greatest
empire television has ever seen.
On bbc 2 now,
episode three of george i
The new 116-part serial
About the famous english king
who hasn't been done yet.
On itv now, the...
...but absolutely
delightful.
But, of course,
you know, who cares?
Ah! 'tis my lord
of buckingham.
Pray welcome,
your grace.
Thank you,
grantley.
Ladies, may i
introduce to you
The man who prophesied
That a german monarch would
soon embroil this country
In continental affairs.
Oh, how so, my lord?
Madam, you will recall that,
prior to his accession
Our gracious sovereign george
had become involved
In the long-standing
northern war
Through his claim
to bremen and verdun.
These duchies
would provide
An outlet
to the sea
Of the utmost
value to hanover.
The treaty
of westphalia
Has assigned
them to sweden.
In 1648.
Exactly.
Meanwhile,
frederick william of denmark
Taking advantage of
the absence of charles xii
Seized them-- 1712.
Oh, yes.
It all falls into
place-- more wine?
Oh, thank you.
However, just prior
to his accession
George had made an alliance
With frederick william
of prussia
On the grounds of party feeling.
While frederick william had
married george's only daughter.
I remember
the wedding.
But chiefly,
through concern
At the concerted
action...
Stand and deliver!
Dennis moore!
The same.
And now, my lords, my ladies
Your lupins, please.
Our what?
Come, come, don't play games
with me, my lord of buckingham.
What can you mean?
Your life or your lupins
My lord.
In a bunch, in a bunch.
Thank you, my friends.
And now a good evening
to you all.
He seeks them here,
he seeks them there
He seeks those lupins
everywhere.
The murdering
blackguard!
He's taken
all our lupins.
Not quite.
Oh, you tricked him.
We still
have one.
Hooray!
Dennis moore, dennis moore,
riding through the night
Soon every lupin in the land
will be in his mighty hand
He steals them from the rich
and gives them to the poor
Mr. moore
Mr. moore.
Try to eat some, my dear.
It'll give you strength.
Oh, mr. moore, mr. moore,
she's going fast.
Don't worry,
I've...
I've brought
you something.
Medicine, at last?
No.
Food?
Nope.
Blankets?
Clothes, wood for the fire?
Nope.
Lupins!
Oh, christ!
I thought you'd
like them.
I'm sick to bloody death
of them!
So am i!
She's bloody dying
And all you bring us
is lupins!
All we've eaten, mate, for
the last four bleeding weeks
Is lupin soup, roast lupin,
steamed lupin
Braised lupin
in lupin sauce
Lupin in the basket
with sauteed lupins
Lupin meringue pie,
lupin sorbet.
We sit on lupins,
we sleep in lupins
We feed the cat on lupins
We burn lupins,
we even wear the bloody things!
Looks very smart.
Oh, shut up!
We're sick to death
with the stench of them!
Look!
The cat's just choked
itself to death on them!
I don't care
if I never see another lupin
Till the day I die!
Why don't you go out
and steal something useful?
Like what?
Like gold and silver and clothes
And wood and jewels and...
Hang on, I'll get
a piece of paper.
Dennis moore, dennis moore,
dum, dum, dum, the night.
dum, de, dum, dum, plight.
He steals dum, dum, dum
and dum, dum, dum, dum, dee
Dennis, dum, dennis, dee,
dum, dum, dum.
This, coupled with the presence
Of peter and his prussians
in mecklenburg
And charles and his swedes
in pomerania
Made george and stanhope eager
to come to terms with france.
Meanwhile, a breach
had now opened with...
Oh, no, not again!
Oh, come on!
Stand and deliver again!
Your money, your jewelry,
your... hang on...
Your clothes, your snuff,
your ornaments
Your glassware,
your pussy cats...
Don't say anything
about the lupin.
Your watches, your lace,
your spittoons...
Dennis moore, dennis moore,
riding through the woods
with a bag of things
He gives to the poor
and he takes from the rich
Dennis moore,
dennis moore...
Here we are.
Dennis moore.
Well, it may be the end of that
But it's certainly far
from the end of...
Well, in fact,
it's the beginning...
Well, not quite the beginning.
Well, certainly nearer
the beginning than the end...
Well, yes, damn it, it is,
to all intents and purposes
The beginning of this year's
ideal loon exhibition
Sponsored by the daily express.
Numbskulls and boobies
from all over the country
Have been arriving to go
through their strange paces
Before a large paying crowd.
This is the 15th
ideal loon exhibition
And we took a good look round
After it was opened
by its patron.
Here's kevin bruce, the
digger duffer from down under
Who's ranked 14th in the
world's silly positions league.
This kind of incoherent behavior
Is really beginning
to catch on down under.
There's norman kirby, from
new zealand, whose specialty
Is standing behind a screen
with a lady with no clothes on.
In real life,
norman is a gynecologist
But this is his lunch hour.
And from france
There's a superb exhibition
of rather silly behavior
By the friends of
the free french osteopaths.
...trois, un, deux, trois,
un, deux, trois
Un, deux, trois,
un, deux, trois...
They do this
over 400 times a day.
Nobody knows why.
But for sheer pointless behavior
You've got
to admire brian broomers
The battling british boy
who, for two weeks
Has been suspended
over a tin of condemned veal.
Always popular with the crowd
Is the scotsman
with nae trews exhibit
And this year's no exception.
Sponsored by natural gas
and glasgow city council
This exhibit is
entirely supported
By voluntary contributions.
But for a truly magnificent
waste of time
You've got to go no further
than the exhibit from italy--
Italian priests in custard
Discussing vital matters
of the day.
These lads from a seminary
near cremona
Have been practicing
for well over a year.
As always,
one of the great attractions
Of this 14-day exhibition
Is the display
of counter marching
Given by the massed pipes
and toilet requisites
Of the colwyn bay massed pipes
and toilet requisites club.
An interesting point
about these boys is
They all have one thing
in common-- hip injuries.
Not far away,
the crowds are flocking to see
A member of the famous
royal canadian mounted geese.
But the climax of the whole
event is the judging.
Mr. justice burke.
Well, that's the last
And let's just see
those last six once again.
And the winner is
number 41, mr. justice burke.
Attention, attention,
suspect heading due north.
Plan 13-a is now in effect.
Whoop!
Yet fear,
not like an aged florin
Can so disseminate men's eyes
That fortune, straining
at a kissing touch
May stop her ceaseless search
To sport amidst
the rampant thrust of time
And bring
the thing undone to pass
By that with which the cock
may chance an arm.
Well, that's all
very well, sir
But this is
an off-license.
Uh, just a bottle
of sherry then, please.
Certainly, um,
amontillado?
Yes, I think
amontillado--
Finely grown,
well-chosen
From the cask
of pluto's hills
Cell'd deep within
the vinous soil of spain
Wrench'd thence from
fiery regions of the sun...
Yes, yes, sir,
just one bottle?
Just one bottle.
Just one jot.
Just one tittle.
That's the lot.
There we are, sir.
That'll be a pound, sir.
A pound, a pound
And all around abound
a pound found found
Lost lost the cost
till was't embossed...
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, good victualler,
nature's trencherman
Mine honest tapster...
I was just wondering,
are you a poet?
No, no, I'm... I'm a solicitor.
A solicitor... oh.
Well-versed within
the written law of man
Who can to those who need...
Oh, shut up!
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid I've caught poetry.
Oh, really?
Well, don't worry, sir
I used to suffer
from short stories.
Really? when?
Oh, once upon a time.
There lived in wiltshire
A young chap
called dennis moore.
Now, dennis was a highwayman
by profession
And for
several months
He'd been stealing
from the rich
To give to the poor.
One day...
Here we are again.
Mr. jenkins?
There we are.
I'll be back.
Meanwhile, frederick william,
busily engaged
In defending against
the three great powers
The province of silesia...
Which he
had seized
In the war of the austrian
succession
Against
his word.
Yes, I remember.
Was now dependent
on pitt's subsidies.
My lords, my ladies,
on your feet, please!
I must ask you to do
exactly as I say
Or I shall be forced to shoot
you right between the eyes!
Well, not right between the
eyes, I mean...
When I say "between the eyes"
Obviously I don't have
to be that accurate.
I mean, if I hit you
in that sort of area, like that
Obviously, that's
all right for me.
I mean, I don't
have to try
And sort of hit a point
bisecting a line
Drawn between your pupils,
or anything like that.
I mean, from my point of view,
it's perfectly satisfactory...
What do you want?
Why are you here?
Well, why are any of us here?
I mean, when you get down to it
It's all so meaningless,
isn't it?
I mean, what do any of us want?
No, no, what do you
want now?
Oh, I see, oh,
just the usual things
A little place of my own,
the right girl...
No, no, no!
What do you want from us?
Oh, um... your gold,
your silver, your jewelry.
You've taken
it all.
This is all
we've got left.
That's nice.
I'll have them.
Come on.
You'd better take the bloody
lupin, too.
Thank you very much.
I've gone through that stage.
Dennis moore, dennis moore,
etcetera, etcetera.
What you got for us
today, then?
Well, I've managed to
find you
Four very nice silver spoons,
mr. jenkins.
Who do you think
you are
Giving us poor
this rubbish?
Bloody silver--
Won't have it
in the house.
And those
candlesticks
You got us
last week
Were only 16-carat.
Yeah, why don't you go out
and steal something nice
Like some venetian silver?
Or a velasquez
for the outside loo.
Oh, all right.
Dennis moore, dennis moore,
riding through the land
without a merry band
He steals from the poor
and gives to the rich
Stupid bitch.
What did you sing?
We sang, "he steals from
the poor and gives to the rich."
Wait a tic...
Blimey, this
redistribution of wealth
Is trickier than I thought.
Good evening, and welcome
to another edition of prejudice
The show that gives you
a chance to have a go
At wops, krauts, nigs, eyeties,
gippos, bubbles, froggies
Chinks, yidds, jocks,
polacks, paddies and dagoes.
Tonight's show comes live
From the tiny village of rabid
in buckinghamshire.
And our first question tonight
is from a mrs. elizabeth scrint
Who says she is going on
a mediterranean cruise next week
And can't find anything wrong
with the syrians.
Well, mrs. scrint,
apart from being
Totally unprincipled,
left-wing troublemakers
The syrians are
also born skivers.
They're dirty, smelly
and untrustworthy
And, of course, they're friends
of the awful gippos.
Well, there you are,
mrs. scrint.
Hope that answers
some of your problems.
Have a nice trip.
Well, now, the result
of last week's competition
When we asked you
To find a derogatory term
for the belgians.
Well, the response was enormous
And we took quite a long time
sorting out the winners.
There were some
very clever entries.
A mrs. hatred,
of leicester, said
"let's not call them anything,
let's just ignore them."
And a mr. st. john,
of huntingdon, said
He couldn't think of anything
more derogatory than "belgians."
But in the end, we
settled on three choices.
Number three, "the sprouts"
Sent in by mrs. vicious,
of hastings.
Very nice.
Number two, "the phlegms"
From mrs. childmolester,
of worthing.
But the winner
was undoubtedly
From mrs. no-supper-for-you,
from norwood in lancashire
"miserable, fat
belgian bastards."
Very good, very good,
thank you, carol.
But, as you know,
on this program
We're not just prejudiced
against race or color.
We're also prejudiced against--
yes, you've guessed--
Stinking homosexuals!
So before the streets start
emptying in chelsea tonight
Let's go straight over to our
popular prejudiced panel game
And invite you once again
to "shoot the poof"!
And could our first contestant
sign in, please?
Our first contestant
is a hairdresser from...
Ooh, I never did like
that kind of person.
Halt! halt!
Gentlemen, ladies, bring out
your valuables, please.
Oh, no!
Come along, sir,
come along.
Come along,
madam.
Now...
Is that all
you've got?
Yes.
Well, he's got much more
than you
So you'd better have
some of his.
He's got
a lot of these.
Oh, sorry... pick them up
in a moment.
There's about, oh, what, nine
down there
So you must
have about...
Oh, he's still
got lots...
You've got what?
You've got more
than he started with
So if I give you
some of those...
Uh, well, now, look,
if I give you that, uh...
Have you got a bit of jewelry?
Yes, if I give you that one
And you have
some of his coins...
Is that
another box?
Were you trying
to hide it?
Ooh,
that's nice!
I'll have that.
Right.
Now, I've got
a tiara...
You've got one,
you've got one.
You've got one
of the boxes.
You've got one.
Anyone else
got a tiara?
Take your
hat off.
Oh, honestly
It's absolutely
pointless
Trying to do this if you're
going to cheat.
It really is
awful of you.
I thought you
should have won.
I mean, judicially,
you swept the board.
All right,
he had posture
But where was he
in the summing up?
Oh, shut up, melford,
there's always next year.