Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
You're traveling
through another dimension-
a dimension not only of sight
and sound, but of mind.
A journey into a wondrous land
whose boundaries
are that of imagination.
That's the signpost up ahead.
Your next stop,
the twilight zone.
This is one of
the out-of-the-way places-
the unvisited places-
bleak, wasted, dying.
This is a farmhouse-
handmade, crude,
a house without
electricity or gas.
A house untouched by progress.
This is the woman
who lives in the house.
A woman who's been
alone for many years.
A strong, simple woman,
whose only problem
up until this moment
has been that of acquiring
enough food to eat.
A woman about
to face terror
which is, even now,
coming at her from...
the twilight zone.
Central control.
Come in, central control.
Do you read me?
Gresham is dead.
Repeat, gresham is dead.
The ship's destroyed.
Incredible race of giants here.
Race of giants.
No, central control.
No counterattack.
Repeat, no counterattack.
Too much for us.
Too powerful.
Stay away.
Gresham and i,
we're finished... finished.
Stay away...
these are the invaders-
the tiny beings from
the tiny place called earth
who would take the giant step
across the sky
to the question marks
that sparkle and beckon
from the vastness of a universe
only to be imagined.
The invaders who found out
that a one-way ticket
to the stars beyond
has the ultimate price tag,
and we have just seen it
entered in a ledger
that covers all the
transactions of the universe-
a bill stamped "paid in full"-
and to be found, unfiled,
in the twilight zone.
Rod serling,
creator ofthe twilight zone,
will tell you
about next week's story
after this word
from our alternate sponsor.
And now, mr. Serling.
Next week, on this very spot,
there commences a very kooky
chain of occurrences.
The story has to do
with a young bank clerk who,
for some unexplained
and most uncanny reason,
finds himself able
to read other people's minds,
and then finds that
the power can get him
into a peck of trouble
and a bushel of travail.
Our show is called
"a penny for your thoughts,"
and it will be here
waiting for you next week
onthe twilight zone.
Captioned by media access
group at wgbh access. Wgbh. Org
be sure and see
the colgate-palmolive company's
new comedy show
my sister eileen
wednesday night
on many of these same stations.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org