SUB CREATED BY SALILA
Hey, Freddy.
How you doing?
All right.
That's what I like to hear.
Not bad .
I spoke to
everyone I know at the Daffy.
Nobody's naming sources,
but it has to be Remy.
Is Galloway going
on the record?
He wouldn't. Not without
speaking to us first.
Well, let's be sure about that.
I'll talk lo Adam.
Maybe it's smarter
to avoid contact.
Well, somebody has to respond.
Whether it's him or us or both.
Well, we have to coordinate and
we have to do it carefully.
Let me take care of this. Well,
let's just think this through.
I've got it
covered, Francis.
Okay. Now what
should I do?
Head back to the office? I
think you should work here.
We can't avoid the
press if you leave.
All right. You hold down the fort.
Yes, sir.
And you follow Claire's lead.
We'll shut this down, sir.
There can't be any doubt.
Let's walk through a timeline.
So you first met him when?
The Whitney Biennial...
This hurts us both, but it's
not my wound to suture.
Claire must be the surgeon.
Only she can stop the bleeding.
We got them
plates in there.
TOMMY: All right, all
the changes you asked for.
Give you five more points
on the post-recoupment share.
Approval over all
the marketing materials.
Approval over the staff hires for
the flagship in Silver Spring.
So what next?
You sign.
And I get my 95,000.
By the end of the week.
Just have to wire it from our
main account into the LLC,
cut a cashier's check for you.
Oh, I want
to show you this.
It's a mock-up
of the bottle design.
And we already started
on the concept layouts for
the Silver Spring location.
Why is that linoleum
peeling up?
You know, make
it seem real.
Well, I wanted it to
look nicer than this.
We can scratch
the peeling linoleum,
but we don't want it
to look too nice.
You want them white folks
to feel like they slummin'.
To have an authentic
atmosphere.
And I get to
play the nigger.
Look, Freddy,
you know how this works.
They don't just want the ribs.
They want the experience.
But without having
to leave the suburbs for it.
We're not selling
candlelit dinners here.
But I promise nothing gets built
without your signing off.
So what do you
want me to do?
I need you to deny it.
The affair?
The affair, taking the
photograph, everything.
We have a public history.
I donated work for your...
You can say we had
a business relationship,
but that you didn't take
the picture of me in the bed.
It was photoshopped. Whatever
it is you need to say.
I'm so sorry, Claire.
I only have one print.
And ifs still here.
You have to destroy it.
The digital file also.
But e-mail us a copy first.
Why'?
We need to make sure that
there's nothing in the image
that links to your studio.
Whatever you think is best.
Thank you, Adam.
I watched you when you
did the CNN interview.
I promised myself I wouldn't,
but I couldn't help it.
It's a shame it takes this for
us to talkie one another.
You're well,
besides this?
Yeah. I spent three
months in Colombia
after you came up here,
to work, but also get away.
I met someone.
Oh.
She's from Bogota. She was
working with an NGO there.
Her name's Inez. And she's
living with me now.
Wow! That...
Things happened quickly.
Yeah. They did.
I should go.
So I won't talk to
the press till I get instructions.
That's right.
It's good to
hear your voice.
You, too.
You finished?
Yeah.
Smack, crack, blow.
No, thanks.
Come on, old man.
We got what you need.
I don't need anything.
You gotta buy something
if you want to get inside.
Get out the way.
What?
For real.
You need to get the
fuck on outta my way.
Just fucking
with you, nigger.
Chill the fuck out.
Who are you?
Your grandfather. Open up.
What's your plan?
Work from home.
You don't need me dragging this
circus to the White House.
I mean in terms
of a statement.
We're drafting one.
Short and sweet.
Forgive me, Frank, but you know !
have to ask...
If it were true,
I would tell you, sir.
Would you like me to go on record?
Say I stand beside...
No, no, no. I appreciate
that, Mr. President,
but you shouldn't dirty your
hands with this sort of garbage.
If the press corners you,
just tell 'em you don't engage in
this sort of gossip-mongering.
Sir, it seems Mr. Galloway is
about to appear on television.
Go. Let me know if there's anything I
can do.
Thank you, sir.
Good afternoon.
I have very little to say.
Only that I never had
any romantic involvement
with Claire Underwood
and that I did not
take the photograph
printed in the D.C. Daily.
I'm sorry that the Vice
President and his wife
have to go through
this ridiculous ordeal.
And I would ask that the media leave
both my fiancée and me out of it.
Thank you.
You'll be
ready in an hour'?
Yes. We'll be ready.
Uh, you might want to change
into something more...
Conservative'?
Uh, yes.
I'm gonna go throw
the hounds a bone.
I know it's demeaning...
Not another word.
I should have been
more careful.
We'll put this behind us,
just like we've always done.
Part of me wishes...
What?
That you'd
be more upset.
Tusk came after you
because of me.
It's you who
should be upset.
Wasted energy, isn't it?
For both of us.
Shall we rehearse?
I don't need your help.
This ain't a handout. You have
to pay me back over time.
Work for it.
Work for you?
I'm gonna get the
house either way.
Whether you choose to
live in it is up to you.
Yeah, just what I need.
You in the easy chair
laying into me
every time I come
in and out the door.
The place is for you
and DeShawn.
I'm gonna be
in my own apartment
You sure this nigger ain't
just selling you smoke?
Says it right in the contract.
Ninety-five Gs no matter what.
I don't know, man.
Five years I don't see you, then
you come knocking on the door
and talking about you got 95 Gs...
Your choice.
You didn't want me to
visit you no more in jail
and you sure didn't want
to see me after you...
I still don't want to see you.
Well, here I am.
Get the fuck outta
here, old man.
You listen to me, boy.
I never had nothin'
to give you.
I didn't have no money.
And you didn't want
whatever I had.
But we talking
about a house.
DeShawn deserves to live better
than in a place like this...
This ain't about him.
It's about you.
You know where to find me.
See you, kid.
Less than 30 minutes.
Are they going to deny?
I'm gonna let the Vice President
and his wife speak for themselves.
Have they been
in contact with Mr. Galloway?
No, they haven't.
Why has it taken them
almost a full day to respond?
I'm sure you can understand
they wanted to consult
with legal counsel first,
regarding defamation
and slander.
So you're saying
they will deny the affair?
I'm saying they'll be
out here in 30 minutes,
and you can quote
them instead of me.
Thank you all very much
for your patience.
I hate this.
What? Waiting?
No, the affair. It's bullshit.
I feel like a tabloid hack.
You'd rather be stuck at
the White House all day?
Fuck this.
Where are you going?
To do something
meaningful with my time.
Hey, I need you to book me
a flight to St. Louis.
Tonight, if you can
find something.
No Q&A, so don't even try.
Behave yourselves, people.
I find it very painful
that anyone would suggest
I'm capable of being unfaithful to
my husband, whom I love dearly.
I've known Adam Galloway
for years, We both have.
When Iran the
Clean Water Initiative,
I commissioned him
to do a series of photographs
for the marketing campaign.
And he was
extremely generous
by donating work for
our fundraising auctions.
So I'm not sure why he would
deny taking the photograph.
I love Adam's work. So I asked
him to take this portrait.
We did it here, at the house.
Francis was there during the shoot.
It was a birthday present.
Claire asked me what sort
of portrait I wanted,
and I said I want
one of her sleeping.
Because she's so very beautiful
when she's steeping.
It hangs in my office
on the second ﬂoor.
They're fucking lying.
So I can only assume
that Adam was intimidated
by the media attention
and he needed
to distance himself.
What?
But really, all we have here
is a very talented photographer
and a prized possession.
Thank you all very much.
Thank you.
Because it would have seemed too
clean otherwise, like we...
You made me look
like an idiot.
If we had
the same story,
the media would assume
we were coordinating.
It needed to look messier.
This was supposed
to go away, Claire.
I've got twice as much press
outside the building now.
Adam...
I've gotta keep
the lights off
'cause they're on the roof across the
street, trying to film us inside.
You just need to confirm that
you took the photo for us.
Confirm our version.
Say you lied
because you were scared.
I don't know why
you didn't just tell me
this is what you
were intending to do.
Because I know you,
and you would have refused.
You have too much pride.
I don't want to speak
to the press again.
Listen, if you say nothing, they're
not going to leave you alone.
They will just camp out
for weeks on end...
This is...
It feels wrong, Claire.
It feels. ,.
I'm sorry I lied.
I wasn't trying
to be manipulative.
I have to go.
Adam? Adam'?
I think he'll do
the right thing.
I don't know.
I hope so.
Cigarette?
No. I'm gonna turn in.
Wake me if he goes on TV.
Doug, why don't you
and Seth come over?
Should we consider
a lawsuit against the paper?
Show we won't tolerate
this son of gossip?
They won't settle.
They'll fight it in the courts
because it'll generate more news.
And what about the President?
He offered to say something.
Draws more attention.
The President
isn't a bad idea,
if we phrase his
statement for him.
He becomes the headline, and we
can't control his press operation.
But if we coordinate
with them, it shouldn't...
Coordination
looks bad.
So it's your job
to conceal it.
If Seth doesn't think the
President should make a comment,
then we should
defer to his judgment.
I'm gonna get
another beer.
I can go grab
you one, sir.
No, no. I feel like
stretching my legs.
Doug? Diet Coke?
I'm fine. Thank you, sir.
Seth? Beer? I have to
drive, but thanks.
I'll be right back.
Watch yourself.
What do you mean?
Connor was an easy target,
but I'm not going anywhere.
Look, Doug, I'm grateful
just to be here...
You think I've survived with the Vice
President so long by being blind?
Upward mobility has a ceiling
with the Underwoods.
I'm the ceiling.
Understood.
What else have you
got on them?
Nothing.
You fork over the journal without
a backup plan for a rainy day?
I don't think so.
I had one hand and I played it.
I don't press my luck.
You can't expect me to believe you.
I don't.
I wouldn't if I were you,
but I'm telling the truth.
A little sibling rivalry
isn't such a bad thing,
especially between
adopted boys.
They either push each other to be
the best versions of themselves
or one of them gets booted
back to the orphanage.
You're in my house,
you drink if I drink.
One Diet Coke for you,
and one beer for you.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, darling,
what a mess.
Sweetheart.
How are you holding up?
The press have been
harassing us the past two days.
Yeah, we barely made it out of
the building without being trampled.
How awful.
You said someone was here to see me.
He's in my office.
Did he tell you
who he was?
I didn't want to say over the phone.
You never know these days.
He says he used to work
for the Underwoods.
Who?
Your assistant.
No, she would never...
She would and she did.
Why are you doing this? It's not
me, but the man I work for.
And who is that?
It doesn't concern you.
This is my life
you're fucking with.
You and I are just
pawns, Mr. Galloway.
You should leave.
We need more. To prove
the affair happened.
Another photograph.
Thirty seconds, you
better be out the door.
I'm not going anywhere.
You recognize
the country code?
And the city
code is Bogota.
Is it still ringing?
Marshall!
Hey, Pops.
Man, never seen it like this before.
That line's down the block.
Something else, ain't it?
Looks like you could
use some help.
Got an extra apron
in the back.
She refuses to leave the lobby.
What's her name?
Ayla Sayyad,
Wall Street Telegraph.
She's part of the Vice
President's press corps.
Oh,yeah.
Send her up.
I appreciate it, Tricia,
but I'm fine.
This whole thing will blow over
in a day or so. And I'll...
Can you hold one second?
The Daily. They called
for a comment.
Did Adam speak
with them?
Yes, but not what
we told them to say.
He sent them this.
Tricia, can I
call you back?
Is that you?
No.
Because he's
saying it is.
It might be.
Mrs. Underwood...
I mean, it could be, yes.
It probably is.
I asked you about
any vulnerabilities.
I didn't know
he took this.
You have short hair
in the picture.
You said it ended
over two years ago.
Well, I visited
him last fall.
Does anyone else know?
Did anyone see you there?
He had friends over
to his apartment.
Christ.
But we've said
that he's a friend.
There's nothing wrong with me
visiting him, being at a party.
There is if this photo is on
the front page of the Daily.
Politics and business are intertwined
in China, as I'm sure you know.
It's not uncommon
to partner with someone
who can ensure
Beijing's approval.
So you needed his
political influence.
All this is moot.
Our venture fell through.
Right after the Port Jefferson
Bridge was approved.
Well, I had nothing to
do with that project.
Neither did Feng,
to my knowledge.
No. But Wu Bin Yang did. He's
Feng's biggest rival in Beijing.
Well, looks like I shouldn't be
schooling you on Chinese politics.
You know far more than I.
You used the word
"intertwined."
That's the sense I'm
getting from all of this.
The samarium subsidy, the
Chinese refinery, the bridge.
your friendship
with the President...
Who sent you?
Who sent me?
When you're as rich as I am,
you're always a target.
Nobody sent me.
You're here in St. Louis.
Instead of covering the Vice
President and his wife.
My gut says there's more to Xander
Feng than has been reported.
Yeah, Yeah.
It's a far better
use of my time
than reporting on
tabloid sex scandals.
That's not real news.
You miss Tehran.
I read some of your work while
you were in the waiting area.
It started to get
too dangerous.
Phew! Yeah.
Not the best
place to be
when you want to get married
and start a family.
Or if you're Jewish.
That, too.
My wife got this for me
when she visited there,
before the revolution.
It's beautiful.
16th century.
It broke when it was being
shipped, into 1,000 pieces.
It took specialists over
a year to restore it.
Here. I want
you to have it.
I can't accept gifts.
No, no, no.
Not as a gift. No.
As a reminder of
how hard it can be
to put something back together
again once it's been crushed.
If you're going
to threaten me,
you don't have to go to the
trouble of veiling it.
I don't usually do
interviews with reporters.
They're parasites.
Usually interested in just finding
a way to knock me down a peg.
Invariably, what they
write is inaccurate.
And when that happens, I have
no choice but to retaliate.
America can be just as
dangerous as Iran, Ms. Sayyad.
Thank you for your
time, Mr. Tusk.
Travel safe back
to Washington.
Get Remy on the line.
BETTY: Remy's on line two.
Remy, let's not hold back
on the other thing.
Hit 'em again
and hit 'em now.
Best day yet.
You gotta get a safe
or something.
Or maybe one of those
pickup services.
That's too much money to be
carrying around at night.
I can handle
it myself.
Hey, ain't nobody can handle
a Glock to the face.
Unless you got
one yourself.
My days of packing
are long gone.
Here. Take mine.
I got one at home.
What the fuck you doing
bringing that thing in here?
Yo, it's just
for protection, man.
I don't know what you're
doing with it anyway.
What about your parole?
I'm a lot more worried
about niggers in my building
than some parole officer.
All right, sit down.
See, man, this is...
This is what I'm
talking about, man.
You being all righteous
and judging me and shit.
Do me a favor and just sit down.
Sit down now!
Look, we got us a good
thing, potentially.
Maybe nothing comes of it,
but maybe something does.
If the joint works out, maybe one
day you could be the manager.
Shit, if it blows up, you could
run the whole fucking franchise.
But that means
you gotta be careful.
That means you cannot
be sent back inside.
We gotta follow the rules.
Hear me?
All right.
You gonna get rid
of that thing.
Yeah.
All right. Now, that's
what's being a man.
I'll need you to cut it.
How short?
This short.
I have a modeling career.
If I cut it that short...
If you actually
had a modeling career,
I would be speaking
to your agency
and not sitting
in your apartment
You want this
job or not?
Okay, yeah.
I can cut it.
All right.
Before we go to the studio, I need
to see how well-spoken you are.
Why does that matter?
Because you're gonna be on
every news channel in America.
Wait. What's
this for?
Read this.
Those exact words.
Read 'em. If you're good,
you'll memorize them.
My name is Stephanie Daldry.
I am a professional model.
"Freddy Hayes
was convicted in 1982
"for sticking up a convenience
store in Columbia Heights.
"During a high-speed pursuit,
"Hayes lost control and
crashed into another vehicle,
"killing an elderly couple.
"He avoided
manslaughter charges
"by pleading guilty
to armed robbery.
"He served nine years.
"In 1992, he opened
Freddy's BBQ Joint,
"a small restaurant
specializing in ribs,
"frequented by Vice President
Frank Underwood.“
Did you know?
No, I didn't.
You think it's Tusk?
Who else?
Who are you texting?
Seth.
All I want to do
is make a short statement.
Freddy did his time.
He's been an upstanding
citizen for 20 years.
He's a convicted felon who
killed two senior citizens.
By accident. Well,
that's beside the point.
I am not gonna
hang him out to dry.
If the Galloway story wasn't
happening, I'd say it's fine.
But it's too risky right now.
Think of how this is shaping up.
A vice president whose
wife cheats on him
and who is friendly with
a former gang-banger?
There is no way you win
standing up for this guy.
He's about
to start a franchise.
I will not have it jeopardized
because Tusk decides...
It's more than just Freddy, sir.
I did some digging.
His son did time for narcotics,
trafficking, distribution...
I've never met his son.
Let's hold off
and tackle one...
No. I want you to organize a
press avail tomorrow morning.
Have Freddy brought over here.
Bring him to the back.
Yes, sir.
I won't leave one of my own
bleeding on the field.
If you gonna have the
Washington Redskins, then you...
Pops, it ain't that deep.
Back off, man. Yo, yo, yo, yo.
Back the fuck off.
Darnell, just ignore them.
You think I'm fucking around here?
Darnell, ignore it.
Ignore 'em.
They can't take our pictures
if we don't want them to.
Sure as hell can.
What'd you say? It's
the First fucking Amendment
You gonna read me the
Constitution now, motherfucker?
Come on, Darnell.
Let's just go on inside.
No, I ain't clone with this asshole.
Hey, don't touch me.
Oh, but you can get all up in my
face, but I can't get up in yours?
Just listen to your daddy...
Darnell, let's go.
Don't push me.
I will fuck you up.
You think I'm scared of you?
You scared of this?
Darnell! Parole!
Can you tell me
your name, please?
Stephanie Daldry.
I'm a professional model.
And this is you in
this photo on the right?
Yes, that's correct.
We shot this photo yesterday
with Ms. Daldry.
So you're suggesting that
Mr. Galloway's photo is a fake?
Well, I don't know anything
about professional photography.
I'm just a flack.
But if we can create a fake
in less than 24 hours,
I think an expert photographer
like Adam Galloway...
Those are
serious allegations,
especially given that Mr. Galloway
vehemently denies it.
Well, I'm not surprised
he's denying.
Ultimately, though, it's gonna
be your word against his.
Oh, not my word.
The Vice President
of the United States.
It's his word versus that of
a potentially troubled man.
Troubled?
Potentially.
Or maybe he has a motive.
What motive could Mr. Galloway
possibly have for a fake photo?
What would he get out of it?
I don't know.
My job is to separate fact from
fiction, just like yours is, Candy.
But maybe fact and fiction
don't matter as much
to the artistic sensibility.
Maybe the lines
are blurred for him.
This is not a man who stages
fictitious scenarios.
Well, like I said, the an
stuff, it's over my head.
And you may be right.
But I would hate to think
that Mr. Galloway
was doing this
just for publicity.
You think it's a publicity stunt.
Come on in.
Sir?
ls Freddy on his way?
There was an incident
with his son.
I look at those photos...
What happened?
He's in custody for threatening
a photographer with a firearm.
Jesus. Where's
Freddy now?
He's at home.
I have to go see him.
That's the projects, sir. I don't care.
You figure it out.
And the press can't know.
Yes, sir.
Francis, you know I love Freddy.
I'm going.
Freddy is dangerous because
you care too much.
When we care too
much, it blinds us.
What Tusk did is cheap.
And you're letting it get to you,
which is exactly what he wants.
If I just ignore this,
if I do nothing...
It's not nothing. Staying
focused requires strength.
You want me
to make something?
You go ahead.
I'm not hungry.
You should eat.
I'm sorry. You
didn't ask for this.
It's not fair to you.
All I want is to be done with it
and my father to be all right.
If I thought there was
any other way that...
I didn't want to take the chance...
I know.
God, these people. I always
knew they were ruthless.
We're caged up in here
like animals.
They're painting me
as some sort...
And your family.
It's inhuman.
They're fucking inhuman.
Getting worked up isn't
going to change anything.
Let me.
Hello?
Hey, Frank.
I'm fine.
Thanks for dropping by.
How you holding up?
Been better.
I ain't never seen you
without a suit before.
We didn't want to draw
too much attention.
Well, this is it.
My castle.
Ain't as big as yours,
but it'll do the job.
Blind Willie.
Are you a blues fan?
Dark Was The Night
gets me every time.
Man, you should've
told me that years ago.
I can jam talkin' about
some blues all day long.
Check this out.
Original 78.
You want something?
Water? Iced tea?
I'd like some iced tea,
thank you.
How's your son?
They set the bail
at 60 grand.
Jesus.
How's your wife doing?
Claire's got a suit of armor
three inches thick.
We'll get through
all this garbage.
Somebody's trying
to take you out.
Appears that way.
Whoever it is,
they done stepped on
the wrong motherfucking
rattlesnake.
That's why
I'm here, Freddy.
I have to distance
myself from you.
I need to make sure you're
not going to play up
what good friends
we've been.
That you've been to my office. That
you've cooked dinner at my home.
Or that the President
was there.
We can't drag him
into anything.
And I won't be coming in
for ribs anymore.
With all that's going on,
we can't add fuel to the fire.
You couldn't
if you wanted to.
I'm selling it.
Selling the joint?
That's right.
What are you talking about?
The franchise thing
with the sauce,
my business partner's
pulling out.
Say them white folks
down in Silver Spring
don't want to go to
no place run by thugs.
Well, why do you
have to sell yours?
Darnell's bail.
Well, doesn't that guy have to
give you 100 grand regardless?
I ain't getting shit.
There's a morality
clause in the contract.
But he's gonna pay me 45
thou for the storefront.
That with what little I got
saved, I can pay that bond.
You can't sell Freddy's.
He's already drawing
up the papers.
Let me help you with the money.
No, Frank.
We'll make it a loan.
You can pay me back.
Not gonna happen.
Don't be prideful.
Frank...
Please. Let me help you.
I ain't taking
your guilt money.
When I was banging, we used
to clear 60 Gs a month.
I seen guys shot down,
execution style.
I didn't give a shit.
And then I got caught
Darnell was born my first year in.
Never saw him once.
Not even a picture.
I can't take back
the bad I done.
All I can do is to make my own
way like I've been doing.
You understand?
Ain't pride, Frank.
If you change your mind,
you let me know.
You was a good
customer. That's it.
You ain't gotta pretend
to be my friend.
You take care
of yourself, Freddy.
You, too, Frank.
Do you think I'm a hypocrite?
Well, you should.
I wouldn't disagree with you.
The road to power is paved
with hypocrisy and casualties.
Never regret.
MEECHUM; This way.
Have a seat, Adam.
You left your phone at
home, as you were asked?
Yeah.
And what did you tell
your fiancée, exactly?
That I'd be gone for a while.
She doesn't know where.
And what will she say if
someone checks in on her?
What is this?
What will she say?
Francis.
We need to work
together now.
I tried.
You lied to me.
And I explained to you
why that was necessary.
You didn't follow
my instructions.
Do you know who
Remy Danton is?
He approached you.
Inez's father is a human
rights activist in Bogota.
The government have charged him with
treason for working with the rebels.
They're going
for the death penalty,
and Danton said they have
the judge in their pocket.
You should have
come to us.
Well, I said I would. Danton
said you couldn't do anything.
He's wrong.
Well, l wasn't gonna
take any chances.
Has he done what the
government's claiming?
No. They're made-up charges.
He's a journalist documenting
atrocities in the Darien Gap.
I can get the charges dropped.
Why should I trust you?
Because the Secretary of State
is a good friend of mine
and because you don't have
any other choice.
We're not your chess pieces.
And this isn't a game,
Mr. Galloway.
Then why are you toying with us?
We are trying to help.
That's a fucking
joke' Claire.
Do not talk to
my wife that way.
Ah, your wife. What does
that even mean to you?
Do not mistake any
history you have shared
for the slightest understanding
of what our marriage is
or how insignificant
you are in comparison.
Can you give
us a few minutes?
I'm gonna go call Cathy.
Forget my career
and my reputation.
I want to marry
this woman, Claire.
We're going
to make this disappear.
Because of you I will always be the
man who placed her father in danger.
I can never erase that.
I'm sorry it's come to this.
I'm sorry I ever met you.
All you've ever done
is cause me pain.
And you're fucking with my
life and the life of the woman
that I love more than
lever loved you.
You'll be driven back
to New York tonight.
In the morning,
you'll make a statement
saying this was
a publicity stunt.
And that the value of your
work had been stagnating
and you wanted to...
No, Claire, I won't do that.
Yes, you will.
How about I tell the press that...
Adam, shut up!
That you wanted attention,
then you got cold feet,
denied it, then you
changed your mind again.
And that you faked the shower
photo and you're coming clean.
Is that clear?
I'm not part of this world.
I didn't sign up for it.
I have no interest in it.
We're giving you
an out, Adam.
And if you choose
not to take it,
I will bury you.
I've never hated
anyone before.
Now I know what
that feels like.
It's a terrible
feeling, isn't it?
End call.
Call ended.
Call Raymond Tusk.
No answer at his place.
Is it a matter of more money?
Secretary Durant has already
called President Moreno.
So we need to move quickly.
The minister of foreign
affairs is involved now.
The judge isn't gonna rush a
conviction in less than 12 hours.
Well, who do we know
who has the minister's ear?
Nobody who can
trump President Moreno.
And he's very sensitive to
Durant's view on human rights.
Are you giving up on this?
No. Just being realistic.
Work on Moreno then.
We'll start leaving footprints.
Quiet.
Excuse me?
Ah, not you. My birds.
I think we need to be
prepared for the possibility
that we can't follow through
with our threat.
lam hearing excuses,
not solutions.
My hands are tied. I can't circumvent
the entire U.S. State Department.
You know,
I hired you to destroy Frank.
You're failing.
Look, Raymond, I am your lobbyist.
Not your henchman.
I don't employ lobbyists.
I employ people
who can be useful to me.
And you are proving otherwise.
Quiet now.
I'll figure something out.
Soon.
Okay, that's good.
You don't have to do this.
Yeah. I do.
The charges are dropped.
They lied to you.
You can lie to them.
New charges can always be filed.
It's not worth the risk.
Okay.
Are you disappointed in me?
Let's just get it over with.
Okay, go ahead.
I'd like to make a statement.
There will be
a little cleanup.
Some folks who will want
to linger on the story.
But we're over the hump,
I'd say.
So we can leave the house now?
The sooner you get back
to normal work, the better.
All the meetings
I had to cancel,
let's find a way
to get 'em back on the books.
Yes, sir.
I need to push ahead
with the assault bill.
We've got your Matt Bai interview
lined up for tomorrow, but I think...
Maybe we should hold off on Bai
till after things quiet down.
That's exactly what I was gonna suggest.
Doug's right.
Okay. Let's get going.
I'll meet you
in the car.
He's done a good job
handling all this.
Yes, he has.
Should we have
any more concerns?
He claims
he doesn't have anything else.
Do you believe him?
I wouldn't go that far.
Keep an eye on him.
I plan to.
As for Raymond, we have to
strike back hard and fast.
I want him obliterated.
More than that.
Let's make him suffer.
I don't know whether to be
proud or terrified.
Perhaps both.
Wish I could do more.
What you gonna do with her?
I don't know yet.
Probably have
to knock it down.
Worth more as an empty lot.
Is there anything else
you want to take?
A memento or something?
Nah.
I ain't one for looking back.
Eyes ahead.
Good luck, Freddy.