Last season on Vikings.
One day, the whole world
will know and fear Ivar, the Boneless.
You must seek revenge.
We want blood-revenge against Aelle.
Not only against Aelle.
King Ecbert offered our father
up like a sacrifice.
Ecbert's kingdom is vast.
How do we overcome it?
In the name of our dead father,
in the name of Ragnar Lothbrok,
we declare war on the whole world.
This is the time of war!
This is the time to hate!
Charge!
We are defeated.
I will renounce the crown in your favor.
You save yourself and your family,
and take back what is yours.
To the great hall!
Who paid for your army?
I was paid by King Harald Finehair.
I will give you legal claim
to the Kingdom of East Anglia.
I accept your offer of land.
But for what you did to my father...
You must die.
The only thing that kept
the sons of Ragnar together
was the death of their father.
And now I feel free to follow my destiny.
But, my brothers will be here for you.
We are all the sons of Ragnar.
We have to stick together.
We have a great army
and we should use it.
You cannot lead the army, Ivar.
Who among you will follow me?
I do not want to follow you, Ivar.
You are crazy.
Ivar! No!
♪ More, give me more, give me more
♪ If I had a heart, I could love you
♪ If I had a voice, I would sing
♪ After the night when I wake up
♪ I'll see what tomorrow brings
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
I know what you're all thinking.
But it is not true!
I didn't mean to kill him.
He made me kill him.
He taunted me. He made fun of me.
What was I supposed to do?
What kind of a man
taunts and tells lies
about his own brother?
And what lies did he tell?
Well, you know that
as well as I do, Hvitserk.
He said you weren't a real man.
And what would you have done
if he had said that to you, Ubbe?
What would you have done
if you were "a real man"?
I swear to the gods and
everything that is sacred
that I never meant to kill him.
Anger overcame me.
And I wasn't thinking.
I am truly sorry.
You cannot leave him in charge
of the Great Army.
That is your affair, Ubbe.
You're his big brother.
You take charge.
I told you, this is none of my concern.
I plan to return to the Mediterranean...
With Halfdan.
Will you return first to Kattegat?
I have no intention of doing that.
My fate is too urgent.
Then I will go there.
And I will tell Lagertha about
the avenging of your father's death
and the defeat of the Saxons.
And the great gift of land to our people.
And tell my mother,
and Torvi and the children
that I think of them,
and I will return...
If the gods will it.
Skol.
This place is full of ghostly memories.
God help those who did this.
If King Ecbert's body is here,
let us find it!
Yes, Your Grace!
Spread out!
Captain! Call your men forward!
Search through there!
Look for signs of life!
Can we make a search through here?
Bring some more men!
Yes! Five more!
Forward!
Tie it up!
Time for food!
We need to hurry!
Put those in the front.
Take this! Be careful!
- Do you have it?
- Another turn!
Don't go away!
You are sure?
I don't understand why
you want to split with me.
We're brothers. We belong together.
We've always had the same dream.
No. It's your dream.
You want to be King of Norway.
I don't have a dream
about being the brother
of the King of Norway.
Then what is your dream?
I want to travel.
I mean, what is your ambition?
You have ambition enough
for the both of us, brother.
I'm a simple fellow.
Traveling to the ends of the known world,
that's enough for me!
I will miss you.
Everyone needs a brother
to cover their back.
I'll still do that.
Wherever I am.
Go to your new boyfriend!
Be happy together!
Tides are turning. We have to leave.
On the left.
Only if we can use it!
May as well pull it down.
- Keep searching.
- We need a fire!
It's destroyed, it's no good.
Salvage what you can!
Pull it down!
We might be able to use that!
I think we've found our King.
Godforsaken people.
Look what they've done.
We must clean and restore this place,
despoiled by those heathen barbarians.
Tell the people who fled from
here that it's safe to return.
Yes, Your Grace.
Hyah! Hyah!
Hah!
Hyah!
Walk on!
Ah...
Floki!
Why are you building a toy boat? Huh?
It's not a toy.
It's a one-man boat.
I don't need the help of
anyone to sail it.
And where do you think
you're going to sail it to?
To where the gods decide.
I don't want you to go.
I still need you in the fight
against the Christians.
My brothers are too soft
and you know that, Floki.
Please?
My brothers...
They don't believe that I
didn't mean to kill Sigurd.
But I didn't want to. He was my brother.
Hmm?
That is why you cannot leave.
I will be too lonely.
I have to leave, Ivar.
With Helga gone, there's
nothing left for me here.
This world no longer interests me.
That's why I will submit myself
to the tides and the winds,
and the will of the gods,
come what may.
My heart is broken.
It will repair.
Ivar, the Boneless.
Scourge of the world, hmm?
You don't need me.
Bring out the oars!
Good luck!
- Good luck!
- Safe return!
Gods be with you!
Row! Keep the pace!
May Thor be at your side!
And so we commit the body of Ecbert,
King of Mercia and Wessex, Bretwalda,
King of Kings, to the earth.
As the Lord sayeth,
"I am the Resurrection and I am the Life.
"He who believes in me
though he is dead will live on.
"He who has life and his faith in me,
"to all eternity
"will not die." Amen.
Amen.
Why did the Northmen let you live?
I don't know.
I suppose they weren't interested in me.
So when I had a chance,
I ran away and hid.
And what purpose did you serve here?
I transcribed and witnessed
the treaty between King Ecbert
and the sons of Ragnar,
whereby they were granted the title
to the lands of East Anglia.
Even as he feared death,
King Ecbert should have never
sold part of his inheritance
to those pagans.
He didn't.
What do you mean?
It wasn't his to sell.
You had best explain yourself.
Before he sent his family
away, King Ecbert
renounced his crown in favor
of his son, Prince Aethelwulf.
Then Aethelwulf is King,
and the grant of land worthless.
Yes.
The King is dead.
Long live the King.
They need to dry here.
Take that one.
I would use these nets.
Edgar!
How is he?
Alfred.
Is he dying?
I don't know.
It's just as the Holy Father said.
God has sent the Northmen
here to scourge us,
punish us for all our vanity,
all our wickedness, all our
abominable iniquities.
And how can you be so sure, Aethelwulf?
Because there's no other
way to understand
what's happened to us.
- None.
- Oh, of course.
Of course, God!
Alfred must... Must die for our sins?
For my sins!
No!
No one is without sin, Judith.
And I can only pray
that our Lord chooses to be
merciful to us,
and bless us,
and cause His face
to shine upon us again.
You were planning to leave
without telling us, Floki, huh?
I wanted to spare you the
trouble of trying to stop me.
But we will anyway.
And you can't.
So let us just say farewell
properly instead.
Where are you going?
Wherever the gods will take me.
But as long as I live and breathe,
you,
the sons of Ragnar Lothbrok,
will always be close to my heart.
- Farewell, Floki.
- Hmm.
You are the greatest boat
builder of all time.
Farewell, Floki.
Beloved by the gods.
You knock-kneed fool.
Stay.
We need you just as much
as our father needed you,
but instead you choose to
run away, you coward.
Stand up and say that to my face!
I will see you again.
Is it true he has completely
committed himself to the sea?
Do not worry.
I have given him
the means to guide himself.
We do not want him to be lost.
Let Odin guide you!
Floki! Farewell!
All hail Floki!
All hail Floki! All hail Floki!
Ecbert, our martyred king,
hear my prayer.
Let the wrath of God fall
upon these heathens
who desecrate the holy places
of our land.
Let them suffer at our hands.
Slaughter them in battle.
Cut them down like
the ears of corn at harvest.
Let us rejoice in their ruin,
and drive them back into
the sea from whence they came.
And let God's holy church arm itself
against these worshippers of the devil.
And let this war never end,
until not a single pagan lives
or breathes.
Ecbert, martyr,
hear my prayer.
Hear my prayer.
Hallelujah.
Do not be afraid.
Christ is here.
You are safe.
Your Grace. Your Grace.
Your Grace.
Your Grace. Thank you.
Thank you.
God bless you, Bishop Heahmund.
God bless you.
Your Grace.
Bless you, Your Grace. Bless you.
Speaking for our father,
I think we should claim
and settle the land
given to us by Ecbert.
The Saxons are in disarray.
This is a good opportunity.
We have the resources to
make a permanent settlement.
Good.
Do you agree, Ivar?
I don't want to disband the army.
In fact, I want to continue
the war against the Saxons
while we are still in
a position of strength.
My suggestion is that we go back north,
to where we defeated Aelle.
We should establish
a permanent camp, as you say,
but near the coast, from where
we can raid wherever we want.
Our father's dream was that
we wouldn't be just raiders.
That we would behave in a different way.
You're not listening, Ubbe.
We have to have a stronghold.
If we go north,
we are closer to our own lands
and shipping routes.
We can build an impregnable fortress.
Where?
I've heard of a town called York.
It is built on a major river,
and it is not far from the sea.
And I think that we should take it.
No. It would seem like a withdrawal.
Yes, yes, it would.
But it is only tactical.
Surely you understand, Ubbe,
if we establish ourselves
in the middle of the country,
then we are surrounded by enemies.
In York, we are nearer home.
Right, Hvitserk?
I agree with Ivar.
We should go north and attack York.
It's good.
Thank you, Ivar.
That the last of them?
There's a lady in the church
needs to talk to you.
Give us the strength,
which the world cannot give,
with Your kindness,
with mercy, and under
Thy protection. Amen.
For whom do you pray?
For all of us, in these terrible times.
- What is your name?
- Aethelgyth.
Aethelgyth.
You should consider your own soul.
Will you take Mass at my hands?
Then kneel.
Amen.
Lord, forgive this pitiful
and miserable sinner.
I have sinned in thought and in deed.
Please forgive me, three-person God.
Punish me, ravish me!
Cleanse me of my sin.
Father.
York. Look at her.
So ripe for plucking!
And they don't even know that we're here.
I say we attack tomorrow
before they find out.
- Yes.
- Hmm...
Wait.
I remember something our father said.
It was always better to attack
an English town
when they are celebrating
one of their Saint's Days.
On those days, most of the people
will either be in church
or they will be drunk.
So how do we find out?
We'll find a way.
All right.
_
Hmm?
Er...
_
Northmen! Ready your bows!
- The walls!
- Prepare!
- Ready.
- Ready your bows!
Stand up, men!
Down!
You two, move!
Charge!
Hyah! Hyah!
Shh, shh, shh.
Domine...
No!
Hold his head.
Hold it.
_
Horse!
Hyah! Hyah!
To you, my brothers.
And to our town of York.
To York.
And to all our brothers,
not forgetting Sigurd.
To all of us!
Skol.
Oh!
Enough. Enough.
You are almost too
strong for me, Guthrum.
You need someone else to train with.
You must remember your father
was a great warrior.
He still is a very great warrior.
I don't mean Bjorn.
I mean your real father, Jarl Borg.
It is a name you must be
proud of, and never forget.
And even though Ragnar killed him,
I know in my heart
that they are now fighting
and feasting together in Valhalla.
Ships!
Who are they?
I have to warn Lagertha.
Queen Lagertha, I bring wonderful news.
The Great Army, led by
your son Bjorn Ironside,
succeeded in avenging the
death of Ragnar Lothbrok.
Both King Aelle and King Ecbert are dead,
but not before King Ecbert
gave us a great gift of land
for future settlement.
You've done well to tell
me this, King Harald.
But why did my son not bring the news?
- Is he dead?
- Oh, no.
Of Ragnar's sons, only Sigurd is dead,
killed by his own brother, Ivar.
Then I ask again, why is Bjorn not here?
He told everyone he wished to sail
straight back to the Mediterranean,
and asked me to convey
his respects to you,
his mother, and to Torvi,
the mother of his children.
Now tell me why you've really
come here, King Harald.
I told you.
Since your own son
refused to bring you
the news of our affairs,
I thought I should do it.
And I thought that perhaps you
wanted to find out how well
Egil the bastard had served you.
Perhaps you expected to find him here,
sat upon the throne,
keeping it warm for you?
Perhaps I did.
The truth can be a bad choice
for a wise man.
I have never been accused of being wise.
Even so, I never took you for a fool.
But you know what they say,
"If a fool persists in his
folly, he can become wise."
The gods may not give you the time.
I cannot blame the gods.
They gave me so much else.
So much else.
I'm happy to die.
Don't be afraid.
Strike.
Strike!
Ah!
Your Grace.
I have news.
We know where the Northmen are.
They're at York.
They captured the town
with great slaughter.
They murdered Bishop Cynebert
most horribly.
Then we know what we must do
to them in return.
You have confessed your guilt.
Yes.
So that all could hear.
Then tell me why I should not kill you.
You have no reason to kill me.
No reason?
Do I not have half a reason?
No.
Everything has changed.
I did what I did because of a woman.
She refused to marry me unless
I became King of all Norway.
So that was my idea.
That was my passion.
I loved her, you see.
So,
I tried to take your kingdom.
I had nothing against you.
It was just to be worthy of her.
Then why has everything changed?
Because she lied to me.
She couldn't wait for me
to become King of Norway.
She married a Danish Earl instead.
And what did you do?
I killed her.
And now that she is dead,
I no longer have any
intentions to attack Kattegat
or try to remove you as its ruler.
So then, what are your intentions?
I want to offer you
my friendship and alliance.
Look at you.
Do you think you are in a
position to offer me anything?
I'm still a King!
With lordship over many kingdoms.
And I am Queen!
Indeed.
And I know, above all people,
how vulnerable Kattegat and its
beautiful Queen has become.
After all, your son
might be away for a long time.
And how much do you trust
the other sons of Ragnar?
Do they still not desire vengeance
for their mother's death?
Or imagine themselves as Kings here?
And what would you want
in return for this alliance?
You have no man in your life,
and I no woman.
Perhaps that's one answer
to your question.
Do you really think, "King" Harald,
that I would prostrate myself
at your feet,
and offer thanks to the Gods that
you would deign to be my husband?
And that I should be grateful
for you that you would offer
to come to my bed?
In all your glory?
Hmm?
What...
What are you doing, woman?
Let us through.
Do you know who we are?
We know who you are.
What do you want?
I want to speak to my brother Ivar.
Now, get out of my way.
I'll ask him and see if it's all right.
No, you won't.
Because you will not have
a tongue to ask him with.
I will nail you to that post
just over there.
Do you understand?
Ubbe! Hvitserk!
Did you take a look around?
The work on strengthening
the defenses is going well.
Why do you need
a personal bodyguard, Ivar?
What?
We were just stopped by your bodyguards.
Why do you need them?
Hmm? Do you need protection against us?
Against your brothers?
Of course not.
Then why have them?
I'm a cripple.
I need a bodyguard.
It's not just the bodyguard, Ivar.
The fact is, you never seem
to consult us about anything.
It's as if you think you are now
the leader of our Great Army.
Do you think you are the leader?
No, I don't.
Why would I ever think such a thing?
I'm glad to hear you say that
because you are not the leader.
We three brothers
are the leaders together.
- Mmm.
- As our father would have wished.
We are older than you, Ivar.
You can't push us aside.
It's unacceptable.
No, you're right, Hvitserk.
But you two have to understand
that it is harder for me to
share and to stake my claim.
I truly want to be your equal
but in order for me to do so,
I have to do better than you.
I have to make you forget
that I'm a cripple.
Listen, Ivar, we know what you are.
And we accept what you are.
- Huh.
- It makes no difference to us.
You are just our brother.
Don't try to make us feel sorry for you.
Because, my brother, we never will.
There's a large Saxon force
on its way here.
But I thought you'd already know that.
Well?
He explained himself.
He explained why he tried
to kill all of us?
He was in love.
In any case, he's not in love anymore.
He wants to make a deal with us.
So you told him we do not make
deals with murderers.
I told him it depends on the offer.
What is he offering?
Alliance.
Protection.
In return for...
Marriage.
That's it?
Surely you can't entertain that?
Doesn't he know who you are?
Of course he does, that's the point.
I would never let a man like
that get anywhere near me!
You can't be so pure.
Sometimes women have to do what women
have to do, just to keep a bit of power.
That is what you say.
There is an element of truth
in what Torvi says.
In any case,
I've no intention of marrying him.
Then you will kill him?
That's none of your business.
You can't set him free!
Whatever I decide
is nothing to do with you.
- I was only thinking of you.
- Thank you.
But I can think for myself.
Shh.
Row.
Get to the boats!
- They've gone!
- Who has gone?
King Harald and his men.
Their boats have gone. They freed him
and killed some of the guards.
Where is Astrid?
Astrid?
Hold the rampart!
Row!
No slowing down now!
Heave!
Pull! Pull!
Go faster!
Why kidnap me?
Oh, you can help me a great deal.
You see, I think
Lagertha's years are numbered
as Queen of Kattegat.
And I still have ambitions to rule there.
Pull!
I still intend to become
King of all Norway.
Which means I shall take over
Kattegat, among other kingdoms.
But I remain unmarried.
I need a Queen.
I need to breed and produce sons.
You want me to be your Queen?
Why not?
You have to understand.
Lagertha has been so good to me.
I owe her everything.
Then there is no way that you
will ever agree to marry me?
No.
Even if it means you will
become Queen of Norway?
The most powerful woman
in the whole country?
Tell me honestly, Astrid,
doesn't that appeal to you at all?
Doesn't that make your blood
race just a little quicker?
Don't your eyes shine
just a little brighter?
Or have I misjudged you?
Pass it down here and pull.
Heave!
Well? What have you to report?
The Northmen have been busy
repairing and improving the
town's defenses, Your Grace.
They are an industrious people.
They are pagans and devils.
Nothing more. Go on.
The town is well defended.
Begging your pardon, but Your Grace
may not yet be strong enough
to attack her.
Not with any hope of success.
I disagree.
I have every hope of success.
It is a pity the new King
is not here with us.
His presence in the field
might encourage new recruits.
Unlike his father, he has
some credit as a warrior.
What will we do about Alfred?
Why must we always talk about Alfred?
Because he's dying, Aethelwulf.
He's dying before your eyes.
Can't you see?
Alfred?
Alfred.
What's he doing?
Alfred?
Alfred!
No!
Save him!
Alfred?
Save my boy!
Move!
Alfred! My boy!
My life!
No!
No. No!
Please, please, please, please!
No, please!
My boy! Please!
He's alive!
Shh, shh! He's trying to talk.
York.
We must... We must go to York.
Why must we go to York?
The Northmen are there.
The Northmen.
And your...
Your people need you.
Alfred, how... How do you know?
My father told me.
Oh, you Gods.
Not like this.
I don't want to die like this.
Why have you abandoned me?
Heimdall, watchman,
you can vouch for me!
Tell the other Gods
how often I think of them,
and how my heart belongs to them.
Be gone, bird.
Find a perch of land and stay there.
Don't come back.
Don't come back!
Hold your line!
Come on, men! Push, push!
Come on!
Forward!
Keep going! Push!
One more!
Why do you think he kidnapped Astrid?
I don't think King Harald ever
does anything without thought.
He told me that he had
abandoned his dreams
of becoming King of all Norway.
I am sure he was lying.
He still believes in his dreams,
and, one day, his ships will return
to Kattegat full of warriors.
Astrid must be part of his plan. But...
What part, I cannot say.
Astrid will never be part
of someone else's plan.
I am old enough to know that
you can never say for sure
what someone else will do.
That's it. Row!
I can smell home!
Keep rowing!
Keep the distance!
Not long now.
Keep it going, men!
Tie it fast!
Have you thought any more
about what I said?
I'm sure you don't like the look of me
but you will change your mind.
I will never marry you.
You have made a big mistake.
Oh, it's true.
I've never had any luck with women.
And yet...
What if, by mistake,
by accident, by the Gods,
and by fate, I made the right decision?
What if you were always meant to be here?
What if there was no place
else for you to be?
Row!
Halt!
Dismount!
Who are you?
We are men of Wessex.
We are here with our King.
With your King?
Do you mean King Aethelwulf?
Son of Ecbert?
He and his men are following
close behind.
I am a companion of His Grace
Bishop Heahmund,
who is camped not very far from here.
My name is Lord Denewulf.
Then well met, My Lord.
Well met, indeed.
This is a happy day.
My Lord Bishop was anxious for
the King to be at his side.
And now, thank God, it has come to pass.
Help me out.
Make room for their horses.
Most noble King,
by God's grace.
My Lord Bishop.
We've heard many reports
of your prowess with arms,
and of your personal sanctity.
We mean to model our lives upon yours.
My wife, Judith.
No, this way.
Noble lady.
Come!
Refresh yourself after your long journey,
and eat.
Make way for the carts!
What courage you have, my lady,
to accompany your husband here.
I'm not so brave, Bishop Heahmund.
But as my husband and my sons elect
to be on the field of battle,
then what should I do?
Stay at home and weep and pray?
In any case,
as the daughter of King Aelle,
I too have a score to settle
with these sons of Ragnar.
In the name of God, who is
both vengeful and merciful,
I swear I will make these pagans pay
for their cruelty and their crimes.
There's plenty to go 'round!
Prince Alfred?
- Yes, My Lord.
- Forgive me.
I have heard stories about you already.
How you traveled to Rome as a
boy, and met His Holiness.
Yes. My father took me.
It must have been an arduous
journey for one so young?
Well, is anything truly worthwhile not
likely to be difficult, my Lord Bishop?
Well said.
Who was your tutor?
My grandfather, King Ecbert.
He was the wisest man I ever knew,
and the most loving.
The barbarians who now occupy York
are responsible for his death.
That's why we are here.
The Northmen have been reinforcing
the defenses of the town.
They have repaired
and extended the ramparts.
That is bad news.
I thought so too.
That is, until my scouts
reported something interesting.
Apparently, they have felt
unable or unwilling
to repair the old Roman walls
that are still standing.
In fact, in several places,
the walls are crumbling.
The stones are loosened
and likely to fall.
Even so, they remain unguarded
and unprotected.
Then we have a plan of attack.
We do.
With your permission,
we should wait,
not rush.
Let our armies be combined.
Let my scouts determine
with absolute certainty
that those sections of wall
remain unguarded and unprotected.
And when all that is done?
Yes, my Prince.
When all that is done, we shall attack.
Scouts!
_
Huh. Bring up the shield!
What do you think
about Lagertha's mistake?
What do you mean "mistake"?
She ought to have killed King
Harald when she had the chance.
Instead of just talking to him.
Perhaps.
Not allowed her enemy,
our enemy, to escape.
And she sacrificed the life of Astrid.
We don't know that.
Listen, all I'm saying
is that Lagertha is fallible.
She makes mistakes.
Maybe her grip of power is not as
fierce or complete as it once was.
Can't you see that?
_
Ivar?
Ah, what are you doing?
Wait and I'll show you.
Ready.