To me, the whole concept
of fear of success...
...is proof that we are definitely
scraping the bottom of the fear barrel.
Will we have to have AA-type
meetings for these people?
"Hi, my name is Bill, and the one thing
I'm worried about is having a stereo...
...and a cream-colored couch."
According to most studies, people's
number-one fear is public speaking.
Number two is death.
Death is number two.
Now, this means to the average
person, if you have to go to a funeral...
...you're better off in the casket
than doing the eulogy.
Why can't I play Kramer?
Look, we've been through this
already. You're not an actor.
- Well, neither are you.
- I know.
Why do we need two people
that can't act?
Oh, come on, Jerry.
How hard is it to act?
You say something.
I'll pretend it's funny.
- What?
- My grandmother's in the hospital.
Your grandmother's in the hospital.
- This is real believable.
- You didn't think I was laughing?
- It stinks.
- All right, let me see you do it.
- Say something funny.
- All right.
I've never been to Mars,
but I imagine it's quite lovely.
Mine was better than that.
Come on, look:
- Why are you pretending to laugh?
- We're acting.
Oh, yeah, real good.
- Any word from NBC?
- No.
I don't understand. They're
supposed to be casting this week.
Maybe they're not doing it.
Well, at least let me audition.
He wants to play Kramer in the pilot.
Out of the question.
How could we not hear anything?
What's with this Russell?
What's he doing?
Hi, Russell.
- Sit. Sit down. It's okay.
- I really appreciate you coming.
Oh, that's okay. I-I don't have much
time, though, so-
All right, well, first of all...
...I want to apologize for
all the phone calls.
It's just- It's just...
I don't understand.
We went out once, and-
Yeah, that was two months ago.
Yes, I know, and I-I-I just-
I can't get you out of my mind.
Ever since that-
The day in that restaurant
when we met...
- Do you have a ketchup secret?
- No, but-
Russell, you are the president of NBC.
You can have any woman you want.
But I want you.
God, I hate these mixtures.
I don't know why- Why don't they
just put pretzels out on the table?
Or peanuts would be good, but...
...I don't know who eats
these cheesy things.
Is it something I said?
Or did?
Look, Russell...
...you're a very sweet guy, but...
...I gotta be honest with you.
I don't like television.
And that's your world.
That's your life.
Maybe if you were in Greenpeace or
something, that would be different...
...but network television, I mean...
...come on, Russell.
You're part of the problem.
Elaine, we're doing some very
interesting things right now.
We've got very exciting pilots
for next season.
We have one with a bright young
comedian, Jerry Seinfeld.
Oh, yeah, you know, I've heard of him.
He's that:
"Did you ever notice this?
Did you ever notice that?" guy.
In fact, he was in the restaurant
the day that we met.
Well, anyway, it's a
groundbreaking show.
Really? What is it about?
Well, really- It's-It's really-
It's very unusual.
It's about nothing.
What do you mean, it's about nothing?
For example, what did you do today?
I got up. I went to work.
Then I came here.
There's a show. That's a show.
Russell, see, I'm really not
interested in this...
...and I do have to...
- ...go to work, so-
- Elaine, when-? When are we-?
- When are we gonna see each other?
- I'm sorry, Russell. I'm sorry, okay?
Bye-bye.
- So I'll see you later, huh?
- Yeah.
Hello. Yeah, he's here. Hey!
- It's for you.
- Oh, yeah?
He's getting phone calls here now?
Hello.
Again with the sweatpants?
What? I'm comfortable.
You know the message you're
sending with these sweatpants?
You're telling the world, " I give up.
I can't compete in normal society.
I'm miserable, so I might
as well be comfortable."
Hold on a second, I got another call.
Hello.
Yeah, he'll call you back.
- Who is it?
- That's NBC.
NBC?!
Give me the phone!
- I'm having a conversation here.
- Get off the phone.
Okay, look, I'll call you back. Yeah.
You know I'm waiting
to hear from them.
- Who was it?
- Russell Dalrymple's secretary.
All right. Now you're doing
something to help me.
Hello. Yes, it's Jerry Seinfeld
returning the call.
Okay, great. Thanks a lot.
Casting tomorrow at NBC, 4:00.
We're in business. The pilot's on!
You're gonna be successful.
What if the pilot gets picked up...
...and it becomes a series?
That would be wonderful.
You'll be rich and successful.
That's why I'm worried.
God will kill me before letting
me be successful.
- He'll never let me be happy.
- You don't believe in God.
I do for the bad things.
Do you hear what you're saying?
God isn't out to get you, George.
What-?
What is that on your lip?
- What?
- It's like a discoloration. It's white.
Yes. Yes, it's white.
- Why is that white?
- You'd better get that checked out.
- "Better get that checked out"?
- I would.
What kind of a therapist are you?
I'm telling you I'm scared
something will happen...
...and you look for tumours?
- I'm trying to help you.
- What are you, like, a sadist?
No matter how bad somebody
feels, you can make it worse.
- You're rooting for a tumour.
- You'd better go.
I'm going, baby. I'm going!
- Where?
- Right here.
Get out of here, it's nothing.
Excuse me.
Do you see anything on my lip?
Yeah. Like a discoloration.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah, it's all white.
It's all white, Jerry.
It's all white.
Would you stop?
I'd get that checked out.
Again with the checked out.
I'm not going to the doctor.
If I don't, nothing will happen.
If I go, he might find something.
- If you go, maybe they'll catch it in time.
- Catch what in time?
- Whatever it is.
- You think it's something?
I hate these bums with their rags.
No, no, no, I don't want it. Get away.
Get away. Get away from my car.
You know, these squeegee-
Oh, my God,
it's Crazy Joe Davola.
Good luck on the pilot, Jerry.
Yeah, I think I see it. It's like a...
...white discoloration.
What do you think it is?
It's like a white discoloration.
Okay, guys, are we ready to start?
Where's Russell? I thought
he was gonna be here.
I don't know. I saw him this morning,
and I said hello. He walked past me.
He must be worried about
the fall schedule.
- It's a real bear.
- Yeah.
So, what's going on?
We're gonna shoot the pilot...
...then it's gonna be on TV
the next week?
Yeah, right.
This is Mark Matz.
He'll be auditioning
for the role of George.
- How you doing?
- Hey, Mark, how are you?
They've gotta be kidding.
This guy's perfect.
Okay, let's read this.
And I'll be reading Jerry's part.
Anyone call for Vandelay Industries?
- No, why?
- Listen to me.
I told the unemployment office
I was close to a job with them...
...and I gave them your number.
When you answer the phone, you've
got to say, "Vandelay Industries."
- I'm Vandelay Industries?
- Right.
- What is that?
- You're in latex.
What do I do with latex?
I don't know. You manufacture it.
This is Michael Barth,
another George.
- Hi, Michael.
- How you doing?
- Everything all right?
- I just came from the podiatrist.
Something's wrong with my foot.
A little gangrene.
They'll probably have to amputate.
Any questions?
What are we looking at?
Is this guy a real loser?
No, not a loser.
Let's start with the second scene.
You have it?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
A man gave me a massage.
So?
Well, he-
He had his hands, you know...
- ...and he was-
- He was what?
Well, he was, you know-
He was touching and rubbing.
That's a massage.
I think it moved.
This is Melissa Shannon.
- Hi.
- Hi, how you doing?
Melissa is reading for Elaine.
It's like a bald convention out there.
Sorry, I made a faux pas.
No, you didn't,
he knows he's bald.
So how about that guy
wearing sweatpants?
Is that for the part, or does he
walk around like that?
Okay. Shall we start?
You know what?
I'll read with her.
Oh, great.
- All right, wanna start?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- What was that look?
- What look?
That look you just gave me.
- I gave a look?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Let's see some more Kramers.
- Hi, how you doing?
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- Good.
- What is this about?
- Levels.
- Levels?
- Yeah. Getting rid of all my furniture.
All of it. I'm building levels...
...with steps, completely carpeted...
...with pillows.
Like ancient Egypt.
How are you gonna be
comfortable like that?
I'll be comfortable.
- Very good.
- Very nice.
Tom, that was terrific.
Thank you for coming in.
- Wonderful reading.
- That's really something.
- Bye.
- Okay. Thank you. Take it easy.
I thought he was really good,
very funny.
Yeah, I liked him.
What happened to the raisins?
Yeah, there was a box
of raisins there.
Did he just steal the raisins?
You think he stole them?
This is Martin Van Nostrand.
- What are you doing here?
- You two know each other?
Wait a minute. I know you.
You're the guy from the Calvin Klein
underwear ads.
That's true.
I saw Joe DiMaggio
in Dinky Doughnuts again.
But this time...
...I went in.
Where's the bathroom?
I think if you go down the hall,
it's on the right at the very end.
Be right back.
Sorry, buddy. Full house.
Sorry. Customers only.
Hey, you need a ticket.
- So who's playing Elaine?
- Oh, don't worry about it.
Very talented young actress.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Who is it?
- She's an Eskimo, actually.
- Oh, God.
- She came down from Juneau by sled.
She was in the Iditarod. Got to the
finish line, just kept going.
She's got the dogs with her
in the hotel room.
Listen, was Russell at the casting?
No, he didn't show up.
You know...
...I'm a little bit worried about him.
I don't understand.
We had one date...
...two months ago.
Am I that charming and beautiful?
No. No, you're not.
- Why do I keep setting you up?
- I don't know.
Could we get a little more?
Heat more.
Ever since this new owner took over,
the service here is really slow.
Yeah. Have you noticed anything
else that's...
...different since the new
management?
They're putting a little lemon
in the tuna. I love that.
Besides that.
Look at the waitresses.
Yeah?
What physical...
...characteristic would
you say is common to all of them?
I mean, look at this.
Every waitress working here has the
same proportions, wouldn't you say?
Yes. I would say.
What's going on here?
How is this possible?
- Do you think it's a coincidence?
- No.
I-I haven't seen four women like this
together outside of a Russ Meyer film.
Hi. Excuse me. Who does all the
hiring of waitresses here?
He does. We're looking for
another girl if you know anyone.
You know what?
That's discriminatory.
That is unfair. Why should these
women have all the advantages?
They get all the attention from men.
They get all the waitress jobs too?
Hey, that's life. Good-looking men
have the same advantage.
You don't see
any handsome homeless.
You see, it's right here.
It's-It's a little white.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
I've never seen this before.
"Never seen this before"?
I'm gonna have to take
a biopsy on this.
- A what?
- A biopsy.
- A biopsy?
- Yeah.
Cancer? Is it cancer?
Do I have cancer?
Well, I don't know what it is.
He took a biopsy, Jerry.
A biopsy.
- What'd he say?
- He didn't know what it was.
All right, so?
When I asked him about cancer,
he didn't say, "Get out of here."
That's what I wanted to hear,
"Cancer? Get out of here."
Maybe he doesn't have a
"get out of here" kind of personality.
How could a doctor
not say, "Get out of here"?
It should be part of medical school
training. " Cancer? Get out of here.
Go home. What are you, crazy?
It's a little test. It's nothing.
You're a real nut, you know that?"
Told you God would never
let me be successful.
I never should've written that pilot.
The show will be a hit, make
millions, and I'll be dead.
Dead, Jerry. Because of this.
Can't you at least die
with a little dignity?
No, I can't.
I can't die with dignity.
I have no dignity.
I want to be the person who
doesn't die with dignity.
I lived my whole life in shame.
Why die with dignity?
Hey.
What happened to you yesterday?
I got mugged.
- You got mugged?
- Mugged?
I wouldn't have minded, but I was
running home to go to the bathroom.
- Why didn't you use it in the building?
- It was full.
I tried a few other places, you know,
but that didn't work.
I mean, it was an emergency, Jerry.
I was really percolating.
So I decided to run home through the
park, and then two guys stopped me.
- Yeah?
- It's me.
Come on up.
Now I got a big problem, buddy.
- What is it?
- Well...
I waited so long, I-
I missed my chance.
- You didn't go?
- No, and now I can't get it back.
The best thing to do
is just not think about it.
How could you not think about it?
- Hey.
- What's the matter with him?
- He's a little backed-up.
Elaine.
So I spoke to some of my sisters
about that coffee shop.
Oh, the sisters.
Have you seen the
waitresses in there?
I never had so much coffee in my life.
So we decided I should go over
there and apply for a job myself.
Apply for a job? What for?
Because it's discriminatory.
It's a coincidence.
- This is what you're gonna wear?
- Yeah.
You're not gonna get the job.
Exactly.
Hello.
Oh, hi.
Yeah, I guess we could do that.
At what time?
All right. I'll see you there.
Okay, bye.
- Who's that?
- TV Elaine.
She wants to talk about the part.
- What about the dogs?
- They're having sex in the hotel room.
So the Elaine character is based
on someone you know.
- Yes.
- And she's really your ex-girlfriend.
- Yeah.
- I want to know her from the inside.
What is she like?
Tell me about her.
Well, she's fascinated with Greenland.
She enjoys teasing animals...
...Banlon and seeing people
running for their lives.
She loves throwing garbage out the
window, yet she's extremely dainty.
How would she eat a hamburger?
- With her hands.
- What about pasta?
Also with her hands.
Seriously.
I want to experience
everything she's experienced.
Everything?
- Everything.
- All right, she cuts pasta with a knife.
Good. What's her favourite movie?
Shaft.
You gotta give me her picture.
What about sex?
She likes talking during sex.
Dirty talking?
No. Just chitchat, movies,
current events. Regular stuff.
- You know, Sandi-
- Elaine.
- What?
- Call me...
...Elaine.
All right...
- ...Elaine.
- How does Elaine kiss?
- Well-
- Does she kiss...
...like this?
Actually, she has a thing where she
spirals her tongue around. It's like a-
Like this?
I think you got it.
Now, I like to eat spaghetti...
...with just a fork.
Because I can keep
the strands long...
...and I can slurp it up to my mouth
like this. Look.
Now, sex, I like the bottom.
Let them do all the work, you know?
You should be writing
this stuff down.
Yeah. Bran flakes.
One hundred percent.
I got a big problem.
- And I'll have the hamburger. That's it.
- Yeah.
- Thanks a lot.
- That's good.
Now, I like to play golf.
Look, this stuff doesn't matter to me.
See, I'm gonna do the character
like me, not like you.
You gotta play him like me.
I'm Kramer.
- I'm Kramer.
What can I do for you?
Would you like table?
No, I'd like to apply
for a waitress job.
Have you ever waited
on tables before?
Oh, yeah. I've been a professional
waitress for the last 10 years.
I've worked all over this city.
These are my references.
I'm sure you'll find
that I'm more than qualified.
I don't think I need
anyone else right now.
You're in big trouble, mister!
And I mean trouble with a capital T!
What? What did I do?
Anyway, there's at least...
...four of them,
and they're all huge.
I mean, one is bigger than the next.
It's like a Russ Meyer movie.
Who's Russ Meyer?
He's this guy who made these...
...terrible movies in the '70s
with these kinds of women.
He's obsessed.
He's obsessed with breasts.
That's hard to say.
Anyway, go on.
There's not really much more to tell.
He was looking for waitresses...
...I went in to apply, and he looked me
up and down, and he rejected me.
Paul, come here for a second.
I want you to listen to this.
- Hi.
The woman here claims there's
a restaurant on the West Side...
...that's only hiring
large-breasted women.
Really?
- What do you mean, made-up?
- It's made-up.
Häagen-Dazs is made-up.
It's not Danish.
- You're crazy.
- No, I'm not.
George, is Häagen-Dazs Danish?
- What do you mean, Danish?
- This guy stinks.
Danish. Is it from Denmark?
They make it in New Jersey.
It's just a Danish-sounding name.
I can't believe that.
They fooled me, Jerry.
Boy, talk about a show
about nothing.
Excuse me.
This-This is not right.
May I?
You see, you're going:
"They fooled me, Jerry."