Well, look at your face in the mirror.
- Yeah?
- It's George.
Come on up.
- I don't believe this.
- You didn't know you were doing this?
- No, I swear.
- I'll bet this is from that kick...
...from Crazy Joe Davola. You better
see a doctor and get some x-rays.
Just the man I'm looking for.
- Me?
- Yeah. Here you go.
- What's this?
- A dry-cleaning bill.
- From that woman at NBC?
- Yeah.
- Dry cleaning bill for what?
- For vomiting on her vest.
Oh, come on, George.
I didn't do that on purpose.
- I shouldn't have to pay.
- Neither should I.
Jerry left the milk in the refrigerator.
- Yeah, it's your milk.
- He drank it.
- I didn't know.
- All right.
Well, we should all chip in, I guess.
- Yeah.
- How much was it to clean the vest?
Eighteen dollars.
Can you get vomit out of suede?
- I don't know.
- Yo-Yo Ma!
What? Yo-Yo Ma?
What about him?
- You just said, "Yo-Yo Ma."
- What's Yo-Yo Ma?
He's a cellist.
You should see a doctor today.
All right. Let's go. Six dollars.
I can't believe
she sent a cleaning bill.
I know.
And it doesn't really bode well
for the show.
Forget about the show. We should
take the idea to a different network.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Like anybody's ever gonna do this.
How did you get me to go with that?
A show about nothing.
It was a good idea.
Susan liked it.
And if he hadn't vomited all over her,
we'd be writing it right now.
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
What are you doing? Give me that.
Go to your apartment and lie down.
I'll make an appointment for a doctor.
Hello? Oh, hi, I'm sorry.
No, that's my neighbour.
He's not quite himself.
He got kicked in the head.
What? Really? You're kidding.
Today? Yeah, sure.
We could make it. Two o'clock?
Yeah, we could do that.
Okay. Great. Thanks a million.
Okay. Bye.
- What?
- NBC.
They wanna have another meeting.
They wanna have another meeting?
They wanna buy it!
They wanna buy it! What did I tell you?
We'll be rich!
What are we gonna get?
- Fifty, 60 thousand.
- I don't know about 60.
Oh, it's gotta be 50.
You know how much
Ted Danson makes?
Ted Danson. How are you
comparing us to Ted Danson?
- I didn't say we're Ted Danson.
- You did. You said we're Ted Danson.
- You know, I think he wears a piece.
- Yeah, don't worry. He can afford it.
- What time do you have?
- Five till.
See, I'm 10 minutes slow again. That's
it for this piece of junk. I've had it.
- The one your parents gave you?
- It never works.
We're supposed to be there.
Let's take a cab.
We'll be a little late.
I'm not taking a cab.
- I'll pay for it.
- It's not the money.
What is it you object to? The comfort?
The speed? The convenience?
Jerry!
- Uncle Leo!
- Hello!
Hello there. How you doing?
- How are you? How's Mom and Dad?
- Good. Fine.
Are you getting to be too much
of a big shot now to give me a call?
I don't hear from you anymore.
Oh, no, I've been kind
of busy, that's all.
You know where I just came from?
- Danny Barber.
- Oh, sure. Danny.
He was in the pyjama business.
Remember, I got my pyjamas
for free.
I'd come over and give you pyjamas.
Oh, yeah, yeah. I remember.
Funny thing is, I can't wear them.
I get too hot.
I sleep in my underwear
and a T-shirt.
If it gets too hot, I just take the T-shirt
off. Anyway, Danny says to me:
- "You need any pyjamas?"
- I'm sorry, Uncle Leo.
I really gotta get going.
Well, you gotta get going, so go.
We got a meeting
with the president of NBC.
- Nobody got a gun to your head.
- Yeah. I'm really sorry.
Go. Really, I understand.
You got an appointment.
Go to your appointment.
- I'm sorry. Really.
- You know...
...I know plenty of people
in Hollywood too.
Sorry. Really.
- Yeah?
- Come on, are you ready? Let's go.
- For what?
- What's with you?
I just talked to you 15 minutes ago.
- About what?
- The courthouse.
You gotta go with me to court.
I'm contesting the ticket.
- I can't. I'm going to the doctor's later.
- You gotta go.
You're my alibi.
You have to take the stand.
- Well, I can't.
- Let me remind you of something.
You wouldn't be here today
if it wasn't for me and my helmet.
I saved your life. You would be dead!
You would cease to exist.
You'd be gone for the rest of eternity.
Can you begin to comprehend
what that means?
Shut up!
I'll get my coat.
Don't step on anything.
There are many things that
I think you can point to...
...as proof that the humans
are not smart.
But my personal favourite would have
to be that we had to invent the helmet.
What happened was
we were involved...
...in a lot of activities
that were cracking our heads.
We chose not to avoid doing
these activities, but instead...
...to come up with
some sort of device...
...to help us continue enjoying
our head-cracking lifestyles:
The helmet.
Not enough people
were wearing them...
...so we had to come up
with the helmet law...
...which is even stupider.
The idea behind the helmet law...
...is to preserve a brain whose
judgment is so poor...
...it does not even try to stop
the cracking of the head it's in.
Did you see the look on his face?
Did you see how insulted he was?
What could I do?
What are we supposed to do?
You can't leave.
There's no excuse good
enough to justify walking away...
...from a conversation
with one of my relatives.
I didn't shave this morning.
I don't feel like myself.
You could be a fireman on
a fire truck on the way to a fire.
You bump into one of my relatives,
"Sorry, Uncle Leo...
...there's a building full of people
burning down. I do have to be running."
He'll go, "Go. Go ahead.
Go to your fancy fire.
If that's what you have to do."
- Look at this.
- Why didn't you shave this morning?
Because I shaved yesterday
in the afternoon.
- Why?
- Because of the day before.
It's a long story.
I can't get back on schedule.
Is that Joe Davola?
It's not him!
I can't live like this.
I'm being stalked.
Mr. Seinfeld. They're ready for you.
Mr. Seinfeld.
What about Mr. Costanza?
I'm not here?
All right. You promised.
You're gonna be a little more
flexible on the nothing idea.
- Just a little.
- All right. A little.
Okay. You all set?
You got your story?
- No.
- When he stopped me...
...I told him I was rushing because
my friend was about to commit suicide.
You're that friend.
All we need is a reason...
...why you were gonna
commit suicide.
I never had an air conditioner.
No. That's no reason to kill yourself.
Why? It gets hot at night.
You can't sleep.
You ever try to sleep in a hot room?
I sleep in a really hot room.
I don't wanna kill myself.
I've slept in really hot rooms
and wanted to kill myself.
No, no, that's not gonna work.
Something else.
I was never able
to become a banker.
Banker! So you're killing yourself...
...because your dreams of becoming
a banker have gone unfulfilled.
You-You-You can't live
without being a banker.
Yeah, yeah. If I can't be a banker,
I don't wanna live.
- You must be a banker!
- Must be a banker!
Okay, we'll go with the banker story.
Story is the foundation
of all entertainment.
You must have a good story.
Otherwise, it's just masturbation.
People really have
to care about the characters.
Care? Forget about care. Love.
They have to love them. Otherwise...
- ...why tune in?
- Wouldn't tune in.
- Would they tune in?
- No tune.
We like to look at a show
as if it were an EKG.
You have your highs and your lows.
And it goes up and down.
This show will be like a heart attack.
Just a huge, massive coronary.
So, what you said last week
about no story...
...you're a little flexible on that now.
Is that what I said, " no story"?
Because Jerry had to tell me later.
He couldn't believe it.
I said- I said, "Get out of here.
No story?
Is that what I said?"
Well, I informed him that he
was exceeding the speed limit...
...and that's when he told me
that he was racing home...
...because his friend was
about to commit suicide.
And then what happened?
He became very loud and hysterical.
He was flailing his arms about
as he told the story...
...and then he threw himself
on the ground...
...and he grabbed me
around the legs...
...and he begged me to let him go.
And when I refused...
...that's when he began to scream,
"My friend's going to die.
My friend's going to die."
I don't know how you guys feel, but we
would like to be in business with you.
- We'd like to be in business.
- Love to.
- We'll do business.
- Business.
- Let's have business.
- This is business.
Would it be possible to get
a copy of La Cocina?
Your off-Broadway play.
Gee, you know...
It's-It's the damndest thing. I-
I moved recently,
and my files disappeared.
Now I-I don't know if
they fell off the truck...
...or if there was some foul play,
but let me tell you:
I am not through with
that moving company.
That's my vow to you.
Well, I got a feeling about you two.
And even more than that...
...I place great confidence
in this lady's judgment.
- Good judgment.
- That's a pile of judgment.
- Yes. Yes, judgment with earrings on.
So let's make a pilot.
I had gone up to Westchester.
I go every Tuesday.
I do charity work with the blind...
...in my spare time
for the Lighthouse.
I was in the middle of a game of
Parcheesi with an old blind man...
...and I excused myself
to call my friend...
...as he was very depressed lately...
...because he never became
a banker.
I don't understand.
You see, it had been his lifelong
dream to be a banker, and he-
Just the day before,
he was turned down by a bank.
I believe it was
the Manufacturers Hanover...
...on Lexington and 40th Street.
That was the third bank in
two weeks to turn him down...
...so I was- I was a little concerned.
I wanted to see how he was doing.
Well, Your Honour,
he was barely audible...
...but I-I distinctly recall him saying-
Hey, Yo-Yo Ma.
So I sped home to save my friend's life,
and I was stopped for speeding.
Yes, I admit I was speeding...
...but it was to save a man's life.
A close friend.
An innocent person who wanted
nothing more out of life than to love...
...to be loved and to be a banker.
So then he didn't kill himself?
No, sir, he did not.
But only by the grace of God.
He is in the courtroom today,
sitting right over there!
And he can corroborate
my entire testimony.
See! Told you! I told you!
- Now all we gotta do is write it.
- Yes!
How are we gonna do that?
- Hey! Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- Thank you. Thanks.
- Thank you.
You know, I thought
you were mad at me.
Mr. Seinfeld, you have
a telephone call.
Phone call? Who knows I'm here?
Hello? Mom?
How did you know I was here?
Oh, I was not rude to him.
That is baloney!
I couldn't talk. I had a meeting.
I don't know. He-He went off
on some thing about pyjamas.
When you sent me the bill, I thought
the show didn't have a chance.
Oh, it was only vomit.
Anyway, I would like to pay
for the dry cleaning.
- Oh, no, no. It's okay.
- Oh, no, no, no.
We all chipped in.
We have the money.
Well, it was $18.
- Okay, $18. There it is. There you go.
- All right.
So maybe we could get
together this weekend.
- Yeah. Call me.
- All right. Great.
- Bye.
- Bye. Thanks.
Bye.
I can't believe she took the money.
Why?
I offered to pay.
She should have said no.
She did. You insisted.
This is what the pilot should be about.
Vomiting on somebody's vest.
How much are we gonna get for this?
- Oh, I-I don't know.
- We gotta get 50. Gotta get 50.
We'll go. You call your manager.
Maybe they made an offer.
- Okay.
- All right, let's go, let's go.
Thirteen thousand?
Thirteen thousand.
- Apiece?
- No, for both.
That's insulting. Ted Danson
makes $800,000 an episode.
- Would you stop with the Ted Danson?
- Well, he does.
- You're nuts.
- I'm sorry.
I can't live knowing that Ted Danson
makes that much more than me.
- Who's he?
- He's somebody.
- And me?
- You're nobody.
- Why him? Why not me?
- He's good. You're not.
- I'm better than him.
- You're worse.
Much, much worse.
- There's Davola.
- What? Where?
- Where?
- Outside. I just saw him outside.
What is it?
Oh, it's this patient.
Again?
I'm fairly certain.
I forgot to leave him an extra
prescription for his medication.
Well, so he can live without his
Valium for a couple of days.
No, you don't understand.
He could be dangerous.
Go outside and see if he's there.
I can't go. He knows we're friends.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
I gotta take Kramer to the doctor.
- Tell the cop.
- Good idea.
Excuse me, officer.
There's a guy outside, and he's a
nutjob, and he's waiting to beat me up.
If you could just walk me outside
and wait till I get into a cab.
Yeah, all right. Just-
Just let me get a muffin.
Thanks.
He's gonna get a muffin.
Then he'll walk us outside.
This is a great way
to go through life, isn't it?
Hey, he's looking at the menu now.
What's he looking at the menu for?
I thought you said he was
gonna get a muffin.
What are you doing?
- What?
- What, you're ordering food now?
Yeah. Yeah, I decided
to get a sandwich.
What happened to the muffin?
I got a little hungry.
All of a sudden you get hungry?
Yeah. You got a problem with that?
No.
Enjoy your lunch.
You know, a muffin
can be very filling.
- He's getting a sandwich now.
- I thought he was gonna have a muffin.
All of a sudden, he gets hungry.
- You know, a muffin can be very filling.
- I know.
Mr. Kramer...
...you heard the testimony so far.
Would you please tell the court,
in your own words...
...what happened on the afternoon
of September 10th?
What do you mean,
"in my own words"?
Whose words are they gonna be?
You know what I mean.
- I was very upset that day.
- And why was that?
- Would you let me say-? Let me talk.
- All right. Go ahead.
- All right.
- Okay.
I was very upset that day because
I could never become a banker.
And this failure to become a banker...
...was eating at you. Eating, eating,
eating at you inside.
Yeah.
It was your family that pushed you into
banking. It was their dream for you.
- Mr. Newman?
- I'm trying to establish...
...Mr. Kramer's fragile emotional state.
My entire case depends on it.
Continue.
- As you were saying, Mr. Kramer?
- What was the question?
You're telling how your parents
pushed you into banking.
Well, my father, when I was a kid...
...he took me to the bank...
...and he lifted me up, and he pointed
to the teller, and he said:
"Sonny boy, take a good look
at him.
That's gonna be you someday."
But you never became a banker,
did you, Mr. Kramer?
Why? Why did you fail?
I don't know.
Because you hated your father...
...and you would do anything
to displease him!
Isn't that true?
- Could you get to the speeding?
- Yes, I intend to, Your Honour.
And then, on the afternoon
of September 10th...
...you received a phone call,
did you not?
Phone call?
Yes, a phone call.
From who?
- From me.
- From you?
Yes, from me! From me!
I called you, remember?
- You called me?
- Yes, I called you, you idiot!
Because you were going to...
- You were going to... Remember?
- What?
You were gonna- You were gonna-
You were gonna do something...
...to yourself.
You were gonna do something.
Remember the banking! The banking!
It wasn't working out.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to call-
- Yes, a banker!
- What banker?
You're a banker!
- Your Honour-
- That's enough, Mr. -
Mr. Kramer is obviously
very distraught.
- I'm distraught?
- You shut up!
I demand a recess so that
I can take him outside...
...and help him regain
his composure.
That'll be $75.
What's the matter with you, you jerk?
We had it all worked out!
Is he out there? Do you see him?
I'm not sure.
Well, either you see him or you don't.
All right, I don't.
What is he doing?
Is he getting coffee?
I think he's getting coffee.
What's with this guy?
Did you just order coffee?
- Yeah.
- This is really too much.
- What is your problem?
- I'm sitting over there...
...waiting for you to finish
for 20 minutes.
Now you're drinking coffee.
That's another 10 minutes.
Well, you're just gonna have to wait.
You never said anything
about the banking.
- You're off your rocker!
- Hey, you guys.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- Why are you here?
- Is Davola outside?
- Davola?
- Yeah.
- I didn't see him.
- Crazy Joe Davola?
- Jerry, yours is $11.
- Eleven dollars? For what?
Muffin, sandwich and coffee.
Hey, NBC okayed our idea.
We're gonna make the pilot.
The circus freak show?
- No.
- A pilot?
What do you make for something
like that? Fifty, 60 thousand?
What's the difference?
The money's not important.
- Hey, Newman, is that your red car?
- Yeah.
- I think you're getting a ticket.
- Run.
- Go! Go! Go!
- Hey, what are you doing?
It's after 6:00!
You can't give me a ticket!
You're not gonna get away with this.
I'll fight this.
- I've got witnesses.
- I saw the whole thing.
This would be a good idea
for the pilot.
Get out of here.
The vomiting is funnier.
Oh, like you know.
No. You do.
Many states now have traffic school
when you have an infraction.
I went to traffic school.
I didn't mind it.
I felt bad for the instructor.
This guy goes to traffic school
every day, no matter how he drives.
What is his incentive to not speed?
He's going to traffic school, anyway.
Why not get a racecar, do 200 miles
an hour down the street?
Cop stops you. "Where you going?"
"Traffic school. " "Go ahead.
And you better hurry.
You really need it."
The punishment should be, instead
of traffic school or traffic court...
...just traffic.
They sentence you
to 100 hours of traffic.
Five people drive all around you...
...at five miles an hour
wherever you go.
You're on your way to Vegas.
There isn't a car in sight.
Come on, move it.