You want to hit "fooled" more.
"They fooled me, Jerry."
You see the difference?
I'm not gonna say it like that.
Just a suggestion.
All right, everybody.
- Take a five.
- Yep, that's five.
George?
I don't have much
experience with acting...
...but from what I can gather...
...they're a little touchy about
being told how to say the lines.
Why is that?
I don't know,
but they don't seem to like it.
By the way, how am I doing?
Oh, you're- You're fine. You're fine.
So you think this guy playing Kramer
took the raisins?
Why would he steal a box of raisins?
Yeah.
It's bizarre.
That little bald guy's driving me nuts.
I'm gonna rip him a new one
if he doesn't leave me alone.
I wish that was our real problem.
What is the real problem?
It's Seinfeld.
He can't act. It's pathetic.
I told you these stand-ups can't act.
I'm cringing watching him.
What's with him?
Russell?
- What?
- You okay?
Yeah. No, I-I was just...
...thinking of something.
I'll be back in a second.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
You're acting weird.
Is anything wrong?
No.
Are you breaking up with me?
Are we going out?
You're breaking up
with me, aren't you?
Do you want me to?
If that's what you want.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Fine, break up with me.
All right, we're broken up.
Can we still be friends?
- Remember when you auditioned?
- Yeah.
There was a box of raisins
on the coffee table.
Did you, by any chance,
take them with you when you left?
What are you talking about?
Well, we were all eating the raisins.
And I remember you- You were
eating some of the raisins.
And then you left...
...and the raisins were gone.
I was just wondering if, you know...
...maybe you took them with you.
Are you accusing me
of stealing the raisins?
- Oh, no, no-
- Why would I steal a box of raisins?
No, you wouldn't.
Nobody would, you know.
It's just that...
...they were missing, and...
...well, I'm just inquiring.
Let me give you a
word of advice, okay?
Stay away from me.
I don't wanna talk to you.
And I don't wanna hear any more of
your stupid notes and suggestions.
I don't like you.
So if you got any other problems,
whether it's raisins, prunes...
...figs or any other dried fruit...
...just keep it to yourself and stay out
of my way, okay?
All right.
I don't think we're gonna have any
problem with that.
Good talking to you, Tom. Really.
Elaine? Elaine?
What do you want?
What can I do?
Is-? Is it...?
Is it my job? Is that what it is?
Elaine, I can't go on like this.
Look, will-? Will-? Will you call me?
Would you call me?
Well, why? I-
All right, you want-? May I call you?
Elaine? Elaine?
Excuse me, Mr. Dalrymple...
- ...I am so sorry.
- All right, what's your name?
- David Richardson.
- Get out, you're fired.
- But, Mr. Dalrymple-
- Don't talk back to me!
I said, get out.
You want me to call the cops?
I make and break little worms
like you every day.
Do you know how much
money I make? Any idea?
Do you know where I live?
I could have any woman in this city
that I want. Anyone.
Now, get out!
What are you all looking at?!
Go back to work.
Back!
Doctor called and said I'm not gonna
get the results for another two days.
Oh, you're fine.
There's nothing wrong.
I'm the one who's dying.
- What do you mean?
- I can't act.
I stink. I don't know what I'm doing.
I'm gonna make a fool out of myself.
Come on, you're...
You're fine.
This show's gonna ruin my career.
- How did I get involved?
- What about me?
I was a total failure.
Everything was fine.
Now this thing's gonna be a success,
and God gives me a terminal disease.
This actress playing Elaine,
she's crazy.
The guy playing Kramer
threatened me.
- Why?
- I asked him about the raisins.
You mentioned the raisins.
- Oh, yeah.
- Did he take them?
I don't know.
Well, if he didn't take them...
...what happened to them?
That's what I'm trying to find out.
- Hey.
- Any luck?
- No. No, nothing.
I got no peristalsis.
- Well, what about bran?
- I tried bran.
Forty percent, 50 percent,
100 percent.
The bran isn't working for me.
- Well, what about Meta-?
- Did it.
- How about Ex-?
- Yeah, had it.
- Milk of Magne-?
- Yeah, yeah.
Well, my friend...
...it may be time to consider
the dreaded apparatus.
Hold it right there.
If you're suggesting what I think,
you're wasting your time.
I am not, Jerry, under any
circumstances, doing any...
...inserting in that area.
Oh, it's not that bad.
Yes, it is.
Well...
...it's all taken care of. I filed a report.
An investigation is under way.
So you going to the taping?
No, I don't think I should go.
I don't want to bump into Russell.
He called me the other day.
Come on, you gotta go. He's harmless.
He's got a little crush on you.
Jerry, this is not a crush.
This is a complete fixation.
He makes me very uncomfortable.
We need you there.
- Hey, are you gonna go?
- No, no, I-I'm gonna stay home. I...
I wanna be close to my home base, in
case there's any news from the front.
No. Pick it up more in the front.
It's gotta be higher. Higher.
Make a wall. A wall.
Sandi, are you in wardrobe?
- Sandi?
- Try " Elaine."
- Elaine?
- Yes?
Elaine?
It's me.
Wilton Marshall. Remember?
Camp Tioga, 1978?
- Remember?
- Right.
You know, you haven't changed a bit.
- I can't remember my lines.
- Just relax, you'll be fine.
I can't relax. I don't-
I don't know any of them.
You're just like George.
He'd do the same thing.
- You're just like him. It's amazing.
- Help me.
George is always saying that.
You don't have to worry anyway.
It's not live.
It's not on till next week.
Have a good show.
What's my first line?
Just tell me my first line.
- "New sneakers."
- "New sneakers. " Right, that's it.
Where's Russell?
You know, I don't know.
I assumed he wouldn't miss it.
He hasn't been well.
Can I tell you something
in confidence?
I think it's a woman.
How pathetic.
Yeah, this is George Costanza.
I'm-I'm calling for my test results.
Negative?
Oh, my God!
Why? Why? Why?
What?
Negative's good?
Yes, of course.
How stupid of me.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
What was I worried about?
Listen.
I know we've had our
problems in the past...
...but we got a show to do tonight.
Time to pull together as a team.
Life's too short.
I say, let's let bygones be bygones.
If you took the raisins,
if you didn't take the raisins...
They weren't even my raisins.
I-I was just curious because...
...seems like a strange
thing to do...
...to walk into a room, audition
and walk out with a box of raisins.
Anyway, whatever.
If you ever want to tell me about it,
the door to my office is always open.
In the event that I get an office.
You'll come in. We'll talk about the
raisins. We'll have a nice laugh.
How would you like it if I just...
...pulled your heart out of your chest
now and shoved it down your throat?
Good evening. Welcome to a taping
of the new show Jerry.
Does everybody know what a pilot is?
- Yeah, he flies a plane.
- No, a pilot is the taping of a show...
...that's the first show
before a TV series.
And this show will air on Thursday.
Are you ready to meet our cast?
All right.
Good evening, folks.
How you doing?
You sound like a great crowd.
We have a show we're gonna put on
for you tonight.
It's a- It's a new TV show.
It's what they call a pilot.
And we hope it becomes a series.
It's called Jerry. I'm playing Jerry-
Sic semper tyrannis!
What about Davola?
Did you believe that?
What was that thing he yelled out,
sic semper tyrannis? Is that Latin?
John Wilkes Booth yelled it
when he shot Lincoln.
- Really? What's it mean?
- It means "death to tyrants."
I could see that.
See, now, this is exciting!
This is exciting!
- Did I miss anything already?
- No, it starts in five minutes.
You were there.
What's the big deal?
Now it's on TV. It's different.
- I told everybody I know to watch it.
- Yeah, me too.
- Did you hear from Russell?
- No.
Strange, him not showing up
at the taping.
Well, well.
- Congratulations.
- Well, thank you.
- You went for the big E, huh?
- Wet and wild.
- Kramer, sit down. It's about to start.
- Oh, yes.
Hey, what is this?
Look, a wallet.
- A wallet? Let me see that.
- Here.
It's my father's wallet. He thought
they stole it at the doctor's office.
- This is it.
- How do you like that?
You hurt me.
- Hey.
- Hey, George.
- New sneakers?
- Yeah.
- What do you need new sneakers for?
- I like sneakers.
How do you decide which ones to
wear? I'd go crazy if I had to decide.
You're crazy anyway.
Why did you eat the top
off the muffins?
- So what?
- I can't eat it now.
- George.
What kind of stupid show is this?
Hey, that's that idiot that took
all my records.
John, what are you doing?
Come back to bed.
This show looks interesting.
Isn't he that Seinfeld fella you
went out with?
Oh, he's horrible. Horrible.
Nevertheless.
That Jerry's a funny guy, huh?
Got to love the "Sein."
I hate the "Sein."
This is a piece of crap.
Oh, Donald, you used to like him.
What a sellout.
Give me that remote. Give me that.
- Give me the remote.
- Donald.
- Jerry, the commercial's almost over.
- All right.
You know, I really like this guy
playing the butler.
Yeah, he's good.
He's John Ritter's cousin.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Hello, Charles.
- Hello.
So where do you want me
to start today?
- Why don't you start in the bedroom.
- I'll start in your bedroom.
- Hey.
- Hey. The butler's here.
He is? Listen.
When he's finished,
send him over to my house.
- I'm not sending him to your house.
- Why not?
The judge decreed he'd become
my butler, not my friend's butler.
Jerry, he is your butler. You can give
him any order you want.
- That's what butlers do.
- But I don't want to.
Jerry, my house is
a pigsty. Come on.
- Yeah?
- It's Elaine.
Come on up.
- I need more Pledge.
- More Pledge?
I just bought two cans last week,
and I don't have any wood here.
Well, it goes fast.
Hello.
What's all this about?
- We had a date last week.
- You had a date?
You went out with my butler? Who
said you could go out with my butler?
- Why do I need your permission?
- Because he's my butler.
That's terrific.
How could anyone not like him?
I like his style.
He has a sort of casual elegance.
But he picks his nose.
Nevertheless.
He's a member of our
health club, isn't he?
Yeah.
You know, that Kim Novak
had some big breasts.
You ever notice a lot of butlers
are named Jeeves?
You know, I think when you-
When you name a baby Jeeves...
...you've pretty much mapped out
his future, wouldn't you say?
Not much chance he's gonna be
a hitman, I think, after that.
"I'm terribly sorry, sir,
but I'm going to have to whack you."
Yeah.
Oh, wow, that was great.
That show was so funny.
It was really funny. I'm not just
saying that because I know you.
All right. Well, let's go out
and celebrate.
- That was so good.
- Come on, let's eat something.
I think this will get picked up, George.
You're gonna be rich!
- You really think so?
- Oh, yeah.
And God didn't kill me.
- Hello?
- Hi, Jerry.
- This is Rita Kirson.
- Oh, hi, Rita.
I'm calling to let you know...
...Russell Dalrymple is
no longer with this network.
Oh, my God. Did he get fired?
To be honest with you,
nobody really knows.
He seems to have disappeared.
Russell's disappeared?
In any event, I've been made
the new president of NBC.
As you may or may not know...
...Russell and I did not see eye to eye
on many, many projects.
And as my first order of business,
I'm passing on your show.
You're passing already?
The show just ended two minutes ago.
Well, I just got the job.
Goodbye, Jerry.
Yeah. See you.
What are you-?
What are you looking at me for?
- It was you.
- What-? What did I do?
Do you realize his obsession with you
cost us a TV series?!
I didn't know that he'd fall for me,
and I'd drive him insane, I mean-
- You know, that's not my fault.
- Yes, it is!
You're very charming!
I can't believe this.
What happened to him?
Where is he?
No one knows.
She works for Pendant Publishing.
She's the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
You know...
...I used to work for NBC,
but when I go back to her this time...
...she'll respect me.
You'd better get down.
They might start firing soon.
Hey, look at this.
What is going on here?
Well, well.
Nothing has changed.
How did this happen?
I talked to these guys at the Equal
Employment Opportunity Commission.
Hey. What are you two guys
doing here?
I thought you were gonna do
something. Now you're eating here?
No, that's- That's-That's why
we're here. We're checking things out.
- We're checking it out.
- Checking it out?
See you back at the office, guys.
Fred, Paul, lunch and dinner?
Boy, you guys ought to move in.
How about a piece of pie, on me, huh?
Sophia, take care of these fellows.
Hey, come here.
I want you to know something.
You are not gonna get
away with this.
- Get away with what?
- "With what?" You know what.
With the waitresses,
how they're all alike.
Of course they're alike.
They are my daughters.
Your daughters.
You must be very proud, Mr. Barzakian.
And may I say, sir, they're lovely girls.
Absolutely lovely girls.
It's nice to see such fine,
upstanding women...
- ...in gainful employment, Mr. Barzakian.
- Here's table for you.
- Oh, a table right here.
- Peggy.
Peggy. All right.
- Peggy?
- Peggy. His daughter Peggy.
Peggy's coming over to serve.
One of the family.
- My daughter Peggy.
- Peggy.
- Good to see you.
- Hi, Peggy.
Thank you very much.
- So guess what I gotta do tomorrow.
- What?
Start looking for a job.
You know what you ought to do?
You should work for Greenpeace.
You know, they attack the whalers
out on the open sea.
Are you crazy?
You take your life in your hands
with those nuts.
Keep fighting it, matey.
Get your head above the water.
I've got you, matey.
I got you. Matey.
I'll remember her name.
Elaine Benes.
I'll write to her.
I'll tell her all about you
and what you did out here.
Goodbye, matey.
Goodbye.
Now, I know women often complain
about the number of things...
...you have to do to get male attention.
The high heels, the pantyhose,
the makeup.
It's even worse if you're a man.
If you're a man,
you don't know what to do.
That's why we're building bridges,
climbing mountains...
...exploring uncharted territories.
You think we wanna do these things?
Nobody wants to build a bridge.
It's really, really hard.
Designing rockets,
flying off into space.
I guarantee you, every astronaut,
when he comes back from space...
...goes up to a girl and goes,
"So did you see me up there?"