Parents like to drag kids
to historical sights.
I remember going to
Colonial Williamsburg...
...and you see the supposedly
authentic blacksmith there.
He's got the three-cornered hat,
knickers...
...and the Def Leppard shirt.
My parents took me to the
Amish country, which to a kid...
...to see a bunch of people that have
no cars, no TV, no phone...
...they go, "So what? Neither do I."
So it's the whole community
that's been grounded.
That's the way they should
punish the kids.
"All right, get up to your room.
I've had it.
You are Amish, young man.
For the rest of this weekend.
Did you hear me? Amish.
Don't come down till you make
some noodles and raise a barn."
They have a guide. He takes you...
...shows you the battlefield,
gives you a bit of the history.
How far is Gettysburg?
I'd like to go.
- About three hours.
- Tommy, you're on.
- Gotta go.
- Have a good set.
What did they do for toilet paper
in the Civil War?
Wonder what toilet paper
was like in the 1860s.
Did they-? Did they carry it
in rolls in their duffel bags?
Everything with you comes down
to toilet paper.
- What?
- That's always...
...the first question with you.
Why is that always your focus?
- Then what did they do?
- I don't know.
Maybe they gave out big loose
clumps to all the soldiers.
It would be nice if there was some
sort of historical record of it.
They should have a toilet-paper
museum. Would you like that?
So we could see all the toilet-paper
advancements through the ages.
Toilet paper during the Crusades.
The development of the perforation.
The first six-pack.
Excuse me, Jerry.
I'm Stu Schirmack. I'm from NBC.
- Could we speak for a few moments?
- Sure.
- Hi. Jay Crespi.
- Hello.
- C-R-E-S-P-I.
- That's right.
I'm unbelievable
at spelling last names.
- Give give me a last name.
- I'm not-
George.
All right. All right.
First of all...
...that was a terrific show.
- Thank you very much.
- And-
I just wanted to let you know
that we've been discussing you...
...at some of our meetings, and we'd be
very interested in doing something.
- Really?
- So if you had an idea for, like...
...a TV show for yourself,
well, we'd just love to talk about it.
I'd be very interested in that.
Well, here.
Why don't you give us a call,
and maybe we can develop a series.
Okay. Great. Thanks.
- It was very nice meeting you.
- Thank you.
- Nice meeting you.
- What was that all about?
- They said they were interested in me.
- For what?
- You know, TV show.
- Your own show?
- Yeah, I guess so.
They want you to do a TV show?
They want me to come up with an
idea. I mean, I don't have any ideas.
Come on. How hard is that?
Look at all the junk that's on TV.
You want an idea? Here's an idea.
You coach a gymnastics team
in high school, and you're married.
Your son is not interested in
gymnastics, and you're pushing him.
Why should I care if
my son's into gymnastics?
- You're the teacher. It's only natural.
- But gymnastics is not for everybody.
- I know, but he's your son.
- So what?
All right, forget that idea.
It's not for you.
Okay, okay. I got it.
You run an antique store.
- Yeah. And?
- And people come into the store...
...and you get involved in their lives.
What person who runs an antique
store gets involved in people's lives?
- Why not?
- So someone comes in...
...to buy an old lamp, and suddenly
I'm getting them out of a jam.
I could see if I was a pharmacist.
A pharmacist knows
what's wrong with everybody.
Antiques are very popular right now.
- No, they're not. They used to be.
- Oh, sure.
- Like you know.
- Oh, like you do.
And you're the manager
of the circus.
- The circus?
- Oh, come on. This is a great idea.
Look at the characters. You got
all these freaks in the show.
A woman with a moustache.
Who wouldn't tune in to see
a woman with a moustache?
You got the tallest man in the world.
A guy who's just a head.
- I don't think so.
- Look...
...the show isn't about the circus.
It's about watching freaks.
I don't think the network
would go for it.
- Why not?
- I'm not pitching a show about freaks.
Oh, come on, Jerry. You're wrong.
People, they wanna watch freaks.
This is a "can't miss."
- Kramer.
- Hello, Newman.
I got the helmet.
Go get the radar detector.
Okay. I'll be back in a second.
You guys coming to my party?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Of course.
- What's this about?
- We're making a trade.
I'm giving him my motorcycle helmet.
He's giving me his radar detector.
- I didn't know you have a motorcycle.
- Well, my girlfriend had one.
You have a girlfriend?
I had a girlfriend.
And she was pretty wild.
- I don't remember you with a girl.
- Nevertheless.
This is a pretty bad deal for Kramer.
A radar detector's worth much more
than that helmet. You're cheating him.
- Don't say anything.
- All right.
Hey, you know you're
getting gypped over here.
Really.
Hey. We had a deal.
Are you reneging out of the deal?
Are you reneging?
- That's a renege.
- Stop saying " reneging."
- Well, you're reneging.
- Okay, okay. I'm not reneging.
All right. Give it to me.
- All right, let go.
- Come on.
- Let go on three.
- Give me that. Just give me that!
- Three.
- Here.
Idiots.
Thanks, buddy. So long.
- Does that thing work?
- No.
I got a postcard from Elaine.
- Really?
- Yeah. They're in London now.
They'll be back in a few weeks.
I can't believe she got
involved with her shrink.
What about the TV show?
Got anything?
No. Nothing.
Why don't they have salsa
on the table?
What do you need salsa for?
Salsa is now the number-one
condiment in America.
Do you know why?
Because people like to say "salsa."
Do you have any salsa?
We need more salsa.
Where is the salsa? No salsa?
You know, it must be impossible
for a Spanish person...
...to order seltzer and not get salsa.
I wanted seltzer, not salsa.
Don't you know the difference
between them?
You have the seltzer after the salsa.
This should be the show.
This is the show.
- What?
- This.
Just talking.
Yeah. Right.
No, I'm really serious.
I think that's a good idea.
Just talking?
Well, what's the show about?
It's about nothing.
- No story?
- No, forget the story.
- You gotta have a story.
- Who says you gotta have a story?
Remember when we were waiting for
that table in that Chinese restaurant?
That could be a TV show.
And who's on the show?
Who are the characters?
I could be a character.
- You?
- Yeah. You base a character on me.
So on the show there's a character
named George Costanza?
Yeah. What? There's something
wrong with that? I'm a character.
People are always saying to me,
"You know, you're quite a character."
And who else is on the show?
Elaine could be a character. Kramer.
Now, he's a character.
So everybody I know
is a character on the show.
Right.
- And it's about nothing.
- Absolutely nothing.
So you're saying I go into NBC
and tell them...
...I got this idea
for a show about nothing.
We go into NBC.
We? Since when are you a writer?
What writer?
We're talking about a sitcom.
You wanna go with me to NBC?
We really got something here.
- What do we got?
- An idea.
- What idea?
- An idea for the show.
- I still don't know what the idea is.
- It's about nothing.
- Right.
- Everybody's doing something.
We'll do nothing.
We go into NBC, tell them we got
an idea for a show about nothing.
- Exactly.
- "What's your show about?"
- I say, " Nothing."
- There you go.
I think you may have something here.
So the show would be
about my real life...
...and one of the characters
would be based on you.
No, I don't think so.
What do you mean,
you don't you think so?
- I don't like it.
- I don't understand.
- What don't you like?
- I don't like the idea...
- ...of a character based on me.
- Why not?
I don't know. It just doesn't sit well.
There's gotta be a character
based on you.
- That's your problem.
- I don't know what the big deal is.
You can do it on one condition.
- Whatever you want.
- I get to play Kramer.
- You can't play Kramer.
- I am Kramer.
But you can't act.
- Okay, fine, we'll use Newman.
- Newman?
- Use me for what?
- Nothing. What do you want?
Well, you'll never guess
what happened to me today.
I was driving home on
the Palisades Parkway...
...when I look in the rearview mirror,
and what did I see?
The fuzz. And it's funny...
...because my new radar detector
was on, but I didn't hear a thing.
- Isn't that strange?
- Yeah, that's strange.
Because the radar detector,
as I understand it, detects radar!
With a series of beeps
and flashing lights.
But for some reason,
I didn't hear a thing...
...except for the sound
of a police siren.
Well, that's queer, huh?
I want my helmet back!
You give me back my helmet,
and pay for that ticket!
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You better think again, MoJumbo.
You gave me a defective detector.
- Jerry?
- Buyer beware.
Are you gonna give me my helmet?
No, we had a deal.
There's no guarantees in life.
No, but there's karma, Kramer.
Karma Kramer?
And one more thing:
I'm not coming to your party!
Salsa, seltzer.
Do you have any salsa?
No, not seltzer, salsa.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
You sure?
- You look a little pale.
- No, I'm fine. I'm good.
Fine. Very good.
- What, are you nervous?
- No, I'm not nervous. I'm very good.
- I can't do this. I can't do this.
- What?
I can't. I've tried. I'm here.
It's impossible.
- This was your idea.
- What idea?
I just said something. I didn't
know you were gonna listen to me!
Don't worry about it.
They're just TV executives.
They're men with jobs, Jerry!
They wear suits and ties.
They're married.
They have secretaries!
- I told you not to come.
- I need some water.
I gotta get some water.
- They'll give us water in there.
- Really?
That's pretty good.
- Oh, God, it's Joe Davola.
- Who?
This guy's a writer. He's a total nut.
I think he goes to
the same shrink as Elaine.
Oh, God, he saw me.
- Hello, Jerry.
- Hey, Joe!
How you doing?
You're under no obligation
to shake my hand.
Oh, no. Just a custom.
That's my friend, George.
You look good.
Why shouldn't I look good?
No. No reason.
You do the karate, right?
Yeah, you wanna hit me?
- What are you doing here?
- I dropped a script off.
Good for you.
Well.
- You don't have to say anything.
- No...
- Hey, I guess I'll see you Sunday night.
- Why?
Kramer's party.
- Kramer's having a party?
- No. No, he's not having a party.
He's doing something. I don't know.
It's nothing. He's not doing anything.
I thought Kramer and I
were very close friends.
No, I'm sure you are.
I'm sure you're very close friends.
Very close.
Give my best to Hinckley.
- What was that?
- I can't believe what I did.
I didn't know Kramer didn't invite him.
I gotta call Kramer.
They're ready for you.
Okay. Okay. Look.
- You-You do all the talking. Okay?
- Oh, relax!
- Who are they?
- Yeah.
- They're not better than me.
- Of course not.
- Who are they?
- They're nobody.
- What about me?
- What about you?
- Why them? Why not me?
- Why not you?
- I'm just as good as them.
- Better.
- You really think so?
- No.
The bit- The bit I really liked was
where the parakeet flew into the mirror.
That was funny.
The parakeet in the mirror.
That is a good one, Stu.
Yeah. One of my favourites.
What about you, George? Have you
written anything we might know?
Well, possibly. I...
I wrote an off-Broadway show.
La Cocina.
Actually, it was off-off Broadway.
It was a comedy
about a Mexican chef.
It was- It was very funny.
There was one great scene
with the chef.
What was his name?
- Pepe.
- Oh, Pepe. Yes, Pepe.
And he was making tamales.
Oh, he actually cooked on the stage?
No, no, he mimed it.
That's what was so funny about it.
So, what have you two
come up with?
We thought about this
in a variety of ways...
- ...but the basic idea is I play myself-
- May I?
Go ahead.
I think I can sum up the show
for you with one word:
Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
What does that mean?
The show is about nothing.
- It's not about nothing.
- No, it's about nothing.
Well, maybe in philosophy.
But even nothing is something.
Mr. Dalrymple, your niece
is on the phone.
- I'll call back.
- D-A-L-R-I-M-P-E-L.
Not even close.
- Is that with a Y?
- No.
- What's the premise?
- As I was saying, I would play myself...
...as a comedian
living in New York...
...and I have a friend and a neighbour
and an ex-girlfriend.
- Which is all true.
- But nothing happens on the show.
You see, it's just like life.
You know, you eat, you go
shopping, you read, you eat...
- ...you read, you go shopping.
- You read?
You read on the show?
Well, I don't know about the reading.
We didn't discuss the reading.
All right, tell me about the stories.
- What kind of stories?
- Oh, no. No stories.
No stories?
- So, what is it?
- What did you do today?
- I got up and came to work.
- There's a show. That's a show.
How is that a show?
Well, maybe something happens
to you on the way to work.
No. No! No! Nothing happens!
Well, something happens.
- Well, why am I watching it?
- Because it's on TV.
Not yet.
Okay, look.
If you wanna just keep doing
the same old thing...
...then maybe this idea is not for you.
I, for one, am not going to
compromise my artistic integrity.
And I'll tell you something else:
This is the show,
and we're not gonna change it.
Right?
How about this?
I manage a circus.
I don't even wanna talk
about it anymore.
What were you thinking?
What was going on in your mind?
Artistic integrity.
Well, where did you
come up with that?
You're not artistic,
and you have no integrity.
You really need some help. A regular
psychiatrist couldn't even help you.
You need to go to, like,
Vienna or something.
You know what I mean? You need
to get involved at the university level.
Like where Freud studied,
and have people looking...
...and checking up on you.
That's the kind you need.
Not the once-a-week for 80 bucks.
No. You need a team.
A team of psychiatrists,
working round the clock...
...thinking about you,
having conferences.
Observing you, like the way
they did with the Elephant Man.
That's what I'm talking about. That's
the only way you're gonna get better.
I thought the woman
was kind of cute.
Hold it. I really wanna
be clear about this.
Are you talking about
the woman in the meeting?
Is that the woman
you're talking about?
Yeah. I thought I might
give her a call.
I don't meet that many women.
I meet, like, three women a year.
I mean, we've been introduced.
She knows my name.
- It's completely inappropriate.
- Why?
Maybe she liked me. I mean, she-
She was looking right at me.
I think she was impressed.
We had good eye contact
through the whole meeting.
- Oh, I forgot to call Kramer.
- Wait a minute, let me call Susan.
- No, this is more important.
- She might leave work any minute.
I gotta warn him that I told
Joe Davola about his party.
No!
What is it?
I was just thinking about
this patient of mine.
What?
Just wondering if he's taking
his medication.
Come on. We're on vacation.
Well, we were standing
in the waiting area there...
...and you know how Davola is.
He's all...
- Yeah?
- It's George.
And so I felt very
uncomfortable with him...
...and, you know, I just blurted out
something about your party.
- Back up a second.
- I didn't know you didn't invite him.
Why would I invite him?
- Well, I just assumed that-
- Assumed?
Never assume anything.
I don't want that nut in my house.
You know he's on medication.
- Well, hello. Oh, hello.
- Hello.
You remember Susan from NBC.
- Of course. How are you?
- Fine. Good to see you.
- This is Kramer.
- Hello.
All right, go ahead, Susan. Tell him.
- Tell me what?
- Well, I-
I'm sorry. Excuse me one second.
- Hello?
- Hi...
...would you be interested
in switching to TMI long distance?
I-I can't talk right now.
Why don't you give me your home
number, and I'll call later?
I'm sorry. We're not allowed
to do that.
I guess you don't want
people calling you at home.
- No.
- Well, now you know how I feel.
- So go ahead. Tell him.
- Well-
Kramer, are you drinking that milk?
- Yeah.
- What's the expiration date on that?
September third.
- The third?
Never should have
brought her up there.
Should have known better.
I should have seen it coming.
I didn't see it coming.
I think she saw it coming.
You know, she was behind the idea.
She was gonna champion the show.
I was bringing her up to tell you,
and she liked me.
Look, just because Kramer vomited
on her doesn't mean the deal is dead.
What are you, crazy?
It's a traumatic thing
to be thrown up on.
Vomiting is not a deal-breaker.
If Hitler had vomited on Chamberlain...
...he still would have
given him Czechoslovakia.
Chamberlain.
You could hold his head in the toilet,
he'd still give you half of Europe.
What happened to you?
Davola came after me.
What? Davola?
See, this guy is crazy.
I can't believe this. What happened?
Can I get coffee? You know,
I was walking home...
I had to pick up my helmet from
the shop. I had to get a new strap.
So I had it on, and I was checking
the strap out to make sure it fit.
And suddenly, I feel this kick
hit me on the side of the head.
It knocks me down. I look up,
and it's Crazy Joe Davola.
And he says, "That's what I think
of your party."
- Boy, that is some kick.
- Newman's helmet, it saved my life.
- Look at that.
- Wow, Newman's helmet.
I got bad news for you, buddy.
Davola says you're next.
Me? Why?
He doesn't like you.
What does he want from me?
I didn't do anything.
See, this is all Elaine's fault. She took
off to Europe with his psychiatrist.
He can't get his medication.
Now I got some nut after me.
Pass the cream.
Wait a second.
All right.
When you vomit on somebody...
...it is a social faux pas...
...from which there
is really no recovery.
At that point, there's really very
little you can say to the person.
There's no Hallmark cards
that cover this occasion.
There's no vomit sympathy-card
section of the store, you know.
"You wear it well."
You know, there's no words...
...that really capture, you know...
"Next time, lunch is on me."
There's no, really,
way to phrase the sentiment.
Where the hell did I put it?
- Where did I put it?
- What are you looking for?
The remote. The remote.
I can't find the remote.
Did I-? I lost it.
Did you take it?
- Did you put it some place?
- No, no, no.
All right, what is this?
- What is what?
- All right, very funny. I get it.
- You're in a weird mood.
- Come on.
Go to your apartment and fix it.
- Fix what?
- Your pants!
What is this? Why do I got
one pant leg on for?
Don't you know? Look at your face. You
only shaved the right side of your face.
- What is this, a joke?
- No joke. What? A joke?
You think this is funny?