1
00:00:03,880 --> 00:00:07,550
Antarctica, a vast, ice-locked continent

2
00:00:07,680 --> 00:00:11,110
larger than the United States
and Mexico combined.

3
00:00:13,720 --> 00:00:17,910
This is the coldest, windiest,
most lifeless place on Earth,

4
00:00:18,000 --> 00:00:21,470
first explored by humans
just 100 years ago.

5
00:00:23,960 --> 00:00:28,350
Today, this vast wilderness
has become a giant laboratory

6
00:00:28,440 --> 00:00:32,830
for the most important
and cutting-edge science on our planet.

7
00:00:45,560 --> 00:00:48,510
Landing at the geographical South Pole,

8
00:00:48,600 --> 00:00:52,870
the southernmost place on Earth,
feels like visiting another planet.

9
00:00:57,960 --> 00:01:02,030
Ahead lies the Amundsen-Scott
South Pole Station,

10
00:01:02,120 --> 00:01:03,470
one of the most sophisticated

11
00:01:03,560 --> 00:01:06,910
scientific research facilities
ever built.

12
00:01:11,760 --> 00:01:16,830
Despite sitting on top of the icecap
at an altitude of almost 10,000 feet,

13
00:01:16,920 --> 00:01:20,710
the station is maintained
at a comfortable 20 degrees centigrade

14
00:01:20,800 --> 00:01:22,270
throughout the year.

15
00:01:29,440 --> 00:01:33,030
It hosts scientists
from a whole range of disciplines

16
00:01:33,120 --> 00:01:37,190
and is home to two of the most
powerful telescopes on Earth.

17
00:01:40,120 --> 00:01:44,350
As well as housing hi-tech kit,
the base provides a life support system

18
00:01:44,440 --> 00:01:48,270
for people to rest, work
and play in relative comfort.

19
00:01:49,800 --> 00:01:54,070
This astonishing building is a triumph
of technology and engineering

20
00:01:54,160 --> 00:01:59,270
and is as close to a space station
as you can find anywhere on Earth.

21
00:02:04,360 --> 00:02:07,590
But a station this big needs support.

22
00:02:12,120 --> 00:02:16,150
Each summer, a convoy of tractors
brings in supplies

23
00:02:16,240 --> 00:02:18,190
travelling along a snow road

24
00:02:18,320 --> 00:02:21,830
nicknamed the McMurdo
South Pole Highway,

25
00:02:22,080 --> 00:02:24,510
a journey that takes
more than four weeks.

26
00:02:25,320 --> 00:02:29,710
The goods they bring will help sustain
the base for the next six months.

27
00:02:31,000 --> 00:02:35,950
Not long after the convoy departs,
the sun sets for the last time.

28
00:02:38,280 --> 00:02:41,350
The Antarctic winter has begun.

29
00:02:42,560 --> 00:02:46,870
A long, dark night
that will last for months.

30
00:02:51,680 --> 00:02:53,150
It's in the polar winter

31
00:02:53,240 --> 00:02:55,990
that the comfort and safety
of the South Pole Station

32
00:02:56,080 --> 00:02:58,470
really comes into its own.

33
00:03:03,840 --> 00:03:06,830
Though the peak of research activity
is in the summer,

34
00:03:06,920 --> 00:03:09,150
the station functions
all the year round

35
00:03:09,240 --> 00:03:13,790
with a skeleton crew of 50 people,
who spend the whole winter here.

36
00:03:16,480 --> 00:03:20,630
They have risen to the challenge
of making a habitable environment

37
00:03:20,720 --> 00:03:23,670
in one of the most
inhospitable places on Earth

38
00:03:23,760 --> 00:03:27,270
with a surprising installation,
a greenhouse.

39
00:03:28,200 --> 00:03:32,630
Here, fresh fruit and vegetables
are grown under artificial lights,

40
00:03:32,720 --> 00:03:35,390
while the rest of the continent
is in darkness.

41
00:03:36,920 --> 00:03:40,870
Regulations prevent soil
from being imported to the Antarctic,

42
00:03:40,960 --> 00:03:44,910
so the vegetables are grown
using a system of hydroponics.

43
00:03:45,000 --> 00:03:47,710
Their roots are held directly
in contact with water

44
00:03:47,800 --> 00:03:49,630
loaded with nutrients.

45
00:03:51,440 --> 00:03:55,910
Inside here, it's a comfortable
25 degrees Celsius.

46
00:03:56,000 --> 00:03:58,790
Relative humidity is about 55%.

47
00:04:00,400 --> 00:04:04,830
Outside, the temperature will be
at least -30 degrees Celsius,

48
00:04:04,920 --> 00:04:07,350
and as the winter
really starts to get going,

49
00:04:07,440 --> 00:04:10,630
it'll get as far down
as -80 degrees Celsius.

50
00:04:11,880 --> 00:04:13,870
So it's pretty cold outside.

51
00:04:13,960 --> 00:04:17,430
And this will be
the brightest environment

52
00:04:17,520 --> 00:04:19,870
one can find in Antarctica, I believe.

53
00:04:21,720 --> 00:04:23,950
This greenhouse is so hi-tech

54
00:04:24,040 --> 00:04:28,270
that the team can control the amount
of food and light the plants receive

55
00:04:28,360 --> 00:04:31,950
from the comfort of their office
in the University of Arizona.

56
00:04:40,200 --> 00:04:42,830
But to really appreciate
the achievements of modern science

57
00:04:42,920 --> 00:04:46,110
at the South Pole,
one must go back 100 years,

58
00:04:46,200 --> 00:04:49,350
to when science
and exploration began here.

59
00:04:51,400 --> 00:04:54,430
In 1911, Robert Falcon Scott
and his team

60
00:04:54,600 --> 00:04:57,070
built this hut as a supply base

61
00:04:57,160 --> 00:04:59,030
from which they would
set off on their quest

62
00:04:59,160 --> 00:05:02,830
to be the first humans
to reach the South Pole.

63
00:05:04,200 --> 00:05:08,590
Little has changed.
It's as if they only left yesterday.

64
00:05:09,960 --> 00:05:12,310
Unlike modern visitors
to the South Pole,

65
00:05:12,400 --> 00:05:16,070
these men had to bring everything
they would need with them.

66
00:05:17,040 --> 00:05:19,510
Their crates of supplies came by ship,

67
00:05:19,600 --> 00:05:22,110
containing materials to build the hut,

68
00:05:22,200 --> 00:05:24,950
as well as food and clothes for the men.

69
00:05:26,280 --> 00:05:29,830
Ten thousand
of these items still remain.

70
00:05:35,760 --> 00:05:40,470
All their food came in tins,
which still line the shelves today,

71
00:05:40,560 --> 00:05:45,350
while the bunks that this 25-man team
slept in during their first winter

72
00:05:45,440 --> 00:05:48,710
still look much as they did
a century ago.

73
00:05:55,960 --> 00:05:59,310
While Scott and his men
prepared for their race to the Pole,

74
00:05:59,400 --> 00:06:02,950
the team carried out
a variety of scientific experiments.

75
00:06:03,040 --> 00:06:06,910
They brought with them equipment
for studying meteorology, geology,

76
00:06:07,000 --> 00:06:08,990
and collecting specimens.

77
00:06:11,640 --> 00:06:14,590
Over the years,
the hut fell into disrepair

78
00:06:14,680 --> 00:06:16,990
until recently, a team began work

79
00:06:17,080 --> 00:06:20,230
on the world's most
remote restoration project.

80
00:06:23,440 --> 00:06:27,270
Their mission is to save the hut
from being destroyed by the ice,

81
00:06:27,360 --> 00:06:28,950
as well as to discover more

82
00:06:29,040 --> 00:06:32,230
about early science and survival
in Antarctica.

83
00:06:33,160 --> 00:06:37,670
The expedition was very well equipped
with equipment and technology.

84
00:06:37,760 --> 00:06:41,630
And there was also a telephone,
which they ran across the sea-ice

85
00:06:41,720 --> 00:06:44,310
and linked various
different places together.

86
00:06:44,400 --> 00:06:47,870
There's quite an elaborate system
of switches and lights.

87
00:06:47,960 --> 00:06:50,230
Interior-exterior electric light bulbs,

88
00:06:50,320 --> 00:06:53,910
which would have been
very cutting-edge indeed.

89
00:06:54,920 --> 00:06:59,230
And an enormous amount of
scientific equipment as well,

90
00:06:59,320 --> 00:07:00,910
of all manner and all sorts.

91
00:07:01,640 --> 00:07:04,430
We're very fortunate that
it's survived in the condition it has.

92
00:07:04,520 --> 00:07:08,590
I mean, the house was only intended
to last for two, three years at most

93
00:07:08,680 --> 00:07:10,270
and here we are, a century on.

94
00:07:10,360 --> 00:07:14,990
So we have this fabulous
opportunity now, if we act quickly,

95
00:07:15,080 --> 00:07:18,910
to preserve what's here
for future generations.

96
00:07:21,600 --> 00:07:23,510
Scott and his men left the hut

97
00:07:23,600 --> 00:07:26,110
on the 1st of November, 1911,

98
00:07:26,200 --> 00:07:29,350
to begin their journey on foot
to the South Pole.

99
00:07:33,040 --> 00:07:35,550
Ahead of them lay 800 miles

100
00:07:35,640 --> 00:07:39,510
of the most challenging terrain
on the planet.

101
00:07:42,040 --> 00:07:45,790
The route they chose through
the Transantarctic Mountains

102
00:07:45,880 --> 00:07:49,750
took them up the mighty
Beardmore Glacier.

103
00:07:49,840 --> 00:07:53,070
Slowly they traversed
its appalling surface,

104
00:07:53,160 --> 00:07:56,870
until finally,
they reached the ice plateau.

105
00:08:00,120 --> 00:08:03,710
They still faced
a further 300-mile trek.

106
00:08:05,720 --> 00:08:09,350
The achievement to finally
reaching the Pole was tainted

107
00:08:09,440 --> 00:08:13,870
by the fact that the Norwegian
Roald Amundsen had got there first.

108
00:08:17,520 --> 00:08:22,070
Scott and four others
perished on their return journey.

109
00:08:22,600 --> 00:08:25,150
Sixteen kilos of rocks and fossils,

110
00:08:25,240 --> 00:08:27,670
specimens that they had
dragged back with them

111
00:08:27,800 --> 00:08:30,550
were discovered
close to where they died.

112
00:08:36,120 --> 00:08:41,430
Nobody stood at the Pole again
for 44 years, until 1956,

113
00:08:41,520 --> 00:08:44,830
when the first scientific base
was established here.

114
00:08:47,120 --> 00:08:49,950
A small party from
the United States Navy

115
00:08:50,040 --> 00:08:51,950
landed supplies by plane

116
00:08:52,040 --> 00:08:55,990
so they could build the first
Amundsen-Scott South Pole Station,

117
00:08:56,480 --> 00:09:00,110
six wooden huts in the midst
of the barren icecap.

118
00:09:01,760 --> 00:09:05,310
That same year,
a science party over-wintered,

119
00:09:05,400 --> 00:09:10,630
the first humans ever to experience
the longest, darkest winter on earth.

120
00:09:12,160 --> 00:09:15,310
The old wooden huts
were replaced in the 1970s

121
00:09:15,400 --> 00:09:17,350
with this gigantic dome.

122
00:09:18,800 --> 00:09:21,110
But this, too, has been superseded,

123
00:09:21,200 --> 00:09:26,030
its panels dismantled and removed
without trace in 2010,

124
00:09:26,120 --> 00:09:30,350
as every manmade item
must be in Antarctica.

125
00:09:31,640 --> 00:09:36,310
The most recent South Pole Station
is designed to withstand extremes.

126
00:09:36,400 --> 00:09:40,510
Its curved sides funnel the wind
and it stands on stilts

127
00:09:40,600 --> 00:09:43,550
that can be raised to accommodate
the build-up of snow,

128
00:09:43,640 --> 00:09:47,230
which accumulates at a rate
of 20 centimetres every year.

129
00:09:49,520 --> 00:09:53,110
All this is a far cry
from the bleak white emptiness

130
00:09:53,200 --> 00:09:55,190
that confronted Amundsen and Scott.

131
00:09:55,280 --> 00:09:59,030
They would be truly amazed
to see what exists here today.

132
00:10:04,440 --> 00:10:07,190
Science has come
a long way in the last century,

133
00:10:07,280 --> 00:10:11,830
yet the goals of those who come here
are in many ways still the same.

134
00:10:16,200 --> 00:10:19,750
This is a place where scientists
look to the skies,

135
00:10:19,840 --> 00:10:22,150
releasing weather balloons twice a day

136
00:10:22,240 --> 00:10:26,550
to collect vital data about the level
of ozone in our atmosphere.

137
00:10:32,640 --> 00:10:36,830
The South Pole is also said
to have the cleanest air on Earth,

138
00:10:36,920 --> 00:10:38,310
which has been sampled here

139
00:10:38,400 --> 00:10:42,630
at the Atmospheric Research
Observatory for the last 50 years,

140
00:10:42,720 --> 00:10:48,350
giving a long-term baseline for gases
such as carbon dioxide, or CO²,

141
00:10:48,440 --> 00:10:51,670
data that is crucial
to modern climate science.

142
00:10:53,000 --> 00:10:55,630
Climate change
is a really hot topic right now

143
00:10:55,760 --> 00:11:00,990
and it's really important
that we monitor the levels of CO².

144
00:11:01,080 --> 00:11:04,590
Basically, we want to know
how much it's increasing

145
00:11:04,680 --> 00:11:06,550
or how much it's decreasing or...

146
00:11:06,640 --> 00:11:09,990
This long-term record
really displays that very well.

147
00:11:10,080 --> 00:11:14,110
Especially down here,
we get a really good global average

148
00:11:14,200 --> 00:11:15,710
because there's no local influences.

149
00:11:15,800 --> 00:11:20,510
We can tell what the level is
without being right next to a city.

150
00:11:29,400 --> 00:11:32,030
And it's not just the current climate

151
00:11:32,120 --> 00:11:34,150
which can be studied here.

152
00:11:38,680 --> 00:11:41,750
The ice of the South Pole
is the perfect place

153
00:11:41,840 --> 00:11:44,350
to investigate our past.

154
00:11:45,880 --> 00:11:48,750
This is the IceCube facility,

155
00:11:48,840 --> 00:11:52,910
the powerhouse for an enormous
underground system of sensors

156
00:11:53,000 --> 00:11:55,750
that uses the pristine Antarctic ice

157
00:11:55,840 --> 00:11:58,150
as a natural laboratory
in which to study

158
00:11:58,240 --> 00:12:00,750
the beginning of the whole universe.

159
00:12:02,280 --> 00:12:08,590
IceCube covers a cubic kilometre
but is buried deep below the surface.

160
00:12:09,480 --> 00:12:12,030
A heated drill is used to melt holes

161
00:12:12,120 --> 00:12:14,670
one and a half miles
down into the icecap,

162
00:12:14,760 --> 00:12:17,870
a process that takes about 48 hours.

163
00:12:26,480 --> 00:12:29,630
Into the holes are lowered
chains of photo detectors,

164
00:12:29,720 --> 00:12:34,470
which look for tiny ghost-like particles
passing through the ice.

165
00:12:35,200 --> 00:12:37,510
The particles are called neutrino,

166
00:12:37,600 --> 00:12:41,390
formed billions of years ago
after the birth of the universe.

167
00:12:43,040 --> 00:12:45,950
Neutrinos are
extremely difficult to detect,

168
00:12:46,360 --> 00:12:50,390
but as they pass through the earth
and enter the pure, transparent ice,

169
00:12:50,480 --> 00:12:53,430
they occasionally crash into atoms,

170
00:12:53,520 --> 00:12:57,830
sparking tiny flashes of blue light
that reveal their existence.

171
00:12:59,160 --> 00:13:01,310
IceCube is a neutrino telescope.

172
00:13:01,400 --> 00:13:03,310
So, it's like a regular telescope.

173
00:13:03,400 --> 00:13:05,470
We're trying to make
an image of the universe,

174
00:13:05,560 --> 00:13:07,790
but instead of using light,
we're using particles.

175
00:13:08,920 --> 00:13:09,990
What they learn

176
00:13:10,080 --> 00:13:12,350
from mapping the direction
of these particles

177
00:13:12,440 --> 00:13:14,470
will provide a fascinating insight

178
00:13:14,560 --> 00:13:17,790
into the cosmos
and the very beginning of time.

179
00:13:28,360 --> 00:13:31,590
While Antarctica's ice can help us
understand our past,

180
00:13:31,680 --> 00:13:35,630
it also holds information
which is very relevant to the present.

181
00:13:54,600 --> 00:13:59,870
This long-range DC-3 plane
was built in 1942,

182
00:13:59,960 --> 00:14:03,750
but has been fitted with
very modern ground-penetrating radar,

183
00:14:03,840 --> 00:14:06,390
which can effectively
see through the ice.

184
00:14:10,440 --> 00:14:12,510
The plane is a mobile lab,

185
00:14:12,600 --> 00:14:16,430
from which scientists can map
the miles of unexplored landscape,

186
00:14:16,520 --> 00:14:21,030
not just at the surface, but deep below,
where the ice meets rock.

187
00:14:25,400 --> 00:14:28,910
This airplane is called
an aero geodesical platform.

188
00:14:29,000 --> 00:14:31,950
And a platform like this allows you

189
00:14:33,680 --> 00:14:35,430
to combine multiple data sets.

190
00:14:35,520 --> 00:14:39,030
In this case we have 14 instruments,
operating simultaneously.

191
00:14:39,120 --> 00:14:43,310
And each of them
has a role in characterising

192
00:14:43,400 --> 00:14:46,790
the geology and the glaciology

193
00:14:46,880 --> 00:14:49,190
in the Antarctic region
that we're flying in right now.

194
00:14:49,920 --> 00:14:52,030
Much of the ice that covers Antarctica

195
00:14:52,120 --> 00:14:54,470
is over two and a half miles thick.

196
00:14:54,560 --> 00:14:57,990
It cloaks mountain ranges,
volcanoes and lakes

197
00:14:58,080 --> 00:15:02,270
and in places, its weight depresses
the land far below sea level.

198
00:15:02,640 --> 00:15:05,310
It's just incredible,
the things that are down there

199
00:15:05,400 --> 00:15:08,350
that you would just never know
without these instruments.

200
00:15:09,080 --> 00:15:10,190
When you look out the window,

201
00:15:10,280 --> 00:15:13,350
all you see is ice
as far as the eye can see,

202
00:15:13,440 --> 00:15:16,270
and you very well may be flying over

203
00:15:16,360 --> 00:15:19,750
a mountain range
the size of the Rockies.

204
00:15:21,440 --> 00:15:24,830
Being in Antarctica
is just a very special experience.

205
00:15:25,640 --> 00:15:29,070
It's an honour to be
a part of a programme

206
00:15:29,160 --> 00:15:32,470
that is acquiring such important data

207
00:15:34,120 --> 00:15:36,070
for building understanding
of our natural environment

208
00:15:36,160 --> 00:15:37,550
that's hard to reach.

209
00:15:39,560 --> 00:15:43,430
Far from being static,
Antarctica's ice is on the move,

210
00:15:43,520 --> 00:15:47,790
flowing out from the thickest part
of the ice sheet towards the coast.

211
00:15:49,960 --> 00:15:52,470
What's more, the ice is changing fast.

212
00:15:52,880 --> 00:15:55,670
It's hard to imagine,
but if all this ice melted,

213
00:15:55,760 --> 00:16:00,190
it would contribute more than
60 metres to our global sea levels.

214
00:16:05,880 --> 00:16:08,990
Scientific programmes
like this one are vital.

215
00:16:09,080 --> 00:16:11,070
We need to know the volume of this ice

216
00:16:11,160 --> 00:16:13,510
and better understand how it behaves

217
00:16:13,600 --> 00:16:17,230
before we can predict
the long-term future of this icecap

218
00:16:17,320 --> 00:16:20,670
and what that in turn
means for the rest of us.

219
00:16:35,160 --> 00:16:38,350
The place where change
is happening most rapidly

220
00:16:38,440 --> 00:16:40,750
is around the edges of the ice sheet,

221
00:16:40,840 --> 00:16:43,430
where the ice flows out over the sea.

222
00:16:45,440 --> 00:16:48,310
And that is where much
scientific attention

223
00:16:48,400 --> 00:16:50,230
is now being focused.

224
00:16:52,000 --> 00:16:54,910
Well, I've been
working down here for 25 years.

225
00:16:55,000 --> 00:16:58,750
But I have never felt
such a sense of urgency

226
00:16:58,840 --> 00:17:01,030
as I do with this particular project.

227
00:17:01,480 --> 00:17:03,910
We know the sea level
is rising right now.

228
00:17:04,000 --> 00:17:06,590
It has been rising for the last century.

229
00:17:06,680 --> 00:17:09,710
But it's rising faster now
than it was before.

230
00:17:09,800 --> 00:17:12,270
And we expect that acceleration
to continue.

231
00:17:13,120 --> 00:17:16,030
To understand what the ocean
is doing to the ice,

232
00:17:16,120 --> 00:17:18,190
we have to get into the ocean.

233
00:17:18,280 --> 00:17:21,870
And the path to get to the ocean
is through that ice shelf.

234
00:17:21,960 --> 00:17:24,110
So, we use a hot water drill

235
00:17:24,200 --> 00:17:27,150
to make a hole, just melt a hole
all the way through the ice shelf.

236
00:17:27,680 --> 00:17:31,670
And through that hole then
we can deploy our ocean profiler.

237
00:17:33,760 --> 00:17:38,470
This ocean profiler is a specially
designed recording device

238
00:17:38,560 --> 00:17:41,750
which is dropped through the ice sheet
to the ocean below.

239
00:17:42,480 --> 00:17:45,870
It's a unique and expensive
piece of equipment.

240
00:17:46,280 --> 00:17:49,550
It's about as tense
a deployment as I've ever made.

241
00:17:51,240 --> 00:17:54,830
There's no spares of this thing.
So far, so good.

242
00:17:54,920 --> 00:17:58,150
But you never really know
how it's all going to work out

243
00:17:58,240 --> 00:18:00,350
until you're out here
in the field doing it.

244
00:18:00,440 --> 00:18:01,790
Over the coming months,

245
00:18:01,880 --> 00:18:04,550
the ocean profiler
will transmit information

246
00:18:04,640 --> 00:18:07,510
about what's happening
below this ice shelf

247
00:18:07,600 --> 00:18:09,710
back to a lab in Monterey.

248
00:18:10,160 --> 00:18:12,350
It's going to be telling us
the type of water

249
00:18:12,440 --> 00:18:14,310
that's coming in underneath the ice

250
00:18:14,400 --> 00:18:16,830
and the type of water
that leaves the ice.

251
00:18:16,920 --> 00:18:20,670
And from that difference,
we know what it's done to the ice,

252
00:18:20,760 --> 00:18:24,270
how much ice has been melted,
because it's that melting of ice

253
00:18:24,360 --> 00:18:27,470
that thins the ice shelf
and that ice shelf...

254
00:18:27,560 --> 00:18:30,950
A thinner ice shelf can't hold
the ice sheet back as well.

255
00:18:31,040 --> 00:18:34,670
So, once the ice shelf thins,
that glacier accelerates.

256
00:18:35,040 --> 00:18:38,550
What we're doing down here
is so important because

257
00:18:38,640 --> 00:18:41,710
sea level all around the world
will be affected

258
00:18:41,800 --> 00:18:43,790
as Antarctica shrinks.

259
00:18:43,880 --> 00:18:45,990
And almost half
of the world's population

260
00:18:46,080 --> 00:18:49,910
lives close to the coast
and is affected by changes in sea level.

261
00:18:50,920 --> 00:18:54,590
Antarctica may feel
like the other end of the planet,

262
00:18:54,680 --> 00:18:57,990
but anything that happens here
affects us all.

263
00:18:58,080 --> 00:19:01,550
We may think of this continent
as being frozen in time,

264
00:19:01,640 --> 00:19:04,350
but in fact, the ice
has a life of its own.

265
00:19:06,360 --> 00:19:08,910
And nowhere is that
more clearly illustrated

266
00:19:09,000 --> 00:19:11,190
than at the South Pole itself,

267
00:19:11,280 --> 00:19:14,470
which before and since
mankind visited it,

268
00:19:14,560 --> 00:19:17,230
has continued to be on the move.

269
00:19:18,440 --> 00:19:21,710
Hi, first and foremost I'd like to thank
each and every one of you

270
00:19:21,800 --> 00:19:23,270
for showing up here today.

271
00:19:23,360 --> 00:19:25,870
It's fantastic to see
such a large turnout

272
00:19:25,960 --> 00:19:28,630
for these traditions of the South Pole.

273
00:19:29,280 --> 00:19:32,390
What we're here today for
is the annual remarking

274
00:19:32,480 --> 00:19:34,790
of the geographic South Pole.

275
00:19:34,880 --> 00:19:38,870
Now, as you all know,
the South Pole Station, our home,

276
00:19:38,960 --> 00:19:42,590
sits on top of a 3,000 metre
deep polar icecap.

277
00:19:42,800 --> 00:19:47,190
And that icecap moves at about
a rate of 10 metres every year.

278
00:19:47,280 --> 00:19:51,950
Or if you prefer, probably about
2.7 centimetres every day.

279
00:19:52,040 --> 00:19:54,870
It is my honour to present to you guys,

280
00:19:54,960 --> 00:19:58,630
on behalf of the winter-over crew
of 2009,

281
00:19:59,720 --> 00:20:03,710
the geographic South Pole marker
for 2010.

282
00:20:07,120 --> 00:20:12,350
It carries the inscription of the name
of every member of the winter-over crew.

283
00:20:12,440 --> 00:20:15,670
With this,
I would like to invite all of you

284
00:20:15,760 --> 00:20:19,270
to participate in relocating
this marker,

285
00:20:19,360 --> 00:20:23,070
the new, accurately placed
geographic South Pole.

286
00:20:24,960 --> 00:20:29,390
The ceremonial marker
and Antarctic Treaties state flags

287
00:20:29,480 --> 00:20:33,630
serve as a reminder that Antarctica
belongs to no one,

288
00:20:33,720 --> 00:20:36,790
but is reserved
for the interests of science

289
00:20:36,880 --> 00:20:39,470
and the progress of all mankind.

