1
00:00:33,280 --> 00:00:34,910
The polar winter.

2
00:00:41,600 --> 00:00:44,830
This is the planet at its most hostile.

3
00:00:58,520 --> 00:01:05,110
Those that stay here at this time must
face the harshest conditions on Earth.

4
00:01:26,840 --> 00:01:30,070
The high Arctic in late autumn,

5
00:01:30,160 --> 00:01:33,990
empty and abandoned to ice and snow.

6
00:01:37,600 --> 00:01:40,430
Most animals migrated south weeks ago.

7
00:01:41,920 --> 00:01:45,230
The few that stay
will face violent winds,

8
00:01:45,320 --> 00:01:48,710
plunging temperatures
and months of darkness.

9
00:01:52,680 --> 00:01:55,510
A female polar bear
searches for shelter.

10
00:02:00,520 --> 00:02:03,790
Other bears are out on
the frozen ocean looking for food

11
00:02:03,880 --> 00:02:07,110
but she won't feed again
until next spring.

12
00:02:11,400 --> 00:02:16,750
Using as little energy as possible,
she starts to dig a shallow nest.

13
00:02:24,040 --> 00:02:26,590
The snow here is easy to work.

14
00:02:26,680 --> 00:02:28,030
It's soft and light,

15
00:02:28,120 --> 00:02:31,990
a sure sign that soon plenty more
will accumulate on this slope,

16
00:02:32,080 --> 00:02:33,710
as winter advances.

17
00:02:36,280 --> 00:02:37,950
And that is what she needs.

18
00:02:48,800 --> 00:02:53,910
If she has chosen well, the Arctic wind
will do much of her work for her.

19
00:03:07,680 --> 00:03:10,030
Once the snow here is deep enough,

20
00:03:10,120 --> 00:03:12,310
she will dig down to make a den.

21
00:03:12,920 --> 00:03:17,910
She'll then lie, waiting for her cubs
to be born as winter sets in.

22
00:03:34,040 --> 00:03:38,390
The sea-ice already covers twice
the area it did in summer.

23
00:03:38,480 --> 00:03:42,990
Those animals that a few weeks ago
came down here feed in the sea

24
00:03:43,080 --> 00:03:44,710
are now locked out.

25
00:03:47,240 --> 00:03:50,190
But there are windows in this
white desert,

26
00:03:50,280 --> 00:03:53,150
gateways to the rich ocean below.

27
00:03:58,160 --> 00:04:02,710
Most birds have migrated south,
but in the frozen Bering Sea,

28
00:04:02,800 --> 00:04:05,310
ducks of one particular species

29
00:04:05,400 --> 00:04:08,830
are gathering together
in a single, immense flock.

30
00:04:14,480 --> 00:04:19,270
Spectacled eiders,
hundreds of thousands of them.

31
00:04:50,600 --> 00:04:54,230
With the seas that fed them
throughout the summer all but frozen,

32
00:04:54,320 --> 00:04:57,070
this is the eider's last refuge.

33
00:05:04,680 --> 00:05:08,830
Such patches of open water,
kept free of ice by strong currents,

34
00:05:08,920 --> 00:05:12,070
are given a Russian name, polynyas.

35
00:05:19,440 --> 00:05:21,990
If this polynya stays open all winter,

36
00:05:22,080 --> 00:05:25,070
the ducks will have avoided
an exhausting migration.

37
00:05:26,480 --> 00:05:31,070
It's a gamble and a tremendous risk,
especially for the spectacled eider,

38
00:05:31,160 --> 00:05:35,030
for this polynya
holds the world's entire population.

39
00:05:54,840 --> 00:05:56,670
Surrounded by ice,

40
00:05:56,760 --> 00:06:02,030
these spectacled eiders' survival
depends on this single, vulnerable oasis

41
00:06:02,640 --> 00:06:05,830
and conditions here can change
very fast.

42
00:06:18,720 --> 00:06:20,270
A smaller pool.

43
00:06:21,320 --> 00:06:24,990
Here, common eider ducks
are learning a bitter lesson.

44
00:06:26,400 --> 00:06:31,270
An early winter storm has caught
them out and the ice is closing in.

45
00:06:34,440 --> 00:06:38,710
The pool is shrinking and
the ducks are freezing to death.

46
00:06:53,000 --> 00:06:55,590
These gamblers have lost.

47
00:07:09,880 --> 00:07:14,270
As the sun's influence continues to
dwindle here in the north,

48
00:07:14,360 --> 00:07:18,030
the cold pushes south
into Arctic lands.

49
00:07:35,720 --> 00:07:39,830
Winter brings
a devastatingly destructive force,

50
00:07:41,240 --> 00:07:42,550
frost.

51
00:07:47,280 --> 00:07:51,190
Ice crystals form
as moisture in the air freezes.

52
00:07:52,960 --> 00:07:56,830
Inside plants, the same thing
is happening to the water in their cells

53
00:07:56,920 --> 00:07:58,670
and their sap.

54
00:08:02,400 --> 00:08:06,150
With these first frosts,
most plants die,

55
00:08:06,240 --> 00:08:09,950
their insides ripped apart
by ice crystals.

56
00:08:16,440 --> 00:08:19,510
Coniferous trees, however,
like fir and pine,

57
00:08:19,600 --> 00:08:21,910
can withstand very low temperatures.

58
00:08:25,000 --> 00:08:29,350
It's these trees that create
the greatest forest on our planet.

59
00:08:31,520 --> 00:08:33,790
This is the Taiga.

60
00:08:40,800 --> 00:08:45,110
It encircles the globe and contains
one third of all the trees on Earth.

61
00:08:57,480 --> 00:08:58,910
As winter deepens,

62
00:08:59,000 --> 00:09:03,310
frigid air from the Arctic meets
warm, moist air from the south,

63
00:09:03,400 --> 00:09:06,230
producing particularly heavy snows.

64
00:09:12,880 --> 00:09:14,950
For the big animals of the forest,

65
00:09:15,040 --> 00:09:17,550
there's no way of hiding
from the winter.

66
00:09:22,600 --> 00:09:27,830
But size, for the bison of Northern
Canada, is in fact their salvation.

67
00:09:27,920 --> 00:09:31,990
Big bodies lose
less heat and can carry more insulation.

68
00:09:33,280 --> 00:09:38,470
That may be why these bison are the
largest land animals in North America.

69
00:09:41,960 --> 00:09:45,230
And only a large predator
can tackle them.

70
00:09:53,680 --> 00:09:55,550
Wolves hunt better in packs,

71
00:09:55,640 --> 00:10:00,110
but there are only two of them here
and the prey they pursue are giants.

72
00:10:16,880 --> 00:10:20,110
A vast Arctic wilderness
stretches all around.

73
00:10:20,960 --> 00:10:23,870
In it, somewhere, there are bison.

74
00:10:30,280 --> 00:10:34,550
These deep tracks in the snow
are easy to follow

75
00:10:34,640 --> 00:10:37,190
but which way were the bison going?

76
00:10:52,480 --> 00:10:55,670
They have detected a scent,
the hunt is on.

77
00:11:01,000 --> 00:11:03,310
Running in the bison's tracks is easy.

78
00:11:03,400 --> 00:11:05,870
The snow here is compressed and firm.

79
00:11:07,640 --> 00:11:10,510
At this rate, the wolves will
soon catch up.

80
00:11:15,560 --> 00:11:17,430
They attempt a shortcut.

81
00:11:18,960 --> 00:11:22,990
The giant bison can plough on
through virgin snow,

82
00:11:23,080 --> 00:11:25,390
but for the wolves,
deep snow is a hindrance

83
00:11:25,480 --> 00:11:27,870
and now they're losing ground.

84
00:11:45,280 --> 00:11:50,190
The hunters rejoin the bison's tracks
and the contest is on again.

85
00:12:07,800 --> 00:12:10,710
The bison are the only prey
here in winter,

86
00:12:10,800 --> 00:12:14,030
the wolves have no option,
they must tackle them.

87
00:12:16,760 --> 00:12:19,310
But bison are 10 times their size!

88
00:12:37,520 --> 00:12:41,390
In winter, the line between life
and death is so narrow

89
00:12:41,480 --> 00:12:45,190
that for a wolf, even a small
injury could be fatal.

90
00:12:46,320 --> 00:12:48,910
It's crucial they select
the right target.

91
00:12:50,000 --> 00:12:51,790
This one is very big.

92
00:12:53,480 --> 00:12:54,950
Good decision!

93
00:13:14,520 --> 00:13:16,990
This is smaller, a yearling.

94
00:13:19,680 --> 00:13:23,990
Even though it's young, it's nonetheless
heavier than both wolves combined

95
00:13:24,080 --> 00:13:26,230
and it is extremely powerful.

96
00:13:53,400 --> 00:13:57,550
The male wolf backs off,
perhaps he's frightened of injury.

97
00:13:57,640 --> 00:14:01,190
But the female is the more determined,
or more desperate.

98
00:14:41,880 --> 00:14:46,070
Having given so much already,
she must make the kill.

99
00:14:46,520 --> 00:14:50,390
This a battle of life and death
for them both.

100
00:15:01,840 --> 00:15:04,590
The bison has no strength left,

101
00:15:06,040 --> 00:15:07,750
the battle is over.

102
00:15:19,880 --> 00:15:21,950
Winter deepens,

103
00:15:22,040 --> 00:15:26,350
the snow continues to accumulate,
smothering the forest.

104
00:15:37,760 --> 00:15:41,430
Some trees are loaded
with three tonnes of snow.

105
00:15:43,480 --> 00:15:46,870
It shuts out what little light
there is at these latitudes,

106
00:15:46,960 --> 00:15:50,150
and that shortens
the growing season still further

107
00:15:50,240 --> 00:15:53,430
and limits how far north
trees are able to grow.

108
00:16:02,760 --> 00:16:07,190
So snow influences
both the shapes of the trees

109
00:16:07,280 --> 00:16:09,430
and the extent of this forest.

110
00:16:15,560 --> 00:16:17,590
And it affects the animals, too.

111
00:16:20,600 --> 00:16:25,430
It helps to have friends if you want to
find food at this time of the year.

112
00:16:27,200 --> 00:16:31,110
Wolverines and ravens,
a match made in the Taiga.

113
00:16:34,000 --> 00:16:36,990
It's the hardest time
of the year to find food.

114
00:16:37,200 --> 00:16:41,910
But the wolverine knows that a raven's
call is as good as a dinner bell.

115
00:16:45,640 --> 00:16:50,470
And the raven has just recruited
the best can-opener in the forest.

116
00:16:53,680 --> 00:16:55,910
The moose carcass is frozen solid,

117
00:16:56,000 --> 00:16:58,790
but the wolverine has
immensely powerful jaws,

118
00:16:58,880 --> 00:17:01,830
well able to deal with "frozen food".

119
00:17:02,400 --> 00:17:06,350
The raven's bill is more suited
to leftovers.

120
00:17:18,080 --> 00:17:19,910
The raven has to be patient.

121
00:17:27,800 --> 00:17:30,310
A wolverine's appetite is legendary.

122
00:17:31,080 --> 00:17:34,390
According to folklore,
it can eat more at one sitting

123
00:17:34,480 --> 00:17:39,030
than any other creature in the forest,
hence its other name, the glutton.

124
00:17:51,200 --> 00:17:55,830
What the wolverine can't eat now,
it stores in the deep freeze.

125
00:17:56,640 --> 00:17:59,710
It will bury these food parcels
across the forest,

126
00:17:59,800 --> 00:18:02,310
planning ahead for leaner times.

127
00:18:12,680 --> 00:18:16,230
For a few, the snow is an ally.

128
00:18:32,480 --> 00:18:36,590
Voles stay active throughout the winter
beneath the snow,

129
00:18:36,680 --> 00:18:39,390
despite the freezing temperatures above.

130
00:18:45,160 --> 00:18:47,270
Travelling along tiny corridors,

131
00:18:47,360 --> 00:18:51,470
they move from pocket to pocket
of perfectly refrigerated food.

132
00:18:55,680 --> 00:18:58,030
Snow is a great insulator,

133
00:18:58,120 --> 00:19:03,670
so down here the temperature never falls
more than a degree or so below zero

134
00:19:04,160 --> 00:19:06,910
and that's warm enough for
a vole to thrive,

135
00:19:07,000 --> 00:19:09,670
even if it lacks the stature of a bison.

136
00:19:17,280 --> 00:19:19,910
In some years vole numbers boom,

137
00:19:20,800 --> 00:19:24,830
and then they are forced break cover
to search for more food.

138
00:19:53,000 --> 00:19:56,790
The great grey owl is
silent and very skilful hunter,

139
00:19:56,880 --> 00:20:00,070
but deep snow can be beyond its reach.

140
00:20:05,360 --> 00:20:08,870
But such snow is no barrier
to one predator.

141
00:20:12,040 --> 00:20:13,670
The least weasel.

142
00:20:14,680 --> 00:20:17,990
A tiny hunter and the vole's nemesis.

143
00:20:21,680 --> 00:20:25,270
Its body is exactly
the same width as a vole's,

144
00:20:25,360 --> 00:20:29,070
so there's nowhere a vole can go
that the weasel can't follow.

145
00:21:14,040 --> 00:21:18,510
The weasel's long, slender shape
is perfect for hunting in tunnels,

146
00:21:18,600 --> 00:21:21,550
but the worst possible shape
for staying warm.

147
00:21:21,680 --> 00:21:24,350
So they need a special
way of doing that.

148
00:21:33,960 --> 00:21:37,430
She plucks the fur from its body,
tuft by tuft.

149
00:21:47,400 --> 00:21:51,390
And now she puts it all
together to make a cosy blanket,

150
00:21:51,480 --> 00:21:54,630
under which to sleep in her den
below the snow.

151
00:22:09,560 --> 00:22:12,070
Midwinter in the northern forests.

152
00:22:13,720 --> 00:22:17,190
The sun is so low
that it's twilight at midday.

153
00:22:23,520 --> 00:22:25,910
Further north in the high Arctic,

154
00:22:26,000 --> 00:22:28,710
the sun has been below
the horizon for months

155
00:22:28,800 --> 00:22:31,830
and it'll be several more
before it appears again.

156
00:23:21,680 --> 00:23:25,630
The male polar bear
spends winter out on the frozen ocean.

157
00:23:28,600 --> 00:23:31,350
Few creatures can
endure these conditions.

158
00:23:37,800 --> 00:23:42,390
If he's lucky, he will find a carcass
that could provide a little food,

159
00:23:42,480 --> 00:23:45,830
possibly that of
a fox or another polar bear.

160
00:23:49,040 --> 00:23:52,390
But otherwise, he must
live on his reserves.

161
00:23:55,160 --> 00:23:59,310
This is the time to scrape by, to wait.

162
00:24:08,800 --> 00:24:14,990
But on lee-side slopes, beneath
the snow, new lives are beginning.

163
00:24:34,720 --> 00:24:38,590
The cubs are born blind and tiny,

164
00:24:38,680 --> 00:24:42,590
an early birth is easier
on the mother, who is barely awake.

165
00:24:57,200 --> 00:25:02,350
Despite her sleepiness,
her instinct to nurse is overwhelming.

166
00:25:16,960 --> 00:25:21,110
The cubs' clucking calls stimulate her
to produce milk.

167
00:25:21,680 --> 00:25:23,430
And what milk!

168
00:25:23,600 --> 00:25:26,270
It's nine times richer than our own

169
00:25:26,360 --> 00:25:29,790
and enables her to double their weight
every few weeks.

170
00:25:48,320 --> 00:25:52,430
It's over two months since
the autumn snows first arrived.

171
00:25:53,360 --> 00:25:58,230
In two more months, polar bear families
will emerge onto the snowy slopes

172
00:25:58,320 --> 00:25:59,990
all around the Arctic.

173
00:26:01,200 --> 00:26:05,750
But for now, they lie protected
within their icy cocoons.

174
00:26:29,160 --> 00:26:34,470
A hundred miles above the earth,
the Aurora lights up the sky.

175
00:26:44,800 --> 00:26:47,750
After travelling millions of miles
across space,

176
00:26:47,840 --> 00:26:51,710
solar winds, attracted by
the magnetic pull of the poles,

177
00:26:51,840 --> 00:26:54,150
collide with the Earth's atmosphere.

178
00:26:56,360 --> 00:27:00,990
Trillions of charged particles
dance across the sky.

179
00:27:09,200 --> 00:27:14,230
Above the Arctic, the Aurora Borealis,
the Northern Lights.

180
00:27:15,400 --> 00:27:19,990
In the south, it's the Aurora Australis,
the Southern Lights,

181
00:27:20,080 --> 00:27:23,150
that bring light to
Antarctica's long winter.

182
00:27:31,800 --> 00:27:35,830
These spectacular light shows
are only a tease.

183
00:27:35,920 --> 00:27:41,110
Solar energy maybe, but no warmth
that will help the emperor penguins.

184
00:27:54,120 --> 00:27:56,830
The Arctic winter is brutally cold,

185
00:27:56,960 --> 00:28:01,190
but in Antarctica,
the darkest months are even more savage.

186
00:28:17,560 --> 00:28:20,750
The male penguins have not eaten
for months

187
00:28:20,840 --> 00:28:24,270
and have only each other
for protection from the gales.

188
00:28:34,400 --> 00:28:37,270
Each has been entrusted
with a single precious egg,

189
00:28:37,360 --> 00:28:39,310
balanced on top of its feet.

190
00:28:39,880 --> 00:28:41,990
If the egg were to drop onto the ice,

191
00:28:42,080 --> 00:28:45,230
even for a moment,
the chick inside would die

192
00:28:45,320 --> 00:28:47,590
and all this would count for nothing.

193
00:28:56,080 --> 00:28:58,910
The emperors are not entirely alone.

194
00:29:03,840 --> 00:29:05,870
The Weddell seal,

195
00:29:05,960 --> 00:29:09,390
the only mammal to remain here
throughout the winter.

196
00:29:15,640 --> 00:29:17,750
They must have breathing holes,

197
00:29:17,840 --> 00:29:21,910
and so have to constantly scrape away
the ice that threatens to close them,

198
00:29:22,000 --> 00:29:26,590
rasping away fresh build-ups
with special, wide-gaped jaws.

199
00:29:31,800 --> 00:29:36,350
Beneath the ice, they are beyond
the reach of the bitter winter winds.

200
00:29:40,400 --> 00:29:43,550
The sea is -2 degrees centigrade,

201
00:29:43,640 --> 00:29:47,230
a warm bath compared to
the conditions overhead.

202
00:29:59,400 --> 00:30:04,510
The roof of ice insulates this world
from the wild fluctuations above.

203
00:30:06,400 --> 00:30:11,670
The temperature down here has
barely changed for 25 million years.

204
00:30:20,000 --> 00:30:23,630
Of course, animals must still be hardy.

205
00:30:23,720 --> 00:30:27,910
These Borchgrevinki fish
have anti-freeze in their blood,

206
00:30:28,000 --> 00:30:31,350
so they are untroubled swimming
among the ice crystals.

207
00:30:36,960 --> 00:30:40,070
Many animals here
are remarkably long-lived,

208
00:30:40,160 --> 00:30:42,910
perhaps because
the conditions are so stable.

209
00:30:43,800 --> 00:30:46,750
Some sponges could be
a thousand years old

210
00:30:46,840 --> 00:30:49,190
and large enough for a human to hide in.

211
00:30:51,480 --> 00:30:53,550
There could hardly be a greater contrast

212
00:30:53,640 --> 00:30:57,230
to the bleak, windswept
world just above.

213
00:31:30,480 --> 00:31:33,630
But there is a constant danger here.

214
00:31:39,480 --> 00:31:43,150
Swirling patterns in the water
reveal its presence.

215
00:31:44,760 --> 00:31:49,190
They are made by brine,
super-concentrated salt water.

216
00:31:50,480 --> 00:31:51,470
It's a warning.

217
00:31:56,400 --> 00:31:58,270
New sea-ice forming above

218
00:31:58,360 --> 00:32:02,950
leaves behind brine that is so
extremely salty it sinks rapidly.

219
00:32:08,920 --> 00:32:12,870
As it descends, the sea water around it
freezes instantly

220
00:32:12,960 --> 00:32:15,190
and forms a sheath of ice,

221
00:32:15,280 --> 00:32:19,190
a brinicle that grows downwards
towards the sea floor.

222
00:32:29,560 --> 00:32:33,150
Winter is reaching down
from the cold world above.

223
00:32:47,000 --> 00:32:51,550
As it touches the sea floor, it kills
whatever living thing it contacts

224
00:32:51,640 --> 00:32:54,710
by encasing it in a tomb of ice.

225
00:33:21,320 --> 00:33:23,950
Even in the relative warmth
of the water,

226
00:33:24,040 --> 00:33:28,310
the lethal cold of
winter threatens life on the sea floor.

227
00:33:38,680 --> 00:33:42,790
Another more constant
attack rises from below.

228
00:33:43,880 --> 00:33:46,150
Pressure in the depths
keeps water liquid

229
00:33:46,240 --> 00:33:48,990
even though its temperature
is far from freezing.

230
00:33:52,240 --> 00:33:56,230
Currents bring up this colder water
and it turns to ice,

231
00:33:56,320 --> 00:33:59,470
covering everything that
can't move away from it.

232
00:34:21,600 --> 00:34:26,510
And then the ice, being lighter
than water, begins to float,

233
00:34:27,200 --> 00:34:29,550
lifting away anything attached.

234
00:34:50,080 --> 00:34:53,310
Even some of the faster-moving animals
are caught.

235
00:35:09,160 --> 00:35:12,430
So the ice cleanses the sea floor

236
00:35:12,520 --> 00:35:16,990
and strews the ceiling above
with remnants of life from below.

237
00:35:28,160 --> 00:35:31,510
A sign that winter is nearly over.

238
00:35:34,080 --> 00:35:39,150
The songs of male Weddell seals,
challenging their rivals to battle.

239
00:35:45,880 --> 00:35:49,710
The male seal's calls
can heard over 15 miles away.

240
00:36:01,480 --> 00:36:04,550
He aims to control
the best breathing holes,

241
00:36:04,640 --> 00:36:07,750
for they will determine
his mating rights in spring.

242
00:36:15,480 --> 00:36:19,150
His calls create powerful shockwaves
in the water.

243
00:36:19,960 --> 00:36:21,270
They are threats.

244
00:36:32,440 --> 00:36:34,710
This hole has already been claimed

245
00:36:34,800 --> 00:36:37,430
and the owner will not
surrender it willingly.

246
00:36:47,760 --> 00:36:49,670
No change this time.

247
00:36:50,360 --> 00:36:53,990
The challenger will need to
find a hole with a weaker owner.

248
00:37:02,200 --> 00:37:05,870
The battles continue
until the females arrive,

249
00:37:05,960 --> 00:37:08,830
and that time is now close.

250
00:37:35,400 --> 00:37:38,230
The sun returns to Antarctica.

251
00:37:41,120 --> 00:37:46,150
The longest night on earth has ended
and winter begins to give way to spring.

252
00:38:16,840 --> 00:38:18,910
Female emperor penguins.

253
00:38:19,000 --> 00:38:23,750
After four months feeding at sea,
they are returning sleek and fat.

254
00:38:55,000 --> 00:38:58,510
Penguins, it seems, can fly after all.

255
00:39:01,000 --> 00:39:04,390
But a winter at sea
has left them a little out of practice.

256
00:39:57,200 --> 00:40:01,870
There is no time to waste.
Far away, the males are waiting.

257
00:40:12,680 --> 00:40:15,950
While the females were gone,
the sea-ice grew

258
00:40:16,080 --> 00:40:19,670
and it's now twice the distance
from its edge back to their colony.

259
00:40:27,400 --> 00:40:31,910
Seventy miles away, the males are
in desperate need of help.

260
00:40:34,800 --> 00:40:37,830
Despite doing all they can
to conserve their energy,

261
00:40:37,920 --> 00:40:41,110
many are close to dying from starvation.

262
00:41:32,440 --> 00:41:35,710
Reunited after three months apart.

263
00:41:46,720 --> 00:41:50,950
The reward for her return,
a first glimpse of her chick.

264
00:41:57,280 --> 00:42:00,710
The reunion made,
it's time for the hand-over.

265
00:42:05,800 --> 00:42:09,190
The father finds it hard to let go.

266
00:42:12,200 --> 00:42:14,830
Some gentle persuasion is needed.

267
00:42:17,280 --> 00:42:20,590
He has endured the most appalling
conditions on Earth

268
00:42:20,680 --> 00:42:24,830
to ensure the survival of his chick
and the bond is strong.

269
00:42:27,400 --> 00:42:28,990
The exchange must be quick,

270
00:42:29,080 --> 00:42:33,590
as the tiny chick, unprotected,
could freeze to death in seconds.

271
00:42:45,040 --> 00:42:48,950
A task that began in autumn
has been completed.

272
00:42:49,040 --> 00:42:51,230
Despite the huge odds against it,

273
00:42:51,320 --> 00:42:53,870
the precious chick has survived
the winter

274
00:42:53,960 --> 00:42:57,630
and is now with its mother,
and she has food.

275
00:43:08,000 --> 00:43:10,190
The chick's first fresh meal.

276
00:43:12,400 --> 00:43:14,150
Her mission is complete.

277
00:43:18,200 --> 00:43:22,790
But for other mothers,
the journey ends in disappointment.

278
00:43:25,640 --> 00:43:28,150
Their chicks have not survived.

279
00:43:32,520 --> 00:43:35,870
The female's need to nurture
remains strong.

280
00:43:35,960 --> 00:43:40,630
Any chick that strays from its parent
is at grave risk of being kidnapped.

281
00:44:17,960 --> 00:44:21,790
The chaos may be a consequence
of frustrated parental urge,

282
00:44:21,920 --> 00:44:24,030
but the outcome can be tragic.

283
00:44:41,600 --> 00:44:46,990
For those emperor penguins that survive,
the worst is over for this year.

284
00:44:52,400 --> 00:44:55,470
There will soon be abundant food
for everyone.

285
00:45:05,080 --> 00:45:08,710
The emperors have taken on
the polar winter and won.

286
00:45:09,640 --> 00:45:11,590
The gamble has paid off.

287
00:45:13,120 --> 00:45:15,070
All other animals escaped,

288
00:45:15,160 --> 00:45:17,710
only they remained to raise their young,

289
00:45:18,520 --> 00:45:23,630
and now it is they who will benefit most
from the rich southern spring.

290
00:45:32,520 --> 00:45:36,470
Another arrival is the certain
confirmation that spring is here.

291
00:45:37,360 --> 00:45:38,550
The Adélies,

292
00:45:38,640 --> 00:45:41,790
having spent winter at sea,
have come back,

293
00:45:41,880 --> 00:45:45,910
but they have not even
mated yet, let alone laid their eggs.

294
00:45:54,120 --> 00:45:56,630
Now at last, the male emperors

295
00:45:56,720 --> 00:45:59,110
can return to
where they are most at home.

296
00:46:15,360 --> 00:46:18,710
One season ends and another begins.

297
00:46:20,080 --> 00:46:23,270
The penguins will soon be joined
by migrants

298
00:46:23,360 --> 00:46:27,870
and the far south will bustle with life
for a few frantic months.

299
00:46:38,200 --> 00:46:42,590
But there are only a special few,
north and south,

300
00:46:42,680 --> 00:46:47,310
who can survive winter
at the farthest ends of our planet.

301
00:47:29,600 --> 00:47:31,870
More than any other season in the poles,

302
00:47:31,960 --> 00:47:35,710
winter was to pose the greatest
challenge to the Frozen Planet crew.

303
00:47:37,080 --> 00:47:39,910
The team endured winds of
over 100 miles an hour

304
00:47:40,000 --> 00:47:43,430
and temperatures as
low as -50 degrees centigrade.

305
00:47:44,560 --> 00:47:47,190
Their boats were trapped in
sea-ice for days,

306
00:47:47,280 --> 00:47:50,030
while bears trapped others indoors.

307
00:47:55,000 --> 00:47:57,110
Some of the coldest
conditions experienced

308
00:47:57,200 --> 00:47:59,910
were near the Arctic circle
in Northern Canada.

309
00:48:01,200 --> 00:48:05,070
In winter, temperatures dropped to
-40 degrees and stayed there.

310
00:48:07,320 --> 00:48:09,830
On the edge of the vast Taiga forest,

311
00:48:09,920 --> 00:48:12,230
the team hoped to film one
the most remarkable

312
00:48:12,320 --> 00:48:14,670
predator-prey relationships
on the planet.

313
00:48:16,480 --> 00:48:20,190
What they experienced was the
struggle against the elements,

314
00:48:20,320 --> 00:48:24,790
what they witnessed was a more profound
struggle for life and death.

315
00:48:35,640 --> 00:48:39,990
Wood Buffalo National Park
covers 28, 000 square miles,

316
00:48:40,080 --> 00:48:41,470
the size of Denmark.

317
00:48:42,400 --> 00:48:47,030
One of the few cameramen to have filmed
wolves and bison here is Jeff Turner.

318
00:48:47,640 --> 00:48:49,750
I first tried to film
bison and wolves

319
00:48:49,840 --> 00:48:54,790
in this national park 15 years ago
and getting around on the ground

320
00:48:54,880 --> 00:48:58,870
is incredibly difficult at any time of
the year, but in the winter it's tough.

321
00:48:58,960 --> 00:49:02,070
We quickly realised that the only way
we were going to get anything here

322
00:49:02,200 --> 00:49:04,190
was we had to get up in the air.

323
00:49:04,280 --> 00:49:05,630
The Frozen Planet team

324
00:49:05,720 --> 00:49:08,830
had never attempted aerial filming
in such low temperatures.

325
00:49:11,480 --> 00:49:13,910
The first challenge
for director Chadden Hunter

326
00:49:14,000 --> 00:49:16,350
was protecting the sensitive
aerial camera,

327
00:49:16,440 --> 00:49:20,950
at -40, electrical cables
short-circuit like fireworks.

328
00:49:22,440 --> 00:49:23,750
- Oh!
- Ooh.

329
00:49:24,360 --> 00:49:27,950
- How cold can you fly this chopper?
- Minus -40.

330
00:49:28,160 --> 00:49:32,030
Aerial cameraman Michael Kelem
comes from sunny California

331
00:49:32,120 --> 00:49:34,630
and has never experienced
temperatures so low.

332
00:49:34,720 --> 00:49:37,510
What kind of temperatures
can you operate down to?

333
00:49:37,600 --> 00:49:41,230
Me, usually about 70 degrees
Fahrenheit. LA kind of weather,

334
00:49:41,320 --> 00:49:43,470
- Yeah.
- I'm only rated for Santa Monica.

335
00:49:44,920 --> 00:49:47,950
Operating delicate
controls while wearing gloves

336
00:49:48,040 --> 00:49:51,390
is not easy.
A computer and joystick are needed

337
00:49:51,480 --> 00:49:55,070
to control the aerial camera attached
to the outside of the helicopter.

338
00:49:55,160 --> 00:49:56,950
It's actually warmed up to -30.

339
00:49:57,040 --> 00:50:01,190
Michael would have to
choose between dexterity or warmth.

340
00:50:03,680 --> 00:50:05,390
With their camera mounted on the nose,

341
00:50:05,480 --> 00:50:09,470
the aerial team could now fly hundreds
of miles in search of the animals.

342
00:50:11,200 --> 00:50:12,990
Jeff, meanwhile, is still on foot,

343
00:50:13,080 --> 00:50:15,550
scouting the other side
of the national park.

344
00:50:16,160 --> 00:50:17,950
I wonder what Jeff's getting
on the ground?

345
00:50:18,040 --> 00:50:19,870
Oh, man, it's cold.

346
00:50:20,320 --> 00:50:23,270
With the wind today it's about -37

347
00:50:23,360 --> 00:50:25,550
so you got to keep
these heaters in here,

348
00:50:25,640 --> 00:50:27,710
to keep the camera running
at these temperatures.

349
00:50:28,760 --> 00:50:30,310
From 3,000 feet up,

350
00:50:30,400 --> 00:50:33,390
Chadden catches a glimpse
of the elusive wolf pack.

351
00:50:34,520 --> 00:50:37,350
I can see wolves,
I can see wolves near buffalo.

352
00:50:37,440 --> 00:50:39,910
- 10, 15, there's a big pack.
- Wow.

353
00:50:40,040 --> 00:50:42,270
We've got a big pack of wolves here.

354
00:50:42,400 --> 00:50:47,110
The wolfpack turns out to number
an extraordinary 25 individuals,

355
00:50:47,200 --> 00:50:48,910
one of the largest ever filmed.

356
00:50:49,000 --> 00:50:51,150
There's two more walking in
from the left.

357
00:50:51,240 --> 00:50:54,070
And it looks like
they're already on the hunt.

358
00:50:54,160 --> 00:50:58,230
The helicopter allows the team to shadow
the wolf pack without disturbing them.

359
00:50:58,320 --> 00:51:02,630
So, let's go back into
nice, slow circle around them.

360
00:51:03,840 --> 00:51:05,630
They look pretty determined.

361
00:51:05,720 --> 00:51:07,670
The pack are moving in
on their prey

362
00:51:07,760 --> 00:51:10,310
and the aerial team
are perfectly placed.

363
00:51:13,880 --> 00:51:15,510
They're making their...
definitely making their move.

364
00:51:15,600 --> 00:51:18,590
Wow,
there's buffalo on the move.

365
00:51:19,600 --> 00:51:22,670
The chase is on.
Extreme concentration is now needed

366
00:51:22,760 --> 00:51:25,870
both from pilot and the cameraman
to keep the shots smooth.

367
00:51:28,640 --> 00:51:30,190
Yeah, there's more coming in now.

368
00:51:30,280 --> 00:51:32,470
There's a nice, tight little pack
challenging them.

369
00:51:32,560 --> 00:51:34,230
We've got a nice shot of the pack,

370
00:51:34,320 --> 00:51:36,950
the wolves coming up at the back.
You got them still?

371
00:51:37,040 --> 00:51:38,910
Yeah, I got them here, I'm just
going to pick it up a little bit.

372
00:51:39,040 --> 00:51:42,230
Okay, okay, tighten up, just a hair.

373
00:51:42,320 --> 00:51:44,950
Just want to get a shot
of the wolves at the back of the pack.

374
00:51:45,080 --> 00:51:47,870
The wolfpack
have picked out a young bison.

375
00:51:49,560 --> 00:51:50,870
Holy.

376
00:51:51,240 --> 00:51:53,590
As Michael struggles
to hold the shot steady,

377
00:51:53,680 --> 00:51:55,870
no one is prepared for what came next.

378
00:51:56,320 --> 00:52:00,230
Oh, hey, look,
they just knocked him down, pretty much.

379
00:52:01,560 --> 00:52:03,230
A one-tonne bull charges through,

380
00:52:03,320 --> 00:52:06,470
taking out both the wolves
and the young bison.

381
00:52:08,440 --> 00:52:12,510
I've never seen anything like that
in the wild, that is unbelievable.

382
00:52:13,600 --> 00:52:16,550
The team have filmed extraordinary
new behaviour from the air

383
00:52:16,640 --> 00:52:18,870
but Jeff was nowhere nearby.

384
00:52:20,080 --> 00:52:22,830
To complete the sequence,
they will need to work together,

385
00:52:22,920 --> 00:52:25,590
only by using the helicopter
to position Jeff

386
00:52:25,680 --> 00:52:29,230
will they able to get both air
and ground coverage.

387
00:52:38,480 --> 00:52:42,790
This pack will now feast for days,
so the crew must move on.

388
00:52:44,800 --> 00:52:47,110
Jeff takes the team deeper
into the wilderness

389
00:52:47,200 --> 00:52:49,750
in search of a new wolf pack.

390
00:52:49,840 --> 00:52:53,430
With everyone on board,
there are more eyes for spotting.

391
00:52:54,560 --> 00:52:57,950
Bison on the run can only mean
one thing, wolves.

392
00:52:58,360 --> 00:53:01,630
But this time, only a pair.

393
00:53:02,720 --> 00:53:05,470
Jeff must anticipate the animals'
every move

394
00:53:05,560 --> 00:53:09,110
and direct the helicopter to
where he needs to be dropped off.

395
00:53:09,200 --> 00:53:10,670
They're going this way.

396
00:53:12,600 --> 00:53:14,150
I had to figure out exactly

397
00:53:14,240 --> 00:53:16,910
where the buffalo were going to run,
try to get there ahead of them.

398
00:53:18,000 --> 00:53:21,110
If I got dropped off
in the wrong position, we would blow it.

399
00:53:22,440 --> 00:53:24,390
There wasn't going to be
a second chance.

400
00:53:33,920 --> 00:53:36,270
That moment when you get
out of the helicopter

401
00:53:36,360 --> 00:53:40,670
and it leaves you behind, you feel
an incredible sense of isolation.

402
00:53:43,400 --> 00:53:44,870
On the lake, I'll guide you in,

403
00:53:44,960 --> 00:53:48,430
down to the right, down, zoom in.

404
00:53:49,480 --> 00:53:52,630
- Are you on the back guy?
- We're on the back guy. On the back.

405
00:53:53,320 --> 00:53:55,710
- Which one is he going for?
- I don't know.

406
00:53:56,080 --> 00:53:57,910
- But there's one broken off.
- Oh!

407
00:53:58,520 --> 00:54:01,510
- Oh, my God.
- They're coming in now.

408
00:54:02,760 --> 00:54:04,310
When I saw the herd
coming around the corner,

409
00:54:04,400 --> 00:54:07,750
I knew we'd picked the right spot,
I was right in front of them.

410
00:54:09,120 --> 00:54:10,870
And the buffalo
running right towards you,

411
00:54:10,960 --> 00:54:12,910
it definitely does get your
heart pounding.

412
00:54:15,320 --> 00:54:16,870
The bison have poor eyesight

413
00:54:16,960 --> 00:54:20,350
and can't see Jeff.
It's now test of nerves.

414
00:54:21,320 --> 00:54:24,030
Weighing one tonne
and running at 40 miles an hour,

415
00:54:24,120 --> 00:54:26,870
one wrong step
and the bison could kill Jeff.

416
00:54:27,240 --> 00:54:28,510
At the last second,

417
00:54:28,600 --> 00:54:31,270
they spot him and three peel
away to the other side.

418
00:54:34,680 --> 00:54:37,710
At the back of the herd,
the wolves have closed in.

419
00:54:39,400 --> 00:54:42,550
They're still at him. They're trying to
separate that little one.

420
00:54:45,920 --> 00:54:48,990
- Oh, they got him!
- Both wolves are on him.

421
00:54:49,080 --> 00:54:51,030
- Both clamping down on him.
- Yeah, he got stomped.

422
00:54:51,120 --> 00:54:52,270
He got stomped on there.

423
00:54:52,400 --> 00:54:55,990
What followed was one of
the most emotional and powerful scenes

424
00:54:56,080 --> 00:54:58,510
the Frozen Planet team
were ever to film.

425
00:55:00,320 --> 00:55:03,150
Jeff has picked his position perfectly,

426
00:55:03,240 --> 00:55:05,710
he is now only 50 meters
from the animals

427
00:55:05,800 --> 00:55:08,430
and able film a truly epic battle.

428
00:55:10,080 --> 00:55:12,950
I had never been so close
to a wolf and bison battle,

429
00:55:13,840 --> 00:55:15,990
I could hear them breathing.

430
00:55:16,960 --> 00:55:18,910
And the power of the buffalo,

431
00:55:19,000 --> 00:55:22,350
the way he just threw this wolf around
like it was a rag doll.

432
00:55:23,360 --> 00:55:25,830
I couldn't believe the beating
this wolf was taking.

433
00:55:29,920 --> 00:55:33,670
The struggles that we'd had with
the winter and the cold and the snow

434
00:55:33,760 --> 00:55:37,790
just felt so insignificant
compared to these two animals

435
00:55:37,880 --> 00:55:40,110
that were struggling
for their very lives.

436
00:55:43,280 --> 00:55:46,270
For over an hour,
I watched this wolf and bison

437
00:55:46,360 --> 00:55:48,550
battle each other to a standstill.

438
00:55:50,120 --> 00:55:52,470
They were both unbelievably exhausted.

439
00:56:00,400 --> 00:56:04,270
Watching these two animals engaged
in this massive life and death struggle

440
00:56:04,360 --> 00:56:08,030
was one of the most powerful things
I'd ever witnessed in the wild.

441
00:56:10,560 --> 00:56:14,310
As a filmmaker, you're definitely torn
watching something like this.

442
00:56:14,400 --> 00:56:18,070
You know you need to keep filming
and you know this a natural event,

443
00:56:18,600 --> 00:56:20,790
but it's also incredibly sad
to know that

444
00:56:20,880 --> 00:56:24,190
one of these two magnificent
animals isn't going to make it.

445
00:56:28,560 --> 00:56:33,030
The bison is fatally wounded,
the battle is over.

446
00:56:36,000 --> 00:56:39,190
The team have managed
to capture a remarkable hunt

447
00:56:39,280 --> 00:56:41,870
from both ground and air.

448
00:56:42,520 --> 00:56:44,110
All of them have been humbled

449
00:56:44,200 --> 00:56:48,030
by witnessing an extraordinary
winter struggle for survival.

