1
00:00:33,200 --> 00:00:34,590
The sun is absent

2
00:00:34,680 --> 00:00:37,670
for up to half the year
in the polar regions.

3
00:00:38,640 --> 00:00:41,190
When it returns
at the beginning of spring,

4
00:00:41,280 --> 00:00:45,030
its warmth will transform
this magical ice world.

5
00:01:05,160 --> 00:01:10,190
The greatest seasonal change
on our planet is now underway.

6
00:01:17,160 --> 00:01:23,070
Antarctica is still locked in ice
and surrounded by a frozen ocean.

7
00:01:23,760 --> 00:01:26,310
Nonetheless, there are signs of spring.

8
00:01:34,160 --> 00:01:37,950
Adélie penguins are arriving.
Just the males.

9
00:01:38,400 --> 00:01:42,510
They've spent five months at sea,
where it's warmer than it is on land,

10
00:01:42,600 --> 00:01:46,190
and now they're in a hurry,
for spring will be short.

11
00:01:53,520 --> 00:01:56,590
They have travelled 6,000 miles
across the ocean

12
00:01:56,680 --> 00:02:01,470
since leaving their colony last year
and now they're returning to breed.

13
00:02:02,040 --> 00:02:05,150
They cannot lay their eggs on ice,
for they would freeze,

14
00:02:05,240 --> 00:02:09,110
so they have to come here,
where there is bare rock.

15
00:02:13,280 --> 00:02:17,470
Over the coming months, the few parts
of Antarctica that are ice free

16
00:02:17,560 --> 00:02:22,590
will be the stage on which five million
Adélies will build their nests.

17
00:02:28,840 --> 00:02:31,550
To construct one, they need pebbles,

18
00:02:31,640 --> 00:02:33,750
and without a good-looking nest,

19
00:02:33,840 --> 00:02:36,830
a male will be unable
to attract a female

20
00:02:36,920 --> 00:02:39,110
when they at last arrive.

21
00:02:39,880 --> 00:02:43,830
An impressive property
demonstrates your worth as a mate.

22
00:02:47,160 --> 00:02:51,270
It takes stones of all shapes and sizes
to build a decent nest.

23
00:02:51,360 --> 00:02:54,550
And finding ones that
are just right is not easy.

24
00:02:59,760 --> 00:03:03,870
So some penguins turn
to a life of crime.

25
00:03:41,680 --> 00:03:45,310
The one who has been robbed
seems unaware that the thief

26
00:03:45,400 --> 00:03:49,110
is just over his shoulder
and looking for more.

27
00:03:59,560 --> 00:04:01,870
The thief's nest is coming along nicely,

28
00:04:01,960 --> 00:04:06,110
probably because he keeps a particularly
sharp lookout for robbers.

29
00:04:07,160 --> 00:04:10,230
After all, it takes one to know one.

30
00:04:18,840 --> 00:04:21,790
It's still cold,
but the early season sun

31
00:04:21,880 --> 00:04:24,790
does lift the temperature
by a few degrees.

32
00:04:24,880 --> 00:04:29,910
That, however, can have unexpected,
even dangerous, consequences.

33
00:04:36,720 --> 00:04:39,550
The sea is heating faster than the land,

34
00:04:39,880 --> 00:04:44,030
pulling cold air from the middle
of the continent towards the coast.

35
00:04:47,840 --> 00:04:51,670
These katabatic winds are
stronger than any hurricane.

36
00:04:53,080 --> 00:04:56,430
They are the coldest
and the most ferocious on the planet.

37
00:05:05,920 --> 00:05:09,230
The storms catch many
new arrivals by surprise

38
00:05:09,320 --> 00:05:14,190
and are the reason that spring here is,
in fact, the deadliest season.

39
00:05:39,120 --> 00:05:42,590
Here, early birds take a great risk.

40
00:05:45,920 --> 00:05:49,990
Some years entire colonies are lost,
buried beneath the snow.

41
00:05:51,480 --> 00:05:54,470
The survivors of this storm
must hope that the females

42
00:05:54,560 --> 00:05:58,670
prove to be worth the wait
when they finally decide to turn up.

43
00:06:06,920 --> 00:06:09,710
Spring in the north of our planet.

44
00:06:10,640 --> 00:06:16,470
The sun, after an absence of six months
breaks the horizon for the first time.

45
00:06:25,760 --> 00:06:29,390
A female polar bear emerges
from her den beneath the snow.

46
00:06:30,160 --> 00:06:34,350
The sun must be a welcome relief
after so long in the darkness.

47
00:06:40,480 --> 00:06:42,710
Her den is on a high slope,

48
00:06:42,800 --> 00:06:46,550
well away from hungry male bears
who would kill her cubs,

49
00:06:46,640 --> 00:06:50,070
but close enough to the sea-ice
where she can find food

50
00:06:50,160 --> 00:06:52,710
for her extraordinary new family.

51
00:06:58,600 --> 00:07:00,390
Three young cubs.

52
00:07:08,120 --> 00:07:10,350
If she can raise them all
to independence,

53
00:07:10,440 --> 00:07:12,590
it'll be a rare achievement.

54
00:07:33,800 --> 00:07:36,070
One of the cubs is underweight

55
00:07:36,520 --> 00:07:39,790
and will be fortunate to
survive these early weeks.

56
00:07:55,480 --> 00:08:00,110
If the family reaches the sea-ice,
where the female can catch seals,

57
00:08:00,200 --> 00:08:02,110
her milk will be enriched

58
00:08:02,200 --> 00:08:05,710
and the smaller cub
will quickly gain size and strength.

59
00:08:08,560 --> 00:08:12,310
The sea-ice, though,
is a dangerous place.

60
00:08:24,320 --> 00:08:28,590
The male polar bear has been out
on the frozen ocean all winter.

61
00:08:29,240 --> 00:08:33,670
Times have been lean and a bear cub
would certainly make a welcome snack.

62
00:08:34,520 --> 00:08:37,350
However, the mainstay
of his diet is seals

63
00:08:38,000 --> 00:08:40,990
and now is the time
when they have their pups.

64
00:08:43,800 --> 00:08:46,190
The surface of the frozen sea is marked

65
00:08:46,280 --> 00:08:50,550
with pressure ridges and cracks
created by the fluctuating tides.

66
00:08:52,840 --> 00:08:55,910
Both are good places to look for seals.

67
00:09:04,160 --> 00:09:07,350
He has detected a seal den
beneath the ice.

68
00:09:08,760 --> 00:09:13,150
Now he must pinpoint it using
only his extraordinary sense of smell.

69
00:09:18,000 --> 00:09:21,190
By treading lightly,
he can avoid scaring his prey.

70
00:09:26,560 --> 00:09:30,390
He will need to punch through
a metre of snow to reach the den

71
00:09:30,560 --> 00:09:35,030
and if his aim is not exactly on target,
the seal will certainly escape.

72
00:10:11,320 --> 00:10:15,470
In fact, the ringed seal abandoned
her den just a few hours ago

73
00:10:17,240 --> 00:10:19,790
and her pup has climbed up
onto the surface.

74
00:10:19,880 --> 00:10:21,670
It's more exposed up here,

75
00:10:21,760 --> 00:10:24,670
but it's easier
to see an approaching bear.

76
00:10:38,480 --> 00:10:40,550
The pup is well camouflaged,

77
00:10:40,640 --> 00:10:43,950
difficult to see when its mother
has left it to go fishing.

78
00:10:51,120 --> 00:10:53,150
But he can still smell it.

79
00:11:22,320 --> 00:11:26,110
Nine out of ten polar bear hunts
end in failure.

80
00:11:32,560 --> 00:11:35,670
The sun's warming effect on the Arctic
is increasing

81
00:11:35,760 --> 00:11:39,270
and the sea ice is showing
the first signs of weakening.

82
00:11:43,720 --> 00:11:47,430
Inland, the northern rivers
are still locked in ice.

83
00:11:50,280 --> 00:11:52,670
The frozen waterfalls are like dams,

84
00:11:52,760 --> 00:11:55,430
holding back billions of tonnes
of fresh water

85
00:11:55,520 --> 00:11:58,430
that has not moved
for almost six months.

86
00:12:02,160 --> 00:12:04,830
The vast water shed lies motionless,

87
00:12:04,960 --> 00:12:09,030
but as spring advances,
it begins to stir.

88
00:12:14,640 --> 00:12:17,470
The frozen waterfalls start to weaken.

89
00:12:17,960 --> 00:12:20,550
Above them, the pressure is mounting.

90
00:12:26,080 --> 00:12:27,430
Now, from high above,

91
00:12:27,520 --> 00:12:30,510
whole sections can be seen
to be on the move.

92
00:12:39,480 --> 00:12:42,550
The waterfalls are straining
to hold back the force

93
00:12:42,760 --> 00:12:45,070
that is building up above them.

94
00:12:52,880 --> 00:12:57,390
The dam bursts
and the river is unleashed.

95
00:13:25,840 --> 00:13:29,630
Millions of tonnes of ice
grind their way downstream,

96
00:13:29,720 --> 00:13:33,070
driven by the unstoppable force
of the meltwater.

97
00:13:41,360 --> 00:13:45,190
Boulders and trees are plucked
from the bankside.

98
00:13:48,120 --> 00:13:52,790
Within just a few days,
the rivers of the north are all running.

99
00:13:53,000 --> 00:13:56,630
The Arctic's fresh water
is flowing again.

100
00:14:07,600 --> 00:14:11,870
These vast floods contain 10%
of the world's fresh water

101
00:14:12,320 --> 00:14:15,950
and as they enter the ocean,
they accelerate the break-up.

102
00:14:16,160 --> 00:14:19,390
Soon, an area of sea-ice
the size of Australia

103
00:14:19,480 --> 00:14:21,870
will vanish from the Arctic Ocean.

104
00:14:29,120 --> 00:14:34,230
As the huge ice-sheet breaks up,
wildlife returns to the north.

105
00:14:45,720 --> 00:14:49,510
The polar bear mother has made
it to the edge of the sea-ice,

106
00:14:49,920 --> 00:14:52,870
but the smallest cub
is nowhere to be seen.

107
00:14:55,240 --> 00:14:57,150
It's a sad outcome,

108
00:14:57,240 --> 00:15:00,990
but the disappearance improves
the chances of the remaining two,

109
00:15:01,080 --> 00:15:03,430
who now have more milk to share.

110
00:15:07,040 --> 00:15:09,550
Having led her cubs
to the edge of the ice,

111
00:15:09,960 --> 00:15:12,990
the mother's next challenge
is to catch a seal.

112
00:15:18,520 --> 00:15:21,070
Not easy with these two in tow.

113
00:15:35,560 --> 00:15:40,070
Her prey, beneath the ice,
can detect the slightest vibration,

114
00:15:40,160 --> 00:15:42,030
especially from bears.

115
00:15:42,120 --> 00:15:45,390
And this is not the stealthiest
of hunting parties.

116
00:15:54,040 --> 00:15:57,630
Leaving her cubs behind, however,
is not an option.

117
00:15:57,800 --> 00:16:00,430
A male bear would eat one in a moment.

118
00:16:07,360 --> 00:16:09,550
This is not going to be easy.

119
00:16:20,920 --> 00:16:25,590
It seems that the cubs already
see themselves as fearsome hunters,

120
00:16:27,360 --> 00:16:31,510
but they are still young enough
to accept their mother's discipline.

121
00:16:32,480 --> 00:16:34,790
It's the naughty corner for you.

122
00:16:55,480 --> 00:16:58,230
This is not going to
be their lucky morning.

123
00:16:58,320 --> 00:17:01,950
They saw no sign of a seal
and the cubs are hungry again.

124
00:17:02,760 --> 00:17:07,150
The mother has been nursing for four
months without once eating herself,

125
00:17:07,480 --> 00:17:09,710
and now her milk is drying up.

126
00:17:11,040 --> 00:17:14,750
She must catch a seal soon
or the whole family will starve.

127
00:17:20,520 --> 00:17:23,310
The challenge of finding food
is getting harder.

128
00:17:23,400 --> 00:17:26,430
She needs the sea-ice as a platform
from which to hunt

129
00:17:26,520 --> 00:17:29,750
and it's breaking up faster
with each passing day.

130
00:17:33,240 --> 00:17:36,510
Even the ice around the coast
is starting to break.

131
00:17:38,240 --> 00:17:41,710
The first cracks here
are eagerly awaited by some.

132
00:17:53,480 --> 00:17:54,750
Narwhals.

133
00:17:59,080 --> 00:18:01,830
The unicorns of the north are
on a mission,

134
00:18:01,920 --> 00:18:04,270
to reach the new fishing grounds
in the bays

135
00:18:04,360 --> 00:18:08,110
that have been frozen up all winter,
but are now opening up.

136
00:18:16,760 --> 00:18:20,030
To get to them,
the narwhals must travel down leads,

137
00:18:20,120 --> 00:18:22,270
temporary cracks in the ice.

138
00:18:23,320 --> 00:18:26,190
But these new roads could close
at any time,

139
00:18:26,400 --> 00:18:29,390
cutting off the air
that they need to breathe.

140
00:18:32,880 --> 00:18:36,790
The road narrows until there's
barely room for one-way traffic.

141
00:18:38,240 --> 00:18:40,310
Then a surprise.

142
00:18:40,520 --> 00:18:43,270
Narwhals coming from
the other direction.

143
00:18:48,840 --> 00:18:50,670
It's a stand-off!

144
00:18:50,760 --> 00:18:54,550
Each team faces an armoury
of sharp tusks.

145
00:19:12,440 --> 00:19:14,950
Finally, one side concedes

146
00:19:16,400 --> 00:19:19,350
and everyone continues
in the same direction.

147
00:19:26,400 --> 00:19:30,430
Within a week,
the remaining bays break wide open

148
00:19:31,680 --> 00:19:35,550
and the narwhals turn their attention
to social matters.

149
00:19:42,520 --> 00:19:46,190
No one knows exactly
what the narwhal's tusk is for.

150
00:19:46,280 --> 00:19:48,310
Some say it's used for fencing,

151
00:19:48,400 --> 00:19:52,910
yet these exchanges
are too gentle to be real fights.

152
00:20:08,400 --> 00:20:11,630
Perhaps these encounters are
to remind each animal

153
00:20:11,720 --> 00:20:14,350
of where it stands in narwhal society.

154
00:20:16,720 --> 00:20:18,430
We may never know.

155
00:20:33,520 --> 00:20:37,230
Bizarre creatures appear
as if from nowhere.

156
00:20:39,000 --> 00:20:41,630
The tiny plankton they eat
have been fuelled

157
00:20:41,720 --> 00:20:46,310
by the increasing warmth of the sun
and fertilised by the nutrients

158
00:20:46,400 --> 00:20:50,350
brought down by the great rivers
and released from the melting sea-ice.

159
00:20:52,520 --> 00:20:56,550
Sea gooseberries strain the water
with their stinging filaments,

160
00:20:56,640 --> 00:20:59,590
their beating cilia
scatter the sun's rays

161
00:20:59,680 --> 00:21:01,990
into dazzling bursts of colour.

162
00:21:09,440 --> 00:21:11,310
Beneath the breaking sea-ice,

163
00:21:11,400 --> 00:21:16,470
a predatory sea slug flies through
the water on translucent wings.

164
00:21:16,760 --> 00:21:20,550
It's on the trail of a peculiar
swimming snail.

165
00:21:33,280 --> 00:21:36,510
And now the most voracious of
the plankton eaters

166
00:21:36,640 --> 00:21:40,030
swim up from the depths. Arctic cod.

167
00:21:47,960 --> 00:21:49,870
The shoals can be enormous,

168
00:21:49,960 --> 00:21:52,750
some containing 500 million fish

169
00:21:52,840 --> 00:21:56,390
and predators travel hundreds of miles
to feast on them.

170
00:21:59,360 --> 00:22:02,230
The cod harvest is the annual event

171
00:22:02,320 --> 00:22:04,670
for the birds and seals
of the far north.

172
00:22:09,440 --> 00:22:11,390
For just a short period,

173
00:22:11,480 --> 00:22:14,150
the combination
of the strengthening sun,

174
00:22:14,240 --> 00:22:17,390
the newly flowing rivers
and the breaking sea ice

175
00:22:17,480 --> 00:22:20,950
make the Arctic Ocean teem with life.

176
00:22:27,760 --> 00:22:31,030
The land is also transformed
by the sun's heat.

177
00:22:33,960 --> 00:22:38,110
The small patches of bare ground
that appear are darker than the snow,

178
00:22:38,200 --> 00:22:40,710
so they absorb more of the sun's energy.

179
00:22:43,000 --> 00:22:45,030
This accelerates the melt.

180
00:22:53,520 --> 00:22:56,710
The Arctic tundra is unveiled.

181
00:23:04,960 --> 00:23:09,510
By tracking the sun, Arctic poppies
catch its rays around the clock,

182
00:23:09,600 --> 00:23:13,270
so their flowers are always warmer
than their surroundings.

183
00:23:19,360 --> 00:23:23,190
For early season insects,
this warmth is even more valuable

184
00:23:23,280 --> 00:23:26,470
than nectar
if they're to stay active in the cold.

185
00:23:37,280 --> 00:23:38,870
The woolly bear caterpillar

186
00:23:38,960 --> 00:23:42,790
does not need the warmth from flowers
to kick-start its spring.

187
00:23:42,880 --> 00:23:47,190
It's always the first insect
to appear after the snow retreats

188
00:23:47,280 --> 00:23:51,070
and the story of how it does so
is truly astonishing.

189
00:23:55,000 --> 00:23:58,830
At the start of spring,
the caterpillar eats as fast as it can,

190
00:23:58,920 --> 00:24:00,510
as indeed it must,

191
00:24:00,600 --> 00:24:03,550
for this far north,
the season will be brief.

192
00:24:05,120 --> 00:24:07,430
The days shorten only too soon,

193
00:24:07,520 --> 00:24:10,350
but the caterpillar
has not yet got enough reserves

194
00:24:10,440 --> 00:24:12,790
to transform itself into a moth.

195
00:24:13,520 --> 00:24:16,350
It can't leave the Arctic,
for it can't fly.

196
00:24:17,000 --> 00:24:19,430
So it settles down beneath a rock.

197
00:24:21,360 --> 00:24:24,150
The sun's warmth rapidly dwindles.

198
00:24:30,040 --> 00:24:32,950
Beneath the rock, the caterpillar
is out of the wind,

199
00:24:33,040 --> 00:24:36,070
but the cold penetrates deep
into the ground.

200
00:24:37,840 --> 00:24:40,510
Soon its heart stops beating.

201
00:24:40,960 --> 00:24:44,870
It ceases to breathe
and its body starts to freeze.

202
00:24:45,920 --> 00:24:48,830
First its gut, then its blood.

203
00:25:11,640 --> 00:25:12,990
Spring.

204
00:25:14,640 --> 00:25:19,190
After four months of darkness,
the Arctic begins to thaw.

205
00:25:22,720 --> 00:25:26,150
And the caterpillar rises from the dead.

206
00:25:35,680 --> 00:25:39,230
By the time the first shoots
of willow appear in the early spring,

207
00:25:39,320 --> 00:25:41,870
the woolly bear is already eating.

208
00:25:43,080 --> 00:25:46,070
But no matter how fast
the woolly bear eats,

209
00:25:46,160 --> 00:25:49,670
it will not have time
to gather enough food this year, either.

210
00:25:50,280 --> 00:25:52,950
And the cold closes in once again.

211
00:26:15,240 --> 00:26:18,910
Year after year, the caterpillar
slows down in the autumn

212
00:26:19,280 --> 00:26:21,190
and then freezes solid.

213
00:26:29,440 --> 00:26:33,390
But eventually, a very special
spring arrives.

214
00:26:36,680 --> 00:26:38,870
This one will be its last.

215
00:26:44,960 --> 00:26:47,270
It's now 14 years old,

216
00:26:47,520 --> 00:26:50,430
the world's oldest caterpillar.

217
00:26:50,520 --> 00:26:53,430
Its remaining days now become frantic.

218
00:26:53,520 --> 00:26:56,310
It starts to weave a silk cocoon.

219
00:26:59,320 --> 00:27:05,230
Inside, its body is changing
into one that can fly and search,

220
00:27:05,320 --> 00:27:08,510
abilities that will be crucial
in the days ahead.

221
00:27:11,440 --> 00:27:16,390
It's waited over a decade for
this spring and now its time is near.

222
00:27:20,800 --> 00:27:24,070
All across the Arctic,
moths are emerging.

223
00:27:24,440 --> 00:27:27,190
After completing
their 14-year preparation,

224
00:27:27,280 --> 00:27:31,150
they now have just a few days
to find a partner and mate.

225
00:27:37,480 --> 00:27:42,470
No life illustrates more vividly
the shortness of the Arctic spring

226
00:27:42,560 --> 00:27:46,990
or the struggle to survive
in this most seasonal of places.

227
00:27:56,040 --> 00:28:00,750
As spring advances, the transformation
of the tundra continues.

228
00:28:51,440 --> 00:28:54,350
Migrants begin arriving from the south

229
00:28:55,240 --> 00:28:59,430
and suddenly the tundra is alive
with birds and chicks.

230
00:29:14,120 --> 00:29:17,310
The Arctic's transformation is complete.

231
00:29:24,400 --> 00:29:29,470
This influx of life is good news
for some permanent residents.

232
00:29:35,760 --> 00:29:38,430
Food is rarely plentiful
out on the tundra.

233
00:29:39,280 --> 00:29:43,630
The Arctic wolves must make the most
of this boom while it lasts.

234
00:30:39,880 --> 00:30:43,030
The wolves must gather
as much food as they can.

235
00:30:43,560 --> 00:30:47,190
Many miles from here, other members
of the pack are relying on them.

236
00:31:01,160 --> 00:31:04,710
This barren landscape is
a hard place to make a living,

237
00:31:04,800 --> 00:31:08,310
forcing wolf packs to be
smaller here than further south.

238
00:31:15,720 --> 00:31:18,190
Six hungry mouths to feed.

239
00:31:18,520 --> 00:31:21,470
The cubs are just over a month old.

240
00:31:32,960 --> 00:31:36,790
The ducks are devoured instantly,
but on the long journey home

241
00:31:36,880 --> 00:31:38,590
they also caught an Arctic hare,

242
00:31:38,680 --> 00:31:40,910
a mainstay of the tundra diet,

243
00:31:41,000 --> 00:31:44,190
and one the cubs seem
to be particularly keen on.

244
00:31:53,440 --> 00:31:57,190
Uneaten food is usually hidden
for leaner times,

245
00:31:57,280 --> 00:31:59,630
but there will be no leftovers today.

246
00:31:59,720 --> 00:32:02,830
The cubs are growing fast
and are always hungry.

247
00:32:19,840 --> 00:32:21,990
The good times are certainly back,

248
00:32:22,080 --> 00:32:27,110
but these white wolves remind us
of the Arctic's less welcoming side.

249
00:32:28,560 --> 00:32:32,630
Their coats are pale, to conceal them
during the long, snowy winter.

250
00:32:36,160 --> 00:32:41,110
It's easy to forget that one month ago,
this land was a barren white desert.

251
00:32:50,800 --> 00:32:52,910
At the southern end of our planet,

252
00:32:53,000 --> 00:32:56,630
the Antarctic sea-ice
is still at its greatest extent.

253
00:32:59,200 --> 00:33:02,070
But there are a few islands
on its outer edge

254
00:33:02,160 --> 00:33:04,470
that the sea-ice never quite reaches.

255
00:33:07,840 --> 00:33:12,590
South Georgia is washed by
the rich waters of the Southern Atlantic

256
00:33:12,680 --> 00:33:14,750
and the comparative warmth of the sea

257
00:33:14,840 --> 00:33:17,870
takes the edge off
the vicious southern winter.

258
00:33:26,400 --> 00:33:28,990
It's even possible
for a few hardy animals,

259
00:33:29,080 --> 00:33:33,830
like the Wandering Albatross,
to live here throughout the whole year.

260
00:33:43,160 --> 00:33:45,710
The enormous albatross chicks

261
00:33:45,800 --> 00:33:47,830
take 13 months to fledge,

262
00:33:47,920 --> 00:33:51,550
so they have no choice but to sit here
throughout the winter.

263
00:33:51,640 --> 00:33:54,910
It can't be easy,
but their thick layer of fluffy down

264
00:33:55,000 --> 00:33:57,310
keeps out the worst of the cold.

265
00:33:58,400 --> 00:34:02,430
Their parents travel thousands of miles
to collect the fish and squid

266
00:34:02,520 --> 00:34:05,150
they need to stay warm and to grow.

267
00:34:15,280 --> 00:34:20,190
The season is turning and
storms blow in with little warning.

268
00:34:28,440 --> 00:34:31,430
King penguins have
also been here all winter.

269
00:34:36,240 --> 00:34:40,830
Their chicks survive by huddling
in crèches to conserve their heat.

270
00:34:40,920 --> 00:34:45,030
A solitary bird here standing alone
would quickly die of exposure.

271
00:34:46,600 --> 00:34:51,390
It seems for a hardy few,
violent storms are a price worth paying

272
00:34:51,760 --> 00:34:55,710
for year-round fishing in
the rich waters of the Southern Ocean.

273
00:35:03,360 --> 00:35:06,310
The penguins have had the beach
to themselves all winter,

274
00:35:07,160 --> 00:35:10,110
but that is a luxury that will not last.

275
00:35:17,040 --> 00:35:21,590
As the winter storms subside,
life begins to return.

276
00:35:32,000 --> 00:35:35,990
For half of the year, South Georgia
has the greatest concentration

277
00:35:36,080 --> 00:35:37,990
of sea birds in the world

278
00:35:38,080 --> 00:35:41,150
and most of them arrive
in the early spring.

279
00:35:49,240 --> 00:35:52,670
Macaroni penguins make
the most impressive entrance,

280
00:35:52,760 --> 00:35:55,070
over five million pairs of them.

281
00:35:55,440 --> 00:35:57,990
They are the world's
most numerous penguin

282
00:35:58,080 --> 00:36:00,350
and half of them are now here.

283
00:36:02,400 --> 00:36:04,350
The arrival is complete.

284
00:36:08,760 --> 00:36:13,110
Courtship is next on South Georgia's
busy spring schedule.

285
00:36:19,400 --> 00:36:22,830
The Wandering Albatross
has the most elaborate display.

286
00:36:29,440 --> 00:36:33,190
These two are renewing their bonds
after being months apart.

287
00:36:38,240 --> 00:36:42,790
Wanderers pair up in their teens and
can spend a further 50 years together,

288
00:36:43,520 --> 00:36:46,830
one of the longest partnerships
in the animal world.

289
00:37:12,120 --> 00:37:13,430
By the middle of spring,

290
00:37:13,560 --> 00:37:17,150
the snows have cleared from the coves
and the low ground.

291
00:37:18,640 --> 00:37:21,390
The beaches are almost free of ice, too,

292
00:37:21,480 --> 00:37:25,190
but that isn't the biggest change
facing the king penguins.

293
00:37:25,880 --> 00:37:31,230
Their peaceful waterfront has turned
into an obstacle course of blubber.

294
00:37:33,920 --> 00:37:36,230
The elephant seals have arrived.

295
00:37:39,520 --> 00:37:44,630
This beach now contains a greater mass
of animals than any other in the world.

296
00:37:56,640 --> 00:37:59,590
The young seals were
conceived here a year ago,

297
00:37:59,680 --> 00:38:03,590
and now that they've been born,
their mothers are ready to mate again.

298
00:38:05,520 --> 00:38:09,830
The mating rights on this patch
of the beach belong to a beach master.

299
00:38:10,640 --> 00:38:13,630
His harem contains 50 females,

300
00:38:14,560 --> 00:38:17,070
females that are coveted by others.

301
00:38:20,040 --> 00:38:22,590
His authority is being challenged.

302
00:38:27,880 --> 00:38:29,910
This rival means business.

303
00:38:42,200 --> 00:38:47,110
This could be the beach master's first
serious test of his spring campaign.

304
00:38:56,360 --> 00:38:59,630
The beach master himself
weighs four tons,

305
00:38:59,880 --> 00:39:02,030
but this rival is his equal.

306
00:39:17,440 --> 00:39:22,550
When these titans clash, bones crunch.

307
00:40:05,200 --> 00:40:09,230
He has won the first battle,
but he may have to defend his harem

308
00:40:09,320 --> 00:40:11,910
every hour for the next month.

309
00:40:13,320 --> 00:40:16,710
If he can stay master
of his beach for this period,

310
00:40:16,800 --> 00:40:19,990
many of the young born here next year
will be his.

311
00:40:25,280 --> 00:40:29,030
It's the end of spring
on the Wandering Albatross cliffs,

312
00:40:29,120 --> 00:40:31,150
their season for fledging.

313
00:40:31,800 --> 00:40:34,750
Last year's chicks
have lost their fluffy down

314
00:40:34,840 --> 00:40:38,190
and step up to the challenge
of getting into the air.

315
00:40:51,200 --> 00:40:54,550
An albatross is not very competent
on the ground,

316
00:40:54,640 --> 00:40:57,990
so until it can fly,
it isn't good for much

317
00:40:58,600 --> 00:41:03,510
and this makes the maiden flight the
crucial event in an albatross's life.

318
00:41:08,400 --> 00:41:12,110
Managing the largest wingspan
in the world takes practice,

319
00:41:15,680 --> 00:41:17,030
lots of it.

320
00:41:33,880 --> 00:41:36,350
Weeks can go by like this.

321
00:41:36,440 --> 00:41:38,870
Certainly the winds must be right.

322
00:41:39,200 --> 00:41:41,190
But it does appear that for some

323
00:41:41,280 --> 00:41:44,030
the problem is
something of a mental one.

324
00:41:58,400 --> 00:41:59,630
At last.

325
00:42:07,520 --> 00:42:09,470
The Southern Ocean beckons.

326
00:42:09,560 --> 00:42:14,310
This bird's feet will not
touch land again for five years.

327
00:42:19,960 --> 00:42:24,950
One thousand miles further south,
on the edge of the Antarctic continent,

328
00:42:25,040 --> 00:42:27,870
the sea-ice is
only just starting to break.

329
00:42:28,520 --> 00:42:32,350
But the Adélie penguins' activities
are certainly warming up.

330
00:42:33,680 --> 00:42:38,270
The males have now finished their nests,
by fair means or foul,

331
00:42:38,360 --> 00:42:41,190
and the females are finally returning,

332
00:42:41,280 --> 00:42:43,710
just as the weather is improving.

333
00:42:44,880 --> 00:42:47,150
Now their courtship can begin.

334
00:43:44,520 --> 00:43:45,870
The eggs are laid

335
00:43:45,960 --> 00:43:49,510
and the females leave the job
of incubating them to the males,

336
00:43:49,600 --> 00:43:53,670
while they go fishing out
on the fragmenting sea-ice.

337
00:44:03,680 --> 00:44:05,230
Killer whales.

338
00:44:13,280 --> 00:44:16,670
It's teamwork that makes
killer whales so dangerous.

339
00:44:17,880 --> 00:44:20,550
And this is a big team.

340
00:46:15,840 --> 00:46:19,190
There is no real need
for the penguins to be alarmed.

341
00:46:20,920 --> 00:46:24,470
These killer whales are a kind
that only eats fish.

342
00:46:29,400 --> 00:46:32,710
Rising out is simply the best way
for the whales to work out

343
00:46:32,800 --> 00:46:36,310
which cracks lead
towards the coast and better fishing.

344
00:46:49,360 --> 00:46:54,910
A new generation of Adélies steps forth
into the short Antarctic spring

345
00:46:55,000 --> 00:46:57,470
to be nurtured by industrious parents,

346
00:46:57,560 --> 00:47:01,190
who've taken great risks
to give their young a head start.

347
00:47:06,360 --> 00:47:09,150
They will need to grow fast
if they are to fledge

348
00:47:09,240 --> 00:47:12,030
and leave before
the freeze sets in again.

349
00:47:13,920 --> 00:47:18,550
It's a battle they will win
or lose over the approaching summer.

350
00:47:42,760 --> 00:47:44,590
To film the entire breeding cycle

351
00:47:44,680 --> 00:47:45,990
of the Adélie penguin,

352
00:47:46,080 --> 00:47:49,590
Frozen Planet sent a team to
one of the world's largest colonies

353
00:47:49,680 --> 00:47:51,830
at Cape Crozier, Antarctica.

354
00:47:52,040 --> 00:47:55,030
I've heard so much about it,
I've read so much about it

355
00:47:55,120 --> 00:47:57,510
and finally we're going to get there,
it's good.

356
00:47:57,600 --> 00:48:00,750
Cameraman Mark Smith
and Director Jeff Wilson plan

357
00:48:00,840 --> 00:48:03,830
to spend the next four months
living amongst the penguins,

358
00:48:03,920 --> 00:48:08,070
in a location first visited by
the early explorers a century ago.

359
00:48:09,280 --> 00:48:12,870
So arduous was Scott's
winter expedition to Cape Crozier

360
00:48:12,960 --> 00:48:16,590
that it became known as
"the worst journey in the world".

361
00:48:17,480 --> 00:48:19,950
Wow! It's fantastic.

362
00:48:21,920 --> 00:48:24,070
Modern means
make Mark and Jeff's journey

363
00:48:24,160 --> 00:48:25,630
a more comfortable affair,

364
00:48:25,720 --> 00:48:29,750
but once there, they will be tested
to the very limits of their endurance.

365
00:48:35,960 --> 00:48:38,950
The pair arrive in early spring
with enough supplies

366
00:48:39,040 --> 00:48:43,310
to survive the next four months working
alone in the Antarctic wilderness.

367
00:48:44,680 --> 00:48:46,030
We're here.

368
00:48:47,280 --> 00:48:49,310
Scott's legend of Cape Crozier

369
00:48:49,400 --> 00:48:52,350
tells of some extreme weather,
to say the least.

370
00:48:52,440 --> 00:48:55,470
So, Mark and Jeff take advantage
of the clear conditions

371
00:48:55,560 --> 00:48:59,030
in the knowledge that
the Adélies' arrival is imminent.

372
00:49:02,640 --> 00:49:05,910
But the next morning,
things take a turn for the worse.

373
00:49:06,800 --> 00:49:09,390
We've just come up to this ridge
to go and check

374
00:49:09,480 --> 00:49:12,470
exactly what it looks like down
in the colony.

375
00:49:13,680 --> 00:49:15,950
But even here you can hear

376
00:49:17,760 --> 00:49:20,630
a huge kind of roaring noise
up on the hill.

377
00:49:22,120 --> 00:49:25,070
I've never really heard anything
like that before.

378
00:49:27,680 --> 00:49:30,990
Up there, it must be blowing
the most almighty gale

379
00:49:31,080 --> 00:49:34,430
and that is, you know,
just a mile away or something.

380
00:49:34,520 --> 00:49:37,710
So, that means that
that could get here very, very quickly.

381
00:49:37,800 --> 00:49:42,150
So, yeah, it makes you slightly scared.
It's weird, isn't it?

382
00:49:42,920 --> 00:49:45,630
The winds here are
famously ferocious,

383
00:49:45,720 --> 00:49:48,230
and with so little experience
of this location,

384
00:49:48,320 --> 00:49:51,990
Mark and Jeff retreat to
the relative shelter of their hut.

385
00:49:53,360 --> 00:49:57,190
I was just stood here thinking,
"Well, it can't be too bad,

386
00:49:57,320 --> 00:49:59,590
"because we haven't seen rocks
starting to blow around yet."

387
00:49:59,720 --> 00:50:04,430
And just at that moment there was like
a rock took off and rolled down there.

388
00:50:08,520 --> 00:50:11,110
You know, it's getting stronger.

389
00:50:13,200 --> 00:50:14,750
By the second day
of the storm,

390
00:50:14,840 --> 00:50:16,670
the winds reach 80 miles an hour

391
00:50:16,760 --> 00:50:18,470
and it's apparent
that even getting lunch

392
00:50:18,560 --> 00:50:21,190
from the outside larder is too risky.

393
00:50:31,960 --> 00:50:35,510
To their increasing alarm,
the storm continues to build.

394
00:50:37,960 --> 00:50:39,790
All afternoon it's been blowing about...

395
00:50:39,880 --> 00:50:42,430
It must have been 100 miles an hour,

396
00:50:42,520 --> 00:50:45,990
and in the last half hour
it's just got a lot stronger.

397
00:50:46,680 --> 00:50:48,790
Aside from
being utterly terrified,

398
00:50:48,880 --> 00:50:52,270
there's the added worry that our gear
is stashed outside somewhere.

399
00:50:52,360 --> 00:50:54,110
We didn't have room for it in the hut

400
00:50:54,200 --> 00:50:57,830
and we just don't know whether it's
going to be there in the morning or not,

401
00:50:57,920 --> 00:51:00,710
which is...
It could spell the end of our trip.

402
00:51:00,800 --> 00:51:02,590
On the third day
of the storm,

403
00:51:02,680 --> 00:51:05,310
the winds hit 130 miles an hour.

404
00:51:05,680 --> 00:51:08,870
The hut starts to shake
from its very foundations,

405
00:51:09,200 --> 00:51:12,270
and Mark and Jeff's situation
becomes critical.

406
00:51:12,400 --> 00:51:15,590
The wind's so strong, it's constantly
blowing the pilot light out

407
00:51:15,680 --> 00:51:17,710
on the paraffin stove,

408
00:51:17,800 --> 00:51:20,870
so the temperature's dropping,
the wind's rising.

409
00:51:22,720 --> 00:51:25,070
Sounds like the bloody roof's
come off.

410
00:51:26,960 --> 00:51:30,110
The really scary thing is
is that had we gone out

411
00:51:30,200 --> 00:51:33,430
down to the colony
and tried to film today,

412
00:51:33,520 --> 00:51:37,030
there's a very high likelihood
that we'd be dead by now,

413
00:51:37,120 --> 00:51:39,430
and I don't say that lightly.

414
00:51:39,520 --> 00:51:42,710
There's no way we would have seen
this through down there,

415
00:51:43,320 --> 00:51:45,670
and that is quite sobering.

416
00:51:53,240 --> 00:51:56,070
After four terrifying days
inside the hut,

417
00:51:56,320 --> 00:52:00,390
the winds finally drop and Mark and Jeff
are keen to see what, if any,

418
00:52:00,480 --> 00:52:02,390
equipment has survived.

419
00:52:02,880 --> 00:52:05,710
All the real important stuff,
the camera stuff,

420
00:52:05,800 --> 00:52:09,310
is all still here
and it's still strapped to this rock.

421
00:52:10,920 --> 00:52:13,310
You have no idea
how much joy that gives us.

422
00:52:14,560 --> 00:52:16,630
We can get on with our jobs now.

423
00:52:21,920 --> 00:52:25,350
The first things to welcome us
into the colony are these skuas,

424
00:52:25,440 --> 00:52:30,230
which come in and batter us from above.

425
00:52:37,240 --> 00:52:39,350
At its height,
the colony will swell

426
00:52:39,440 --> 00:52:41,790
to over half a million penguins.

427
00:52:41,880 --> 00:52:45,030
And in the 24-hour daylight
of the Antarctic summer,

428
00:52:45,120 --> 00:52:48,670
Mark and Jeff spend all
of their waking hours filming.

429
00:52:49,840 --> 00:52:52,950
Unpredictable weather continues
to force the team

430
00:52:53,040 --> 00:52:56,670
to climb the two miles back
to the relative shelter of their hut,

431
00:52:57,080 --> 00:53:00,470
and Mark devises another way
of testing the wind speed.

432
00:53:09,320 --> 00:53:11,710
After six weeks, the first sign

433
00:53:11,800 --> 00:53:15,430
that the pair might be tiring
of their penguin neighbours.

434
00:53:15,920 --> 00:53:17,270
Over there's a leopard seal.

435
00:53:18,160 --> 00:53:21,750
It's the first non-penguin-looking
animal in two months.

436
00:53:22,000 --> 00:53:24,830
Will you look at that?
It's a leopard seal!

437
00:53:25,440 --> 00:53:27,630
I was down here filming
the penguins coming in,

438
00:53:27,720 --> 00:53:30,350
followed this penguin
that came out of the waves

439
00:53:30,440 --> 00:53:32,550
up the beach, very nice shot,

440
00:53:32,960 --> 00:53:34,830
stopped the shot
and there, in the middle of the frame,

441
00:53:34,920 --> 00:53:37,390
was this completely white penguin

442
00:53:38,160 --> 00:53:40,310
trying to get into the shot.

443
00:53:40,840 --> 00:53:43,230
We kind of suspect that
he might be following us around now.

444
00:53:47,640 --> 00:53:50,070
Working around the clock
for this length of time

445
00:53:50,160 --> 00:53:53,070
in the presence
of half a million screaming penguins

446
00:53:53,160 --> 00:53:55,350
would test anyone's resolve.

447
00:53:57,000 --> 00:53:59,310
I hate carrying gear. Hear that?

448
00:53:59,400 --> 00:54:01,830
I hate carrying gear.
I don't want to do it any more.

449
00:54:03,800 --> 00:54:05,070
Midway through their trip,

450
00:54:05,160 --> 00:54:08,110
after more than 1, 000 hours
amongst the penguins,

451
00:54:08,200 --> 00:54:11,270
their grip on reality
is beginning to loosen.

452
00:54:13,160 --> 00:54:15,510
Here we are
on the penguin superhighway,

453
00:54:16,720 --> 00:54:19,350
where the penguins go down to the sea.

454
00:54:19,960 --> 00:54:23,990
It seems
that they follow the American system,

455
00:54:24,800 --> 00:54:28,790
driving on the right,
going down to the sea on the right,

456
00:54:29,520 --> 00:54:33,350
coming back from the sea on the left
as you're facing the sea.

457
00:54:35,320 --> 00:54:39,430
I'm fairly sure that yesterday,
they were doing the British system.

458
00:54:42,200 --> 00:54:46,550
The legendary Cape Crozier weather
soon snaps them back into reality.

459
00:54:47,320 --> 00:54:49,030
Well, I'm just filming the penguins

460
00:54:49,120 --> 00:54:55,230
with this huge windstorm
coming over the ice cap.

461
00:54:55,400 --> 00:54:56,870
This is the kind of thing we were
warned about

462
00:54:56,960 --> 00:54:59,510
by the guy who was here before,
who has been here for several years

463
00:54:59,600 --> 00:55:02,470
and saying, "If you see skies like this,
then you should run for home."

464
00:55:02,560 --> 00:55:04,790
But of course, we're just going
to stay and film it.

465
00:55:05,400 --> 00:55:07,350
Because we're the BBC.

466
00:55:08,280 --> 00:55:09,870
But in this part of the world,

467
00:55:09,960 --> 00:55:13,070
working for the BBC
doesn't count for much.

468
00:55:13,160 --> 00:55:15,430
Within minutes,
the winds reach hurricane strength

469
00:55:15,520 --> 00:55:18,030
and the crew are in serious trouble.

470
00:55:18,600 --> 00:55:20,310
So, we've got to now venture out
and go up the...

471
00:55:20,400 --> 00:55:22,630
about a mile up this valley, where...

472
00:55:22,720 --> 00:55:27,070
which looks like it's got about
80-mile-an-hour winds blowing down it,

473
00:55:27,160 --> 00:55:28,510
so it's going to be quite an adventure.

474
00:55:29,480 --> 00:55:31,230
Bit frightening, though, really.

475
00:55:31,720 --> 00:55:34,630
After three months,
the pair are now fully aware

476
00:55:34,720 --> 00:55:36,870
of the strength the winds can reach.

477
00:55:36,960 --> 00:55:38,990
Getting a little stronger now!

478
00:55:39,080 --> 00:55:41,630
There is a very real danger
that they could be separated

479
00:55:41,720 --> 00:55:44,270
and lost in these white-out conditions.

480
00:55:57,000 --> 00:55:59,110
Hey, watch this, Jeff.

481
00:56:08,040 --> 00:56:10,070
We're going to go...

482
00:56:12,720 --> 00:56:14,630
Two terrifying hours later,

483
00:56:14,720 --> 00:56:18,310
and their relief at
finally reaching the hut is tangible.

484
00:56:21,840 --> 00:56:24,590
With a month still to go
at Cape Crozier,

485
00:56:24,680 --> 00:56:29,070
Mark, Jeff, and the penguins
will face many more storms like this.

486
00:56:29,280 --> 00:56:31,510
But it seems that
their greatest challenge

487
00:56:31,600 --> 00:56:34,030
will be to maintain their sanity.

488
00:56:35,360 --> 00:56:38,830
Here we are, travelling
through the Antarctic by sled.

489
00:56:38,920 --> 00:56:41,150
We're being pulled
by a herd of huskies.

490
00:56:41,240 --> 00:56:42,310
Oh !

491
00:56:44,320 --> 00:56:49,150
Twelve of them panting out front,
breath steaming from their mouths,

492
00:56:50,120 --> 00:56:53,990
and as we go along,
we see the happy people waving at us.

