1
00:00:35,760 --> 00:00:39,270
Over one third of our planet is frozen,

2
00:00:39,360 --> 00:00:42,710
and yet the icy worlds
of the Arctic and Antarctic

3
00:00:42,800 --> 00:00:47,310
are as alien to most of us
as the surface of another planet.

4
00:00:49,560 --> 00:00:52,150
They are places of superlatives,

5
00:00:52,480 --> 00:00:56,870
from ice caps that hold nearly 80%
of our planet's fresh water

6
00:00:57,520 --> 00:01:01,950
to frozen forests
that encircle the entire globe.

7
00:01:05,480 --> 00:01:08,110
These are places that feed
our imaginations,

8
00:01:08,200 --> 00:01:11,830
places that seem to be borrowed
from fairytales.

9
00:01:13,800 --> 00:01:16,590
They're dominated and shaped by the ice,

10
00:01:18,480 --> 00:01:21,590
both by its coming and by its going.

11
00:01:25,520 --> 00:01:29,270
This is our planet's
last true wilderness

12
00:01:29,360 --> 00:01:33,470
and one that is changing just as
we are beginning to understand it.

13
00:01:36,000 --> 00:01:39,910
In this series we'll be travelling
to all parts of these lonely lands,

14
00:01:40,000 --> 00:01:41,710
both north and south,

15
00:01:41,800 --> 00:01:45,190
to witness its wonders,
perhaps for the last time,

16
00:01:45,640 --> 00:01:48,510
and to discover
some extraordinary examples

17
00:01:48,600 --> 00:01:50,990
of survival against all the odds

18
00:01:51,080 --> 00:01:53,790
as can be found anywhere on the planet.

19
00:02:17,520 --> 00:02:21,110
The Poles are
permanently capped with ice.

20
00:02:21,200 --> 00:02:25,710
Nowhere is colder,
windier or more hostile to life.

21
00:02:30,800 --> 00:02:33,550
I'm standing at the North Pole,

22
00:02:33,640 --> 00:02:36,510
the very top of the Earth.

23
00:02:36,600 --> 00:02:41,830
Up here, it's easy to see
why the polar regions are so cold.

24
00:02:42,400 --> 00:02:47,510
The sun never rises high enough
in the sky to warm my back

25
00:02:48,000 --> 00:02:51,390
and those rays
that do strike the surface

26
00:02:51,480 --> 00:02:55,830
are mostly reflected back
from this great whiteness.

27
00:02:56,600 --> 00:02:58,870
But the fundamental problem

28
00:02:58,960 --> 00:03:03,630
is that there's no sun here at all
for half the year.

29
00:03:05,040 --> 00:03:08,910
The polar winter
is unrivalled in its harshness,

30
00:03:09,000 --> 00:03:11,910
a night that lasts for months.

31
00:03:12,920 --> 00:03:16,150
Only the toughest stay,
as temperatures plunge

32
00:03:16,240 --> 00:03:18,710
to minus 70 degrees centigrade.

33
00:03:19,440 --> 00:03:23,670
And yet the greatest challenge
to life here is not the cold,

34
00:03:23,760 --> 00:03:26,910
but the extreme swings
between the seasons.

35
00:03:29,360 --> 00:03:34,510
When the sun finally returns,
an extraordinary transformation begins.

36
00:03:35,840 --> 00:03:39,350
This frozen world begins to melt away.

37
00:03:44,080 --> 00:03:47,470
The polar spring
brings a brief opportunity for life.

38
00:03:51,440 --> 00:03:56,070
By summer, the sun no longer sets
and works its magic for 24 hours a day.

39
00:04:01,520 --> 00:04:05,310
Now it's a race to breed
before the sun departs.

40
00:04:09,840 --> 00:04:13,550
By autumn, all but the hardiest
abandon the Poles

41
00:04:13,640 --> 00:04:15,710
and the ice extends its grip.

42
00:04:22,920 --> 00:04:27,190
Land and sea close down
for the long polar winter

43
00:04:28,200 --> 00:04:31,670
until, once again, the sun returns.

44
00:04:39,040 --> 00:04:41,350
It's spring in the high Arctic

45
00:04:41,440 --> 00:04:44,750
and the sun illuminates
a giant frozen ocean,

46
00:04:44,840 --> 00:04:47,070
the first stop on our journey.

47
00:04:51,080 --> 00:04:55,270
The most powerful land predator
is on the prowl.

48
00:05:01,200 --> 00:05:04,550
A male polar bear
is searching for a mate.

49
00:05:08,160 --> 00:05:10,830
Willing females are few and far between

50
00:05:10,920 --> 00:05:14,750
and the sea-ice on which he travels
will soon melt and vanish.

51
00:05:18,120 --> 00:05:23,070
He's running out of time to find a mate
in this vast frozen desert.

52
00:05:38,920 --> 00:05:40,870
Ten miles ahead,

53
00:05:40,960 --> 00:05:44,030
a single female without cubs,

54
00:05:44,120 --> 00:05:46,510
exactly what the male is seeking.

55
00:05:49,520 --> 00:05:53,510
He seems to relish her scent,
even though she's miles away.

56
00:05:55,320 --> 00:05:57,590
This is an exciting prospect.

57
00:06:00,080 --> 00:06:02,910
She's clearly giving off
the right signals.

58
00:06:06,040 --> 00:06:09,910
He locks onto her tracks,
eager not to lose her trail.

59
00:06:10,280 --> 00:06:13,990
It's easier to tread
in the compacted snow of her footprints.

60
00:06:14,960 --> 00:06:17,950
This pursuit could last for days.

61
00:06:24,280 --> 00:06:26,790
The female eventually comes into view.

62
00:06:28,720 --> 00:06:31,030
The search is finally over.

63
00:06:44,080 --> 00:06:48,830
For the female, only half his weight,
this must be a nerve-wracking encounter.

64
00:06:49,920 --> 00:06:52,590
The male could kill her if he chooses.

65
00:06:56,200 --> 00:06:58,950
But he has other intentions.

66
00:07:00,000 --> 00:07:02,630
And she is ready and willing.

67
00:07:05,520 --> 00:07:08,550
She leads him to higher ground.

68
00:07:13,920 --> 00:07:17,270
It seems that courting polar bears
prefer privacy,

69
00:07:17,760 --> 00:07:20,790
often leaving the sea-ice
and heading for the hills

70
00:07:20,880 --> 00:07:25,430
to avoid the prying eyes
of rival males who might disturb them.

71
00:07:29,320 --> 00:07:31,790
Few have witnessed this moment.

72
00:07:33,360 --> 00:07:38,870
For the male, his only tender encounter
in an otherwise solitary life.

73
00:07:43,520 --> 00:07:45,270
But it doesn't last long.

74
00:07:45,360 --> 00:07:48,590
A rival suitor has also caught
the female's scent.

75
00:07:51,240 --> 00:07:55,150
Courtship has to be put on hold,
he must fight for his rights.

76
00:08:06,240 --> 00:08:10,310
He sees off this first challenger
without injury to either party.

77
00:08:11,360 --> 00:08:14,110
But bloodier battles are to come.

78
00:08:41,640 --> 00:08:45,830
Another battle won,
though he has been slightly injured.

79
00:08:46,320 --> 00:08:48,230
He hurries back to his mate,

80
00:08:48,320 --> 00:08:51,350
but now she seems
to have lost her enthusiasm.

81
00:08:53,320 --> 00:08:56,630
Female polar bears are high maintenance.

82
00:09:11,760 --> 00:09:16,070
Wherever she goes he will follow,
mating with her when she allows

83
00:09:16,160 --> 00:09:18,550
and guarding her at all times.

84
00:09:31,440 --> 00:09:35,350
Over the next two weeks,
the male sees off many rivals,

85
00:09:35,440 --> 00:09:38,110
but the battles take their toll on him.

86
00:09:43,880 --> 00:09:46,070
He is almost spent,

87
00:09:46,160 --> 00:09:50,750
but he has ensured that no other bears
have mated with his female.

88
00:09:55,280 --> 00:09:58,550
It's time for the couple to go
their separate ways.

89
00:09:59,320 --> 00:10:04,230
She will give birth to his cubs, alone,
in nine months' time,

90
00:10:04,600 --> 00:10:06,910
and he may never see her again.

91
00:10:09,240 --> 00:10:11,510
He returns to the frozen ocean,

92
00:10:11,600 --> 00:10:14,990
no doubt relieved
to resume his solitary ways,

93
00:10:15,600 --> 00:10:17,310
and just in time.

94
00:10:17,640 --> 00:10:21,070
The ice beneath his feet
will soon be gone.

95
00:10:24,480 --> 00:10:29,470
Each spring the Arctic Ocean undergoes
an extraordinary transformation.

96
00:10:30,560 --> 00:10:33,670
An area of sea-ice
the size of Europe melts,

97
00:10:33,840 --> 00:10:36,270
exposing the rich waters beneath.

98
00:10:39,680 --> 00:10:44,630
Short-tailed shearwaters have travelled
10,000 miles from Australia to be here.

99
00:10:52,200 --> 00:10:55,750
Eighteen million visitors
darken the skies,

100
00:10:55,840 --> 00:10:58,990
the largest gathering of sea birds
on the planet.

101
00:11:14,440 --> 00:11:17,630
Humpback whales have come all the way
from the Equator

102
00:11:17,720 --> 00:11:20,390
to feed in these rich polar waters.

103
00:11:28,200 --> 00:11:31,190
Their giant tails are
five metres across.

104
00:11:34,000 --> 00:11:35,990
Simply raising them above the surface

105
00:11:36,080 --> 00:11:38,550
gives the whales
enough downward momentum

106
00:11:38,640 --> 00:11:41,670
to reach the great swarms of krill
and herring below.

107
00:11:57,240 --> 00:11:59,990
The shearwaters follow the giants' lead.

108
00:12:20,480 --> 00:12:22,830
For those who can get here, in summer,

109
00:12:22,920 --> 00:12:26,430
these waters provide a feast
of epic proportions.

110
00:12:27,080 --> 00:12:29,830
But the good times will be very short,

111
00:12:29,920 --> 00:12:33,350
a problem that faces all life
in the polar regions.

112
00:12:36,800 --> 00:12:39,350
Journeying south
across the Arctic Ocean,

113
00:12:39,440 --> 00:12:44,110
the first land you reach is Greenland,
the largest island in the world.

114
00:12:45,920 --> 00:12:49,430
Despite its name,
Greenland is mostly white,

115
00:12:49,520 --> 00:12:51,150
covered by a giant ice sheet

116
00:12:51,240 --> 00:12:54,190
six times the size
of the United Kingdom.

117
00:12:58,400 --> 00:13:02,150
In the middle of the island,
the ice is nearly two miles thick.

118
00:13:02,240 --> 00:13:04,910
It's a bleak, quiet world.

119
00:13:10,960 --> 00:13:14,550
Sapphire-blue melt-lakes
are the first sign

120
00:13:14,640 --> 00:13:17,110
that a dynamic process is underway.

121
00:13:21,120 --> 00:13:23,630
Each lake forms in a matter of days,

122
00:13:23,720 --> 00:13:28,190
expanding until it's miles across
and starts to overflow.

123
00:13:30,400 --> 00:13:33,950
The spill water then carves its way
through the ice.

124
00:13:45,800 --> 00:13:48,510
The water courses through an icy delta

125
00:13:48,600 --> 00:13:52,270
like blood along the arteries
of a cold-blooded monster,

126
00:13:53,080 --> 00:13:55,430
a monster that is stirring.

127
00:14:07,680 --> 00:14:12,750
And without warning, the water suddenly
plunges down an open shaft,

128
00:14:12,840 --> 00:14:16,390
falling a vertical mile
into the heart of the ice sheet.

129
00:14:41,160 --> 00:14:44,590
This meltwater has a surprising effect.

130
00:14:45,000 --> 00:14:49,310
It lubricates the junction between
the ice and the rock floor beneath,

131
00:14:49,720 --> 00:14:53,630
so the entire ice-sheet
is now on the move,

132
00:14:53,720 --> 00:14:56,870
sliding downhill into the ocean.

133
00:14:58,920 --> 00:15:01,830
This, Jakobshavn Isbrae,

134
00:15:01,920 --> 00:15:04,710
is the fastest flowing glacier
on our planet

135
00:15:04,800 --> 00:15:07,710
moving as much as 40 metres a day.

136
00:15:10,880 --> 00:15:14,950
As it advances,
it destroys everything in its path,

137
00:15:15,200 --> 00:15:18,950
even cutting its way through
Greenland's great mountain ranges

138
00:15:19,040 --> 00:15:21,910
on its drive downwards towards the sea.

139
00:15:25,160 --> 00:15:27,910
When speeded up,
these solid rivers of ice

140
00:15:28,000 --> 00:15:30,710
seem to flow just like liquid rivers.

141
00:15:37,120 --> 00:15:39,550
This is the titanic force

142
00:15:39,640 --> 00:15:44,030
that cuts down mountains
and levels the surface of continents.

143
00:16:01,760 --> 00:16:05,910
The ice is now entering
the last stage of its descent.

144
00:16:08,600 --> 00:16:14,230
As it gains speed, huge crevasses open
that extend down to its very core.

145
00:16:19,800 --> 00:16:22,910
It's reached the ocean,
and millions of tons of ice

146
00:16:23,000 --> 00:16:25,790
have lost the support
of their rocky bed.

147
00:16:29,560 --> 00:16:31,590
Something must give.

148
00:16:51,960 --> 00:16:55,830
These icefalls are an ominous sign
of what is about to happen.

149
00:16:57,840 --> 00:17:00,750
A rupture deep within the glacier.

150
00:17:27,800 --> 00:17:30,830
A colossal iceberg is born.

151
00:17:55,160 --> 00:17:59,070
This single block of ice,
many hundreds of metres across,

152
00:17:59,160 --> 00:18:02,590
would dwarf the biggest
of mankind's buildings.

153
00:18:09,720 --> 00:18:12,750
Every year,
tens of thousands of icebergs

154
00:18:12,840 --> 00:18:15,550
are spawned by Greenland's glaciers,

155
00:18:15,640 --> 00:18:20,310
and their number is steadily increasing
as the climate continues to warm.

156
00:18:31,240 --> 00:18:32,870
The break-up of the bergs

157
00:18:32,960 --> 00:18:36,710
fills the bays of the Arctic
with exquisite ice sculptures.

158
00:18:38,960 --> 00:18:43,470
It also releases great volumes
of cold fresh water into the sea.

159
00:18:45,760 --> 00:18:49,870
Greenland's meltwater influences
the course of the ocean currents,

160
00:18:49,960 --> 00:18:54,350
which in turn has an effect
on the weather around the world.

161
00:19:03,000 --> 00:19:06,790
The Arctic is closer to home
than many of us realise.

162
00:19:07,160 --> 00:19:10,630
It includes the northernmost parts
of the three continents

163
00:19:10,720 --> 00:19:15,550
on which most of us live,
Europe, Asia and North America.

164
00:19:18,400 --> 00:19:21,750
The first bare land we reach
on our journey south

165
00:19:21,840 --> 00:19:25,590
is a bleak, treeless wilderness
known as tundra.

166
00:19:28,280 --> 00:19:31,430
Each spring, animals travel up
from the south

167
00:19:31,520 --> 00:19:33,590
to be ready for the rich grazing

168
00:19:33,680 --> 00:19:36,430
that will be unveiled
by the spring melt.

169
00:19:37,720 --> 00:19:39,990
For the caribou, the timing is critical.

170
00:19:40,080 --> 00:19:43,150
Arrive early
and a winter storm could kill you.

171
00:19:43,240 --> 00:19:46,830
Delay too long and you may fail
to lay down the fat needed

172
00:19:46,920 --> 00:19:48,790
to survive a polar winter.

173
00:19:57,960 --> 00:20:02,150
Further south still
and stooped, shrouded figures

174
00:20:02,240 --> 00:20:04,950
end the flat monotony of the tundra.

175
00:20:08,520 --> 00:20:10,350
This is the tree-line,

176
00:20:10,440 --> 00:20:14,470
the first place on our journey
with sufficient warmth and liquid water

177
00:20:14,560 --> 00:20:16,550
to enable a tree to grow.

178
00:20:18,720 --> 00:20:21,430
Surviving here
is so crushingly difficult

179
00:20:21,520 --> 00:20:24,070
that it can take hundreds of years
for a seedling

180
00:20:24,160 --> 00:20:26,550
to grow into a stunted shrub.

181
00:20:35,360 --> 00:20:40,150
But even small trees
can provide cover for a predator.

182
00:20:41,360 --> 00:20:42,550
Wolves.

183
00:20:42,960 --> 00:20:44,270
These in northern Canada

184
00:20:44,360 --> 00:20:47,070
are the largest
and most powerful in the world

185
00:20:47,160 --> 00:20:49,550
and they are setting out to hunt.

186
00:20:53,640 --> 00:20:55,910
The pack is 25 strong,

187
00:20:56,000 --> 00:20:59,590
a sign that the prey they are seeking
is formidable.

188
00:21:07,880 --> 00:21:10,990
These bison are even bigger
than their southern cousins

189
00:21:11,080 --> 00:21:13,830
and the largest land animals
in North America.

190
00:21:15,040 --> 00:21:17,870
For generations, wolves and bison here

191
00:21:17,960 --> 00:21:20,590
have been shaped by their battles
with each other,

192
00:21:20,680 --> 00:21:23,830
making each the most impressive
of its kind.

193
00:21:26,160 --> 00:21:29,270
The bison will not stay long
among the trees.

194
00:21:29,360 --> 00:21:31,030
They are not safe here.

195
00:21:37,560 --> 00:21:39,350
The wolves are closing in,

196
00:21:39,440 --> 00:21:43,030
but their chance of ambushing the bison
in the woods has passed.

197
00:21:43,120 --> 00:21:46,990
Their prey are now in the open
and grouped together for safety.

198
00:21:50,320 --> 00:21:54,350
The wolves will need to work as a team
if they're to make a kill.

199
00:21:58,200 --> 00:22:01,990
They circle the herd,
trying to unsettle it and split it up.

200
00:22:02,360 --> 00:22:04,590
But the bison are armed and dangerous,

201
00:22:04,680 --> 00:22:07,870
they will be safe
as long as they stick together.

202
00:22:13,560 --> 00:22:16,110
The wolves up their game,
harrying the herd,

203
00:22:16,200 --> 00:22:20,510
a ploy to trigger a stampede
and split away one of the smaller ones.

204
00:22:23,240 --> 00:22:26,030
The bison form a defensive circle
around their young,

205
00:22:26,120 --> 00:22:28,590
horns pointing outwards.

206
00:22:34,520 --> 00:22:37,310
The wolves need a bison to break rank.

207
00:22:43,440 --> 00:22:47,030
But the tables are turning
and now the wolves have to retreat.

208
00:22:50,720 --> 00:22:53,870
The pack focus their attention
on the rear of the herd

209
00:22:53,960 --> 00:22:56,190
and the bison begin to panic.

210
00:23:30,800 --> 00:23:33,190
A young bison falls behind.

211
00:23:39,120 --> 00:23:42,110
Even this yearling dwarfs the wolves.

212
00:23:50,040 --> 00:23:53,630
Running head-down,
the herd's only thought is escape.

213
00:23:58,680 --> 00:24:00,990
A stroke of luck for the wolves.

214
00:24:14,320 --> 00:24:17,390
The kill will feed the pack
for several days.

215
00:24:17,800 --> 00:24:20,670
But then they will have to resume
the chase.

216
00:24:21,320 --> 00:24:26,390
At the frozen ends of our planet,
the struggle for survival never eases.

217
00:24:37,120 --> 00:24:40,310
South of the tree-line
the winters are shorter,

218
00:24:40,400 --> 00:24:45,550
so trees grow faster and taller,
and forests begin to appear.

219
00:24:47,240 --> 00:24:51,630
As the warm, humid air from the south
meets the cold Arctic air,

220
00:24:51,720 --> 00:24:57,550
the moisture it carries crystallises,
and snowflakes fall from the sky.

221
00:25:00,960 --> 00:25:04,990
Each crystal forms around
a particle of dust.

222
00:25:10,400 --> 00:25:12,590
All have a six-fold symmetry

223
00:25:12,680 --> 00:25:16,670
but no two have ever been
found with exactly the same shape.

224
00:25:24,800 --> 00:25:28,470
Their variety and complexity
is breathtaking.

225
00:25:34,000 --> 00:25:38,350
Each snowflake is water
waiting to be released in spring.

226
00:25:38,880 --> 00:25:43,630
For this reason, snow is the lifeblood
of these silent forests,

227
00:25:43,720 --> 00:25:47,870
and all that live here depend on it
in one way or another.

228
00:25:54,320 --> 00:25:57,230
Some, like the great grey owl,

229
00:25:57,320 --> 00:26:02,910
appear in spring for the boom times,
then vanish like phantoms.

230
00:26:06,000 --> 00:26:10,790
Others, like their lemming prey,
are here year-round beneath the snow,

231
00:26:10,880 --> 00:26:13,350
insulated from the cold air above.

232
00:26:34,600 --> 00:26:38,630
The northern forests are a crossroads
for seasonal visitors

233
00:26:38,720 --> 00:26:40,670
and Arctic specialists.

234
00:26:41,880 --> 00:26:43,950
But they are so much more than this.

235
00:26:44,040 --> 00:26:48,350
Together they make up the Taiga,
an unbroken belt of forest

236
00:26:48,440 --> 00:26:51,750
that stretches 7,000 miles
around our planet

237
00:26:51,840 --> 00:26:55,950
and contains one-third of all the trees
on Earth.

238
00:27:06,040 --> 00:27:10,030
The Taiga forest marks the end
of our journey through the Arctic,

239
00:27:10,160 --> 00:27:14,670
from the frozen ocean
down across the lands that surround it.

240
00:27:22,920 --> 00:27:28,270
The other end of our planet,
the Antarctic, is starkly different,

241
00:27:28,800 --> 00:27:32,190
a frozen continent
completely surrounded by ocean.

242
00:27:34,600 --> 00:27:36,790
Icebergs here are so large

243
00:27:36,880 --> 00:27:39,670
that they're measured in miles,
not metres.

244
00:27:40,640 --> 00:27:43,830
They are the only obstacles in the path
of giant waves,

245
00:27:43,920 --> 00:27:47,990
which circle around the continent
unchecked by other lands.

246
00:28:02,560 --> 00:28:08,350
These seas may be cold and storm-racked,
but they're bursting with life.

247
00:28:37,800 --> 00:28:42,790
No bird is more at home in water,
and they are masterful surfers.

248
00:28:48,600 --> 00:28:52,390
Penguins are found only
in the Southern Hemisphere.

249
00:28:53,320 --> 00:28:56,830
They can't fly, but they don't need to.

250
00:28:56,920 --> 00:28:59,230
There are no polar bears here.

251
00:29:07,680 --> 00:29:10,030
These are Gentoo penguins.

252
00:29:10,640 --> 00:29:14,790
Each spring they come ashore
to lay their eggs and rear their young.

253
00:29:15,040 --> 00:29:17,550
Their hungry chicks demand
so much seafood

254
00:29:17,640 --> 00:29:20,230
that both parents have to go fishing.

255
00:29:26,160 --> 00:29:28,870
And fishing can be dangerous.

256
00:29:44,040 --> 00:29:46,390
A southern sea lion.

257
00:29:51,320 --> 00:29:55,750
It uses the speed of a breaking wave
to catch up with the Gentoos.

258
00:30:10,840 --> 00:30:12,750
Sea lions normally eat fish,

259
00:30:12,840 --> 00:30:16,030
so he's used to catching
streamlined swimmers.

260
00:30:16,720 --> 00:30:19,790
But the Gentoos seem more than
his match out at sea.

261
00:30:19,880 --> 00:30:21,430
He must change tactics.

262
00:30:26,640 --> 00:30:29,350
Perhaps it will be easier
in the shallows.

263
00:30:51,520 --> 00:30:55,510
But no, it seems penguins
are uncatchable in water.

264
00:31:01,640 --> 00:31:03,670
How about on land?

265
00:31:05,600 --> 00:31:08,150
The penguin's wings,
so powerful for swimming,

266
00:31:08,240 --> 00:31:10,510
are of no help when it comes to running.

267
00:31:10,760 --> 00:31:13,710
Now, surely, the sea lion has a chance.

268
00:31:18,680 --> 00:31:22,390
But on the beach,
both are like fish out of water.

269
00:31:44,840 --> 00:31:49,350
Rarely do hunter and hunted
play their roles with so little skill.

270
00:31:49,440 --> 00:31:52,030
The outcome is anyone's guess.

271
00:32:28,040 --> 00:32:33,510
Every summer, over 40 million penguins
take to the Southern Ocean to feed.

272
00:32:39,440 --> 00:32:44,390
They're joined by thousands of whales.
Minkes are the most numerous.

273
00:32:46,920 --> 00:32:51,190
They all come here to
harvest the richest ocean on Earth.

274
00:32:53,600 --> 00:32:56,830
Carrying on south,
we get our first glimpse

275
00:32:56,920 --> 00:32:58,870
of the frozen continent.

276
00:33:13,360 --> 00:33:18,150
Southern humpbacks, after travelling
4, 000 miles from the Equator,

277
00:33:18,240 --> 00:33:21,030
are finally arriving in Antarctica.

278
00:33:26,040 --> 00:33:29,950
Humans have long felt the lure
of this mysterious world,

279
00:33:30,200 --> 00:33:35,030
yet it was only 100 years ago
that the first explorers walked inland

280
00:33:35,320 --> 00:33:40,830
and were confronted by the highest,
driest and coldest territory on Earth.

281
00:33:45,880 --> 00:33:48,950
Every year the continent is transformed

282
00:33:49,040 --> 00:33:52,750
as the sea-ice that surrounds it
begins to disappear.

283
00:34:01,440 --> 00:34:05,110
This melt halves the size of Antarctica.

284
00:34:06,840 --> 00:34:09,950
It's the most spectacular
seasonal change

285
00:34:10,040 --> 00:34:12,430
occurring anywhere on our planet.

286
00:34:16,680 --> 00:34:20,710
The remnants of the sea-ice
are occupied by sunbathing seals

287
00:34:20,800 --> 00:34:23,310
that have been here all winter.

288
00:34:25,920 --> 00:34:29,630
But new arrivals are
following the retreating ice edge

289
00:34:29,720 --> 00:34:32,430
and they have come here to hunt.

290
00:34:39,640 --> 00:34:42,870
Killer whales, the ocean's top predator.

291
00:34:44,520 --> 00:34:46,030
Killers are like wolves,

292
00:34:46,120 --> 00:34:49,430
for they will hunt animals far larger
than themselves.

293
00:34:49,520 --> 00:34:52,990
But even smaller prey are a problem
if you can't reach them.

294
00:34:58,880 --> 00:35:01,310
The solution is teamwork.

295
00:35:03,720 --> 00:35:07,710
Swimming in perfect formation,
they flick their tails in unison

296
00:35:07,800 --> 00:35:10,870
and create a wave that cracks the ice.

297
00:35:18,680 --> 00:35:21,150
They regroup and assess the damage.

298
00:35:22,160 --> 00:35:24,390
A more powerful wave is needed.

299
00:35:29,640 --> 00:35:32,030
The ice floe is breaking up.

300
00:35:33,880 --> 00:35:37,150
Now they are close enough
to get a good look at their target.

301
00:35:37,520 --> 00:35:41,590
The seal is a crab-eater,
sharp-toothed and feisty.

302
00:35:41,680 --> 00:35:43,110
Not their favourite.

303
00:35:47,200 --> 00:35:51,190
The wolves of the sea move on,
in search of easier quarry.

304
00:35:56,160 --> 00:35:58,390
A Weddell seal. That's better.

305
00:35:59,720 --> 00:36:02,550
These are more docile
and easier to tackle.

306
00:36:05,360 --> 00:36:09,430
The pod stays close together
and travels silently.

307
00:36:11,840 --> 00:36:15,150
This time they unleash
a far more powerful wave

308
00:36:15,240 --> 00:36:17,470
and with astonishing accuracy.

309
00:36:24,560 --> 00:36:27,510
These big waves are not intended
to break the ice,

310
00:36:27,600 --> 00:36:31,670
but to knock the prey into the water,
and they rarely fail.

311
00:37:17,320 --> 00:37:19,870
The seal is now
where the killers want it.

312
00:37:21,760 --> 00:37:23,990
But the hunt is far from over.

313
00:37:25,960 --> 00:37:28,310
They need to grab their prey
by the tail,

314
00:37:28,400 --> 00:37:30,790
while avoiding its snapping jaws.

315
00:37:31,480 --> 00:37:34,990
Only then will they be able to
pull it down and drown it.

316
00:37:38,680 --> 00:37:43,430
Sideswipes create violent
underwater turbulence, a new tactic.

317
00:37:51,040 --> 00:37:55,230
Blowing bubbles gives cover
for others to lunge at the seal's tail.

318
00:38:03,560 --> 00:38:07,310
Somehow the seal manages
to reach a tiny ice floe.

319
00:38:12,520 --> 00:38:14,630
The killers could easily grab it,

320
00:38:14,720 --> 00:38:17,510
but now this seems to have become
a game.

321
00:38:19,840 --> 00:38:23,750
The seal's life hangs on
a roll of the ice.

322
00:38:35,600 --> 00:38:38,950
Yet again, the pod joins forces
to dislodge the seal.

323
00:38:57,200 --> 00:39:00,070
The seal sees a chance to escape.

324
00:39:04,000 --> 00:39:08,230
Exhausted, it no longer has the energy
to pull itself to safety

325
00:39:09,000 --> 00:39:11,230
and the killers are moving in.

326
00:39:20,080 --> 00:39:21,830
Game over.

327
00:39:33,680 --> 00:39:36,630
Although such team hunts
are rarely seen,

328
00:39:36,720 --> 00:39:40,390
scientists believe they may be
the most complex ever documented

329
00:39:40,480 --> 00:39:42,390
in the natural world.

330
00:39:42,480 --> 00:39:45,470
They were first witnessed
by Captain Scott and his men

331
00:39:45,560 --> 00:39:49,110
when they came to explore Antarctica
100 years ago.

332
00:39:53,080 --> 00:39:54,910
Journeying further south,

333
00:39:55,000 --> 00:39:58,790
the fragmenting ice is replaced
by a permanent sheet

334
00:39:58,880 --> 00:40:01,670
that doesn't melt
even at the height of summer.

335
00:40:03,160 --> 00:40:06,430
It's a barrier that
many creatures find impassable.

336
00:40:09,160 --> 00:40:12,030
It repels even powerful Minke whales.

337
00:40:12,360 --> 00:40:13,430
They have to turn back

338
00:40:13,520 --> 00:40:17,150
if they can no longer reach
the air they need to breathe.

339
00:40:24,040 --> 00:40:29,750
Under the ice, life has to be
extremely specialised to survive.

340
00:40:31,680 --> 00:40:36,310
Few of us will ever experience
this strangely still world,

341
00:40:36,840 --> 00:40:40,190
and as yet, no one knows much about it.

342
00:40:45,120 --> 00:40:48,030
The crystalline surface
of the ice stalactites

343
00:40:48,120 --> 00:40:52,990
provides a home for ice-fish,
whose bodies are full of anti-freeze.

344
00:40:57,880 --> 00:41:00,870
The ceiling of ice shields those
living below it

345
00:41:00,960 --> 00:41:04,430
from the violent polar weather
that rages above.

346
00:41:04,920 --> 00:41:08,150
Little here has changed
for millions of years.

347
00:41:11,520 --> 00:41:17,350
The cold allows animals
to grow very slowly and become giants.

348
00:41:32,520 --> 00:41:36,670
A relative of the woodlouse
is the size of a dinner plate.

349
00:41:39,240 --> 00:41:43,910
And this so-called sea spider
has legs that span half a metre.

350
00:41:47,640 --> 00:41:50,230
Now explorers are revealing other worlds

351
00:41:50,320 --> 00:41:53,510
that lie hidden beneath the ice
on land.

352
00:41:56,800 --> 00:42:02,070
These smoking towers are the gateway
to a network of caves.

353
00:42:04,640 --> 00:42:08,590
Each contains an extraordinary assembly
of ice crystals

354
00:42:08,680 --> 00:42:10,790
unlike any other on Earth.

355
00:42:18,600 --> 00:42:22,350
Like snowflakes,
every crystal is unique.

356
00:42:24,640 --> 00:42:26,710
Some are taller than a man.

357
00:42:29,760 --> 00:42:31,830
Others are thought to harbour life,

358
00:42:31,920 --> 00:42:36,830
seeded by strange bacteria that thrive
in these extreme conditions.

359
00:42:38,600 --> 00:42:41,590
The breeze that
gently sways these crystals

360
00:42:41,680 --> 00:42:43,750
is responsible for making them.

361
00:42:43,840 --> 00:42:47,670
It's steam from the molten heart
of Mount Erebus,

362
00:42:47,760 --> 00:42:50,790
the most southerly
volcano on our planet.

363
00:43:02,480 --> 00:43:06,110
It's now thought that
the ice caves fringing this crater

364
00:43:06,200 --> 00:43:10,150
may even be a home
for hitherto unknown life forms.

365
00:43:15,400 --> 00:43:18,550
From this oasis of warmth
at the edge of the continent,

366
00:43:18,640 --> 00:43:22,150
our journey continues inland
towards the South Pole.

367
00:43:23,440 --> 00:43:28,310
The first great hurdle is the formidable
Transantarctic mountain range.

368
00:43:31,120 --> 00:43:34,550
We are following the route
taken by Scott and Amundsen

369
00:43:34,640 --> 00:43:36,950
as they struggled
to become the first humans

370
00:43:37,040 --> 00:43:38,990
to reach the South Pole.

371
00:43:43,840 --> 00:43:45,870
They were travelling on foot

372
00:43:45,960 --> 00:43:50,390
and their first sight of these mountains
must have been daunting indeed.

373
00:43:50,480 --> 00:43:53,830
In front of them stretched
one of the world's longest ranges,

374
00:43:53,920 --> 00:43:55,830
spanning 2,000 miles

375
00:43:55,920 --> 00:43:58,790
from one side of the continent
to the other.

376
00:44:02,120 --> 00:44:04,750
The winds up here
are the fastest on Earth.

377
00:44:04,840 --> 00:44:07,550
They reach speeds of 200 miles an hour.

378
00:44:11,240 --> 00:44:14,830
An ice-capped mountain
bears the scars of the gales,

379
00:44:15,280 --> 00:44:18,470
bizarre sculptures carved
from solid ice.

380
00:44:29,920 --> 00:44:32,390
It's not only the ice that yields.

381
00:44:34,000 --> 00:44:37,790
This sculptured spire
is a remnant of a mountain,

382
00:44:37,880 --> 00:44:41,510
eroded from all sides
by the ferocious elements.

383
00:44:44,880 --> 00:44:50,230
Beyond, a wholly unexpected landscape,
the Dry Valleys.

384
00:44:56,840 --> 00:45:03,270
Only 1% of Antarctica is free of ice,
and most of that bare rock is here.

385
00:45:10,760 --> 00:45:13,590
The Dry Valleys are more like
the surface of Mars

386
00:45:13,720 --> 00:45:16,270
than is any other place on Earth.

387
00:45:24,600 --> 00:45:28,710
The floor is covered with
extraordinary natural sculptures,

388
00:45:28,800 --> 00:45:33,190
created by the same winds that help
to keep these valleys free of snow.

389
00:45:36,960 --> 00:45:40,870
Over time, entire boulders are
weathered from the inside out,

390
00:45:40,960 --> 00:45:43,510
until just a shell remains.

391
00:45:48,440 --> 00:45:52,590
At the head of these valleys,
the ice is making a break-through.

392
00:45:55,320 --> 00:45:59,950
Millions of tons are tumbling
in slow motion into the valley.

393
00:46:11,640 --> 00:46:15,630
These ice blocks
are the size of skyscrapers.

394
00:46:22,440 --> 00:46:25,550
And this is the Beardmore Glacier,

395
00:46:25,760 --> 00:46:29,830
which Scott and his men
somehow traversed on foot.

396
00:46:33,320 --> 00:46:35,670
It's over 100 miles long

397
00:46:35,760 --> 00:46:38,590
and one of the largest glaciers
on Earth.

398
00:46:43,920 --> 00:46:47,470
But nothing could have prepared
those early explorers

399
00:46:47,560 --> 00:46:50,230
for what they were about to encounter.

400
00:46:56,480 --> 00:46:58,590
The Antarctic ice cap,

401
00:46:58,680 --> 00:47:01,750
the largest expanse of ice
on the planet.

402
00:47:03,080 --> 00:47:05,390
It's three miles thick in places

403
00:47:05,480 --> 00:47:09,870
and imprisons 70%
of the world's fresh water.

404
00:47:12,800 --> 00:47:19,350
From here to the South Pole 700 miles
away, there is nothing but ice.

405
00:47:31,160 --> 00:47:34,990
I'm at the South Pole
at the end of my journey.

406
00:47:35,600 --> 00:47:37,750
Although it's mid-summer,

407
00:47:38,400 --> 00:47:43,590
the temperature here is a bone-chilling
35 degrees below freezing.

408
00:47:43,920 --> 00:47:47,790
It's exactly 100 years,
almost to the day,

409
00:47:47,880 --> 00:47:50,910
that the first human beings
stood right here,

410
00:47:51,480 --> 00:47:53,790
Amundsen followed by Scott.

411
00:47:55,000 --> 00:47:57,830
In those days, reaching the poles

412
00:47:57,920 --> 00:48:02,990
was regarded as the ultimate
in human endeavour and endurance,

413
00:48:03,080 --> 00:48:05,710
and a source of great national pride.

414
00:48:06,720 --> 00:48:11,190
Today the polar regions
have a rather different significance.

415
00:48:11,840 --> 00:48:17,310
Because now we've come to understand
that what happens here and in the north

416
00:48:18,000 --> 00:48:23,350
affects every one of us,
no matter where we live on this planet.

417
00:48:52,680 --> 00:48:55,430
The greatest challenge for
the team making Frozen Planet

418
00:48:55,520 --> 00:48:58,510
was the extreme remoteness
of their locations.

419
00:48:59,280 --> 00:49:01,510
Many of the shoots
lasted months at a time,

420
00:49:01,600 --> 00:49:04,670
and needed a number of crews
to join forces.

421
00:49:07,680 --> 00:49:10,630
One location that would require
such siege tactics

422
00:49:10,720 --> 00:49:14,190
was Mount Erebus,
Antarctica's most active volcano.

423
00:49:15,640 --> 00:49:19,270
This magical mountain
does not give up her secrets easily.

424
00:49:25,640 --> 00:49:27,750
To capture the full story
of Mount Erebus

425
00:49:27,840 --> 00:49:31,310
from top to bottom
required four different film crews.

426
00:49:34,520 --> 00:49:38,750
The cave team is dropped off
at 12, 000 feet, close to the crater.

427
00:49:43,040 --> 00:49:45,270
In howling winds and thin oxygen,

428
00:49:45,360 --> 00:49:48,870
their challenge is to find a way
into the volcano itself.

429
00:49:50,600 --> 00:49:52,470
They are venturing into the unknown.

430
00:49:53,840 --> 00:49:56,830
Somewhere below
are spectacular ice caves,

431
00:49:56,920 --> 00:49:59,110
melted out by volcanic steam.

432
00:49:59,600 --> 00:50:01,750
Getting the team safely underground

433
00:50:01,840 --> 00:50:04,430
is a relief for director
Chadden Hunter.

434
00:50:04,520 --> 00:50:06,470
Excellent, it's a lot warmer down here.

435
00:50:06,560 --> 00:50:09,350
It's freezing up there.
Minus 29.

436
00:50:09,440 --> 00:50:12,030
With him is cameraman Gavin Thurston.

437
00:50:12,120 --> 00:50:16,390
You sort of forget being in here,
you are actually inside a volcano.

438
00:50:17,440 --> 00:50:20,870
You know, above us there's...
and below us, there's bubbling lava.

439
00:50:20,960 --> 00:50:22,950
And you've got all these gases
seeping up through here,

440
00:50:23,040 --> 00:50:24,750
which is how these caves are made,

441
00:50:24,840 --> 00:50:27,150
so there's also increased
carbon dioxide in here.

442
00:50:28,360 --> 00:50:30,190
As the cave team
head deeper,

443
00:50:30,280 --> 00:50:33,150
dangerous volcanic gases
make breathing difficult.

444
00:50:33,240 --> 00:50:35,550
The clock is ticking.

445
00:50:35,680 --> 00:50:39,110
They will not have long
to find the caves of crystals.

446
00:50:41,480 --> 00:50:45,710
Above ground, the aerial team
is pushing for the summit of Erebus.

447
00:50:47,040 --> 00:50:50,950
Series producer Vanessa Berlowitz
directs from the front seat,

448
00:50:51,160 --> 00:50:53,350
while aerial cameraman Michael Kelem

449
00:50:53,440 --> 00:50:55,990
controls the camera
attached to the nose.

450
00:50:56,080 --> 00:50:57,750
We're going to be around 14,000 feet,

451
00:50:57,840 --> 00:50:59,710
we're going to be on the
performance limits of this aircraft.

452
00:51:00,040 --> 00:51:03,070
Any bad weather comes in up there,

453
00:51:03,160 --> 00:51:07,110
and you're pretty much screwed, really,
you've got to get off the mountain fast.

454
00:51:07,320 --> 00:51:10,510
Above 10,000 feet,
the pilot must breathe oxygen

455
00:51:10,600 --> 00:51:12,950
- through a plastic tube in his nostrils.
- Yeah, that's fine.

456
00:51:14,080 --> 00:51:17,150
Approaching the crater,
conditions do not look good.

457
00:51:17,240 --> 00:51:20,030
Today Erebus is belching out
steam and gases,

458
00:51:20,120 --> 00:51:22,430
making flying extremely risky.

459
00:51:23,200 --> 00:51:24,910
Up here, the air is so thin,

460
00:51:25,000 --> 00:51:28,070
the helicopter can't hover
and must keep moving.

461
00:51:29,600 --> 00:51:32,350
This is aerial filming
at its most extreme.

462
00:51:34,160 --> 00:51:36,590
They struggle to get a clear view.

463
00:51:39,320 --> 00:51:41,870
We're just coming up to 14,000 feet,

464
00:51:41,960 --> 00:51:43,670
you can actually look
right into the lava lake.

465
00:51:47,040 --> 00:51:49,510
Oh, that's looking really good,
Mike, just hold that there.

466
00:51:49,880 --> 00:51:53,070
The cameraman captures
a rare shot of the molten lava,

467
00:51:53,160 --> 00:51:55,310
but it's soon obscured again.

468
00:51:59,240 --> 00:52:00,950
The volcano is temperamental.

469
00:52:01,040 --> 00:52:05,310
The team have seized a rare opportunity
to see into its molten heart,

470
00:52:05,800 --> 00:52:08,310
but now they must descend to safety.

471
00:52:10,640 --> 00:52:15,150
As the weather closes in above,
the cave team are making progress below.

472
00:52:22,480 --> 00:52:26,270
It's Christmas Day, and the crew
are dressed for the occasion.

473
00:52:29,320 --> 00:52:31,030
Just watch my back on these icicles.

474
00:52:31,120 --> 00:52:33,670
-I don't want to snap that top one off.
-No problem.

475
00:52:33,760 --> 00:52:34,830
Oh !

476
00:52:35,520 --> 00:52:38,630
Right. How strong
are these pillars of ice, Matt?

477
00:52:40,000 --> 00:52:41,590
How big around is it?

478
00:52:41,680 --> 00:52:44,550
- It's about that round, about five...
- Really strong.

479
00:52:44,640 --> 00:52:47,710
So, if I squeeze past,
it's not going to snap it.

480
00:52:48,280 --> 00:52:52,150
Gavin is reassured
by advice from the scientist.

481
00:52:55,880 --> 00:52:58,830
Oh, Gavin!

482
00:53:00,440 --> 00:53:02,030
I'm sorry.

483
00:53:02,960 --> 00:53:07,270
That's terrible. Oh, look, look.
It fits perfectly, look. Look at that.

484
00:53:10,520 --> 00:53:13,670
Fortunately, these crystals
are made of frozen water

485
00:53:13,760 --> 00:53:15,830
and can grow back in weeks.

486
00:53:16,400 --> 00:53:19,190
You've got these beautiful,
clear, glass-like pillars,

487
00:53:19,520 --> 00:53:21,310
and right next to it,
this really delicate...

488
00:53:21,400 --> 00:53:23,950
Look how thin that filament is there.

489
00:53:27,320 --> 00:53:29,230
As the cave team
explore deeper,

490
00:53:29,320 --> 00:53:31,630
each chamber reveals ice crystals

491
00:53:31,720 --> 00:53:34,550
more strange
and spectacular than the last.

492
00:53:38,720 --> 00:53:42,150
No one on the team imagined
a single Antarctic mountain

493
00:53:42,240 --> 00:53:44,510
could house so many wonders.

494
00:53:48,480 --> 00:53:52,230
Down at the foot of Mount Erebus,
a third crew, the dive team,

495
00:53:52,320 --> 00:53:54,950
plan to explore
the volcano's lower slopes,

496
00:53:55,040 --> 00:53:57,830
which extend beneath the frozen sea.

497
00:53:58,440 --> 00:54:01,470
On board is underwater cameraman
Hugh Miller.

498
00:54:01,680 --> 00:54:04,310
The problem is we don't actually know
what's under the ice here.

499
00:54:04,760 --> 00:54:07,390
So who knows?
It's a bit of an adventure.

500
00:54:08,880 --> 00:54:10,950
Old-fashioned tools
still work best.

501
00:54:11,040 --> 00:54:13,790
First, a hand chisel
to create an opening,

502
00:54:13,880 --> 00:54:16,430
then a saw to widen the hole.

503
00:54:18,600 --> 00:54:20,990
Ice-diving in the coldest waters
on the planet

504
00:54:21,080 --> 00:54:23,270
should be taken extremely seriously.

505
00:54:23,800 --> 00:54:26,270
This dive's going to be a lot of things

506
00:54:26,560 --> 00:54:28,990
and warm is not on that list.

507
00:54:29,560 --> 00:54:31,630
Insulatedsuits will keep them alive

508
00:54:31,720 --> 00:54:33,710
under the ice for only 60 minutes.

509
00:54:35,200 --> 00:54:38,750
Once the helicopter departs,
there's no margin for error.

510
00:54:43,160 --> 00:54:46,590
The dive team begin to explore
the lower slopes of Erebus,

511
00:54:46,680 --> 00:54:49,990
discovering a hidden world
rarely seen by humans.

512
00:54:52,880 --> 00:54:56,190
Patrolling the icy shores
of the volcano are killer whales,

513
00:54:56,280 --> 00:54:58,430
the most southerly in the world.

514
00:54:59,880 --> 00:55:02,710
Tracking them from above
is the Orca team.

515
00:55:05,960 --> 00:55:08,310
They need a helicopter
to get ahead of the whales

516
00:55:08,400 --> 00:55:11,110
and to land them on the fragile sea-ice.

517
00:55:13,440 --> 00:55:16,790
Cameraman Jamie McPherson
must pick his spot carefully.

518
00:55:16,880 --> 00:55:18,790
His aim is to get the cameras

519
00:55:18,880 --> 00:55:23,030
as close to the killer whales
as possible without disturbing them.

520
00:55:26,160 --> 00:55:29,750
He uses a film camera
to capture the action in slow motion.

521
00:55:37,400 --> 00:55:39,710
And orcas come right by him!

522
00:55:42,080 --> 00:55:43,830
Even in the extreme cold,

523
00:55:43,920 --> 00:55:46,990
a film camera proves to be
rugged and reliable,

524
00:55:47,720 --> 00:55:50,510
provided there's enough film
in the camera.

525
00:55:53,040 --> 00:55:55,070
- End of the roll.
- No!

526
00:55:57,600 --> 00:55:59,910
I got him coming out,
I just didn't get him going back in.

527
00:56:08,520 --> 00:56:09,790
Below the sea-ice,

528
00:56:09,880 --> 00:56:13,070
the dive team is setting up
an underwater studio.

529
00:56:13,160 --> 00:56:16,550
Using a range of waterproof lights
and time-lapse cameras,

530
00:56:16,640 --> 00:56:21,110
they hope to capture the growth
of bizarre underwater ice formations.

531
00:56:29,000 --> 00:56:30,190
Over the coming weeks,

532
00:56:30,280 --> 00:56:33,710
the dive team would go
below the ice over 100 times

533
00:56:33,800 --> 00:56:36,070
to film the extraordinary secret world

534
00:56:36,160 --> 00:56:38,870
on the lower flanks of Mount Erebus.

535
00:56:40,520 --> 00:56:44,110
On top of the ice,
the Orca team has repositioned.

536
00:56:44,200 --> 00:56:47,430
Their new goal is to get
underwater shots of the whales.

537
00:56:48,560 --> 00:56:51,150
They don't dare
to get in the water with Orcas,

538
00:56:51,280 --> 00:56:54,350
attaching a camera to a pole
is a safer option,

539
00:56:54,520 --> 00:56:56,750
provided the whales
aren't put off by it.

540
00:57:01,960 --> 00:57:05,550
No one is prepared
for what happens next.

541
00:57:06,280 --> 00:57:08,590
Tell Scotty what you just saw.

542
00:57:08,680 --> 00:57:10,430
Hello!

543
00:57:11,960 --> 00:57:13,950
The entire podarrives.

544
00:57:33,360 --> 00:57:36,230
Eyeball to eyeball,
this is about as close

545
00:57:36,320 --> 00:57:39,150
to killer whales
as it's possible to get.

546
00:57:39,240 --> 00:57:43,070
By using multiple crews and cameras,
the Frozen Planet team

547
00:57:43,160 --> 00:57:45,990
have been able to capture
the full Erebus story,

548
00:57:46,080 --> 00:57:47,910
from the fire at its crater

549
00:57:48,000 --> 00:57:51,190
down to the whales
that patrol its frozen shores.

550
00:57:53,280 --> 00:57:56,830
It's quite a privilege
to feel whale breath on your face.

551
00:57:56,920 --> 00:57:58,190
Oh!

