1
00:00:37,720 --> 00:00:40,110
Summer in the polar regions

2
00:00:40,200 --> 00:00:42,150
and the sun never sets.

3
00:00:44,240 --> 00:00:47,990
Imagine a single day
that lasts for months.

4
00:00:51,560 --> 00:00:54,830
Some polar animals
will face great challenges

5
00:00:54,920 --> 00:00:57,670
as their ice world vanishes around them.

6
00:01:00,240 --> 00:01:03,510
Others must use
this special time wisely,

7
00:01:03,600 --> 00:01:06,710
for summer's riches will not last.

8
00:01:34,080 --> 00:01:38,790
The summer is just beginning
and the increasing power of the sun

9
00:01:38,880 --> 00:01:42,510
is creating a spectacular new landscape.

10
00:01:50,680 --> 00:01:56,110
This melting ice sheet in the Arctic
is 150 miles long

11
00:01:56,200 --> 00:01:58,590
with a thousand waterfalls.

12
00:02:04,040 --> 00:02:10,190
Vast expanses of ice that were
once stone-still have come to life.

13
00:02:34,760 --> 00:02:39,710
The polar bear's world is melting away
under the constant summer sun.

14
00:02:48,960 --> 00:02:51,310
As the season advances,

15
00:02:51,400 --> 00:02:54,830
the frozen surface of the ocean
disintegrates.

16
00:02:54,920 --> 00:02:58,510
Soon, the ice here
will have totally vanished.

17
00:03:08,000 --> 00:03:12,670
The polar bear family have to adapt
to their rapidly changing home.

18
00:03:19,440 --> 00:03:23,750
For the two cubs,
this is a whole new watery world.

19
00:03:24,120 --> 00:03:27,630
It's the first time they have seen
the sea-ice break up.

20
00:03:34,280 --> 00:03:36,230
They're only six months old

21
00:03:36,320 --> 00:03:40,070
and will be dependent on their mother
for another two years.

22
00:03:44,680 --> 00:03:47,110
They have much to learn.

23
00:03:55,680 --> 00:03:57,830
Their first swimming lesson,

24
00:03:59,040 --> 00:04:01,710
and they're not sure that they want it.

25
00:04:12,440 --> 00:04:16,070
For their mother,
swimming is second nature.

26
00:04:19,120 --> 00:04:24,390
But the cubs still prefer to have ice
beneath their feet whenever they can.

27
00:04:35,920 --> 00:04:40,030
Soon, it will be impossible
to avoid the water.

28
00:04:45,360 --> 00:04:48,790
This lone male has lived through
a dozen summers

29
00:04:48,880 --> 00:04:51,390
and is perfectly at home in the sea.

30
00:04:57,680 --> 00:05:00,430
He can swim up to 50 miles a day.

31
00:05:02,560 --> 00:05:07,270
He's hungry and he's searching
this ice maze for seals.

32
00:05:17,280 --> 00:05:21,630
But travelling across this
increasingly fragile ice-scape

33
00:05:21,720 --> 00:05:25,470
is hard work for an animal
weighing over half a tonne.

34
00:05:38,440 --> 00:05:42,270
It's also harder to hunt
when you have to swim.

35
00:05:43,400 --> 00:05:47,230
In open water,
the odds are in the seals' favour.

36
00:06:06,920 --> 00:06:09,950
Lean months lie ahead
for the polar bears.

37
00:06:10,040 --> 00:06:15,510
They will have to adopt new
hunting strategies or risk starvation.

38
00:06:21,320 --> 00:06:24,950
The northern part of the earth
is now tilting towards the sun

39
00:06:25,040 --> 00:06:29,510
and all around the Arctic
the sea-ice continues its retreat.

40
00:06:39,400 --> 00:06:44,950
The last remnants of the ice-world
drift with the wind and the tides.

41
00:07:05,480 --> 00:07:09,070
The sun's heat may be gentle
at these latitudes,

42
00:07:09,160 --> 00:07:12,390
but it is continuous for 24 hours a day

43
00:07:12,480 --> 00:07:16,030
and it carves the ice
into magical shapes.

44
00:07:32,080 --> 00:07:36,990
Those that need ice have to visit
the glacier fronts to find it.

45
00:07:42,360 --> 00:07:45,310
A comfortable bed is hard to come by.

46
00:07:55,120 --> 00:07:59,590
A polar bear's fur is so dense
that water is easily shaken off.

47
00:08:06,240 --> 00:08:09,550
And ice absorbs water like a towel.

48
00:08:31,160 --> 00:08:32,630
That's better!

49
00:08:36,440 --> 00:08:39,190
There's now little chance
of catching seals

50
00:08:39,280 --> 00:08:42,790
and this bear may not eat again
until the end of summer.

51
00:08:47,080 --> 00:08:50,670
It's better to save energy
and doze in the sun.

52
00:09:00,800 --> 00:09:06,630
The warmth of the sun's rays is now
bringing the Arctic lands back to life.

53
00:10:05,920 --> 00:10:07,830
Red phalaropes.

54
00:10:07,920 --> 00:10:10,310
They've flown all the way
from the tropics

55
00:10:10,400 --> 00:10:13,470
to feed in these rich Arctic waters.

56
00:10:13,960 --> 00:10:17,430
They stir up the tiny creatures
that are now flourishing here

57
00:10:17,520 --> 00:10:19,910
with a special spinning dance.

58
00:10:26,040 --> 00:10:30,590
All excellent fuel, as they hurry
to rear the next generation.

59
00:10:34,440 --> 00:10:38,830
The Arctic terns have made an
even longer journey to breed here.

60
00:10:38,920 --> 00:10:42,710
They have flown 11, 000 miles
from the Antarctic.

61
00:10:45,640 --> 00:10:48,550
Their newly hatched chicks
will need to grow fast

62
00:10:48,640 --> 00:10:50,550
if they're to accompany their parents

63
00:10:50,640 --> 00:10:53,670
when they return south
in only six weeks' time.

64
00:10:57,920 --> 00:11:02,270
An eider duck has chosen to nest
in the centre of the tern colony,

65
00:11:02,360 --> 00:11:05,470
hardly a tranquil place
to raise your young.

66
00:11:09,480 --> 00:11:13,390
But the noisy neighbours
have a feisty attitude to life

67
00:11:13,480 --> 00:11:15,710
and that can be very valuable.

68
00:11:28,520 --> 00:11:30,910
A hungry bear looking for a meal

69
00:11:31,000 --> 00:11:34,670
can destroy hundreds of nests
in a single raid.

70
00:11:35,200 --> 00:11:38,390
Defensive squadrons of terns
take off immediately.

71
00:11:46,640 --> 00:11:49,670
Sharp beaks stab down from above.

72
00:11:49,760 --> 00:11:53,510
The bear has nothing in his armoury
that can cope with this.

73
00:12:09,320 --> 00:12:12,710
The terns have drawn blood
from his muzzle.

74
00:12:22,160 --> 00:12:25,310
He leaves, in search of an easier meal.

75
00:12:29,400 --> 00:12:33,230
The eiders survive
thanks to their choice of neighbours.

76
00:12:40,680 --> 00:12:43,790
And the ducklings begin
their sprint to maturity.

77
00:12:48,560 --> 00:12:50,670
Fishing continues around the clock

78
00:12:50,760 --> 00:12:55,310
as the terns race to rear their young
before the return of the freeze.

79
00:13:05,200 --> 00:13:10,070
So the rich waters of summer
fuel the breeding of all these visitors

80
00:13:10,520 --> 00:13:13,470
and enable them to build up
the reserves they will need

81
00:13:13,560 --> 00:13:15,990
for the long return journey south.

82
00:13:28,880 --> 00:13:34,590
Inland, the winter snows have gone,
revealing a vast, treeless wilderness.

83
00:13:42,320 --> 00:13:47,510
The male snowy owl is finding
plenty of lemmings to bring to his mate.

84
00:13:52,200 --> 00:13:54,390
But they're not just for her.

85
00:14:02,480 --> 00:14:05,470
She is brooding their
rather scruffy young.

86
00:14:07,720 --> 00:14:10,270
She tears the meal
into beak-sized chunks

87
00:14:10,360 --> 00:14:12,790
that the owlets can swallow whole.

88
00:14:13,080 --> 00:14:15,830
Each of them can eat two lemmings a day.

89
00:14:26,480 --> 00:14:28,870
The male has no time to rest.

90
00:14:28,960 --> 00:14:32,310
Over the course of the summer,
he will have to provide his family

91
00:14:32,400 --> 00:14:34,950
with over a thousand lemmings.

92
00:14:38,040 --> 00:14:41,710
The hungry owlets keep the adults
working around the clock.

93
00:14:45,480 --> 00:14:49,630
The arctic summer may be short
but the days are long.

94
00:14:51,280 --> 00:14:55,030
Everyone must take advantage
of the 24-hour daylight,

95
00:14:55,120 --> 00:14:57,830
none more so than
the owls' tiny neighbours,

96
00:14:57,920 --> 00:15:00,230
the Lapland buntings.

97
00:15:15,000 --> 00:15:17,950
Both parents feed their growing family
continuously.

98
00:15:29,560 --> 00:15:32,190
A mere 10 days after hatching

99
00:15:32,280 --> 00:15:35,350
and they will all have left
in record time.

100
00:15:39,320 --> 00:15:41,790
The last needs a little encouragement.

101
00:15:50,760 --> 00:15:53,390
The owlets have also left their nest

102
00:15:53,480 --> 00:15:56,870
and turned into
football-sized balls of fluff.

103
00:15:56,960 --> 00:16:01,270
But they still depend on their parents
for food and protection.

104
00:16:07,160 --> 00:16:08,350
A skua.

105
00:16:09,760 --> 00:16:12,590
Their mother's talons
are her best weapons.

106
00:16:36,000 --> 00:16:39,390
The owlets are dangerously exposed
out on the tundra,

107
00:16:39,480 --> 00:16:42,310
so they must hurry to change
from balls of fluff

108
00:16:42,400 --> 00:16:44,510
to fully-feathered adults.

109
00:16:44,600 --> 00:16:48,030
And to do that they need more lemmings.

110
00:16:58,080 --> 00:17:00,950
A lemming doesn't last long these days.

111
00:17:10,320 --> 00:17:14,630
Times are harder for the wolves here
in the high Arctic.

112
00:17:30,320 --> 00:17:34,470
The cubs are now six weeks old
and increasingly hungry.

113
00:17:46,600 --> 00:17:50,510
The adults have to struggle
to feed their growing family.

114
00:17:56,040 --> 00:17:59,030
Somewhere on this vast
expanse of tundra

115
00:17:59,120 --> 00:18:01,670
there must be larger prey.

116
00:18:13,760 --> 00:18:16,750
Musk oxen are on the move.

117
00:18:23,720 --> 00:18:27,270
They're heading into the valleys,
where the brief summer rains

118
00:18:27,360 --> 00:18:29,350
will produce fresh grazing.

119
00:18:41,000 --> 00:18:43,550
This is an opportunity
that must be seized,

120
00:18:43,640 --> 00:18:46,630
even if it means travelling
80 miles in a day.

121
00:18:56,320 --> 00:18:58,590
Their task is a formidable one.

122
00:19:00,880 --> 00:19:03,510
Musk oxen are immensely powerful

123
00:19:04,360 --> 00:19:06,470
and their sharp horns can kill.

124
00:19:15,960 --> 00:19:19,870
A heavily armoured bull
would be an unwise choice.

125
00:19:20,520 --> 00:19:24,470
Even two wolves would find it
a struggle to bring it down.

126
00:19:32,120 --> 00:19:33,310
A calf.

127
00:19:35,040 --> 00:19:36,430
Much easier.

128
00:19:57,920 --> 00:20:02,470
The two wolves work together to split
the herd and isolate their victim.

129
00:20:23,320 --> 00:20:27,110
It seems that the wolf cubs
will at last eat well.

130
00:20:32,120 --> 00:20:33,950
But the herd regroups.

131
00:20:42,520 --> 00:20:44,870
The cavalry ride to the rescue.

132
00:20:50,360 --> 00:20:54,830
The whole herd encircles the calf
with a protective wall of horns.

133
00:20:59,920 --> 00:21:04,030
For the musk oxen,
it's all for one and one for all.

134
00:21:18,080 --> 00:21:23,510
For the wolves, another attack
would be not only futile but dangerous.

135
00:21:26,720 --> 00:21:28,670
They have spent a lot of energy

136
00:21:28,760 --> 00:21:31,310
and have nothing whatever
to show for it.

137
00:21:46,000 --> 00:21:50,710
Their failure will be felt
most keenly back at the den.

138
00:22:03,640 --> 00:22:06,590
They have nothing to take back
to the family.

139
00:22:27,160 --> 00:22:31,590
The pack are forced to move on
in search of better hunting.

140
00:22:37,640 --> 00:22:39,870
They must find something soon

141
00:22:39,960 --> 00:22:43,550
in this vast wilderness
to feed their growing family.

142
00:22:45,880 --> 00:22:48,910
The brief Arctic summer is almost over.

143
00:23:08,280 --> 00:23:13,550
At the southern end of the planet,
the long summer days transform life,

144
00:23:13,640 --> 00:23:18,470
just as they do in the north,
but the cast here is very different.

145
00:23:26,720 --> 00:23:28,230
King penguins.

146
00:23:30,040 --> 00:23:34,950
A parent, returning with food,
must recognise its chick's call

147
00:23:35,040 --> 00:23:38,670
amongst a chorus of 400,000 birds.

148
00:24:01,400 --> 00:24:03,510
Huge colonies like this one

149
00:24:03,600 --> 00:24:07,270
are found all along the north coast
of South Georgia.

150
00:24:11,600 --> 00:24:15,070
King penguins are active
throughout the long summer days,

151
00:24:15,160 --> 00:24:19,230
so they have to deal with
an uncharacteristic polar problem.

152
00:24:29,200 --> 00:24:34,510
By midday, the temperature can reach
a sizzling 17 degrees centigrade.

153
00:24:38,920 --> 00:24:41,750
Any effort can lead to overheating.

154
00:24:42,160 --> 00:24:45,190
It's best not to overexert oneself.

155
00:24:48,640 --> 00:24:51,670
The heavily insulated penguins
stretch out

156
00:24:51,760 --> 00:24:54,510
so their naked feet
can cool in the breeze.

157
00:25:07,160 --> 00:25:10,190
Their gigantic neighbours
use a different approach.

158
00:25:10,800 --> 00:25:14,990
Wet sand cools the backs
of these elephant seals

159
00:25:15,080 --> 00:25:17,630
and also acts as a sunscreen.

160
00:25:27,280 --> 00:25:30,910
The chicks, in their downy coats
that have kept them warm all winter,

161
00:25:31,000 --> 00:25:34,030
are in even greater danger
of overheating.

162
00:25:50,960 --> 00:25:53,870
It will be two months
before they can swim properly,

163
00:25:53,960 --> 00:25:57,430
but a dip in the shallow river
brings a little relief.

164
00:26:15,800 --> 00:26:19,750
There is, however, another way
to cool the blood.

165
00:26:23,920 --> 00:26:28,550
This murky pool has become
a penguin spa.

166
00:26:36,120 --> 00:26:40,710
It's a great way to cool the feet,
but there is no reason to stop there.

167
00:26:40,800 --> 00:26:44,470
You can indulge yourself
with the full treatment.

168
00:26:59,280 --> 00:27:01,710
Mud, glorious mud!

169
00:27:15,640 --> 00:27:17,350
For the fully feathered adults,

170
00:27:17,440 --> 00:27:20,310
there's a cleaner,
more invigorating option.

171
00:27:26,160 --> 00:27:29,470
The bracing waters
of the Southern Ocean.

172
00:28:32,400 --> 00:28:36,190
The 100-mile long island
of South Georgia

173
00:28:36,280 --> 00:28:39,430
lies on the northern fringe
of Antarctica.

174
00:28:47,960 --> 00:28:51,150
Ice-free all year,
its rich coastal waters

175
00:28:51,240 --> 00:28:55,430
make it a popular breeding destination
for all beach lovers.

176
00:29:05,000 --> 00:29:11,110
In summer, 95% of the world's population
of Antarctic fur seals come here.

177
00:29:13,160 --> 00:29:14,430
Packed tightly together,

178
00:29:14,520 --> 00:29:18,710
they form one of the densest
gatherings of marine mammals on Earth.

179
00:29:23,200 --> 00:29:26,470
The island's beaches are filling fast
and will soon be crammed

180
00:29:26,560 --> 00:29:30,230
with five million
of these summer visitors.

181
00:29:32,440 --> 00:29:37,190
Space is at a premium, as every female
needs a dry patch of sand

182
00:29:37,280 --> 00:29:40,070
the size of a beach towel for herself.

183
00:29:47,600 --> 00:29:49,710
And for good reason.

184
00:29:55,800 --> 00:30:00,790
Virtually all of them give birth
within just 10 days.

185
00:30:14,000 --> 00:30:17,630
It's crucial to establish
a strong bond with your baby

186
00:30:17,720 --> 00:30:19,870
in such a crowded colony.

187
00:30:28,240 --> 00:30:31,870
The pups grow quickly on rich,
high-fat milk.

188
00:30:42,280 --> 00:30:45,750
After giving birth,
the females are ready to mate,

189
00:30:45,840 --> 00:30:50,430
so each male guards up to 15 of them
in his small patch of beach.

190
00:30:51,160 --> 00:30:55,870
A bull may only hold a territory
for one season in his entire life.

191
00:30:57,600 --> 00:31:02,230
So, when a challenger arrives,
he will risk everything to retain it.

192
00:31:35,680 --> 00:31:38,630
Their sharp teeth
inflict terrible injuries.

193
00:31:54,600 --> 00:31:58,390
Many bulls die from exhaustion
after these fights.

194
00:32:03,800 --> 00:32:07,830
In the heat of the battle,
the pups are also in real danger.

195
00:32:25,400 --> 00:32:27,910
The defeated bull makes his escape,

196
00:32:28,000 --> 00:32:31,990
but the colony still suffers
from the side-effects of the battle.

197
00:32:40,120 --> 00:32:44,070
Many of the pups get lost
in the violence and confusion.

198
00:33:21,000 --> 00:33:23,950
This time, there is a happy ending.

199
00:33:33,320 --> 00:33:34,830
As summer progresses,

200
00:33:34,920 --> 00:33:38,670
even more of the Southern Ocean
is gradually opening up.

201
00:33:47,120 --> 00:33:49,750
The summer melt, as it moves south,

202
00:33:49,840 --> 00:33:52,790
arrives first
at the Antarctic Peninsula,

203
00:33:52,880 --> 00:33:55,550
the most northern tip of the continent.

204
00:33:59,200 --> 00:34:03,430
As the ice retreats,
a dramatic 500-mile-long coastline

205
00:34:03,520 --> 00:34:07,310
is revealed for the first time
in seven months.

206
00:34:14,480 --> 00:34:19,950
This new seascape is home to one of
the most numerous mammals on the planet.

207
00:34:22,840 --> 00:34:24,270
Crabeater seals,

208
00:34:24,360 --> 00:34:28,590
over 15 million live here
amongst the drifting ice floes.

209
00:34:39,640 --> 00:34:43,430
They owe their existence here
to living organisms so small

210
00:34:43,520 --> 00:34:44,990
you might hardly notice them.

211
00:34:48,680 --> 00:34:52,950
The underside of the sea-ice
is stained by algae.

212
00:34:53,800 --> 00:34:56,110
These microscopic plants

213
00:34:56,200 --> 00:34:59,630
support the most important
Antarctic creatures of all.

214
00:35:01,840 --> 00:35:02,990
Krill.

215
00:35:04,800 --> 00:35:08,830
They have been grazing on
the algal layer throughout the winter.

216
00:35:10,640 --> 00:35:15,030
As the ice melts, more of the algae
are released into the water.

217
00:35:18,000 --> 00:35:21,950
Both algae and krill flourish
in the summer sun.

218
00:35:28,440 --> 00:35:32,150
The krill collect the algae
in the sieve-like basket

219
00:35:32,240 --> 00:35:35,910
formed by the interlocking hairs
between their front legs.

220
00:35:44,760 --> 00:35:49,710
There are 300 million tonnes of krill
in the Southern Ocean,

221
00:35:50,240 --> 00:35:54,950
with a greater combined weight than that
of any other animal on the planet.

222
00:36:00,360 --> 00:36:04,190
Almost all the animals of the Antarctic
depend on krill,

223
00:36:05,000 --> 00:36:07,510
including its giants.

224
00:36:09,240 --> 00:36:10,830
Humpback whales.

225
00:36:21,280 --> 00:36:24,430
They drive the krill to the surface

226
00:36:24,520 --> 00:36:29,350
and then strain it from the water
with the baleen sieves in their mouths.

227
00:36:46,440 --> 00:36:51,550
Humpbacks often feed in teams,
so the overspill from one huge mouth

228
00:36:51,640 --> 00:36:54,190
can be collected by another just behind.

229
00:37:29,880 --> 00:37:33,150
The abundance of krill
attracts other visitors

230
00:37:33,240 --> 00:37:35,510
to the peninsula in the summer.

231
00:37:37,400 --> 00:37:39,990
Antarctic minke whales.

232
00:37:40,800 --> 00:37:46,590
Their pointed heads and short dorsal
fins give them speed and endurance.

233
00:37:53,760 --> 00:37:55,870
And they need both.

234
00:38:03,320 --> 00:38:05,710
There are other whales here, too.

235
00:38:08,440 --> 00:38:09,670
Killers!

236
00:38:16,160 --> 00:38:19,670
This is an extended family
of mothers and their young.

237
00:38:22,360 --> 00:38:27,950
And a male with a huge dorsal fin
almost two metres high.

238
00:38:39,520 --> 00:38:41,750
A lone minke whale.

239
00:38:47,600 --> 00:38:51,270
It's just what this group
of killer whales are looking for.

240
00:38:54,200 --> 00:38:57,630
Working as a team,
as they have done for decades,

241
00:38:57,720 --> 00:39:01,310
they fan out across the strait
in search of their quarry.

242
00:39:12,120 --> 00:39:13,750
And they've found it.

243
00:39:13,840 --> 00:39:18,510
The minke races away,
pursued by outriders on each flank.

244
00:39:47,400 --> 00:39:50,150
Terrified, the minke
heads for the shore.

245
00:39:51,920 --> 00:39:56,190
It's so desperate to escape
it almost beaches itself.

246
00:40:06,080 --> 00:40:08,830
It makes a desperate break for freedom.

247
00:40:18,600 --> 00:40:21,030
Two hours and 20 miles later,

248
00:40:21,120 --> 00:40:24,110
the minke is still alive
and swimming strongly.

249
00:40:25,720 --> 00:40:29,110
It's only real defence is its endurance.

250
00:40:29,640 --> 00:40:31,430
But the killers work as a team,

251
00:40:31,520 --> 00:40:34,710
with fresh ones replacing
the outriders in relays.

252
00:40:47,960 --> 00:40:53,310
And as the minke tires,
the battering and the biting begins.

253
00:41:06,800 --> 00:41:11,390
Sea birds are attracted by the smell
of fresh blood rising from the water.

254
00:41:30,240 --> 00:41:32,910
The killers try to flip the minke over.

255
00:41:33,000 --> 00:41:36,150
If they can manage to keep
its blowhole underwater,

256
00:41:36,240 --> 00:41:37,950
it will drown.

257
00:41:42,360 --> 00:41:46,830
One forces the minke's whole body
down below the surface.

258
00:42:02,320 --> 00:42:04,750
And then, the final strike.

259
00:42:09,320 --> 00:42:12,790
The team drag the minke under
for the last time

260
00:42:13,200 --> 00:42:16,030
and the hunters, finally, can feed.

261
00:42:32,800 --> 00:42:36,390
As the summer advances,
the most southerly stretches

262
00:42:36,480 --> 00:42:40,030
of the Antarctic Ocean
are released from the ice.

263
00:42:49,600 --> 00:42:53,070
Adélie penguins have been
feeding in the open ocean.

264
00:43:05,440 --> 00:43:07,750
The most southerly of all penguins,

265
00:43:07,840 --> 00:43:10,270
they're returning
to the Antarctic continent

266
00:43:10,360 --> 00:43:12,590
with stomachs full of krill.

267
00:44:04,680 --> 00:44:09,830
The sea-ice has finally retreated
all the way back to the beach,

268
00:44:09,920 --> 00:44:14,310
so the walk back to the colony
is as short as it will ever be,

269
00:44:15,120 --> 00:44:17,630
crucial for the half million
penguins here

270
00:44:17,720 --> 00:44:21,870
who are hurrying to raise their chicks
before the freeze returns.

271
00:44:25,400 --> 00:44:28,750
Most of the pairs have two chicks
to care for.

272
00:44:31,640 --> 00:44:36,830
Each chick requires nearly 30 kilograms
of food before it's fully grown.

273
00:44:41,400 --> 00:44:43,390
Most of their catch is krill

274
00:44:43,480 --> 00:44:46,430
and Adélie penguins consume a staggering

275
00:44:46,520 --> 00:44:49,550
one and a half million tonnes of it
a year.

276
00:44:57,560 --> 00:45:01,390
There are no land-based predators
in Antarctica.

277
00:45:03,880 --> 00:45:07,070
The threat here comes from the skies.

278
00:45:18,040 --> 00:45:19,990
A South Polar skua.

279
00:45:39,560 --> 00:45:43,070
An unguarded chick is an easy catch.

280
00:46:11,600 --> 00:46:13,870
Nothing can save the chick now.

281
00:46:31,560 --> 00:46:36,470
But now the parents can focus
all their attention on the second.

282
00:46:57,120 --> 00:47:01,110
Only half of these chicks
will survive to adulthood.

283
00:47:01,520 --> 00:47:05,910
But there are thousands more parents
with young in this huge colony.

284
00:47:08,880 --> 00:47:10,830
Parents that cannot rest,

285
00:47:10,920 --> 00:47:13,430
for their young must be fit and strong

286
00:47:13,520 --> 00:47:17,630
if they're to survive the dangers
that autumn will bring.

287
00:47:53,240 --> 00:47:56,110
In summer, the frozen oceans melt

288
00:47:56,200 --> 00:48:00,030
and the polar animals disperse
to feed amongst the broken ice.

289
00:48:01,960 --> 00:48:05,110
So, even finding them
in this vast expanse of sea

290
00:48:05,200 --> 00:48:08,230
and drifting ice floes wouldn't be easy.

291
00:48:14,040 --> 00:48:17,790
In the Arctic, the aim was to
get close to a polar bear family

292
00:48:17,880 --> 00:48:20,430
and film them in this
fast-melting world.

293
00:48:28,280 --> 00:48:33,110
Firstly, the team had to use a ship
capable of breaking through the pack ice

294
00:48:33,200 --> 00:48:37,110
around the 2,000-mile-long coastline
of Svalbard.

295
00:48:40,280 --> 00:48:43,710
Producer Miles Barton
and cameraman Ted Giffords

296
00:48:43,800 --> 00:48:47,990
are checking out fjords
known to be frequented by bears.

297
00:48:49,920 --> 00:48:51,430
We've just seen a bear
that was walking around

298
00:48:51,520 --> 00:48:53,190
in front of a glacier over there.

299
00:48:53,280 --> 00:48:56,390
We've just arrived, so this is
kind of a test more than anything,

300
00:48:56,480 --> 00:48:58,030
but we're going to go and see
if we can film it.

301
00:48:59,360 --> 00:49:02,990
We're seeing how smoothly
we can make this operation work.

302
00:49:10,600 --> 00:49:15,030
Stay on Channel Six. Can you
give me directions to the bear, please?

303
00:49:15,840 --> 00:49:19,590
The plan is that
the team's stabilised aerial camera,

304
00:49:19,680 --> 00:49:21,470
now fitted to the speedboat,

305
00:49:21,560 --> 00:49:24,990
will give perfectly stable shots
of the bear swimming.

306
00:49:25,960 --> 00:49:27,950
Spin this around
or we'll lose it.

307
00:49:28,040 --> 00:49:29,430
The fellow's over here, yeah?

308
00:49:29,520 --> 00:49:32,310
- Got him, yeah.
- I can't get any tighter.

309
00:49:32,400 --> 00:49:34,150
You shoot it?

310
00:49:37,200 --> 00:49:38,670
Wahey!

311
00:49:40,720 --> 00:49:44,390
That's nice.
Nice sparkle, nice liquid look.

312
00:49:44,480 --> 00:49:46,550
- Going to let him go.
- Okay, cut.

313
00:49:50,080 --> 00:49:52,030
After their initial success,

314
00:49:52,120 --> 00:49:54,430
the weather takes a turn for the worse.

315
00:49:55,800 --> 00:49:57,950
We're used to the Baja.

316
00:49:58,800 --> 00:50:02,910
For five days, there are
no more polar bears to be found.

317
00:50:05,560 --> 00:50:11,190
The captain decides to take a break
and parks up in the pack ice.

318
00:50:13,520 --> 00:50:18,750
But after all that fruitless searching
by the crew, a bear visits them.

319
00:50:23,000 --> 00:50:25,830
A large and inquisitive adult male.

320
00:50:32,560 --> 00:50:35,070
So, the team decides to follow him.

321
00:50:38,760 --> 00:50:41,350
The open water between boat and bear

322
00:50:41,440 --> 00:50:45,470
means the crew can safely film
from surprisingly close range

323
00:50:45,560 --> 00:50:47,030
without disturbing him.

324
00:50:47,120 --> 00:50:49,590
That's nice. Oops.

325
00:50:53,120 --> 00:50:54,790
The bear is so relaxed

326
00:50:54,880 --> 00:50:57,750
he even begins to hunt
right alongside them.

327
00:50:59,160 --> 00:51:01,870
He's looking for a seal inside.

328
00:51:01,960 --> 00:51:03,950
But he's just completely ignoring us.

329
00:51:04,040 --> 00:51:07,030
Just hold it there.
Just hold it there for a minute.

330
00:51:07,720 --> 00:51:10,310
He's going to climb up. Ready?

331
00:51:13,360 --> 00:51:15,510
That's a big bear.

332
00:51:20,320 --> 00:51:22,630
That's pretty good, pretty good.

333
00:51:23,200 --> 00:51:25,790
The closest we've been
to a polar bear so far.

334
00:51:27,760 --> 00:51:30,710
Despite this remarkably close encounter,

335
00:51:31,400 --> 00:51:35,310
the team still wants to film
a family of bears.

336
00:51:35,400 --> 00:51:39,190
These female and two cubs
to starboard side.

337
00:51:39,280 --> 00:51:40,710
She's at two...

338
00:51:40,800 --> 00:51:42,350
There's good news
on the radio.

339
00:51:43,560 --> 00:51:46,470
Oh, there's a cub.
Yeah, I've seen the cubs.

340
00:51:47,520 --> 00:51:51,630
They're looking straight at
us. Look at that. That's amazing.

341
00:51:52,120 --> 00:51:54,510
As the mother looks
distinctly hungry,

342
00:51:54,600 --> 00:51:59,350
they will need to keep at least 15 feet
of open water between her and the boat.

343
00:52:01,120 --> 00:52:03,310
Having a good look at us.

344
00:52:04,200 --> 00:52:05,430
Oh, look at them,
look at the cubs.

345
00:52:05,520 --> 00:52:07,550
Yeah.

346
00:52:13,200 --> 00:52:15,870
Jason, just go when you need to.

347
00:52:17,320 --> 00:52:19,950
Oh, here she comes. Bloody hell.

348
00:52:22,280 --> 00:52:25,390
Mother bears are always
desperate for food for their cubs,

349
00:52:25,480 --> 00:52:28,230
so the crew could be the perfect supper.

350
00:52:29,840 --> 00:52:30,870
She's getting in.

351
00:52:30,960 --> 00:52:33,510
Oh, my God,
she's going to go in the water there.

352
00:52:33,600 --> 00:52:36,990
The 15-foot gap
was just enough.

353
00:52:37,080 --> 00:52:38,830
That was amazing.

354
00:52:40,240 --> 00:52:42,110
Hands are freezing.

355
00:52:43,720 --> 00:52:46,990
- We have to go.
- Okay.

356
00:52:48,680 --> 00:52:50,950
Do you want to get
close up to the cubs?

357
00:52:51,040 --> 00:52:53,310
Still rolling. Yeah, that's cute.

358
00:52:53,400 --> 00:52:54,870
She's going in the water, okay.

359
00:52:54,960 --> 00:52:57,710
And water and then...
Stay with the cubs.

360
00:52:58,720 --> 00:53:01,110
Okay, the cubs for a nice splash.

361
00:53:03,560 --> 00:53:09,150
Go on, cubs. Yeah ! Hooray!
Well done, well done.

362
00:53:10,280 --> 00:53:11,670
Great stuff.

363
00:53:13,000 --> 00:53:15,550
She looked like she wanted
to get in the boat once or twice.

364
00:53:17,920 --> 00:53:20,510
Sometimes it's quite shocking
to actually look up from the monitor

365
00:53:20,600 --> 00:53:23,710
and realise they're about
15 feet away from you.

366
00:53:24,040 --> 00:53:26,070
But a lovely family group.

367
00:53:29,840 --> 00:53:33,270
The boat-based camera has helped
to get remarkably close shots

368
00:53:33,360 --> 00:53:34,510
of the bear family.

369
00:53:34,600 --> 00:53:37,230
But how would it cope
in the more extreme conditions

370
00:53:37,320 --> 00:53:38,670
of the Southern Ocean?

371
00:53:48,400 --> 00:53:51,630
Another Frozen Planet team headed south.

372
00:53:51,720 --> 00:53:55,710
The plan is to use the same camera
system to film the hunting strategy

373
00:53:55,800 --> 00:53:59,750
of the most spectacular
marine predators in Antarctica.

374
00:54:02,120 --> 00:54:03,590
Killer whales.

375
00:54:05,960 --> 00:54:10,430
The team enlisted the help of
scientists Bob Pitman and John Durban.

376
00:54:11,480 --> 00:54:14,070
They had put satellite tags
on the whales

377
00:54:14,160 --> 00:54:17,110
and so could locate them
for the camera team.

378
00:54:19,120 --> 00:54:22,670
Doug Allan operates the camera rig
from the wheelhouse,

379
00:54:22,760 --> 00:54:25,510
while Doug Anderson films from the deck.

380
00:54:27,280 --> 00:54:30,750
Yeah, there. See it?
It just surfaced right with them.

381
00:54:30,840 --> 00:54:33,110
Okay, there's a killer whale
at 11 o'clock,

382
00:54:33,200 --> 00:54:36,790
about 200 metres, heading towards
those two seals on the floe.

383
00:54:36,880 --> 00:54:39,910
- Good.
- This could be really good.

384
00:54:40,320 --> 00:54:42,990
At last, having tracked
the group for several days,

385
00:54:43,080 --> 00:54:46,030
the whales look as if
they are about to hunt.

386
00:54:46,920 --> 00:54:48,430
Yeah, they're going to go in for it.

387
00:54:52,360 --> 00:54:54,070
There it goes!

388
00:54:57,440 --> 00:54:58,790
Four whales here.

389
00:54:58,880 --> 00:55:02,870
Um, two adult females,
a juvenile and a big adult male.

390
00:55:02,960 --> 00:55:04,350
Swimming in formation,

391
00:55:04,440 --> 00:55:08,310
the killers create a wave
to wash the seal off the floe.

392
00:55:09,160 --> 00:55:11,270
It's all pretty intense.

393
00:55:11,360 --> 00:55:12,750
Oh, another wave.

394
00:55:13,400 --> 00:55:14,430
-Yes, we have...
-Wave.

395
00:55:15,000 --> 00:55:19,390
- Wow!
- Yeah, he's in the water.

396
00:55:19,840 --> 00:55:22,070
Having successfully
filmed several hunts

397
00:55:22,160 --> 00:55:24,470
with the boat-based cameras from above,

398
00:55:24,560 --> 00:55:27,390
the team are keen to see
what's happening underwater.

399
00:55:29,640 --> 00:55:31,630
Only one way to find out!

400
00:55:35,560 --> 00:55:37,590
Time to launch the dinghy.

401
00:55:46,040 --> 00:55:48,630
Doug Anderson approaches
the seal and the killers

402
00:55:48,720 --> 00:55:51,310
with an underwater camera
mounted on a pole.

403
00:56:00,920 --> 00:56:06,310
For the first time, the team can see how
the whales create the killer wave.

404
00:56:06,400 --> 00:56:08,230
There it is.

405
00:56:11,280 --> 00:56:13,550
The underwater camera
also reveals

406
00:56:13,640 --> 00:56:16,430
surprisingly cautious behaviour
by the whales.

407
00:56:17,400 --> 00:56:20,750
They seem wary of being bitten
by the much smaller seal.

408
00:56:22,560 --> 00:56:25,310
And they even blow bubbles
to confuse it.

409
00:56:26,640 --> 00:56:28,750
They're so cautious
with the seals.

410
00:56:28,840 --> 00:56:31,350
You know, at the end of the day,
the seal's got a big mouth full of teeth

411
00:56:31,440 --> 00:56:34,110
and these whales just don't take risks.

412
00:56:43,400 --> 00:56:44,950
Having dealt with the seal,

413
00:56:45,040 --> 00:56:48,030
the whales turn their attention
to the dinghy.

414
00:56:49,480 --> 00:56:53,430
First, they get right up close
for a better look at Doug.

415
00:57:00,480 --> 00:57:03,590
Then, they line up to create
the kind of wave

416
00:57:03,680 --> 00:57:05,750
that washed the seal off the floe.

417
00:57:05,840 --> 00:57:07,270
Oh!

418
00:57:09,440 --> 00:57:13,350
For a moment, the crew get
an uncomfortably close seal's eye view

419
00:57:13,440 --> 00:57:15,870
of this remarkable hunting strategy.

420
00:57:21,360 --> 00:57:23,270
Look at that, look.

421
00:57:23,360 --> 00:57:26,190
See that, Bob?
The juvies are making waves.

422
00:57:27,960 --> 00:57:31,830
It's a great feeling being there,
being so close to the behaviour,

423
00:57:31,920 --> 00:57:34,830
actually having the water
coming into the boat.

424
00:57:34,920 --> 00:57:35,990
From our point of view, you know,

425
00:57:36,080 --> 00:57:39,870
it's all about trying to get the feeling
of being with these whales,

426
00:57:39,960 --> 00:57:43,430
and with these whales, there's no bother
with that because they're so confident.

427
00:57:43,520 --> 00:57:47,030
They just want to be all around you
and checking you out.

428
00:57:47,120 --> 00:57:48,590
I mean, I can't imagine
that I'm going to have

429
00:57:48,680 --> 00:57:50,550
another experience like this
in my career, you know.

430
00:57:50,640 --> 00:57:52,750
These come along rarely,

431
00:57:52,840 --> 00:57:56,230
and you just feel happy and lucky
when they do come.

432
00:57:57,880 --> 00:58:00,630
You just don't get
better days than that.

